<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[我匆匆地走入森林中丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzXZeGIW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzX ZeGIW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260804 &quot; title=&quot;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&quot;>;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer, a dazzling news: 94 Lu Delin, a 20-year-old Shanghainese man, told on social media that he was abused by his nanny and defrauded of his pension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to Shanghai&#39;s 2022 elderly population and aging undertaking monitoring statistics, the registered elderly population aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022 will be 5.5366 million, accounting for nearly 40% of the total registered population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone is 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connection between individual circumstances and the lifeline of the times is about to emerge. It is a topic of public value. After encountering countless stories, I still can’t help but feel the initial excitement and impulse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, standing in winter and thinking back to that summer, the first thing that comes to mind is the part about mosquitoes. The scene we first arrived at was the community where the incident occurred. The community is located in Huangpu District, Shanghai, in the city center. It was built in the early 1990s and has 4 high-rise buildings interspersed with lush tall trees and low grass. It was a summer evening in Shanghai, and there were two or three old people sitting on the benches downstairs enjoying the shade. I wanted to know some surrounding information, and I became the target of &quot;mosquitoes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culprit is probably the &quot;flower mosquito&quot; as the local elderly call it. In just three or two hours, it left more than a dozen red and swollen bumps on my legs that were already wearing trousers. It was obviously not appropriate to scratch and chat at the same time, so I had to scratch twice quickly in the gap from one bench to another. The physical feeling was real, and this unspeakable and unseemly detail became the first fragment that hit me in my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This feeling is like a coincidence, and it has been fulfilled in several recent questions, which are about the body. In the topic of Lu Delin, the accused nanny is no longer in the local area. Even during the exchange of evidence before the court session, she still did not appear. The subjects on the other side, the two elderly people, were taken to Hangzhou by their son and daughter-in-law, and their mental condition was not very good for a time. Well, considering that I was afraid that the visit of strangers would bring excitement to the two old people, I did not go to see them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the message left for me? It&#39;s an empty house, and there are surrounding clues that need to be found. Room number 2401, pushing open the closed door, the first thing that came out was a sour smell. This is supposed to be well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. There are several orchids on the balcony. The flower pots are quite old, and the branches and leaves are wilting. For a moment, people don&#39;t know whether they should be described as being well-groomed or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moldy cutting boards, dirty yellow clothes, expired food, all indicating the disorder of life, suddenly broke into my eyes in an instant. In the eyes of young people, in the undisordered time, what I discussed with my friends around me was more about the spiritual part, and the instinct of the body was automatically ignored in the surface respectability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last topic was in Xi&#39;an. The interview subjects were some disabled people. In the continuous rain, we could not wait for the scene of their &quot;reunion&quot; and had to go door to door to chat. During the process, everyone The disorder of the body was mentioned invariably; and after Lu Delin chose the topic, I continued my business trip in Shanghai. The new topic was about Alzheimer&#39;s disease. The wife who became a caregiver told the story of taking care of her sick husband for nine years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From these stories, we can see what everyone is trying their best to maintain, and this effort seems to be an inevitable disorder of life. As a bystander, I hurriedly walked into this forest and felt the &quot;disorder&quot; that I had never experienced in real life. Some disorders are accidental, such as a car accident or sudden illness. They are also unprepared and rush into the forest and never get out; some disorders are slow, such as aging. They are already on the road to aging. It has been too long, so long that I have to admit that aging has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the perspective of journalism, when we encounter these stories, how should we report this disorder? After the initial excitement and impulse, it’s time to write. I think that we should not visit this forest with a pair of curious eyes and notice something unsightly. It should not be regarded as the author&#39;s delicate observation and be presented freely. It’s better to enter this forest with a level gaze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this time we entered this forest because of work, such a forest may break into our real life at any time, and in addition to the accident that breaks in at any time, its final arrival is a kind of inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“巴基斯坦可以从中国学到很多”:专访巴参议院国防委员会主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261738]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73936&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70727&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Exclusive interview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At noon on December 1, Mshahi De accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporter. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260507&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December At noon on the 1st, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of December 1, Guangzhou Yuexiu International Conference Center. After the one-hour press conference, Pakistani guest Mushahid Hussain Saeed walked out of the venue quickly. Entering December, the weather in Guangzhou turns cooler. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I like Guangzhou. It has a pleasant climate and is a very dynamic place in China.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid is the chairman of the Defense Committee of the Senate of Pakistan and the chairman of the Pakistan-China Society. From December 1st to 3rd, he was invited to participate in the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference to discuss and communicate with domestic and foreign guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past fifty years, Mushahid came to China many times. In his words, he witnessed the poverty-stricken China in the 1970s and the reform and opening-up China in the 1980s. &quot;What we see today is a prosperous and powerful China that is leading the development of globalization.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;I am very happy to witness the rise of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Mushahid Shahid spent four years in Washington, the United States, and obtained a master&#39;s degree in international relations from Georgetown University&#39;s School of Foreign Service, &quot;with an understanding of the U.S. political system and how it operates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He proposed that there are two different &quot;roads&quot; in the world today. One proposed by the United States and Western countries is security-centered, military-led, and focused on conflicts and confrontations. On the contrary, China insists on connectivity and cooperation, respecting diversity and being more inclusive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years, the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor, an important pilot project of the “Belt and Road Initiative”, has brought development opportunities to Pakistan. &quot;26 billion U.S. dollars of investment, 250,000 job opportunities, and 28,000 Pakistanis came to China to study. Electricity, roads, hospitals, education, etc. are constantly improving.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;These have benefited Pakistan.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Global and regional security are also the focus of the conference. Regarding peace on the India-Pakistan border, Mushahid has optimistic expectations. &quot;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is will. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on December 1, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/h4>; strong>;&lt;span>;Is this your first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum? How do you feel? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is my first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum. This forum is very valuable. First of all, we use this platform to understand China, the region and the world, and how they change and develop. Secondly, it is important for Pakistan to understand China. Because China is our closest strategic partner and our neighbor. Third, personally, I have been dealing with China for nearly fifty years. When I first came to China, I was still a young man of 17 or 18 years old. As a friend of China and a student of Chairman Mao, I saw China at that time. It can be said that I have witnessed China&#39;s transformation. If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with the first time you came to China, now what is the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to China was in the 1970s. At that time, China was very poor and isolated from the world. Today, China has become rich and powerful, a global leader, and a leader in globalization. China has proposed the “One Belt, One Road” initiative to lead green development and technological innovation. So, this is a huge change. In addition to China, the world has also changed. Because the global center of gravity is shifting from the West to the East. This change in China also reflects global changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What are your impressions of Guangdong? For example, for the two big cities of Guangzhou and Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to Guangdong Province was in 1972, when Guangzhou A trade fair is being held. During that time, I went shopping at Guangzhou Friendship Store. I only had 200 yuan with me at that time, but I felt like a &quot;millionaire&quot;. Because no matter how I bought it, I never spent all the money. At that time, the price of Chinese goods was too cheap. There were no computers at that time, so people used calculators to calculate accounts or calculate money by hand. Then, I took a train from Guangzhou to Hong Kong, which was indeed a wonderful experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Shenzhen was in 1982, and then in 1984. At that time, Shenzhen was a remote fishing village. After seeing it in person, I also felt that it was too backward and underdeveloped. When I first came to China, the city of Shenzhen did not exist. But in the subsequent 1980s, I saw the rapid rise of Shenzhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many Pakistani businessmen do business in Guangzhou. Can they find business opportunities here? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid: Of course. Pakistani businessmen in Guangzhou have been working here for years, even decades. In fact, many trades began not just now, but decades or even centuries ago. Guangzhou has always been a hub of connectivity and a warm and welcoming city. Foreigners are welcome to come here to do business and stay here. It has a pleasant climate, is close to the sea, and is a beautiful city. So Pakistanis enjoy life here, we support them and they can make a lot of money. So I think it&#39;s very good and they play a very good role in promoting relations between the people of Pakistan and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Pakistan can learn a lot from China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span >;Over the past 40 years, China has undergone tremendous changes. What lessons do you think this has for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Pakistan can learn a lot from this. First, have a clear vision. Second, there must be the will to turn this vision into reality. Deng Xiaoping, the architect of China&#39;s reform and opening up, once said, &quot;Seek truth from facts&quot; and &quot;development is the last word.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insist on development and openness, simplify bureaucracy and cumbersome processes, give talents the attention they deserve, and put them first. Good leadership qualities, policy continuity, learning from mistakes, openness and inclusiveness, focus on people-centered development, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I said, we can learn a lot from Guangdong, China, and China&#39;s reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Are you confident about Pakistan’s future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very optimistic about the future of Pakistan. I studied in the United States for four years, but I didn’t want to live there. I said I would go back and serve my country. This is thanks to our relationship with China, which is our neighbor and our best friend. China invests extensively in Pakistan. We must unleash the energy and creativity of the people of Pakistan, move forward, reduce bureaucracy and allow them to develop. We need to build industries, innovate, get education, and let them focus on what they should do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73937&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70728&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;At the media meeting on December 1 , Mushahid said that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260508&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At a media conference on December 1, Mushahid said that the “One Belt, One Road” initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, development opportunities have come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot; >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Is the “One Belt, One Road” initiative a development opportunity for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan, and we must seize this opportunity. In the past ten years, China has invested US$26 billion in Pakistan, created 250,000 jobs and produced 8,000 megawatts of electricity. These results have given Pakistan and its people confidence in the future. For example, Gwadar Port has developed and become a hub between Pakistan and Central Asian countries. So this is a big opportunity. Because of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative, a whole new world is unfolding. This is a historical opportunity for Pakistan to develop rapidly, and it is also a historical opportunity to learn from China&#39;s poverty alleviation and green development model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have misunderstandings about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, but most Pakistanis fully support the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Maritime Silk Road. Many Pakistanis care about China. They believe that China is Pakistan&#39;s good friend and close ally. Therefore, the negative voices come from foreign propaganda. They come from misinformation, false stories and fake news. We have to fight back against this. This is the biggest challenge facing the Belt and Road Initiative in the next decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Terrorist attacks occur frequently in Pakistan. How should the government solve the problem of terrorism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, terrorist incidents do happen from time to time. Some of the terrorists come from neighboring areas, which are very unstable. Some are forces that do not want cooperation and development between Pakistan and China. In addition, we feel that there are foreign forces controlling terrorist activities in Pakistan, and they specifically target Chinese companies, individuals and projects. Therefore, we must develop an effective counter-terrorism strategy in Pakistan, carry out effective Pakistan-China security cooperation, and develop effective plans to protect Chinese projects and Chinese people living in Pakistan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We reject global hegemony and regional hegemony”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2023, Pakistan’s Foreign Minister will visit India for the first time in 12 years. Do you think India and Pakistan have the will and motivation to deal with border conflicts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is a will. India should be broader-minded and not become narrow-minded in dealing with small countries. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony. Whether it is Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, etc., they all reject hegemony. Look at Afghanistan, they reject American hegemony even though they are a small country. Therefore, the size of a country does not equal its strength. India should learn from the mistakes of other major powers and understand how they went in the wrong (direction). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The internal and external obstacles to solving the India-Pakistan issue are What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the internal obstacles mainly come from the negative attitude of the Indian government, and their mentality must change. The external problem is the &quot;new cold war&quot; launched by the United States against China in Asia. They are using India to counter China. This is where the problem lies. Therefore, India should be part of the Asian countries and should be part of the Belt and Road Initiative. We want India to be united with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India is a nation-state with a great civilization. Why say no to this? Why should India work and behave like Washington or London? India should cooperate with Beijing, Kathmandu, Dhaka and Colombo. This is a regional issue. The future belongs to this region, not Europe or the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If India continues to respond negatively to relations between the two countries, will there be a risk of escalation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think escalation can be avoided because India also knows that if they try to escalate, the other country will respond . Every country hopes to safeguard its territorial integrity, safeguard sovereignty, and maintain unity and dignity. They tried to launch an attack on Pakistan in February 2019, and they sent several aircraft over Pakistan. But we fought back and shot down two helicopters. So the country will respond, and this response will come quickly and strongly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/ a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融合规榜：万余条罚单中，哪家银保机构在坚守底线？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:24:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the financial industry with strict supervision and strong supervision, compliance Rules are the bottom line that must be adhered to. As the world&#39;s largest banking market and the second largest insurance market, China&#39;s banking and insurance industries have always been the focus of supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Today, financial institutions’ compliance will be elevated to a new level. The Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that &quot;financial chaos and corruption problems continue to occur, and financial supervision and governance capabilities are weak&quot; and emphasized that &quot;financial supervision must be comprehensively strengthened to effectively prevent and resolve financial risks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Compliance has thus become a core consideration for the soundness of financial institutions’ operations. Which financial institution often commits crimes? Which financial institution frequently charges sky-high fines? Which financial institution has the most business lines involved? This is not only the key regulatory orientation of regulatory agencies, but also a concern of every financial consumer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to monitor the compliance of various financial institutions in real time, the relevant departments of Southern Weekend worked together for nearly a year to build the &quot;Shepherd-China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud&quot; Platform” (hereinafter referred to as the “Sheepdog Platform”). After continuous iterative upgrades and improvements, the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; now collects in real time the administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and their national offices, and simultaneously performs manual correction. test. In order to ensure the accuracy of the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; data, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared the recorded data with the information released by the three institutions one by one. The comparison results show that the accuracy of the penalty information data collected by the Shepherd Platform is as high as 100%, with no omissions or errors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively present the compliance of 20 systemically important banks and nine major life insurance companies in 2023, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; &quot;More than 10,000 pieces of data collected were mined and analyzed to construct the 2023 China New Financial Compliance List. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Penalty information from three regulatory agencies, two dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; in real time Includes administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, and their national offices. Therefore, this data information basically covers all regulatory penalties for the banking and insurance industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also conducts statistical analysis on the number of fines and the amount of fines received by financial institutions, because the number of fines and the amount of fines respectively reflect the extent of violations. How many and whether the violation is serious or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to statistics, from January to October 2023, 20 Chinese systemically important banks and their branches received a total of 802 fines, with an average of 802 fines per bank. and its branches received 40 fines; the above-mentioned fines totaled nearly 1.127 billion yuan in fines, and each bank and its branches were fined nearly 56.3548 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Nine major life insurance companies and their branches received 287 fines, with an average of 31 fines per life insurance company and its branches; the total of the above fines The fine was nearly 52 million yuan, and each life insurance company and its branches were fined nearly 5.73 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From a mean perspective, banks have higher values ​​than life insurance companies in terms of both the number of fines and the amount of fines. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that this is related to the bank&#39;s large scale and business volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center collected 10,467 pieces of penalty information (including institutions) issued by the three major regulatory agencies from January to October 2023 on the Shepherd Platform Penalty information and personal penalty information) conduct data mining analysis and construct a new financial compliance list for 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Which bank was fined the largest amount? Which company has been punished the most? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank compliance list shows that China Construction Bank, Minsheng Bank and Shanghai Bank took the top three spots. Among them, China Construction Bank and China Minsheng Bank were fined more than 200 million yuan each, far exceeding the 98.544 million yuan imposed by Bank of Shanghai. The list of the number of penalties imposed on the bank compliance list shows that the five major state-owned banks of Industry, Agriculture, Postal Service, Construction, and China are among the top five in the list, and the number of institutional penalty information is more than 70, far exceeding the sixth place Minsheng Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness Ranking - Bank Compliance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banks in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, from January to October 2023, the number of institutional fines received by each bank is basically the same. They are arranged in order of state-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks. There is no obvious pattern in the amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For state-owned banks, during the time period included in this list, compared with the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, and Postal Service Bank, Bank of Communications The degree of compliance is relatively good. In terms of the amount of fines, Bank of Communications ranked twelfth, while the other five state-owned banks were all ranked in the top ten. At the same time, the number of fines received by Bank of Communications is also relatively small, and it is the only bank that is not in the echelon of state-owned banks in terms of the number of fines. The bank received 41 pieces of penalty information during the time period of this statistics. The number of penalty messages is only higher than that of China Minsheng Bank, a joint-stock bank in the echelon, with 42 messages. China Construction Bank became the bank with the largest amount of fines at this stage due to a fine of nearly 200 million yuan issued by the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission (now the State Administration of Financial Supervision) on February 16, 2023. In addition, the amount of each fine of ICBC, which ranked first in the number of fines, did not exceed 6 million yuan. Therefore, its total amount of fines ranks low among state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The compliance status of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks is relatively similar. During the statistical time period of this list, one bank in each of the above two categories ranked in the top three in the list of fines imposed, and the reason was that they received large fines of more than 60 million yuan. Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu are the two banks with the best compliance during the statistical period of this list. The fines imposed on the above two banks did not exceed 10 million yuan, which were 600,000 yuan and 8.601 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that because the four major banks have large business scale and many branches, a high number of penalties does not necessarily mean that their compliance is lower than that of other banks. bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Loans are still the hardest hit area for violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Analyzing the types of violations, the statistical time of this list During this period, the violations of the 20 systemically important banks were concentrated in three areas: loans, external guarantees and customer identification. Among them, the loan business is the hardest hit area for bank violations. The above-mentioned fine of nearly 200 million yuan from China Construction Bank involves a total of 38 violations of laws and regulations, 15 of which are related to violations of loan business. Among the top ten in terms of the amount of fines received, except for Shanghai Bank, which only had one fine for &quot;violating the handling of domestic guarantees and overseas loans&quot; and seven other fines involving illegal handling of foreign exchange business, the fines received by the remaining nine banks all related to loans. Business violations. In fact, according to penalty information over the years, loan business violations have always been an &quot;old disease&quot; in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Illegal handling of domestic guarantees for overseas loans and illegal external guarantees are the largest fines imposed on banks by the State Administration of Foreign Exchange during this statistical period. Bank of Shanghai and China CITIC Bank were fined 98.544 million yuan and 11.7544 million yuan respectively for the above-mentioned issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, customer identification issues were the third highest fine imposed on banks by regulatory agencies during this statistical period. Among them, the highest fines received by Ping An Bank and Postal Savings Bank during this statistical period both involved &quot;failure to perform customer identification obligations as required&quot;, and the fines for these two tickets were 53.4117 million yuan and 31.86 million yuan respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above analysis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that banks need to focus on the compliance of loan business, guarantee business and payment and settlement business. How to eradicate old diseases and ensure the compliance of loan business is an issue that major commercial banks need to think about urgently. Today, some banks have applied artificial intelligence technology to assist manual loan review and other processes. Therefore, improving the accuracy of artificial intelligence technology in assisting in reviewing loan information may be one of the feasible solutions to rectify the &quot;old disease&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance companies urgently need to strengthen the implementation of internal control systems&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance compliance list shows that regardless of Ping An Life ranks first in terms of both the amount of fines and the number of fines it has received. Taikang Life ranked third and second respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The second place in the list of the amount of fines and the third place in the list of the number of fines are Taiping Life and China Life respectively. It is worth noting that AIA Life Insurance Co., Ltd. performed better in this compliance list. During this statistical period, AIA Life was the only financial institution among all participants in the list that did not receive any fines from the three major financial regulatory agencies and their dispatched agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness List - Life Insurance Compliance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the perspective of the types of violations, life insurance companies’ violations are mainly fraud, deception and inducement of policyholders and system management issues . According to the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, from January to October 2023, there were 453 pieces of information about penalties for life insurance companies. Among them, 187 involve fraud, 105 involve deceiving or inducing policyholders, and 130 involve internal control systems and management issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, most of the fines involving &quot;inadequate implementation of internal control systems&quot; involve &quot;preparing false information&quot; and &quot;inciting and inducing insurance agents to engage in acts that violate integrity&quot; voluntary activities”. &quot;Instigating and inducing insurance agents to engage in activities that violate their fiduciary obligations&quot; is the root cause of &quot;deceiving or inducing policyholders&quot;. This may be related to the business value concept of the company and its branches. If the design of the company&#39;s assessment indicators is unreasonable or the implementation is deformed, or the managers of relevant departments behave inappropriately, it will be difficult for their subordinates, especially grassroots personnel, to ensure business compliance when conducting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, the compliance issues of life insurance companies this year can basically be attributed to the unscientific design of the indicator system and the inability to implement the internal control system. The Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recommends that leaders of life insurance companies should adhere to the strategic focus of high-quality development and should not ignore compliance for temporary performance impulses, let alone engage in fraud that affects the image of the company or even the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿险效能提升榜：谁现在领先？谁拥有未来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2023, China’s life insurance industry will continue to undergo difficult transformation. In a complex and ever-changing market: Life insurance was a hot seller in the first half of the year due to high interest rates, but the twists and turns in the equity market made life insurance investments suffer. &quot;Integrating newspaper and bank into one&quot; (see Southern Weekend App for details) Perennially deformed? &quot;>;&quot;Big accounts are high and small accounts are constantly rising. Why is the bancassurance business deformed all year round?&quot;&lt;/a>;) The new regulations have made the bancassurance channel under pressure even more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, life insurance companies are still determined to continue transformation, pursuing efficiency improvements, and are more committed to the blue ocean market of pension insurance and insurance +, and are competing for more considerate customer service upgrades . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Who is leading the race to transformation? Who sticks more to the &quot;customer-centric&quot; strategy? Which company is more transparent and open to the media and the public? Which company pays more attention to compliance? Which company pays more attention to innovation? Based on the principles of objectivity, fairness and science, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed an evaluation index system for life insurance performance improvement rankings and evaluated the performance of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight major dimensions&amp;nbsp;Fourteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Life Insurance Performance Improvement List&quot; Quantitative The qualitative evaluation index system consists of six first-level indicators and fourteen second-level indicators. Among them, the first-level indicators include three quantitative dimensional indicators of &quot;operational capabilities, customer service, and regulatory compliance&quot; and three qualitative dimensional indicators of &quot;business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecology, and product innovation.&quot; The secondary indicators are refined into fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of the quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on the special research on the above-mentioned life insurance companies, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the participating life insurance companies. The company conducts independent real-name scoring. Both scores have a weight of 15%. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the life insurance company under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2087&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a.png&quot; data-key= &quot;260503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now The specific description of quantitative and qualitative indicators is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(1) Business capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How to judge the management ability of a life insurance company? From the perspective of business models, the business logic of life insurance companies is to collect premiums to form insurance liabilities, use insurance liabilities to invest in investment assets, and investment assets generate investment income. Therefore, evaluating a life insurance company&#39;s ability to operate is good or bad, one is to obtain premium capabilities; the other is to see the ability of investment assets. The industry&#39;s common premium income measures the liability capacity of life insurance companies, but the premium income of nine life insurance companies accounts for about 3/4 of the life insurance industry, and the life insurance efficiency list aims to select the excellence. Therefore, the new indicator insurance service revenue is included in the statistics &lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; What is insurance service income? According to the interpretation of the Ping An Semi -annual report, insurance service revenue refers to the confirmation of the insurance period based on the service provided and eliminates the investment component. Insurance service income reflects income from insurance business. In accordance with the revision of the &quot;Enterprise Accounting Standards No. 25 -Insurance Contract&quot; (Caixin [2020] No. 20) on December 24, 2020, listed insurance companies will be implemented from January 1, 2023. This regulation is also called &quot;Chinese version of ifRS17&quot;. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found in the survey that except for China Life and Taikang Life Insurance, 7 other life insurance companies have applied for IFRS17 for new insurance contracts. Under the new accounting standards, insurance service revenue replaces insurance business income, which has also led to a significant decrease in confirmation of premium income in life insurance companies. Life insurance companies with a large proportion of investment and savings products and high premium premiums are more affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; In addition, the value, profitability and sustainable development of new business value and internal value measurement of insurance companies, total investment yield measurement investment performance. These three indicators are commonly used in the industry. In summary, the total right of the four -level indicator of this dimension has a total of 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; (2) customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The insurance industry is a typical service-intensive industry. How to implement the development concept of &quot;customer -centric&quot; to meet the diversified needs of customers, and improving the quality of service in the insurance industry is a key issue for my country&#39;s insurance industry to achieve high -quality development. From the perspective of demand, the age composition and demand of the insured group have changed significantly, and the requirements for insurance services for young customers have become increasingly improved. From the perspective of the supply side, my country&#39;s insurance products are highly homogeneous, product pricing is not large, and the scope of responsibility is basically similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that life insurance industry cannot sell insurance as &quot;fast-moving consumer goods&quot;. Otherwise, large -scale surrender may occur, and the service attributes of &quot;slow experience&quot; and &quot;slow decision&quot; should be returned to insurance. Risk guarantee is the core function of the insurance industry. To implement &quot;customer -centric&quot;, on the one hand, it is necessary to allow insurance surnames to insurance and return to the guarantee function. On the other hand, it is necessary to make insurance a &quot;valuable value&quot; insurance. In other words, it is necessary to make consumers afford to buy, buy it, buy it convenient, and rest assured. Based on this, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sets up three second -level indicators: the amount of claims, the average claims time limit and the surrender rate of the insurance service dimension in the customer service dimension. The three dimensions of the three indicators have a total of 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; (3) compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; During the &quot;Fourteenth Five-Year Plan&quot; period, &quot;specification&quot; became a keyword for the development of the insurance industry. At present, institutional supervision, behavior supervision, functional supervision, penetrating supervision and continuous supervision have been gradually formed. In 2021, the focus of supervision is designed in the top -level reform of the reform. For the field of corporate governance, solvency, and insurance use of insurance capital, the &quot;Bank Insurance Institutional Company Governance Guidelines&quot;, &quot;Insurance Company&#39;s Capital Calculation Rules (II) and&quot; Regarding the Division of the Insurance of Insurance Funds Partial Sectional Partial Section Notice of Normal Documents. In 2022, the regulatory agency deepened the supervision of consumer equity and released the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Protection of Consumers&#39; Rights and Interests of Bank Insurance Institutions&quot;. This is a basic and programmatic document in the field of consumer rights protection in the banking and insurance industry. In 2023, regulatory transfer to bank insurance and insurance channels regulated, and issued the &quot;Notice on Regulating Banking Channel Insurance Products&quot; and &quot;Administrative Measures for Insurance Sales Behavior&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sets four sub-indicators at the compliance dimension, of which the core solvency adequacy ratio and comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio are the key regulatory indicators; insurance The service quality index refers to the 2022 Insurance Service Quality Index issued by Bank of China Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Silver Insurance Credit&quot;); Regulatory data from January-September contained in the system. The weight of the four sub -indicators of this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; (4) business cross-penetration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; This dimension reflects the synergy effect and cross-sales capabilities of life insurance companies on different business lines. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the growth of life insurance institutions has shifted from &quot;scale&quot; to &quot;quality&quot;. The &quot;insurance+service&quot; development strategy is already an industry consensus. The weight of the dimension is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; (5) big healthy ecological construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The development of pension finance is inseparable from the big healthy ecological construction, because &quot;the elderly are raised and the disease is medical&quot; is inseparable. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the development of life insurance companies in the field of major health business in accordance with the annual reports of various life insurance companies or other public information. The weight of the dimension is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; (6) product innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; This dimension mainly reflects the ability of life insurance companies to develop and innovate. The weight of the dimension is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; China Life Lead &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; According to the above dimension and indicator system, and comprehensively comprehensively life insurance companies 2023 Annual report and announcement and data on third -party rating agencies, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated nine insurance companies, respectively to obtain the overall score of quantitative qualitative indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Comprehensive media factor weights and external expert review weights, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has established a life insurance efficiency list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The list shows that the top three of Chinese Life, Ping An Life and AIA&#39;s life are ranked. Among them, China Life and Ping An Life Leading has obvious advantages, and it is also the only life insurance company with a total score of more than 60 points on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;img alt = &quot;(Liang Shuyi/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/1da3a7600F.PNG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1188 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/1da3a7600F.Png &quot;Data-key =&quot; 260504 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: justify; &quot;>; (Liang Shuyi/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: justify ; &quot;>; Sub -index system observation, in the quantitative qualitative index scores, China Life, Ping An Life, and AIA Life are ranked in the top three, and the gap between the scores of other six life insurance institutions. The third place in AIA is nearly very different from the Taiping Renshou score in the fourth place. This shows that the leading advantage of the first ladder life insurance company is greater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; In the score of the expert jury, the expert judges have the eyes of Ping An Life. The company is the only life insurance company with 9 points. In the media factors, the reasons for AIA Life Insurance and Life Insurance and Taibao Life Insurance failed to respond within a limited time and did not score, and then affected the total score to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Divide in different dimensions, China Life, Ping An Life and Life Insurance are ranked among the top three. China Life Insurance&#39;s interim reporting in 2023 did not apply for the new insurance contract standards, but instead of insurance service revenue with insurance business income, so there is a total of estimate to a certain extent. However, the data of China Life in the third quarter of 2023 shows that its insurance service revenue reached 136.439 billion yuan, which was slightly lower than Ping An Life&#39;s 168.945 billion yuan. The New Financial Research Center of the Southern Weekend found that after adjustment, it did not affect China Life List in the Life Insurance Effective List. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Why can China Life top the top? China Life has obvious advantages on the debt side. According to the third quarter of China Life, in the first three quarters of 2023, the scale of premium income, new single premiums, the scale of first -year premiums and growth rates all reached a record high in the past three years. The first -year and above first -year premiums were RMB 44.639 billion, an increase of 15.4%year -on -year, accounting for 42.12%of the first -year premiums; the value of new business in the first three quarters of 2023 continued to increase, an increase of 14.0%year -on -year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; From the asset side, the decline in investment yields is a common problem in the industry. Under the background of the interest rate center movement and the fluctuation of the equity market, the return on investment in the insurance industry generally declined. According to China Integrity International data, in 2022, the return on investment in the life insurance industry fell to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which was significantly lower than the average level of investment in the industry in the past ten years. Therefore, the overall score of this indicator is low, and the personnel life insurance uses the group&#39;s data score the highest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; China Life&#39;s performance in the customer service dimension. From the perspective of sub -indicators, three indicators of China Life are at the leading level of the industry. According to the company&#39;s 2023 report data, the average time limit for claims was 0.39 days, a year -on -year speed -up of 17%; &quot;claims prepaid&quot; exceeded 74 million yuan; &quot;claims direct payment&quot; exceeded 3.41 million people; 5.4 billion yuan, an increase of 50%year -on -year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; At the same time, China Life is not delayed in regulatory compliance. From the perspective of sub -indicators, the company&#39;s core settlement capacity adequacy ratio reaches 140%, and the comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio reaches 204%, which is much higher than the regulatory requirements. It is also at the average level among 9 life insurance companies. Among the 2022 insurance service quality index released by China Banking Letter, China Life obtained a high score of 94.61, which is higher than the average level of the personal insurance industry 85.28. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; But according to the &quot;shepherd dog&quot; -China-China financial industry compliance cloud platform data. The average value is 29 times. Because China Life has a large business volume and a large number of branches, this indicator does not show that the company&#39;s compliance is lower than other peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; For pension finance, cultivate new growth poles &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; As the core composition of the pillar of the third pension, pension insurance is becoming a strategic type of insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend believes that there is huge potential for pension finance. The three dimensions of business cross -penetration, large healthy ecological construction and product innovation reflect the development of the pension and financial company of life insurance companies to a certain extent. However, life insurance companies have not disclosed their standards due to the exploration period. Therefore, on the basis of the annual reports of various life insurance companies in the Southern Weekend, the Southern Weekend of the Southern Weekend refers to various information such as announcement and public publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The list shows that although Ping An Life ranks second in the overall score of the list, it scores first in the evaluation of three qualitative indicators. China Life Life Second, AIA Life Insurance, Taiping Life and Sunshine Life are tied for third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also found in the investigation that nine life insurance companies are actively participating in pension financial construction. Among them, China People&#39;s Pension Insurance Co., Ltd. and China Life Insurance Co., Ltd. and Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd. are the first batch of pension insurance companies designated by the State Administration of Finance and Administration to participate in commercial pensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Other life insurance companies are also actively exploring pension financial business. For example, Ping An Life relying on China&#39;s Ping An Group&#39;s resources, it continues to make efforts in the direction of &quot;insurance+service&quot;. In terms of &quot;insurance+health&quot;, Ping An Life launched the &quot;Ping An Zhen Run&quot; health service plan. In the first three quarters of 2023, Ping An Life has served more than 19 million customers, an increase of more than 10%year -on -year; &quot;In terms of, other professional companies in Ping An Life Insurance have built high -quality recreational brands&quot; Zhenyi Nian &quot;. In October 2023, Ping An Zhenyi officially released the 3.0 of Kangyang, and launched two new rights: living and CCAH (Continuing Care at Home). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; In terms of &quot;insurance+home care&quot;, Ping An Life continues to explore home pension services. As of the end of September 2023, the Ping An home -care service has covered 54 cities across the country, with a cumulative qualification of more than 70,000 people. 50%of the 54 cities have activated home service rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Taikang Life has collaborated with 20 &quot;Taikang Houses&quot; in the country, becoming a benchmark for the industry. Sunshine Life will start with the Kangyang Community of Sunshine Family (Guangzhou), and successively deploy the CCRC pension community in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend believes that the combination of medical care is the general trend, and &quot;insurance+service&quot; is becoming a new blue ocean. Each life insurance company should continue to innovate in terms of products and services. On the one hand, it enriches product connotation and expands the scope of insurance product security. On the other hand, it will extend the insurance service value chain and provide comprehensive services such as health management, medical services and long -term care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欠发达县1个在编身后1.8个临聘：转移支付保“吃饭财政”难以为继]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261728]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 18:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot;, the reporter in a county in Wumeng Mountain District During the investigation, it was found that the county&#39;s total salary budget was 2.63 billion, of which 26 billion were inquiries, 170 million retirees were retired, and 460 million were appointed. The number of employees is 1.8 times that of the in -service staff, but the former&#39;s total salary budget is less than a quarter of the latter. In addition, the county&#39;s total salary expenses have exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue. In several districts and counties in the county, the number of employees was 1.7 times that of the employees. &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Specifies, the per capita income of the people in the county is about 16,100 yuan per capita, and the total number of personnel is 28806; 10,000 yuan, the total number of personnel is 15,580. The per capita annual income of employees is eight times that of the employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; How do you think of this phenomenon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; First of all, the county has completely reduced to &quot;eating finance&quot;. The total salary budget of the people in the first year is 460 million, which has exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue, which means that the county&#39;s economic strength and endogenous financial drawing ability are very weak. In the context of the housing market, especially in small land fiscal stalls, the annual annual wage budget expenditure of 2.63 billion yuan is likely to come from transfer payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now it provides economic developed areas with transfer payment sources, and it is not even difficult for finances. In the county, the county may have to lose weight: reducing people, reducing, reducing budgets, and reducing expenses is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Secondly, the so-called in-service staff is the formal work of the preparation; the so-called temporary worker and contract worker. If people must be reduced, which type of people will be eliminated first? From the perspective of effects and efficiency, how should we eliminate redundant staff? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The answer to the first question is obvious. In the case of financial difficulties, it will first be eliminated. It is called &quot;Temporary Workers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The reason is simple: the principle of minimum actual amount. In theory, there is no iron rice bowl. The current &quot;Civil Service Evaluation Regulations (Trial)&quot; has an annual assessment. If you are not competent, you will be dismissed. &quot; But in fact, unless a major principled mistake is made, it is difficult to implement an economic layoff on a civil servant or a career preparation. The rice bowl may be troubled by himself or family, which is hindered and &quot;not good.&quot; However, the temporary workers who have not been preparation are different. It is psychologically prepared for the dismissal because the unit has no money or the request of the superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, should temporary workers (first) be eliminated? Before answering this question, you must understand why the unit recruits temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Temporary workers are different from temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One is related, but the relationship is not hard enough and is not enough to get in place in one step. The reporter&#39;s investigation was discovered that most of the recruitment and management of the employees were not responsible for the unified department. Basically, in accordance with the principle of &quot;who employer, who recruited&quot;, no need to be approved by the establishment department, the financial department, the organization department, and the human -social department or the human and social department. The recruitment procedure is more casual, there is a phenomenon of disorderly growth and unavailable quality, and it is difficult to eliminate human emotional hire and relationship employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The other is nothing to do with or almost nothing. , Suffering and trouble, the accident may be pushed out of the pot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，此类单位内部也矛盾重重：一方面，正式工，拿钱多、福利好，干活少，有各种获取荣誉与Promoting opportunities; on the other hand, the temporary workers who do work, take less money, welfare, and more work. Such a close contrast, the latter&#39;s psychology will be unbalanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But, if the logic of the market, the salary obtained by working temporary workers is the market price; The part is the premium brought by the preparation. Multi -person competes for a preparation, competing for this premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The public thinks that &quot;the temporary work is retired&quot; is the first type, so that the unrefined relationship is left to improve the efficiency, but in fact It is often the second type of retreat to let the working temporary workers walk away. It does not matter and hard work, and the resistance to retreat is the least. However, after they are retired, the formal work will often be suffering, because there are always people who have to do. After the abolition of these many people, the work can still be done. In this sense, the efficiency is still improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Finally, it is still necessary to look at government functions from the perspective of government and market/society. Government management should also be quantified: a county&#39;s tax revenue of less than 500 million yuan a year, with a total salary budget of 2.63 billion yuan, and a fiscal meal has been eaten by the county. It really needs so many people, spend so much money, and care so much? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It should be sorted out: which management and service functions are absolutely necessary and can only be performed by the government, how much budget and personnel are appropriate; which can be delayed and allowed Socially managed itself; which belongs to excessive control and improper control instead of stifling the economic vitality; even, if the net flow of a county is too large, the population and the economy are constantly shrinking. There have been practice in many places in the township, which has reduced the government scale and released market vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition, because the civil servants have become the actual iron rice bowl, the premium brings by the preparation is very high, so everyone will have such a large and compilation of the examination and compilation of the examination public examinations. enthusiasm. If the annual assessment of civil servants and public institutions can be implemented, and dare to dismiss the old fried dough sticks that do not work like a market -oriented enterprise, so that the premiums brought by the preparation will be zero. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In order to compress and eliminate the premium brought by the preparation, there is another way: market salary is market-oriented, depending on the temporary working salary from the market, Then the formal work&#39;s salary should be aligned as much as possible to squeeze the premium premium. A cleaners are prepared in a certain place, and the cleaner employees who have edited to do their own work, and then enjoy the difference. This difference is the premium brought by the preparation. The government or taxpayer became a big head and spent more money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:25:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：目前流行的急性呼吸道疾病均由已知病原体引起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261726]]><description> &lt;DIV>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 15:16:28 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; The National Health and Health Commission will hold a press conference today to introduce the situation of the prevention and control of winter respiratory diseases. Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, said that at present, the National Health Commission, together with the State Administration of Traditional Chinese Medicine and the National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention, continue to carry out winter respiratory disease monitoring and research and judgment, and are doing a good job in allocating medical resources, optimizing the medical treatment process, and playing a central role. Medical functions and other work are deployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to monitoring, the current popular acute respiratory diseases are caused by known diseases, and there are corresponding mature treatment methods. No new virus or bacterial new hair infectious diseases are found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To further increase the supply of medical services, promote the pediatric clinics of various medical institutions such as traditional Chinese medicine hospitals, maternal and child health hospitals, etc., &quot;should be opened&quot; according to the number of patients. Service time, expand the hospital bed, and continuously optimize the process of registering, inspection, payment, etc. to facilitate the masses to seek medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is necessary to do a good job of hierarchical diagnosis and treatment, unblocked referral channels, cross -section and inter -hospital adjustment personnel, ensure the supply of medical supplies, promote Internet medical care, and maximize the ability to take care of the diagnosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is necessary to give full play to the role of traditional Chinese medicine, combine traditional Chinese and western medicine, and target common diseases in the winter respiratory tract, popularize the knowledge of traditional Chinese medicine prevention and treatment of diseases, and improve the effect of prevention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To do a good job of supply and vaccination services such as influenza, the elderly, children and other key groups are vaccinated as soon as possible to reduce the risk of disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Persist in masks, wash hands, and often ventilate, which is very effective for preventing the spread of respiratory diseases. It is necessary to take good personal protection, go to work without illness, go to school without illness, and adhere to good personal hygiene habits and a healthy lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪后长城，巨龙伏纱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261720]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 15:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[订阅号的爱情陷阱：老年人深陷“互联网弟弟”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 12:35:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The 51st Statistical Report on China&#39;s Internet Development Situation released by China Internet Network Information Center &quot; shows that as of December 2022, people aged 60 and above account for 14.3% of the total number of Internet users, and the number of elderly Internet users has reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly Internet users lacks attention. (Visual China Map)&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d215d9ba31.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d215d9ba31.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;China Internet The 51st &quot;Statistical Report on China&#39;s Internet Development Status&quot; released by the Network Information Center shows that as of December 2022, people aged 60 and above accounted for 14.3% of the total number of Internet users, and the number of elderly Internet users reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly netizens lacks attention. (Visual China Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At three o&#39;clock in the morning, Ruidi had insomnia again. He sent greetings to his sister on the other side of the network, just like the &quot;good morning&quot; and &quot;good evening&quot; repeated almost every day, waiting for his sister&#39;s greetings. comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ruidi said that the encounter between him and his sister was arranged by fate. He reminded his sister to wear more clothes in the cold weather and take good care of her body. After exchanging heart-to-hearts with his sister day after day, his thoughts were &quot;a ray of sunshine&quot; and &quot;I want to turn into the moonlight in front of the window to accompany her forever.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video sent by Ruidi shows that he is a man in his thirties or forties with a gentle voice and a back that looks like Jin Dong. Recently, his parents suddenly fell ill. In order to win the prize, he decided to participate in a singing competition. Just the night before the competition, he told his dilemma:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are thresholds for participating in this competition. The popularity on the day of registration must be Only those who meet the requirements can be shortlisted... If you support your brother, can you help him increase his popularity data?... Sister, please give your brother some likes and praise for the author. 188 or 256 praises can help him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;At the end of 2020, the &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; phenomenon surfaced. A large number of fake accounts pretending to be actor Jin Dong used short videos and live broadcasts to make money from middle-aged and elderly fans. Two years have passed, and the aftermath of the &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; incident continues. In September 2023, &quot;Xiucai&quot;, an Internet celebrity with tens of millions of fans who specifically targets middle-aged and elderly people, was reported for tax evasion and defrauding fans, and his account was banned. In October 2023, the Shanghai Jing&#39;an District Procuratorate prosecuted eight people who committed fraud under the false identity of Jin Dong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the position of &quot;Fake Jin Dong&quot; has moved from short videos to public accounts. These accounts calling themselves &quot;Dongdi&quot; and &quot;Ruidi&quot; first used video accounts to attract traffic and induce fans to pay attention to the subscription accounts, and then continued to make up stories in the public accounts to gain fans&#39; sympathy and rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new round of emotional harvesting is more private. After adding fans to WeChat on a large scale through public accounts, the interaction is transferred to private chats or circles of friends. The emotional hollowness of over 100 million elderly people has led them to fall into the trap. Is it not just a scholar or Jin Dong? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835012371236170&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Public account &quot;Eastern Sound Accompanying&quot; &quot;The latest video released tells the story of a younger brother who encountered setbacks in a singing competition and asked his older sister for help. This is a common routine for such public accounts. .MP4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/12/02/2TqweEM14D2koLeC4n5MiWe3FgLYwXjV5G77ZM1B.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/63e6b592327083501237123 6170/aHSmLYlmfF0A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/63e6b5923270835012371236170/aHSmLYlmfF0A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Grandma is in love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru discovered the secret behind the subscription account by chance, and his 71-year-old grandma was already deeply involved in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My life is so busy every day, you know? I have nothing to do, sleep, watch videos, and that&#39;s it. Of course I want to see you, why do I want to see you? You miss me, and I do too. I miss you.&quot; My grandma said to a person on WeChat who had a note called &quot;The Love of My Life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru looked through his grandma’s watch list and found a large number of public accounts and video accounts with similar names - &quot;Brother Ruidong accompanies you&quot;, &quot;Brother Dong accompanies sister&quot;, &quot;Ruidi warmly accompanies me&quot;, &quot;Ruirui Always with you&quot; etc. The titles of public account articles are very long, for example, &quot;Sister, I am really anxious. If I can&#39;t even seize this opportunity, I will be sad for a long time.&quot; The accompanying picture is usually a photo of a man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the official account of &quot;Rui Dongdi Lives Together&quot;, he claimed that he would participate in the top 20 of the singing competition, and Dong Xueru&#39;s grandmother encouraged him to work hard. Then the official account sent a payment QR code with the following sentence: &quot;After my brother is done with work, he will accompany his sister to chat about daily life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking through these push notifications, you will find that this Rui Dongdi is really Very busy: one moment I have to help promote the competition, another moment I was successfully promoted, and now I am on TV. &quot;I am in a hurry. If I don&#39;t see my sister at this time, my brother&#39;s future will be gone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This handsome and caring fake brother occupies an important position in some people&#39;s lives. From the comments, you can get a glimpse of the passionate hearts of fans. They are &quot;Lotus&quot;, &quot;Caiying&quot;, &quot;Peace and happiness&quot; or &quot;Tomorrow will be better&quot;. They say, &quot;Sister knows, I know you in my life, I am the happiest sister&quot;, &quot;Thank you for caring about me&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In their minds, the brother who spoke to them could be anyone. Dong Xueru discovered that her grandma regarded the other party as her crush in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My grandma is from Sichuan and lives in Beijing with few friends. For more than ten years, a man has regularly organized square dances for two to three hundred people near her residence. This teacher Tie often wears floral clothes with English letters printed on them, dyes her blond hair, and wears a little makeup. She becomes the idol of middle-aged and elderly people and calls them &quot;sister&quot;. Later, my grandma moved and could no longer dance in the square. Instead, she took online dance classes and could only watch videos in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma firmly believed that these messages were sent by Teacher Tie, because only Teacher Tie, who was eight years younger than her, would treat her like a sibling. &quot;These (public accounts) different names are all the pseudonyms of Teacher Tie, and they are all his online names... All these articles are written for her.&quot; Dong Xueru told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma sends a lot of messages every day. &quot;I feel like I have so much to say. As long as I sit down, I will hide in the room with my mobile phone and send voice messages.&quot; Once, my younger brother sent a message saying that he came to his sister&#39;s city and saw a figure that looked like his sister. He was very disappointed to find that it was not the same. Grandma comforted, &quot;Fool, why are you disappointed? I&#39;m thinking of you too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru and his family tried to persuade him many times but to no avail, and his grandmother felt bored. They took grandma to the local public security bureau to receive Internet security education, but grandma wouldn&#39;t listen and just asked the police if they could find people online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru’s mother and uncle had no choice but to ask Teacher Tie himself for clarification. Teacher Tie denied that it was him and made it clear that he had no time for a relationship and would not like her. The family played the recording to grandma, but she decided that the children were hindering her and pushing Teacher Tie too hard. &quot;He is immature and childish.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After speaking out online, Dong Xueru’s post received nearly 4,000 replies. Many netizens said that their family members have encountered similar situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A girl sent a private message to Dong Xueru, saying that her grandmother was also obsessed with such public accounts and corporate WeChat. In addition to giving rewards, she would also buy high-priced goods sold by them. When the mother found out, she deleted the accounts in anger. Soon, the grandmother added them back, accusing her daughter of blocking her pursuit of happiness. The relationship between mother and daughter is still at a stalemate. The girl said to Dong Xueru, I really don’t know what to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A large number of younger brother accounts use subscription accounts, corporate and personal WeChat and Moments to conduct false emotional exchanges with the elderly, thereby inducing rewards. (Screenshot of Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;260411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;A large number of brother accounts use subscription accounts, corporate and personal WeChat and Moments to conduct false emotional exchanges with the elderly, thereby inducing rewards. (Screenshot by Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The fake younger brother is back&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Dong Xueru’s post attracted attention, the platform successively banned some younger brother accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai got angry when talking about these Dongdi and Ruidi numbers. Ma Kai runs a number of emotional public accounts and has been implicated recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai’s public account is similar to an emotional radio station. The largest account has 34 million followers. It posts a six- to seven-minute emotional chicken soup every day, “What should you do if you feel tired, etc.” Emotional words.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Kai emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that his account is different from the scam account. Accounts like Dongdi and Ruidi &quot;won&#39;t tell you any emotional quotes or send you any songs, they will just kill pigs&quot;; while my own &quot;di&quot; account relies on emotional copywriting to seek rewards. There will be no false identities, false stories, or emotional deception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been paying attention to these younger brother public accounts for a long time. They all speak in the same way and can be roughly divided into two categories: one is for younger brothers to participate in concerts and needs support from popularity; the other is for younger brothers who are sick and hospitalized and need support. Medical expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diverting traffic from video accounts to public accounts is the beginning of harvesting. Operators leave links to public accounts in the comment area of ​​video accounts, place payment codes in articles on public accounts, or leave corporate WeChat or private accounts. WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the registered entities of these public accounts are enterprises. Southern Weekend reporters found that a large number of similar accounts were registered by several department stores in Haikou, with names such as &quot;Xiu Cai Singing Department Store&quot; and &quot;Rui Rui&#39;s Department Store&quot;. According to industrial and commercial information, many department stores have different operators, but use the same mobile phone number when registering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted one of the operators Y. There are four Hainan department stores under Y&#39;s name, which are specially used to register younger brother&#39;s public accounts. WeChat stipulates that an individual business owner can register two public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Y told Southern Weekend reporters that his team of three people has registered a total of 12 individual businesses. He has been working in this industry for nearly a year, and the largest public account has 70,000 to 80,000 followers, all of whom are Drain and accumulate traffic through video accounts. He refused to disclose his income, saying only that he &quot;doesn&#39;t make much.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the e-commerce platform, for only 100 yuan, some merchants provide individual business license agency services, upload ID card information and mobile phone number, and perform remote real-name authentication. The store said that there is no limit to the number of registrations per person, and there is no need to pay money to continue after applying, and there is no need to worry about inspections by the industrial and commercial authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using false individual business registrations to increase the number of WeChat public accounts is no longer a secret in the industry. These public accounts have become a powerful tool for batch release of information and batch operations. Y proved this. He is in Guangzhou, but his registered store is in Hainan. Ma Kai added that compared with the complicated materials that ordinary companies need to submit, individual industrial and commercial households only need to spend tens of yuan a year to prepare an annual report, and the above-mentioned merchants also provide agency services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A small program called &quot;Praise&quot; provides praise services for younger brother accounts. Unlike WeChat&#39;s direct rewards, third-party programs reward through jump links, which can avoid the risk of having your account frozen after being reported by users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comment area of ​​this mini program, there are still a lot of messages from sisters, &quot;Hello, dear baby brother! Good afternoon! Sister gives you some love for the author. How is your brother? I miss you so much. You, my sister has had trouble at home these days, so she hasn’t sent many messages to my brother. I hope my brother will understand and forgive my sister. My sister really likes you and loves you. She loves you and will never leave you and will always be with you.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 14, &quot;Praise&quot; issued an announcement stating that the platform had no way of knowing whether users who received praise were committing fraud, and revealed that from October 9 to November 4, 2023, A user who was complained received a total of more than 250,000 yuan in praise. &lt;/span>;The amount of money defrauded can be staggering. In the early days, these accounts used WeChat to reward, and the number of rewards was publicly visible. Ma Kai observed that a Ruidongdi subscription account team from Fujian received at least 400 rewards a day at its peak, and it was estimated that the daily income could be as high as two or three dollars. Ten thousand yuan; another subscription account from Hebei has about 7,000 to 8,000 reads per day. The official account has not many fans. Before being blocked, it had accumulated more than 3,000 likes. According to his understanding, this type of account first started in Fujian and spread to Guangdong, Jiangxi, Chongqing and other places, and lasted for about a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After these public accounts were banned by WeChat, they had to start looking for new methods. Their corporate WeChat account is still functioning. The original link to the official account was changed to a link to the &quot;Tencent Content Creation Platform&quot;. The payment code can still be placed on the content interface. Moreover, if users have previously added their business WeChat accounts, they will still receive push messages every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Ma Kai has been reporting on these corporate WeChat accounts, but with poor results. He dug up the historical records and said, “What you see is just the chatting and tipping on the surface. It is conceivable whether there are chats and transfers behind the scenes, right?” He believes that Enterprise WeChat is the real concentration of traffic. “Enterprises WeChat is originally a marketing tool and can add more people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Y told Southern Weekend reporters that two-thirds of the accounts on the market are no longer there. He no longer has a similar account and plans to prepare live broadcasts to bring goods out of town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/GLkoxSPeP2ndaFoKiXmqdVIyfZ8gE8uzlQcsfO82.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;2078&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/GLkoxSPeP2ndaFoKiXmqdVIyfZ8gE8uzlQcsfO82.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 1, the public account &quot;Dongyinxianban&quot; published a new article, continuing the false younger brother persona and telling stories in the video to induce rewards. As of 10 o&#39;clock that night, 38 people had tipped. The author of this article has posted similar content many times before, but has deleted it and canceled his account. Now it appears in a new public account. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;She needs love, she is truly not alone&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Xiao Lin runs an emotional public account for young people. Recently, she often receives some strange messages in the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to changes in the push mechanism of WeChat public accounts, the platform will recommend content that may be of interest to non-followers. As a result, her public account was accidentally seen by some middle-aged and elderly people and became a favorite of some people. Emotional tree hole. Most of their messages are scattered and unclear, and they seem to express their feelings to someone:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do you know? I have forgiven you a long time ago, and I am waiting for your sincerity to pick me up, you know?&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have been away from me for more than three years. It is normal to get married, start a family and start a business, but you are still in my heart.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman from the Northeast has been sending voice messages almost every day since September. At first it was a long string of scoldings, but later her tone became gentle. She seems to have fallen in love with a man and regarded his official account as his. Sometimes, she speaks quickly and in a crying tone, always starting with &quot;Dear baby&quot; and repeating: Why don&#39;t you come back? Why don&#39;t you reply to my message? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Lin did not dare to reply, for fear of breaking her confession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru only realized the delicate side of her heart from her grandma&#39;s love. My grandma lost her first husband more than 20 years ago and experienced two failed relationships. She followed her children to Beijing and barely attended school. She became literate through the Internet and likes to watch video accounts and public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Xueru grew up with his grandma. When his grandma first fell in love, she couldn’t type. She read a sentence and Dong Xueru typed: &quot;Dear husband, I miss you so much. I love you. When will you come back to see me?&quot; .&quot; Sometimes, my grandma didn&#39;t know how to express it in words, so Dong Xueru helped her write some templates - &quot;Dear, eat more and take care of your health&quot; and &quot;Dear, go to bed early&quot;, and grandma passed it on to the other party as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter how old a man or a woman is, they will be lonely, especially if they are single. As a relative, the care you can give him is only part of it. She needs love to truly not be alone.&quot; Dong Xueru said that grandma was avoiding them more and more, and was still obsessed with the conversation with the teacher Tie in her mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wenhan’s grandma is also addicted to short videos. In her description, her grandma was a simple and compassionate person who had been deceived many times in her eighty years of life and always believed those stories about poverty and misery. After my grandfather passed away five years ago, my grandma suddenly became free and her life revolved around her children. After moving to a big city, she lost contact with her friends and seldom socialized. Soon, she started to watch short videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She often sees her grandma falling asleep while watching short videos, and then continues after waking up, muttering to herself in conjunction with the AI ​​dubbing in the short videos. The short video said, &quot;Can I call you mom?&quot; and grandma murmured, &quot;Of course, kid.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wenhan majored in gerontology when he was studying abroad. According to her observation, many elderly people abroad live in retirement communities and have their own social circles, but the elderly in China seem to need more emotion and sustenance. &quot;They need to be provided with some emotional value, that is, they are needed, or they still have charm.&quot; Wang Wenhan said. For a while, her grandma told her that she always dreamed that she was leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Research Report on Emotional Care for the Elderly and the Use Value of Short Videos&quot;, Peng Huamao, a professor at the Department of Psychology at Beijing Normal University, conducted a survey of 2,000 elderly people across the country. The research team found that the elderly who chase Internet celebrities on the Internet are still &quot;too lonely and lack attention&quot; in their offline lives. During the survey, Peng Huamao asked the elderly people interviewed whether they still need love. The vast majority of the answers are need, mostly the love of children, and of course the love of the opposite sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Huamao told Southern Weekend reporters that when the elderly and short videos are mentioned on the Internet, they are always about addiction, earthiness, etc., and most of them have negative impressions. An old man who travels thousands of miles to chase celebrities or give rewards in a live broadcast room will always be considered to be cheated. &quot;The advanced psychological needs of the elderly are always ignored, such as the need for love, respect, and self-realization.&quot; One of the results of the survey is that the vast majority of elderly people have the ability to control and understand that this compensation is not actually true satisfaction, but a diversion of attention or the passing of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Dong Xueru’s online post, a user left a message saying that her aunt encountered the same situation and fell into a brother-like public account and secretly rewarded her. After her wife discovered something was wrong with the money, she confiscated her mobile phone and called her relatives to persuade her. My aunt, who had been in charge of housework all her life, became almost crazy and cried loudly, not believing that this was a scam. The policeman called by her family was determined by her to be an actor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final solution was that the family registered a fake WeChat account for the younger brother and chatted with the aunt in a way that &quot;destroyed the personality&quot;. The younger brother ceased to be perfect and decent and became rude, shattering his aunt&#39;s fantasy. Finally, my aunt blocked this younger brother’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Dong Xueru, Ma Kai, Xiao Lin, Wang Wenhan are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子编排“老头强奸孙女致怀孕”被拘留：可比照“老夫少妻”造谣案入刑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Let me tell you a story. There was an old man who took care of a granddaughter and a granddaughter at home, and ruined both children. The older one was only twelve years old and was three months pregnant, and was finally discovered by the teacher.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 27, a video was circulated on the Douyin platform, attracting public attention. On November 29, Chongqing Hechuan Police issued a notice: This video is a rumor. Liu (female, 46 years old), a criminal, posted unverified rumors through Douyin in order to earn gold coins on the Douyin platform. Faced with doubts from netizens about the unverified rumors. To refute the rumors, it was clarified that as of the time the information was deleted, it had been commented and shared nearly 700 times by netizens, causing adverse effects. At present, the police have imposed administrative penalties on the woman involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the police report, the woman involved should have committed an act that constituted &quot;publicly insulting others or fabricating facts to slander others&quot; in paragraph 2 of Article 42 of the &quot;Public Security Administration Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. She accepted the &quot; shall be detained for not more than five days or fined not more than five hundred yuan.&quot; Judging from the behavior of the woman involved, her alleged illegal and criminal behavior may not be just &quot;fabricating facts to slander others&quot;, and there is still room for continued discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the timeline of this case, the video uploaded by the woman involved can be said to be completely unrelated to pictures and texts. It only excerpted the video picture of the victim old man and his granddaughter, and then started to show the video to the wall. The fiction &quot;played its best&quot; and weaved an &quot;incest tragedy&quot;. Its frivolous tone, bad nature, and clumsy techniques all made netizens look at it. When netizens questioned it, the woman involved did not delete it immediately, nor did she clarify or apologize. As a result, the video continued to spread. At the time of the incident, it had accumulated 700 comments and shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not yet clear what channel or method the woman involved used to obtain the information of the old man and his granddaughter, but this first violated the personality rights of the victim’s grandparents and was a blatant violation. Their right to image and reputation. The particularity of this case is that the woman in question misappropriated the victim’s information, in addition to seeking the benefits of the Douyin platform gold coins. From the perspective of the result, it was a brutal trampling on the personal reputation of the victim’s grandparents and grandchildren. The severity of the crime was far beyond a simple &quot;Making pornographic rumors&quot; or &quot;slandering&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Douyin platform can be regarded as a public place. If the woman in question makes such a specific and &quot;below the lower limit&quot; accusation in a public place, she has an obligation to ensure the authenticity of the accusation and at the same time defend her remarks. Responsible. Therefore, in addition to violating the Public Security Administration Punishment Law, the woman involved is also suspected of other illegal and criminal acts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Article 1 of the &quot;Interpretations of Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in the Handling of Criminal Cases Using Information Networks to Commit Defamation&quot; by the two top governments, &quot;tampering with the original information content involving others on the information network into facts that damage the reputation of others&quot; , disseminate on information networks, or organize or instigate people to disseminate on information networks&quot; shall be deemed as &quot;fabricating facts to slander others&quot; as stipulated in Article 246, paragraph 1, of the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior of the woman involved in this case has obviously met this requirement, and the video comments she posted on Douyin have been shared 700 times, which is in line with Article 2 of the judicial interpretations of the two Supreme Courts that &quot;the number of reposts reaches More than 500 times&quot; standard for &quot;serious circumstances&quot;. According to Article 246 of the Criminal Law, the woman involved is guilty of defamation and the circumstances are serious, and she should be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention, public surveillance, or deprivation of political rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, compared with similar previous cases, the woman involved may deserve criminal punishment for her illegal and criminal behavior, rather than just administrative punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case of &quot;a woman was rumored to be an old husband and a young wife&quot; in 2021, the man involved, Wu Moumou, took a photo of the woman with her grandfather&#39;s grandparents and rumored to be an &quot;old husband and a young wife&quot;, and also issued a sensational content of rumors. After the incident, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of the First District of Dongguan City prosecuted him for defamation. In September 2023, the court ruled that Wu Moumou fabricated facts to slander others on the information network. The circumstances were serious and seriously endangered social order. Based on the circumstances of the defendant&#39;s crime and his confession and punishment, the defendant Wu Moumou was sentenced to one year in prison for defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Moumou’s behavior constituted the crime of defamation. The court adopted the relevant definitions in the judicial interpretations of the two Supreme Courts and determined that Wu Moumou had tampered with “original information content involving others on the Internet to damage the reputation of others.” Facts, disseminated on information networks”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, even if &quot;old husband and young wife&quot; is true, it does not violate any law in the marriage and family section of the &quot;Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, and it does not even touch upon the so-called moral and ethical issues. This kind of news can at most arouse the curiosity and onlookers of netizens. In comparison, the rumor-mongering behavior of the woman involved in this case is even more outrageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that if the accusation of the woman involved is true, then such a despicable &quot;grandfather-grandson incest&quot; has violated the criminal law and constitutes the crime of rape, and it meets the requirements of &quot;under the age of fourteen, a severe punishment&quot; &quot;The standard is also in line with the standard in the &quot;Opinions on Punishing the Crime of Sexual Assault on Minors According to the Law&quot; that &quot;persons who have a common family relationship with minors must be severely punished in accordance with the law.&quot; The &quot;old man&quot; involved may face severe punishments of more than ten years in prison, life imprisonment or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the woman involved made such a serious public false accusation, she was suspected of false accusation and frame-up in addition to defamation. Article 243 of the Criminal Law also stipulates that fabricating facts to frame others with the intention of subjecting others to criminal prosecution constitutes the crime of false accusation and frame-up. If the circumstances are serious, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or surveillance; if serious consequences are caused, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years and not more than ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, if the life of the victim’s grandfather and grandson is greatly affected and causes bad consequences, the woman involved should bear greater responsibility. Therefore, this case is not in compliance with the principle of proportionality. The woman involved is suspected of a criminal offense. The public authorities can continue to pursue her criminal responsibility, require her to apologize, eliminate the impact, and provide civil compensation. The three victims of the crime will also be given justice to their grandfather and grandson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[婚礼上听“常识课”：“互免模式”下，老家变时尚了丨回乡偶书]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261680]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My old friend, Brother Chunqiu, invited me back to my hometown for a wedding banquet on WeChat. His son-in-law is getting married and he will be back from abroad at the end of the month. wedding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Putting down the phone, I suddenly remembered how young and shy Brother Chunqiu was when he got married, and how busy Brother Chunqiu was when I was organizing the wedding banquet. At that time, he was still a newspaper reporter and made a cameo appearance in wedding photography. In the blink of an eye, our children also entered the palace of love one after another, and they &quot;swore&quot; like a couple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about the routine of the wedding dinner in my hometown, it’s actually a bit boring: first, it’s late and the endless waiting; second, it’s noisy and the endless routine. However, when I went back several times recently, I found that my hometown was also changing, becoming younger and more fashionable. When there is a happy event in the family, it is now fashionable not to be a part of it or give red envelopes. The &quot;mutual exemption model&quot; allows ordinary people to &quot;joy&quot; easily and &quot;love&quot; without worries, and also makes the hometown one of the first batch to be selected as an experimental area for national marriage custom reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wedding of Chunqiu Brother and Young Master was simple and cheerful. The subtleties are eye-catching and full of surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight was the thank you session for the parents of the new couple. Dear Brother Chunqiu, hold your breath in Mandarin and write the first paragraph &quot;thank you&quot;, the second paragraph &quot;gratitude&quot;, and the third paragraph are two sentences of &quot;remarks&quot;, specially given to your son and daughter-in-law: In a sea of ​​more than one billion people, you meet and get to know each other. Meet and fall in love. I hope you will cherish the fate of thousands of miles and thousands of years, and respect, understand and help each other. As parents of newlyweds, I would also like to remind you: First, always be kind and help those in need around you in a timely manner; second, always be grateful and never forget to care about those who help us... The true marriage between a Jiangsu boy and a Hunan girl is For the love of &quot;rivers and lakes&quot;, I look forward to you riding the wind and waves and being proud of the &quot;rivers and lakes&quot;! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These golden expressions are enough to be provocative. At the wedding scene, the parents of the newlyweds simultaneously hung up the red couplets of &quot;Always Be Kind&quot; and &quot;Always Be Grateful&quot;. The eight big characters attracted the attention of the entire audience. , the banner of &quot;Swordsman Jiangsu and Hunan&quot; was unfolded, which pushed the atmosphere of the night to a new climax. In an instant, many people switched to &quot;hilarious mode.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most ceremonial part was the &quot;tribute moment&quot;, the high-profile appearance of the groom&#39;s 99-year-old grandmother. The old man came from out of town, more than 4 hours&#39; drive away, to wish the newlyweds a long and happy life. The bride and groom made a special trip to hand over red envelopes and shouted in the old man’s ears: Grandma, may you be healthy for a long time! Happy for a long time! ! This was the fourth time the old lady attended her grandson&#39;s wedding, but it was the first time she received a blessing red envelope from the couple. She smiled like a child. According to reports, the red envelope is a lucky number: 999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is interesting is the on-site blessing from Professor Zhu of Shanghai University Hospital: I am a cardiologist and have been dealing with the &quot;heart&quot; all my life. On this special day, I returned to my hometown and said a few words from my heart: First, in a small family, new people must be loyal to each other and care for each other. Entering the marriage hall today means the beginning of firewood, rice, oil, salt, pots and pans. In the future, small families will inevitably encounter small difficulties and setbacks. You must be patient! Second, in the workplace, you must be open-minded when it comes to professional matters, have perseverance in sticking to your post, and be enthusiastic about your colleagues! The third is to be kind and filial to your relatives, friends, parents, and elders in your hometown, and pay more attention to the details - your parents do not ask you to make much contribution, but there are overseas video calls every now and then, and they are sent to the family group every day. A smiling face is enough! As long as you have love, we can rest assured in our hometown! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wedding is the highlight moment for the newlyweds. The protagonists of the wedding are the groom and the bride, their growth background, love story, and future vision. However, the protagonists are not necessarily the highlights of the scene. The family or friends of the newcomers, those characters who appear in supporting roles, can sometimes surprise and win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This wedding is full of positive energy, without clichés, not preachy, and down to earth. The only bad thing was that people ended up forgetting a few dishes and a few glasses of wine. Some people say that marriage is a school that teaches people to tolerate, understand, and share. Then, the wedding may be the &quot;first lesson of school&quot;, a lesson in life, life, and respect for the elderly. At the end of the day, it’s all common sense lessons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a Jiangsu media person)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; Share what you see and hear the villages and hears. Submitting mailbox: nfzmreams@163.com) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿拉伯的劳伦斯：传奇、神话和现代中东诞生记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwoPm87.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;715&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwo Pm87. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Thomas Edward Lawrence&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in 1920, in a private house in Westminster Abbey, London, T.E. Lawrence was immersed in writing his war memoirs. After being expelled from the Paris Peace Conference a year ago, this famous World War I hero was struggling with persistent depression. Only writing could temporarily pull him out of the swamp of despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The silence was broken by a ringing sound. It was a call from Whitehall in London - the other party was Winston Churchill, who was to be the Colonial Secretary. He wanted to invite Lawrence to assist him in handling Middle Eastern affairs. This controversial figure who was reduced to a &quot;political pariah&quot; five years ago due to his defeat in the Middle East battlefield has made a comeback and is trying to figure out how to deal with the mess of the British Empire in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;World War I&quot; has ended, the Ottoman Empire has been dismembered, and peace has not come: In Palestine, conflicts between the Zionists supported by the British and the local Arabs quickly intensified, and eventually escalated to Bloody conflicts; even more serious was the outbreak of a full-scale anti-British uprising in Iraq, an oil-producing area controlled by the British, and tens of thousands of people died in bloodshed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The allies are not having a good time either - in the desert of Transjordan, Prince Abdullah from the Hashemite family has been ferociously attacking the French who control the Syrian region. A few months ago, the French had just used force to seize this territory from Faisal, another prince of the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 1919, the Paris Peace Conference, which had been wrangling for half a year, came to an end. The Middle East, divided among the victors, is filled with hatred, bloodshed and conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite Lawrence&#39;s rejection, Churchill had no intention of giving up. This extraordinary man, who would go on to become one of the most important statesmen of the 20th century, knew that Lawrence of Arabia was the key to unraveling this mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two unconventional &quot;political pariahs&quot; are about to work together to shape the history of the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1913, Lawrence (second from right) and British archaeologist Leonard Woolley participated in archaeological operations at the ancient Hittite city Carchemish in the Ottoman Empire. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Smart &quot;illegitimate son&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; He is an Irish nobleman and a mistress eloped. crystallization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In order to avoid social pressure, Lawrence&#39;s parents&#39; surnames were anonymous to avoid living in the countryside and frequently moved, and they almost did not communicate with the surrounding neighbors. It wasn&#39;t until the education and future of the five sons that he had moved to the lively Oxford County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the eyes of the teacher, the boy is very smart, quiet, likes books, but is keen on prank. He especially likes to play games that test his extreme survival endurance, such as not drinking water, eating, and sleeping, and he can always persist in fainting. The principal of Oxford Public School recalled: Lawrence and boys of the same age are very different. There are quite some ancient Greek -Gepai style, &quot;I don&#39;t care about the joy and pain of the flesh.&quot; , Especially obsessed with the Middle Ages Cavaliers literature, interested in military history and archeological. During the holiday, he would ride a bicycle to explore the monuments of England with his friends, and also went to the Ashmorin Museum in Oxford as an assistant. He was later admitted to the main history of Jesus College of Oxford University. During college, he rode 2400 miles to inspect the ancient castles and military relics in Europe, and went to the Mediterranean all the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In January 1909, in order to understand a academic case in the medieval military history, he went to Syria to investigate. Under the scorching sun, he set off from Berut, passed through the Lebanese mountains, and arrived in northern Palestine; returned to Berut three weeks later, and then went north to continue to be more difficult archeology. After returning, he wrote the thesis &quot;The Influence of the Crusades of the 12th Century on the European Military Architecture&quot; and won the highest first prize of Oxford. In addition, it is awarded a scholarship for graduate stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1910, the British Museum launched the archeological excavation of the Calkimish ancient city site in Turkey and Syria today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence served as the junior assistant, and soon became the person in charge of the excavation site and managed more than two hundred local workers. He did well. He usually used Arabic to chat with workers, visited and visited their family, and recorded their folklore, the structural relationship between the family and the tribes, and their political views. Workers also have a good opinion of this young European, because he really respects their customs and culture, and is willing to accept money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It can be said that at the time, there was no better understanding of Westerners in the Syrian region than Lawrence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Karkimish, Lawrence and a 13 -year -old Syrian teenager are inseparable and very close. This young man who was called Darhm in his memoir, the real name, Saishmad, dedicated the war memoir &quot;SA&quot; to &quot;SA&quot;. Dahom was smart and handsome, with two deep dimples on his face, and he laughed innocently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the curiosity of scholars, Lawrence has made real appreciation and respect for near -East culture in contact with local society. He began to reflect on the proud imperialist consciousness of Western&#39;s proud imperialism on the West. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a scholar who really penetrates into the hinterland of Syria, Lawrence has clearly seen the general trend of the Ottoman Empire collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, the Ottoman Empire, which ruled the Arabian Peninsula for more than four centuries and across Asia, Africa and Europe, had entered the dusk and was known as the &quot;European sick husband.&quot; With the rise of nationalism and the development of international trade around the world, more and more domestic and foreign challenges faced by Ottoman. In the outside, the strong European strengths are constantly eating its territory and sovereignty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eavznh9ps2iktoaaruyacubk02ldofh1.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;735&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eavznh9puk8ps2iktoaCubk02ldofh1.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259971&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In November 1917, the British Egypt expeditions broke through the Ottoman army&#39;s defense line and captured the Palestinian region; in December, the British entered Jerusalem &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; ( Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Inside the empire, the power to promote reform and demand modernization has always existed. In 1908, a group of young officers, known as the &quot;Young Turkish Party&quot;, launched a coup, forcing Hamid II to restore the Constitution of the Parliament. In 1913, the party&#39;s nationalist radicals in charge of power and established a centralized dictatorship system with the &quot;three oligarchs&quot; as the core. They adjusted the reform plan into the implementation of modernization, defending Islam and Pan -Turkicism in order to fight for the united empire&#39;s territory in the territory of the empire. Each group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in a huge empire with a multi -language multi -ethnic group and the society that constitutes abnormally complicated, it is impossible for any reform program to appease all groups: the secular efforts have greatly irritated the traditional Muslims with a large number of people. ; Advocating pan -Turkicism, and other ethnic groups of non -Turkish people, such as the Arabs and Armenians, are born with the heart ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this moment, young archaeologists are drunk. And love. When he was determined to invest and study the ruins of the ancient city in the next four or five years, the bad news came: the project funding of the British Museum has been exhausted, and the excavation work must be suspended until there are new funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But there is another opportunity to work: funded by a foundation, a special team of the Royal Workers in the UK wants to conduct an archeological adventure of the desert area in southern Palestine. Ask if they are interested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence and his companions readily accepted. &quot;Fang Mo&quot; in the south of Israel today, according to the Old Testament, it is the last place where the ancient Jews ran away from Egypt and the wild in the wilderness under the leadership of the prophet Moses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Smart as Lawrence, he soon guessed that the adventure operation under the name of the foundation was actually a secret military geographic exploration. At that time, the British troops occupied the buffer belt of the Suez Canal and the Sinai Peninsula, and the relationship with the Ottoman Empire was always nervous. By the outbreak of the &quot;World War I&quot;, because they were worried that once the Ottomans forth with Germany, they would attack the Egypt and seize the canal. The situation of the desert area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The British Captain Stuart Newkom was responsible for this operation. He has a good opinion of this Oxford scholar who does not care about enjoying, stunning endurance, and even being abused, and is particularly impressed by his quirk. In general, Lawrence is a very shy person, but once someone attempts to attempt He will become resolute and bold to obstruct or fool him. On the way to find a deserted adventure, because of the surveillance and obstruction of the Ottoman military police everywhere, Lawrence showed this kind of breakthrough ability with children&#39;s prank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the &quot;World War I&quot; broke out, he brought Lawrence into the British army&#39;s military intelligence agency in Cairo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 28, 1914, the Austro -Hungarian Empire Emperor Chu Dihinan and his wife were assassinated in Sarajewo, and the First World War broke out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; October, Lawrence, who was just 26 years old, was sent to the Geography Department of the General Staff of the UK as a map painter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Senior military and political officials in the empire, this arrogant young man is still sloppy, freely scattered, indifferent to various rules and regulations. In his eyes, these senior officials were all silly forks in the abdomen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because a general wanted to make a report with an identity report to himself, Lawrence was dramatically promoted as a big lieutenant. But what he longed for was to show his skills at the front line. Lawrence is less than 1.65 meters tall and lower than the British Army&#39;s lowest standard, so the only opportunity to go to the front line is where he needs his special talent -the Middle East battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 2, 1914, the Ottoman Empire eventually joined the Allies and officially participated in the war. On December 15, Lawrence came to Cairo with a French carboat and reported to the military intelligence unit led by Newkom. At this time, the hustle and bustle of Cairo was an important transit hub of the personnel and supplies in the &quot;World War I&quot;. Hundreds of thousands of British colonies from India, Australia and New Zealand opened from here to the European battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/of9gtmleihfgx1qvqgiyxmtijzqwhszCT3R.JPG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;632&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/of9gtmleihfgx1qvqgiyxmtijzqwhszct3r.jpg =&quot; 259969 &quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In 1918, Lawrence led in Drac and launched the most fierce attack on the Hanzhi Railway. The picture shows Lawrence view the destroyed train &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Million cracks of &quot;European sick husband&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;/h4>; P>; In the British intelligence agency in Cairo, one of Lawrence&#39;s work content is to write a report describing the topographic and cultural and ethnic composition of the Osman Empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The experience of deepening Syrian society for many years has allowed Lawrence to see the countless cracks inside this old empire -in the huge territory of the Turkish people&#39;s heyday in the past, there are a lot of The ethnic group of the war to the relationship; they were originally full of resentment with the rulers of Turkish, and the war made this hatred deeper. In this empire, the largest population is the Arabs who believe in Islam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1908, the modern and secular reforms promoted after the youth Turkish Party came to power, which angered Hussein Ibn Ali, a religious and political leader in controlling the Hanzhi region of the Arabian Peninsula. He is the leader of the famous Hashim family, the prophet Muhammad&#39;s direct descendants, and has been guarding the Macata Holy Land for generations. As the &quot;saint&quot;, Hussein is one of the most lofty religious leaders in the Islamic world and has a strong influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the Ottoman Empire joined the &quot;World War I&quot;, the relationship between the two sides became more deteriorating. Hussein, a religious leader launched the so -called &quot;jihad&quot; propaganda launched by the official, remained silent; the Ottoman Empire asked him to send troops to assists in the Suez Canal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, in February 1914 before the outbreak of &quot;World War I&quot;, Abdullah took the opportunity to visit Cairo to visit the British Egypt Governor Kirinner. Sexual question: If the Arabic uprising erupts in the Hanzhi area, how will Britain react. Kinsona carefully avoided it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the official participation in the Ottoman Empire in November 1914, Kicinsner, who became the British Minister of the British Army, immediately sent a secret electricity to Cairo, so that the old Sottoz faction and Abdullah secretly secretly Contact, to find out Hussein&#39;s true attitude. This time, Hussein recovered cautiously that he would maintain neutrality, but at the same time hinted that if the British provided external aid and ensured that he would not interfere with the internal affairs of Arabia, he might lead his followers to launch an uprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This makes Kicinsner very happy. He wrote to Hussein&#39;s letter- &quot;From today, we will be friends with noble Arabs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Knowing it After these secrets came to the letter, Lawrence felt like &quot;Shenqi&quot; -after Cairo, he has been studying the possibility of launching the Arab uprising in the Syrian region. The Middle East battlefield is relatively lacking from European roads and obtained resources. Therefore, Lawrence believes that the United Kingdom needs to adopt a unconventional war, that is, the use of the social, ethnic contradictions and divisions in the internal social, ethnic contradictions and divisions of the Ottoman Empire. Undested Turkey&#39;s rule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5tnegpf03MPRBRXWBRSHTN9q7q15L7J7ypg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;743&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5TNEGPF03MPRBUQRXWBRSHTN9q7q15L7J7YPZ.JPG&quot; data- &quot;>; 259973&quot;>; &lt;/>; p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; In 1919, the Fergal (front row) and Lawrence (second right of the second row) during the Paris time in Paris and &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;(visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The uprising of the heavy contract &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; From July 1915 to January 1916, Hussein and the British senior commissioner in Egypt Henry Mike Mahong (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; that is, &quot;McMahon Line&quot; deliner &lt;/span>;) secretly comes to bargain to bargain. Several Arab nationalist secrets in Syria also secretly contacted Hussein in secret, hoping to jointly launch the uprising to resist the Turks, providing support from the United Kingdom, and using him as a spiritual leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But what Hussein finally decided to fall to the United Kingdom was a rumor -at the time, it was rumored that Constantinople intentionally abolished him and let the leader of the Zaid family replaced. On May 6, 1916, Jemalpatha, one of the &quot;three oligarchs&quot; of Ottoman, executed 21 Arab nationalists in Damascus. Hussein sent his son Fasal to say love and was rejected and intimidated. This has made him more aggravated of the restlessness of future destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In these secret communication, the British assured Hussein: If he led the army to assist the British Middle East war, after the war, the British would assist him to establish a place between Egypt and Persia, but It does not include the Arab Empire in Kuwait, Aden and the Syrian coast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Mcma Hong also inserted an inconspicuous condition in the letter: these commitments enabled only when &quot;Britain can be freely decided, not endangering the interests of its allies France&quot;. Among them, part of Palestine&#39;s part of the part was not talked about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When France learned that Britain and Hussein were talking about secrets, they immediately proposed their rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In January 1916, a &quot;amateur politician&quot; from a nobleman, a &quot;amateur politician&quot; named Mark Sicks and the French diplomat Franvo George-Pipo reached a war in London Later the draft of the Middle East vision, which was later officially signed in Peter Geller in Russia, which is known as the &quot;Socker-Portrak Agreement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据这份秘密协定：独立的阿拉伯国家被大致限制在阿拉伯半岛的荒漠里，法国直接控制大叙利亚，英国则占领产油的整个伊拉克；另有两块飞地，侯The north of the Hanzhi kingdom ruled by Saiyin, all areas of the remaining inland are &quot;semi -independent areas&quot;, are indirectly controlled by Britain and France; Palestine is a &quot;international co -management area&quot; and will be jointly shared by Britain, France, and Russia. manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How is this series of &quot;oolong&quot; incidents become the factual facts step by step in the acquiescence, and historians are still arguing for this. In short, the British government&#39;s contradictory documents signed with the Arabs and French respectively will laid the roots of the turbulence of the Middle East in the future of the Middle East, so it will push Lawrence to the classical tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 5, 1915, in the Holy Land, Micatriga, Hussein Ibn Ali climbed into a tower in the palace, and fired a shot with a Turkish fortress in the city in the city. . On the same day, his two sons Ali and Ferobar took the lead in acting, and 1,500 Arabian knights fired on McDIC&#39;s pair. After that, Hussein&#39;s followers launched an attack in the Turkish base in Hanzhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hussein issued a declaration to Muslims around the world: publicly condemned the Turkish authorities to &quot;persecute and slaughter the Arab nationalists, deviate from Islamic spirit&quot;, and announced that the Arabian Empire was separated from the Ottoman Empire. He was self -proclaimed as the king of the Kingdom of Han. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The famous &quot;Arab uprising&quot; in the modern history of the Middle East broke out and officially opened on the stage with Lawrence as the main character. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Find the &quot;Rabbit&quot; who is looking for the prophet and holding the king &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;The hotness of the Arabian Peninsula is like a sharp sword with a sheath, which makes us open.&quot; October 16, 1916 In the morning light of the day, when Lawrence accompanied the British Eastern Culture Secretary to the important port Gada, who was controlled by the Hussein uprising, he recorded this moment in the diary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before embarrassed Han Zhi, he had designed a new direction for the Arabic uprising, and the positioning of the role of himself- &quot;Looking for the unknown master soul for the uprising, and measured him The ability to advance the uprising to the goal I envisioned. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Hussein launched the first shot, and after a month of bloody alley war, the insurgents and the Ottoman army entered the stalemate stage. Moreover, the prestigious righteousness of the Melizer&#39;s sacred guardian is not as expected -it aroused a wider ethnic uprising on the Arabian Peninsula and did not respond in Syria and other regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence believes that the core of the problem is the lack of a leader. Unlike Western political culture, the Arab uprising is not a clever politician, but a prophet, &quot;not intelligent, not judgment, not political wisdom, but can ignite the passion of the desert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When his chief and the leaders of the rebels discussed the details of the cooperation, Lawrence looked for the opportunity to carefully observe Hussein&#39;s four sons: the eldest son Ali, the second son Abdullah, the three sons Ferza Er and young son Zair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He first met the three princes except Fasal: Abdullah was happy, and he blessed early because he was greedy for enjoyment. Sad and exhausted, there is no obvious ambition, and it is easy to be affected by the people around him. As for Zael, he is only 20 years old. people. Lawrence concluded that they could not be the kind of &quot;armed prophets that wins in the revolution in history&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Until Lawrence rode a camel 100 miles, crossed the regions controlled by multiple hostile tribes, and saw Fergal, who was stationed in the desert oasis with another tribal soldier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I felt at the first glance when I saw him, this is the person I came to the Arabian Peninsula, the person who will bring the Arab uprising to bring a full glory.&quot; Ferobasal was thin and long, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, there was a one, and there was a one. The strange and quiet, the passion and the rhetoric when they speak, the iron -like determination revealed behind the words has deeply attracted Lawrence. This was what he couldn&#39;t find in the other three princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence was still walking around in his camp for a long time, chatting with soldiers with fluent Arabic. He found that the more than 6,000 people summoned by Fasal include almost all the tribes in the western Hanzhi. Although they just lost a battle, their morale rose and had unwavering confidence in victory. It was Fasal who united them and always encouraged them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The more he is firm, the more firm Fergar is the &quot;prophet&quot; he want The trip made Lawrence the first foreigner to observe the battlefield in the Arabian Peninsula. When returning to Yanbu and other ships back to Cairo, he wrote a report of 15,000 words in five days and made two important judgments: one is that Britain only sent a small number of troops to Hanzhi region; the other is that the real &quot;prophet&quot; of the leadership uprising is fee. Sal, not the British familiar Abdullah. He also pointed out that the only way to cooperate is that the British must accept the way of fighting the Arabs and adjust their strategy and expectations accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This report of Lawrence basically changed the British policy to the Arabian Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the huge bureaucracy of the British Empire, many smart ideas are buried every day. After writing a report in Cairo&#39;s office for nearly two years, Lawrence slowly found the rules of the game. He was very good at using the bureaucratic system and faction to achieve his own goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After returning from Han Zhi, under the dazzling operation of Lawrence, through memo, reporting, and reporting, intentionally guided, bypassing and even destroying &quot;obstacles&quot;. In the end It was adopted and obtained green lights from the senior management of military and political from Egypt to London. Soon, Cryon, director of the Arabian Arab Arabian Arabia, informed Lawrence: He would send him to the Arabian Peninsula to serve as a temporary liaison officer around Fasal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The superiors and colleagues were happily sent away this &quot;arrogant and self -sophisticated, stinky, and hairy rabbits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ev9bygqfq730yztxt16fkkgadylvQicw4kpj.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;704&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ev9shs7bygq730yztXt16FKKGADYLVQICW4KPG&quot; data-key = &quot;259970&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; In 1921, Churchill (in the front row) and Lawrence (fourth right of the second row) &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/ Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become the &quot;Son of Desert&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In December 1916, when Lawrence was the British liaison officer, he came to Fergar&#39;s camp again and was The suggestion was put on a pure white robe of the Ferga La. During the entire war, he lived with the soldiers of the Arab tribe as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Arab tribal camp, the typical day spent the day: Early morning, an Imam wake up the camp with prayer, and then the long breakfast time. Every morning, anyone can come to Fasal to sing unjust, petitions, and fixed disputes. During the day, most of his time he was eating, drinking tea, and chatting with staff and tribal leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence himself has always been known for his irritability and strictness, but he realized that these long -time and aimless chats are the way Arabs deal with war and peace. Fergaal united these loose tribes and clan around him with this as a adhesive. During the entire operation, he also acts as a mediation arbiter between the tribes, listening, suggestions, and coaxing if necessary, and often paid for the reconciliation of both parties in the interests of interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the uprising, almost all British military advisers who have been sent to Hanzhi are very scornful for the fighting power of the Arabs. Lawrence also agreed, but after fighting with them, he came to an important point: he could not measure the European war standards to measure the Arabs, and it was difficult to organize and train them into European combat forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are really good at guerrilla warfare, coupled with the geographical environment, the mobility is strong. In the war, when the force and weapons and weapons were obviously not as good as the enemy, the weak party should not be connected to the other person&#39;s positive short soldiers, but &quot;floating around like the air.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the first day of the uprising, whether it is Hussein and his followers, or British, they have taken the second Holy City McDIC in Islam as the main goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Danaor believes that the correct strategy is to abandon McDonaline where the heavy soldiers guard, so that the Ottoman army stays there almost infinitely, so that they can barely maintain the supply line. The rebels were captured. In the end, he convinced the insurgents to transfer the strategic focus to harassment and destruction of the area along the Hanzhi Railway. While forcing Tujun to send heavy soldiers to defend the railway, it has to bear continuous maintenance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Arab uprising, the new goals and new strategies set by Lawrence make the situation reverse, the blow has become effective, and the casualties have decreased significantly. During the &quot;World War I&quot;, the guerrilla warfare that the Arabic uprising continued to launch effectively delayed the operation of the Ottoman army and helped the cooperation country to eventually defeat the Ottoman Empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ru2VLCM0Z8CZJ9I6SEMMLQYNW01DMZSL.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;769&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ru2vlcm0z8czj9i6semmlqynw01dmzsl.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;259976&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Lawrence (left) and American traveler and journalist Lovil Thomas in Arabia &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become a legend -attack Avaspa &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The Aqaba Bay is located east of Sinai Peninsula and west of Arabia. It is a bay in the north of the Red Sea. The port of Yakha is at the end of its northern part. From the plan, it is an ideal assembly place for attacking southern Palestine from Egypt. Entering 60 miles east is the Hanyan Railway on the Arabian Peninsula on the Arabian Peninsula. In the future of the Middle East War, this is the strategic place of offensive and defensive offensive and defensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1914, Lawrence was also an archaeologist at the British Museum, who had an adventure at Aikepa Bay. From the port of Aqaba to the inland, there are steep mountains that are rising altitude, followed by inland deserts. The only passage from the port of Akaba to the inland is the canyon, where the Ottomans built a network system composed of bunkers and trenches along the line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Britain and France have their own abacus for how to deal with this obvious strategic position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of January 1917, with the cooperation of Lawrence&#39;s contact and the British army, Fasal led his tribal army to seize the important port Wosh in the middle of the Red Sea. The French representatives began to lobby Britain to attack and control Avas Caska, so that the British Egyptian Expeditionary Force launched the British Egyptian Army in the right wing. Another more secretive motivation is to suppress the Arab uprising with a momentum of the momentum in Hanzhi and command them to cooperate as needed. If they do not accept it, they threaten the support of weapons and gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence has always opposed Fasal&#39;s plan to attack Avas. He knew the abacus of the contract: if the Arabs were only cooperated with the British and French attacks, Aikepa would become their &quot;death trap&quot; and finally fell empty -handed. To this end, he did not hesitate to risk the &quot;crime of betrayal&quot; and disclosed the British -French secrets to Fergal in February 1917. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On the other hand, if the Arabs control the port of the northernmost point of the Red Sea themselves, once the uprising troops are fighting in the Syrian region north, the material supply line can be greatly shortened, from the original 300 -mile to 60 miles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 1917, the boss Cryon issued a secret order from Cairo to Lawrence: Do not let the Arabs appear in Aasha. He understood his subtext -Cright&#39;s letter to a general was more clear: given the importance of Avaspa to Egyptian defense, the British must firmly control the sea port city after the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April of that year, when Lawrence asked a dozen Turkish prisoners of war sent by the British army, Lawrence got a new information: the Aqaba garrison just changed, and the number of people rarely exceeded 100 people, and from Asia The road between Ma&#39;an Town, the Hanye Railway hub in the inland, has only 200 natives stationed in Ma&#39;an Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence quickly made a bold adventure decision -before the British and French army dyed Avha, the United Desert tribal forces convened an Arab armed forces, and then turned over the mountains and rolled the mountains. At the end of Ma&#39;an Town, the Port of Akhapa. Through the victory that the Arabs strived to minimize the influence of European strong forces in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is also Lawrence&#39;s bold and most famous military operation in &quot;World War I&quot;. He used his lightly described excuses to stuff other British officers around him and his boss far away from Cairo. &quot;So, no matter whether there is or not or not, go to his own way.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Lawrence and 45 Desert Warriors set off from Vosh, with gold coins worth 20,000 pounds and some re -guns, riding camels into the Hul Desert in the Northeast inland, and planned to go to the Hostert Tribe deep in the desert to recruit soldiers. And encouraged the Syrian tribe to go north and liberate Syria&#39;s front station for the uprising army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They stayed in the Waldisir Han Oasis who entered the Syrian area. More and more tribal representatives came to discuss with the insurgents and join the Arab independence cause. When Lawrence accepted a round of tribal feasts, his guilt was getting deeper and deeper. He knew that after being deceived -after winning, the contract country would inevitably betray the Arabs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under a extremely complicated painful mentality, he made a suicide adventure -go north to Syria alone, detour 400 miles in the enemy, and arrive in the outskirts of Lebanon and Damascus northward. Potential uprising allies, including tribal leaders and urban Arab nationalists. At that time, Damascus was located in the Joint Command of the Ottoman Army and the German Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a desert oasis, he saw the lofty prestige Emir (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; The nobility of the Arab world &lt;/span &lt;/span >;) Nuri Salad. When the old chief who was at the depths of the desert took out a bunch of copywriting copies of the document that contradicts each other and asked him exactly what the British promised, Lawrence had to recommend the closest choice date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The old chief was persuaded, and Lawrence was ashamed. &quot;I used lies to make a reputation for myself and become the leader of the fraud group.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence said he really woke up With the motivation to survive. &quot;I vowed to spare no effort until they brought the final victory to the Arabs, asking for respect for the Arabs, and negotiating a fair and reasonable solution. Only by protecting the troubled times in front of me in the future . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Swamp -like situation, Whenever Lawrence&#39;s most incredible courage, ingenuity and endurance are stimulated. The legendary battle during the &quot;World War I&quot; -attacking the battle of Avas Caska -it happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 18, 1917, Lawrence and the &quot;Legendary Desert Samurai&quot; Oda Abu Toy led the 500 camel cavalry from the Wadisir Han to march southwest. When they arrived in Bell, they found the footprint of the Ottoman army -the most important water well in the desert march was blown up, and the goal of the uprising army was Avaspa. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Lawrence commanded and led the Arabs to put on a god -level ecstasy array -as early as ten days ago, when he went north to Syria, he made a pavement and brought a local team to bomb. Destroy a small bridge on the Hanzhi Railway north of Damascus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 21, he led 100 soldiers to Amman on the railway 150 miles north, and quickly destroyed a railway culvert and then returned quickly. In the south of Syria, the insurgents launched a series of guerrilla warfare. This made the Turkish troops unable to find the law at all, and had to diversify their troops and follow them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A good news came: a team they sent a few days ago had just captured and destroyed the Turkish military base, Fuvila, and the road from the inland to Avasaka was basically basically. Open. When they hurriedly bypassed Ma&#39;an Town and rushed to Aikeha, there was news of bad news: On the morning of the same day, about 500 Ottoman soldiers rushed to Fvira to increase their troops. at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After thinking about it, Lawrence made a decision: must actively find and annihilate Ottoman reinforcements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the dawn on July 2, in a narrow road south of Fvira, they found an enemy who was sleeping. After cruel killing, they finally killed 300 people and 160 captives. . However, when the prisoners of war revealed that Ma Anzhen defended the emptiness, the tribal warriors from the bandits shouted, and wanted to take the opportunity to loot the rich transportation hub. Lawrence tried to persuade and promised to give them more compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When they moved west along the highway, they passed through the empty Turkish fortress and trenches -this proves that Lawrence has not been recognized by the boss. &quot; We will attack from the inland. In all their large defensive industries, there is no trenches and no posts are facing inland. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; After two days of stalemate, the troops led by Lawrence are almost not bloodless blades. The ground won the port of Yakha. The next day, he went to Egypt again, traveled through the camel through the 150 -mile desert to the Suez Canal, and informed the British to quickly add reinforcements and transport food and other supplies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On July 10, 1917, Lawrence, who had been &quot;missing&quot; for more than two months, wore a sloppy Arabic robe and suddenly appeared in the Cairo office of the British intelligence agency. Within a few days, his heroic deeds spread in the senior management of Egypt and London. As the Western Front war was unfavorable and the French army was changing, the victory of the British in the Middle East battlefield was particularly exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the general public, this is a legend of lonely heroes that can arouse endless romantic imagination -a young, blue -eyed British officer wearing a alien robe, riding a camel, and a single shot deep into the horse. In the hinterland of the enemy, secrets to meet and strive for potential conspirators, walking around in the middle of the people who want to be smoked, they may be sold and executed at any time. Then, the hero led the tribal warriors, who made a conspiracy and won a series of incredible victory with less victory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The British Egyptian commander Wengate proposed to the senior management of London: Lawrence awarded the highest military honor in Britain -Victoria Cross. Soon, he was promoted to colonel and nominated the third -class knight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This time, the unruly Lawrence accepted humblely -official recognition and honor can also become a powerful tool to affect high -level decision -making to achieve his in order to achieve his incense The vows from the desert: break through the &quot;red line&quot; set up by the French, burns the war of war to Syria, and help the British help the Arabs to liberate Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Standing in front of Edmond Allenbi, commander -in -chief of the new Egyptian Expeditionary Army, he depicts a exciting situation and future prospects. Immediately, Allen took a telegram filled with optimistic emotions to the Empire Chief of Staff William Robertson. In the end, the general coordination of the western line was promised to add 50,000 troops to the Middle East for the offensive of the Palestinian battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a key turning point in the Arabic uprising. It is Lawrence who leveraged the gear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under the requirements of the senior management, the &quot;popular fried chicken&quot; wrote a summary of the experience of the reference of overseas combat officers, which is for the Article 27 Suggestion. His most important experience is: abandoning the habit of the British and letting himself be completely immersed in the local environment. He must be familiar with &quot;local families, clan and tribes, friends and enemies, wells, hills and roads.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2006, the United States launched military operations on Iraq, and the US commander -in -chief David Peterreus ordered senior officers to read the &quot;27th suggestion&quot; to learn how to win Iraq from Lawrence. People&#39;s heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/29gobfcycabnkcwvtvyn6jtzdwoovshoucg6i.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;717&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/29gobfcycabnkcwvtvyn6jtzdwoovshoucg6i.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; &lt;259974&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Lawrence &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; Heroes &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; From October 1917, some people close to Lawrence found that he was in a quiet state of depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the British liaison officer who served as the Arabic uprising, he has always lived a highly intense life, like a great actor who has continued to perform &quot;thrilling performances&quot;. This is a huge consumption in intelligence, physical strength, and spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The main reason is the increasingly upgraded killing. In &quot;Wisdom Seven Pillars&quot;, he recorded a person for the first time, and then he fell ill. At first, he led the Arabs to fight guerrilla warfare to avoid killing innocent. During an ambush, they grabbed a shepherd boy who hit them. Lawrence tied him to the tree to prevent him from giving a ventilation to the Turkish army. Before the battle was ended, he released him. As the war became more and more nervous and cruel, he couldn&#39;t care much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wait until the end of the Battle of the Fvila Canyon in the Battle of Aqababa, he described the corpses of hundreds of Turkish soldiers who saw hundreds of clothes in the moonlight in the moonlight. Going up to the young, fair, and quiet, it is compassionate, &quot;So I put all of them neatly, one by one. I am also exhausted and eager to become one of these tranquil people, rather than returning to the valley high. The group of thugs who did not have peace, noisy, and painful pains for a while. Those people are still fighting for loot. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In the face of increasingly frequent killings, he seems to be more and more indifferent, more and more increasingly indifferent. The more indifferent. But in the letter to Oxford&#39;s close friends, he poured: &quot;I hope that the nightmare is over, I can wake up and live again. Killing, killing Turkey is really terrible.&quot; Times, if you can, you have to do it a few hundred times &quot;,&quot; I won&#39;t be able to support it in this game. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Boss Cryon has noticed this most powerful mental state He acknowledged that he was very worried about Lawrence&#39;s state. &quot;We will withdraw him as soon as possible, and don&#39;t continue to let him risk, but the time has not yet arrived, because he still needs him.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; November 1917 1917 In order to match the Egyptian expeditionary army&#39;s offensive against Palestine, Lawrence took a guard to investigate the situation near the Railway hub in Syria, and he was arrested by an Ottoman troops and was then detained to the local governor. Lawrence lied that he was a civilian of a mountain nation in Caucasus. This nation is known for its fair skin, light eyes, and is exempted from military service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, the most horrible scene in his entire memoir. Lawrence used the entire five -page to describe the details he suffered -he was first applied by the Governor of Turkey to the violence of the bloody flavor. Invasion; then beaten by four soldiers, and then repeatedly kicked by the torture officer; he was dragged back to the governor&#39;s room. Later he was thrown in a courtyard, and an Armenian came over to create and bandage him. This group of people went away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When it was light, Lawrence was awake and walked out of the town. With the help of a camel merchant, he found his companion and then told a &quot;happy story of escape the enemy&#39;s palm through bribery and strategies&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; People discovered: After the return of Dra, some things on Lawrence have changed, and he is more arrogant and indifferent. Since then, the bold man in the past organized a 50 -person elite guard for himself, always with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 10 months later, when he led the Arab soldier to return to this railway town again, he ordered a bloody massacre with the flame of revenge. More than 4,000 people were killed. Thahalska. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mental trauma left by the Drac to Lawrence is permanent- &quot;World War I&quot; ended, and after the end of the War, Mrs. Xiao Bernard, who was regarded as a confession priest, he poured into his inner quilt. After the sense of stains and strong self -aversion, after &quot;that thing&quot;, he vowed to &quot;abandon the decent life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7QS17Ixa1tkbmuvrygpq9jt1yskqDuux.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;747&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7qs17ixa1tkbmuvrygpq9jt1yskq -uux.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259972&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; 1962 movie&quot; Lawrence of Arabia &quot;stills &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Visual China/Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; The more entangled the more chaotic: Bellford Declaration, Weitzman and Lawrence &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In November 1917, the British Egypt Expeditionary Force successfully broke through the Osman army&#39;s defense line and captured the Palestinian region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this time, Lawrence has learned that a news that will make the future situation becomes more and more chaotic: British government cabinets have initially passed the support of Jewish Reinstateists to establish a &quot;national homeland&quot; in Palestine at the end of October. The Bellford Declaration &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Zionism&quot;, which is generally called &quot;Jewish stateism&quot; in my country, is a trend of Jewish nationalism. Jewish country, revive the Jewish nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; By the end of the 19th century, after a new round of anti -Jewie wave in Europe appeared in Europe, the Utah Austrian reporter Shi Orto Hitzel proposed the theory and program of modern Jewish stateism, and held in 1897 The first Zianist Congress created the World Zianist Organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 1916, the new British Prime Minister David David Laor George took office. Mum Witzman has a relationship. In addition to religious sympathy, this also has the consideration of realistic politics: After the &quot;World War I&quot; fell into a deadlocked, both the battle between the war aware of the widespread influence of the Jewish re -state and hoped to get their help; The territory of the Ottoman Empire could not promise too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 31, 1917, the British government cabinet passed supportive resolutions, followed by the Bellford Declaration: support the establishment of the Jewish &quot;nation&#39;s home&quot; in Palestinian, The condition is not to harm the rights of local ethnic groups, except for political rights. At that time, Palestine was still the territory of the Ottoman Empire, and Jews were just local ethnic minorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Bellford Declaration is an important document in the Middle East policy of the British Empire and an important document in the history of the founding of Israel. It contributed to the establishment of Palestine&#39;s hosting land, which later became the territory of Israel and Palestine, so declarations were also regarded as one of the reasons that caused Palestine&#39;s conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As early as 8 months ago, Lawrence published an analysis of the status quo of Syria in the Arab Public Press. He talked about the causes of the area that caused the region, including various contradictions between the tribe, nation, and religion, and any foreigner attempting to strengthen his will to Syria, and will face many challenges. Lawrence also pointed out that southern Palestine has a great hatred for the Jewish recovery movement, including Muslims and Christians. Recently, the situation has exacerbated this natural hatred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, this article was written two years ago, and Lawrence fully foreshadowed the countless turmoil, conflict and anxiety in the Middle East in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 1918, this article caused a special interest in the United States named William Yale in the Middle East. The young former American oil giant employee wanted to let his country participate in the Middle East affairs, so he went to visit Lawrence and wanted to know more about information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting, Lawrence could not be reserved, and even revealed the Military Observation goals of the Arabic uprising. He also predicted the consequences of the Bellford Declaration: &quot;If a Jewish country is established in Palestine, it can only be established through force and maintains through force through force.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; P>; Some biography author analyzes: Lawrence is interested in it. He wants to influence and guide the US government that has been joined by Yale and has recently adopted the policies that he recognized and has for Syria and Palestine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, President Wilson is nothing to do at the Paris in 1919. Until the Second World War, the United States completely replaced Britain to become the number one hegemon in the world, and at the same time took over its power in the Middle East, becoming the most solid ally after the founding of modern Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The announcement of the Bellford Declaration, together with the exposed &quot;Symbs-Pasco Agreement&quot;, ignited the fire of anger in the Arab world. In Cairo, the Muslims of the Egyptian Muslims have erupted for group protests. Exiles of Syria are also increasingly worried that a Jewish country will be imposed to Palestine in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; King Hussein, the largest opponent in the Arabian Peninsula, to launch a new round of public opinion attacks. Ibn Saudi Arabia comes from the Saudi family in the Inner region, representing the Islamic retro power -Wakahabi sect. He has always been ambitious to unify the Arabian Peninsula. He announced to the outside world that King Hussein was the puppet of Western Christianity. But in fact, he himself also relies on the support of the British colonial branch of the British Empire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The strong rebound of the Arab world has made Britain disturbed. They put pressure on Hussein and asked him to publicize public support. Clayton asked Lawrence to do persuasion from Fersell, although Lawrence had always opposed the agreement between the British government and Jews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 1918, accompanied by the British, the &quot;Jewish State Council&quot; led by Weitzman&#39;s team visited the Egyptian and Palestine regions. In Egypt, he launched a charming offensive to the British and exile Syrians, and repeatedly expressed the goodwill of Jewish recurrence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 4th of that year, Weitzman personally visited Fasal in Avaphaw. The atmosphere of the meeting was very harmonious, and Witzmann even brought Arabic headscarves; Festa avoided any substantial commitments and said that all the right to decide was with his father. Lawrence made excuses to avoid it, no matter how his boss calls for pressure. He has determined that the harmony of the British imposed will only make Fasal and Lao Hussein a greater opposition in the Arab world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Egypt 10 days later, he still saw Weitzman. The key to the Jewish political leader of the world: whether the Arab uprising leader can achieve an understanding is that the little British officer of the baby face is. After the master&#39;s tricks, he also gave birth to Xiang Xiang -Lawrence also admired Weitzman&#39;s Linglong wrist. On the one hand, he successfully eliminated the Arabs&#39; concerns, and inspired the Jewish fighting spirit with another set of words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个聪明人达成一个共识——如果犹太人希望能在巴勒斯坦建立一个“民族家园”，就必须先让英国人打赢这场战争，这也就意味着他们应该先支持阿拉伯人的起义。魏茨曼还主动提出一项颇具诱惑力的“支持”：让国际犹太复国主义运动组织来资助阿拉伯独立事业，包括资金、武器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏茨曼的魅力攻势取得了成效，他说服了大多数曾因《贝尔福宣言》而对巴勒斯坦未来感到担忧的英国官员，让他们相信：在巴勒斯坦，犹太社区可以和人口占多数的阿拉伯人在政治上和经济上共同生活、和谐相处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让上司们高兴的是，劳伦斯对犹太复国主义运动似乎不再那么抵触。但他也没有这么天真。在一份秘密报告中，他犀利地指出了这位犹太领袖的真实愿景——“50年之后犹太人将完全控制巴勒斯坦，而当前的目标是犹太人在英国幌子之下控制巴勒斯坦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1930年代，希特勒在德国上台后，纳粹党徒对犹太人进行惨绝人寰的种族大屠杀，摧毁了欧洲多数犹太族群，犹太复国主义运动因此高涨，于1948年达到顶峰。当年5月14日，现代以色列正式建国，魏茨曼为首任总统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一切比劳伦斯预见的还早了20年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;徒劳的最后一搏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年7月，劳伦斯开始策划耽搁许久的阿拉伯起义军北上叙利亚作战。随着事态发展，他越发清楚一个道理：只有在阿拉伯人自己解放的地区，他们的独立才能得到保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在劳伦斯万般促成之下，安曼和约旦河以西聚集起一支由阿拉伯部族武装、阿拉伯北方军士兵、英法顾问和专门的炮兵、装甲车单位组成的混合部队，人数为几Thousands of people.一同到场的，还有重要的起义领袖：费萨尔、奥达，以及沙拉昂在内的主要部落酋长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大战前夕，传来一个令人心碎的噩耗——劳伦斯在卡尔基米什时期的伙伴、爱人达霍姆，那个有着灿烂笑容的叙利亚少年死于一场肆虐于叙利亚北部的伤寒疫情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《智慧七柱》的扉页上，他写下一首献给达霍姆的情诗：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我爱你，故我将这千军万马掬于手中/在繁星灿烂的天空里写下我的心愿，去为你赢来自由…/当我长驱直入，你的眼睛将因此熠熠生辉…/你的微笑令其（死神）妒从悲起，抛下我，将你掳走，囚入他死寂的幽冥。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对劳伦斯而言，对达霍姆的爱，是他为阿拉伯人赢得自由和独立的最初动力。当梦想即将实现，爱人已逝，一种巨大的痛苦和虚空感把他压倒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争还在继续。 1918年9月，劳伦斯从英军司令部得到命令：让阿拉伯人彻底切断德拉以南的铁路线，但不可以北上冲向大马士革，以配合英军在约旦河西岸的北上行动。他们也转达对费萨尔的暗示：如果阿拉伯人在这个关键时候保持忠诚，将会得到很好的补偿，甚至将会允许他在大马士革建立一个政府。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得到政府的口头保证后，劳伦斯在德拉一带领导、发动了对汉志铁路最凶猛的袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月27日，在德拉附近那个给劳伦斯留下过严重创伤的名叫塔法斯的村镇，他和阿拉伯部队看到了一支撤退下来的同盟国军团留下的暴行：到处是残缺不全的尸体，姑娘和妇女们则裸露着带血污的身体，显然是被奸杀；在一堵矮墙上，倒着一具被刺刀穿透的裸身孕妇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯随后下令：不接受任何俘虏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;屠杀进行了一整夜，延续到第二天，共有四千多名被俘的同盟国士兵死于杀戮，是为“一战”中著名的“塔法斯屠杀”。次日清晨，劳伦斯进入德拉镇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位英军将领率部稍晚赶到这里，他目睹的是肮脏、野蛮和残忍，阿拉伯战士如何折磨、打劫医护列车上痛苦呻吟着的土耳其病员，“任何一个普通的文明人都无法忍受这样的惨景”。当他向劳伦斯控诉时，劳伦斯平静温和地告诉他：这就是阿拉伯人的“战争观念”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过德拉之战，奥斯曼军队已经全线崩溃。艾伦比将军给费萨尔发来热情洋溢的贺信说：“我向殿下表达我的祝愿，以及我对于您部队伟大成就的诚挚祝贺……多亏了我们的共同努力，现在土军正全线溃退。”他随后下令：把首先攻入大马士革的荣誉留给费萨尔的军队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年10月3日，在大马士革维多利亚饭店，英军总司令艾伦比和费萨尔会面了。劳伦斯充当翻译。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦比将军宣布：阿拉伯人作为参战国的地位，得到协约国承认；在叙利亚独立问题上，费萨尔没有选择，法国将成为保护叙利亚的“宗主国”；费萨尔作为侯赛因国王的代表，“将拥有叙利亚的管辖权”，但是“在法国的指导和财政支持下”，且他的管辖权“仅限于叙利亚内地”，不包括巴勒斯坦和黎巴嫩；法国将给费萨尔配一名联络官，他将与劳伦斯一同工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯和费萨尔惊呆了。费萨尔一开始激烈反对，但在艾伦比的施压下，最终只得屈从。在疲惫和失望中，劳伦斯转而向将军告假。将军最终同意了。次日，他离开了大马士革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;谈判桌上的溃败&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年12月，巴黎和会召开之前，英国首相劳合·乔治与法国总理乔治·克里孟梭用了五分钟就中东愿景达成一致意见：英国人控制美索不达米亚和巴勒斯坦；法国人则有权处置叙利亚。除了《赛克斯-皮科协定》的基本结构被确定外，他们还大大超越了它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴黎和会上，身着阿拉伯长袍的劳伦斯担任费萨尔的顾问，为阿拉伯独立事业继续奔走，以翻译身份参与演讲和谈判，组织新闻发布会以及引导报纸舆论。这给同在会场的著名历史学家阿诺德·J·汤因比留下难以磨灭的印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，恼怒万分的克里孟梭去英国代表团那里告了劳伦斯一状，并把这个年轻人叫来当面训斥。有“猛虎”绰号的法国总理劈头盖脸地问：“劳伦斯上校，你知道自从十字军东征以来，法国在叙利亚就有利益吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯回答：“是的。我知道。但是叙利亚人打败了十字军，我们永远不会忘了这一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克里孟梭被驳得哑口无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个饱受折磨的灵魂。我觉得劳伦斯在巴黎时已经意识到，尽管他在阿拉伯事业上取得了很多成功，但仍没有赢得胜利。”汤因比写道. “这让劳伦斯很苦恼，但痛苦并没有消磨掉他的幽默感，他有点伟大，还有点调皮。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英法的勾兑，摧毁了劳伦斯发下誓言为之奋斗的理想——阿拉伯人的民族独立。而对大英帝国的大人物们，“英雄劳伦斯”已经成为一个麻烦。在一份备忘录上，他们称其为“有害影响”，“很大程度上是我们与法国在叙利亚问题上麻烦的根源”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯最终被剥夺了参加巴黎和会的资格，同时被禁止在会议上协助费萨尔。他输掉了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，他仍做出一个堪称了不起的努力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年12月巴黎和会前夕，在他促成下，作为阿拉伯世界代表的费萨尔和犹太复国主义运动领袖魏茨曼拟定一份联合声明，宣布双方的合作意愿.其中第四条为：“应采取一切必要措施，鼓励和促进犹太人向巴勒斯坦大规模移民”，然后是一个关键性条件句——该协定“仅在叙利亚区独立的情形下有效；如果不满足这个条件，就完全无效。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，费萨尔还友好地谈到阿拉伯人和犹太人之间的“种族亲缘关系和古老纽带”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴勒斯坦地区，水火不容的阿拉伯人和犹太复国主义者也曾携手起来想建立一个阿拉伯-犹太人的联合国家。然而，劳伦斯的努力真有现实可能性吗？ ——如果他在1918年成功了，一个独立的泛阿拉伯国家会因此诞生吗？如果历史如费萨尔和魏茨曼之间协议的那样发生了，阿以/巴以会彼此和谐地相处吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为和劳伦斯相隔一个世纪的后人，我很难乐观——纵观中东现代史，每回出现和解的曙光，都会有极端势力发起针对性的暗杀、破坏行动。在遇害者名单上，有侯赛因次子、约旦首任国王阿卜杜拉，埃及总统萨达特，推动“以土地换和平”的以色列总理拉宾……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现代中东的诞生——划定疆域、拥立国王之人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1919年秋的巴黎和会上，失去劳伦斯帮助后，费萨尔不得不接受法国人给出的条件。等回到大马士革，他发现自己被谴责为向欧洲帝国主义出卖祖国的叛徒。他转而利用民众的愤怒，于1920年撕毁了与法国人的协议，发动一场宫廷政变，自立为大叙利亚国王。同年4月，叙利亚被托管给法国。 7月，法国在麦塞隆战役中获胜，费萨尔流亡英国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，历史走向了另一条轨迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;控制了叙利亚地区的法国也没有好日子过——阿卜杜拉从外约旦对他们发动持续、凶狠的进攻。让英国人头痛的则更多：在巴勒斯坦地区，巴勒斯坦人和犹太定居者之间的冲突不断升级；在美索不达米亚，反英起义揭竿而起，到处都是流血和对抗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年，前海军大臣温斯顿·丘吉尔复出，后在劳合·乔治内阁转任殖民大臣。他向被打入冷宫的劳伦斯发出邀约，请他担任中东事务部负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;心灰意冷的劳伦斯推说自己忙于写回忆录，对政治再无过问的兴趣。丘吉尔于是再三保证：在即将召开的开罗会议上，授予他几乎完全自由的权力，以帮助英国重新塑造中东棋盘上属于英国的那一部分。劳伦斯答应了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他对一位传记作者透露：1921年3月的开罗会议只是走了一个过场，他和丘吉尔在会前“不仅确定了会议将审议哪些问题，还确定了将会达成何种决议”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据决议，英国将它所控制的两块前奥斯曼帝国领土交给哈希姆家族。双方同意：费萨尔王子成为美索不达米亚新国家国王，即伊拉克王国；他的兄长阿卜杜拉王子则统治约旦河以东、由部分巴勒斯坦组成的新国家，即今天的约旦王国. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这基于劳伦斯一直为之奋斗的两个想法：首先，阿拉伯人必须获得对自己土地的控制权。其次，被赋予这种权力的阿拉伯人，是起义领袖哈希姆家族成员：侯赛因国王和他的儿子们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯的努力，为中东地区带来一段时间和平，也部分兑现了他对阿拉伯人在大起义时的承诺。一般认为：在1921年的开罗会议上，劳伦斯的作用大过了丘吉尔——最终，他真的成为了在中东地区划定疆域、拥立君王的那个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在安纳托利亚地区，前奥斯曼将领穆斯塔法·凯末尔带领土耳其民族主义者，把所有企图瓜分者打得落花流水。 1923年，他和协约国签订条约，确定了现代土耳其的疆域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南方，汉志国王侯赛因拒绝接受中东的现实政治，即使劳伦斯也无力说服。他的顽固和反复无常，最终让英国政府感到厌烦。老对头伊本·沙特利用了这一矛盾，于1924年带领瓦哈比战士逼近麦加。在众叛亲离之下，侯赛因避难塞浦路斯，后到新约旦首都安曼和次子阿卜杜拉团聚。 1931年6月，侯赛因去世，安葬于耶路撒冷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赢家伊本·沙特吞并汉志后，建立沙特阿拉伯王国。 1927年，英国人宣布承认其独立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过短暂的和平后，新的动荡又开始了。 1946年，法国人最终被迫放弃大叙利亚地区，但又从中分割出一个新国家——黎巴嫩。 1958年，伊拉克民族主义者发动军事政变，推翻了亲英政权，费萨尔独子费萨尔二世被处决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年代，西方殖民主义时代落下了帷幕。因为拥有占全世界六成的石油资源，中东如同被咒诅一般，继续成为地缘政治中最不安宁的角落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“当死神追上了我”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1921年，当劳伦斯在为丘吉尔奔走效力时，他给一位朋友写信说：“阿拉伯人就像是我翻过的一页，续集是我很讨厌的东西”。一战后，他一直患有严重的创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）,不断受到噩梦惊扰，多次陷于严重的抑郁，甚至萌生过自杀的念头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年起，劳伦斯根据笔记和回忆，重写自传，完成战争回忆录《智慧七柱》。他用手摇印刷机印了8本，分赠好友。后应公众的强烈要求，他做出妥协，在1926年出版了该书的删节版，同时又发行了大众版《沙漠中的起义》，后者取得了市场成功。劳伦斯把版税全部捐给慈善组织，并拒绝有生之年再版《智慧七柱》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他再也无法回归到一个学者的往日生活。 1922年，结束了在英政府殖民部的任职后，他化名约翰·休姆·罗斯，以普通列兵的身份加入英国皇家空军，但很快就被新闻界所发现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他又改名为托马斯·爱德华·肖，继续在军队服役，逃避对他穷追不舍的报界和公众。在生命的最后十多年，他过着离群索居的生活，用各种借口推掉朋友们的邀请，即使是最亲近的朋友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成为伊拉克国王的费萨尔跟劳伦斯后来又见过两次，一次是1925年，面对曾经并肩作战的生死之交，劳伦斯无所适从，二人一度相顾无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1933年费萨尔访英时再次提出要见劳伦斯，劳伦斯态度消极，后来费萨尔不得不借助军方的命令，才得以见到“列兵肖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1935年5月13日，劳伦斯骑着摩托车，去博文顿军营发一份电报。回程途中，遭遇一起交通事故。在部队医院昏迷六天后，于5月19日清晨去世，时年46岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“二战”阴云逼近，正陷于“困惑岁月”的丘吉尔前来悼念，写下一段政治家才有真正共鸣的悼词：“在我眼中，他是我们时代最伟大的人物之一……我担心，不管我们多么需要，像他这样的人都永远不会再有了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考书目及资料：《智慧七柱》T·E·劳伦斯著；《阿拉伯的劳伦斯：战争、谎言、帝国愚行和现代中东的形成》斯科特·安德森著；《交游录》阿诺德·J·汤因比著；Clio数字化历史博物馆网站。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>