<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[江苏205国道将收费引质疑：公共福利易涨难降，能否推进有待观察丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260825]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a toll station was built on the Huai&#39;an section of 205 National Highway in Suqian, Jiangsu, and the news that vehicle tolls will be collected soon has aroused social concern. great concern and doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to China Jiangsu Net, on October 20, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved that after the Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is completed and meets the traffic conditions, it will be managed as a government loan repayment road and jointly operated by Suqian and Huaian. Charges have been set and the charging standards for various types of vehicles have been determined, ranging from 10 yuan to 50 yuan. Media reports indicate that the toll station has been built. This means that tolls may be activated on this section of the national highway at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New toll stations on national highways! Many people believe that this is contrary to the country&#39;s policy of gradually canceling ordinary highway toll stations in recent years. However, the Jiangsu Provincial Transportation Department stated that the toll collection of first-class highways for which the government repays loans complies with the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot;, roads constructed by the government using loans or paid funds raised from enterprises and individuals can collect tolls upon approval. The Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were built with government loans. According to the Jiangsu Transportation Department, this section still has nearly 1 billion yuan in debt to be repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the historical context of the Suhuai Toll Station on National Highway 205, we can find that the toll collection on this section is not a recent decision. In the early 2010s, the Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were successively renovated and expanded and upgraded to first-class highways. In 2014, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved in a document the establishment of a toll station at the junction of National Highway 205 Huai&#39;an and Suqian, and the two cities will jointly charge fees. In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Development and Reform Commission approved the feasibility report for the construction of the toll station. Today, the toll station is built and the provincial government issues documents approving the toll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the minds of many people, only expressways still charge tolls, and all other ordinary highway toll stations have been abolished. However, in fact, there are not only ordinary highway toll stations, but they have increased in the past two years. According to information released on the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Transportation, as of December 2022, there are still more than 10 national and provincial highway toll stations in Jiangsu Province. Also on National Highway 205, more than 90 kilometers north of Suhuai Toll Station, there is Xinyi Toll Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Toll Road Statistical Bulletin of the Ministry of Transport, at the end of 2021, there were 308 first-level highway main line toll stations and 115 second-level highway main line toll stations across the country. Compared with the end of the previous year, there were 308 second-level highway main line toll stations. The number of toll stations decreased by 7, but there were 8 more toll stations on first-class highways. The total mileage of tolled first-class highways was 17,600 kilometers, an increase of more than 200 kilometers over the previous year. Media reports show that since 2022, at least 7 new national highway toll stations have been added in various provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years, it has become a trend to cancel tolls on ordinary highways. The central government has repeatedly proposed reducing road transportation costs and reducing road and bridge tolls. As early as 2009, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Transport and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued a document calling for the gradual and orderly elimination of tolls on secondary roads for government loan repayment. The revised draft of the &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot; released in 2018 stipulates that the construction of new first- and second-level toll roads and independent bridges and tunnels will be stopped, and only expressways can collect tolls. However, this revision has not yet been completed. In 2020, the General Office of the State Council forwarded the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Further Reducing Logistics Costs&quot; from the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Transport, once again requesting to ensure that the overall burden of truck tolls is not increased. Under these policies, a large number of toll plazas have been eliminated across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, although Jiangsu’s new 205 National Highway Suhuai Toll Station collects fees, it is not impossible to rely on it. Although the project was established based on loans for road construction and toll repayment at the beginning of the reconstruction and expansion, the funds mainly came from banks. Loans, and there are still huge loans that have not been repaid, but this is now and then. In the early 2010s, the construction and reconstruction of first- and second-level toll roads was still allowed, but after a few years the policy has changed. Except for expressways, the central government has discouraged and even explicitly proposed to stop the construction of first- and second-level toll roads, and many places have also canceled them. A large number of toll stations on primary and secondary roads have been installed. Especially in the past year or two, due to the impact of the epidemic, the economy is struggling to recover. Under such circumstances, adding new toll stations and increasing public transportation costs will of course be questioned by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no explicit regulation, &quot;national highways, provincial highways and other ordinary highways should be free of charge&quot; has become &quot;common sense&quot; in the public mind, just like highways are free on holidays. Once this kind of psychological expectation is formed, if you want to reverse it, you will certainly be questioned. It is easy to bring welfare from scratch, but it is difficult to bring it from existence to nothing. It is easy to go from paid to free, but difficult to go from free to paid. If the previously charged service is changed to free, the public will think they have benefited. But conversely, if it was free before and now it has to be charged, everyone will feel that their interests have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is true not only in public policy, but also in business. Since the birth of the Internet, various services have been almost free for ordinary users. Netizens are accustomed to enjoying free services. Once charges start to be charged, they will of course feel very unhappy if they have to pay to watch videos or use large-capacity, high-speed download network disks. Broadband and data traffic have been charged from the beginning, and no one thinks these should be free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a truly free lunch does not actually exist. If you want to watch free videos, you have to endure a lot of ads; if you want to use a free network disk, you can only endure the download speed of a small water pipe. Likewise, public benefits also need to be paid for by someone. There are no tolls on national highways, and construction and maintenance costs are indispensable. They can only come from fiscal revenue such as taxes, which means taxpayers must pay for them. If the local government&#39;s fiscal revenue is sufficient, then of course it won&#39;t be a problem. But if finances are tight, I&#39;m afraid we can only reduce spending on road construction and maintenance, or consider charging fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is preparing to collect fees at this time, which may be related to the local financial difficulties in recent years. But it remains to be seen whether it can move forward after attracting huge attention and opposition. Although Suqian and Huai&#39;an are in northern Jiangsu and are less economically developed than southern Jiangsu, they are still much more prosperous than many places in the west. There is still 1 billion in road construction loans, which may not be too big for local finances. of holes. What&#39;s more, Jiangsu, as the country&#39;s second largest economic province, should have enough financial resources to make transfer payments to local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if no tolls are allowed on national and provincial roads in the future, will the enthusiasm of local governments to build new roads be greatly reduced? This is also worth noting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[的里雅斯特：微型世界丨意长意短]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5ummeC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5um meC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258623&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Trieste in 1895. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time I pass through Trieste, I have to go and sit for a while in the ancient San Marco Cafe . This city has the best coffee in Italy, and the headquarters of Illy is here. Like many cities that were once glorious and then fell into silence, this city is half reality and half exists in words. Trieste was once the most important port of the Austro-Hungarian Empire and a blend of Slavic, Latin and Germanic cultures. More than a hundred kilometers away, Venice has kept the world&#39;s attention in a flashy way. Although every stone that built it came from elsewhere, and all the beauty is artificial, the first sight of Venice will make you wonder. One feels amazed and mesmerized. In comparison, Trieste is a sleepy city. She is located in the northeastern border of Italy, more than ten kilometers away in Slovenia. It faces the sea, backed by karst rocks, and under the mountains are checkerboard-like neighborhoods. There are many deep houses and compounds on the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James Morris, an Englishman who served as a soldier here, later changed his gender and became Jane Morris. After World War II, she wrote full-time and became a reporter for The Guardian and a famous travel writer. In her book &quot;Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere&quot; (Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere), Trieste is an unforgettable city, but when she tried to remember it, she found that it was like an unforgettable city. Presented face. This city has no unforgettable scenery, no unique food, and it doesn’t even have an Italian flavor. In a 1999 survey, 70% of Italians didn’t even know that this city belongs to Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, Trieste also has her unique charm. This former free port chose to be included in Italy during the dispute between Yugoslavia and Italy in the last century. The chaotic past can stimulate people&#39;s imagination and reflection. She is more literary than any other city. At the beginning of the last century, Joyce lived in many places in this city. He worked as an English teacher and began to write &quot;Ulysses&quot; here. For him, Trieste was a particularly draining place for his liver. Joyce interacted with the melancholy Italo Svevo, encouraged the Jewish businessman to write, and highly praised his &quot;Zeno&#39;s Consciousness&quot;. Svevo&#39;s writing has a slowness that is rare in Italian. Most of the writing is about a businessman questioning his own conscience, which complements the thoughtfulness of a stream-of-consciousness novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a kind of continuity in the literature of this city. The writings of contemporary Trieste writer Claudio Magris also have the melancholy of Svevo, and his works are very similar to It was translated from German into Italian, which is not surprising since Magris is a professor of German literature at the university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a writer wants to present a city, it is actually difficult to capture its spirit and soul. Magris has been telling stories about the land. As the most important seaport in the Austro-Hungarian Empire, Trieste&#39;s once glorious history made her current situation look bleak, and the entire city was shrouded in a twilight. Magris&#39;s writing is, in a sense, a pursuit of Trieste&#39;s literary tradition and an attempt to get closer to reality. His &quot;Micro World&quot;, which won the &quot;Strega&quot; award but is difficult to classify, has many texts related to the space of the city and the literature of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult for a person with limited life experience to establish a deep connection with the vast world. Sociologist Xiang Biao proposed the concept of &quot;nearness&quot;. Magris is an example of practicing &quot;neighborhood&quot;. He lives in this city and uses the tenacity of a scholar to understand the place and penetrate deeply into the life here. His &quot;miniature world&quot; actually consists of cafes, parks and Sacré Coeur. After reading his &quot;Micro World&quot; and then seeing the San Marco Cafe, the park and the nearby Sacré Coeur, you will recognize everything and feel that the world is what he described. The San Marco Cafe, which opened in 1914, has a very high ceiling with leaves and coffee beans on the top. The ebony bar and the wine racks against the wall stand firmly there. You will recognize the mask behind the counter. There is a The golden coffee machine with the flying eagle logo and the lion-shaped table legs under the table are reminiscent of Saint Mark, the patron saint of Venice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The city’s ancient cafes resist the times in their own way. In the San Marco Cafe, the bar is still made of solemn dark wood, and the tables, chairs and wall decorations are still the same as a hundred years ago. One side of its &quot;L&quot;-shaped structure has been transformed into a bookstore, filled with nostalgic books. The most conspicuous place is Magris&#39;s &quot;Micro Worlds&quot;, which has dozens of pages describing the past and present of the San Marco Café. The café is the living room of the city, an open public space where some faces disappear and new ones appear. In this urban space, the history of literature here is recorded. Cafe San Marco is a place frequented by literary &quot;pilgrims&quot;. Everyone, in their own way, hopes that this cultural &quot;ark&quot; will continue to exist. In addition to drinking coffee, you can also eat exquisite pasta in this cafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After coming out of the cafe, you can go for a walk in the nearby park to get some fresh air. There are towering plane trees in the park, and the sun shines through the leaves, and the golden light falls on a pool in the garden, which Magris also described. There are benches everywhere in the garden, where people read newspapers, books, or just sit around. There is a children&#39;s playground and an open-air cinema at the end of the park. Statues of city celebrities are scattered around, including a bust of Joyce wearing a hat and glasses, which was erected on the centenary of his birth in 1982, and a bust of local poet Saba, a second-hand bookseller of Jewish origin. , a neurotic patient and the cultural soul of Trieste, once wrote a poem titled &quot;Trieste&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I walked through the whole city,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;climbed a large Slope,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It was crowded at first, but then the road became empty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of the road is a low wall:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am sitting alone in this small corner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Where the low wall ends,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is also where the city ends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Trieste has an inaccessible beauty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you like, this city is like a rough, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Greedy wild child, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Having blue eyes and using a pair of overly large hands&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sent A flower;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Like a paragraph full of jealousy&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&#39;s love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On this hillside, I see the city (Trieste)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every church, every street, even the crowded beach,&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;And the top of the mountain is full of rocks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The last house seems to be firmly rooted there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everything around me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;all have a strange, tortured feeling,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is the smell of hometown (this is where I was born). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every part of my city is full of life&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;She reserved a corner for me, suitable for me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A worried and lonely life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone lives in the corners of the city, including poets like Saba. The city has beaches, hills, and therefore a hint of countryside. Watching life from above, but not participating in it, while not feeling like an outsider, is exactly what this city offers Saba. Magris lives in this city in another way. He exists in a strict ritual, as cautious and solemn as the black and white marble floor of the Sacre Coeur. For him, everything was close by, a trip to the park was like traveling around the world, the clear cistern of the Sacre Coeur was like a spring in the glade, and the dim light of the church was as deep as the sea at night. Unfathomable. His life permeates the San Marco Cafe, the Park in the Street and the Sacred Heart Church two steps away. Magris even designed a reassuring ending for himself: with the comfort of his two sons, he lives in the Sacred Heart Church. In the golden sky painted by the church, jump through the ring of fire held by two angels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Trieste described by Magris is a city of twilight. In 2019, when he was 80 years old, he published &quot;The Bent Time of Krems&quot;. This is a book about twilight. There are five short stories in the book, telling the stories of five men in their twilight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Concierge&quot;, there is an old man who is reluctant to advance but to retreat, a president who once owned several companies. He enters an unknown field to get rid of the reality of facing enemies on all sides. He is a Czech who walked from the interior to Trieste for development. When he was young, the world was beautiful and big. He played his role successfully, building himself a strong armor with checks and profits. However, one day, his desire for success and inner panic left him. He became relaxed, sold his company, and became a concierge of an apartment with a calm mood. Once the sea has returned to the waterside safely. He tries to avoid roads where he can see the sea in the morning, takes the bus, and then walks to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist of &quot;Music Lesson&quot; is a Polish Jew who has entered his twilight years, a survivor with shame. He takes a car to go up the mountain to the home of his former student. The student, who became a musical master, showed him a piece of music he had composed as a tribute to the tragedy of the Jews, and he accepted the piece with embarrassment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist in &quot;Bent Time in Krems&quot; is the closest thing to Magris. He gives a lecture on Kafka and has dinner in a city called Krems. At the dinner party, someone mentioned Noni, the goddess of his youth, and by chance, he actually contacted her later. The &quot;now&quot; changes the &quot;before&quot;, time becomes curved, and all that is left is &quot;his&quot; longing for the god-like Noni. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Awarding&quot; is about an old writer attending a literary award ceremony, feeling melancholy and relieved as time passes. In &quot;Outing Day&quot;, an old man went to the set to see the actor who played him in his youth. Everything was different from the previous story, and the old man got a kiss that he missed when he was a teenager. The five fragments of life are all based on the theme of &quot;old age&quot;, allowing people to see the scene of the city&#39;s twilight reflecting on life: the sunset fills the sky, and everything tends to be relieved. Magris uses short words to accurately outline some life fragments. The past and present coexist at the same time, and death becomes infinitely gentle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Magris, there is also a world-class best-selling female writer Susana Tamaro among the contemporary writers in Trieste. Most Italian families have her book &quot;Where the Heart Guidance&quot; 》. It was also a woman in her twilight years who was reckoning with the past through letters. There is also a writer recently introduced to the country - Gianfranco Kaligaric, who has certain connections with Trieste. He was born in Asmara, Eritrea, Africa. His family is a &quot;cosmopolitan&quot; family from Trieste, and he carries traces of the city&#39;s ethnic mix. He lived and worked in Milan and Rome. In 1974, he wrote the highly praised &quot;Waste of Summer&quot;. There is an indelible trace of youthful debauchery in his style, which still exudes endless charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又一中管干部被点名搞“七个有之” | 时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260846]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that Chongqing Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of the city, violated discipline and law and was expelled from the party. (Internet data map)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/954c5c3e3c.png&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/954c5c3e3c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258712&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing, violated disciplines and laws and was punished. Expelled from the party. (Internet data map)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission publicly announced the handling of disciplinary and law violations by Xiong Xue, the former deputy mayor of Chongqing. Situation: Expelled from the party and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. &lt;p>; Remain consistent and address many issues such as &quot;seven things&quot; and formalism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Seven principles&quot; was proposed at the Fourth Plenary Session of the 18th CPC Central Committee held in October 2014. The specific content is, &quot;Some people ignore the Party&#39;s For the sake of their so-called official career and their so-called influence, some engage in nepotism and exclude dissidents, some engage in gangs and cliques, and some engage in anonymous false accusations and rumors. In other words, there are those who try to win people&#39;s hearts and votes, there are those who appoint officials and make wishes and celebrate with others, there are those who do things on their own and act against the will, there are also those who try to make mistakes and make unreasonable comments about the central government, and so on.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before Xiong Xue was dismissed, many central management cadres had been characterized as &quot;seven qualities&quot;, such as Zhou Jiankun, former vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, and former chairman of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Congress. Deputy Director Gong Jianhua and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second time this year that Xiong Xue’s name has appeared on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Half a year ago, on May 11, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced on its website that Xiong Xue was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and was undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. This also makes him the 19th central management cadre to be dismissed in 2023, and the &quot;second tiger&quot; to be dismissed from Chongqing after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before Xiong Xue fell, more signs had been revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Failed to pass the National People&#39;s Congress qualification review&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Born in Xiong Xue, who grew up in Chongqing, is a typical &quot;local cadre&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating from the Chinese major of Chongqing No. 1 Normal School in Sichuan Province in 1982, Xiong Xue entered the Chongqing Nan&#39;an District Committee and served successively as the mayor of Chongqing Jiangjin City and the Municipal Party Committee. He is the deputy director of the High-tech Zone Management Committee (director level) and director of the Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission. He is in charge of education, science and technology, and was promoted to deputy mayor of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Government in May 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the beginning of 2023, Xiong Xue has suffered setbacks one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On January 17, 2023, the new Chongqing Municipal Government leadership team was made public. Xiong Xuewei was re-elected as deputy mayor, but continued to serve as a member of the municipal government party group . On the morning of the same day, at the third plenary session of the Sixth Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Congress, Xiong Xue was elected as a representative of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress. However, a month later, on February 24, the National People’s Congress website released a representative qualification review report, and Xiong Xue and other three people failed to pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before and after the National People&#39;s Congress confirmed his qualifications as a representative, Xiong Xue briefly continued to appear in public as a &quot;member of the Party Leadership Group of Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Government.&quot; On March 13, 2023, Xiong Xue also went to Wansheng Economic Development Zone to investigate the operation of industrial enterprises and energy supply guarantee work, and proposed to solve the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of enterprises and continue to optimize and improve the business environment. But this was also the last time Xiong Xue appeared in public reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s search found that they also failed to pass the National People&#39;s Congress qualification review. Except for Xiong Xue, who was notified of being investigated, the other two people were not reported to have been actually investigated. Impact and is still working normally today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking back at past public speeches, Xiong Xue has repeatedly emphasized the importance of &quot;party conduct and clean government&quot; and &quot;anti-corruption&quot; work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a survey conducted after he was appointed Secretary of the Chongqing Yongchuan District Party Committee in 2013, he emphasized the need to further enhance the people’s trust and satisfaction in the Party committee and government. We must do a good job in building a clean and honest government, strengthen education, supervision, and punishment to prevent corruption. In June 2020, when the Discipline Inspection Commission and Supervision Office of Chongqing High-tech Zone were officially unveiled, he also gave a speech, proposing to play the role of demonstration and leadership of leading cadres, take the lead in respecting the law and abiding by the law, and stand the test in small matters and details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, judging from the investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, Xiong Xue failed to complete the above requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The report mentioned that Xiong Xue accepted banquets and services that may affect the fair execution of official duties, accepted gifts and gifts in violation of regulations, obtained large returns through private loans, and was in conflict with Unscrupulous businessmen collude, engage in power-for-money transactions, take advantage of their positions to benefit others in project contracting, land approval, etc., illegally receive huge amounts of property, and fail to explain truthfully when organizing interviews and inquiries, among many other problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Seven Things&quot; is essentially a political issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;Xiong Xue is the third central management cadre to be clearly pointed out in the past two years for engaging in &quot;seven things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Jiankun, the former vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, who was &quot;double-opened&quot; in June 2023, was accused of losing his ideals and beliefs, losing the people&#39;s position, abandoning his duties and mission, and implementing Ineffective implementation of the Party Central Committee’s major decisions and arrangements on poverty alleviation and the consolidation and expansion of poverty alleviation results, use of poverty alleviation projects for personal gain, serious damage to the interests of the Party and the people, failure to fulfill the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the Party, implementation of “seven things”, and confrontation Organizational review, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gong Jianhua, the former deputy director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Congress who was &quot;double fired&quot; in 2022, was accused of losing his ideals and beliefs, abandoning his duties and mission, and betraying the &quot;two &quot;Maintain&quot;, organize &quot;small circles&quot; and &quot;small gangs&quot;, engage in &quot;seven things&quot;, pollute the political ecology, fail to implement the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and arrangements on trade union work, secretly manipulate the selection of model workers, and privatize the honor of the party and the country. Give and receive, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the concept of &quot;seven things&quot; was proposed at the Fourth Plenary Session of the 18th CPC Central Committee, many central management cadres have been named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;News on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission on September 16, 2020 stated: Former Deputy Chairman of the Internal Affairs and Judicial Committee of the Twelfth National People&#39;s Congress, Yunnan Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China Former Secretary Qin Guangrong &quot;publicly made remarks that were contrary to the requirements for comprehensive and strict governance of the party&quot;, and Meng Hongwei, former member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Public Security and former director of the China Coast Guard, &quot;refused to implement the decision of the Party Central Committee&quot;... In 2019, the Central Committee Without exception, all the central management cadres who have been investigated by the Discipline Inspection Commission and the National Supervisory Commission have &quot;seven problems&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the release of the &quot;Work Plan of the Central Anti-Corruption Coordination Group (2023-2027)&quot; in September 2023, the head of the Central Anti-Corruption Coordination Group Office once When answering questions from reporters, he pointed out that we must continue to focus on the &quot;seven problems&quot; and resolutely eradicate political groups that form cliques and parties for private gain. On November 10, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission also issued an article emphasizing that the &quot;seven things&quot; are essentially political issues, and they attempt to seize the power of the party and the state and undermine the centralization and unity of the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After more than a month of inter-provincial transfer, Wang Libo assumed the new vice governorship of Liaoning Province]&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;On November 14, 2023, &quot;Liaoning Daily&quot; released the news , after voting at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Liaoning Provincial People&#39;s Congress, Wang Libo was elected deputy governor of the Liaoning Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Resume shows that Wang Libo was born in Dingzhou, Hebei Province in 1968. He has worked in Shanxi for a long time and served as the director of the National Economic Comprehensive Division of the Shanxi Provincial Development and Reform Commission and the deputy secretary of the Provincial Party Committee. long. In May 2016, Wang Libo was confirmed to be at the director level, and later served as deputy secretary-general of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee, director of the General Office of the Provincial Party Committee, secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Shanxi Provincial Department of Culture and Tourism, deputy secretary-general of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee in charge of daily work, and deputy secretary-general of the Provincial Party Committee in charge of daily work. Director of the Finance and Economics Office, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2023, Wang Libo served as Secretary and Director of the Party Leadership Group of the Shanxi Provincial Development and Reform Commission, and was later transferred to Liaoning. A month ago, on October 10, Wang Libo appeared at a special study meeting held by the Theoretical Study Center Group of the Liaoning Provincial Government Party Group and spoke as a member of the Liaoning Provincial Government Party Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sun Yeli is appointed as Party Secretary of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to an update on the official website of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, Sun Yeli has been appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism. Hu Heping previously held this position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information shows that Sun Yeli, born in December 1964, is a graduate student in history at Peking University. After graduation, he entered the Central Document Research Office and worked as the Central Document Research Director. Deputy Secretary-General of the Office and Editor-in-Chief of &quot;Party Documentation&quot;, Member of the Office of the Central Documentation Research Office, Director of the Fifth Edition and Research Department, Director of the Sixth Edition and Research Department, Deputy Director of the Central Documentation Research Office, etc. He has long been engaged in party and state leaders. Book editing and ideological research, research on the history of the Party and modern Chinese history. In the past two years, Sun Yeli has also appeared publicly as deputy director of the Central Propaganda Department and spokesman for the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Heping is currently the deputy minister in charge of daily work of the Central Propaganda Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Intensive adjustments by leaders of more than ten universities including Peking University] &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;Current Leaders&quot; column of Peking University&#39;s official website shows that there have been many changes in the school&#39;s leadership. Among them, Jiang Guohua, currently deputy provost and executive vice dean of the Graduate School of Peking University, serves as deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Peking University. Fang Fang, currently director of the Personnel Department of Peking University, and Piao Shilong, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, serve as vice president of Peking University. Currently, he serves as director of the Propaganda Department of the Party Committee of Peking University. Ren Yuzhong serves as a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of Peking University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, on November 14, the Shaanxi Provincial People&#39;s Government website issued a cadre appointment and dismissal notice. Sun Qingwei, formerly a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee and Vice President of Peking University, became the Vice President of Northwest University. , preside over administrative work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to media reports, many universities in Shandong and Inner Mongolia have also recently welcomed &quot;new coaches.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, the Ministry of Education’s Personnel Department announced the appointment and removal decision of the Ministry of Education’s Party Group at Ocean University of China. Zhang Junfeng, former Vice President of Nanjing University, was appointed as President of Ocean University of China. , Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee. On the same day, the People&#39;s Government of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region released a batch of personnel appointments and dismissals, appointing Han Wei, member of the Party Committee of Inner Mongolia Normal University, as vice president; Meng Xianghong, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Inner Mongolia University for Nationalities, as president; Han Yongquan, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Chifeng University, and the Academic Affairs Office of Inner Mongolia University of Science and Technology. Chang Zhao Yongwang is the president and vice president of Inner Mongolia University of Science and Technology respectively; Liu Liqiang, director of the Academic Affairs Office of Inner Mongolia University of Technology, is the vice president; Zuo Hejun, dean of the Desert Management College of Inner Mongolia Agricultural University, is the vice president. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, three ordinary undergraduate colleges and universities in Jilin welcomed new secretaries or new presidents on the same day. They were the former presidents of Qilu University of Technology (Shandong Academy of Sciences) Wu Yantao, deputy secretary of the party committee, and Yang Jingbo, former deputy secretary of the party committee of Shandong Jianzhu University, were promoted to secretaries, and Kong Weijin, former vice president of Qingdao University, was transferred to deputy secretary of the party committee and dean of Shandong Jiaotong University. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[One year after his ouster, Deng Zhenxiao, the former mayor of Bozhou City, Anhui Province, was double-crossed]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;On November 14, 2023, the website of the Anhui Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision announced that Deng Zhenxiao, the former deputy secretary of the Bozhou Municipal Party Committee and former mayor of the Bozhou Municipal Government, seriously violated disciplines and laws and was expelled from the party and public office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;News shows that in November 2022, Deng Zhenxiao was fired on suspicion of serious violations of discipline and law. After investigation, Deng Zhenxiao was engaged in officials and business hooks, accepted the banquet in violation of regulations, and used its powers or positions to make profit for relatives. The indulgence of illegal businessmen intervened in cadre personnel work and intervened in the use of fiscal funds, causing major losses of state -owned property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot; [&quot;After the Central Financial Work Conference, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported to investigate and deal with finance. The number of cadres reaches 9] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the morning of November 15th, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that the Chinese agricultural agricultural agricultural actively voted in May this year Lu Xiaodong, former deputy president of the Bank of Zhejiang Branch, was &quot;double -opened&quot;. At this point, after the Central Financial Work Conference at the end of October, the Central Discipline Inspection Commission has reported to the investigation or disposal of financial cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 3, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced the former member of the Party Committee of Guangfa Bank, the Chairman of the Supervisors Wang Guizhi, and the former member of the former Party Committee of the Bank of China Yunnan Branch. The news that deputy president Shen Rui was expelled from the party. The next day, Zhang Hongli, a former member of the Party Committee and Deputy Governor of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, was dismissed. On the 7th, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Zhu Congzheng, former vice chairman of the Zhejiang Provincial Political Consultative Conference, was opened. On the 10th, Chen Communist Party, the former secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Galaxy Securities Co., Ltd., was investigated; Yang Chunlei, the former full -time deputy director of the Office of the Party Committee of the Party Committee of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, was doubled. Four days later, An Qingsong, who replaced Chen Communist Party as the president of the China Securities Association, announced his dismissal; Li Dajun, former party secretary and president of the Bank of Communications Yunnan Branch, was notified to expel the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Ministry of Ministerial Information &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaiti, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; [Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, etc. will start the first batch of pilots of comprehensive electrification of vehicles in the public domain in 15 cities] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-alignter : left;&quot;>;2023年11月13日，工业和信息化部、交通运输部等八部门正式印发《关于启动第一批公共领域车辆全面电动化先行区试点的通知》，确定北京、深圳、 Chongqing, Chengdu, Zhengzhou and other 15 cities are the pilot zone for this pilot. According to the expected goals, the promotion of new energy vehicles will focus on official vehicles, urban buses, sanitation vehicles, taxi, postal courier vehicles, urban logistics distribution cars, airport cars, and specific scenes of heavy trucks. The number of promotion is expected to exceed 600,000 In terms of charging and replacement infrastructure, more than 700,000 charging piles and 07,800 power stations will be completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot; [&quot; Opinions] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recently, the Ministry of Public Security and relevant competent departments drafted the &quot;telecommunications network fraud and their associated criminal punishment methods (draft for comments) &quot;, For extensive opinions for the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 19 &quot;Punishment Methods (Draft for Opinions)&quot;, mainly includes the principles of punishment, punishment objects, disciplinary measures, grading punishment, disciplinary procedures, appeal verification 6 In terms of content. For those who are investigated for criminal responsibility for the implementation of telecommunications network fraud and their associated crimes, the punishment period is 3 years; the punishment period for disciplinary targets identified by public security organs at or above the municipal level of the municipal level is 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Rule of rule of law &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; [More than 7,500 cases of public interest litigation in the field of barrier-free environmental construction since 2019] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-alft: left ; &quot;>; On November 13, 2023, the Supreme Procuratorate, the Ministry of Construction, and the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation jointly held a press conference. From 2019 to September 2023, the national procuratorial organs handled a total of public interest litigation cases in the field of barrier -free environmental construction. 7,526, including 7,497 cases of administrative public interest litigation, and 29 civil public interest litigation cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Supreme Law Releases New Regulations, standardize comprehensive governance judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial judicial Recommended work] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft;&quot;>; The Supreme People&#39;s Court issued the &quot;Regulations on Several Issues on Comprehensive Governance Judicial Proposal Work&quot; on November 15. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The judicial suggestions are constructive opinions issued to the units or individuals in the process of reviewing civil, economic, and administrative disputes in the process of reviewing civil, economic, and administrative disputes. According to the Supreme Law, due to the current judicial suggestion work, there are still issues such as insufficient performance of deepening traceability and the lack of standardized procedures. The &quot;Regulations&quot; will be implemented from November 16, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Local political conditions &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaiti, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; [Shanghai releases the&quot; Silk Road E-commerce &quot;cooperation pioneer plan] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; On the morning of November 14, 2023, the Press Office of the Shanghai Municipal Government held a press conference. Zhang Xiong, deputy secretary -general of the municipal government, introduced the main content of the &quot;Program on the Creation of the&quot; Silk Road E -commerce &quot;cooperation in Shanghai&quot;. Trying the environment, vigorously promoting international and regional exchanges and cooperation, and expanding the opening of the e -commerce sector, etc., put forward 19 tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to the overall goal proposed by the plan, by 2025, Shanghai will form a number of institutional open results with demonstration and leading effects, gathered a group of international competitiveness The main body of e -commerce business has created a group of distinctive regional carriers, and a public service platform that promotes the joint development of the &quot;Silk Road E -commerce&quot; partner country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Beijing 24 municipal management enterprises fully advance 430 after the disaster Rebuilding Project] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; People&#39;s Daily News on November 15th, 24 municipal management companies in Beijing are fully promoting the three districts of Mentougou, Fangshan, and Changping 430 post -reconstruction projects involve four aspects: infrastructure, public services, financial support, and people&#39;s livelihood services. The above three districts were severely damaged in the rain and flood disasters at the end of July and early August this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to reports, the Beijing State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission is currently focusing on the overall idea of ​​&quot;basically recovery, three years of comprehensive improvement, long-term and high-quality development&quot; The core of improving people&#39;s livelihood, taking the actual needs of the reconstruction of reconstruction in the disaster area as the starting point, and guiding the supervision of municipal management enterprises to deeply integrate into the disaster to restore and rebuild various tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; science and education dynamics &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; [The establishment of the National Student Mental Health Work Consultation Committee] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; November 15, 2023 On the day, the Ministry of Education issued a notice on the establishment of the National Student Psychological Health Working Committee. The notice proposes that the consulting committee will undertake duties such as research, consulting, monitoring, evaluation, scientific popularization, and guidance under the leadership of the Ministry of Education. Each work area will organize at least once a major activity of the province where the provinces are located through research, science popularization preaching, and free clinic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [China successfully launch a new generation of marine water color observation satellite] &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; According to China Aerospace Technology Group, at 11:55 on November 16th, at the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center in my country, Long March 2/Expedition 1 The S Lange Rockets supported the new generation of marine water -color observation satellites to rush straight into the clouds, and then the satellite entered the scheduled track smoothly, and the launch task was successful. This means that my country&#39;s marine water color series satellites have been officially upgraded to the second -generation observation system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 【&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; Liaoning no longer approves new school-oriented children. Training institutions] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recently, 7 departments including the Education Department of Liaoning Province jointly issued the &quot;Liaoning Province&#39;s non-disciplinary training institutions for elementary and middle school students in Liaoning Province,&quot; Measures to make systematic deployment of non -disciplinary off -school training management. The &quot;Measures&quot; proposes that training institutions that implement non -disciplinary training activities such as science and technology, culture and arts, sports, etc. must submit an application to the education administrative department. license. No new training institutions for preschool children will no longer be approved, and online training shall not be provided for preschool children. The &quot;Measures&quot; will be implemented from December 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; sound &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family : Kai style, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>; [&quot; Zhang Feng, deputy secretary of the Haixi State Committee of Qinghai Province: The gap between the thought is the biggest gap, the backward concept is the biggest backward] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;Text-Align: LEFT;&quot;>; From April 3rd to 9th, 2023, the Republic of Qinghai Province sent 11 party and government delegations to the two places in Changzhou City, Jiangsu Province and Ankang City, Shaanxi Province for study and inspection. The Standing Committee of the Hainan State Party Committee and the Secretary of the Republican County Party Committee is one of the members of the delegation. After the inspection, he wrote a 10 -character report and recently published in the &quot;Party Life&quot; of the Qinghai Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Feng mentioned that the gap between the ideology is the biggest gap, and the backward concept is the biggest backward. &quot;Many things, especially project construction, industrial development, We are still arguing if we can do it, or not, and other policies and finding the basis. >; In October this year, Zhang Feng has been promoted to the deputy secretary of the Haixi State Committee of Qinghai Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (integrated from surging news, daily economic news, Caixin.com , Qilu Evening News, the official WeChat of the General Office of the Inner Mongolia, the website of the Anhui Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, First Finance, Xinhua News Agency, Shangguan News, People&#39;s Daily, Procuratorate Daily, etc.) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[怕老的年轻人正被世界富豪们牢牢盯上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260613]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recent &amp; nbsp; Angermayer) invested in Rejuveron, a longevity biotechnology company, and wanted to achieve the purpose of prolonging life by solving age -related diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In recent years, Zuckerberg, Bill &lt;/span>; Gates, Google founder and other technological circles Investment in the field has led to controversy from all walks of life, and capital has become a key force for studying human &quot;longevity&quot; and has been criticized by morality and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The capital is finally profitable, and they are seeing the big cake behind anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Data show that from 2015-2021, the global anti-aging market increased by 76.5 billion US dollars. Especially under the circumstances of China&#39;s consumption upgrade and deepening health demand, China&#39;s demand for delaying aging is increasing, and the anti -aging industry has continued to expand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As the scale of anti-aging market gradually expands, anti-aging products and medical beauty projects are emerging, and it is also subtlely affected people&#39;s perception of aging. For the old age, most people are worried about skin problems, such as &quot;dark skin color&quot;, &quot;thick pores&quot; and &quot;aging of the eyes&quot; are the common problems of the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is worth noting that aging is not just the trouble of middle-aged and elderly people. Under the words of advertising and grass -breeding storms in social media, more and more young people have also produced anti -aging anxiety. And providing emotional value for this group of young people with damaged young people is the various home beauty instruments that are more active on the grass planting platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Bring home the cinema beauty effect&quot;. From the unique precision instruments of the medical and beauty institutions to the convenient instrument of the home use, the home beauty instrument is loved by consumers. Some brands also play a new concept of &quot;technology beauty&quot;, that is, the combination of beauty instruments+skin care products to attract to attract the way Many young people have produced consumption behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some research reports show that 42 % of users spend more than 1,000 yuan on skin care on skin care every quarter. Under the dual consideration of economic strength and anti-aging needs, the 35-39-year-old people have the strongest willingness to pay for their face value. 21 % of people sell more than 3,000 yuan per quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, in the face of thousands of household beauty instruments, many people still hesitate to be IQ taxes. Hot discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Today, &quot;know&quot; and talk to you about it worth it for anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/8ae7276b4d.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/8AE7276B4D.PNG &quot;data- key =&quot; 258286 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343De0e4ec.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1440&quot; &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343De0e4EC.Png &quot;Data- key =&quot; 258287 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot; &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/5020a852e0.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5020a852e0.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/4929a36023.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot;/iMages.infzm. CM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/14/4929A36023.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 258289 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http: //images.infzm. CM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/14/E9777A9.png &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/medias/ Image/23/11/14/E9777a9.png &quot;Data- Key =&quot; 258290 &quot;>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cmedias/ Image/23/11/14/91b7312bdf.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/23/11/ 14/91b7312BDF.PNG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 258291 &quot;>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 14/ddbff4839c.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ddbff4839c.png &quot;&quot; data-key = &quot;258292&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你家附近借书便利吗？期盼普及社区借阅服务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260844]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-17 23:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; After reading the limited collection of the family, I feel that there is no book to read it. Telephone, saying to send me a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xiao Xu is my former colleague, he knows I like to read books. I also sent it a few times before, each time a few big books. I was embarrassed to let him send it again, and I declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have two hobbies, one is walking, and the other is reading. The walking makes me refreshing, and reading makes me live. I didn&#39;t take a walk for a day, and I felt uncomfortable; I didn&#39;t read a book for a day, and I had a taste of life on this day. Reading a few pages a day has long become a habit of life. If you do n’t find a book one day, you will feel fragrant when you sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few years ago, most of the books I read relied on my son to borrow from the college library. My son&#39;s university is studying locally. This is a great benefit to me, that is, I can use the university library as my own private library. This is all stained with the light of the son. Now that my son graduated from university, I have been working on a job, and I have lost that convenient reading condition. After my son left school, the source of the book was broken. I had to turn the box at home to pour the cabinet and start the idea of ​​collecting books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The collection of books at home is too limited to meet my needs. The days when there is no book can be read, I feel particularly long, and it seems to have a sense of inferiority. Xiao Xu called at this time, and I wanted to send a book. As I felt like, I felt like I couldn&#39;t always owe the feelings of others. Now that the book price is high, Xiao Xu is just a working class. How can he always make people spend? No matter how iron is the relationship, there must be a scalp. So I thought that if there is a place to borrow books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, there is no borrowing book office. The library in the city can be borrowed, but it is a bit regrettable. The place is not close to home, there are more than ten miles back and forth. In this way, it is natural to think that if it can be borrowed near the home, isn&#39;t it good to borrow a book? Such as the library of the community. But I couldn&#39;t find such a place, asked people, and said I have never heard of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The son joked that we would buy it near the library in the future. Even if this joke can come true, it is far from the water. It is said that it is difficult to create a book incense society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I admit that there are fewer and fewer people who read paper books now. But even so, there are still public services that should be there, and there must be no less. We often say that we need to carry out bottom -type assistance to difficult groups, and there must be bottom -type assistance in reading, because there are always people who can&#39;t afford too much books, and some people always face the high book price. Even if you ca n’t help but do it, you can only endure love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Let reading enter our daily life and become an important part of life, thereby improving the quality of individual literacy and the population quality of the entire society. This is the fundamental point of creating a scent of society. Not to mention anything else, just to this, we also need to have a place to make people borrow nearby. Such a place does not need to be large, and it can provide convenience for people. At least one community neighborhood committee must have such a place. The large community must determine the number of places according to the population distribution, and in order to save costs, books can be regularly circulated between different places, so as to maximize the use of books and maximize satisfaction to the greatest extent. The needs of lovers. I don&#39;t know if such desires can be implemented in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (the author is Anqing City, Anqing City) &lt;/p>; &lt;pan style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; &quot; >; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend APP &quot;Hi, Southern Week&quot; section is looking forward to your manuscript. Submit mailbox: nfzmreams@163.com) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪国芭蕉——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（五）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260812]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-17 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/23/ 11/17/fxpujkhddpeuaavi8nl2nl2nrjawnmdwritl3nz.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i MAGE/23/11/17/FXPUJKHDDDPEUAAVI8NL2NL2NRJAWNMDWRCTL3NZ. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258619 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Matsuo Banana Sentence in Daehe Shrine, Niigata Prefecture, photo on the left in 2023 4 Month, the picture on the right was taken in September 2023. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Author&#39;s picture/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After walking a few points of the &quot;Austrian Road&quot; of Panaican Banana in the fall of 2019, it is tight Then there is a new crown epidemic in three years. It&#39;s like a dream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In early April and early September 2023, early spring and early autumn, I went to Niigata Prefecture in northern Japan twice. After the Vietnam, one of the ancient Japan&#39;s &lt;span>; Ling Guo &lt;/span>; is facing the &lt;Span>; Japan Sea &lt;/span>;, and it is narrow north and south. &lt;span>; Meiji &lt;/span>; Four years later, the county is abolished, named Xinxie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xinxie in April, the car was driving between the continuous farmland. The brown rice fields in early spring have just turned the soil and are waiting for a new round of sowing. The schedule in September has been in my plan, so I started to imagine the scene of autumn. Large -area solid color scene, yellow is the most suitable, pure and gorgeous with the blue sky. In the Chengdu Plain where I live, there is a prosperous scene in the spring of March every day. The rapeseed spreading exhibition is spectacular, which is quite excited in the breath of early spring. At this time, the Chengdu people in the house basically go out to spring, live up to nature, and live up to themselves. Fortunately, when I visited Xinxie in early September, the scene of Jinya Mano was enjoyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are many swans in the barren fields in Niigata in April. They fly back to Siberia after pecking the food falling in the soil and fertilize. Migrate like this every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking at these beautiful white birds from a distance. Have you seen them? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There should be no. Matsuo Banana and his disciples He He Zeng Liang arrived in the summer of 1689. After the Vietnam, it is a stop of &quot;Austrian Road&quot;. The entire &quot;Austrian Road&quot; journey is a total of 2400 kilometers on a hiking journey. Depart from Edo, go north, and then fold west. It is said that the magnificent journey comparable to it is the road tour of the eighty -eight temples of the four nations of the empty sea monk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This trip to Japan in the spring of 2023. Before the trip, in the excitement and longing, it was mixed with a different mood from the travel of previous years. For three years, except for a few short -term travel in China, he has not gone to the country. The three -year partition is psychologically faint, but I don&#39;t know where this anxiety comes from. In the body, it feels like a slow and stagnant feeling. After three years of rhythm, the effect is really powerful, the body is heavy, and even the mood is sinking down. I asked myself, what would happen if I won&#39;t go out in the future? It seems to be okay. For middle -aged people, it is an important reason for three years, and it is an important reason. By September, after the Japanese trip in April, I drove in Yunnan in May, and coupled with several short -distance travels, I felt that my psychology and body began to adapt to the journey again. It was very happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Friends Ding Yuan settled in &lt;Span>; Niigata County &lt;/span>; Murakami, and operated a homestay called &quot;Four Seasons&quot; with her husband Nakamura. Various content of travel. Regarding the banana, Ding Yuan helped me find out: Banana and Zeng Liang stayed in the village for two nights and three days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Banana Plants in Murakama can be checked and determined according to local literature, but the scenery of the year is no longer the same, and it has become a salmon restaurant, so the warm curtain at the door is very interesting. This is a two -story Japanese -style house on the streets of Murakami. The three warm curtains are hung on the door side by side. &quot;Salmon dishes&quot;, a book on the left &quot;Banan&#39;s Bo Su Di&quot;. There was a wooden sign at the door, &quot;In the second year of Yuanlu (1689) in June, the banana and Zeng Liang arrived on the village on the&quot; Austrian Road &#39;journey, two lives for three days (two nights and three days), and stayed here. At that time, it was called &#39;Su Jiu Zuo Weimen&#39;. &quot;In order to show that this brand was not the shop&#39;s self -speaking, the money was&quot; Murakami&#39;s Listed Education Commission &quot;. The salmon industry in Murakami is very famous. Each year, many salmon will travel here, and the output and quality are superior. Therefore, there are a considerable number of salmon restaurants and marinated air -dried salmon processing workshops on Murakami. I asked Nakamura, is the &quot;Inoue House&quot; the most famous salmon shop in Murakami? Nakamura laughed. It was not necessarily. It was the light of banana, but most people would not care about this, and your cultural people were very concerned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/mqzaibocPFMPLWCHVYVYGJFUL4PLJPG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/mqzaibocpby1l4bFMPLWCHVYGJqujful4pljrqa.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; 258620&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Pine-tailed Banana and Disciple He He Zeng Liangxing to the accommodation place for the listing of Murakami. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Author&#39;s picture/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Banana wrote in the &quot;Thirty -Five Vietnamese Road&quot; in &quot;Austrian Road&quot; &quot;As soon as the mouse passed, we entered the territory from the out of the feathers, and then we rushed to Yuezhong&#39;s city Zhenguan again. After nine days. In the meantime, sometimes the heat is unbearable, sometimes the cold rain is poured with heads, and we are exhausted. Even getting sick is really miserable. Therefore, I did n’t record the journey. ”&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Maybe because the banana is ill during the period, so there is very little records about the aftermath of the Vietnam in Olympic Road. According to the results of Ding Yuan&#39;s help me, I found out in the early spring and early autumn in my village. But this trace is no longer a certain place, and it can only be found in the banana quantic monument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is a banana monument in the Tibetan Church in Shippotcho &quot;けふはか けふはか も も よ &amp; &amp; nbsp; first rain&quot;. It can be translated as: Today, people know that people are old, the first show. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Daehe Shrine has a banana sentence stone. The latter is a sentence in the seven episodes of &quot;Spring&quot;, which was made in 1685. Banana visited Murakami in August 1689. It is estimated that because of his bad health, he did not leave any works. There is also a sacrifice stones next to the Banana Sentence. The handwriting is blurred. The idea I read is: the moonlight under the water shore, and the pine leaves are covered with umbrellas (I don&#39;t know if it is right). Looking at the introduction on the side card, these two sentences were established in October 1843. At the 150th year of Banana and the 17 -year sacrifice of Suxian. In the introduction, it is also specially said that there are two important parts of the relics of Banana in the market. One is the Inari Shrine where it is located here, and the other is the Iwa Shrine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The rock boat shrine built by the seaside has a much larger scale and momentum than the Daehe Shrine, with red torii and white torii. In front of the Red Torii, there is a banana sentence stone, which is engraved with the sentence &quot;Flower き て て て 红 红 る る な な な&quot;, which can be understood as &quot;the cherry blossoms are scattered for seven days, so beautiful is just a crane.&quot; The banana sentence stone in front of the white torii is &quot;Wenyue や Six days も の の の は は は は は は は は は は は は は は&quot;. The previous banana&#39;s sentence has nothing to do with &quot;Austrian Road&quot;, and the latter sentence is taken from the &quot;Bohitari Road&quot; in the Beiyu section. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April, the day before the visits of &lt;Span>; Xinli County &lt;/span>; Banana Trace, we went to Katsuoka Wenshuyuan, Dasheng Temple in Yamagata County. In the drizzle, there are still snow in the distance in the distance and the roof nearby. When I went down the mountain, I suddenly found that there was a banana monument on the side of the road. Lishi Temple (Shan Temple) in Shanxing County is an important visit to the &quot;Diandao Road&quot; journey of the Banana Masters and Apprentice. I have been to 2019. Dasheng Temple did not know if they had been there, and did not mention it in the book. Some people may have studied these travel details, and the results of these studies must be carefully explored to know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have read a lot of Chinese translations before. The so -called poem cannot be translated, it is really the case. Because my Japanese foundation is still shallow, and it also involves the problems of ancient and modern Japanese. But maybe this is this kind of ignorance. After leaking out some clear information, the extremely simple and unusual and complicated semantics of the sentence was a little understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The heavy head of the banana in Murakama is Yi Bao Temple. In the early spring and early autumn, I went to Yibao Temple two times. The cherry blossoms in the early spring are obviously much more beautiful than the early autumn scenes that have not yet appeared. It is said that it is Murakami. In fact, Yibao Temple is located in the fetal city next to the village. This temple was built in the 8th century AD. The temple covers an area of ​​more than 80,000 square meters. The &quot;triple tower&quot; built in the temple in 1620 was designated as a key cultural heritage in Japan. This temple is the only ancient temple that logs in to the new &lt;span>; Xie &lt;/span>; in &quot;Today&#39;s Story&quot;, and it is also the temple that has been worshiped by the Songwei Banana that roams &quot;Austrian Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uyiv1rkos05Cira8y6dkaodlxphpl.jpg&quot; widt = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;720&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uyiv1rkos05Cira8y6dkaodlxphpl.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258621&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Matsuo Banana Step in Bibao Temple. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Author&#39;s picture/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this point, a few words are said. In the early autumn, the Bibao Temple, near noon after the visit, Mr. Nakamura said that there was a steamed bun shop next to him, and he hadn&#39;t eaten it for a long time. We decided to solve it in lunch. At the door of the door, it was explained that in the first year of culture, it was 1804, more than 200 years of history. The shop is really small, with a few stools two or three tables. When the steamed bun came up, at a glance, it turned out to be a bean paste. Later, I checked the information. In Japan, the so -called steamed buns are bean paste. The outer skin can change. There are white steamed buns made of flour, brown tea buns made of wheat powder, as well as sweet potato flour, yam powder and rice noodles. The steamed buns made of potato and meal fermented flour are made, but they are all bean paste stuffing inside. Yibao Temple steamed buns are delicious. I am even more emotional that such a snack shop has a history of more than 200 years. In Japan, I have encountered a variety of small shops with a history of hundreds of years. I have eaten a ramen in Kyoto. After eating, I saw the signboard at the door. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I posted a photo of the Yibao Temple in the circle of friends in WeChat. Some friends asked: Is it the Bibao Temple in &quot;The Story of the past&quot;? It seems that its name is first from &quot;The Story of the past.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Today&#39;s Story&quot; is a collection of folklore stories in the late Japanese period. There are thirty -one volumes, and the story is more than a thousand. Divided into Tianzhu (India) (one to 5 volumes), Zhendan (China) (6 to 10 volumes), and the dynasty (Japan) (11 to 31 volumes). At present, the Chinese version of this dynasty is scheduled by Zhou Zuoren. The story in &quot;The Story of the past&quot; is all -encompassing. The Buddhist story and the secular story are mixed. In addition, there are many fairy stories. Many of the creations of later generations come from this book and are one of the source of Japanese literature. Sanxiao two -character shoots and Liao Zhai Zhi Yi in China. Because each volume starts with the word &quot;this past&quot;, it is named &quot;The Story of the Premier&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among Japanese writers, Akutagawa Ryomi has made full use of the Story of the past. It is said that the historical novel he created is about one -fifth of the materials from &quot;Today&#39;s Story&quot;, including &quot;Luo Sheng&quot;, which includes &quot;Luo Sheng&quot; &quot;Gate&quot; &quot;in the jungle&quot;. Akutagawa Ryosuke called &quot;The Story of the past&quot; in ancient Japanese &quot;world comedy&quot;. He said that &quot;The Story of the Premier&quot; is full of &quot;wild beauty&quot; and is &quot;a beauty that is the most beautiful and luxurious.&quot; Many of the content of Yin and Yang Dao and Yin and Yang division commonly comes from &quot;The Story of the past&quot; in Japanese anime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the wide garden of Yibao Temple, there are banana monuments, round stone monuments, and the handwriting has been blurred. There is a wooden sign next to the Sentence, which records the content of this quantic monument: &quot;In the second year of Yuanlu (1689), Matsuo Baban Banana worshiped. I envy). Around the Banana Sentence, there were many sentences of &lt;span>; Xinxie &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; altar at the time. Yibao Temple has been a name of cherry blossom viewing since ancient times. Bananas have lamented the beauty of the cherry blossoms in the northern country, although he was not in the flowering period of cherry blossoms when he visited. Looking at Sakura Ye, he also expressed his envy mood in imagination. The other people&#39;s response and two sentences were written in the description of the quotes alone. It is estimated that it was the most famous local person at that time. Luke and B Temple, flowers, flowers. One is Antian Yimi Fang. They are all sentences to sing cherry blossoms. In Japan, the word spent, if not referred to, is cherry blossom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xinxie in early April was the full period of cherry blossoms, but the spring of 2023 came fiercely. When we arrived, the cherry blossoms had been a little bit too much. In the garden of Yibao Temple, there were several cherry blossoms hanging down on the stele of the banana, which was close to the eve of the withering. Behind the quotes is a small hill, with several red vertical curtains standing on the steps on the steps. Song curtain fluttered gently in the sun and breeze. In this situation, the monument that is not clear with the handwriting is also complemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like other Shinkansen landscapes, there are very few tourists. I stood on the terrace outside the main hall and watched the Buddha statue in the garden below watching the yin and yang scene cut by the sun. Such a move is twice in me. The seemingly the same weather, early spring and early autumn, the segmentation line of sunlight and shadows is obviously different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I visited Yibao Temple in September, and suddenly discovered the master of Hongfa (Konghai) here. I didn&#39;t notice the trip in April. Here is the statue of the Master of the Fa Master. It is a common shape of the empty sea on the journey. This empty sea stone statue is a bit cute and has been shaped into a chubby little boy. I turned to the back of the stone statue to see the instructions. The handwriting was a bit blurred, but I can clearly see the words &quot;The Eighty -eight Royal Ling Farm in the Four Kingdoms ...&quot;. It is estimated that someone went to the road before, and returned to Niigata to commemorate in Yibao Temple. The road is the practice route of the empty sea monk. Later, it gradually became the most famous hiking route in the world, with a total length of more than 1,400 kilometers and worshiped the 88th temples of the four countries.目前每年有五十多万来自全世界各地的人会走在这条路上。对于我们来说这也是好奇特的缘分啊，见过乙宝寺的空海之后，我和同行友人谭卫东博士第二天就离开了新潟，飞到大阪短暂停留后，再前往四国，开启了我们计划准备了三年的遍路之行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[格力电器：董明珠“绯闻”是造谣，已向公安机关报案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260839]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月17日，格力电器方面回应南都湾财社记者：“就近期多个自媒体为了获取流量，恶意剪辑相关视频、使用低俗污秽言辞侮辱诽谤公司高管，格力电器已向公安机关报案，公安机关均已受理并立案。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都湾财社记者获悉，近期在社交平台上有谣传称，格力电器董事长兼总裁董明珠与格力电器“渠道改革项目负责人”王自如在恋爱。在近日的电视台节目中，董明珠对此作出回应表示，“我看都不看，我觉得没所谓。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在同一节目中，王自如的言论：“没看过格力开给我的工资条”“入职请求一间离董总近的办公室方便汇报”等备受关注和争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而近日，猎豹移动CEO傅盛在朋友圈发表对王自如的看法。傅盛表示，“我只能说，王自如不仅是个吃软饭的，而且是个流氓。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据公开资料，王自如是ZEALER（载乐网络科技）创始人。天眼查显示，ZEALAR成立于2012年6月，是一家主打电子产品测评及问答的科技资讯网站，而后拓展了手机维修业务、移动设备硬件实验室等。 Wang Ziru is not only an executive director and general manager of Zealer, but also a digital evaluation blogger with 1.97 million fans. He &quot;became popular&quot; because of the public debate of the Hammer Technology CEO Luo Yonghao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258706&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;图片来自王自如个人微博。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从公开信息来看，王自如与董明珠相识于2016年。 On the aired entrepreneurial show &quot;I am the founder&quot; that year, Dong Mingzhu served as Wang Ziru&#39;s mentor.此后王自如还在微博上晒出自己与董明珠的合照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258707&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;图片来自王自如个人微博。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，董明珠举行全国巡回直播带货活动，王自如多次作为主持人登场，与董明珠一同直播带货拿下7.03亿元销售额。当年，董明珠13场直播带货总金额达476亿元，占到2020年格力电器当年总营收近30%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在2021年7月，格力电器方面确认了王自如入职格力电器的消息。当时有业内人士表示，王自如所在的部门隶属于格力总裁办及文化培训传播中心，同期，王自如辞去了自己创办的媒体ZEALER的职位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有传言称，王自如在格力的职级与副总裁相当，年薪超300万元，但从近两年的格力电器财报来看，王自如从未出现在高管报酬表格middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;入职格力电器以后，王自如鲜少在公共平台露面。格力电器也未透露他的具体工作内容。但从一些公开报道可知，他目前负责格力渠道改革项目。今年5月下旬，入职格力两年却仍未露面的王自如，首次以“渠道改革项目负责人”的身份公开现身南昌，在2023年格力电器（江西）新营销模式宣讲会上发言。 10月和11月，格力电器山东和河北销售公司也发文，王自如在新营销模式会议上登台演讲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，在今年年初时社交平台上就已经出现格力电器董事长兼总裁董明珠与其公司85后男高管谈恋爱的消息，该消息源于大V龚文祥发布在网络上的一张截图。今年2月时，董明珠在接受南都湾财社记者等媒体采访时主动提及并直斥：“低级、下流、无聊！用这几个词形容也不为过”，明确否认了恋爱绯闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在今年3月时，大V龚文祥在南方都市报就此前的言论登报向格力电器董事长兼总裁董明珠道歉。龚文祥在道歉声明中称，他于2月26日在今日头条发表了对董明珠女士私生活歪曲事实的言论，被大量广泛传播，客观上损害了董女士的名誉。 “我深表后悔，对董女士深感抱歉，特登报表示对董女士公开道歉、真心忏悔，希望取得董女士的原谅。我以后并以此为鉴，做一个三观正的自媒体人。”龚文祥在声明中说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月17日，格力电器方面回应南都湾财社记者：值得一提的是，网络不是法外之地，公司将采取法律措施坚决维护企业及员工的合法权益，对任何恶意中伤和造谣行为保持零容忍的态度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在上述提及的电视节目中，王自如则表示，没有任何一家企业是被口水淹死的，作为企业的经营者、管理者，应该花更多时间关注自己该things to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[跨越45年，披头士乐队的最后一首歌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;披头士乐队（The Beatles）成立于1960年，流行音乐史上里程碑式的乐队。 In 1980, the lead singer John Lennon was killed. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1969年1月30日，在英国萨维尔街3号苹果唱片公司总部的天台上，披头士乐队举办了一场时长为42分钟的即兴音乐会。几乎是到最后一刻，这个想法才被确定下来——他们讨论过这件事，然后沉默了，直至约翰∙列侬说：“……让我们去做吧！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中午12点30分左右，四人抵达天台。随着消息传开，人们开始聚集在周围的街道和附近建筑物的屋顶上。当天，列侬穿着一身皮草大衣，林戈则穿上了妻子的红色外套。在1月的凛冽寒风中，成员们共循环演唱了五首歌曲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;音乐会最终在《Get&amp;nbsp;Back》的旋律中落下帷幕。列侬幽默地朝现场的观众说：“我想代表乐队和我们自己说声谢谢，我希望我们已经通过了试镜。”然而，彼时的大众或许未曾料到，这是披头士乐队的最后一次公开合体演出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月2日，在跨越了45年时光后，一首名为《Now And Then》的新的披头士合作曲终于来到大众面前。熟悉的“一、二、三”计时后，伴奏声响起，列侬的声音缓缓地流淌出来：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;“&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I know it&#39;s true / It&#39;s all because of you / And if I make it through / It&#39;s all because of you&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;……&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MV中的列侬和乔治还是年轻时候的面孔，他们穿着当年鲜丽的服装，与保罗和林戈在同一个空间里演奏。而与他们的年轻鲜活不同的是，保罗与林戈脸上的皱纹已清晰可见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在我父亲离开这么多年后，听到他们还能一起工作，真是令人难以置信的感动，”列侬的儿子肖恩说，“这是我父亲和保罗、乔治、林戈一起制作的最后一首歌。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“我们几乎等待了四分之一个世纪”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《Now And Then》的故事开始于1978年。在位于纽约的公寓中，列侬弹着钢琴，录下了这一段带伴奏的人声样带。那时候的他已将重心放至家庭，几乎暂停了自己的音乐事业，没有巡演，也没有履行任何主要唱片公司的义务。不过，在儿子肖恩的记忆中，列侬总是会在家里弹奏音乐，并录下来制作样带。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994年，距列侬去世已有14年之久，在一次与披头士成员的聊天中，列侬的遗孀小野洋子说自己还留有一些列侬的录音磁带，她将它们交给了其余的披头士成员。 “如果我们三个要做一些事情，虽然也很有趣，但显然没有约翰在时有趣。”乔治说，“我们真的要珍惜还能听到约翰的声音，我相信他肯定会真心享受和我们再次一起的机会。”现在，这个机会来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们可以利用列侬的音乐，尝试去制作一张唱片。自从他去世后，这是我们离他最近的时刻了。”林戈说。面对列侬的样带，保罗也思索过，“我们是不是不应该这样做？”但每当他这么想时，他总会打断自己，假设自己如有机会问列侬——“嘿，列侬，你希望我们完成你的这首歌吗？”——列侬的回答会是什么，而他相信，列侬一定会说，“当然！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，歌曲的制作并不如预想的那般顺利，当时还没有可以将人声与伴奏声分离的技术。在某种程度上，列侬的声音其实是被隐藏了。每当他们想要将列侬的声音调得更加清晰，钢琴的伴奏声也会随之增大，效果实际上变得更差了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们感到挫败，“我们有点失去时间和动力。”保罗说，似乎他们应该放弃这首歌。 “事情无法进展，也让列侬已经不在这个事实，在我们眼前越来越清晰。”林戈说。就这样，《Now&amp;nbsp;And Then》被搁置了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到时间来到2022年。在此之前，《指环王》导演彼得·杰克逊的团队开发了一项基于人工智能的技术，它可以将特定的人声与伴奏声分离并进行修复。而这项技术，在2021年彼得·杰克逊为披头士乐队制作的纪录片《Get Back》中被证明是成功的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过技术的帮助，列侬的声音再次从播放器中传了出来，“如水晶般清透”。 “我们几乎等待了四分之一个世纪，直到这一刻，能够再次制作《Now And Then》。”保罗说。他打电话给林戈，告诉他自己想要继续完成这首歌的制作，林戈欣然赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了列侬的钢琴伴奏，保罗还加入了自己的贝斯部分，林戈也在此基础上加进了自己的鼓点。他们保留了乔治在1995年的吉他演奏部分，“这是对乔治的一种致敬。”保罗说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在已故的披头士乐队制作人乔治∙马丁的儿子吉尔斯∙马丁的帮助下，弦乐部分也加入进来。在进行这一部分的录制时，为了保密，他们并没有告诉演奏的弦乐团这是一首新的披头士乐曲，而是假装成保罗自己的新单曲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“所有的那些回忆都涌了上来，我的天啊，能有这些人出现在我的生命中，我是多么幸运……在2023年还仍然在做披头士乐队的音乐，哇！”保罗感叹道，“《Now And Then》应该是我们最后一首歌了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“时不时地想起我，老朋友”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1964年2月，披头士乐队首次前往美国演出。伴随着他们起飞的，是希思罗机场挥手送别的四千多名粉丝；迎接他们降落的，又是另一批约三千人的接机队伍。当年9日，披头士在埃德·沙利文秀上进行电视直播表演，吸引了约7300万名观众观看，这大概占到美国人口的34%，英伦摇滚的流行风暴以前所未有的力度席卷美国. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那也几乎是披头士乐队最如日中天的几年。然而，分离与死亡，过早降临于他们之间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在披头士乐队最后一次公开合体演出的同年9月，列侬在与林戈、保罗及他们的经纪人艾伦∙克莱恩的一次会面中，通知他的乐队成员们，他打算退出披头士乐队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时的他们，因商业、创作、感情等诸多方面的原因，摩擦与分歧已日渐严重，解散似乎只是时间问题。在那次会面中，乔治缺席了，克莱恩说服其他乐队成员对解散一事保持沉默，因为一些重要的商业事务还在进行中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隔年4月10日，保罗公开宣布自己退出披头士乐队，这也被看作是披头士乐队解散的标志事件。那时，距离他们成立刚好十年，一位美国媒体人更声称其为“大英帝国衰落的里程碑”。在被问及他的离开是暂时还是永久，保罗回答，“我真的不知道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年以后，在一次媒体采访中，保罗否认是自己促使乐队解散。由于克莱恩的要求，他们得对乐队解散一事守口如瓶，有几个月不得不假装一切正常。他只是“受够了隐瞒”，最终，“将猫从袋子里放了出来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在之后的时间里，哪怕披头士乐队已各自发展，但乐迷心中仍有余念，期待某一天，他们又将合体。然而，列侬的去世，却直接将这种希望击得粉碎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1980年12月8日，列侬完成了当天的工作后，与妻子小野洋子一同返回住处。两人从车上下来，步行前往达科他公寓的大楼入口。就在这时，25岁的马克∙大卫∙查普曼出现了，他朝着列侬连开了五枪，列侬永远地停止了心跳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对于每个希望披头士能持续存在的人来说，谋杀是另一回事。这是一场暗杀，是对某种难以名状的东西的仪式性杀戮，也许是希望，也许是理想主义，或是时间。它不仅是失去，而且是突然错位、支离破碎。”评论家杰伊·考克斯在当年的《时代》杂志封面文章里写道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隔年2月，音乐人卡尔∙帕金斯为保罗写了一首歌《My Old Friend》。完成的第二天早上，卡尔拿着吉他，坐在保罗旧的双混响放大器上，为他演唱了这首歌：“如果我们此生难以再见……我的老朋友，你会不会时不时地想起我……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保罗和他的妻子琳达坐在地板上聆听。唱完歌，卡尔发现，保罗哭了。之后，他起身离开房间。琳达向他解释，“自从列侬发生那件事后，他就一直无法真正崩溃……可是你怎么知道的呢？”她说，列侬生前在达科他大楼的走廊里对保罗说的最后一句话正是——当时他拍了拍保罗的肩膀，说：“时不时地（now and then）想起我，老朋友。”&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“玩好乐队的关键就是化学反应，我们四个性格大相径庭的人组合成为披头士，是非常特别的。当失去约翰的时候，我们知道，这一切真的已经结束了。”保罗说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2001年，他们又一次体会挚友离世的痛苦，这一次是另一名披头士成员乔治∙哈里森，他因癌症不幸去世。 “失去了乔治，这就像我们在航海途中没有了风。”保罗说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隔年11月，由乔治的遗孀奥莉维亚和他的儿子达尼∙哈里森组织的纪念音乐会在伦敦皇家阿尔伯特音乐厅举办，保罗和林戈等好友纷纷turn up.演出结束前，保罗走到话筒旁，说：“当达尼站在台上时，就像是我们已经老了，但乔治依然年轻。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样年轻的或许还有他们的音乐。 2023年11月10日，凭借《Now And Then》这首歌，披头士乐队再次登顶英国音乐排行榜榜首，这是他们的第18首冠军单曲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它不仅延续了披头士在英国官方排行榜历史上拥有最多冠军单曲的纪录，也使他们成为历史上第一次和最后一次登上排行榜冠军间隔时间最长的乐队——这首歌，距离他们第一首登顶的冠军单曲《From Me to You》，已过去了整整六十年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生陈荃新对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁老人状告保姆：虐待自己还骗走200万养老钱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQyy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQyy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258602&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;保姆虐待案&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢俊杰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“被告2是谁，我都搞不清楚，”面对法官的询问，沈一南坐在写有“被告代理人”的席位，面带疑惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“被告2是你爹，”律师见状出言提醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述略显荒诞的一幕发生在一起赠与合同纠纷案的庭前会议。 2023年11月7日，上海市黄浦区人民法院就该案进行证据交换。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈一南的母亲卢德麟是原告，家中保姆蒋爱珍为被告1，沈一南的父亲沈宗礼为被告2。根据民事起诉状，沈宗礼曾“赠与”保姆蒋爱珍200万元，现卢德麟要求返还；同时卢德麟状告遭保姆蒋爱珍虐待，要求对方支付精神损害赔偿20万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈一南“搞不清楚”的原因在于这引发的不是单一案件，民事的合同纠纷与刑事案件都在程序进行中。相关法律文书显示，卢德麟被虐待案已在上海市公安局黄浦分局刑事立案，目前刑事案件正在办理中。沈一南多年来生活在国外，对中文环境理解不足，且每年固定回上海探亲从2019年底开始因新冠疫情持续中断了3年。 During this period, the nanny Jiang Aizhen lived in the house to take care of Lu Delin and Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年6月29日，上海94岁老人卢德麟实名在网络发布第一条视频，称自己遭到保姆虐待、养老金被保姆转走。此后，该账号发布多条视频，卢德麟出镜讲述自己的遭遇：“我也就活着一口气了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是个例。就在交换证据当天，上海的一则类似新闻再次冲上热搜。一保姆称照护的老人要将房产过户给自己，“不是我主动，是叔叔要给我”，视频中保姆在办理窗口解释。工作人员发现存在不妥后中止过户流程并报警。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市卫健委日前披露，截至2022年底，全上海60岁及以上户籍老年人有553.66万，占户籍总人口的36.8%。在重度老龄化的现代都市中，如何体面养老，老年人的居家照料问题正引起全社会的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7日下午的法院现场，蒋爱珍没有到，法官表示，法庭会公告送达，预计两个月后再次传唤蒋爱珍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;卢德麟卧室，儿媳沈艾伦已找保洁重新打扫&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（韩茹雪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;94岁老夫妻的晚年生活&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;推开眼前紧闭的门，首先飘来的是一股酸味。这房子看起来应该通风良好，户型方方正正，望进去是客厅的另一边，阳台宽，窗户大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是上海市黄浦区丽园新村斜土路118弄某栋2401。脏乱的另一面，是这栋房子自身的不菲价值。这个小区共有4栋楼，均为高层，位于上海市中心地段，临近多条地铁、公交线路，生活方便。相关资料显示，这栋小区建于20世纪90年代初，目前二手房市场挂出的价格每平米超过10万元人民币。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在该小区物业工作多年的夏师傅告诉《南方人物周刊》，小区里老人多，都是“有身份的体面人”，雇佣钟点工或住家保姆很普遍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;眼前的这套房子属于一对老夫妇，卢德麟和老伴沈宗礼，两人今年均已94岁，退休多年。卢德麟患有脊髓炎，下半身瘫痪在床；沈宗礼如今一只眼睛失明，一只眼睛只剩0.25的视力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两人的独生子沈一南，定居美国数十年，亲戚基本都在国外生活。两人都曾去过美国，帮着儿子照顾孙辈，但每次签证时长最多只有半年。几次往返，两人年事愈高，慢慢只得留在这所房子里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，这栋房子正空置。 2023年6月29日，卢德麟实名在网络发布第一条视频，称自己遭到保姆蒋爱珍虐待、养老金被保姆转走。目前卢德麟、沈宗礼已被儿子沈一南、儿媳沈艾伦接走，安置在杭州。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈艾伦打开房门，一一展示房中布置，这些生活痕迹她都小心拍照、编号、留存，在案件侦查阶段，多份证据都由此而来。客厅一角的桌上堆着袋装木耳、黄花菜、菌菇等等补品、山货，琳琅满目，有十多种。站在一侧的沈艾伦说，这栋房子她已经找清洁人员里里外外重新打扫过，目前能闻到的酸臭已是不多的残余，那些补品“是剩下的，扔掉的更多，很多已经过期了，保姆不做给老人吃”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个家原本是“稳定体面”的，卢德麟、沈宗礼每月的退休金均在一万元以上，加上固定的理财利息，每月额外有8000元左右的收入。名下除了在住的这套房子，之前还有另外一处房产，前两年拆迁后拿到了一笔不菲的赔偿金，经济方面生活无虞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿子沈一南每年固定回国探亲，“7年总共586天，平均每年84天”，自2013年至2019年，沈艾伦一一整理好这些护照中的出入境记录。但这样的联系被突然的新冠疫情打破，2019年11月29日离开中国后，超过3年的时间，沈一南没能回来，直到2023年2月23日才再度见到父母。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height=&quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈儿子回国时间记录表&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3年里，生活在这套房子里的是两位老人，和保姆蒋爱珍。同单元的邻居告诉《南方人物周刊》，前几年自家和卢德麟家有来往，偶尔做点吃的送一下，但后来不再去她家里走动，“（卢德麟）家味道太重，下不去脚。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厨房在进门右手边，发霉长毛的菜板、罐子散在台面；进门左手边是浴室，几平方米的小浴室贴着白色瓷砖，这是翻新过的，包括花洒、马桶等，翻新花费几万元。账单来自保姆蒋爱珍，其中花洒价钱备注4000块，“实际只要400块”，沈艾伦从物业处打听到这个细节——花洒的安装有物业参与。夏师傅在该小区物业工作多年，向《南方人物周刊》记者证实了这个数额的出入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height=&quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258601&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;保姆经手装修翻新后的浴室，图中花洒被标注花费4000元&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（韩茹雪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了卧室，腐臭的味道更加明显。卢德麟下身瘫痪，一直在卧室内一个椅子状的马桶上解决大小便。床单被罩已经更换，溢满白色粉末的床垫收在一边的箱子里，沈艾伦打开给记者看，正是卢德麟此前几年卧床一直使用的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公公沈宗礼的衬衣也被保管起来了，领口处有大片发黄、发黑的污渍，这些“都是证据”。在这个不熟悉的空间里，沈艾伦小心搜集着过去的痕迹，决心与保姆蒋爱珍打官司。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;早已埋下的矛盾&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;卢德麟一家最早跟保姆蒋爱珍接触，是在2013年，经由楼上的邻居王维介绍，当时蒋在附近一带做钟点工。到2017年，蒋爱珍成为卢德麟家长期、固定的钟点工。王维称是因为“小蒋做得好”，沈艾伦称是因为蒋爱珍找工作四处碰壁，向卢德麟老两口哭诉，才获得这份工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相处日久，在新冠疫情肆虐的3年时间里，卢德麟夫妇由蒋爱珍居家看护，无旁人照看。直到卢德麟发布视频，称遭保姆虐待、被骗养老金等，冲突爆发在大众视野。此前的漫长时间里，这家人与保姆的矛盾早已埋下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height=&quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258603&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;卢德麟老师此前数年使用的被褥，霉臭味重&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（韩茹雪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初，蒋爱珍每天到家做两小时钟点工，老两口每月支付6000元费用。 2022年3月，蒋爱珍搬进这所房子，从钟点工变成了住家保姆，薪水涨到了每个月12000元。沈艾伦告诉《南方人物周刊》，蒋爱珍在拿这份薪水的同时，还在其他4个地方同时做钟点工。在这点上，她觉得保姆没有契约精神，“已经支付了全部的住家保姆的薪水，怎么还能再去外面上别的班？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方人物周刊》记者走访了解到，目前卢德麟所在的上海黄浦区，钟点工一个小时的薪资是45元左右，在晚间高峰时段会上涨到50元左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小区所属桑城居委会工作人员告诉《南方人物周刊》，这个价钱是钟点工还是全职住家保姆，要看雇主和保姆是怎么具体协商的。从居委会的登记来看，只要晚上在雇主家里过夜，那就属于住家保姆，蒋爱珍的确一直以住家保姆的身份登记在册。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样也长期雇佣钟点工的介绍人王维不认为12000元是一种“买断”价，两个老人、不能自理，肯定要加钱，保姆再打别的工是正常of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方人物周刊》记者以卢德麟老两口的现状向当地的三家家政机构咨询，它们均表示12000元的价格是全职住家保姆价格，属于“买断价”，阿姨不应该再去做别的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中一家家政机构成立于2014年，总部位于广州，在上海、深圳均有分公司，通过员工制的方式，向客户提供全职住家保姆，每个阿姨都经过背景调查，她们的日常情况被公司用管家模式监督。这家公司会通过管家做定期回访，属于同类机构中重视监管的一家。即便如此，阿姨的好坏仍依赖于客户的主动反馈。在家人常年不在身边的情况下，老人被迫依赖于单个保姆，“这类反馈相对困难，可以说是空白的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258600&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;卢德麟老两口厨房中日常使用的菜板&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（韩茹雪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金钱之外，是无法计算的“情分”。新冠疫情期间，两位老人由蒋爱珍一人看护，推上推下排队做核酸，是居委会看在眼里的。照顾得好与不好、是否有虐待，那是“关在门里的事”，居委会和一些邻居均以此为由，表达自己的不知情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在沈一南夫妇回国后，蒋爱珍多次声称自己“救了老人命”，拿出沈宗礼手写签名的“证明”和“委托书”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;落款日期为2022年9月1日的一份委托书显示：“我们百年以后现在的住处由蒋爱珍住在这里。由蒋爱珍为我们养老送终。我们的骨灰先放在家里，最后丢进黄浦江。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同日的另一份“证明”中，沈宗礼表示赠予蒋爱珍“一百万元”；2023年3月3日的一份“证明”中，赠予蒋爱珍的金额涨至“两百万元”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅仅是纸面承诺，2022年8月22日和2023年2月7日，沈宗礼的个人账户分别转账100万元到蒋爱珍账户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3张纸，对应200万元人民币和房子的居住权，都给了保姆蒋爱珍。老人是否清醒、自愿，赠与是否合法、有效，问题最终交给了法庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;找证据&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“当时谁在场？”法官多次询问以确认这个关键问题，指向的就是最新一份赠与合同——2023年3月3日沈宗礼手写给保姆蒋爱珍200万元的“证明”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒋爱珍没有到庭，沈一南与沈艾伦向法官讲述经过：蒋爱珍拿出一份证明，落款有卢德麟、沈宗礼、沈一南，要卢德麟和沈一南在相应位置签名，遭两人拒绝，当时沈艾伦在场，也制止。当时以为事情了结，沈一南与沈艾伦离家外出办事，等再回到上海，才得知“证明”其实早就写好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被制止的证明落款为2023年3月9日，实际上，早在一周前，即2023年3月3日，蒋爱珍就拿到了有沈宗礼签名的“证明”。沈艾伦发现沈宗礼的支付宝被人注册，找人用技术手段恢复了老人手机的数据，发现了一段蒋爱珍录制的视频，视频内容是沈宗礼手写赠与保姆200万的证明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年9月1日的委托书显示：“我们百年以后现在的住处由蒋爱珍住在这里。由蒋爱珍为我们养老送终。我们的骨灰先放在家里，最后丢进黄浦江。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢德麟代理律师周兆成提供的一份录音资料显示，居委会一值班律师表示，蒋爱珍曾多次用轮椅推沈宗礼到居委会值班律师处咨询。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月3日，蒋爱珍拿到沈宗礼手写签字的证明。为了保证这“200万元”的赠与合法有效，一周后，她再次拿出一份证明，落款在沈宗礼之外加入了“卢德麟沈一南”，这份证明是沈一南、沈艾伦印象中唯一亲眼见到过的“赠与”证明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前的赠与100万元、赠与200万元、让保姆住在房子里的3份证明，沈一南都是在网上看到保姆方发出来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258599&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年3月3日，沈宗礼手写给保姆蒋爱珍200万元的“证明”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈宗礼是掌握家庭“账户”的人，此前的证明都是他手写的。沈艾伦称保姆对待沈宗礼、卢德麟方式是不同的，“知道哪个该哄着，用这样的洗脑方式骗走了老人的钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初，一家人对保姆是信任的。第一次发现不对劲，是有次沈艾伦给公婆邮寄食品，讲电话时发现公婆没有收到、且不知情，而此前沈艾伦给老人手机发了消息讲过此事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“保姆会删除聊天记录，”这个答案是沈艾伦安装摄像头后找到的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月，因新冠疫情而分离约3年后，沈艾伦再次踏入2401的房门。婆婆卢德麟让她看看脚，说感觉坑坑洼洼的，沈艾伦发现脚趾甲被“剪坏了”，她意识到不对劲。沈艾伦去查账，发现公婆的账户上有200万元被转到了蒋爱珍名下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从轮椅到墙面，沈艾伦偷偷安装了7个微型摄像头，用于“监视”保姆，夫妇俩假称回美国，想看看自己不在的时候，保姆有没有好好照顾老人.丈夫告诉她，这是为了取证，一定要把脾气忍住，不管看见什么，以保留证据为首要目的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是第二天，沈艾伦还是和蒋爱珍吵架了。她回忆，蒋爱珍讲话有一个习惯，有点像老师训小孩子的感觉，“你怎么回事，你怎么回事”的口头禅不断，“听得我脑袋瓜嗡嗡的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矛盾很快爆发到台面。有天中午，婆婆卢德麟说想吃螃蟹，让沈艾伦做，沈艾伦说让阿姨（指蒋爱珍）做，蒋爱珍说自己不吃螃蟹，不会做。 “当时我就想骂她，但我忍住了，”沈艾伦继续回忆，“保姆就问我婆婆怎么做，我婆婆让她问我，她问我的时候还很正常，然后我说，你刚刚不是问我妈了吗？你按照我妈说的方法做就可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耐心似乎是突然消失的，蒋爱珍一下子不乐意了，音量陡然变大，“你妈让我问你，你让我问你妈，我真搞不懂你们了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这句话一出，沈艾伦压不住火了，“我真的是从祖宗十八代就开始骂她了，我说你不要这么跟我俩讲话，有一天我让你哭，你给我滚出去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时蒋爱珍还不知道家里安装摄像头的事，但沈艾伦已经通过录像看到了保姆平时的行为，这让她难以接受，“她把所有的气撒到了我婆婆身上，嗓子都骂破音了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看完摄像头拍下的一些画面，睡在公婆家的那晚，沈艾伦害怕蒋爱珍从厨房拿刀做出极端事情，就把厨房里大的、小的几把刀都收走，放到房间，反锁了门，又把其中一把刀放在枕头下面，以备意外之需。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;关于&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;蒋爱珍&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的两种说法&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;虐待、骗钱、极端行为的背面，是“介绍人”王维的另一种说法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王维也听过200万元赠与的事情，她同样看到了网上视频流传的“虐待”画面。但她始终认为保姆做得没问题：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“网上看到的视频，一个是动作比较粗鲁，其实拉老人起床就是这样，我家以前也有老人，小蒋也是这么拉起来。小蒋也是快60岁的人了，只是钟点工，没有受过护理方面的专业培训，只能这样。我们习惯了，在我们家也是这样的动作，阿姨凶是凶的，嘴巴也是有点说话不客气的，她脾气性格就是这样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“还有就是脚趾甲剪出血，剪的是灰指甲，剪灰指甲是肯定要出血的。被褥发霉肯定和小蒋没关系，这是卢老师他们老两口的个人习惯。他们家的习惯就是说，进了他们家的东西，没有垃圾，全是宝，什么东西都不扔的，用过的卫生纸都要晒干了继续用……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个楼里面雇佣小蒋的，都是王维介绍过去的，她称出问题的只有卢德麟一家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蒋爱珍是早先保安介绍的钟点工，2012年开始就在王维家做。 “在这次儿媳妇回到上海之前，卢老师一家和保姆关系很好，他们说这个保姆是自己的干女儿，幸亏有保姆，不然自己命也没了。儿媳妇回来了，一切都反过来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王维告诉《南方人物周刊》，200万元这笔钱是分两次给蒋爱珍的，都是有原因的：第一次是因为疫情封控，当时一段时间几乎每天做核酸，保姆一个人天天推上推下，就靠她一个人；还有一次是沈老先生的一套房子动迁了，他说就凭他一个老人没有办法去交涉，全是他委托这个保姆去搞的，最后好像拿到了一些钱。沈老先生说“如果不是阿姨帮他去搞的话，他拿不到这么多”，最后还得要小蒋给自己养老送终。当时处在疫情封控期间，也不知道儿子什么时候回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这两件事，在沈艾伦眼中是另一种情形。身体照护方面，沈艾伦称，2020年5月，有次老人肺炎住院，蒋爱珍照护，但是按一天300元的价钱付给保姆额外薪水，这是契约，并非“情分或帮忙”；房屋拆迁方面，是保姆没有做好，拆迁款比应得的少拿了很多……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，由沈一南、沈艾伦照护的卢德麟、沈宗礼均在视频中要求蒋爱珍还钱。未被接走前，老人和保姆共处的时候，《南方人物周刊》获取了一段录音，是2023年3月22日保姆蒋爱珍和沈宗礼因钱的问题有过的对话：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保姆：“全部钱全都转走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈宗礼：“我的钱要留着的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保姆：“留着的你放在我这里不是一样的吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈宗礼：“两样的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保姆：“我就要就要。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈宗礼：“你欺负我啊。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“保姆管家”的无奈&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;给保姆钱是不是自愿？沈宗礼的答案前后不一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初他说是自愿赠与，直到后来看到保姆取钱的流水、录音、录像，他才改了口。相关录音录像显示，保姆亲口承认多取了老人账户的7万元钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈艾伦告诉《南方人物周刊》，沈宗礼自称多次被保姆告知，自己的钱放在保姆账户是一样的，需要的话随时可以支取。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠疫情3年，沈艾伦只回国一次，当时准备去看望公婆，但在隔离酒店收到婆婆写来的字条，上面写着“不要回”。考虑到当时怕传染，沈艾伦没有返回2401。事后，卢德麟告诉沈艾伦，字条是保姆授意写的，“被逼的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3年时间里，“保姆管家”成为2401的主题，连打交道的“外人”都看在眼inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物业的夏师傅告诉《南方人物周刊》，两个老人生活不能自理，下楼均要保姆陪同，保姆一直在身边，老人就算想说些什么也说不出来。平时两位老人在家，无亲属照看，只有卢德麟的学生偶尔会来，但“毕竟不是家属，很多话也不能说，他们一家都是体面人，要面子的，不好说的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;附近的一家连锁修脚店是保姆蒋爱珍和沈宗礼会定期去的。店员称呼沈宗礼为“大白兔”，因为他爱吃大白兔奶糖，有时候会一次吃好几块。沈艾伦打开手机购物APP，有多次的大白兔奶糖购买记录，都是邮寄到2401。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;店员称他们一家的情况为“保姆管家”：保姆带着大白兔来，大白兔修脚、保姆也修脚，做一样的项目，付钱的时候是保姆付钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这样的保姆很少见，”店员回想起保姆蒋爱珍的举动，一方面觉得她凶、有权，另一方面是每次都是保姆一个人带着老先生来，别家往往是子女家属陪同。就在记者采访这天，这家修脚店接待了一位103岁的老人，是由外甥女陪着来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从小区出发，相隔几百米有家馄饨店，蒋爱珍有时带卢德麟夫妇来吃饭。这次回国后，馄饨店老板曾私下告诉沈艾伦，“快把你家保姆辞了吧。”记者向老板了解，证实了这一点，“没见过别的保姆讲话这么凶的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;像卢德麟夫妇这样年纪的老人，在这个小区还有很多。桑城居委会工作人员告诉《南方人物周刊》，家属时不时来看望是普遍现象，独留保姆一人照顾则比较罕见。此前，居委会在闻讯后曾试图调解，但保姆没来，“保姆一直没有出现过。我们居委会也不能代表哪一级政府或者相关部门，不能强制传唤保姆到场，我们做不到，我们没有那个权力。还有就是，在保姆缺席或者不在场的情况下，我们也建议他们走司法途径，去法院或者公安报案都可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在该居委会工作多年的工作人员告诉《南方人物周刊》，平时碰到过保姆蒋爱珍，在打个照面的接触中，没有感受到“虐待”相关事情。但很多事情是关起门来的，没有谁会在大庭广众下去做怎样过分的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不会是个例。上海是全国老龄化程度最高的超大型城市。据2022年上海市老年人口和老龄事业监测统计信息公布的数据，2022年上海户籍的60岁及以上老年人口有553.66万，占户籍总人口的36.8%，其中，独居老年人为30.06万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是否被虐待、是否被骗，长达3年的“保姆管家”，直到矛盾大爆发、冲上热搜，很多邻居才在手机上看到这则消息。此前有的邻居曾在业主群看到过儿媳控诉保姆蒋爱珍的消息，而更多的邻居对此一无所知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中人物沈一南、沈艾伦、王维为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“清朗·网络戾气整治”专项行动启动，打击网络厕所、开盒挂人等行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;各省、自治区、直辖市党委网信办，新疆生产建设兵团党委网信办：&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;按照2023年“清朗”系列专项行动总体安排，中央网信办决定即日起在全国范围内启动为期1个月的“清朗·网络戾气整治” Special action.现将有关事项通知如下。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一、明确工作目标&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;聚焦网络戾气容易滋生的重点环节版块，从严打击恶意攻击谩骂、挑起群体对立、宣泄极端情绪等突出问题，坚决惩治一批违规账号、群组和网站平台，有力遏制网络戾气传播扩散。 By carrying out special rectification, further compact the main responsibility of the website platform, in -depth search of the loopholes of problems, improve the institutional mechanism of preventing the governance of the network of gas, effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of the majority of netizens, and safeguard the good network ecology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二、集中整治7类突出问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;专项行动围绕社交、短视频、直播等重点平台类型，坚决打击以下7方面问题：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1.“网络厕所”“开盒挂人&quot;Behavior.创建专门的BOT账号、贴吧、话题、群组等，通过匿名投稿、隔空喊话等方式，接收并发布针对特定群体或个人的嘲讽讥笑、恶意评价、诅咒谩骂信息。 &quot;Open the box&quot; and &quot;hanging people&quot; in the name of disclosure and criticism, and disclose personal privacy information such as other people&#39;s names, ID numbers, mobile phone numbers, family address, work unit, personal photo, social account number and other personal privacy, incite netizens to attack and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.借社会热点事件恶意诋毁、造谣攻击。 Rumors and stigma of the parties related to emergencies, or pictures and videos that are seriously inconsistent with the facts that are seriously inconsistent with the facts, induced netizens to question the parties. Using the image of the hotspots, the parties to produce emoticons, use AI software to synthesize false pictures or videos such as vulgar pornography, bloody horror, etc., to make rumors and spoof it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.污名化特定群体、煽动地域对立。将个别恶性社会事件、负面人物与性别、职业、地域等特征相关联，对特定群体污名化、打负面标签，发布性别对立、阶层对立、地域歧视言论，进行泛化攻击，激化社会矛盾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.斗狠PK等低俗不良直播行为。 Internet anchors use bravely fighting, PK drinking, abusive vomiting and other behaviors to drain powder. During the live broadcast of others, use the functions of barrage, Lianmai to perform personal attacks, and even encourage extreme behaviors such as suicide and self -harm. Forming violent conflict scripts such as fighting and fighting, attracting netizens onlookers and disturbing public order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.有组织地恶意辱骂举报他人。以“帮忙做事”“解忧解气”等名义，提供有偿代骂服务，对特定账号进行留言辱骂、私信攻击。组织粉丝群体使用平台“举报”“反黑”等功能，恶意批量举报他人。发布娱乐、体育、电竞等领域拉踩引战、恶意炒作言论，诱导粉丝互撕谩骂、刷量控评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.编造网络黑话、恶意造梗。通过拼音、谐音、指代词等方式，恶意编造低俗烂梗、不良流行语，污染网络风气。使用污言秽语、粗口脏话，故意挑起矛盾、制造对立冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.煽动网上极端情绪。编造耸人听闻的帖文标题，发布无中生有、毫无底线的“泄愤帖”。恶意夸大师生矛盾，渲染家长“压迫”“压榨”孩子，挑起关系对立，对未成年人形成不良导向。刻意渲染消极负面、焦虑怨愤情绪，散布仇视对立言论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三、依法严惩违规账号、群组和平台&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;专项行动期间要坚持重拳出击，集中关闭一批严重违规、影响恶劣的账号群组，坚决取缔一批戾气聚集、&lt;/span>;问题突出的功能版块，从严查处一批履责不力、顶风作案的网站平台，形成有力震慑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.从严查处违规账号、群组、贴吧。深入排查高风险账号、群组，坚决取缔以“网络厕所”“开盒挂人”“拉踩引战”等为主题的账号、群组，严肃查处组织斗狠PK、直播约架的主播账号，从严惩治发布“标题党”内容故意煽动网络戾气的“自媒体”账号，集中关闭一批以侮辱性词汇命名、网络戾气扎堆的圈子、超话、贴吧，下架关闭提供有偿代骂等服务的商家店铺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.从严查处违规功能设置。强化直播弹幕、连麦、PK等重点功能管理，坚决清理处置网络戾气内容。 Concentrate to cancel a batch of functional applications for maliciously reporting.禁止通过“相关推荐”“TA关注”“可能感兴趣的人”等功能向用户推送“网络厕所”类账号。 Strengthen the review and management of functions such as emoticons, P -picture puzzles, video editing, AI synthesis and other functions, and clean up emoji, pictures and videos that contain spoof attacks and provoke opposition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.从严查处违规平台环节。督&lt;span>;促网站平台加强榜单、话题、推荐、评论、私信等环节管理，严禁在榜单、推荐等位置推送煽动、宣扬网络戾气的内容，通过设置“私信折叠”“消息盒子”等减少陌生人私信骚扰。对于存在突出问题的网站、APP、小程序，依法采取限期整改、罚款、暂停相关功能、关停下架等处置处罚措施。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四、细化工作要求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1.抓好部署推进。结合本地实际，制定细化实施方案，配齐配强工作力量，狠抓任务部署落实，视情组织对网站平台治理效果进行评估，督促做好整改落实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.压实平台责任。指导属地网站平台全面排查问题漏洞，聚焦重点环节、版块和功能，深入开展自查自纠，完善内容管理机制，确保专项行动取得实效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.强化宣传曝光。公布&lt;span>;专项行动启动、阶段性进展，重点平台每周公布典型案例。加强教育引导，鼓励网民积极参与举报投诉，共同抵制网络戾气。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;中央网信办秘书局&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年11月10日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>