<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[透视我国增发2023年国债1万亿元的深意]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the 24th, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted to adopt the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress The resolution approving the State Council’s additional issuance of treasury bonds and the 2023 central budget adjustment plan clarifies that the central government will issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of 2023 treasury bonds in the fourth quarter of this year. What is the purpose of issuing additional national bonds in 2023? Where will the additional national debt be used? How to manage trillions of yuan in national debt funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why additional issuance: A necessary move to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and improve disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since this year, many places in our country have suffered from heavy rains, floods, Disasters such as typhoons have severely affected some areas and caused heavy losses, and local post-disaster recovery and reconstruction tasks are relatively heavy. At the same time, various types of extreme natural disasters have occurred frequently in recent years, placing higher demands on my country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on August 17 to study and deploy flood prevention and disaster relief and post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. The meeting proposed &quot;accelerating recovery and reconstruction&quot; and &quot;further improving my country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These key tasks cannot be separated from the guarantee of &quot;real money&quot;. The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that although the budget at the beginning of the year had arranged relevant regular disaster relief and disaster prevention and reduction funds, it was difficult to meet the needs of improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Liu Yi, director of the Department of Finance at Peking University School of Economics, by combining factors such as resolving local government debt risks and ensuring &quot;three guarantees&quot; expenditures, local governments have more room to significantly increase funding arrangements in related fields through their own financial resources. Small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The issuance of additional treasury bonds in 2023 is a major decision-making arrangement made by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, and an important measure to implement the people-centered development idea.” The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that with strong funds Ensure the implementation of relevant work, focus on supporting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and make up for shortcomings in disaster prevention, reduction, and relief, and overall improve our country&#39;s ability to withstand natural disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From an international perspective, many countries will also make some budget adjustments in the middle of the year based on the actual situation of economic and social development.” Shi Yinghua, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Fiscal Sciences, said that based on the disaster situation in our country this year, the central government The government&#39;s issuance of additional national debt and budget adjustments are pragmatic moves that reflect the guidance of the government&#39;s efforts to ensure key expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to use: All funds from the additional treasury bonds issued in the fourth quarter will be allocated to local governments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is understood that combined with the needs of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and disaster prevention, reduction and relief work , and to coordinate fiscal affordability, the central government will issue an additional 1,000 billion yuan in 2023 national debt in the fourth quarter, and arrange all of it to local governments through transfer payments. Among them, 500 billion yuan is planned to be used this year and 500 billion yuan will be carried forward for use next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The central government issued additional treasury bonds, but all the specific funds were used locally. This helped ease the pressure on local fiscal revenue and expenditure, further optimized the fiscal expenditure structure, and further optimized the debt structure.” Shi Yinghua explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of use of funds, according to the Ministry of Finance, the funds will be used in eight major areas: post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, key flood control projects, natural disaster emergency response capacity improvement projects, other key flood control projects, irrigation area construction and renovation, and key water and soil projects. Loss control projects, urban drainage and flood prevention capacity improvement actions, key natural disaster comprehensive prevention and control system construction projects, and high-standard farmland construction in Northeast China and disaster-stricken areas in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This fund use arrangement spans this year and next, reflecting the continuity of the policy. The direction of fund use takes into account both the present and the long term. While supporting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and ensuring people&#39;s livelihood, it also focuses on making up for shortcomings. , strengths and weaknesses, and strengthen long-term capacity building to resist natural disasters, which is conducive to promoting high-quality development.&quot; Shi Yinghua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The additional treasury bonds will be issued in the fourth quarter of this year. &quot;We will start the issuance of treasury bonds in a timely manner. At present, the Ministry of Finance has made adjustments to the treasury bond issuance plan for the fourth quarter to leave room for additional issuance of treasury bonds.&quot; The official said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Finance will work with relevant departments to strengthen project review and control and allocate funds to specific projects as soon as possible. The Ministry of Finance will also issue budgets for national debt projects in a timely manner to accelerate the formation of physical workload. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After the national debt funds are put into use, it will also help drive domestic demand and further consolidate the economic recovery.” Liu Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to manage: The central budget will be adjusted accordingly and funds from the additional issuance of government bonds will be included in the direct mechanism&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the issuance of additional government bonds, the central budget in 2023 will also be adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that central government expenditures at the same level will remain unchanged in 2023, and transfer payments from the central government to local governments will increase by 500 billion yuan compared with the budget at the beginning of the year; local general public budget expenditures will increase by 500 billion yuan accordingly, and the expenditure growth rate will increase from 5.2%. to 7.4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the fiscal deficit has also increased accordingly. In 2023, the national fiscal deficit will increase from 3.88 trillion yuan to 4.88 trillion yuan, the central fiscal deficit will increase from 3.16 trillion yuan to 4.16 trillion yuan, and the fiscal deficit rate is expected to increase from 3% to about 3.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, China’s government debt ratio has been lower than that of other major world economies. In Liu Yi&#39;s view, the Chinese government currently has room for additional issuance of treasury bonds, and the overall risk after this additional issuance is controllable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to manage and use trillions of yuan in national debt funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that in the next step, the direct mechanism will be fully utilized, all government bond expenditure funds will be included in the scope of direct fiscal funds, and the whole process tracking and monitoring will be implemented to ensure that the funds are used according to the prescribed purposes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We will also organize the local supervision bureaus of the Ministry of Finance to establish a normalized supervision mechanism, keep a close eye on the use of government bond funds, strictly investigate illegal activities such as misappropriation of government bond funds, and effectively prevent government debt risks.&quot; This said the person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京市委常委、副市长靳伟因北京长峰医院重大火灾事故被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259288]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:49:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;A few days ago, with the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission issued a Member and Vice Mayor Jin Wei initiated a case review and investigation into the issue of dereliction of duty and dereliction of duty during the &quot;4·18&quot; major fire accident at Changfeng Hospital in Fengtai, Beijing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, Comrade Jin Wei, as a member of the Standing Committee of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee and deputy mayor in charge of health work, has gaps in the implementation of the Party Central Committee’s instructions and requirements on production safety, which has a negative impact on Beijing. The health department’s safety management strength is weak and medical institutions’ fire safety hazards are outstanding. The city’s health and health department is urged to fulfill its responsibility of “managing safety in the industry” and medical institutions are not fully responsible for the main responsibility for safety production, which plays an important role in the occurrence of accidents. Leadership responsibilities should be held seriously accountable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In accordance with the &quot;Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishment for Public Employees&quot; and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided Comrade Jin Wei was given a political warning by the State Supervision Commission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“要么赢，要么死” 加沙至暗时刻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:03:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“Gaza is very dangerous, but my brother insists on going back. Because there is his wife and 4 children there—— The oldest is 13 years old and the youngest is only 1 year old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 23, 2023, Sharif, a Palestinian young man working in Guangzhou, sent his brother to the airport. His brother will fly directly from Guangzhou to Egypt and look for an opportunity to return to his hometown of Gaza when the port opens. There, the Israeli army, which has superior military strength, is launching a fierce attack. In live video footage, bombs fell from the sky and many houses were reduced to fragments and rubble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif told Southern Weekend reporters that it was his brother&#39;s own decision to go back and &quot;he had no choice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Israeli-Palestinian conflict escalates, a humanitarian crisis is unfolding in the Gaza Strip. As of October 24, this round of conflict between Palestine and Israel has killed more than 7,200 people on both sides. According to UNICEF news on the 24th, 2,360 children were killed in the Gaza Strip and another 5,364 children were injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the conflict broke out, the Israeli military has required residents of northern Gaza to move to the south within a time limit, otherwise they will be regarded as &quot;accomplices of terrorists.&quot; However, many Palestinians, including Sharif&#39;s family, remain in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to disclosures from multiple international rescue organizations, a total of 57 rescue trucks entered Gaza from October 21st to 23rd. But for the more than 2 million Gazans, this is undoubtedly a drop in the bucket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are blockades everywhere, how do we leave? Even if someone evacuates, they will be killed by air strikes on the road. More importantly, we don&#39;t want to leave our own land.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In Sharif&#39;s hometown of Beit Hanoun, residents&#39; houses were reduced to ruins after the bombing. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Sharif&#39;s hometown of Beit In Hanon, after the bombing, residents&#39; houses were reduced to ruins. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have seen three wars in Gaza, and this is the most difficult”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 19, Sharifou lost contact with his family in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif&#39;s home is in Beit Hanoun, a small town in northern Gaza, which is close to Israel and is known as a &quot;dangerous place.&quot; On the 19th, Sharifou saw from news reports that his hometown had been bombed. He then contacted his family many times, but the other party&#39;s mobile phone always reminded him that he was &quot;not in the service area.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn’t until 6 hours later that Sharifu contacted them again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to get in touch better, Sharifou bought an ESIM card for his parents. &quot;Just like an international roaming card, you can also use Israeli or Egyptian network services in Gaza.&quot; Sharifou added that such a card would not receive a signal all the time. When using it, people must stand at a high place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif comes from a merchant family in Gaza. For many years, he and his family traveled to Yiwu, Guangzhou and Gaza to trade in general merchandise such as candy, motorcycle parts, and home appliances. He and his brother have lived and worked in Guangzhou for many years, and his brother&#39;s two children also studied in Baiyun District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after arriving in China, Salifu told his parents that they must come to China one day. &quot;My father was originally going to attend the Canton Fair this year. However, the war changed everything.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week after the war broke out, Sharifo lost many relatives - &quot;My uncles and aunts passed away, their sons and grandchildren are gone, and the whole family disappeared together.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A week after the conflict began, Sharif lost his family, and his uncle&#39;s family was killed. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A week into the conflict, Sharifou lost Relatives, his uncle&#39;s family were unfortunately killed. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sharifo’s family members are also gathered together. His parents, 5 brothers, 2 sisters, and children of his brothers and sisters, totaling more than 50 people. &quot;A large family has left their home in northern Gaza and moved to a new location that &#39;cannot be disclosed.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2008, 2012, 2014, and 2021, Gaza has experienced &quot;wars.&quot; But this time it seems different. &quot;My family told me that this bombing was different from any previous one, and the sound sounded like a new weapon.&quot; Sharifou said, &quot;Stop the war. This is the only way to save them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Also in Gaza, 26-year-old Ismail is worried about his family&#39;s food rations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Late at night on October 23, Ismail sent a message for help to Annie, a Chinese friend who cared about him. He wanted to borrow $1,000 from Anne and promised to &quot;pay it back to you after the war is over.&quot; He and his family are currently in a settlement in a school in Gaza, but aid agencies have provided limited help. Food on the market is scarce and expensive, and must be traded in U.S. dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Annie told Southern Weekend reporters that Ismail studied abroad in a university in Zhejiang and understands Chinese. The two met by chance at a party. Not long before the conflict, Ismail had consulted her on how to handle the procedures for his brother, who had graduated from high school, to study in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Annie said that Ismail uses two mobile phone numbers on a daily basis, belonging to operators in Gaza and Israel. After the conflict broke out, communication facilities in Gaza were extensively damaged. Ismail barely got in touch with Anne through an Israeli mobile phone number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When I was contacted, his family was preparing to go to an evacuation site near their home. Because his family did not have a car, it was not practical for the whole family to evacuate on foot,&quot; said Anne. When asked how he was doing, Ismail replied in Chinese, &quot;Not dead yet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the day on October 24, Anne, who had raised the US dollars, contacted Ismail again, but received no reply. On the morning of October 25, I finally received news that Ismail was safe. According to his description, the fighting there was &quot;very, very severe&quot; and &quot;the sound of bombings and explosions did not stop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have seen three wars in Gaza before, and this is the hardest.&quot; He wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rescue is hampered at every turn&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“In Gaza, we never imagined such a scenario: 2 million civilians would live under heavy bombing and face interruptions in water, food, electricity and medicine. . We should take all measures immediately to avoid this situation from happening.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, local time, Fabrizio Carboni, Regional Director of the Near and Middle East of the International Committee of the Red Cross, said on social media Platform to speak out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After two weeks of Israel&#39;s sweeping siege, limited aid has finally arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public disclosures, three batches of humanitarian relief supplies entered the Gaza Strip from October 21st to 23rd local time, with a total of 57 trucks shipped. These include medical supplies, disinfectant chlorine tablets for water treatment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, these supplies are really a drop in the bucket for the more than 2 million people in the Gaza Strip. EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell said in a speech in Luxembourg on October 23 that under normal circumstances, if there is no war, 100 trucks enter Gaza every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Obviously, 20 (trucks) are not enough.&quot; Borrell called for more humanitarian support to be provided. In particular, fuel support will be provided so that power stations and desalination stations can be operated to &quot;restore water and electricity supplies&quot; as quickly as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tamara Alifa&#39;i, spokesperson for the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA), also said that Gaza&#39;s need for fuel is &quot;as urgent as its need for water and food.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite repeated warnings from international relief agencies, the Israeli side still puts the fuel on the embargo list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mark Regev, a senior adviser to the Israeli Prime Minister, publicly stated in an interview on October 23 that Israel would not allow fuel to enter the Gaza Strip even if all hostages were released. Regev explained the reason for the embargo, &quot;These fuels may be stolen by Hamas and used to power rockets.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the conflicts between the parties difficult to reconcile, the operation of hospitals in Gaza is in trouble. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The level of death, destruction and displacement is shocking.” On October 24, Christoph Hanger, public relations officer of the International Committee of the Red Cross, gave a written interview to a reporter from Southern Weekend The agency’s team in Gaza visited hospitals in the northern region on the ground, it said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People sleep in hospital stairwells. Thousands of people, with nowhere to go, seek shelter in hospitals. Building walls shake from nearby explosions. If the situation does not improve, there is no clean drinking water and crowded shelters, the potential for disease outbreaks increases dramatically,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shortages of electricity and fuel have put hospitals in Gaza in dire straits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Without electricity, the hospital will become a morgue.” Christopher said that after the power outage in Gaza, the hospital also stopped supplying power. Newborns in incubators and elderly patients who require oxygen are at risk. Kidney dialysis was interrupted and X-rays could not be taken. He pointed out that most hospitals in Gaza are no longer functioning and they need electricity to maintain their services. The hospital&#39;s situation has become even more difficult as insufficient fuel supplies have affected power generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A report from surgeons at Al Shifa Hospital in Gaza showed that they worked 24 hours a day to care for the wounded; when they tried to triage patients, they found that they could not cope with the large number of casualties, and &quot;the entire system was saturated.&quot; All operating theaters are occupied”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Doctors report that there is no precedent for such large-scale casualties in previous escalations of conflict.&quot; Christopher said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, a hospital in northern Gaza was bombed, causing some casualties. Gaza&#39;s health authorities and the Israeli Defense Ministry called each other the attackers. United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres later strongly condemned the deadly attacks on Gaza hospitals and said hospitals and medical personnel should be protected by international humanitarian law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Palestinian Red Crescent Society&#39;s disclosure on October 22, the area near the Holy City Hospital was heavily shelled that day. In the video released by it, at the moment of the attack, staff wearing Red Crescent uniforms rushed to find refuge on walls, pillars, ambulances and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;35 employees of the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East have been killed since the conflict broke out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are speechless.” UNRWA posted on social platforms on October 23, “We pay tribute to the 35 colleagues who were killed in Gaza since October 7. They Not just numbers. They are our friends and colleagues. Many are teachers in our schools.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Win or die&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After conflict breaks out, Israel cuts off Water and electricity supply to the Gaza Strip. On October 9, Israel announced a &quot;total blockade&quot; of the Gaza Strip controlled by Hamas and mobilized 300,000 reservists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the war imminent, Israel issued an &quot;expulsion order&quot; to the people of northern Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces informed the United Nations in the early morning of October 13 that it had notified approximately 1.1 million Palestinians in the northern Gaza Strip and required them to evacuate to southern Gaza within 24 hours. On the morning of the 14th, the Israel Defense Forces issued another notice, requiring residents in the northern Gaza Strip to evacuate through the &quot;evacuation corridor&quot; between 10 a.m. and 4 p.m. that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an orange paper leaflet printed with the IDF logo, the Israeli army issued a warning to the Gaza people. It read: &quot;Anyone who does not evacuate from the northern valley of Gaza to the south may be considered a member of a terrorist organization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Multiple Palestinians interviewed confirmed this to Southern Weekend reporters information. But they believe that not everyone will have convenient transportation to leave in a very short period of time. At the same time, the evacuation route is not safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video sent by Sharif, people evacuating in large tractor-trailer trucks were attacked on the way. On the open-air compartment that was originally filled with women, children, and children, only stumps and blood were left. In another video, in front of the evacuation road with cars, motorcycles, and donkey carts, yellow flames from bombs suddenly rose, and the vehicles turned around one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, both the south and north of Gaza were bombed.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guterres said before the Security Council’s closed-door consultation on the Palestinian-Israeli situation held on the 13th that more than 1 million residents would be moved from a completely besieged and densely populated war zone to an area without food, drinking water and Housing areas, which are &quot;extremely dangerous&quot; and in some cases &quot;impossible&quot;. He called for the cancellation of the deportation order and hoped that all parties would avoid further escalation and spread of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharifou told Southern Weekend reporters that his family will not leave Gaza even if the border is reopened. &quot;If we leave, we will lose our home forever. Like 1948 and 1967, we will not repeat the same mistakes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the people evacuated, the livestock that could not be taken away Stay in the ruins. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the people evacuated, the livestock that could not be taken away were left in the ruins. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sharifou’s view, Israel wants to force residents to leave Gaza... They achieve their goals step by step, “first by closing the border and sending us from the north to the south, and then Tell us to leave Gaza and go to Egypt.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif&#39;s worries are not groundless. After the Palestinian-Israeli conflict escalated, when US President Biden visited Israel, the United States and Israel jointly proposed a proposal to transfer Gazans to Egypt, but Egypt clearly opposed this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They (Israel) thought that by blowing up all the bakeries, hospitals and houses, people would leave Gaza and run away. But they are wrong, people here will never leave, win or die .&quot; Sharifu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rasha.G lives in the Palestinian area of ​​the West Bank and runs a chocolate business with her husband and children. Affected by the war in Gaza, the atmosphere here has also become tense. &quot;Business is very deserted and people have nothing to celebrate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As she said, to a certain extent, the West Bank is safer than Gaza because there are &quot;no bombs and no air strikes&quot; for the time being. But Resha felt a deep sense of crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resa told Southern Weekend reporters that in the conflicts between Palestine and Israel, many Palestinians evacuated elsewhere, or moved to neighboring countries, such as Egypt, Jordan, Syria, Lebanon, or moved to the Jordan River west coast. But most of them live in refugee camps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t imagine how difficult life is in the refugee camps. There are many people living in a small space and the environment is very poor.” Resha said that in Palestine, many refugees can only rely on the United Nations Near East for their education. Relief and Works Agency. Refugees can find jobs in Palestine, and a small number can do business, but in other countries, these refugees are &quot;not even treated as citizens.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resa is well-educated, fluent in English, and has lived in Europe for two years. But she returned to Palestine. &quot;I never thought about evacuating. I would not leave my home and become a refugee. I would rather die.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;DIVISION&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The humanitarian crisis in Gaza is imminent, but All parties still have differences on whether to cease fire and carry out rescue operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, Spain, the Netherlands, Ireland, Slovenia and Luxembourg have publicly supported the humanitarian ceasefire. Irish Foreign Minister Michael Martin said that &quot;Gaza urgently needs access to water, food and medical supplies.&quot; &quot;The human suffering is enormous. We must distinguish between Gazan civilians and Hamas civilians.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the leaders of the European Union, Germany did not respond to calls for a ceasefire. German Foreign Minister Annalena Berbock said that providing aid to Gaza was important, but large-scale rocket attacks against Israel were taking place. &quot;We cannot end the humanitarian catastrophe while terrorism in Gaza persists.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U.S. State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told the media on October 23 that the ceasefire will &quot;give Hamas the ability to rest, reorganize and prepare to continue launching terrorist attacks against Israel.&quot; U.S. President Biden also said on the same day that a ceasefire in Gaza would be possible only after Hamas releases all hostages it has held. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the Israeli government, the purpose of this operation was demonstrated as early as the beginning of the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This should be our last ground offensive in Gaza, for the simple reason that Hamas will cease to exist after this.” Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Galant publicly stated that Israel A ground offensive will be launched in the Gaza Strip that will last for several months, aiming to completely eliminate Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the latest statement from the Israeli army, the Israel Defense Forces air raided more than 400 targets of the Hamas organization in the Gaza Strip on October 23, including its armed personnel assembly areas, command centers and a road leading to the seaside. underground tunnels and killed dozens of Hamas commanders and their armed men. The Israeli army also dispatched tanks, artillery and helicopters to attack Hamas military posts and anti-tank missile launch sites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, in response to a reporter’s question, Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said that China is very saddened by the large number of civilian casualties caused by the Palestinian-Israeli conflict and the sharp deterioration of the humanitarian situation. Responding to violence with violence will only lead to a vicious cycle. The top priority is to cease fire and end the war as soon as possible. All parties should earnestly abide by international law and international humanitarian law, protect civilians, and make every effort to avoid serious humanitarian disasters. The international community should provide more humanitarian assistance to the people of Gaza to alleviate the humanitarian disaster they have suffered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, China will continue to support all efforts that are conducive to promoting dialogue and restoring peace, and make efforts to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and promote a comprehensive, fair and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Gu Yuebing and Southern Weekend intern Zhai Huan also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[温州实现数据资产“入表”第一单，万亿市场仍藏水面下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259268]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrTtK2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrT tK2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Data exchanges are springing up like mushrooms after a rain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Shi Xuan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The capitalization of data is ushering in new progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, the data product &quot;Credit Data Treasure&quot; of Wenzhou Big Data Operation Co., Ltd. completed the data asset confirmation registration. The Wenzhou Municipal Finance Bureau stated in the announcement that this is the first order to confirm the registration of data assets in Wenzhou, and it is also the first order to list the data assets of a financial guidance enterprise in China that has been publicly reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incorporating data resources into the balance sheet refers to recognizing data resources as an &quot;asset&quot; in the company&#39;s balance sheet, and reflecting its value in financial statements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Credit Data Treasure is developed based on the Wenzhou Government Blockchain &quot;Data Asset Cloud Voucher&quot; system. After authorization by individuals or enterprises, it provides financial institutions with data services related to credit business, simplifying loan application materials and process to improve credit approval efficiency and bank verification accuracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2020, data was upgraded to the fifth major factor of production alongside land, labor, capital and technology, and a series of policies related to the capitalization of data were closely introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If you had asked me two years ago, I would have told you that most enterprises knew nothing about data capitalization.” Today, data capitalization has become a hot topic, but according to UFIDA Group Data Governance Expert Shi Xiufeng observed that most companies have not yet truly touched upon their essence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the difficulties in capitalizing data? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The trillion-dollar market under the water&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“First of all, it must be clear that not all data is data assets.” Deputy Director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission Director Wang Jiandong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of China Academy of Information and Communications Technology (hereinafter referred to as the Academy of Information and Communications Technology), data assets refer to data legally owned or controlled by organizations (government agencies, enterprises and institutions, etc.), recorded electronically or by other means , such as structured or unstructured data such as texts, videos, databases, and sensor signals, can be measured or traded, and can directly or indirectly bring economic and social benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, only data that can bring value to the organization is a data asset, and its formation requires active management and effective control of data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Hanlin, chairman of Guizhou Databao Network Technology Co., Ltd. and general manager of East China Jiangsu Big Data Trading Center, explained to Southern Weekend reporters that data capitalization is to transform data resources into data assets, and its core is to fully release data value of resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the development, use and market operation of public data are still being explored. In December 2022, the &quot;Opinions on Building a Data Basic System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements&quot; (also known as the Twenty Data Articles) was issued and proposed to &quot;promote the paid use of public data used for digital development in accordance with government guidance and pricing, and enterprises and A price formation mechanism that combines independent pricing in the personal information data market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng analyzed from the perspective of enterprise development that enterprises have accumulated a large amount of data in the informatization process over the past 20 years. Nowadays, these data can generate greater value, thus pushing enterprises to start data governance, realize the utilization and value maximization of data assets, and ultimately realize the digital transformation of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Informatization refers to the realization of enterprise business process management and data recording through network, computer, database and other information technologies, such as financial computerization, OA collaborative office, etc. Digitalization is the use of digital technologies such as cloud computing and blockchain to achieve innovation in enterprise business and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng has more than 16 years of working experience in the data field. His business involves consulting and delivery in the fields of enterprise data governance, data asset management, data applications and other fields. He has led many companies in traditional manufacturing, energy and other industries. Planning and implementation of large-scale data projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng believes that currently 80% of companies are still in the process of forming data assets. Wang Jiandong said that in the short term, the data infrastructure system will give rise to a data trading market of 300 billion to 500 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This 100-billion-dollar transaction will leverage the trillion-level market behind it.” Wang Jiandong said that by further considering the derivative markets such as the evaluation, pledge, and financing of data assets, the potential scale of the entire data asset market will be More than 10 trillion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that, like production factors such as land, data elements can also be explored using hierarchical governance. The primary data market is the transfer of ownership rights and open usage rights of data resources, while the secondary data market is the market for data products and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The main part of enterprise data capitalization is still hidden under the water.” Wang Jiandong explained that currently, only a small part of the data owned by social institutions has entered the circulation and transaction process, and most of the other data They are all circulated in the zero-level market in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The zero-level data market refers to the market behavior that does not enter the transaction link, but data sharing, exchange and equity transfer occur, such as within an enterprise and between enterprises with certain business or equity relationships. Another example is that data sharing and exchange occurs every moment within Internet companies, but no external transactions are conducted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong said that according to preliminary calculations, the potential scale of data assets and their pledge, financing and other derivative markets in the current zero-level data market is 30 times to 60 times that of the primary and secondary markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Obtain a position first&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“It’s hot at the top and cold at the bottom.” Senior data Industry insider Cheng Guo described the current data capitalization process to Southern Weekend reporters. He has participated in corporate research and the formulation of industry rules for many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Guo’s view, the only newly established deputy ministerial-level national bureau in this round of institutional reform of the State Council is the National Data Bureau. The bureau is affiliated with the National Development and Reform Commission, alongside the National Grain Administration and the National Energy Administration, which shows that senior officials regard data as a core strategic resource. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 25, 2023, the National Data Administration was officially launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The introduction of a number of relevant policies has also prompted a new wave of enthusiasm in the preparation and construction of data exchanges. After the fourth quarter of 2020, data exchanges have sprung up like mushrooms after a rain, including Shanxi, Shanghai, Shenzhen, Fujian and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;White Paper on Data Elements&quot; released by the Academy of Information and Communications Technology shows that as of August 2023, 53 data trading institutions have been established across the country. From January to August 2023 alone, 5 new data trading institutions have been established in the country. Home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, generally speaking, most of the data trading institutions established in the early stage have not found successful business models. Most of them have stopped operations or changed their business direction, and their development has not been as expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The East China Jiangsu Big Data Trading Center (hereinafter referred to as the East China Data Trading Center) where Tang Hanlin works was established in 2015 and is one of the earliest data trading institutions in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said frankly that in the past, there was no clear requirement that data transactions must be conducted on exchanges. The East China Digital Exchange serves more as an announcement platform - allowing both supply and demand parties to better understand each other, in order to promote Both parties mainly conduct offline transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Guo’s view, the importance of data capitalization has been emphasized at the national level, but local governments are still relatively confused. &quot;Their (local government) idea is that although I can&#39;t understand this new thing yet, I will take a position first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Shenzhen Data Trading Co., Ltd. was established, and then based on The Shenzhen Data Exchange (hereinafter referred to as the Shenzhen Data Exchange) was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“深数所前几年的工作重点都不是提高交易额，而是培育市场生态。”2022年9月底，深数所副总经理王冠在一次会议中透露，深圳数据交易市场无论是在交易额还是在交易活跃度上，都已领跑全国。但市场供需不太平衡，供给方相对较少，需求方又很多，同时第三方服务机构和数据商的数量也不丰富。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“高质量的数据产品供给是最关键的。”上海数据交易所（下称上数所）副总经理韦志林向南方周末记者强调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年11月底，上数所几乎与深数所同时成立。其目标明确，以“构建数据要素市场、推进数据资产化进程”为使命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韦志林透露，截至目前，上数所挂牌超1600个数据产品，月交易额已超一亿元，预计2023年全年交易额突破10亿元。上数所目前重点提供金融、航运交通和贸易等领域的数据产品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，金融业数据交易市场存在时间较长，交付产品和金融方式更加成熟，是数据密集型行业。近五年来，金融业数据要素采购项目数量复合年增长率达40%，远超金融业采购总项目数量复合年增长率26%，显示出金融业数据交易市场规模发展迅速。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但韦志林也坦陈，当前整个数据要素市场场内交易的规模占比相对较小。 “场内交易的建设至关重要，其在合规、可信、效率和资产化方面的作用不可替代。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;896&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年5月6日，天津滨海新区，一名行人从筹备中的北方大数据交易中心前走过。视觉中国/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王建冬表示，数据资产化未来的发力方向之一是鼓励企业尽可能多地进场交易，通过场内交易实现对其数据资产价值的确认，让交易所内形成的价格成为对数据资产估价的“锚”，这样交易所也会活跃起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“相当于企业入场不是只为了挣交易那笔钱，而是通过交易得到资产增值的机会。”王建冬解释，企业数据资产价值得到市场认可，在后续实现资本化操作，企业才有更大积极性参与场内交易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汤寒林相信，对企业数据资产入表的要求，会推动数据交易市场发生很大改善，今后供需双方会更希望通过场内交易对数据资产形成一套公允的价格体系，这样才便于估价并入表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;确权难题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年8月和9月，财政部和中评协先后就数据资源入表和数据资产的评估发布相关文件，分别为《企业数据资源相关会计处理暂行规定》（下称《暂行规定》）和《数据资产评估指导意见》（下称《指导意见》）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两套文件一出，竞天公诚律师事务所合伙人、数据法律专家袁立志立刻接到了客户的咨询。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“会计师、审计师和评估师都希望我们律师能先出一份法律意见，作为企业数据资产入表或资产评估的基础。”袁立志对南方周末记者说，他们担心的根本原因在于数据资产的权属无法得到确认。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;业内普遍认为，实现数据资产化有三大环节也是三大挑战，分别为法律角度的数据资产确权、市场角度的数据资产估值与交易和会计角度的数据资产入表。其中，数据资产的确权是一切的前提。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在数据生产、流通、使用等过程中，个人、企业、社会、国家等相关主体对数据有着不同利益诉求，且呈现复杂共生、相互依存、动态变化等特点，传统权利制度框架难以突破数据产权困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据二十条提出，建立数据资源持有权、数据加工使用权、数据产品经营权“三权分置”的数据产权制度框架，淡化所有权、强调使用权。在一定程度上破解了数据资产确权难题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王建冬表示，“三权分置”提供了一条解决问题的基本思路。目前在技术上对数据资产登记确权已无根本性障碍，而具体实施中的难点在于缺乏上位法的支持。如证券法之于证券登记，物权法之于不动产登记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中华人民共和国民法典》第一百二十七条规定，“法律对数据、网络虚拟财产的保护有规定的，依照其规定”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前与之相关的法律法规，如个人信息保护法、数据安全法和网络安全法等，更多从数据安全和隐私保护的角度入手，均未对数据确权作出明确规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袁立志介绍，在实际案例中，由于涉及的利益相关方较多，企业在开发及利用数据资产时或会碰到从各种角度提出的利益诉求，如个人信息保护、不正当竞争、商业秘密、知识产权、合同债权等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果在调研时发现，在此情况下，一些企业对于其数据资产入表也显现出顾虑。入表，意味着企业要接受严格审计，但目前许多企业很难说清其数据真正的权属。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，上述《暂行规定》和《指导意见》只是对现存相关规则的细化规范，“并没有突破现有的财务会计制度”。在袁立志看来，产权制度是市场交易的前提。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袁立志表示，在出正式的法律文件时，律师们对数据资产合法性的判断已相对成熟，对其权属的认定则会比较谨慎。 “尤其在涉及第三方权益时，我们会根据一般的法律原理作出判断，但会保留意见”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关部门在出台规定时显然也意识到了其中难点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果将《暂行规定》称为对数据资产的“小入表”。原因在于该文件并未针对所有数据资产，而是根据数据资源是否符合《企业会计准则——基本准则》中资产的确认条件，将其分为满足条件可“入表”的数据资源和不满足条件的“不入表”的数据资源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，《暂行规定》是未来适用法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;程果表示，一些企业在数据资产化的投入主要在前期，之后每年仅进行规律性的小部分投入，其入表的数据资产仅以新增投入为基础计算，不会对企业的资产规模产生太大影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;另辟蹊径&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;短时间内，确权难题无法解决，市场主体也开始另辟蹊径。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韦志林看来，数据产权“三权”中数据产品的经营权，解决的便是所谓的确权难、定价难，包括数据的监管问题。在此基础上，上数所提出“数据产品”的概念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韦志林称，只有将数据按照一定的需求和应用场景组织加工成数据产品，才能形成有需求和供应关联的市场。这样，才能建立起相应的交易规则、标准制度、技术、生态和监管等流通交易体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，如果流通交易的是原始数据，将会涉及数据的安全和确权等目前难以破解的问题，而“数据产品”概念的提出，很好地解决了数据的权属问题。将企业持有的原始数据加工形成的数据产品，赋予企业确定数据产品的权利，基于数据产品，企业可以享受该数据产品的经营权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前有媒体报道，在建设具体的数据产权制度方面，知识产权制度是唯一正在试点实践中的制度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海对外经贸大学法学院讲师高阳曾公开表示，知识产权作为保护无形资产财产权的制度，适用于数据具有正当性。数据经过人类创造性智力劳动方能获得较高经济价值，符合知识产权保护智力成果的范畴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高阳在上述采访中说，通过对满足条件的数据授予知识产权，为数据交易主体提供明确指引，提高了数据交易的安全性及效率，进而激励企业数据产品创新，以解决市场中数据产品供给不足的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汤寒林同样认可知识产权制度在数据确权中的应用。 2023年4月，江苏省知识产权局出台《江苏省数据知识产权登记管理规则（试行）》，华东数交是江苏省数据知识产权试点单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他透露，华东数交已经和江苏省知识产权局直接打通。 “我们的数据交易商在交易所提交数据产品后，可以直接经由江苏省知产局审核，进行在线确权，由此完成一个确权的闭环服务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《新华日报》报道，2023年10月中旬，江苏省联合征信有限公司（下称联合征信）研发的一款数据产品“企业批量查询”，在交通银行江苏省分行获得质押融资1200万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合征信是经江苏省政府批准设立的金融科技公司，是获得了央行备案的征信机构。 “企业批量查询”是联合征信在对数据清理加工的基础上，通过四十多个维度指标建构模型，最终形成的企业信息查询类数据产品，主要用于反映企业信用状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述报道称，作为全国数据知识产权工作地方试点，江苏省于2023年5月颁发第一批数据知识产权登记证书。截至10月11日，江苏省已有125笔数据知识产权登记，已实现数据知识产权质押融资额五千余万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在数据资产的价值评估方面，王建冬一直呼吁，在国家未来的数据资产登记平台中，应该包含数据溯源功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这意味着企业需说明其数据资产在形成过程中每一个环节上的数据来源。通过这样的方式，可以更加公正地评估该数据资产未来的价值潜力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随着数据资产入表和实现有效评估，企业在会计报表上有了表达，就有了实体经济活动的支撑。”韦志林认为，数据资产化的进程在入表的基础上，一定会取得更大的突破和创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他总结，数据资产创新应用主要有六大方向，包括数据资产入表、数据资产增信、数据资产质押融资、数据资产保理、数据资产作价入股以及数据资产证券化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者通过电话约访温州市财政局并发送采访函，对方婉拒了采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，程果为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查报告公布]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259282]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:08:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年4月18日12时50分，北京市丰台区靛厂新村291号北京长峰医院发生重大火灾事故，造成29人死亡、42人受伤，直接经济损失3831.82万元。日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。经国务院事故调查组调查认定，这是一起因事发医院违法违规实施改造工程、施工安全管理不力、日常管理混乱、火灾隐患长期存在，施工单位违规作业、现场安全管理缺失，加之应急处置不力，地方党委政府和有关部门职责不落实而导致的重大生产安全责任事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故发生后，党中央、国务院高度重视。习近平总书记立即作出重要指示，要求全力救治受伤人员，妥善做好遇难者善后和家属安抚工作，并尽快查明火灾事故原因，依法严肃追究责任。强调各地区和有关部门要时刻绷紧安全生产这根弦，切实把安全生产责任落到实处，加强安全管理，彻底排查各种风险隐患，坚决防范遏制重大安全事故发生。李强总理等领导同志作出重要批示，对善后处置、事故调查、专项整治等工作提出明确要求。北京市立即组织抢险救援、伤员救治和善后处置等工作。应急管理部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局等部门立即调度部署，并派工作组赶赴现场指导应急处置工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4月21日，北京市人民政府成立事故调查组开展调查工作，国务院安委会对该起事故查处实行挂牌督办。鉴于该起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，依据有关法律法规规定，经国务院批准，成立由应急管理部牵头，公安部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局、全国总工会和北京市人民政府参加的国务院北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”火灾事故调查组，在北京市前期工作基础上，对该起事故进行提格调查。事故调查组按照科学严谨、依法依规、实事求是、注重实效的原则，通过现场勘验、调查取证、视频分析、检测鉴定、模拟实验、专家论证等，查清了事故经过、发生原因、人员伤亡、直接经济损失和有关单位情况，查明了地方党委政府、有关部门和单位存在的问题和责任，总结分析了事故主要教训，提出了整改和防范措施建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组查明，事故直接原因是北京长峰医院改造工程施工现场，施工单位违规进行自流平地面施工和门框安装切割交叉作业，环氧树脂底涂材料中的易燃易爆成分挥发、形成爆炸性气体混合物，遇角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花发生爆燃；引燃现场附近可燃物，产生的明火及高温烟气引燃楼内木质装修材料，部分防火分隔未发挥作用，固定消防设施失效，致使火势扩大、大量烟气蔓延；加之初期处置不力，未能有效组织高楼层患者疏散转移，造成重大人员伤亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查查清事故暴露的主要问题是医院主体责任严重不落实，施工单位违规动火交叉作业，地方党委政府防范化解重大风险意识薄弱，医疗卫生机构行政审批和安全管理短板明显，建设工程安全监督管理存在漏洞，消防安全风险防控网不严密等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组按规定将调查中发现的地方党委政府及有关部门公职人员履职方面存在的问题等线索及相关材料，移交中央纪委国家监委追责问责审查调查组。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对事故中暴露的问题，事故调查组总结了五个方面的主要教训：防范化解重大风险意识薄弱，医疗卫生行业行政审批和安全管理不严格，建设工程规划、施工安全监管存在短板漏洞，消防监督检查和专项整治不深入，初期应急处置能力不足。同时，提出五项整改和防范措施建议：切实扛起防范化解重大风险政治责任，着力补齐医疗卫生机构安全管理短板，坚决堵塞建设工程安全监督管理漏洞，全面织牢织密消防安全风险防控网，加快提升基层一线应急处置能力和水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院事故调查组相关负责人就北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查工作答记者问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:16:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。记者就该事故调查中社会关注的热点问题，采访了事故调查组相关负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：国务院事故调查组是怎样组成的？调查的过程如何？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故发生后，党中央、国务院高度重视。 4月21日，北京市人民政府成立事故调查组开展调查工作，国务院安委会对该起事故查处实行挂牌督办。鉴于该起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，依据有关法律法规规定，经国务院批准，成立由应急管理部牵头，公安部、住房城乡建设部、国家卫生健康委、国家消防救援局、全国总工会和北京市人民政府参加的国务院北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”火灾事故调查组，在北京市前期工作基础上，对该起事故进行提格调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组认真贯彻落实习近平总书记重要指示批示精神和党中央、国务院决策部署，按照科学严谨、依法依规、实事求是、注重实效的原则，通过现场勘验、调查取证、视频分析、检测鉴定、模拟实验、专家论证等，查清了事故经过、发生原因、人员伤亡、直接经济损失和有关单位情况，查明了地方党委政府、有关部门和单位存在的问题和责任，总结分析了事故主要教训，提出了整改和防范措施建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查认定，这是一起因事发医院违法违规实施改造工程、施工安全管理不力、日常管理混乱、火灾隐患长期存在，施工单位违规作业、现场安全管理缺失，加之应急处置不力，地方党委政府和有关部门职责不落实而导致的重大生产安全责任事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：事故发生的主要原因是什么？为何会造成大量人员伤亡？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故调查组通过视频分析、现场勘验、检测鉴定及模拟实验分析，认定事故直接原因是北京长峰医院改造工程施工现场，施工单位违规进行自流平地面施工和门框安装切割交叉作业，环氧树脂底涂材料中的易燃易爆成分挥发、形成爆炸性气体混合物，遇角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花发生爆燃；引燃现场附近可燃物，产生的明火及高温烟气引燃楼内木质装修材料，部分防火分隔未发挥作用，固定消防设施失效，致使火势扩大、大量烟气蔓延；加之初期处置不力，未能有效组织高楼层患者疏散转移，造成重大人员伤亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查组对起火原因、火灾蔓延原因、人员伤亡原因进行了逐一分析。起火原因方面，北京长峰医院南配楼三层ICU改造工程施工现场，作业人员开展自流平地面施工和净化门门框安装切割动火时，违规交叉作业；自流平地面施工涂刷的环氧树脂底涂材料中易燃易爆成分挥发，加之现场未保持有效通风，形成爆炸性气体混合物，且浓度达到爆炸下限；角磨机切割金属净化板产生的火花，遇爆炸性气体混合物引起爆燃，并引燃西北门外坡道下方堆放的可燃物。火灾蔓延原因方面，爆燃发生后，作业人员未将现场形成的多处火点全部扑灭且未第一时间报警，事发医院工作人员发现火情后也未第一时间报警，未有效组织初期火灾扑救，固定消防设施失效，自动喷水灭火系统和消火栓系统管网无水，未能有效控制火势；坡道和医院通道墙面采用木质装修材料、施工区域与非施工区域未按规定采用不燃材料进行防火分隔，导致明火蔓延至东楼主体建筑内；部分管道竖井未进行防火封堵且未设置防火门，部分楼梯间防火门闭门器损坏无法正常关闭，北通道五层东侧楼梯间常闭式防火门未保持关闭状态，南通道六层西侧楼梯间防火门上方石膏板隔墙被烧穿，导致烟气蔓延扩散。人员伤亡原因方面，未能及时转移疏散、吸入含一氧化碳的烟气是造成大量人员伤亡的主要原因。火灾初期事发医院未启动应急预案，未有效组织疏散转移被困人员；病区设置不合理，事发医院将行动不能自理或行动不便的患者集中安置在七层、八层等高楼层，大部分患者无自主逃生能力；危重病患者移动难度大，楼内通道狭窄、转移条件差，救援转移困难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：涉事医院及相关单位存在哪些违法违规行为？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;调查发现，涉事医院、施工单位存在诸多违法违规行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主要有以下方面：一是医院主体责任严重不落实。长峰医院公司违反医疗机构管理规定，未按照要求进行床位数变更登记、医护配比不符合规定，住院部公共走道宽度1.4米，明显小于规范要求的至少2.1米；未履行建筑施工法定义务和施工现场安全管理职责，2017年以来陆续进行的38个装修改造类施工项目均未按规定向相关部门申请办理施工许可或向街道乡镇申请办理开工登记手续，未发现并制止ICU改造工程现场违规动火、交叉作业行为；未按规定履行消防安全主体责任，符合界定标准但未进行消防安全重点单位申报，未对消防设施、器材定期组织维修，火灾自动报警系统、自动喷水灭火系统、室内消火栓系统未保持完好有效。二是施工单位违规动火交叉作业。中源信诚公司施工现场安全管理缺失，作业人员在未办理动火审批手续违规进行明火作业、现场无人监护、未对现场可燃物进行清理的情况下，使用角磨机进行切割作业；未针对易燃易爆物品制定防火安全措施，违规在作业场所调料；环氧树脂自流平地面施工与净化门安装交叉作业；未保持建筑业企业资质许可条件，且未按规定设立安全生产管理机构并配备专职安全生产管理人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故中地方党委政府和有关部门存在哪些问题？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;事故调查组查明了地方党委政府和有关部门职责落实方面存在的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是地方党委政府防范化解重大风险意识薄弱。北京市丰台区未认真履行安全生产属地管理责任，对街道乡镇基层安全监管能力建设重视不够，2022年全市安全生产和消防工作考核排名倒数第一，未有效组织开展建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查，事故信息报送不及时、伤亡人员情况报告迟缓。北京市安全发展理念不够牢固，对相关部门未认真落实属地医疗机构、施工现场等重点场所安全生产和消防安全管理职责的问题失察，未有效督促指导丰台区委、区政府严格落实属地安全生产管理责任。二是医疗卫生机构行政审批和安全管理短板明显。丰台区卫生健康委未严格履行医疗机构校验管理职责，对北京长峰医院长期未按规定申请床位数变更登记、人员配备不符合要求等问题监管不力，未履行对北京长峰医院ICU改造工程无施工许可的行业监督管理职责，未检查发现工程存在的消防问题隐患，未通过正式渠道向丰台区委、区政府和区应急办报告事故伤亡人员信息。北京市卫生健康委未认真履行“管行业必须管安全”安全监管职责，对丰台区卫生健康委履行行业安全监管职责不力等问题失察失管；指导落实北京市医疗机构消防安全组团体检式检查、建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查要求不力，未有效推进隐患整改工作。三是建设工程安全监督管理存在漏洞。丰台区住房城乡建设委未认真履行行业安全监管职责，对不具备取得施工许可的建设工程监管不力；未对移交街道乡镇管理的限额以下建设工程进行有效业务指导和服务配合；对限额以上的北京长峰医院ICU改造工程未取得施工许可证的行为，未依法依规予以查处。北京市住房城乡建设委落实建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查要求不力；未按要求对建筑业企业资质进行动态监管，对施工单位未保持建筑业二级资质许可条件的问题失察失管。四是消防安全风险防控网不严密。当地消防部门未认真履行消防监督管理职责，日常消防监督检查和消防安全专项整治不扎实。丰台区消防救援支队（原丰台区公安消防支队）2012年对北京长峰医院东楼内部装修工程进行消防验收时，在未检查管道竖井封堵完整性、未对建筑内部装修防火等进行评定，以及在消防用电设备未采用专用供电回路的情况下，违规出具验收合格评定结论；长期以来未将北京长峰医院确定为消防安全重点单位。北京市消防救援总队指导落实北京市医疗机构消防安全组团体检式检查、建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查工作不力，未有效推进隐患整改工作。此外，国务院事故调查组还查明，北京市规划和自然资源委员会丰台分局未认真履行制止和查处违法建设职责，未及时发现并查处北京长峰医院部分建筑未办理建设工程规划许可证违法行为；丰台区应急办在首次获知事故信息后4小时24分才正式报告，违反北京市应急值守工作有关规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故暴露出哪些深层次的教训？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;这起事故教训十分深刻，暴露出当地消防安全存在诸多突出问题和明显短板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是防范化解重大风险意识薄弱。一些领导干部对本地区存在的重大风险认识不足，没有及时发现并有效防控重大风险，也没有把他人的教训当作自己的教训，对相关重特大火灾事故暴露出的违规动火或电焊作业问题没有引起足够重视。这些问题根本原因在于，学习贯彻习近平总书记关于防范化解重大风险的重要论述不认真不深刻，没有结合实际认真研究和排查本地区风险隐患。二是医疗卫生行业行政审批和安全管理不严格。丰台区卫生健康部门工作作风不实不细，审批许可流于形式，1998年以来先后对事发医院校验18次，在病床数量成倍增加却未变更登记、医护配比不符合要求等情况下，每次校验结果均为合格；对安全生产工作面上重视，实际却撤销安全生产科；没有定期开展医疗卫生机构消防安全检查，也没有对事发医院近3年消防检测发现的重大问题进行督促整改。三是建设工程规划、施工安全监管存在短板漏洞。北京市住房城乡建设部门对建筑业企业资质条件保持情况疏于监管，动态排查清理不符合条件企业工作滞后。北京市建设工程施工管理自我设“限”，对限额以上未办理施工许可证的建设工程未主动开展监督管理，把不具备申请办理施工许可条件的建设工程排除在监管范围外，“只管合法、不管非法”；对限额以下工程施工安全疏于管理，对属地培训指导、协调督促又没跟上，导致基层接不住、管不好。北京市城乡规划部门履行制止和查处违法建设职责不到位，未能有效指导属地政府及其相关部门违法建设查处工作，对辖区内无规划手续即新建、扩建的行为查不出、管不住。四是消防监督检查和专项整治不深入。当地消防部门未认真履行消防安全监管职责，2009年事发医院已符合消防安全重点单位界定标准，至2022年才将其确定为重点单位进行监管；确定为重点单位后，消防监督检查质效依然不高，未及时发现和督促整改消防设施、消防供电等问题隐患。北京市消防救援总队在全市部署开展的建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查中，未能有效指导丰台区消防救援支队严格落实消防监督检查职责。五是初期应急处置能力不足。这次事故中，自流平地面和净化工程作业人员均为临时雇佣人员，未经任何施工交底和安全教育培训直接上岗，违规交叉作业导致发生火灾，之后作业人员均未第一时间报警。医院值班人员、管理人员和医护人员，在发现火情后均未第一时间报警，医院未有效组织初期火灾扑救和人员疏散。同时，这次事故也暴露出一些政府部门和单位存在事故信息报送特别是伤亡人员信息报送不及时不规范等问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，为进一步汲取教训，防止此类事故再次发生，有哪些整改和防范措施建议？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;为深刻汲取事故教训，举一反三，坚决防范遏制重特大事故发生，事故调查组提出了五个方面的整改和防范措施建议：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是切实扛起防范化解重大风险政治责任。各级领导干部要结合学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想主题教育，全面深入学习领会习近平总书记关于安全生产重要论述，坚持人民至上、生命至上，牢固树立安全发展理念，进一步增强防范化解重大风险的政治自觉、思想自觉和行动自觉。各地区、各部门、各单位要切实提高风险隐患排查整改质量，切实提升发现问题解决问题的强烈意愿和能力水平，进一步压紧压实企业主体责任、部门监管责任、地方领导责任，建立安全风险防范长效机制，坚决守牢安全红线底线。二是着力补齐医疗卫生机构安全管理短板。各级卫生健康部门要加强医疗卫生行业安全管理，督促各类医疗卫生机构严格执行安全生产和消防安全管理规定，加强安全风险分级管控和隐患排查治理，组织开展医疗卫生机构安全生产和消防安全专项排查整治。严格医疗卫生机构登记校验、行政审批等，组织开展医疗卫生机构依法执业情况核查，严查不如实申报情况、超许可范围执业、违规开展医养结合服务等行为。督促医疗卫生机构统筹考虑院感防治和病患应急疏散转移，指导各类医疗卫生机构制定专项灭火预案和应急疏散预案。三是坚决堵塞建设工程安全监督管理漏洞。各级住房城乡建设部门要加大资质审批后动态监管力度，严格建设工程施工许可管理，加强施工现场特别是施工动火作业安全管理，及时发现并消除事故隐患。城乡规划等部门要加大对违法建设的巡查和处置力度，对新增违建实行“零容忍”。四是全面织牢织密消防安全风险防控网。各地区要按照“三管三必须”要求，进一步压实行业部门消防安全管理责任，推行行业消防安全标准化管理；对职能交叉和新业态新风险，及时明确监管责任。推动街道乡镇建设应急站、消防所，发挥公安派出所、社区、网格等群防群治力量，切实加强对小场所小单位的消防安全管理。各级消防部门要严格履行消防监督管理职责，推动公共消防安全治理模式向事前预防转型，切实提升消防监督检查质效。五是加快提升基层一线应急处置能力和水平。各地区要进一步强化对各类企事业单位应急预案、演练、培训等应急准备的组织指导、监督检查。加强基层一线作业人员安全教育和应急培训，深入开展实操实训应急演练，确保熟悉作业场所现场处置方案。加强应急文化建设，强化应急科普宣传，切实增强社会公众安全意识，做到人人讲安全、个个会应急。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[聚焦北京长峰医院火灾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/247513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年4月18日12时50分，北京市丰台区靛厂新村291号北京长峰医院发生重大火灾事故，造成29人死亡、42人受伤，直接经济损失3831.82万元。 日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦陷“二选一”风波：是否触发反垄断调查值得关切丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259275]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 16:17:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;About Li Jiaqi, there have been waves of ups and downs. On the morning of October 24, 2023, Jingdong Procurement and Sales publicly called Li Jiaqi to &quot;choose one of the two&quot; in the circle of friends. The staff member said that JD.com received a lawyer&#39;s letter from the brand owner Hai&#39;s. The brand complained that because the price of a certain Hai&#39;s oven on JD.com was lower than the price of Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast, it violated the &quot;reserve price agreement&quot; signed between them and Li Jiaqi, which would lead to a claim for compensation. Huge liquidated damages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, Li Jiaqi’s company, MeiONE, responded: Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room and Hai’s did not sign a so-called “reserve price agreement”; Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room has never asked the brand to make any choice; Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room has never asked the brand to make any choice; The pricing power of goods lies in the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hi&#39;s issued a statement saying: The Hai&#39;s brand has not signed any &quot;reserve price agreement&quot; and the information released by JD.com is untrue. Hai&#39;s stated that the price guarantee was to bring the lowest sales price to the same level across the entire network. JD.com did not have the right to modify the price without authorization. After its own refusal, JD.com still chose to lower the price. Moreover, the losses of each oven sold by JD.com at a lower price will be borne by the Hai&#39;s brand, instead of being subsidized by the platform as JD.com claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How do you view the confrontation between e-commerce platforms and e-commerce live broadcasts this time? What is the essence of the debate between the two parties and even the three parties (plus the brand)? It deserves detailed analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there is a factual question that cannot be avoided: Did Hai&#39;s and Li Jiaqi or his company sign a &quot;reserve price agreement&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a &quot;Mei ONE Live Broadcasting Promotion Service Contract&quot; disclosed by Sina Technology, the contract states: ... The brand must ensure that the value of the gift is the highest value under the same conditions within the guarantee range within the guarantee period; During the guarantee period, the brand needs to ensure that the promotional intensity provided by the designated experts under all promotional services agreed by both parties under the framework of this contract is the maximum intensity under the same conditions within the scope of the guarantee during the guarantee period. In the event of a breach of contract, the brand needs to refund five times the price difference to consumers, compensate ONE with liquidated damages of RMB 2 million, and bear all expenses and losses incurred due to the refund of the price difference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Attachment 3 of the contract is the special guarantee clause. The scope of the best price is specified to be the Taobao platform controlled by Party A (brand party) (including but not limited to Taobao/Tmall stores, anchor live broadcasts and other Taobao content channels), other e-commerce platforms and offline channels. The best price guarantee period is 60 days before and after the actual date of the live broadcast promotion service (121 days in total). There are three special guarantee contents. The first one is: within the guarantee period, the brand also needs to ensure that the final transaction price of the promotional objects within the corresponding planned sales volume under all the promotion services provided by the designated experts is within the guarantee range within the guarantee period. lowest price within. Articles 2 and 3 are the same as the provisions on gifts and promotion intensity in the main body of the contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, comparing the text of the contract with Attachment 3, the requirements of the US ONE Live Broadcast for the brand are: within a total of four months, the final transaction price of the live broadcast promotion object must be relative to all e-commerce platforms and The lowest price for offline channels, and the value of gifts and promotion intensity are also stipulated to prevent brands and other platforms from circumventing the minimum price clause through these two methods. This is the &quot;lowest price agreement in the entire network&quot; that is comprehensively stipulated from the price of genuine products, the value of gifts and the intensity of promotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question now becomes whether Hai&#39;s and Li Jiaqi signed a contract with a &quot;reservoir price agreement&quot;. If what JD.com said is true, then it is signed. Of course, between JD.com and Haishi and US ONE, we can see which side is telling the truth. We can see further disclosure of hard evidence by both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, JD.com Publicly accused Li Jiaqi of &quot;choosing one of two&quot; and engaging in a &quot;low-price agreement&quot; in WeChat Moments. Li Jiaqi&#39;s company denied this. Obviously, the former may be summoning the Sword of Damocles: the Anti-Monopoly Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Anti-Monopoly Law has provisions against &quot;abuse of dominant market position&quot; (Article 22). The 2021 &quot;Anti-Monopoly Guidelines of the State Council Anti-Monopoly Commission on the Platform Economy&quot; stipulates: Operators in the platform economy with a dominant market position may abuse their market dominance, restrict transactions with counterparties without legitimate reasons, and exclude or restrict the market. compete. To analyze whether it constitutes restricted trading behavior, the following factors can be considered: requiring operators within the platform to &quot;choose one&quot; between competing platforms, or other behavior that restricts trading counterparties to conduct exclusive transactions with them...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In other words, the platform&#39;s requirement for merchants to &quot;choose one of two&quot; may be regarded as &quot;abusing market dominance&quot; and &quot;eliminating or restricting market competition&quot;, thus triggering an antitrust investigation. This is why Li Jiaqi&#39;s company denies &quot;choose one of two&quot;. But now who can deny that Li Jiaqi is a platform? “Choose one from two” essentially forces businesses to choose only themselves. As for why Heidegger stood up to the &quot;strong&quot; Li Jiaqi this time, it should be the result of weighing his own pros and cons. Therefore, it is also worthy of concern whether this confrontation will lead to consequences for regulatory agencies and antitrust law enforcement agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, it is still an industry practice for leading anchors to require merchants to sign the &quot;lowest price agreement in the entire network.&quot; The so-called &quot;the pricing power of Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast products lies in the brand&quot; is obviously unconvincing and is just a rhetoric or a rhetoric to avoid legal risks. There are two further points to interpret this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, as the economy enters the era of medium-low growth and stock market, the involution among all platforms is intensifying. From e-commerce platforms to top anchors, in fact, the game methods of all Internet platforms are being simplified, and winning with price has become a trend, because now consumers are most concerned about price. Your head anchor wants to offer the lowest price on the entire network. Why can’t my e-commerce platform offer a lower price than yours? In other words, this is a competition for the title and persona of &quot;lowest price on the entire network&quot;. The goal of many e-commerce platforms is to take back this title and persona and establish a &quot;mental footprint&quot; among consumers. This is the business logic and essence behind this matchup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law&quot; revised in mid-2022 does not clearly include provisions for the &quot;lowest price on the entire network&quot; for leading anchors. However, according to the logic of the Anti-Monopoly Law, merchants must guarantee to the live broadcast platform within a few months that it must be the lowest price in the entire network relative to all other platforms and channels. This may be regarded as an abuse of market dominance. Article 22 of this requirement is clear. Clause: &quot;Other abuse of market dominance determined by the anti-monopoly law enforcement agency of the State Council.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, regarding this alignment, we must also pay close attention to the regulator’s attitude and views on the long-term “floor price agreement” in all fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家发改委解读2024年放假安排：史上最长春节假期]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259264]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Five highlights of the 2024 holiday arrangement] The annual holiday arrangement has always been a social A focus topic that the public pays high attention to and is eagerly awaiting. After overall coordination and comprehensive consideration, the General Office of the State Council released some holiday arrangements for 2024 in a timely manner. This holiday arrangement mainly presents five major highlights:&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Highlight 1: 9 days, the longest Spring Festival holiday in history&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2024 Spring Festival At least 8 days of vacation, from the first day to the eighth day of the lunar month. If combined with paid leave, you can have 9 days of vacation, which can be called the first gift package of the new year. Although there is no nominal holiday on New Year&#39;s Eve, all units and institutions are encouraged to make flexible arrangements based on actual conditions. At the same time, the expressway has been made free of charge, which essentially creates conditions to give people an extra day off. The extension of the Spring Festival holiday can satisfy the general public&#39;s wish to have more time for family reunions, and can also achieve the small goal of reuniting first and traveling later during the holiday. This is an innovative and heart-warming move based on the provisions of the National Holidays and Anniversary Holidays, which fully reflects the good intentions and careful design of the policy makers. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Highlight 2: It has to be adjusted, but it is more humane and flexible&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Adjusted leave is a common public holiday arrangement. On the topic of concern, whether and how to adjust vacation time, the current public opinions vary greatly. Generally speaking, adjusting the vacation is better than not adjusting the vacation, and it is necessary to adjust the vacation. Because among the seven statutory holidays, the Spring Festival, Dragon Boat Festival and Mid-Autumn Festival are determined according to the lunar calendar, New Year&#39;s Day, Labor Day and National Day are determined according to the Gregorian calendar, and Qingming Festival is determined according to solar terms, which is different from the Gregorian calendar. The weekends are not connected enough. If there is no adjustment, there will basically be one working day between some holidays and weekends every year, resulting in the &quot;fragmentation&quot; of holidays, resulting in many &quot;single jumps&quot;, which is not &quot;tired sleep&quot; &quot;Don&#39;t love&quot;, but &quot;tired and don&#39;t love&quot;. Adjusted holidays are effective policy arrangements made to avoid the &quot;fragmentation&quot; of holidays on the premise that the total number of holidays is fixed. In 2024, through the adjustment of holidays, a &quot;9573&quot; holiday schedule will be formed, showing strong humanization and flexibility. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Highlight 3: Minimal intervention, try not to disrupt people’s normal life rhythm&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;The holidays throughout the year in 2024 will be relatively balanced. The secondment is close to the weekend, with at least 8 days for Spring Festival, 7 days for National Day, 5 days for Labor Day, 3 days for New Year&#39;s Day, Tomb Sweeping Day, Dragon Boat Festival, and Mid-Autumn Festival. The longest working day after the long holiday is only 6 days. The adjustment range is relatively small to avoid problems. The long working hours after the long vacation better meet people&#39;s actual needs for a balance between work and rest. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Highlight 4: Combining long and short periods to better meet people’s travel requirements and vacation expectations&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;my country’s legal holidays have a time distribution of “upper There are characteristics such as &quot;more in the first half of the year and less in the second half of the year&quot; and &quot;shorter in the first half of the year and longer in the second half of the year&quot;. Five of them are concentrated in the first half of the year. This holiday arrangement fully takes into account the date characteristics of these statutory holidays, forming a holiday distribution of four 3-day short holidays, one 5-day long holiday, one 7-day long holiday, and one 9-day super long holiday, which better realizes the balance between long holidays and Short vacations are intertwined. Through a reasonable combination of long and short vacations, people can make travel plans and arrangements for the whole year in advance, have more and better date choices for family visits, leisure, tourism, etc., and avoid &quot;swarm&quot; travel and &quot;gathering&quot; tourism. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Highlight 5: Encourage the implementation of paid annual leave to better protect the people’s rest rights and interests&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;For the first time, the State Council issued a document to encourage Combined with the implementation of systems such as paid annual leave, it is essentially advocating that enterprises and institutions should be able to do whatever they can on the premise of ensuring basic operations. my country&#39;s current total number of legal holidays is 11 days, with 104 days of weekend rest and 5-15 days of paid leave. The total number of holiday days is at an above-average level internationally. The reason why everyone still feels that there are not enough vacations and a weak sense of gain is mainly because the paid annual leave system is not implemented in place. We cannot blame the statutory holiday arrangements and adjusted leave. This holiday arrangement is a very clever exploration by encouraging employers to include the New Year&#39;s Eve holiday into the paid annual leave arrangement. Relatively speaking, paid annual leave has longer vacation time and more flexible arrangements, which is more suitable for people&#39;s objective needs of off-peak travel and scattered arrangements. Only by coordinating and arranging paid annual leave and legal holidays can workers&#39; rest rights be more protected and fully protected&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吸食除尘罐的女孩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The girls hallucinate after smoking dust cans. (Nongjian/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1152 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Girls hallucinate after smoking dust cans. (Nong Jian/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The night Chen Minru was burned by the fire, she had a hallucination: a disheveled monster slowly approached with a rolling electric saw. A pair of red eyes stared at Chen Minru&#39;s best friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I quickly protected my bestie, which scared me to tears.&quot; When I woke up in the middle of the night, nothing happened. Chen Minru looked around and saw that most of the people in the room were already asleep. Eight young people under the age of 20 were crammed into three beds, seven women and one man, four of whom were underage. The high-pressure gas dust canisters they had just smoked were scattered all over the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;High-pressure gas dust removal tank, a liquid spray device used to clean computer keyboards, cameras or dead corners of dust in car interiors. The main component is HFC cleaning gas, which is sprayed In an instant, the liquid will turn into a strong airflow. Its slogan reads: The airflow is strong enough to easily blow a 132-gram mouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of June 17, 2023, eight people, including Chen Minru, smoked dust canisters in Room 501 of Rulan Hotel in Shangluo City, Shaanxi Province. &quot;Sucking that thing can cause hallucinations.&quot; 17-year-old Chen Minru told Southern Weekend reporters that the gas emitted from the dust removal canister smells astringent and is not easy to inhale. &quot;When I started smoking that day, my face still hurt a little, and then I started hallucinating. I woke up and wanted to smoke.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Minru didn&#39;t pay attention to the bottle of the dust collector. Instructions: Do not expose to environments above 40 degrees Celsius, and do not throw into fire. The product description also states: Keep away from heat sources to prevent the can from exploding. That day, there were forty or fifty bottles of dust removal cans in the room, some of which had not been finished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At about 3 o&#39;clock in the morning on the 18th, Chen Minru pressed the lighter, and 19-year-old Guo Zhen was sleeping soundly in the next bed. The fate of the two girls was completely reversed. , the two families behind them fell into the abyss together. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I forgot how many cans I smoked”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the light on the ceiling exploded with a bang. Chen Minru&#39;s face was closest to the lighter and caught fire first, rolling around on the ground crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several girls woke up one after another, with sparks lighting up on their bodies, and they ran around the room anxiously. The door couldn&#39;t be opened, so they ran into the bathroom and turned on the shower. &quot;But the water was hot, scalding, so we ran out again,&quot; Chen Minru recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen is still asleep, and her reaction is much slower. Afterwards, she recalled that when she was picked up by a good friend, she was still in a daze and lost her mind when she saw the fire in front of her. The curtains and quilts against the wall were full of fire, and they burned more and more intensely. It wasn&#39;t until about 10 minutes later, when Guo Zhen opened the door that was locked from the inside, that he noticed that his hands had turned out and his knuckles were clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This scene was photographed by residents in the building opposite the hotel. A video taken that night showed a raging fire coming out of the window of Room 501, and the crackling sounds were mixed with the girls&#39; calls for help. Eight people ran down the stairs from the fifth floor and stopped a patrolling police car on the road. Ambulances and fire engines arrived later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In the early morning of June 18, 2023, residents near the incident site took photos of the fire. (Photo courtesy of the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early morning of June 18, 2023, Residents near the scene took photos of the fire. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was past 6 o&#39;clock in the morning, and Chen Shuai had not yet entered the door of the emergency room of Shangluo Central Hospital. He was far away&lt;span>; I smelled the smell of burning skin, &quot;My hair was so fried that I couldn&#39;t even recognize who it was&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;Eight burnt-black children lay on stretchers, spread out in a row. Chen Shuai saw a red-haired girl and was sure it was his sister Chen Minru. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen’s mother He Weili came earlier. Guo&#39;s father recalled that at 4 a.m. on June 18, his wife received a call from the police saying that her daughter was in the hospital. She rushed in and hugged a girl and cried. Guo Zhen next to him made a trembling voice, &quot;Mom, I&#39;m here,&quot; and then fainted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The doctor diagnosed that among the eight people, Chen Minru and Guo Zhen had the most serious burns, and they were recommended to be sent to a large hospital in Xi&#39;an for treatment. Their burn wounds were distributed on the head and face, front and rear trunks and limbs, and the grades were all between II and III. The burn area of ​​Chen Minru&#39;s body surface was as high as 75%, and that of Guo Zhen was 60%-69%, both of which were extremely severe burns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The remaining 6 people suffered minor injuries. The mildest one only injured the skin of the calf, and you could go out for activities the next day. Five people suffered burns all over their limbs, and they have been healing by applying medicine at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A girl with burnt limbs concluded that there are two &quot;culprits&quot;, one is the cigarette lighter, and the other is Xu Kexin who organized everyone to smoke dust cans . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Kexin, a 15-year-old girl from rural Shangluo. People in the circle who hang out with her say that Xu Kexin&#39;s family is poor, but she has never been short of money since she came out to join the society early, and her food and clothing are of a much higher standard than those in her circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She said, she smoked &#39;Mrs. Shuang&#39; and let me try it.&quot; In early 2023, when Guo Zhen was playing with Xu Kexin in Xi&#39;an, he touched the high-pressure dust removal tank for the first time. The smell was so disgusting that I couldn&#39;t inhale it, but I finally came to accept it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also saw Xu Kexin smoking from another unnamed aluminum can. &quot;It was a very big can. She said that after smoking it, it felt much better than a dust can.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Shangluo, Shaanxi, the place where the dust collector explosion occurred. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/6743675af5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /6743675af5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shangluo, Shaanxi, where the dust tank explosion occurred. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen recalled that on the night of the incident, Xu Kexin &quot;couldn&#39;t wait any longer and really wanted to smoke&quot;, so she booked a room at the Rulan Hotel and invited her friends to come over and smoke together. I placed two orders for the dust removal canister. I bought it in stock in the same city at a high price of 80 yuan per can, and it was quickly delivered to the hotel room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It costs about ten yuan to buy a bottle online, but it costs 80 yuan to buy it from others.&quot; On the evening of October 9, Xu Kexin told me on the phone A reporter from Southern Weekend said that he bought forty or fifty dust removal cans that night. “That thing makes me want to sleep as soon as I hit it. I forgot how many cans I smoked.”&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“I can’t control it, there’s nothing I can do”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 9, a Southern Weekend reporter walked into Chen Minru&#39;s ward and was greeted by a strong smell of burn cream. She was supporting the board with her elbows and heels, lifting her bandaged legs in turn, and slowly moved laterally to the hospital bed by the window, so that she could be closer to the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the 4th month after Chen Minru was burned. Her body has been skin grafted twice, and her face is covered with pitted scars. &lt;span>;The skin&lt;/span>; is as solid as plastic. surface, even reflective. This is completely different from the girl with lively eyes in her circle of friends and short video account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the video, Chen Minru has fair skin, big eyes, and pouty lips. She has a figure that is envied by her friends. She is 165cm tall and likes to wear short shorts and JK uniforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photos of Chen Minru before she was burned. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/93b62d9453.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/93b62d9453. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photo of Chen Minru before being burned. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen was lying on bed No. 30, two wards away from Chen Minru, with his whole body covered with gauze, except for his arms and The hand can move to a small extent, but other parts cannot move at all. Like Chen Minru, she was dressed exquisitely in short videos in the past, and there was no hint of her ordinary family background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is posted by people who live in a mixed society and do not learn well.&quot; In 2022, Chen Shuai added his sister WeChat for the first time, browsed the circle of friends, and felt She has changed a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Minru has two brothers. 23-year-old Chen Shuai is the eldest, but Chen Minru and her brothers have not seen each other several times since they were young. In 2009, when Chen Minru was 3 years old, her father was imprisoned for a crime. Her mother, Pan Yafang, was so stimulated that she became mentally ill and the family fell apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;My grandma took her two brothers to her hometown. They favored boys over girls and didn&#39;t want me.&quot; Living a wandering life with Pan Yafang made Chen Minru often hate herself. She stared at the ceiling of the ward and shed tears, &quot;Everyone in my family hates me, so I shouldn&#39;t have been born in this family.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;When Chen Minru’s grandmother heard about it, she cried and explained, “The family’s conditions are not good and we can’t afford to support her.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Chen Minru was five years old, she followed Pan Yafang by train to Xi’an to make a living. . Xi&#39;an is too big, and Pan Yafang only knows the old train station. The mother and daughter live at the foot of the city wall next to the train station, filling their stomachs with food every day at the aid station that helps homeless people. After wandering for a period of time, Pan Yafang would take her daughter back to Shangluo and stay with her sister or brother. She had no money and was reluctant to spend money. Chen Minru claimed to have learned how to steal money from relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pan Yafang always has disheveled hair, a touch of chicken blood, and three strings of colorful plastic beads on her wrists and neck. These are all magic weapons she begged from the temple to ward off evil spirits. Chen Minru said that her mother did not know how to cook and did not live at home. She often danced outside. As a result, Chen Minru was lost for more than ten days. She lost her footing and fell into a pool, almost choking to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is not a home at all, it feels like a stranger.&quot; Living in a muddle, Chen Minru became a typical rebellious girl, she described I am &quot;a bit of a mixed bag&quot;. I entered a vocational middle school through my relatives&#39; connections. I don&#39;t want to go to school and often spend the night at my friends&#39; houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Chen Shuai, who was working outside, returned to Shangluo and worked in a car factory to make money. He took the initiative to contact Chen Minru and had a serious chat. If Chen Minru was willing, he could assume the role of father. Chen Minru agreed without hesitation, &quot;My brother said that he will do his best to control me until I am 18 years old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Shuai restrained his sister&#39;s first One condition is that you don&#39;t want to hang out with people from society. Chen Minru obviously didn&#39;t listen. She would still skip classes to find friends. She also beat a fourteen-year-old or fifteen-year-old child so badly that the police called Chen Shuai after getting drunk. In Shaanxi dialect, he described his sister as a &quot;second-rate person&quot; with no brains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zenghu said that he also received many calls from the police station, all because of his daughter Guo Zhen. Either Guo Zhen asked a group of friends to beat others, or someone asked a group of friends to beat Guo Zhen. &quot;He stayed like that all day and didn&#39;t study.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If this accident had not happened, Guo Zhen and Guo Zenghu would still be strangers. They had already verbally severed the relationship between father and daughter and had no relationship for two years. connect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I can&#39;t control her. She has a boyish personality and is very wild.&quot; He Weili said that the couple had nothing to do with this daughter. Guo Zenghu was helpless. He was 57 years old and still had to worry about his daughter. &quot;If I can&#39;t control it, I won&#39;t be called to come here. I won&#39;t come back for a year and a half.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since he was 17 years old, Guo Zhen ran away from home. I worked several jobs, and finally worked as a waiter at a bar with two friends. Guo Zenghu didn&#39;t know about Guo Zhen&#39;s early smoking and drinking, but he wasn&#39;t surprised when he heard, &quot;In rural areas, people make different kinds of friends. They are like this in their circle. It&#39;s okay to just follow those kids.&quot; Good habits”&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 9, 2023, Shangluo, Shaanxi, He Weili takes care of Guo Zhen for dinner. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255334&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, in Shangluo, Shaanxi, He Weili took care of Guo Zhen for dinner. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I just don’t want to go home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That was not the case at first. Guo Zenghu missed Guo Zhen when he was a child, &quot;very well-behaved, very well-behaved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Guo Zhen was six or seven years old, he would clean the house. When Guo Zenghu and his wife came back from planting corn in the fields, their little daughter would bring them face wash. Once, when Xiao Guo Zhen was helping to boil water, he accidentally put his arm into the iron pot of boiling water and burned a large area of ​​his arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;What I value most is this daughter.&quot; The Guo family has three daughters. In the past, family conditions were not good, and the eldest dropped out of school midway through school; He was sent to a relative&#39;s home for foster care. Finally, there is the third child, Guo Zhen. Guo Zenghu is determined to raise his little daughter well without leaving any regrets. &quot;I will let her study hard. Whatever she can learn, the family will do everything possible to show it.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen is also quite successful. After elementary school, he was admitted to the best private junior high school in Shangluo. Guo Zenghu moved his family from the countryside to the city. During the high school entrance examination, Guo Zhen was admitted to Shangluo Middle School, the best local school. However, within a year, he was expelled from the school for fighting. Guo Zenghu hates that iron cannot be made into steel, &quot;The two women often said that I was partial and thought that I valued Guo Zhen the most, but I didn&#39;t expect that it would end up like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I came from my hometown to study in the city and turned bad. .&quot; In Guo Zenghu&#39;s impression, the junior high school teacher notified him several times to go to school and suggested that Guo Zhen transfer to another school, stop being in the city, and just make some friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in Guo Zhen&#39;s view, this matter became a knot in her mind because she was afraid of Guo Zenghu. Since elementary school, she has not dared to let her father attend parent-teacher meetings, fearing that he would lose his temper after hearing bad comments. Whenever he couldn&#39;t solve a question, Guo Zenghu picked up the broom and chased her in front of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the junior high school teacher reported the problem, Guo Zenghu’s attitude became more severe. &quot;My dad started scolding me, and I had to stare at the book every day. I was very good at that time, but the teacher said that I was hanging out with the second-rate people in the outside world, and wouldn&#39;t let my good friends play with me, and kept targeting me. &quot;Guo Zhen said, feeling aggrieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During that time, the teacher assigned a lot of homework, and Guo Zhen gradually became more and more stressed. &quot;I am not good at studying, so they don&#39;t understand. If I don&#39;t do well in the exam, I will When it comes to me, I don’t praise myself for passing the exam, I have no motivation, and I feel like I can’t stay at home. In addition, I fell in love with someone in class, and we had a quarrel, so I cried all night.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;She began to suffer from insomnia frequently, and was frightened by nightmares in the middle of the night. She screamed nonsense, and took the initiative to show He Weili the scars on her wrists. &quot;Mom, what if I jump into the reservoir and a fish bites me?&quot; &quot;I What if I climb to the roof and survive the fall but become disabled?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Weili has never studied. She doesn’t understand this, so she takes her daughter to Xi’an. I spent eight to nine thousand yuan to see a doctor in a big hospital, but no problem was found. &quot;The doctor said that the baby is under too much pressure and the family is too strict. If the baby is given some time and space to relax, it might be better.&quot; He Weili guessed that the baby has been beaten and scolded by her father since she was a child, which made her depressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The burn scar on his arm when he was a child was covered up by Guo Zhen quietly &lt;span>;writing&lt;/span>; a pattern in a non-mainstream style. The pattern is of a scarred two-headed teddy bear. One head has an expressionless face, and the other head has empty eyes wide open, revealing a mouth of fangs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guo Zhen&#39;s tattoo on his arm scar. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/be5077424b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /be5077424b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zhen’s pattern on the arm scar. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Guo Zhen&#39;s emotional problems, Guo Zenghu also had a headache, &quot;I&#39;m stupid and the baby is a girl. I don&#39;t know what to do.&quot; Communicate.&quot; In this way, Guo Zhen was &quot;relaxed.&quot; He found that his daughter&#39;s temper was getting worse and worse. &quot;I hit her lightly, and she wanted to make the building collapse and jump off it again. In the end, she didn&#39;t even come into the house. As soon as I talked about her, she went out to live. She didn&#39;t answer the phone calls and didn&#39;t reply to messages. You think this is the last thing. What can we do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It wasn&#39;t until Guo Zhen was expelled from Shangluo Middle School when she was in her first year of high school that Guo Zenghu beat her again and proposed to sever the relationship between father and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He not only beat me, but also called my sister to come back and beat me. My sister hit me on the head with a lamp.&quot; After the beating, Guo Zhen moved out Every time He Weili asked her to go home, she would first ask if her father was at home. &quot;He only knows how to curse, and keeps hitting me, slapping me, and hitting me with a stick. Anyway, he just doesn&#39;t want to go home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​day, Guo Zenghu bumped into me on the road. When he got to Guo Zhen, whom he had lost contact with for a long time, he slapped her several times in public. For the first time, Guo Zhen had the idea of ​​fighting back, so she called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When mentioning this incident, Guo Zhen cried so hard that he couldn&#39;t breathe. &lt;span>;He&lt;/span>; Wei Li on the side was &lt;span>;very&lt;/span>; surprised. She had never seen her daughter shed a single tear after the dust canister explosion accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A downtrodden family&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen saw Guo Zenghu, who always had a straight face, cried every day. &quot;He lay next to me and looked at me every day, and cried as he watched.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hospital began to say that the hope was not very high.&quot; Guo Zenghu recalled, When he first went to the hospital in Xi&#39;an, the doctor told him to be mentally prepared because Guo Zhen&#39;s lungs were severely burned. &lt;p>; After the skin was removed, the skin was still eroded. &quot;The more I look at it, the more hopeless it becomes. The worst-case scenario is that I want to jump off the building, but I can&#39;t hold it up anymore.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen took the initiative to give up the treatment, &quot;I don&#39;t want to be treated anymore, you can go back and don&#39;t worry about me&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I really don&#39;t want to care about her, but &lt;span>;she&lt;/span>; is my woman after all, so I can&#39;t bear to leave her.&quot; Guo Zenghu really didn&#39;t Qian continued his treatment. He was just a worker working at a construction site. During chestnut harvesting season, he collected chestnuts everywhere. He had saved less than 100,000 yuan over the years, and raised more than 300,000 yuan with relatives. It was not enough to put it all in. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Shuai experienced exactly the same suffering as Guo Zenghu. After Chen Minru&#39;s accident, he borrowed money from all the relatives he knew and didn&#39;t know to collect 400,000 yuan. After staying in the hospital for 40 days in Xi&#39;an, he couldn&#39;t afford it anymore, so he had to take his sister back to Shangluo Central Hospital for continued treatment. Later, he owed more than 40,000 yuan to Shangluo Central Hospital. After being urged to pay the fee over and over again by the hospital, he stopped going to the hospital, and Chen Minru was forced to stop taking medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If she learns well, I will give her my life, but she won&#39;t obey.&quot; Chen Shuai retracted his head &lt;span>;in&lt;/span>; his collar, The voice is deep. At first, the 23-year-old boy refused to be interviewed several times. He wanted to be cruel and stay away from everything about his sister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the years, Chen Shuai&#39;s performance is actually not much better than Chen Minru&#39;s. Although it has been taken over by grandparents, it is also in a free-range state. At the age of 8, he followed the second-rate kids into the supermarket to steal snacks to satisfy his hunger. When he grew up, he spent all day in Internet cafes just to have a place to live. At the age of 13, he started working outside to make money on his own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Approaching this strange sister made his already tight life even worse. In just one year, Chen Minru first fell seriously into a ditch while riding an electric bicycle. She fainted and was admitted to the hospital several times because of her weak body. Once Chen Minru had an appendicitis attack, and the operation cost 20,000 to 30,000 yuan, which was all handled by Chen Shuai. What made him especially heartbroken was that Chen Minru was absent from class without telling him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She said she went to school. I asked the teacher, and the teacher said she didn&#39;t go. She didn&#39;t go home, she just hung out.&quot; Chen Shuai was furious, &quot;As long as you tell me that you don&#39;t want me to care about you, I will never care about you in the future.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;Chen Minru also had a firm attitude and replied, &quot;Don&#39;t worry about me.&quot; Since then, the two have lost contact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until the day before the incident, the Dragon Boat Festival was approaching. Chen Shuai had not seen Chen Minru for two months. He took the initiative to send a message saying that his family had made rice dumplings. Chen Minru also hoped that the relationship between brother and sister could be eased and promised to go back to her hometown to eat rice dumplings in two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The brother and sister met again in the hospital. Chen Shuai hated and felt sorry for this sister, &quot;At that time, I really wanted to leave her alone. This was all She did it herself&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fire caused by the dust can completely overwhelmed Chen Shuai. He quit his job, sold his motorcycle worth 13,000 yuan, was almost penniless, and had a debt of more than 400,000 yuan. Even if he didn&#39;t go to the hospital, his mother and sister would have to rely on him for food and money. He had no intention of looking for a job anymore. He slept during the day and thought wildly at night. He felt that life was hazy. &quot;I don&#39;t know what I should do now, and I have no motivation to do anything.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Regret and nostalgia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a moment, Guo Zenghu thought that his deviant daughter was about to get back on track, &quot;There needs to be someone.&quot; That’s it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;On the afternoon of the accident, she called the cargo puller and moved all the large and small boxes of things back.&quot; Guo Zenghu heard his daughter say that he would be in Live at home. &quot;When I saw it, she didn&#39;t live outside anymore. She seemed to have changed her mind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What Guo Zhen didn&#39;t tell Guo Zenghu was that she was kicked out by the landlord. , because Xu Kexin always takes her friends to play in rental houses. That night, after Guo Zhen went out, He Weili made several calls to ask her to go home, but Guo Zhen still didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The real change of heart is in the hospital bed. Guo Zhen told her father again and again that she really knew she was wrong. But when he learned that Guo Zhen would still keep in touch with Xu Kexin, Guo Zenghu was so angry that he scolded Guo Zhen again and again for his unrepentance. &quot;She still hasn&#39;t repented of herself and is still in contact with those people. Now I just want to do my best to take good care of the baby. After she is cured, she will do whatever she likes, and I won&#39;t care about her.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But for Guo Zhen, she only has these friends. They all come from rural areas and have similar family backgrounds and preferences. &quot;I am happy to be with them. Say whatever you want to say.&quot; What, do whatever you want to do”&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She didn&#39;t listen to me.&quot; Guo Zenghu was scared just thinking about it. The hospital said that Guo Zhen would not be able to return to normal skin after recovery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For girls, the most important thing is their face.&quot; After the accident, Chen Minru, who was originally talkative, became &lt;span>;rejected&lt;/span>; into a man of few words. She was particularly worried about the disfigurement, and kept thinking about the past scenes in her mind. She obviously had many opportunities to avoid this disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t know how to smoke that thing, and I can&#39;t light it up.&quot; Chen Minru said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If time could go back to the past, I would not come back from Jiangsu.&quot; The day before the incident, Chen Minru had just returned to Shangluo from an internship in Jiangsu. It is said to be an internship, but it is actually a summer labor dispatch job arranged by the vocational school. She was sent to a television factory by her school. She wore dustproof clothing and stood on the assembly line in the workshop for 12 hours every day, from 7:00 in the morning to 7:30 in the evening. After two months, she earned More than 5,000 yuan. To her, this was a huge sum of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although the days of working were hard, the staff dormitory was spacious and life was smooth. After thinking about it, Chen Minru also regretted why she didn&#39;t listen to her brother&#39;s words in the first place. &quot;It was too confusing at the time. I got used to that state over time.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being transferred back to Shangluo from Xi&#39;an for hospitalization, Chen Minru heard about a similar accident that happened in Shangluo. A group of children gathered together to smoke dust cans. One of them, a 13-year-old boy, swallowed 40 pills in order to seek happiness. &quot;It is said that the hallucinations he had were particularly terrifying. They were all green, happy and painful.&quot;&lt; span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the online shopping platform, a suspected smoker looks at the dust can Product reviews. Internet screenshots&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;975 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the online shopping platform, suspected smokers commented on dust removal can products. (Internet screenshot/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the boy huddled on the ground, twitching all over, foaming at the mouth, and asked his friends to call 120. &quot;A few other people didn&#39;t dare call the police. When they finally dared to call an ambulance, the person was already dead when they arrived at the hospital.&quot; Chen Minru sighed, &quot;At least I&#39;m still alive, so I&#39;m lucky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she quickly changed her mind. Every night, every inch of skin and bones in the body aches. What made her even more uncomfortable was that her mother, who had no ability to live independently, did not know how to take care of others. She was chatty and kept talking about herself. She would also suddenly lose control of her emotions, pointing at Chen Minru and yelling at her for having no conscience, and quarreling in the ward. Continuously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I might as well just die.&quot; Chen Minru turned her head away, tears overflowed, and she shouted with all her strength, &quot;Can you see how pitiful I am, and don&#39;t do it again?&quot; You&#39;re talking about me.&quot; But after calming down, Chen Minru felt distressed again when she saw Pan Yafang eating moldy leftovers, &quot;I have hated her during these years of wandering, but it&#39;s not easy for her to drag me down so much.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of October 21st, Chen Minru posted a post on Moments. It was a video taken with her best friend. In the video, she puffed out her cheeks. , a cute pet filter is added to the tip of the nose, shaking the head and looking cute. She wrote three words: &quot;I miss you very much.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(Chen Minru, Guo Zhen, Xu Kexin and Pan Yafang are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不出奇葩政策”：搞好中国足球，“不做什么”比“要做什么”更重要丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259252]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, Song Kai, the new chairman of the Chinese Football Association, made it clear at a symposium that &quot;the Chinese Football Association will never We can no longer introduce weird policies, this is the bottom line, and the policies introduced must meet social expectations.&quot; This statement aroused widespread attention and heated discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Song Kai is facing this time when he takes office is that the aftermath of the anti-corruption storm in football is raging, and all walks of life are annoyed and critical of Chinese football. Chinese football is still at a low point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Kai’s speech that “no weird policies can be made” has won him a lot of praise. There is no other reason. In the past few years, the Chinese Football Association has launched many bizarre policies that achieve half the result with half the effort or even be counterproductive. Take the &quot;New Policy for U23 (Under 23) Players&quot; launched by the Football Association in the past few years as an example. The original intention of this policy is to allow young players to get more playing time in the league and to cultivate more outstanding domestic players. However, in the process from policy formulation to implementation, the outside world has witnessed a farce of &quot;weird and unlimited&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2017 professional league season, the Chinese Football Association’s regulations are that there must be two U23 players in the 18-man roster, and one of them must start. As a result, in order to ensure results first, each team implemented the operation of &quot;replacing young players when they come on&quot; and &quot;replacing them in stoppage time to improve data&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 season, the Football Association upgraded this policy to &quot;the number of U23 players playing must not be less than the number of foreign players playing.&quot; This policy ultimately backfired. Each team would rather not recruit foreign players than give U23 players a chance. How to arrange U23 players to appear on the court to &quot;brush data&quot; has even become an &quot;arithmetic problem&quot; for the coaches of each team. In 2023, the U23 policy has to be cancelled. Over the course of six or seven years, this policy became a typical example of &quot;mission creep,&quot; with goals and means completely out of touch and a huge waste of resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The weird thing about the U23 policy is that it goes against the fundamental laws of football and the market laws of professional leagues. If young players are capable, they can get playing time without the help of policies; young players who are incompetent will not win the starting position even if they are given time forcibly. Forcibly asking for &quot;given opportunities&quot; seems to be training young players, but in the end it hurts everyone&#39;s interests. Not only did this operation of forcibly converting effects into causes arouse ridicule from the outside world, but the process of removing seedlings to encourage growth also yielded a lot of feathers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U23 policy is just one of the many weird policies of the Chinese Football Association. Therefore, if you want the work of the Chinese Football Association to &quot;comply with social expectations&quot; and if you want to do a good job in Chinese football, what you should consider is not necessarily &quot;what the Chinese Football Association should do&quot;, but &quot;what the Chinese Football Association should not do&quot;. I&#39;m afraid this This is the lesson that the new Football Association leadership team should remember. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Song Kai&#39;s speech, &quot;no weird policies&quot; is the keynote of the argument, and he also has the vision of &quot;the youth competition system must remain stable&quot;, showing his ambition to bring order to things. In fact, by extending this line of thought, we can also think deeply about what kind of binary relationship the &quot;Chinese Football Association&quot; and &quot;Chinese Football&quot; should have in order to better meet social expectations. Or to put it more directly, can we really only rely on the Chinese Football Association to improve Chinese football? The answer is probably not so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To evaluate whether a country&#39;s football is prosperous, we cannot simply use the national team&#39;s performance as the criterion. In addition, there are many fields such as the league system, football industry, and football culture. In these areas, a national football association does not have the ability to take over everything, nor does it have the power to issue orders. It is completely unreasonable to expect that football in a country can be revitalized by administrative hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Football is a very scientific sport. Only by returning to objective laws can we truly improve football, and this requires the joint efforts of the whole society. The Chinese Football Association still should not overestimate its own capabilities, let alone artificially expand its own power, hoping that it can fundamentally improve such a huge compound concept as &quot;Chinese Football&quot; on its own. Rather than saying that the goal of the Chinese Football Association is to be a good manager of Chinese football, it is better to say that it should strive to be a good service provider, do a good job in administrative services, let private football institutions make their own decisions, and let the market judge the choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Chinese football does not lack a folk foundation. The high attendance rate of the Chinese Super League and the popularity of the &quot;Village Super League&quot; all show the potential of Chinese football culture and the possibilities of the football industry. What the Chinese Football Association should do is respect the autonomy and self-construction of the private football system, and at least not use &quot;weird policies&quot; to destroy the football soil that is still growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentine star Valdano once said, “Football does not belong to any one person. Everyone must have a sense of ownership of this wonderful sport, and football also needs everyone to have a little control over it. Otherwise, excessive concentration of power will inevitably lead to corruption. Even in the football industry, no one can surpass this law.&quot; From the separation of management and management to &quot;good service&quot;, the Chinese Football Association&#39;s statement of &quot;no weird policies&quot; is just a step forward The first step is to hand over this wonderful sport of football to everyone who loves football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>