<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[蔡磊：“抗冻”先行者向死而生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the fate of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 997&quot; height=&quot;1496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250528&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/251236&quot; title=&quot;Cai Lei: Hunting Medicine The shock caused by the patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&quot;>;Cai Lei: The shock caused by the drug-hunting patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After lumbar puncture , a bottle of liquid was quietly pushed into the spinal cavity of Nanjing (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;pseudonym&lt;/span>;) from outside the body through a needle. A few days later, her family discovered that her hands could support the armrests of her wheelchair and help her stand on her own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years ago, Nan Jing, who was in her early 20s, suddenly found it difficult to lift her left leg. Since then, her condition has deteriorated rapidly, and it has become increasingly difficult for her to walk. Several times while going up and down the steps of the work commuter bus, Nanjing fell to the ground and was almost run over by a vehicle speeding behind him. Soon, she was diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early June 2023, Nanjing was enrolled in the clinical trial of a new single-gene drug that Cai Lei and a team of scientists collaborated with Beijing Tiantan Hospital, and has used the drug four times so far. Although her leg muscle strength has not improved significantly, she has made great progress compared to the time before when she had to be helped by her family to stand up. For Cai Lei, who has led the team to develop drugs and fight ALS for more than four years, this is a historic breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nanjing is lucky, but there are still 500,000 ALS patients around the world who are in urgent need of the attention and assistance of the whole society.&quot; Cai Lei said. &quot;Furthermore, Nanjing belongs to the SOD1 subtype, which accounts for less than 2% of all patients. The other subtypes and the pathology of sporadic ALS are still a mystery, waiting to be explored and solved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because A disease of the motor nerve cells in the brain and spinal cord, patients with ALS gradually weaken their muscles and eventually become completely paralyzed and lose their body functions. For more than a hundred years since its discovery, the pathology of ALS is unknown and there is no cure. Most patients die within 2 to 5 years of the disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly four years ago, Cai Lei, the former vice president of JD.com, was also diagnosed with ALS. In the industry, Cai Lei, who is full of passion, keen insight and action, and good at organizing and cooperating, is like a &quot;hard-working man&quot;. When he got sick, he was in his early forties and had just married and had a son. Being thrown into a sudden desperate situation, he also experienced despair. But within a month after his diagnosis, he decided to mobilize all the resources he had accumulated over half his life to invest in scientific research and drug development for ALS. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s impossible, it can’t be done.” These opinions from inside and outside the industry have never shaken Cai Lei’s belief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was difficult to get through patient data between hospitals, so he used the most primitive methods to build the world&#39;s largest big data platform for ALS patients through phone calls and WeChat exchanges; he visited the house again and again, He impressed a number of top scientists who were not involved in ALS research, including Chen Gong, Dai Jianwu, Lu Yunfeng, Meng Songdong, and Chen Lingling, to cooperate with him and promote the launch of more than 100 R&amp;D pipelines; he took the lead in signing letters of intent, leading more than a thousand patients and family members to Voluntarily donating brain and spinal cord tissue samples after his death; he shortened the recruitment of patients for clinical trials from the previous one or two years to the &quot;extreme speed&quot; of two hours...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether it is financial or professional, In fact, I am not the strongest candidate in the world to overcome ALS. But I don’t want to just sit and wait for medical progress. I have to do things that others have not done or done.” Cai Lei put the funds, Laboratories, scientists, pharmaceutical companies, hospitals, and patients are connected one by one, becoming the lubricant and booster in many aspects of basic research and the medical industry. He believes that only by making the fight against ALS a cause that is valuable and beneficial to all parties involved can it become a sharp blade to tear through the darkness and let light continuously shine in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is far from a simple inspirational story of an individual fighting against fate, but arousing the goodwill and motivation deep in the heart.” Xu Wanjiao, a medical practitioner who has been engaged in drug research and development for 15 years, sighed with emotion. &quot;Everyone approaches Teacher Cai because Teacher Cai approaches each other. This connection itself is a kind of energy and energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, Cai Lei has been a long-term staff member of Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China. When he was teaching a postgraduate student majoring in accounting at a university, he spoke frankly when faced with the confusion of young students. &quot;They often ask me, how can we be successful and respected? Some students think that our generation has many opportunities and can make money in anything, and is not as competitive as them. I want to say, which era is not fierce? Which era is not fierce? Is success not difficult? Struggle and progress are the life young people should pursue. Helping others can also reduce confusion and emptiness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After falling ill, Nanjing, who works as a clerk in Nanjing, can only use a wheelchair. as a companion. The mother is suffering from terminal cancer and needs to come to Beijing for treatment. The grandmother accompanies her daughter and granddaughter to rent a house and see a doctor in this strange city. Nanjing experienced anxiety and worry, not knowing what she could do. After meeting Cai Lei, she changed. &quot;I have no reason to be decadent. I can sweep the floor, mop the floor, and wash clothes. Whatever I can do is a little bit. Find your own meaning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter what your fate is, strive to continue to create value and live out your own spirit.&quot; This is the wealth that Cai Lei believes he can leave to the world, and his footsteps have not stopped yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the destiny of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[偷遍上海所有无印良品店铺，小偷夫妻自称“品牌代理”，半年赚26万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256731]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼师针扎孩子、对孩子使用麻黄碱：当让持扭曲价值观的人远离孩子丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256856]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Parents with children are very worried after reading this. On September 12, a parent of a young child in Shanghai posted a message: On March 24 this year, parents found injuries on their child who was studying at the Dahua Tadpole Music Park in Baoshan District, Shanghai, and suspected that the kindergarten teacher had abused the child. On March 27, the parents called the police, and the police issued an injury examination form for the child to go to the hospital for examination. &quot;The police issued an injury examination form to check the child&#39;s injuries that day because there were many bruises on his body. In the next few days, the police issued an injury examination form again.&quot; , doctors at the Children’s Hospital found multiple pinpoint-like holes.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hospital injury examination sheet uploaded by the parent showed that there were many pinpoint-like holes on the child&#39;s body. &quot;The parents immediately asked for a hair test. The results showed that all five children contained ephedrine, two of them.&quot; Child contains lidocaine&quot;. &quot;It has been more than half a year since the case was reported. Parents have suffered a lot. They have suffered from insomnia and nightmares. We just want to know the truth! What have the children experienced? What have they endured? What will happen to their physical condition in the future?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 13, a reporter from Dawan News called Dahua Tadpole Music Park. The kindergarten replied: &quot;You can go to the police station and they can give you the most correct answer, or the answer you want most.&quot; &quot;All our processes They all follow the arrangements of the Education Bureau and the police station.&quot; Subsequently, the reporter called the local police, but there was no reply; when calling the Baoshan District Education Bureau, a staff member said: &quot;We as a whole attach great importance to this matter and have been following up and handling it. We have also seen the content posted by parents on the Internet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Half a year has passed for such an abominable and suspected criminal incident, and there is neither any explanation nor any explanation as to whether the perpetrators have been dealt with. Below, it’s no wonder that parents are reluctant to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the nature of this matter is vile, and the relevant circumstances are outrageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the injury examination notice from the Shanghai Public Security Bureau uploaded by the parents, the parents stated that the boy was only four years old. The day before he was admitted to the hospital, the parents found a suspicious pinpoint-like hole. After asking the child, they learned that &quot;maybe There is abuse or use in clinical trials.&quot; On that day, fever symptoms appeared, with the highest temperature being 39 degrees; the test results were: &quot;Stomach and energy have become worse than before, there is tenderness in the penis and scrotum, and repeated swelling and pain.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s all because you have a little more. It looks like a needle-like hole, and some of it has healed. &quot;There are also many needle-like holes in the penis and scrotum.&quot; The test conclusion is: &quot;The scrotum is red, swollen, and tender.&quot; &quot;There are many suspicious needle-like holes all over the body. The purpose is unknown. The police need to be called.&quot; Collaborative treatment.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The parent said: &quot;All five children contained ephedrine (in their hair), and two of them contained lidocaine.&quot; If what is said is true, it would be even more terrifying. Because ephedrine has central nervous system stimulant effects, it is a drug-making raw material strictly controlled by the government. Lidocaine is a local anesthetic. Think about it, everyone. Even when you go to a pharmacy to buy pseudoephedrine, a drug that relieves cold symptoms, you have to buy it in limited quantities and register your ID number. Where did the perpetrators get these drugs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more questions: Are these &quot;needle-like holes&quot; just a needle stick in the child, or are they the marks left by using a syringe to inject ephedrine and lidocaine? For such a long period of time, many children have been systematically injected with acupuncture, ephedrine and lidocaine. Is it a crime committed by one person, or is it a coordinated crime by multiple people? Where is the perpetrator now? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time a kindergarten teacher stabbed a child with a needle. Similar incidents have been exposed many times and occur all over the country. Therefore, we must consider the possibility of imitating crimes and abetting crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2019, the Tianjin Binhai New District Court held the first public hearing on the case of two middle five teachers of the Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten suspected of abusing their care recipients. The prosecutor alleged: From July to October 2018, the defendants Zhao and Dou, as kindergarten teachers in the fifth class of Tianjin Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten, resorted to needle sticks, pushing, and The children in care were abused by pulling and other violent behaviors, and the number of victims was as many as 24. Two kindergarten teachers were sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, a mother’s 3-year-old daughter was in the middle class at Chuntian Huahua Kindergarten in Dachang Kulun Village, Saihan District, Hohhot City. One day she overheard her daughter saying that Teacher Guo from the kindergarten pricked someone with a needle. Later, I discovered that there were scabs that looked like needle holes on my daughter’s body, head, ring finger, armpits, thighs, ankles, etc. Two other parents also found scabs on their children that looked like needle holes. The kindergarten was later closed down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these cases, the case in Baoshan District, Shanghai was even more egregious in nature, going beyond the scope of general abuse, with obvious intentions and consequences of personal injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the perpetrator’s motive is worth exploring. There is always a motive for abusing or physically harming a child: feeling that the child is disobedient and disobeying management is one kind; having conflicts with parents and being angry at the child is another kind; being driven by distorted values ​​​​and crazy hatred is also another kind. kind. The last one is probably the scariest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kindergarten should be a place where children live, play and play together. It should be a place of relaxation, freedom and safety, like a sweet dream. Kindergarten teachers should love children and care for each child as their own. Having normal values, loving children, and being patient are the minimum requirements for a kindergarten teacher. If a seemingly normal face hides disgust and hatred for children, then the kindergarten will not only not be a warm and loving paradise, but will become a chilling nightmare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, especially in first-tier cities, kindergartens generally charge a lot of money. From the perspective of professional ethics, how can we take money from parents and turn away, close the door, abuse, and harm children like angels? Such evil behavior not only breaks through the bottom line of professional ethics, but also represents the degradation and loss of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary to conduct a thorough investigation and examination of the perpetrator&#39;s life world and spiritual world to see who the perpetrator usually associates with, what content he follows on social platforms, celebrities and himself. Media, which groups and circles to join, and see if this person and the online and offline circles he interacts with have any extreme remarks, actions or even organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, it is necessary to install monitoring equipment in kindergartens across the country. In principle, all activities of children and all interactions between teachers and children should be recorded on video to deter those treacherous people who hold distorted values. ; At the same time, kindergarten teachers and early childhood staff who are entering and working should review their social media, speech and values, and keep those who hold distorted values ​​away from children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[若尔盖：黄河在这“美丽回眸”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256735]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京跳水大爷：只愿安静跳水，不想当网红]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256880]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team coach Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1, 2, 3, jump!&quot; Coach Meng Derui gave the order, and more than a dozen adults and aunts in swimsuits jumped into the water from left to right, splashing everywhere. splash. &quot;Someone jumped, let&#39;s do it again.&quot; Coach Meng was in second place, and he heard that the rhythm of entering the water behind him was wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Diving Team&quot;) rehearsing the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump in the South Moat on September 13. Every day at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, this group of 60 and 70-year-old people come here from all directions to participate in &quot;training&quot;. They perform tuck-knee pose, swallow pose, back swallow pose, front and back somersaults...all of them are as strong as swallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Training is over , Zhang Yuan rode an electric bike home &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting out of the water, water droplets lay on her wheat-colored skin, which was particularly bright under the sun. . Although the team has been established for less than three years, most of the team members have 20 to 30 years of winter swimming or diving experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the personal training session, Coach Meng completed a set of backward somersault half-circle pike jumps. &quot;201B, performance level, so exciting,&quot; teammates and passing spectators clapped and praised. Applause and laughter continued on the shore - some applauded, and some who failed the jump were heckled and joked, &quot;Isn&#39;t this shot painful enough?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, everyone is laughing so hard Mouth, everyone is here just to have fun.&quot; Mengdry said while looking at his teammates. This 67-year-old Beijinger grew up in the alleys of Di&#39;anmen. He remembered two very happy things when he was a child. One was flying a kite on the tiles of a bungalow, and the other was swimming in Shicha Sea. In the 1960s, Meng Derui, who was in primary school, studied diving at the Shichahai Sports School. His coach later went abroad to teach and also brought out world diving champions. Because of his professional background and his approachability, the team members affectionately called him &quot;Meng Jiao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For every new position, Meng Jiao explained the movements to us from head to toe and demonstrated it personally. No matter how cold the weather was, he could do a standard demonstration when he climbed on the platform. In his Under the leadership of the diving team, we adults have moved from a group of diving bastards to a quasi-professional level,&quot; said 62-year-old team member Zhang Yu&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The team members rehearse the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Don’t want to take risks Risking your life to become an Internet celebrity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 3, 2023, Meng Jiao led the diving team to Tianjin to socialize with local diving friends. At that time, the diving master of Tianjin Lion Forest Bridge was popular all over the world. net. Some netizens posted a video of the team members arriving in Tianjin online with the title &quot;Beijing Diving Master Comes to Tianjin to Play Gym&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, it’s not a competition at all, but an exchange and learning between diving friends. We have known each other for many years and are very familiar with each other. We go there to dive there every year because there are more suitable venues for high school students in Tianjin. The environment for bridge diving - the water is deep, the bridge is high, and the water bottom is clean.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an introduced, &quot;Like the Beijing South Moat where we train daily, the water depth is about 3 meters, and the bridge deck is 5 meters away from the water. For safety reasons, law enforcement officers do not allow us to To jump from the bridge, you can only jump from the guardrail on the shore, the height is only 2 meters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop in Tianjin is the Chifeng Bridge, which is more than 9 meters high. Wang Tieshun, the &quot;Ironman of Winter Swimming&quot; in the team, was the first to take the stage. In his first jump, the &quot;Reverse Swallow&quot;, his buttocks touched the water first, and he was slapped hard, which was not ideal. He analyzed that it was due to the increase in height that there was a problem with the angle of entering the water. He immediately adjusted his posture when entering the water, and performed a wonderful dance afterwards, which won bursts of applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Brother Wang is 69 years old. Generally, when a person of this age stands at a height of 9 meters and looks down, his legs will tremble. Not only does he dare to jump, but he is also a &quot;anti-Yan&quot; who is cool and neat, so generous. People are impressed.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an said as he opened his arms in a &quot;swallow pose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second stop was the &quot;8A-level scenic spot&quot; Lion Forest Bridge. The deck of the Lion Grove Bridge is about 6 meters above the water surface, which is an ideal height for high bridge diving. The team members just skipped here three months ago and it was a great experience. But at this time, there were already a sea of ​​people on and off the bridge, and the scene was very chaotic. Those who could jump and those who couldn&#39;t jump plunged into the water. Meng Derui saw a man walking into the water with his child in his arms, and he still has lingering fears. For safety reasons, he decided to lead his team members to evacuate immediately without jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training , the brothers went to a nearby restaurant to have a drink&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Someone at the scene recognized that we were from Beijing and chased us all the way. We were following the filming, but we still withdrew. Everyone comes to dive for physical and mental pleasure and to improve their skills. They don’t want to risk their lives to become an Internet celebrity and be in the limelight.&quot; Zhang Yuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Changluo, director of the emergency department of Changsha Central Hospital, said in an interview with the media that high-bridge diving is very dangerous, and it is easy to get injured if you blindly try it without professional guidance. In addition to damage to the retina, head and cervical spine, if the diving posture is incorrect and the abdomen falls into the water first, the impact may damage the internal organs, or even cause fatal consequences such as spleen rupture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another risk comes from the complex and unpredictable underwater conditions of natural waters. Every time the diving team arrives at a new water area, they will send members to go into the water first to survey - how deep is the water and whether there are large rocks or sharp foreign objects. Wang Tieshun once found a shared bicycle and several broken beer bottles underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Safety is the most important thing for the diving team. In addition to their own safety, there is also the safety of others. Some young people passing by also want to dive with the old men on a whim. &quot;When encountering this situation, we will first dissuade them - if you haven&#39;t practiced before, don&#39;t jump blindly. If you jump, we will also remind you: the water depth here is not enough. If your head enters the water, you must raise your head in time, otherwise it will be easy to poke vertically to the bottom of the water.&quot; Meng Meng and his team members have encountered many such young people. Some of them couldn&#39;t wait to take off their clothes and shoes, and shouted to plunge into the water. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the training, Zhang Yuan rode his electric bike home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years, the team members We have rescued many people who accidentally drowned. &quot;Especially in the summer of 2023, which was extremely hot, more people came to swim than in previous years. Many delivery boys came here to take a shower. They parked their cars on the shore, took off their riding clothes, and plunged in. After a while, He was dangling in the water, and when we found out, we quickly swam over and pulled him ashore,&quot; Wang Tieshun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the 1990s, Meng Derui participated in the New Year diving event at Xinjiekou Gap&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fun and hidden dangers of natural waters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For adults and adults, on the premise of ensuring safety, the fun of swimming in natural waters is something that cannot be achieved in indoor swimming pools. Comparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the view is wide and there are few people. You can enjoy the natural scenery while swimming. Secondly, there is the water quality. Many adults said that they cannot stand the smell of disinfected water in indoor swimming pools, which &quot;makes their brains hurt.&quot; Natural waters like the South Moat are treated gray water, which is safe and odorless. Of course, there are also economic reasons. A swim in an indoor swimming pool costs at least dozens of yuan, and you only need to prepare a pair of swimming trunks in natural waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, as Beijing’s water ecological environment has gradually improved, the water affairs department has continued to increase the openness and sharing of river and lake spaces to meet citizens’ water-related needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About two years ago, a group of swimming enthusiasts that Zhang Yuan belongs to forwarded eight officially opened natural water swimming spots in Beijing, including Beijing Bay Sunken Square, Dongzhimen Triangle, and Yongyin Canal 8. A lake and the south moat where the diving team is currently located, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The warning sign here used to be &#39;No Swimming&#39;, but now it is &#39;Civilized Water Activities, Ensure Life Safety&#39;. Recently, the relevant departments have also equipped lockers on the shore. These are welcome new features. Weather.&quot; Mendry said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Regulations on the Protection and Management of Rivers and Lakes in Beijing&quot;, in non-water source protection areas and waters where there are no &quot;No swimming, skating and other water activities&quot; signs, event personnel or organizers should take safety protection measures. activities under the premise. However, due to safety concerns, relevant managers will dissuade you from doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every afternoon, the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team will train on the bank of the South Moat&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;The two movable jumping platforms currently used by the team members are made by Wang Tieshun, which is safe, easy to move without damaging the guardrails&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;Some managers are afraid of being held responsible for accidents, so they set up obstacles and prevent swimming in legal natural waters. We have our own ideas about this. Many of us have been swimming our whole lives, and we often travel in groups. How could something happen so easily? Among our team members, there are quite a few people who have rescued people who slipped and fell into the water, accidentally drowned, and committed suicide. Without daily outdoor exercise, how could we have the ability and physique to save people?&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an hopes to pay attention to nature. The management of water activities in water areas should not be &quot;one size fits all&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As evening approached, Mr. Li, who lived nearby, took his children to the river to swim. The family had just moved to Dongcheng District for the purpose of studying for their children. One day I was riding by here and saw people swimming and diving in the river. The children also wanted to try it. Now they can&#39;t wait to come here to play in the water every day after school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For children, this kind of natural water area is definitely much better than the experience in an indoor swimming pool. You can have more fun here. Diving is not allowed in the indoor swimming pool, and you cannot change swimming lanes at will, because it will It affects other people.&quot; Mr. Li was a little concerned about the water quality at first, but the children swam for more than half a month and felt fine. &quot;The water quality here may have a higher microbial content, and the residual chlorine and urea in the swimming pool may be higher. . Chlorine is very harmful to the respiratory tract, especially children. If you keep swimming in it, there may be some potential harm. There is no such problem in natural waters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, a large area The water plants floated slowly, and the curious children wanted to catch them, but Mr. Li immediately stopped him, &quot;Don&#39;t touch the water plants, they will tangle you up and make you unable to move your hands and feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Beijing’s middle-aged and elderly diving team took a group photo with the Bayi Lake diving team who came to exchange and learn. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Diving is a spirit Relief&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking back on Meng Derui, the three years he spent learning diving in the sports school were unbearable. Other children were happily playing pinball and shooting cigarette boxes after school, but he could only go to training hard. &quot;Although I was in the amateur team at the time, the training was very strict. A group of 10 jumps for each movement was counted, and five or six groups had to be danced in half a day. Basic skills such as leg presses and shoulder presses were interspersed in between. The coach was also very strict, and the movements were not up to standard. Just hit the bottom of the shoe.&quot; Meng Derui has a family with many children, and he is the sixth child. His family sent him to a sports school just to have a free place to take care of him and to exercise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Derui loves water by nature. He feels excited when standing on the diving platform, and it is indescribable satisfaction to jump into the water. Later, when he went to the mountains and countryside, he took advantage of his lunch break to go to a nearby reservoir to continue practicing. After returning to Beijing for work, after dinner, I rode my bicycle to a bridge at Xinjiekou Gap to dive. On weekends or holidays, go dancing on the high platform of the outdoor swimming pool in Gongti or Taoranting Park. It costs 10 cents for two hours. At this time, there is no urging from the coach, but an inner need - when diving, you must concentrate on thinking about the movements and not have distracting thoughts, so that you can forget a lot of &quot;messy things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Mengdry helped take care of his grandson. Sometimes when he did not come to training in the afternoon, his teammates knew that he must have gone to pick up his grandson. &quot;At home, it&#39;s all about fulfilling obligations, being tired and worrying. Coming here to dive with everyone is the most relaxing and joyful thing of the day,&quot; Mengdry called it a &quot;spiritual relief.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the training, the team members shared their fruits, and the brothers occasionally met up to have a drink. If a team member has a birthday or someone’s grandchild is one month old, they have to find a place to celebrate together. Not long ago, Meng Jiao&#39;s wife broke her foot. Zhang Yu&#39;an immediately sent his unused wheelchair to his home and accompanied him to the hospital. Several teammates went to visit his home. &quot;The relationship between our teammates is closer than that of real brothers.&quot; Mengdry sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yuan had many hobbies when he was young and studied art and decoration in his spare time , photography and design. In terms of sports, he is involved in skating, skiing, swimming, diving, cycling, running, and mountain climbing. He knows that he is not good at everything but enjoys the process and joy of learning and mastering each sport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Zhang Yuan got acquainted with Meng Jiao and these like-minded teammates, and concentrated his energy on diving, almost without landing for three years. He felt physically stronger and more energetic than before. &quot;We seniors in our 60s have a very simple idea: move more, exercise more, get sick less, and put less burden on the country and our children.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an has many dancing friends around him, and many years of chronic diseases such as high blood pressure, hyperlipidemia, and arthritis have passed. Keep exercising and get effective control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training, Wang Tieshun rinsed his body with his own water. Almost every team member has such a homemade bucket&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One early morning two weeks ago, an 80-year-old man came for a morning tour of the moat alone. Died of sudden illness. After hearing this, the team members expressed their regrets. Zhang Yuan had his own thoughts: &quot;It is very sad that such an accident happened. But I think this old man died very happily and could immerse himself in his lifelong hobby at the last moment of his life. In this way Leaving silently is much better than struggling in the hospital bed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[和心智障碍者成为同事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nervous and scared, I pushed open the door of the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others, I don’t know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked forward cautiously, and no colleagues with mental disabilities showed up. Don’t ever encounter it, I thought silently in my heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pap tap tap~&quot; came the sound of footsteps going down the stairs, and around the corner I met the first colleague with a mental disability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl, with her high ponytails, smiling, with bright eyes, raised her hands and shook them at me, &quot;Sister...Hello, sister!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It was an opening that I had anticipated a lot in advance but didn’t expect. I didn&#39;t know how to respond to her enthusiasm, so I forced a smile on my tight face, said &quot;Hello&quot;, and turned around to go upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who knew that this girl was just here to lead the &quot;warm greeting army&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was catching up with my colleagues with mental disabilities in the factory who had changed into work clothes and went downstairs to do morning exercises. As they filed out, each one of them greeted me: some stopped and stood to say good morning to me. ; Some ran past me quickly, leaving echoes of hello drifting through my ears; others slowly walked downstairs, shyly saying good morning to me... The nervousness turned into surprise, and I suddenly Time just smiles and nods and says &quot;hello&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they finished walking, the stairwell became quiet again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I felt their outpouring of enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I walked up the stairs, there were pictures of them hanging on one side of the wall: profiles of employees working hard; employees participating in events; female employees dressed beautifully for Women’s Day... They seemed to be telling me: look! I&#39;m not dangerous, I can work, I can be beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing the entry procedures, the ordinary employees of the factory began to introduce me to the basic information of the entire factory and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked into the production workshop. Every colleague with mental disabilities was working seriously at his or her position. There was only the sound of the machine and the trainer&#39;s voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are engaged in some simple assembly and sorting work, which is boring, but they enjoy it very much. On my first day here, I heard that one of my colleagues with mental disabilities was called the &quot;Clamp King&quot; because of his excellent work on clamps. This resounding name was well known in the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The factory is very user-friendly and will arrange work according to their characteristics and provide them with some auxiliary tools to help them complete their work more efficiently. For example, when sorting two types of parts, one large and one small, because the difference is very small, the factory will use a 3D printer to make a slot into which one type of part can be placed, so that colleagues with mental disabilities can tell which type of part it is by placing it. As I got familiar with the factory, I secretly admired it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch, the employees lined up in an orderly manner when they heard the lunch bell and walked to the dining area carrying their plates. After I sat down, an employee sat next to me and started some conversation: Hello, sister, what is your name? My name is so-and-so, sister, are you here to work? Sister, you look so beautiful today. Sister, where are you from? … They spoke a little slowly and maybe a little unclear, but they were very polite. What surprised me most was that the girl with the twin tails said to me after finishing the meal: “Sister, I’ll eat and leave first, please take your time.” &quot;Then he picked up his dinner plate, wiped the table clean with paper, pushed the chair under the table, and left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They would sing their favorite songs in the lounge during lunch break, mostly catchy old songs. Some people sang seriously, some interrupted and made trouble, some sat quietly by the window and watched the scenery... The work bell rang, and they returned to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will not shout suddenly or rush to attack others. Observation is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was chatting with others that I was interning in a factory where people with mental disabilities were the main people. Others looked at me strangely: Can these people also work? Is it a welfare institution organized by the government? Before actually entering this workshop, I also had this &quot;strange vision&quot;. However, after truly understanding it, I realized that there is light and love here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be civilized and polite, they are the best practitioners of this slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a graduate student majoring in journalism and communication)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国三大车企工人首次同时举行罢工 前十天累计损失或超50亿美元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256852]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021183175256&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;The cumulative losses in the ten days before workers from the three major U.S. auto companies went on strike simultaneously for the first time may exceed US$5 billion.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2. myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12 51434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width= &quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the contract between the auto workers and the auto manufacturer expired on the 14th, and the two parties failed to reach an agreement, a large number of American auto workers began to strike in the early morning of the 15th local time. Analysts pointed out that the auto workers&#39; strike may plunge the operation of the auto industry into chaos, thereby affecting the US economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At midnight local time on the 14th, which is noon on the 15th Beijing time, the labor contracts of approximately 150,000 American auto workers with the three automakers General Motors, Ford and Stellantis expired, and both parties have not yet agreed. A new contract can be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250948&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, 12,700 workers of the United Auto Workers union went on strike at the three plants of the three major automakers in Michigan, Missouri and Ohio. This is also the first time in more than 80 years since the founding of the United Auto Workers that auto workers have staged a strike against the three automakers mentioned above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;United Auto Workers President Sean Fein said that a larger &quot;general strike&quot; has not yet been held, but said that if labor and management cannot reach a new contract, &quot;any option is possible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Auto industry analyst Garrett Nelson:&lt;/strong>;The most optimistic estimate we have seen so far is that in terms of strike costs, the cumulative losses in the first ten days may exceed $5 billion. The automobile industry is the largest manufacturing sector in the United States. If this situation continues into October and November, economic growth will definitely be affected in the third quarter and even more severely in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花高价找“高富帅”？婚恋网站的“结婚保”与“VIP”套路多]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256741]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Relying on the rapidly developing Internet, dating and dating websites can theoretically provide broader and more convenient dating and matching services. However, in recent years, various routines and suspected cases of &quot;pig killing plate&quot; have occurred frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Beijing Business Daily&quot; reported in April this year that Ms. Zhang spent 20,000 yuan on Baihe.com to purchase a &quot;marriage insurance&quot; matchmaking service. The &quot;matchmaker&quot; who matched the service said that she would introduce high-quality men to her, and then successively Recommended 5 men. Ms. Chen mentioned that the five men did not express sufficient communication intentions, did not introduce themselves, and could not confirm the personal information mentioned by the &quot;matchmaker.&quot; Yuyao (pseudonym), who purchased a matchmaking service at Century Jiayuan’s Beijing Anzhen store, also revealed that she signed a contract and paid nearly 100,000 yuan. The store staff promised Yuyao that they would introduce “high-quality men” and “guaranteed success.” After Yuyao connected with several male users, none of them established a relationship between male and female friends. The two women asked for a refund because they were dissatisfied with the services of the dating website, but the other party had to deduct high fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Online social networking is a loose and progressive dating model, but the services provided by dating websites are very purposeful. Men and women who register as members or even purchase paid services have clear demands for marriage and love, and they hope to pass them. Dating and dating websites find people who match their own requirements and have corresponding expectations and measurement standards in terms of appearance, income, position, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mating and dating websites will provide two services for this type of men and women. One is a free registration service. After the user registers, they will &quot;audition&quot; for opposite-sex users who are also registered on the website to find those who meet the conditions and can communicate with each other. of opposite-sex communication. However, this method is inefficient and consumes a lot of time and energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save screening costs and improve success rate and safety, some consumers choose paid services provided by dating websites. In this regard, marriage and love websites provide &quot;offline matchmaker&quot; services, which are divided into telephone customer service and emotional consultants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, a reporter from The Paper applied for a job and went undercover to enter an offline store of Jiayuan Online. After the short-term training, the store opened back-end permissions for reporters. Through the back-end, they can view the personal information of registered members of Century Jiayuan.com, including the user&#39;s browsing history and chat history. After obtaining the user&#39;s &quot;big data&quot;, the telephone customer service invites the user to the store for an interview through phone calls, text messages, etc. The reporter inquired about the statistics on the number of calls in the background of the system and found that most of the store&#39;s sales made an average of about 100 calls per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a customer comes to the store, the emotional consultant responsible for the interview will use words to guide, for example, &quot;Compared with buying a commercial house worth millions or tens of millions, it is better to spend tens of thousands of dollars to find your lover.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s worth it&quot;, and then displays the high-quality candidate information it has to induce users to sign up and pay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Paper reported: In 2017, Liu Gang, a consumer who had used the &quot;matchmaker one-on-one&quot; service, said that online membership fees are relatively low, and members are charged for sending and viewing messages, and users also pay more every year. It only costs a few hundred yuan in membership fees. Prices for high-end services range from 10,000 to hundreds of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do so many people fall into this trap? The supply and demand relationship in the marriage market also plays a driving role. Century Jiayuan has not announced the proportion of male and female paid members, but Ideal Island VIP, known as the &quot;Master and Doctoral Dating Platform&quot;, released the &quot;2023 Ideal Island VIP User Report&quot; stating that 40.2% of Ideal Island VIP users are men and 59.8% are women. Among them, women account for more than 60% of users in Shanghai, Chengdu, Guangzhou, Beijing, and Shenzhen. It is reported that after becoming the VIP of Ideal Island and searching for the opposite sex, if you need to initiate an exchange WeChat application, you need to pay to purchase a membership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a phenomenon of &quot;more boys and girls&quot; among users of dating websites, or it may be because men often bear the majority of dating expenses for both parties during the relationship, especially men at the bottom of the class who have to pay betrothal gifts when they get married. For the decision-making process of purchasing paid dating services More cautious. Some women consider more based on their age, partner&#39;s income, occupation, etc., and the need to find high-quality men through paid services is more urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to understand why female users are more likely to be deceived among the various service traps designed by dating websites. In 2021, Zhejiang Radio and Television&#39;s &quot;Xiaoqiang Online&quot; column reported that Ms. Lu, a Hangzhou citizen, registered as a member of Century Jiayuan in November 2019 and wanted to find a suitable partner. For this reason, she did not hesitate to borrow more than 130,000 yuan to pay the membership fee, because the contract stipulated that as long as she registered for marriage with the person recommended by the matchmaker during the contract period, the membership fee could be returned in full. However, after signing the contract, the candidates recommended by the matchmaker often did not meet Ms. Lu&#39;s standards, and Ms. Lu eventually requested a full refund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the recommended products not matching the previous promises, some users have also encountered suspected &quot;marriage trusteeship&quot; incidents. The Beijing News reported in 2017 that Xiaoqing, who had worked at Zhenai.com and Jiayuan for two years, said that marriage entrustments were common. Some sales matchmakers think that this member is useless, or that the conditions required are difficult to find, so the matchmaker will introduce their people to the other party and make it clear that they cannot establish a relationship, but just gather the number of people and go through the motions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the above incidents that the promises of &quot;full refund on scheduled marriage&quot; and &quot;marriage insurance&quot; services of dating websites are all based on so-called back-and-forth promises to allow female users to fall into their serial routine—— Brainwashing them with words to induce them to pay, and pretending to be a high-quality man as a &quot;marriage agency&quot; during the meeting. Although as early as 2017, the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League, the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and the National Health and Family Planning Commission formulated and issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Further Improving Youth Marriage and Love Work&quot;, requiring the promotion of marriage and dating platforms to strictly implement real-name authentication and real-name registration, and severely crack down on Illegal matchmaking activities such as marriage entrustment and marriage fraud, but relying solely on the self-discipline of dating websites lacks the strength and breadth of normalized governance, making it difficult for users to safeguard their rights, and such routines will continue to spread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一边补贴购车，一边对中国电动车反补贴调查，欧盟为何双标？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256872]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0gH0XflmZuPMb1fs2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1062&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0g H0XflmZuPMb1fs2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Munich Auto Show. This year has the largest number of references for Chinese car companies in history. Not only BYD, Xpeng Motors, Leap Motors, SAIC MG, Avita and Cyrus participated in the exhibition, but also CATL, Yiwei Lithium Energy and so on. , Sunwoda and China New Aviation and other parts, software and hardware suppliers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s electric cars, which are rapidly entering the market, have encountered &quot;stumbling blocks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers, in the first eight months of 2023, China&#39;s new energy vehicle exports surged 110% year-on-year. However, on September 13, 2023, European Commission President von der Leyen announced that it would launch a countervailing investigation into electric vehicles from China. The core of the investigation is whether the Chinese government provides subsidies to assess whether the EU needs to impose punitive tariffs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qiu Kaijun, founder of &quot;Electric Vehicle Observer&quot; believes that all countries are introducing policies to support the development of their own electric vehicle industry, and China just implemented subsidies earlier, and there is no legitimacy issue. Moreover, China’s “state subsidy” policy for new energy vehicles has been terminated in 2022, but some EU member states are still subsidizing their own new energy vehicles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 14, a spokesman for the Ministry of Commerce of China responded that China’s electric vehicle industry has developed rapidly and its competitiveness has continued to improve. This is the result of unremitting technological innovation and the construction of a complete industrial chain and supply chain. China urges the EU to proceed from the overall situation of maintaining the stability of global industrial and supply chains as well as the China-EU comprehensive strategic partnership and engage in dialogue and consultation with China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;China’s “state subsidy” policy for electric vehicles has been withdrawn&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The global market is now flooded with cheaper Chinese electric vehicles. And huge state subsidies have artificially depressed their prices.” Von der Leyen said that this is the core reason why the EU is considering launching a countervailing investigation into electric vehicles from China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Commission said that China’s market share of electric vehicles sold in Europe has risen to 8% and may reach 15% in 2025. This rapid growth in proportion is due to the fact that Chinese electric vehicles generally have a price advantage of about 20% compared to European models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese government does provide subsidies for electric vehicles, but it also set up an exit mechanism for subsidies very early. At the beginning of 2022, four departments including the Ministry of Finance jointly issued a document clarifying that the new energy vehicle purchase subsidy policy in 2022 will be terminated on December 31, 2022. Subsidies will no longer be provided for vehicles with subsequent license plates, and the &quot;state subsidy&quot; policy for electric vehicles that has continued for 13 years has been officially Withdrew from the stage of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at Europe, many subsidy policies for the electric vehicle industry have been introduced in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Germany provides different subsidies for pure electric vehicles based on the selling price, with the maximum subsidy of 4,500 euros for models under 40,000 euros. In 2023, the car purchase subsidy for ordinary French consumers will be 5,000 euros, and the electric vehicle subsidy for low-income families will increase to 7,000 euros. On February 1, 2023, the European Commission proposed increasing state subsidies to enable EU countries to compete with other countries in the production of electric vehicles and other green products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the development of emerging industries such as electric vehicles, the industrial policies of various countries are very active, but there are differences in degree.&quot; Qiu Kaijun said, &quot;In the early years, the so-called completely free market did not interfere with industrial development at all. The economic theory is actually no longer popular in Europe and the United States, where there is also strong intervention and support for emerging industries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The impact on Chinese car companies still needs to be observed&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to According to EU regulations, countervailing investigations can take up to 13 months, which means that we still need to wait for the &quot;boots to land&quot; in about a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the evening of September 13, Chinese concept stocks of new energy vehicles had already fallen collectively. Xpeng Motors fell 3.11%, Li Auto fell 0.54%, and NIO fell 4.64%. Hong Kong auto stocks fell in late trading, with BYD and Xpeng Motors falling 3.53% and 2.47% respectively, Geely Auto falling 1.52%, and Great Wall Motors, NIO, and Li Auto falling slightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the launch of the anti-subsidy investigation, European policies were relatively friendly, with a tariff of 10% on cars imported from China, while the United States&#39; tariff was 27.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Kaijun said that the current cost advantage of Chinese car companies is very obvious. If countervailing tariffs are imposed after the investigation, the increase will be small, and Chinese car companies will still be competitive; but if punitive tariffs are imposed, such as 100% or 150%, the blow will be very severe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Forsighted Chinese car companies are preparing to build factories in Europe, and the anti-subsidy investigation may speed up their progress in building factories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dan, a researcher at the Institute of International Affairs of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), suggested that Chinese car companies should strengthen coordination and consultation with the assistance of industry associations, form a joint stance and strategy, and improve the foreign economic and trade legal toolbox , accurately grasp EU legislative information and progress, work closely with the Ministry of Commerce, and negotiate with the European side in the China-EU high-level economic and trade dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;China has the best electric vehicle industry chain&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Many foreign car companies have factories in China, and the so-called electric vehicles from China also include them. Countervailing investigations will also affect non-Chinese brand models manufactured in China, such as Tesla and BMW. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Foreign brands are willing to set up factories in China, and they are voting with their feet. It is not because China has subsidies, but because China has the best electric vehicle industry chain and good automobile industry workers, just like the Ma Skoda praised the workers at Tesla&#39;s Shanghai Gigafactory for being smart and hard-working,&quot; Qiu Kaijun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, the China Chamber of Commerce in the European Union issued a statement that China&#39;s electric vehicles and upstream and downstream industry chain companies have continued to innovate and have accumulated overall industrial advantages in the fierce Chinese local market. This advantage is not based on The so-called huge subsidies are formed. CITIC Securities’ research report also pointed out that China’s current electric vehicles do not rely on low prices as a selling point. Their competitiveness comes from technology accumulation, quality control, and user experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industrial advantage is reflected in the price advantage. Qiu Kaijun gave an example to Southern Weekend reporters. Volkswagen&#39;s ID.3 model is produced in both China and Germany. It sells for 40,000 euros in Germany, while it sells for about 15,000 euros in China. The huge price difference has caused caused a wave of public opinion in Germany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a statistics from the research organization JATO Dynamics, since 2015, the average price of electric vehicles in Europe has risen from 49,000 euros to 56,000 euros, and in the United States from 53,000 euros to 64,000 euros, while China dropped from 67,000 euros to 32,000 euros. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1086&quot; height= &quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, 2023 local time, in Debrecen, Hungary, an electric vehicle battery factory invested by China Contemporary Amperex Technology Co., Ltd. (CATL) is under construction. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The road to sea is long and difficult&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This time the EU imposes restrictions on electric vehicles from China The anti-subsidy investigation launched by automobiles reminds people of the &quot;double-reverse&quot; (anti-dumping and countervailing) investigation conducted by the EU on photovoltaic modules exported from China in 2012. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Kaijun introduced that when China&#39;s photovoltaic industry emerged, it was commonly known as &quot;three heads outside&quot;, that is, raw materials, technology, and markets were all abroad, with China as the main processing place, and it developed from this. China’s photovoltaic industry suffered a huge blow during the “double-reverse” investigation. However, it was also at this stage that China’s photovoltaic industry fully tapped its endogenous power and localized raw materials, technology, and markets. When the “double-reverse” investigation After the investigation was withdrawn, it regained a large market share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development path of the electric vehicle industry is different from that of the photovoltaic industry. China&#39;s electric vehicles originated in the local market and then went abroad after developing to a certain extent. The current market penetration rate of China&#39;s new energy vehicles is about 35%, and there is still a huge domestic market demand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This EU countervailing investigation also sounded the alarm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dan believes that the EU’s launch of a countervailing investigation on electric vehicles from China is a typical trade protectionism and a manifestation of the EU’s double standards. It is completely untenable both legally and morally. Currently, there are huge differences within the EU regarding this anti-subsidy investigation. The political forces within Germany and France both support and oppose it. However, in the current political environment, the supporting forces within Germany and France have the ability to push the EU to launch an investigation and even influence it. Investigation conclusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to facing the obstacles of trade protectionism, Wu Dan believes that factors such as the inconsistency between China&#39;s national automobile standards and international standards, the fact that my country&#39;s new energy vehicle export certification system has not yet been integrated with international standards, and the decline in overseas consumption capacity are all constraints. It has promoted the international development of my country’s new energy vehicles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dan once wrote that at the current stage, the scale of overseas investment and factory establishment by Chinese car companies is far less than that of traditional multinational car manufacturers in developed countries. Chinese car companies want to transform from a traditional trade model to an overseas business development model. Improving the autonomy and brand influence of the supporting supply chain still has to go through a long and difficult process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[恒大财富杜某等涉嫌犯罪人员被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256870]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic.cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzw LxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt= jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1&amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 0.5;&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic. cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzwLxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt=jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1 &amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1694873788117-0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走近霍尔果斯“守关人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256824]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15M5p9oKUr1J14C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;539&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15 M5p9oKUr1J14C. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police monitor China-Europe trains leaving the country at night&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 10 o&#39;clock in the evening, the sun has just set, the rails and stones are still hot, and the high temperature emitted by the train engine is uncomfortable. Police officer Yue Shuang walked in the heat wave and urged police officers at all points to pay attention to train monitoring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Horgos railway port located on the China-Kazakhstan border, and is also the center of China-Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚&lt;/span>;) One of the major passages on the west line. The four lanes of the railway freight yard were filled with trains waiting for entry and exit, and subsequent trains waiting for admission sounded their whistles in the distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Horgos Railway Port and surrounding freight yards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is a 1,050-meter-long supervision road running through the east and west ends of the freight yard. As the deputy of the third team on duty at the Horgos Entry-Exit Border Inspection Station (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Horgos Border Inspection Station&quot;&lt;/span>;) Captain, Yue Shuang has been on this road for 11 years and witnessed the opening and development of the railway port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Horgos has a customs clearance history of more than 100 years and is my country’s closest and most convenient window to Central Asia, West Asia and even Europe. In July 2012, Yue Shuang, who had just graduated from the military academy, was assigned to the Horgos Border Inspection Station. At that time, this border town had a sparse population. Most shops were closed after 10 p.m., and “there were no people eating noodles on the street.” There is no place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Before going to work, Yue Shuang checks the police appearance and discipline&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 22, 2012, the Horgos Railway Port opened for trial operation. Yue Shuang was among the first batch of policemen stationed at the scene. There were only four railway tracks, one guard bridge and a temporary structure in the vast Gobi. color steel house. According to the agreement between China and Kazakhstan, the railway port implemented a 7-day × 12-hour service model at that time, but there were only seven or eight inbound and outbound freight trains every day. Yue Shuang used &quot;boring&quot; to describe the work at that time, &quot;There was not much business volume, but it was very tiring.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change occurred in 2014, when the railway port was officially opened in February of that year. Yue Shuang still remembers that the number of trains that summer more than doubled than before, and the number continued to grow. The background of this change is that China proposed the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative in 2013, and Horgos is located in the &quot;core area&quot; of the &quot;New Silk Road Economic Belt&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Check the front of the truck to prevent hiding illegal items&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huo Ergos means &quot;the place where the camel caravan passes&quot; in Mongolian. It has been an important pass on the Silk Road since ancient times. Nowadays, this is the starting and ending point of the Lianhuo (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lianyungang-Horgos&lt;/span>;) Expressway and the 312 National Highway, &quot;Double West&quot; The eastern entrance of the &quot;Highway&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Western China-Western Europe&lt;/span>;) has an unparalleled position in promoting the interconnection between Eastern and Western societies. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police officers climbed onto the covered bridge to monitor the train&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In March 2016, the Horgos Railway Port opened for China-Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Asia&lt;/span>;) trains, relying on its unique location advantages It has become the &quot;golden channel&quot; for international logistics land transportation - from the initial operation volume of less than 400 trains in the first year, it now passes through Central Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Asia&lt;/span>; ), the total number of trains exceeds 30,000, and the total number of train routes reaches 78, covering 18 overseas countries and 45 cities and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250560&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Police pre-check outbound passenger documents&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yueshuang In my memory, the initial inspection mainly relied on manpower. The police had to climb into the carriages one by one and check the bottom of the carriages to prevent criminals or prohibited items from hiding in them and illegal entry and exit. It took more than half an hour to inspect a train. Later, they formed a mature inspection process, strengthened technological means, and carried out comprehensive monitoring of inbound and outbound trains. Now it only takes about 10 minutes to inspect a train. In order to better adapt to the growing demand for customs clearance, the border inspection station has adjusted the railway port to a 365-day × 24-hour service model, so that entry and exit trains can be inspected and released at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Check the identity of the outbound truck driver&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Spring and Autumn Return Well, the most difficult parts are summer and winter.&quot; Yue Shuang said that the highest temperature in summer at the duty site is over 50 degrees Celsius, eggs can be fried on the railway tracks, and people often faint at the duty site; in winter, the lowest temperature drops to more than 30 degrees below zero. degrees Celsius, when the police inspected the car, their hands were accidentally stuck to the iron sheet of the carriage. If they tore it apart with force, bloody skin and flesh would be left on the carriage. In December 2018, the port encountered a blizzard with more than 70 centimeters of snow. In order not to affect the normal operation of the train, the police cleared the snow all night. Everyone was covered with thick ice when they returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the northwest of the railway port, about two kilometers away in a straight line, stands the sixth-generation national gate that was opened in September 2018. Hundreds of trucks leave the country from highway ports every day, transporting Chinese products to Central Asia and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Highway Passenger Transport Duty Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Border of Horgos Zeng Qi, captain of the second team on duty at the inspection station, has witnessed the changes from the fifth generation to the sixth generation of the national gate. In his opinion, the design concept of the new national gate is more advanced. Passengers only need to scan their fingerprints and faces to clear customs in just 15 seconds; trucks adopt one-stop inspection and one-time customs clearance to improve customs clearance efficiency. From January 1 to July 21, 2023, the number of entry and exit vehicles at the port exceeded 100,000, exceeding the annual customs clearance volume of highway ports in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are many potential changes that cannot be seen at ordinary times.” Zeng Qi said. In the past, export commodities were mainly fruits and vegetables, department stores and various daily necessities, but now they include building materials, machinery and equipment, precision instruments, etc. Among them, Chinese-made new energy vehicles are especially popular with countries along the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Vehicles of various types waiting to leave the country in front of the sixth-generation national gate&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Jia/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What touched Zeng Qi most deeply was one day in May 2023. As he was getting off work, there was still a long queue of vehicles waiting to clear customs. They urgently met and negotiated with the Kazakh border inspection department and obtained the other party&#39;s consent to extend the customs clearance time. When the news came, the drivers waiting for customs clearance in front of the boundary bridge applauded in unison. They worked until about 5 a.m. the next day, and finally completed the inspection and release of all vehicles to be inspected. &quot;Seeing so many Chinese products leaving us, no matter how tiring it is, it&#39;s worth it.&quot; On August 15, 2023, the Horgos Highway Port began to implement 24-hour freight customs clearance on a trial basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. With the continuous growth of port customs clearance, more and more tourists are visiting Horgos, and &quot;gold diggers&quot; from various countries are also pouring in. This border town is undergoing rapid changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Shuang once went out of the country to meet with the Kazakh border inspection department, and it was already night when he returned. He stood in the dark wilderness outside the country and looked at Horgos. It was brightly lit and bustling with traffic, making it a veritable &quot;city that never sleeps.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>