<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从魂魄、中阴身到幽灵Vs魔鬼：万圣节话中西之鬼异同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259582]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every year before Halloween comes, all kinds of creative and scary costumes bloom everywhere, and you can constantly watch short videos. Although today&#39;s Halloween is no different from &quot;Cosplay Festival&quot;. But its original &quot;ghost-driving&quot; element is still vaguely visible - even though in modern society, ghosts and gods have long become the objects of ridicule played by humans. However, various countries&#39; understanding of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; still follows thousands of years of tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a wonderful discussion and definition of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; in &quot;Book of Rites·Jiyi&quot;: &quot;Zaiwo said: I heard the names of ghosts and gods, but I don&#39;t know what they mean. The Master said: Qi is also , the prosperity of gods. The prosperity of souls, the prosperity of ghosts. The combination of ghosts and gods is the ultimate teaching. All living things must die, and after death they must return to the earth. This is called ghosts.&quot; Zaiwo didn&#39;t understand what ghosts and gods were, so Confucius told him: &quot; God is essence, and ghost is soul. All living things will die, and after death they will return to dust, which are called ghosts.&quot; - Confucius played a homophonic joke here: ghosts are all living things. ultimate destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of this, in China’s oldest traditions, ghosts and gods are often not clearly distinguished. As the saying goes, &quot;Ghosts are ancestors, and ancestors are also ghosts.&quot; The Confucian attitude towards ghosts and gods is also very interesting. Confucius once said: &quot;Respect ghosts and gods and keep them at a distance.&quot; He also said: &quot;If you can&#39;t serve people, how can you serve ghosts?&quot; In short, he tried his best to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods, and even showed an agnostic tendency to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Confucianism places great emphasis on respecting ancestors and offering sacrifices on time. If ghosts and gods do not exist at all, then what are they worshiping? Confucius added another patch to this: &quot;Sacrifice to the gods as if they were present, and sacrifice to the gods as if the gods were present. Confucius said: If I don&#39;t offer sacrifices, it would be as if I didn&#39;t offer sacrifices.&quot; In other words, when offering sacrifices to ancestors, it seems as if the ancestors are really in front of you; when offering sacrifices to gods, It was as if God was really in front of me. Confucius also said that if I do not personally participate in the sacrifice, the sacrifice will be the same as no sacrifice. From this, it can be seen that Confucius emphasized that those who participate in the sacrifice should have pious emotions in their hearts. According to Confucianism, sacrifice is a moral ritual used to unite the community, rather than a religious ritual used to pray for blessings and ward off disasters. Therefore, salutes are just out of recalling the feelings of ancestors. As the saying goes, &quot;sages teach with Shinto.&quot; And the sacrifices are mainly for the living people to see: &quot;Be careful and pursue the long distance, and the people&#39;s virtue will be strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From today&#39;s perspective, Confucius&#39;s view is very advanced. However, on the other hand, it seems to be contradictory to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods while requiring people to worship sincerely. Mohism, the lifelong enemy of Confucianism, once seized this point and vigorously ridiculed Confucianism. Contrary to Confucianism, Mohism strives to prove the real existence of ghosts and gods, so it regards sacrifice as more important than Confucianism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Taoism, the attitude is more distinct than that of Confucianism. It is believed that after death, one returns to heaven and earth, and there is no such thing as ghosts and gods. Therefore, &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; sings with drums and pots, and &quot;Liehzi&quot; believes that death means eternal rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when Mozi argued that &quot;the ghosts and gods must be solemnly sacrificed&quot;, he also exposed his true thoughts: &quot;Although the ghosts and gods are asked to die, this can still bring joy to the crowd and get relatives in the hometown&quot;—— &quot;Even if there are really no ghosts and gods, we can still connect with the villagers through ritual gatherings.&quot; This is the same as Confucianism, which shows that Mozi&#39;s own belief was not so firm. After all, it is hard to imagine that monotheistic believers would say, &quot;Even if there is really no God, belief in God can have the following benefits...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the Mohist school, which emphasizes ghosts and gods the most among the local schools, has this kind of attitude towards the existence of ghosts and gods. Attitude, it is not difficult to understand why the early setting of the underworld in Chinese mythology is so monotonous. Before the introduction and prosperity of Buddhism, although China had the concept of the underworld, it was still very simple: the underworld is the destination of the soul and is controlled by the Lord Taishan, but there is no such thing as hell; and although the story of reincarnation appeared very early, it is not It is regarded as a fixed procedure in the underworld, and is just an anecdote similar to &quot;seizing the body&quot; in later generations. Therefore, there is no concept of reincarnation and rebirth. For the ancients, death still means eternal separation and tranquility. As the saying goes, &quot;What is the way to die? The body is supported by the same mountain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going to hell after death is also the oldest view of life and death in China. It is still used as a euphemism for death to this day. There is also a famous story here, where Zheng Zhuanggong dug into the ground to meet his mother:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zheng Zhuanggong decided that his younger brother had rebelled, he was very angry with his mother Wu Jiang who favored his younger brother. He put Wu Jiang under house arrest in Yingdi, and swore a poisonous oath: &quot;It&#39;s not as good as Huangquan, and we won&#39;t see each other again.&quot; This means we won&#39;t see each other until we die. As a result, Ying Kaoshu, an official of Yingdi, successfully persuaded Duke Zhuang of Zheng and aroused his family affection and filial piety. But Duke Zhuang still used the oath of poison as an excuse, so Uncle Yingkao said: &quot;This is easy to do. We can dig tunnels until the yellow spring water is dug out, and build an underground courtyard there. Can&#39;t you guys meet?&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;So Zhuang Gong, mother and son were able to meet in the tunnel. They hugged each other and cried, and reconciled as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people were speechless when they first read this paragraph: they reconciled as before, but the problem is that Zheng Zhuanggong and his mother didn&#39;t like each other at first... And the Yellow Spring is really a yellow spring? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Huangquan Temple comes from burial. After death, people go underground, not just Huangquan. Most scholars believe that the original meaning of Huangquan is underground water, because many three-generation ancient tombs are located below the water level. When Buddhism brought reincarnation in, it combined with the view of Huangquan to create &quot;Hell&quot; (Naluka) - the Indian native &quot;Naluka&quot;, which is more similar to a parallel universe or an alien space. After death, people will enter this Space is judged; but Chinese tradition believes that after death, people must go underground. Therefore, the Buddhists had no choice but to move &quot;Naluojia&quot; underground, which gave it the name &quot;Hell&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reincarnation of Buddhism is inherited from the traditional setting of Hinduism. There are actually similar theories all over the world. For example, the ancient Greek philosopher Plato often mentioned reincarnation in his books. But for most civilizations, this theory is just an anecdote, not a universally accepted assumption. Only in South Asia, reincarnation is the axiomatic basis of all religions and philosophies. Even the reason why the Buddha became a monk was to find the right path to escape the suffering of reincarnation. Buddhism believes that if all living beings are freed from reincarnation, it means the end of all &quot;suffering&quot;. This is what Buddhism says &quot;all living beings are suffering&quot;. Beings who are not in the &quot;reincarnation&quot; are no longer sentient beings, but Buddhas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Buddhist theory of reincarnation is obviously in conflict with China’s native sacrifices. In order to solve this conflict, there are various patches, such as &quot;Ghosts queue up in the underworld to be reincarnated, and they have to live during the lottery.&quot; This &quot;lottery&quot; state between two reincarnations and two deaths is called the &quot;bardo&quot; in Buddhism. But this patch is still incomplete - the emperor wants to offer sacrifices to his ancestors. Is it because the ancestors have waited hundreds of years and still not passed away? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after Taoism absorbed the concept of reincarnation, it added another patch: humans have three souls and seven souls, and the three souls are the heaven soul, the earth soul, and the life soul. What dissipates after death is not the soul, but the soul. The three souls reincarnate after death, the heavenly soul goes to heaven, and the earthly soul lives in the ancestral hall or tomb. Therefore, before a person&#39;s life soul is reincarnated, all the money burned is for the life soul. The soul of life is reincarnated, and what is burned is for the soul of earth. Different Taoist schools have different patch theories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in modern times, Christianity has brought heaven into the world, and the situation has become even more confusing: After death, a person can enjoy the sacrifices of his descendants in the underworld and enter the six realms of reincarnation. Can he also watch his descendants in heaven at the same time? Some people have tried to reconcile this: after death, people enter Hades to be judged. After the verdict, the guilty go to reincarnation or hell, and the innocent ascend to heaven where they are, and accept sacrifices, perfect. In fact, these are not important, because the Chinese people&#39;s attitude towards life and death still comes from Confucianism: everything is a moral ceremony rather than a religious ceremony, and everything is to comfort the living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Christian attitude towards ghosts, it is also very interesting to study in detail: the devil (Satan, the devil) or demons (that is, the fallen angels who follow the devil) we often call, although they are translated as &quot;ghosts&quot;, But it is not the same thing as Chinese ghosts. The ghost that the Chinese talk about is closer to the ghost that the Europeans talk about. According to the Bible, after death, the soul will sleep with the body, waiting for the arrival of judgment and resurrection in the last days. People who belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death, which the Bible calls the new heaven and new earth; people who do not belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death. Imprisoned in Hades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Christianity believes that ghost phenomena in the world are all illusions made by Satan, and there are no ghosts in the world at all. Some Christians believe in the existence of ghosts, but are opposed to any form of communication with them because the Old Testament repeatedly warns against ghost communication rituals. Therefore, we can see that ghosts rarely appear in European and American ghost films. Vampires, werewolves, and cursed children are the common protagonists - but even these ghosts are also opposed by Christianity. Therefore, every year on Halloween, there are still Christian churches in Europe and the United States advocating a boycott and advocating that if children come to ask for candy, they can be given a Bible or a cross as a gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海关总署：11月1日起出入境人员免于填报健康申明卡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259653]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:42:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Frontier Health and Quarantine Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and its implementation rules, the General Administration of Customs decided to Starting from 0:00 on November 1, 2023, entry and exit personnel are exempted from filling in the &quot;People&#39;s Republic of China Entry/Exit Health Declaration Card&quot;, but they have infectious diseases such as fever, cough, difficulty breathing, vomiting, diarrhea, rash, and unexplained subcutaneous bleeding. Entry-exit personnel who have symptoms or have been diagnosed with infectious diseases must actively declare their health to the customs and cooperate with the customs in health and quarantine work such as temperature testing, epidemiological investigations, medical inspections, and sampling tests. Those who conceal or evade quarantine will bear corresponding legal responsibilities; those who cause the spread of quarantine infectious diseases or pose a serious risk of spread will bear corresponding criminal responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General Administration of Customs&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 26, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访德勤中国副主席吴卫军：  “巩固银行改革成果，需要一张干净的资产负债表”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The elephant danced, and everyone was shocked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the list of the top 500 companies in 2023 released by Fortune, China&#39;s four major state-owned banks are all in the top 50; in the 2023 world&#39;s 1,000 banks based on Tier 1 capital released by the British &quot;Banker&quot; In the ranking, four major state-owned banks have ranked among the top four for the sixth consecutive year. In terms of net profit alone, the four major state-owned banks have surpassed their international peers: in the first half of 2023, the total exceeded 603.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than twenty years ago, the four major banks fell into &quot;technical bankruptcy.&quot; After China&#39;s accession to the WTO, the country&#39;s door opened wide, and foreign banks entered China frequently, and since 2006 they have enjoyed national treatment. Observers and the industry have been crying wolf for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, China Construction Bank and Bank of China were designated by the State Council as pilot projects for the shareholding reform of wholly state-owned banks, and were expected to &quot;transform into internationally competitive modern joint-stock commercial banks in about three years.&quot; After unprecedented financial restructuring and the introduction of international strategic investment, China Construction Bank and Bank of China were listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange and Shanghai Stock Exchange in 2005 and 2006 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This move has clarified a replicable path for the shareholding reform and listing of ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China and Postal Savings Bank of China. As Jiang Jianqing, the then chairman of ICBC, said, the joint-stock reform is a glorious prelude to the reform of my country&#39;s state-owned banks. It is also a desperate battle with no retreat and a reform that cannot afford to lose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the glorious prologue, strengthening corporate governance is an important task. Under layer upon layer supervision, the four major industries are moving inwards and innovating continuously. A clean financial statement trusted by global investors is an example of 20 years of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deloitte, PricewaterhouseCoopers, KPMG, and Ernst &amp; Young are the four internationally renowned accounting firms (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Big Four&quot;). Among them, Deloitte China Vice Chairman Wu Weijun has served as the Bank of China and China Postal Savings The signing accountant for the stock reform and listing of banks. The former is the pilot stock reform and listing of China&#39;s state-owned banks, and the latter is the final project of the stock reform and listing of China&#39;s state-owned banks. He is praised by the financial industry for participating in and leading the design of a &quot;bank reform roadmap&quot; suitable for China&#39;s national conditions, and providing technical guidance for promoting the reform of the four major state-owned commercial banks in the three areas of corporate governance, financial reporting and capital restructuring. He is also known as the accountant most familiar with China&#39;s state-owned banks, as he has served as the signing accountant for Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Postal Savings Bank of China. Today, he has served as the signing accountant for the annual report of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China for three consecutive years. As early as more than 20 years ago, he served as a partner of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, actively promoted the implementation of the localization transformation plan of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, and has been committed to playing the role of auditors as &quot;gatekeepers&quot; in the capital market. &quot; value and have a &quot;capital eye&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a fellow traveler in the great era of China&#39;s banking reform and opening up, on the occasion of the 45th anniversary of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up, Wu Weijun repeatedly emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the reform of China&#39;s four major state-owned commercial banks is a The results and historical significance of the arduous reform despite all difficulties are also remarkable. Today, the world is facing major changes unseen in a century, and China&#39;s financial industry will face huge historical challenges. At this important moment in the deepening and development of international and domestic finance, the presence of Chinese financial entrepreneurs is crucial. They will lead Chinese financial companies to shift from expanding externally to strengthening connotation with high quality. He personally is willing to continue to serve the development of the country&#39;s financial industry professionally. “It is the most glorious thing in my profession that the accounting statements I sign can be recognized by the international capital market and international supervision.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Weijun particularly emphasized the internationalization of talents. &quot;I suggest that Chinese enterprises comprehensively review the existing international talent training system and build an advanced international talent competency model. Without talents with international vision and international standards, it will be difficult to consolidate the results of 45 years of reform and opening up, and it will be difficult to Become an effective participant in the international capital market and international financial industry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;894&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Weijun: Vice Chairman of Deloitte China and one of the first Chinese partners of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms. Starting from 2021, he will serve as the signing accountant for the accounting statement audit of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the accounting statements signed out are recognized by the international capital market, it will be my most glorious &quot;Things&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Weijun grew up rapidly from an ordinary farmer&#39;s family in the tide of reform and opening up. He was not only the first Chinese partner of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, but also the first to obtain the British Chartered Certified Accountant after 1949. Qualified Mainland Chinese. During his more than 30-year career, he has worked in mainland China, Hong Kong, New York, London and Sydney, and has participated in, promoted and witnessed many historic transformational events in the financial and accounting fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1993 to 1994, he assisted American expert Tom Macy in serving the People’s Bank of China’s Financial System Prudential Supervision Reform Consulting Project, introducing the most basic risks into the risk management of commercial banks. Evaluation method - five-level classification of loans, and establish an accounting system for the Chinese banking industry that can be basically understood and accepted by international organizations and global peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When assessing the historical value and even the impact of these two events on today, he said, &quot;The impact of these two events cannot be overemphasized. The accounting system of commercial banks is in line with international standards and has provided international Investors and counterparties recognize our banks, and the Basel banking regulatory system accepts our banks, creating conditions for state-owned commercial banks to establish accounting controls, risk management and modern corporate governance systems. The five-level loan classification not only provides banks with It provides basic risk management tools, helps maintain asset quality, and also provides regulatory agencies with a regulatory grip for financial stability. This is the institutional foundation for modern financial development. It is important to realize that the institutional construction for the development of China&#39;s modern financial industry only takes 30 years In two years, we still have a lot to learn and improve.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, he experienced an unforgettable memory in his career - participating in and leading the design of the &quot;Bank Reform Roadmap.&quot; He commented on this, &quot;The reform of China&#39;s four major state-owned commercial banks is an arduous reform that overcomes all difficulties. But its results and historical significance are significant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can the reform persist and advance rapidly? Wu Weijun said, &quot;Supporting such a difficult banking reform to move forward is the determination of the central government&#39;s top management, as well as the professionalism and courage of the leaders at the executive level. At that time, I was the only one in the leadership team of the audit team who grew up in mainland China. . I very much want to carry out the reform of China’s banking industry and bring China’s state-owned banks into the ranks of the international banking industry. If the accounting statements I sign can be recognized by the international capital market and international supervision, it will be a great achievement in my major. The most glorious thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also participated in the formulation and implementation of the localization transformation plan of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms from 2010 to 2012. &quot;I value the inheritance of professionalism. Professionalism has two supporting points, one is moral integrity, and the other is professional service to the country, because the premise of professionalism is patriotism. Professionalism is the foundation of professionals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that in financial companies, the work of external auditors has special characteristics, that is, high-quality external audits are not only needed to protect the rights and interests of shareholders, but also to meet the regulatory compliance needs of domestic and foreign banks, and are also global financial and commodity trading counterparties. needs for party exposure risk management. The total on-balance sheet assets of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, where he serves as the signing accountant, exceed 40 trillion yuan. He told the team that they must make professional efforts to help ICBC increase its return on assets, even if it is only one ten thousandth. One ten thousandth of 40 trillion yuan in assets is 4 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only serving the banking industry, in important overseas capital markets, the &quot;Big Four&quot; members generally serve more than 70% of the listed companies. At present, China&#39;s capital market has become the second largest market in the world, but as of the end of October 2023, there were about 5,300 A-share listed companies, of which the number of companies with audit reports issued by the &quot;Big Four&quot; Chinese member firms only accounted for about 7%. Faced with such a gap, Wu Weijun believes that there is still much room for improvement in being a &quot;capital eye&quot;, which mainly includes clarifying the relationship between financial information preparers, auditors and regulators in the financial reporting chain and consolidating responsibilities; using large Data analysis and other technological means can improve the accuracy and effectiveness of audits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is generally believed that audit reports signed by the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, including Deloitte, are a passport to the international capital market. With it, the price of international financing for enterprises can be maintained at a more reasonable level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;Without international talents, it is difficult to achieve&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;international integration of capital chains”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said that when professional service organizations first entered China, they helped attract foreign investment. Later, their services focused on supporting the reform of Chinese enterprises and their entry into international capital. market. May I ask, what was the biggest difficulty in attracting foreign investment into China in the 1990s? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1978, China began to implement the policy of reform and opening up. In the early 1990s, China&#39;s economic system reform entered a new stage of transformation, starting from a &quot;planned economy as the mainstay, market regulation as a supplement&quot; to a &quot;socialist market economy&quot; system. In 1992, the 14th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed the establishment of a socialist market economic system, and China&#39;s economic system began to undergo profound changes. How can international investors have enough confidence to enter China and understand China? The biggest difficulty in attracting foreign investment at that time was how to convince international investors that the Chinese government could truly embrace the market economy, follow international rules, and protect the legitimate rights and interests of investors during the transition from a planned economy to a market economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the state-owned bank reform period that began in 2003, state-owned banks What are the difficulties for commercial banks to attract foreign capital to invest in Chinese state-owned banks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2002, I served in the restructuring and share reform and listing of Bank of China Hong Kong. This project made me realize that the real stage for China’s financial system reform is in the mainland. After returning to Beijing, I served on the reform of the Bank of China. In 2005, Bank of China successively introduced international strategic investors—Royal Bank of Scotland, Temasek, UBS Group, and Asian Development Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When state-owned commercial banks introduced international strategic investors in the early 21st century, the main focus of negotiations between China and foreign parties included the following aspects: first, whether they had consolidated their balance sheets; second, whether they had The ability to establish a corporate governance mechanism and operate it in accordance with the board of directors&#39; charter and rules of procedure; third, whether the risk management mechanism is effective in the long term. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foreign capital entering China is attracted not only by the size of the Chinese economy and the market opportunities brought by its high growth, but also by its diligent and studious workers and its management that is willing to abide by international rules and cooperate with the international community. By. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foundation of financial cooperation lies in the &quot;ability&quot; and &quot;willingness&quot; of the counterparty. For example, if you borrow money from someone else, what the person who lends you money cares most about is your ability to repay it? Are you willing to pay it back? Therefore, we cannot damage or lose the goodwill that has been established in the international capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Judging from the foreign-funded companies you have contacted, they are now investing in China What to expect from the environment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Foreign capital enters China because they can make money in China. The basis for making money is not the absence of risks, but an understanding of risks and predictable returns. Only when the government&#39;s rules are transparent and things are done according to rules can capital flow more effectively. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The focus of the &quot;Big Four&quot; services in China is Support Chinese enterprises in reforming and entering international capital markets. Compared with more than 20 years ago, what new phenomena are emerging for Chinese companies going global now? What advice do you have for companies with a “going global” strategy? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We should not only discuss the &quot;going out&quot; of Chinese enterprises, but also expand to the international integration and international integration of Chinese enterprises. . Talent is always the foundation of development strategy and the source of core competitiveness. Without international talents, it would be difficult for Chinese companies to &quot;go global&quot; and enter the international capital market, let alone the international integration of supply chains and the international integration of capital chains. I suggest that Chinese companies comprehensively examine the existing international talent training system, build an advanced international talent competency model, explore more effective talent training models in the digital economy era and the post-epidemic era, and let the international capital market better see that it is What kind of people are managing Chinese companies now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bank of China and Industrial and Commercial Bank of China have opened operating institutions and outlets in more than 50 overseas countries and regions. They provide financial support for the integration of Chinese enterprises into the world economy. The overseas financial licenses and network resources of Bank of China and Industrial and Commercial Bank of China are important assets accumulated from the reform of China&#39;s financial industry. In the current international geopolitical environment, it is almost impossible for Chinese financial institutions to obtain financial licenses in important overseas financial center cities. Therefore, the overseas license assets and network resources of Chinese financial institutions must be particularly cherished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country’s financial institutions must send their best talents to overseas financial center cities for experience, accumulate experience in collaboration with international regulatory agencies, establish communication channels, and form an echelon of international financial talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Be on thin ice&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As early as 1993 to 1994, you assisted American expert Tom Macy in serving the People’s Bank of China’s financial system prudential supervision reform project. 30 years ago, where was the gap between the supervision of China&#39;s financial industry and that of the international market? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Thirty years ago, the gap between China’s financial industry supervision and its international counterparts was mainly due to the lack of professionalism in supervision. It was not until the establishment of the China Banking Regulatory Commission and the China Insurance Regulatory Commission, that is, in 2003, that China formed a specialized regulatory agency and regulatory team. In 1993, there was no technical basis for dialogue between China’s financial regulators and international peers. Therefore, we assisted the People’s Bank of China in designing an accounting subject system and introducing the most basic risk assessment method—five-level loan classification. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the general direction of China&#39;s financial industry reform was marketization and internationalization. Both regulators and regulated persons had the enthusiasm and initiative to actively learn from foreign experience. This is the starting point for an international dialogue. Professional service organizations, such as Deloitte, mainly serve as a bridge for dialogue and communication between Chinese regulatory agencies, financial companies and international organizations. When China&#39;s financial institutions were reformed and listed, we played the role of &quot;marrying daughters&quot; and carrying the sedan chair. The gap is not terrible. The terrible thing is that there are no people on both sides of the gap who are willing to take a step forward. In the financial industry, we still don’t have the capital to be proud of. We must have an attitude of walking on thin ice. In the financial battlefield, it is never your competitors who defeat you. This is called professionalism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past 20 years, the financial regulatory system has undergone many changes. The China Banking Regulatory Commission and the China Insurance Regulatory Commission were born out of the People&#39;s Bank of China and were established simultaneously in 2003. Later, they were merged into the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission in 2018 until the State Administration of Financial Supervision was listed in 2023. Do you think there is room for change compared to the international regulatory regime? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For China’s financial industry, 2023 is an extraordinary year. China&#39;s financial regulatory system has been transformed into &quot;one committee, one bank, one bureau and one meeting.&quot; No matter how the organization is set up, there is only one room for change, and that is to improve professionalism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of improving China&#39;s regulatory level in the past 20 years, I have put forward my professional opinions in three areas and had a positive impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first point of view is to strengthen the &quot;iron triangle&quot; relationship of financial supervision. This point of view was raised in 2009 after I returned from my secondment at the UK Financial Regulatory Authority. Under the financial regulatory framework, the &quot;iron triangle&quot; relationship refers to the tripartite relationship between the financial regulatory authorities, the central bank and the Ministry of Finance. The financial crisis tests a country&#39;s financial emergency and leadership capabilities. Improving the coordination capabilities of the &quot;Iron Triangle&quot; relationship and responding quickly and effectively to crises plays an important role. Solving the problems of the financial system requires more than one government agency alone. Even in normal economic times, the three agencies need to coordinate to provide clear and non-duplicate guidance to the financial system. In terms of unified leadership of the financial system, the coordination and execution capabilities of this &quot;iron triangle&quot; need to continue to be improved. Therefore, the establishment of the Central Financial Working Committee is a need for modern economic and financial management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second point of view is to establish a regulatory tripartite negotiation mechanism. This view was raised when I, as a representative of an accounting firm, communicated with the then leaders of the China Banking Regulatory Commission after the establishment of the China Banking Regulatory Commission in March 2003. At that time, I proposed that we should learn from advanced international practices and that the regulatory authorities organize tripartite meetings every year for regulated financial institutions and their external auditors to discuss financial and business risk issues of regulatory concern and arrange regulatory work. Sometimes, closed meetings can even be arranged, where the regulator and the external auditor communicate on important and material issues without the presence of the regulated institution&#39;s management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third point of view is to supervise the shareholders of financial institutions. This was raised seriously by me at a seminar held in Xianghe, Hebei Province in 2005 to prepare for the listing of Bank of China. The bank&#39;s capital adequacy ratio requirement is 8%, which means the bank uses a leverage ratio of 12.5 times. If shareholders are not monitored, banks may be exposed to bad shareholder behavior. Discussion of the proposed regulation of shareholders also extends to Huijin&#39;s management model. I firmly express my support for Huijin’s model and promote Huijin to become a professional management organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back now, these views of mine can stand the test of time. I believe that some of the views I expressed today will prove to be important 30 years later and will appear on my transcript of professional service to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the structure of my country&#39;s financial regulatory system has been significantly adjusted and optimized. Under the existing regulatory framework, how to improve the effectiveness of the regulatory system and operating mechanisms? In terms of operational effectiveness, the following three articles must be done in particular: first, how to attract and retain the best financial talents to join the financial supervision team; second, how to coordinate supervision between the central bank, the State Administration of Financial Supervision, the China Securities Regulatory Commission and other regulatory authorities Collaboration, how to respect the Ministry of Finance’s status as the last savior, how to give full play to the shareholder supervision role of the Financial SASAC (currently undertaken by Huijin and the Financial Department of the Ministry of Finance); third, how to develop and apply more powerful regulatory technology tools to enhance Supervision quality and effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You suggest attracting and retaining the best financial talents to join the regulatory team. In the civil service sector, how to achieve breakthroughs and attract outstanding talents at market prices? Is there anything we can learn from foreign financial regulatory agencies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Financial supervision and fiscal management and other institutions must respect professionalism. They function and are professionally based. We must trust experts and not doubt the patriotism possessed by professionals. Technical talents must be protected and supported in the civil service system. In the British and American financial regulatory systems, only high-level people, such as the chairman of the Federal Reserve, are listed in the civil service system. All other professionals are paid according to market prices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have said before that the financial industry needs to strengthen supervision . In fact, the financial industry has been tightening regulations. How do you view the relationship between strong supervision and reform and innovation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Strong supervision and reform and innovation are not contradictory and cannot be neglected. Only by strengthening supervision can we prevent and resolve systemic financial risks; only by reform and innovation can we enhance the diversity of financial products and services, enhance the breadth and depth of the financial market, and better meet the financial needs of the people and the real economy. Smart financial entrepreneurs believe that supporting the real economy is supporting the future of the financial industry. The strengthening and bonding of the relationship between the real economy and the financial industry requires financial innovation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strong supervision and reform and innovation are &quot;both necessary&quot; and &quot;necessary&quot;. The key is to balance the relationship between supervision and innovation and grasp the intensity and boundaries of supervision. In short, regulation must be neither insufficient nor excessive. Excessive regulation will hinder reform and innovation for sustainable financial development. Of course, reform and innovation cannot be at the expense of significantly increasing systemic financial risks, and financial behaviors that are divorced from the real economy cannot be condoned. &quot;Idling&quot; financial innovation that is divorced from the real economy and within the financial link is &quot;pseudo-innovation&quot; for the purpose of financial profit-seeking, and must be stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“ &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Respect for professionalism is &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;bank reform &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;guarantee of courage in the face of danger &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The regulatory system is constantly changing, and banks are also constantly changing. You have participated in and led the design of the &quot;Bank Reform Roadmap&quot; that suits China&#39;s national conditions. At that time, the four major banks were considered &quot;technically bankrupt&quot; due to their extremely large non-performing assets. Where did your courage come from to design a &quot;reform roadmap&quot; and participate in bank reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Before the reform, China’s four major state-owned commercial banks were “technically bankrupt” and relied only on implicit state financial guarantees. to make ends meet. If there is no shareholding reform, the four major state-owned commercial banks will go from &quot;technical bankruptcy&quot; to actual bankruptcy. This was an urgent problem that needed to be solved in China&#39;s economic system reform at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们敢于为“技术性破产”的四大国有商业银行设计改革路线图，是因为我们看到了国家破釜沉舟、排除万难的改革勇气和定力；是因为我们对自身的专业能力有信心，我们有能力对金融机构面对的问题动手术；是因为金融机构的管理层有担当，并且敢于承担责任，能够把我们列出来的任务清单执行下去。 2003年，在完成中国银行的审计后，我们提出了五百多条管理建议，中国银行的行领导专门责成内审部成立工作组，监督落实我们提出的建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003年至2006 年，你担任签字会计师，协助中国银行在香港和上海两地上市。 2012 年，你担任签字会计师协助中国邮储银行在香港上市。你对国有大行进一步深化改革有信心吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我对国有大行的改革和发展一直充满信心。这种信心的基础是对金融改革决策者和领导者的认同，包括对他们制定的政策方向的认同。金融机构的领导者意识到不改革便是死路一条，他们利用自己的知识储备，愿意与国内外专家配合，寻找改革的出路，是他们提出来，“我们需要一张路线图”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时的金融改革决策者和领导者，坚持市场化和国际化方向，尊重专业人士，信任并充分发挥国内外专家的力量。国有大行已经完成改革阶段的工作任务，当前面临的挑战是持续提升核心竞争力，更加高效地适应新环境、新变化、新趋势。与我们打过交道的国有大行的领导者是专业的。在任何时代，我们都需要尊重专业，尊重专业是信心的来源，是临危不惧的胆识保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了协助中国银行和中国邮储银行股改上市外，你还曾担任或正担任中国建设银行、中国农业银行、中国工商银行的签字会计师。在上市之后，国有银行改革和发展的难点是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于股改上市之后中国银行业的发展，我想用八个字来概括：成就巨大、任重道远。在股改上市之后，国有控股大型商业银行取得了令人瞩目的成就：财务和风险防控能力增强；资产负债表比较夯实，创造利润的能力增强；建成了以“四会一层”为核心，获得国际资本市场认可的公司治理体系；形成了国际化经营的布局。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如今，银行改革和发展面临着更加复杂、严峻的挑战。如何建设现代化的商业银行永远是一个难题，是一个复杂而艰巨的工程，涵盖战略管理、风险管理、信息系统和企业文化方方面面。尤为艰难之处是，国有商业银行的领导要明确如何平衡国有银行的政策属性和商业属性，在坚持党的领导前提下，实现经济效益社会责任兼顾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;它们为何有动力自我革命？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有大行的自我革命动力主要来自以下三个方面：国家和政府办好银行的决心和领导力；国有大行与国际接轨的治理体系已经建立；金融企业家和职业银行家的成长、成就和积极作为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以国有大行董事会的有效性为例，我做个说明。国有大行的董事会主要由三组董事组成，一组是代表国有股东的股权董事，他们来自财政部和中央汇金公司；一组是独立董事，他们具备国际经验及风险管理、法律、会计等领域的专业知识；一组是负责经营管理的执行董事，他们是中管干部。这是一支兼具专业性和政治性的、强大的银行战略管理队伍。他们的自我驱动力很强，有崇高的使命感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;增强“数目字管理能力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2018年，作为清华大学国家金融研究院金融与发展研究中心客座研究员，你专注深度研究中国银行业及金融体系改革的相关问题，总结改革开放40年在会计发展和银行改革方面累积的经验。请问，在会计领域，你提出的主要问题和总结的经验是什么？会计和金融的关系是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;会计准则体系、审计市场建设和会计人才水平直接影响一个国家的会计能力。回首改革开放的45年，中国会计准则不断优化完善，实现行业覆盖，全国统一，国际接轨；审计市场进行制度性改革，建成适应国家市场体系的多层次会计师事务所；会计人才培养获得重视，建立国家会计学院，开展全国会计领军人才项目，为中国改革与发展培育专业力量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“经济越发展，会计越重要”。企业会计准则是市场经济的重要规则，注册会计师行业承担着建设社会诚信的重要责任，而会计人才也是国家发展需要的战略人才。会计准则，注册会计师行业和会计人才的水平是会计能力的重要因素。一个国家的会计能力反映了它的经济制度和政府管治软实力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄仁宇教授在《万历十五年》一书中论述了他的大历史观。其中最为重要的一个理论是国家的“数目字管理能力”。他认为，一个稳定的和成熟的商业社会需要具备计算和记录整个社会的资源的能力，只有这样，“资金方便对流，实物经济变为金融经济，可以交换的条件增多，分工进一步合理化，整个国家可以以&#39;数目字管理&#39;”——进而国家可以强盛。简单而言，黄仁宇教授认为，数目字管理能力是国家强盛的基础。我十分认同这个观点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会计能力是国家治理能力的基础，特别是在数字经济时代，形成和运用数字资产都需要会计这一基本功能的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于会计和金融的关系，我的观点是鲜明的。企业的金融是财务，社会的财务是金融。会计、财务和金融将是“三位一体”的学科。每个人都应老老实实地学点会计知识，因为所有的经济活动最终都要经受“借记”和“贷记”的检验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;金融企业需从“外延做大”转向“内涵做强”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最新的世界500强名单里，四大行均在前50名；在英国《银行家》杂志的评选中，四大行霸榜前四。你观察，中国银行业在逆周期经营能力和风控能力方面存在哪些挑战？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有商业银行的资产负债表不再是简单的商业经营实体的资产负债表，而是由中国经济基本面支撑，它反映了中国社会的金融资产分布。商业银行的资产质量，将高度依赖国有经济和政府财务状况的健康度。这是国有大行资产负债表的主体特殊性。银行要发挥好在经济运行中的风险代理监督作用，及时发现风险，并向国家相关部门呈报经济运行中存在的风险和隐患。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有商业银行的成绩单必须以“长期主义”为基础，资产负债表的快速扩张更加需要执行严格的风险纪律，特别是严格的信贷纪律。银行家需要更执著地坚持专业主义精神，吸收上一轮去杠杆的教训，提高放贷和购买债券的质量标准，在增量上管好不良资产的入口，同时不断夯实存量资产质量，保持充足的资本和损失吸收缓冲垫，坚持科学的流动性管理方法，坚守一张干净的、健康的、可持续的资产负债表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;目前看，你认为中国国有银行业还需要深化哪些改革和促进哪些发展？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;金融业的发展始终与时代大局保持高度关联。当今世界面临百年未有之大变局，中国金融业已经迎来巨大的历史挑战。在国际和国内金融深化与发展的重大时刻，中国金融企业家的存在，至关重要。作为世界第二大经济体，今天中国的金融业，比任何时候都更迫切地需要一支强大的金融企业家队伍，需要他们充分发挥领导力，引领中国金融企业从简单地外延做大，转向高质量地内涵做强。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们要爱护中国的金融企业家。金融是承担风险的行业，金融企业家要做的业务决策就是承担风险的决策。如果运用没有边界的问责制度来束缚金融企业家，这肯定会扼杀金融企业家承担风险的主动性，削弱金融对实体经济的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融企业家在社会经济运行中还发挥着一个鲜为人知的功能，他们对社会经济的运行履行着代理监督作用。以银行家为例，他们把贷款借给企业，令他们感到日夜不安的是借款人无法偿还贷款本息的风险。因此，银行家从放贷之日起，就会定期走访企业，要求企业维护健康的财务状况，满足贷款合同要求，这种监督作用提高了中国经济发展的效率；同时，金融机构也累积了有关借款人和行业的知识，为资金有效地流向实体经济把握方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国创新为何会成功？因为中国的经济体量大，试错成本平摊下来很小。成功之后，创新带来的总体经济效果很大。因此，必须要鼓励这样一个试错机制，更好地吸引资本进入创新市场。这就需要投资银行的参与，我们要鼓励培养一批在中国扎根、支撑中国经济向高质量、高效率发展的投资银行家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[约瑟夫·奈：中美不会彼此构成威胁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 07:57:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011604556288&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;成稿555&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot;>;&lt;/source>;成稿555&lt;/video>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日常用语的“职业密码”丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259566]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 23:02:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;朋友是资深律师，一天接到老同学的电话，问他医院有没有熟人，家里长辈突发疾病，需要立即住院。正在应酬，律师急问：“你父亲涉嫌什么罪名？”一言既出，众人大笑，他才愣住：酒还没多喝，话怎么乱了？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年之前，也是这位律师，也是到饭店用餐，一位迟到的兄弟打电话问他在哪个包间，他自信满满地回复：第三法庭！——看看，一个人的口误里，藏着多少他的职业信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个张口说话的人，都有程度不同的口音，大致可以“听”出他的出生地或成长地。那些貌似天生说一口标准普通话的，其实也不过是他的口音。日常交流时，人们遣词造句、引经据典，往往则有着他职业的烙印，或许只是用语的惯性而已。有道是，三句话不离本行。有时，一个词句就可能暴露当事人的职业信息，也算一种“话里有话”吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三百六十行，行行有行话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;省级电视台一位同行，和我一样口拙，平时也操一口原产地“不懂话”。他是专门做监督类报道的，我有些担心他的暗访能不能顺利。“不懂话”同行得意地向我透露：因为口音重，到家乡方言区周边暗访、明查，更有迷惑性，都被当成家乡人。一旦“跨区”，鸡同鸭讲，常常要急出几身汗，不知道对方“唱什么歌”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，那位电视同行在自己的方言“舒适区”也屡屡遭遇尴尬。在追踪调查一件民生投诉时，他以当地百姓身份，亲历办事程序，政务中心接待人员阅人无数，颇有经验，当场发现“破绽”：你，你是……记者吧？问这问那的，而且翻来覆去。咱们老百姓来办事很直接，不会像你这样！一语识破暗访者，那位同行假装苦涩一笑飘过，只好默认倒霉，换个时段再去暗访一回。这一次，默念三遍：去套路，去套路，去套路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你当时是怎么想的”“这件事你怎么看”“这个问题有什么解决办法”……记者的套话，已经潜入我们的日常。最近一次从老家返回省城，手机上嘀嗒了一辆顺风车，司机提前半小时接上我，然后南辕北辙，去接下两位乘客。闲聊间，我的记者职业习惯发作，先问他载客情况，后问他乘客背景，再问他从业经历和感受，又问他行业竞争的形势，有一搭没一搭，想了解了解当下顺风车车主的辛酸和快乐。途中服务区休息时，司机主动凑近我：老板，你人真好，和我们聊天客客气气，把我们当自己人，不像有些老板，上了车就催快开快开，一点不能耽误……我笑笑，准备给他解释刚才的聊天行为，不过是一次“流动采访”，他不过是我的又一位“采访对象”。话到嘴边，我还是决定以“老板”自居，回应他的感激：大老板都有人开车，小老板才搭顺风车。顺风，不一定顺路。要顺路，就独享不拼车。我们都是打工的，能理解你的不容易。——一段回应，好像又不自觉暴露自己的职业身份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“三句话不离本行”，揭示人的表达习惯背后大脑使用的习惯——思维习惯。职场之中，人们沟通交流、处理信息，往往有专用术语或特定话术，日复一日地高频应用，容易形成思维（表达）定势，而当现实场景不断发生变化之时，人们往往难以即时转场、切换到位。人在某个岗位（职位）上的时间越长，相应的表达惯性越大。“三句话不离本行”，也凸显人在思维、表达上的“路径依赖”。人有不同的生活、成长、专业背景。熟悉的话术，令人更有安全感，甚至是优越感：计算机专业出身的官员主政一方时，处处强调“系统化思维”；长期从事职业教育的官员转岗基础教育后，大力倡导“适合的教育”……昨天的“屁股”何以指挥今天的“脑袋”？可能也是一种“肌肉记忆”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为江苏媒体人）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目之“人在职场”，欢迎来信分享职场心声、吐槽职场经历、打破刻板印象、揭秘行业规则。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《完蛋！我被美女包围了！》热销：戳中男性痛点，顺利开辟生态位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 22:25:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;&quot; became the number one best-selling game on Steam in China after only one day of being online. Discussions about this game have also become hot searches on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon deserves concern and analysis. The plot line setting of the game is very simple. You transform into the male protagonist Gu Yi and use the first-person perspective to immersively meet, interact and socialize with six beauties with different ages, looks, personalities and family backgrounds. You can choose one of them. Develop the character deeply and make it your other half: the charming witch who loves to go to nightclubs, the intellectual sister who loves literature and art, the innocent school girl who is not materialistic, the unruly rich lady, the sexy mother who raises her children alone, and the girl who wants to be a little girl at heart. The cool CEO, the choice is yours, which one you will end up with, you can do whatever you want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, this is a male-oriented love clearance game. The target audience is men. There is no harem or side effects. It is just pure love and satisfying men&#39;s various fantasies about their significant other. There are relatively few games in this category on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public has the impression that young people, especially young men, love to play games, which is true. The hunting and war that our ancestors engaged in in the tribal era were the first priority for survival. This has become the pursuit of power and victory engraved in genes. The mainstream favorites of men are action, combat, war, civilized hegemony and strategy. The game involves a battle of wits and courage. In this type of game, most of the male players are male. Love is either absent or is just an add-on or embellishment. There is a high probability that the game producer has established such a mental position: every man’s dream is to conquer the world. , falling in love is also about capturing a woman’s heart by conquering the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The design idea of ​​this game is very different. It just allows a very ordinary man without any cheats to fall in love with a beautiful woman. Although the game has 12 hidden endings and hundreds of route choices , &quot;Every choice you make will trigger unexpected hidden stories.&quot; However, compared with the mainstream male-oriented games on the market, it is not really complicated, nor can it be said that the workmanship is exquisite, so it must be so popular. Particularly successful is that it hits the pain points of young men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A major feature of the game is &quot;real-person interactive images&quot;: six beauties with different styles are all played and photographed by real people. In the era of general artificial intelligence (AGI) led by GPT-4, it is not difficult to use AI to design stunning beauties that are more perfect than real people, and the cost is lower. This approach has already had a negative impact on the profit model of &quot;welfare girls&quot; who sell personal photos. The impact. The producers of this game went in the opposite direction, using real people to act on camera, and pre-filmed various plot lines like genuine film and television works, allowing players to choose the objects and plots they want to develop in depth, allowing players to become film and television male protagonists. , the power to control and promote the development of the plot on your own, and it can also approach the experience of interacting with real people in real life, which can be said to be thoughtful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sexual version of this game is the so-called otome game. Otome is a girl. Women choose to fall in love with men, whether they are domineering CEOs, rich second generation, celebrities, or race car drivers. In short, it is to satisfy women&#39;s perfect imagination of their significant other. In terms of proportion, there are several orders of magnitude more otome games than male-oriented romance games. In this sense, &quot;Done!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;The reason why it is so popular may be because there are too few such games. Game producers ignore and underestimate men&#39;s emotional needs. In addition, &quot;live-person interactive images&quot; fill the gap, so it suddenly opens up. an ecological niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popularity of this game is enough to show that the male world is not all about killing and working to make money. Men also have emotional needs. Our traditional culture does not encourage men to open up and express themselves. &quot;A man cannot shed tears easily.&quot; Men must appear strong and carry everything without being weak or shrinking. However, everyone has moments of weakness and emotions. There are times when I cannot bear the need to express myself and my emotions break down. Men are human beings too, and their spiritual world should also be cared for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, men’s voices have been absent from public opinion. In the statements of some merchants, there is even a saying that &quot;men&#39;s consumption power is not as good as that of dogs.&quot; However, this situation is changing. The values ​​and consumption concepts of the new generation of young men are very different from their parents. They care more about themselves and invest more in their own image and spiritual world. For example, in recent years, the consumption and consumption of male cosmetics have increased annually. Significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to iiMedia Consulting data, among Chinese users who choose to shop through online live streaming channels, 58% are men and 42% are women. Among them, those born in the 1980s and 1990s are the main shopping force, accounting for The total exceeds 80%; live streaming e-commerce shopping users are mainly distributed in first- and second-tier cities, with second-tier cities leading the way with 42%. This is very different from the impression some people have. The consumption power of young men is rising and blowing out, which is a trend worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When men convert their productivity into consumption power, they also win the hospitality of businesses. This is the rule of the game in the consumer society. &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! 》The fire is another footnote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, since it is a romance game, it will inevitably lead some people to discuss the relationship between games and reality. Some people worry that the quality of opposite-sex partners in romance games is much higher than in real life, which will cause players to invisibly raise their inner expectations and standards for mate selection, and lose interest in the available partners in reality. There should be a real social investigation on whether this effect exists and how big it is, and it is meaningless to talk about it in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a person who has to earn money to support his family and career during working hours, but only occasionally spends some time playing games during get off work hours or weekends to satisfy his dreams and fantasies that cannot be realized in real life, should not be punished. Even if you are harsh, you won’t lose your sense of reality just by playing a few games, because the gravity of the real world is strong enough to pull you back to the ground. Occasionally falling into fantasy, even if it is a fantasy that cannot be realized, will make a person&#39;s heart shine, or make the soul gain a sense of relaxation and transcendence, which is necessary for a person&#39;s mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if you are completely immersed and lost in fantasy due to the lack of anchors in the real world, and never want to get out of the virtual world, or use the perfect objects in the virtual world to ask for optional objects in the real world, then of course It is a pathology and not desirable. A sane adult should never go to this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[​张又侠：中国军队绝不答应、绝不手软]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:25:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器丨视频]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259590]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[500万人次求助，800亿元捐赠：慈善法修正可否终结个人求助争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, this type of personal help donations has exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256024&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2022, when a girl fell from a building, her family asked for help on Shuidichou. At present, such individual donations for help have exceeded 80 billion yuan. Chinese Business Daily Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 25, 2023, the draft amendment to the Charity Law after deliberation at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress will be officially released for public comment. The revised draft adds new content to regulate personal help-seeking behavior and the management of personal help-seeking online service platforms, which is considered to fill the legislative gaps and has attracted much attention. On the National People&#39;s Congress website, this is called one of the four highlights of this draft amendment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recent incident of a 2-year-old girl being bitten by a Rottweiler dog in Chengdu, public opinion questioned the individual&#39;s request for help. After the girl was bitten, her family started to raise 2 million yuan on the Easy Raising Platform. Within 5 hours and 18 minutes, more than 87,000 people donated, and the donation goal was achieved. But the girl&#39;s family quickly fell into disputes over the amount of the aid and the use of the funds. On October 25, EasyCho released refund instructions and refunded all unused donations in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, Xu Anbiao, deputy director of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, said that the original intention of this revision of the law is to improve the charity, fundraising, funding, service and other systems during emergencies, and to address some new issues that have emerged in the charity field. New situations and new problems, summarizing practical experience, such as &quot;fingertip public welfare&quot; and &quot;public welfare for everyone&quot; and other new situations and new problems that have emerged in the Internet era, it is necessary to reasonably regulate these phenomena and improve relevant systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are endless problems with personal help-seeking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Charity Law was reviewed and passed by the National People&#39;s Congress in March 2016 and has been in effect for 7 years. However, personal help-seeking has not been included in the regulation before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin, a professor at the School of Public Administration at Tsinghua University and deputy director of the Philanthropy Research Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that the legislative purpose of the Charity Law is to promote charity and regulate charity behaviors and charitable organizations. Charitable organizations can raise funds publicly for public welfare purposes and enjoy tax-free treatment, which is equivalent to the use of public resources, so its beneficiaries must be a non-specific public rather than a specific individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Personal help-seeking does not meet the purpose of public welfare, so the Charity Law did not regulate personal help-seeking at the beginning of the legislation. However, in recent years, with the help of online fundraising platforms such as LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, personal help-seeking has become more active and prominent than charity activities, and problems in the field of personal help-seeking have also emerged one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Luo Yixiao, a 6-year-old girl from Shenzhen, Guangdong, unfortunately suffered from leukemia. Her father Luo Er wrote an article online to raise about 2.7 million yuan for treatment expenses. Later, it was revealed that Luo Er had three houses and three companies in his home. He also said in an interview that &quot;the house in Shenzhen is reserved for his son,&quot; which caused him to be questioned. Amid the whirlpool of public opinion, Luo Yixiao died of illness, and Luo Er also returned all donations to the donors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Wang Fengya, a 3-year-old girl from Taikang County, Henan Province, suffered from retinoblastoma. Her mother requested help on multiple online platforms. In April 2018, it was revealed that his mother had donated 150,000 yuan through fraudulent donations to treat her son&#39;s cleft lip. Although the police investigation found that the donation fraud claim was untrue, Wang Fengya died of illness in May of that year, and her family was also subjected to online abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amid repeated controversies, calls for strengthening supervision of online fundraising platforms are getting louder and louder. In 2018, under the guidance of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, the three major online fundraising platforms, LoveChou, EasyChou and ShuidiChou, issued a self-discipline convention. This was upgraded again in 2020, proposing that platforms should abide by seven &quot;bottom-line rules&quot; to strengthen platform self-discipline management and improve Risk prevention level and improve social supervision mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2019, the country’s first online dispute over personal critical illness help was pronounced. In this case, Mr. Mo launched a personal fundraising campaign on Shuidichou for his seriously ill son. However, because he concealed his property and other social assistance, the fundraising platform took him to court and demanded the return of the donation. After trial, the Beijing Chaoyang District Court found that Mr. Mo misappropriated the funds raised for other purposes in violation of the agreed purpose, constituting a breach of contract. The first instance order ordered the full return of more than 150,000 yuan raised and the payment of corresponding interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference after the verdict was announced in the case, Wang Min, the president of the Wangjing Tribunal of the Chaoyang District Court, pointed out that there are problems in the field of personal help for serious illnesses on the Internet, such as unclear legal definitions and overly principled provisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment of the case also mentioned: &quot;At present, only departmental regulations stipulate that personal seeking help does not belong to charitable fundraising and charitable public fundraising information. Regarding the rights between the network platform and the donor in personal seeking help for serious illness on the Internet, The obligations have not yet been clearly defined.” In addition, many unclear boundaries emerged during the trial, such as whether Mr. Mo provided comprehensive information, whether the fundraising platform should provide separate items to fill in the family property item by item, whether there were insufficient verifications, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, the Chaoyang District Court sent judicial suggestions to the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Shuidichou platform respectively, recommending that the Ministry of Civil Affairs coordinate and promote the legislation on personal help-seeking behavior for serious illnesses, establish and improve departmental regulations, and promote orderly personal help-seeking for serious illnesses on the Internet. carry out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke, a lawyer at Beijing Zhicheng Law Firm, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that as an individual right, individual seeking help is not subject to legal restrictions or prohibitions. For example, going to the streets to beg, as long as it does not violate city management regulations; seeking help from classmates or relatives after falling ill is a small-scale personal request for help. Whether the information for help is true or not only involves both the donor and the recipient. issues of rights and obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the factors of the Internet, the scope of communication and influence of personal help-raising on the Internet have changed dramatically. At this time, the authenticity of the help-seeking information has a certain degree of publicity. Netizens who make donations on an online fundraising platform are both donors and users of the platform. From the perspective of providing services to users, the platform also needs to verify the authenticity of the information of the help seekers, &quot;for our vast number of donors.&quot; Very good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, the volume of personal requests for help on the Internet is huge. The first domestic &quot;Research Report on the Personal Serious Illness Help-Seeking Internet Platform (2022)&quot; shows that according to incomplete statistics, from September 2014 to the end of 2021, a total of more than 5 million serious illness patients posted help information through the personal serious illness help-seeking Internet service platform, and more than 20 100 million people donated funds through critical illness help platforms including Shuidichou, with a fundraising scale of more than 80 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Individual seeking help is a relatively active and large-scale phenomenon in society at present, and it is necessary for the Charity Law to respond in principle to this.” Jia Xijin said, but the current amendment to the Charity Law includes the addition of individuals The content of asking for help does not mean that individual asking for help is regarded as a charitable activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Information inspection” rather than “information review”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a member of the Expert Advisory Committee of the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, He Guoke participated in the meeting discussion of the revised draft of the Charity Law. According to him, due to the essential difference between personal help-seeking and charitable public welfare activities, the personal help-seeking section did not include chapters on charitable donations and charitable fundraising. Instead, it was placed in the supplementary provisions, and in the form of authorized legislation, the Civil Affairs Department of the State Council, in conjunction with Relevant departments will formulate specific management measures separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This draft amendment to the Charity Law clarifies: If an individual causes financial difficulties for his family due to illness or other reasons, and releases information for help to the society, the person seeking help and the information publisher shall be responsible for the authenticity of the information, and the personal assistance network service The platform shall bear the obligation to inspect information, and specific management measures shall be formulated separately by the civil affairs department of the State Council in conjunction with relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Guoke believes that compared with the first revised draft, the latest revised draft has three main adjustments to the content of personal help-seeking: first, the definition of personal help-seeking puts more emphasis on the reasons of &quot;personal illness&quot;; In addition, the &quot;network service provider&quot; in the amendment is clearly defined as &quot;personal assistance network service platform&quot; in the amendment, which means that when the Ministry of Civil Affairs formulates specific management measures in the future, it is likely to re-qualify the platform party to do so. Stricter management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last adjustment is that the &quot;information review obligation&quot; that the platform should bear is changed to &quot;information inspection obligation.&quot; &quot;&#39;Review&#39; is more important than &#39;inspection&#39;.&quot; He Guoke said that the platform has not been granted the power and responsibility like government departments and judicial agencies, and cannot review the property in the name of the requester. &quot;For example, the requester said that he only has one house. &quot;The platform can only see that the real estate certificate of this house is basically true, but it cannot go to the Housing Authority to check how many properties he owns in total.&quot; This adjustment was made after considering the opinions of multiple platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xijin believes that in the draft amendment to the Charity Law, it is necessary to add the principle content that &quot;the person asking for help and the person publishing the information should be responsible for the authenticity of the information&quot; because the basis for personal seeking help is still civil. In the &quot;gift&quot; relationship, the primary responsible parties are both the donor and the recipient. &quot;Whoever publishes false information is responsible&quot;; as a third party that promotes cooperation, the platform needs to conduct necessary formal reviews, such as requiring family financial information. Certificates, medical certificates, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above-mentioned Shuidichiou case, the Chaoyang District Court held that the Shuidichiou platform has strict formal review obligations and strict supervision obligations. In this case, the court found that Shuidichiou had review flaws, but this did not affect Mr. Mo’s responsibility to return the donation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information provided by Shuidichou to Southern Weekend reporters, Shuidichou has currently strengthened measures to ensure the authenticity of fundraising cases, using technology and manual methods to pass preliminary review, reexamination, third-party review, etc. The platform will continuously review user information. Only after the platform reviews the information is correct and meets the qualifications, can online fundraising be initiated normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the materials provided by Shuidichou, the platform intercepted an average of 12 fundraising applications that did not meet the requirements every day. In the first half of the year, it intercepted and rejected a total of 2,096 fundraising applications that did not meet the launch conditions, including There are 544 illegal users who have been permanently blacklisted from the platform and are prohibited from launching fundraising again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in Jia Xijin&#39;s view, individual case assistance and personal help are like &quot;after-care medicine&quot; for the plight of seriously ill families. They can exist but do not need to become bigger and stronger. She believes that it is more important to establish multiple response mechanisms, such as inclusive medical insurance and medical assistance systems, commercial insurance, public welfare advocacy and beneficiary services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明星发声缘何遭遇舆论反弹：公共空间不应是少数人表演的舞台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the discussion surrounding the incident of vicious dogs injuring people in Chongzhou, Sichuan has gradually extended to the management and disposal of stray animals in the city. On many public affairs, it has become a vent for social emotions for a period of time, including relatively rational thinking and suggestions, as well as more radical remarks and propositions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon of &quot;using topics to vent emotions&quot; is common in itself, but one of the phenomena is very interesting. After several well-known actors made remarks on personal social media calling for kindness to stray animals, their comment areas were blocked. Netizens were &quot;outraged&quot; and a large number of fans left messages to &quot;unsubscribe&quot; and &quot;drop followers&quot;. Many actors have closed the comment area to passively fight against the storm of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of traditional communication studies, it is generally believed that film and television stars rely on their personal charm, the persona they have created in public affairs for a long time, as well as the fans and traffic they bring, and they have great influence in the field of public opinion. With huge appeal and influence, the joint &quot;voice&quot; of several celebrities can often change the direction of public opinion. However, in this incident, the celebrities without exception failed in the field of public opinion. This is thought-provoking The changes actually include a series of quite profound social changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“A stage for the few” and “a society for the majority”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the era of television media and the early era of online media, “unitary subjectivity” and “central focus” are reflected Incisively and vividly, young people in frontiers and villages gaze at the love affairs and joys and sorrows of middle-class people in the reinforced concrete forests of Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou from fashion magazines, movies, TV and computer screens, and have not yet realized the need for self-subject expression. Most cultural products are produced in megacities and only depict life there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the society of the majority revolves around the stage of the minority, and regards the lifestyle of the super urban middle-class citizens performed on the stage as an advanced, civilized, and universal And one-size-fits-all paradigms and templates. The imitation of this lifestyle is considered a fashionable, progressive, and civilized pursuit, while the opposite is considered an archaic, backward, and barbaric conservatism. This “progressivist life template” is not original to urban middle-class citizens, but an imitation of the lifestyles of European and American middle-class citizens who achieved modernization and urbanization earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cultural industry born in super cities produces cultural products through imitation and interpretation of this &quot;progressive life template&quot;, and then promotes it to the whole society through cultural products. As one of the producers of cultural products, actors must naturally accept this &quot;progressive life template&quot; and the ideas behind it. Otherwise, not only will they not be able to work smoothly, they will even find it difficult to gain a foothold and live in the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is not difficult to see that although the acting styles of the actors are different, a considerable number of actors have a highly consistent personality in life: they love nature, sports and travel, and have certain ideas. Depth and artistic taste, emphasis on material enjoyment and emotional value, and a &quot;personality&quot; that is passionate about environmental protection and public welfare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in a series of public discussions derived from the &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident&quot;, some celebrities&#39; actions to speak out for &quot;kindness to stray animals&quot; are not only a commercial act to create and maintain their personalities, but also their A true reflection of values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some celebrities have ignored two issues. Their standards of civilization are based on their living environment and lifestyle. The probability of them being bitten and injured by off-leash dogs and stray dogs in their lives is extremely small. . But this is not the case for ordinary people. Data from a public health study show that taking Zhengzhou City, Henan Province as an example, there are more than 90,000 rabies exposure risk cases in Zhengzhou City every year, and dog bites account for 77.68%. More than 80% of bite cases occur in urban areas. This The data also does not include bites that did not seek medical attention. Judging from Zhengzhou&#39;s population base of nearly 13 million people, the probability of being bitten by a dog in the city is not low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a natural and instinctive reaction for people to become anxious about their own safety due to the incident of vicious dogs in Chongzhou and their own living environment. While some celebrities make empty calls to &quot;be kind to animals&quot;, they lack in-depth rational thinking about the incident itself, let alone put forward any meaningful suggestions and feasible solutions. Instead, they deliberately pretend to be &quot;civilized&quot;. Inadvertently pushing those netizens who are worried about their own safety to the opposite side of &quot;barbarism&quot; will naturally encounter fierce backlash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the trend of flattening of social public opinion in the Internet era has become more and more obvious, and &quot;mono-subjectivity&quot; has been eliminated. The routine of eliminating freedom and pluralism under the banner of freedom and pluralism has increasingly aroused public concern. In the past, it was difficult for a few celebrities to appeal to their fans and reverse the trend of public opinion. On the contrary, this can easily make &quot;vocal&quot; stars become the target of public criticism and the vent of collective emotions, leading to a situation where the comment section has collapsed and fans have collectively lost their fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let the screen return to the screen, let the reality return to reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with developed countries, our country’s modernization process is too rapid. In the process of modernization, the film and television industry has developed particularly As a result, a considerable part of the public lacks an accurate understanding of the profession of actors, and a considerable number of actors also lack an accurate positioning of their profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confusing the image of an actor in reality with the image he plays in opera is a common psychology among people in pre-modern society. Our overly rapid modernization process has more or less extended this psychology to modern society. Actors play politicians, scientists, business tycoons and other social elites on the screen, as well as the profound lines of these elite images. , making it easy for the audience to ignore one of the most basic facts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how professional and outstanding the doctors, scientists, and soldiers the actors play on stage and screen, their most professional and outstanding field is still acting. Only in the field of performance are they truly outstanding experts. They may shine in other areas outside their majors, but in the final analysis they are still ordinary people. Once their opinions exceed their professional fields, they can easily make the same mistakes as ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because of the ultra-high income level and ultra-high social status that this profession achieved during the economic boom period, which far exceeds that of general industries in society, the above basic facts are easier to ignore. Not only do a considerable number of ordinary people generally follow celebrities as &quot;opinion leaders&quot; who are morally and intellectually superior to others, there are also a considerable number of actors who increasingly express opinions outside of their own profession on public affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the &quot;disenchantment&quot; effect brought about by the flattening of the Internet, more and more people&#39;s perception of celebrities is becoming increasingly mature, and they can objectively realize that acting is just one of many professions, and celebrities are among other professions. Apart from the halo of his acting career, he is just an ordinary person who specializes in art. When faced with some public opinions expressed by celebrities that are not constructive, lack in-depth thinking, and are purely emotional expressions, we dare to express different opinions instead of blindly following them. This is also an important reason why the comment sections of many celebrities have overturned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thoughts derived from this &quot;rollover&quot; incident are actually more than the above two points, but one thing is absolutely certain: in a social environment where the pre-modern state lasts too long, the post-modern state comes too early. , the standards of &quot;civilization&quot; are set by a few people and required to be accepted by the majority, which is definitely not a civilized plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香山论坛 外国代表怎么看？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 18:57:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>