<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[育人集团贷款上班：企业巧立名目规避非法集资，员工贪图“利息差”难洗合谋嫌疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In September this year, Henan Zhengzhou Yuren Education Group’s “allowing employees to take loans to support the company” attracted widespread attention. At that time, many employees of the group reported to &quot;Red Star News&quot; that since 2019, the group has been asking employees to borrow 100,000 to 150,000 yuan each from Zhengzhou Rural Commercial Bank in the name of &quot;decoration loans&quot; for corporate use. The total loan amount More than 20 million yuan. According to a report by the CCTV Financial Channel in September, the statistical table released by the group&#39;s finance showed that in January 2021, 181 people in the group had loans of 26.02 million yuan in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yuren Group once promised its employees to provide mortgage guarantees with school buildings and land, and the borrowed money would be used to &quot;get through the difficulties together.&quot; The generous conditions proposed were to pay monthly loan interest to employees at a standard of 1.33%. , higher than the bank&#39;s 0.66%, and at the same time provide employees with benefits in terms of children&#39;s education and property purchase. Since the end of 2021, the group has often stopped paying interest, causing some loans to be overdue and credit damaged, and some employees&#39; loans will also expire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 2 this year, seven employee representatives reported illegal lending to the Henan Supervision Bureau of the State Administration of Financial Supervision. Recently, the Henan Supervision Bureau of the State Administration of Financial Supervision issued a letter of investigation opinion in response to employee representatives. After investigation, Zhengzhou Rural Commercial Bank violated the &quot;three checks&quot; regulations on loans and did not have adequate credit management in the process of issuing consumer loans to employees of Zhengzhou Yuren Education Group. Some employees violated the contract and changed the purpose of the loan, assisting Yuren Group to misappropriate loan funds and obtain certain economic benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time that “loans to work” have made news. In September 2022, Lanzhou Public Transport Group proposed that employees borrow from banks in their own names to cover their salaries from June to September. The bus company provided a joint guarantee and was responsible for monthly interest settlement and principal repayment upon maturity; in March 2023, Gome also An &quot;employee loan&quot; plan was launched, and Minsheng Bank credit loans were introduced to alleviate employees&#39; pressure on salary arrears. Before the company pays wages, employees will be reimbursed for loan interest within 30,000 yuan every month, and employees will be responsible for the excess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lanzhou Public Transport’s “loan to work” is to pay employees, Gome Group’s “employee loan” is to relieve the pressure of salary arrears, and Yuren Group’s “loan to work” is generally “for the group’s use” &quot;: Let employees take loans in their personal names, and then the employees will hand over the loaned money to the company, and the company promises to repay the money to the employees at an interest rate higher than that of the bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the whole process of the incident, the first thing to ask is, why do companies not conduct social financing in their own names, but instead ask employees to borrow money? There may be problems such as greater operating risks, lack of effective guarantee collateral, and low corporate credit. And if a company borrows money directly from employees, it is a purely private lending relationship, and the company needs to bear repayment responsibilities, and may also be suspected of illegal fund-raising. Yuren Group encourages employees to apply for &quot;decoration loans&quot; from banks in their own names. This is tantamount to taking advantage of the fact that employees have formal work units and complete credit records to use their personal loan qualifications for their own use. Not only did they successfully obtain loans from banks, The borrowers of the money are employees rather than companies, which can be described as &quot;well-intentioned&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, why are employees willing to help companies get loans to &quot;get through the difficulties together&quot;? &quot;Some employees violated the contract and changed the purpose of the loan, assisting Yuren Group to misappropriate loan funds and obtain certain economic benefits.&quot; This sentence in the investigation opinion of the Financial Supervision Bureau shows that the employees involved in the incident were not completely unaware. &quot;Being loaned&quot; means that at least some employees knew where the loan funds were going, but still conspired with the company to complete the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether these employees are coveting the &quot;interest difference&quot;, or are trying to keep the company and their own positions, or a combination of both, it seems possible at present that a conflict has formed between the employees and the company. substantial collusion. In its opinion, the Financial Supervision Bureau stated that “the whistleblower’s request to change the subject of the loan to Zhengzhou Yuren Education Group is a civil dispute and should be resolved through negotiation or litigation in accordance with civil laws and regulations.” This is also equivalent to stating that, Since employees sign and seal the loan contract, they should bear responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, the employees involved may even be suspected of breaking the law. According to Article 175 of the &quot;Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, for the purpose of making profits through on-lending, defrauding credit funds from financial institutions and on-lending to others at high interest rates constitutes the crime of on-lending at high interest rates and shall be punished with criminal detention, imprisonment or a fine; and according to the Supreme Court&#39;s &quot;On the Trial of Private Article 13 of &quot;Provisions on Several Issues Applicable to Laws in Loan Cases&quot;, the &quot;Special Loan Use Agreement&quot; signed between Yuren Group and its employees may also have a high probability of being an invalid contract, and disputes between the two parties still need to be resolved through negotiation or litigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at this incident, the company cleverly created a pretext to allow employees to use their personal credit for corporate loans, the bank neglected to review the borrower&#39;s qualifications and loan purposes, the employees were greedy for the so-called &quot;interest spread&quot; and their current positions, and the supervision was lax. As a matter of fact, all parties are responsible for the incident. The &quot;loan to work&quot; incident also showed that there were problems in the relationship between Yuren Group employees and the company. Let me ask, if a company is so embarrassed that it needs to take out loans in the name of its employees to save itself, what is the point of employees keeping their jobs? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unless there is an employee stock ownership plan or option plan, there is only an ordinary employment relationship between the employee and the company. The &quot;loan to work&quot; program of Yuren Group can be called a clever name. This behavior not only avoids illegal fund-raising, but is not an internal financial product of the company, nor does it count as a company directly borrowing money from employees, nor does it count as an employee stock ownership plan or option. The plan is more like an employee debt plan, and the result is a lose-lose situation for both the company and its employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this incident, the behavior of &quot;employees taking loans to support the company&quot; was more like making themselves hostages of the company, and the greed for &quot;interest difference&quot; can also be called &quot;profit-making stupidity&quot;. The employment relationship between employees and the company should be one in which rights and responsibilities are equal. &quot;Talk about money&quot; or &quot;talk about feelings&quot; that go beyond legal rights and responsibilities are untenable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花上万块在五星级大酒店吃一年自助餐，真划算还是大冤种？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美两国发表关于加强合作应对气候危机的阳光之乡声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 10:33:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 15, China and the United States issued the Sunshine Land Statement on Strengthening Cooperation to Address the Climate Crisis. Statement The full text is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Sunshine Land Statement on Strengthening Cooperation to Address the Climate Crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revisit President Xi Jinping and President Joseph Biden met in Bali, Indonesia, and China and the United States reaffirmed their commitment to cooperation and working with other countries to address the climate crisis. To this end, China’s Special Envoy for Climate Change Xie Zhenhua and the U.S. President’s Special Envoy for Climate Issues John Kerry held talks in Beijing from July 16 to 19, and in Sunshine Country, California from November 4 to 7, 2023, and issued the following statement: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. China and the United States review, reaffirm and commit to further effective and sustained implementation of the April 2021 China-US Joint Statement on Addressing the Climate Crisis and the November 2021 China-US Agreement on Strengthening Climate Change in the 21st Century20s. Glasgow Joint Declaration of Action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. China and the United States recognize that the climate crisis has an increasingly significant impact on countries around the world. In the face of warnings from the best available scientific findings such as the Sixth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), the two countries are committed to effectively implementing the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change and the Paris Agreement, reflecting fairness and common but differentiated responsibilities. and their respective capabilities, taking into account different national conditions, and in accordance with Article 2 of the Paris Agreement, it is achievable to control the increase in global average temperature below 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C, including efforts to maintain 1.5°C, and achieve this goal. purpose of the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. China and the United States are committed to the effective implementation of the Paris Agreement and its decisions, including the Glasgow Climate Agreement and the Sharm el-Sheikh Implementation Plan. The two countries emphasized that the 28th Conference of the Parties (COP28) to the Convention is critical to meaningfully address the climate crisis during this critical decade and beyond. The two countries recognize that both countries play an important role in implementing the goals of the Paris Agreement and promoting multilateralism, both in terms of domestic response measures and joint cooperative actions. For the sake of current and future generations of humanity, the two countries will cooperate and join with other parties to the Convention and the Paris Agreement to face one of the most serious challenges in the world today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. China and the United States decided to launch the &quot;Working Group on Strengthening Climate Action in the 2120s&quot; to carry out dialogue and cooperation to accelerate specific climate actions in the 21st century. The working group will focus on the joint statement and areas of cooperation identified in the joint declaration, including energy transition, methane, circular economy and resource efficiency, low-carbon sustainable provinces/states and cities, deforestation, and other topics agreed by both parties. The working group will exchange information on policies, measures and technologies to control and reduce emissions, share their respective experiences, identify and implement cooperation projects, and evaluate the implementation of the joint statement, the joint declaration and this statement. The working group is co-led by the climate change envoys of the two countries, and officials from relevant ministries and government agencies of the two countries participate in appropriate ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. China and the United States will focus on accelerating the following specific actions under the working group before and after COP28, especially practical and practical cooperation plans and projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Energy Transition&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;6. In the critical decade of the 2120s, the two countries support the efforts stated in the G20 Leaders’ Declaration to achieve Global renewable energy installed capacity will triple in 2030, and it is planned to fully accelerate the deployment of renewable energy in the two countries from now to 2030 at the 2020 level to accelerate the replacement of kerosene and gas power generation, so that emissions from the power industry can be expected to peak after Achieve meaningful absolute reductions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7. The two sides agreed to restart the China-US Energy Efficiency Forum to deepen exchanges on energy conservation and carbon reduction policies in key areas such as industry, construction, transportation and equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8. China and the United States plan to restart bilateral energy policy and strategic dialogue, conduct exchanges on mutually agreed issues, promote track two activities, and strengthen practical cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9. The two countries strive to promote at least five large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilization and storage (CCUS) in industry and energy by 2030. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Methane and other non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gas emissions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10. The two countries will implement their respective national methane action plans and plan to refine further measures as appropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11. The two countries will immediately launch technical working group cooperation to carry out policy dialogue, exchange of technical solutions and capacity building, and formulate their own nationally determined contributions in 2035 based on their respective national methane action plans. methane emission reduction actions/targets, and support the progress of both countries in methane emission reduction/control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12. The two countries plan to cooperate on their respective measures to manage nitrous oxide emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;13. The two countries plan to work together to gradually reduce HFCs under the Kigali Amendment and are committed to ensuring that all refrigeration equipment produced adopts strong minimum energy efficiency standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Circular economy and resource utilization efficiency&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;14. Recognizing the important role of circular economy development and resource utilization efficiency in addressing the climate crisis, the two countries have The government departments plan to launch a policy dialogue on these issues as soon as possible and support enterprises, universities and research institutions on both sides to carry out exchange discussions and cooperation projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15. China and the United States are determined to end plastic pollution and will work with all parties to develop a legally binding international instrument on plastic pollution (including plastic pollution in the marine environment). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Local Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;16. China and the United States will support provinces, states and cities in climate change in areas such as electricity, transportation, construction and waste. cooperate. Both parties will promote local governments, enterprises, think tanks and other relevant parties to actively participate in cooperation. The two countries will conduct policy dialogue, share best practices, exchange information and promote project cooperation through agreed regular meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17. China and the United States plan to hold high-level events on local climate action in the first half of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18. Both sides welcome and appreciate the local cooperation that the two countries have carried out, and encourage provinces, states and cities to carry out practical climate cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Forest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;19. Both sides commit to further efforts to halt and reverse forest loss by 2030, including comprehensive implementation and implementation through regulatory and policy means. Effectively enforce their respective laws prohibiting illegal imports. Plans include discussions under the working group on how exchanges can enhance efforts to strengthen implementation of this commitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Coordinated emission reduction of greenhouse gases and air pollutants&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;20. The two countries plan to cooperate to promote relevant policy measures and technology deployment to strengthen greenhouse gas and atmospheric pollutant emission reduction. Coordinated control of atmospheric pollutant emissions such as nitrogen oxides, volatile organic compounds and other tropospheric ozone precursors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nationally Determined Contributions in 2035&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;21. Reaffirm the nature of nationally determined contributions determined by countries, and recall Article 4, paragraph 4, of the Paris Agreement , the two countries’ nationally determined contributions in 2035 will be economy-wide, including all greenhouse gases. The emission reductions reflected are in line with the Paris temperature control target of controlling the rise in global average temperature below 2°C and striving to limit it to 1.5°C. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;COP28&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;22. China and the United States will, together with the United Arab Emirates, invite all countries to participate in the &quot;Methane and Non-Carbon dioxide Greenhouse Gases&quot; Conference held during COP28. Summit”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23. China and the United States will actively participate in the first global stocktake of the Paris Agreement. This is an important opportunity for the parties to review the intensity, implementation and cooperation in order to comply with the temperature control goals of the Paris Agreement. Control the increase in global average temperature below 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C, consistent with the Parties’ determination to keep the 1.5°C temperature control target achievable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;24. The two countries are committed to working together and working with other Parties to reach a global stocktake decision by consensus. The two countries believe that the decision:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—should reflect substantial positive progress towards achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement, including actions facilitated by the Agreement by both parties and non-party stakeholders, and The world is clearly in a better position on the trajectory of temperature rise than without an agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Equity should be considered and informed by the best available science, including the latest IPCC report;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ——It should maintain a balance in various thematic areas, include retrospective and responsive elements, and be consistent with the design of the Paris Agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——It should reflect the need to combine different national conditions in action and support to achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement Significantly increase ambition and strengthen implementation;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Energy transition (renewable energy, coal/oil/gas), carbon sinks such as forests, non-carbon dioxide gases such as methane, and low-carbon technologies should be Send a signal;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Recognizing the nationally determined nature of NDCs and recalling Article 4, paragraph 4, of the Paris Agreement, economy-wide NDCs in 2035 should be encouraged to cover all greenhouse gases;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>; - Should reflect the critical importance of adaptation and be supported by a strong decision to propose a strong global adaptation goal framework - to accelerate adaptation, including the development of targets/indicators to strengthen adaptation effectiveness; Provide early warning systems for developing country Parties; strengthen adaptation efforts in key areas (such as food, water, infrastructure, health and ecosystems);&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; - It should be noted that developed countries are expected to achieve 1000 by 2023 US$100 million climate finance target, reaffirming the urge for developed country parties to at least double the adaptation finance they provide; looking forward to COP29 adopting a new collective quantified finance target; and making financial flows consistent with the goals of the Paris Agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—— The proposal of the Transitional Council to establish financial arrangements to address loss and damage, including the establishment of a fund for this purpose, should be welcomed and appreciated;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—The important role of international cooperation, including the global nature of the climate crisis, should be emphasized The broadest possible cooperation is required as a key enabler for strong mitigation action and climate-resilient development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;25. China and the United States are committed to further strengthening dialogue and collaborative efforts and supporting the UAE, the UAE chairmanship, in successfully hosting COP28. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[千人托位数仅1.3，北京托育如何提速“补课”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260589]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the past six months, Beijing childcare has finally begun to speed up “make-up classes”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of March 2023, the Beijing Municipal Government issued a document stating that it plans to have 4.5 childcare centers for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people by 2025, of which inclusive childcare spaces will account for no less than 60 %. In October, two sub-district nurseries were unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Beijing was a &quot;poor student&quot; in childcare: as of the end of 2022, the number of childcare centers per 1,000 students was only 1.3, far behind the national average (2.03) and not as good as Shenzhen (2.0 ), Shanghai (2.12) and Guangzhou (3.58). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, 95% of childcare institutions in Beijing are for-profit, and there are only 2 public nurseries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is childcare so scarce in Beijing? How to keep up with the pace of the country? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Finding a venue is not easy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to find a venue for children. An insider in Beijing&#39;s health care system described to Southern Weekend reporters that of the two streets that were the first to open nurseries, one was &quot;squeezed&quot; and the other was &quot;borrowed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Known as the first street-run nursery in Beijing, it is located in Xiaojing Automobile Station, a remote parking lot in Liuliqiao, Beijing. The Liuliqiao Sub-district Office is located in the corner of this parking lot, and the nursery is also squeezed out of the Sub-district Office&#39;s premises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a house of about 80 square meters, compactly equipped with a toilet, pantry, doll house, reading corner and a mini slide. Outdoor activities are held on the football field on the other side of the parking lot. This artificial turf formerly belonged to a badminton hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After one month of operation, only 5 children have been enrolled out of a total of 18 places. The teachers’ explanation is that every new student needs to be assigned a teacher to follow him throughout the whole process. Counting the principal, there are 4 teachers in total. , &quot;Actually, our admission schedule has been until next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, its location is not ideal. It is backed by a highway. There is only one community within one kilometer nearby, and there is a main car road in front of the parking lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a parent, a reporter from Southern Weekend participated in an enrollment meeting of a Liuliqiao subdistrict nursery school. Many of the parents who came to visit were not residents of the neighborhood. The advantage here is that it is cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nursery outside costs 7,000 to 8,000 yuan a month, but here it only costs 3,600 yuan.” A pair of “Beijing drifter” parents from Hunan told Southern Weekend reporters that the elderly at home could not help take care of their children, so they had to I found a nursery near the company, and including meals, the monthly cost was 4,200 yuan. This is almost the cheapest nursery in Beijing. &quot;Except for a public physical fitness classroom, the classroom where children usually stay is only 30 square meters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end, they failed to make up their mind to deliver it. &quot;If you come here, you need to deliver it in advance in the morning. Counting the delay fee of 50 yuan/hour, the prices on both sides are almost the same.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A person in charge of a childcare institution told Southern Weekend reporters that childcare centers are more sensitive to distance. “Kindergartens can also radiate to nurseries within three kilometers of the surrounding area. It must be at the doorstep. It’s so cold in Beijing in winter, how many people would be willing to hold such a small baby and go out for more than ten minutes?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Desheng Children’s Center, located in No. 1 Xinfeng Street, Xicheng District, Beijing, is The second childcare center run by a street in Beijing is located in the core area where land is at a premium - Desheng Street. A two-story building with an independent courtyard, the first floor has been transformed into a nursery, and the second floor is still reserved as an early education center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person responsible for operating this nursery is Han Xiaoliang, the founder of Huayu Tiancheng (Beijing) Childcare Service Co., Ltd. They originally opened a nursery in Desheng Street, which was a model park in Xicheng District . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Desheng Street introduced Han Xiaoliang’s agency through bidding to operate the Desheng Children’s Center. Han Xiaoliang told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;As long as I don&#39;t lose money, I am willing to participate. It can be regarded as making some contributions to the streets.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s guide price for inclusive childcare institutions is no more than 20% of the disposable income of residents in the district in the previous year. “The price is no more than 3,900 yuan.” The price of this nursery It is 3,600 yuan per month. Han Xiaoliang said that Beijing requires a teacher-student ratio of 1:7 for kindergartens over two years old. Under normal circumstances, there are 15 to 18 children with five teachers. &quot;We have just maintained a balance of income and expenditure, and still have a slight loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last week of September, Desheng Street held a round of enrollment briefings. “On-site applications were made for 18 full-day cares and 12 half-day cares,” Han Xiaoliang said, including those who signed up later. , currently more than 50 support spaces are basically full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The venue for this nursery does not belong to Desheng Street, but is borrowed from other communities. An insider in Beijing’s health system told Southern Weekend reporters, “This used to be a boiler room in a community that was renovated.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The for-profit nursery that Han Xiaoliang previously opened in Xicheng District also had to wait three or four years for the venue. &quot;It happened that a training school was not available during the epidemic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a chain kindergarten brand told Southern Weekend reporters that many districts in Beijing no longer approve new kindergartens. The Xicheng District Education Commission is one of the few that actively welcomes everyone to open kindergartens. Even if I have money, I can&#39;t find a suitable place.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing health care system said that even a venue like Liuliqiao is difficult to find, &quot;because we require that the venue must be rent-free.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xiaoliang has also communicated with some streets before, and everyone is generally faced with the problem of space shortage. &quot;Some streets said that they are not enough for office space. Where can I find a house?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt=&quot;The first street-run nursery in Beijing. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/2cfbdac886.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/2cfbdac886.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258236 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The first street-run nursery in Beijing. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Of the 102 streets, 96 have no plans&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Beijing’s plan, every street will have an inclusive nursery by 2025. In this regard, Southern Weekend reporters contacted a total of 121 streets in the five urban districts of Beijing, Xicheng, Dongcheng, Haidian, Chaoyang, and Fengtai. In addition to 19 streets that still received no answer after repeated calls, 102 of the streets that answered the call 3 are in planning, 3 are under construction, and 96 streets are still unplanned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinglongqiao Street in Haidian District, Longtan Street and Dongsi Street in Dongcheng District are the three streets where nurseries will be opened after Liuliqiao and Desheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the site in Qinglongqiao Street, Haidian District has been completed and is being filed. Longtan Street is speeding up construction and is expected to be completed in early December. Dongsi Street has found a place and is &quot;waiting for approval from above.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Chaoyangmen Street in Chaoyang District said, &quot;The street has no place to do it now, and we are waiting for the next plan from above.&quot; Panjiayuan Street also said, &quot;The space is tight,&quot; and Zuojiazhuang Street is planning middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter how tight the venue is, the street can find ways to solve it.&quot; The above-mentioned insiders of the Beijing health care system said that they all know that this matter is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another worrying issue is how many children will be attracted once the nursery is built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member from the sub-district office told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;Private childcare institutions only have 7-9 children, and it seems that the market demand is not very strong at the moment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to survey data from the Social Affairs Department of the Beijing Municipal Development and Reform Commission, as of 2022, the average utilization rate of support seats in Beijing is 35.4%, with the highest being 64.9% and the lowest being only 13%. Most childcare facilities are vacant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xiaoliang said that another for-profit nursery he runs has a monthly childcare fee of more than 8,000, and the occupancy rate is only 50%. Even the current inclusive nursery on Desheng Street is just full. There was no “hard-to-find” person as imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are so many worries about sending children to kindergarten after the age of three, let alone younger babies.&quot; Han Xiaoliang believes that the bigger issue now than building a nursery is how to change parents&#39; perceptions. &quot; We always regard two- and three-year-old children as incompetent and ignorant babies, and fail to realize that children also need a space to develop skills.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Beijing has launched a pilot program for inclusive childcare and announced that it will subsidize childcare institutions based on the policy of inclusive kindergartens, the specific details are still awaited. The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing Municipal Health Commission said that after the city issues the document, the specific details will still be determined by the district government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The park has been open for more than a month, and Han Xiaoliang has not received any subsidies yet. &quot;They say they will be subsidized, but how? How much? We can only wait now.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Shanghai has already &quot;handed in the papers&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Shanghai, which is a few steps ahead of Beijing, has already seen a phenomenon where it is hard to find a job. In November 2023, data released by the Shanghai Municipal Education Department showed that the utilization rate of inclusive care seats in Shanghai kindergartens has reached as high as 90%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the total fertility rates of Shanghai and Beijing will be only 0.74 and 0.87 respectively. The total fertility rate refers to the total number of children a woman gives birth to in her lifetime. A woman has an average of 2.1 children to ensure that the total population of the next generation does not decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction of inclusive childcare has just started in Beijing and has already been handed in in Shanghai. In 2017, Shanghai began to build inclusive child care centers, and the goal set at that time was to add 50 new centers every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Shanghai took the lead in the country in releasing the &quot;Shanghai Childcare Service Action Plan (2020-2022)&quot;, with the goal of opening at least one inclusive childcare center in every street and town in the central city by 2022. The coverage rate of universal child care centers in the city’s streets and towns shall not be less than 85%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The implementation of this action plan has been included in the supervision and evaluation of the district government’s performance of educational responsibilities, and key indicators have been included in the annual self-evaluation bulletin, becoming an important criterion for assessing the district government’s performance of its duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Shanghai has overfulfilled its task. At least one inclusive childcare center has been opened in every street in the central city, with the city-wide coverage reaching 95%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai, the founder of &quot;Nursing School&quot;, is also the deputy secretary-general of the Shanghai Infant Care Services Committee, a professional committee under the Shanghai Early Population Development Association to assist the government in promoting infant care. Service is one of its functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that Shanghai conducted many pilot projects at the beginning, “from the earliest independent childcare institutions, to integrated early childhood care, and even community childcare such as ‘baby houses’. Do it. With a hundred flowers blooming, from the final practice point of view, it is most cost-effective to run kindergartens to solve the problem of parents sending care.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Across the country, Shanghai is the only one where the Education Commission is in charge of child care. In other places, the health commission is in charge of child care. To this end, the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission has specially established a &quot;Child Care Work Office&quot; to encourage kindergartens to extend downwards to open child care classes, requiring &quot;to open as many kindergartens as possible and as many as possible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai said that Shanghai’s publicization of preschool education is also the best in the country. “In the process of solving the problem of universal preschool education, childcare is also solved.” Data from the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission shows that nearly 1,000 kindergartens in the city have opened day care classes, accounting for 60% of all kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai requires that newly built, renovated and expanded kindergartens all plan to provide childcare classes. Existing public kindergartens will consolidate resources and strive to add more childcare classes, and private kindergartens will actively offer inclusive childcare classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public kindergartens enjoy the same per-student subsidy as a kindergarten degree—31,000 yuan per student per year. Inclusive private kindergartens offer daycare classes with a subsidy of 1,200 yuan per student per year. The Shanghai Municipal Education Commission also provides a one-time start-up fund of 100,000 yuan for each inclusive childcare center to support the purchase of toys, teaching aids, facilities and equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This makes Shanghai almost the city with the lowest childcare fees in the country. Monthly childcare fees for demonstration kindergartens are 700-800 yuan, first-level kindergartens are 270 yuan, and second-level kindergartens are 220 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai said that in some core areas, kindergartens with the same academic qualifications have to queue up according to age, giving priority to older children. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kindergarten is the main channel&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the four first-tier cities in Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen, Beijing’s action plan was the latest to be introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen and Guangzhou issued action plans in 2020 and 2021 respectively. The &quot;Three-Year Action Plan for the Construction of Beijing&#39;s Childcare Service System (2023-2025)&quot; will be released in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s goal is to have 4.5 childcare centers for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people by 2025, of which inclusive childcare spaces will account for no less than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above action plan, Beijing will add no less than 62,000 inclusive child care places in the future, of which 30,000 will be provided by kindergartens and another 32,000 will come from streets, companies and other places. form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing Municipal Health Commission told Southern Weekend reporters that this plan is dynamically adjusted. “When we made the plan, it was not clear how much preschool resources could be extended to child care classes. I made some estimates. The whole of Beijing is dynamically adjusted, and there will be no restrictions on which part can handle 32,000 and which part can handle 30,000.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with various forms of childcare such as streets and enterprises, kindergartens have obvious advantages. &quot;Of course, this will save manpower, material and resources than building an institution from scratch. The venue is ready-made, it can be approved quickly, and it is standardized. Moreover, parents have gained more trust in the kindergarten after so many years.&quot; The person familiar with the matter said. Classes must be the main channel.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The integration of child care is seen as a shortcut to inclusive child care, and its resistance mainly comes from the kindergarten itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many industry insiders told Southern Weekend reporters that kindergarten teachers generally lack enthusiasm for opening day care classes. Compared with children over 3 years old, the work of children under 3 years old is more demanding and more difficult. Especially for public kindergarten teachers, the salary will remain unchanged and the workload will increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai analyzed that since Shanghai’s Education Commission takes the lead in promoting day care, it has stronger execution capabilities than other cities led by the Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many places, kindergartens need to give priority to solving the problem of &quot;large class sizes&quot; when running daycare classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, when responding to the proposal to promote qualified kindergartens to open inclusive nursery classes to enroll children aged 2-3, Vice Minister of Education Zheng Fuzhi said that it has not yet been fully popularized across the country. In preschool education, although the problem of children aged 3-6 years old having difficulty enrolling in kindergarten has been alleviated, it has not been fundamentally solved. At present, kindergartens in various places have a relatively high proportion of &quot;large class sizes&quot;, and there are still millions of children studying in kindergartens across the country who exceed the class quota. &quot;In this case, areas that have achieved full universal access to preschool education must create conditions to add nursery classes. Areas that have not yet fully popularized preschool education, especially those with a low penetration rate, must provide kindergartens for those aged 3-6 and 0-3 years old. The relationship between admission and day care issues should be properly handled and promoted step by step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Opportunities for professional institutions? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A Shanghai childcare industry entrepreneur told a Southern Weekend reporter that after attending some industry exhibitions recently, he clearly felt that private capital was withdrawing from the childcare industry. “There are only some toy and teaching aid manufacturers participating. , almost no childcare companies can be seen.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How can 7,000 yuan and 700 yuan compete?&quot; This entrepreneur has persuaded many friends who wanted to join the game in recent years. &quot;Now capital no longer cares about this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Youer Academy is a national daycare chain brand. Founder Su Dezhong told Southern Weekend reporters, “In the future, inclusive schools will account for the majority. Starting from 2020, Youer Academy will be more closely related to the government and local state-owned enterprises. Business cooperation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, kindergartens do not solve the problem of childcare by running daycare classes. “It actually solves the problem of kindergartens. Now kindergartens are facing a transition from ‘hard to find one child’ to ‘hard to find one child’” &#39;The problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national “14th Five-Year Plan” requires that by 2025, there will be 4.5 nurseries for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Dezhong made some calculations. Even if there are only 10 million births in the country every year, there will be 30 million people under the age of 3. By 2025, 4.5 places per 1,000 people will be achieved, which is about 6 million places. The actual enrollment rate is only 20%. Today, the enrollment rate in developed countries has reached 50%-60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, he believes that the development of inclusive childcare is an opportunity for professional institutions. “The kindergarten system is very mature, but the childcare system is still in a blank period. Many kindergarten teachers don’t know how to get there. For children under 3 years old. What kindergartens save is the initial investment, but the challenges faced by kindergartens in terms of talent training and refined management are no different from those of corporate childcare and medical education.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The question now is, &quot;Can the childcare services keep up? Can the price be reduced?&quot; At this stage, many childcare centers have not reached full capacity. Some people think that childcare is a false demand, and they are not satisfied with the demand. Su Dezhong gave an example, &quot;For example, if you open a restaurant or a nursing home, when your quality is not good enough or your service is not up to standard, people will not be able to actively go to the restaurant to eat, and the nursing home will not be full. But this is not a false demand, but a service.品质不够好。”他指出，现在很多声音在讨论托育园怎么开出来，“但是最根本的是托育园怎么做好，服务品质怎么提升。只有服务品质好，这个东西才会产生价值，刚需才能被满足。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月底，北京即将有6000个来自幼儿园的托位开始招生。对于北京第一家由街道兴办的托儿所而言，即将到来的冬天将给它带来一次艰巨的考验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与南方周末读者交换一本书，你要来玩吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260552]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;云中谁寄锦书来？先卖个关子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国作家萧伯纳说，“如果你有一个苹果，我有一个苹果，彼此交换，我们每个人仍然只有一个苹果；你有一种思想，我有一种思想，彼此交换，每个人就有了两种思想”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们相信，书也一样。文字是花火，在浩渺宇宙与茫茫人海中，可以创造出奇妙的联系。有趣的灵魂总会产生交集，如果让你的书开启一段奇妙的未知旅程，要来玩吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/sGDyrmL6k5KEbXsHsnXBE0cU2rfW8ico8gtSiWIS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/sGDyrmL6k5KEbXsHsnXBE0cU2rfW8ico8gtSiWIS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;与南方周末读者互换一本书&lt;/strong>;。可以是你的珍藏、旅途读本、最近的阅读刊物，总之，欢迎分享。让我们一起使文字跨越山海，让故事随波漂流，也让你的品味与志趣在南方周末找到知音。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未曾谋面，但见字如面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;活动规则很简单&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●点击“&lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com/6EaxEe5F/&quot;>;我要参与&lt;/a>;”提交你的联系方式和计划交换的书籍。 （&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一定要留哦，保证你能收到快递&lt;/span>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●把想要与陌生人交换的书籍（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;请注意：最少一本，最多三本&lt;/span>;），同时内附你的收件信息一并寄往南方周末收件处。我们将打开所有快递包裹，根据你的意愿以及书籍的品相、类型进行交换。 &lt;strong>;选一份与你最搭的书籍转送给你，同时把你的书籍送给最合适的那个人&lt;/strong>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●本次活动寄件运费自理。点击活动中“我要免运费”，完成助力后我们将为你交换到的书籍包邮。 （&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;去邀请好友助力吧，不然是到付呦&lt;/span>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com/6EaxEe5F/&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5R5vLVylaCdMzltsiLfMwtMrGpHgamn1HAUV9dE3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;1334&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5R5vLVylaCdMzltsiLfMwtMrGpHgamn1HAUV9dE3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258267&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;750&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1334&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这些细节也请留意：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●活动时间11月15日-11月22日。 &lt;strong>;快递收件地址：&lt;/strong>;广州市广州大道中289号南方报业菜鸟驿站（收)，&lt;strong>;联系人：&lt;/strong>;小南，&lt;strong>;电话：&lt;/strong>;18028553727。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●参与本次活动需为公开正式出版物，内容健康、品相较好，无缺页、无严重残损，具备一定阅读价值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●书籍依照“等量交换”。举个例子，你寄送了三本，最终也会收到三本。我们猜测的喜好也许不能完全如你所愿，但希望能在这个冬日为你带去惊喜与愉悦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一份陌生人的书籍，到达另一个陌生人的手中，交换的乐趣不就是这样吗——未知的期待与惊喜。轻轻拆开包裹的那刻，两个有趣的人隔空相遇，而你也有机会给他说一声：Hi，我读完了你最喜欢的书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;收到交换的书籍后，欢迎在南方周末APP分享你的活动体验与阅读感受，有机会获得我们送出的神秘盲盒哦。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鸡蛋的坏名声从何而来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260593]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Eggs are one of the most easily available and commonly consumed animal-source foods for humans. At present, the global per capita consumption of eggs is about 150 eggs per year, with more than 210 eggs in Europe and 300 eggs in China. In ancient times, eggs were not only food, but also a medicine for treating diseases. Since the 1960s, eggs have had a bad reputation for being unhealthy. For a time, many people were wondering whether they should eat eggs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A warning from a cardiologist&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Eggs’ “bad” reputation comes from cholesterol. As early as the early 20th century, scientists discovered through animal experiments that increasing the cholesterol in feed could increase the serum cholesterol levels of animals and promote the development of atherosclerosis in animals. Given that cardiovascular disease has become the leading cause of death in the United States, on June 16, 1948, U.S. President Harry Truman signed the National Heart Act and allocated $500,000 to launch a 20-year study on the epidemiology of heart disease. study, the Framingham Heart Study. In 1957, the Framingham Heart Research Team published a blockbuster study that concluded that elevated serum cholesterol levels were closely related to the risk of cardiovascular disease. In the 1960s and 1970s, scientists successively observed a certain correlation between dietary cholesterol intake, serum cholesterol concentration, and the incidence of cardiovascular disease. Unfortunately, since one egg (about 50 grams) contains about 200 mg of cholesterol, and eggs had become a daily food in the United States at that time, eggs inevitably became one of the &quot;culprits&quot; in the high incidence of cardiovascular disease in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1968, the American Heart Association clearly stated for the first time that in order to reduce the incidence of cardiovascular disease, it recommended limiting dietary cholesterol intake, and for the first time proposed limiting egg consumption to no more than three eggs per week. This may have been the source of subsequent recommendations from nutritional experts or doctors around the world to limit three eggs per week. This recommendation from a group of American cardiologists on limiting egg consumption seems logical and easy to operate. It has been recognized by many and has gradually become an important basis for the United States and other countries in the world to formulate national dietary nutrition guidelines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The media&#39;s fueling has deepened the public&#39;s misunderstanding of eggs. The most typical example is the two cover reports on cholesterol in the American &quot;Time&quot; magazine. In 1984, Time magazine&#39;s front-page article was titled &quot;Cholesterol and Today&#39;s Bad News,&quot; and included a picture of a sad, round face on the cover of the magazine. The eyes were made of two fried eggs, and the sad mouth was Use a piece of bacon with both ends bent downward. Although Time magazine did not originate the bad reputation of eggs, its huge influence undoubtedly further deepened the public&#39;s association between eggs and &quot;bad&quot; cholesterol. Fifteen years later, Time magazine once again put an egg on the cover. The omelette still had the round eyes, but the mouth had been replaced by a melon with upturned sides, showing a cheerful smile. The corresponding front page The title of the article is &quot;Cholesterol, now the good news.&quot; Although this article marked a more scientific and comprehensive understanding of cholesterol by doctors and nutritionists, it did not quickly eliminate the misconceptions that had been instilled in the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the joint promotion of the medical community and the media, the bad reputation of eggs has lasted for more than 50 years. The biggest impact is undoubtedly the laying hen industry. From 1968 to the early 1990s, U.S. egg production basically stagnated, hovering around 4 million tons. During the same period, the U.S. population increased by more than 20%. Obviously, per capita egg consumption in the U.S. continued to decline during this period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3wGetBG43ptbpUG1Vj1VHnQbf0cdR4trlEeWXiIN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height= &quot;512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3wGetBG43ptbpUG1Vj1VHnQbf0cdR4trlEeWXiIN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1984, Time magazine published a report with the title &quot;Cholesterol and the Bad News Now&quot; and included a picture of a sad, round face on the cover. Fifteen years later, the egg appeared on the cover again, with the mouth replaced by upturned melons on both sides, and the corresponding article was &quot;Cholesterol, Now It&#39;s Good News.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is increasing evidence to the contrary&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Incredibly, there is a lack of direct scientific evidence that eating more cholesterol-rich eggs increases the risk of cardiovascular disease. Recommendations by the American Heart Association and others to limit egg consumption are based primarily on three imperfect pieces of evidence. The first is evidence from animal models that excessive cholesterol intake increases serum cholesterol levels and the development of atherosclerosis in animals. , the second evidence is epidemiological surveys showing that a high-cholesterol diet is associated with a higher incidence of cardiovascular disease, and the third evidence is clinical observations showing that high cholesterol intake leads to an increase in serum cholesterol levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These three seemingly interlocking pieces of evidence have fatal flaws. Scientists generally use rats, guinea pigs, rabbits and other animals to conduct animal cholesterol feeding experiments. The amount of cholesterol added is much higher than the daily dietary cholesterol intake, and it often needs to reach the pharmacological level to cause changes in serum cholesterol levels. For example, researchers at the University of Arizona once fed a group of guinea pigs 0 (control), 0.08% (equivalent to 600 mg/day for humans), 0.17% (equivalent to 1275 mg/day for humans) or 0.33% (equivalent to 2475 mg/day for humans). mg/day) dietary cholesterol, and a positive relationship was found between dietary cholesterol intake and serum LDL cholesterol. However, in this study, there was no significant difference in serum cholesterol concentrations between guinea pigs fed 0 dietary cholesterol and feed containing 0.08% cholesterol. Serum cholesterol concentrations increased significantly only when higher doses of cholesterol were fed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Epidemiological survey results on the correlation between dietary cholesterol and the incidence of cardiovascular disease often &quot;fight&quot;, leaving the public confused and at a loss as to what to do. Most of the early epidemiological surveys relied on simple correlation analysis to draw conclusions. For example, they only recorded the consumption of eggs, but did not consider the impact of other dietary components, or even other factors that may cause cardiovascular disease, such as smoking and drinking. factors, so the conclusions of this type of research are unreliable. However, this type of research is often more eye-catching due to the large number of subjects involved and long follow-up time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 1990s, an increasing number of studies have shown that egg consumption, dietary cholesterol, and the incidence of cardiovascular disease have little association. In 1999, researchers from the Harvard School of Public Health published a major study in the Journal of the American Medical Association. The researchers conducted a follow-up study of more than 117,000 people for 8-14 years. After excluding age, After controlling for smoking and other factors that influence cardiovascular disease, the results showed no significant difference in cardiovascular disease risk between those who ate one egg per week versus one egg per day. In 2015, researchers from the Karolinska Institute in Sweden conducted a 13-year follow-up study on more than 60,000 people and also concluded that daily egg intake was not related to the incidence of cardiovascular disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some studies even suggest that eating eggs appropriately will reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease. In 2018, researchers from Peking University, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences, Oxford University and other institutions conducted a cohort study involving 500,000 people and found that compared with basically no eggs, moderate levels of egg consumption (an average of 0.79 eggs/day) ), the risk of death from cardiovascular disease was reduced by 18% and the risk of death from hemorrhagic stroke was reduced by 28%. This is similar to the results of a 2003 study by the Hiroshima Radiation Effects Research Foundation in Japan. After following more than 40,000 people for 16 years, Japanese researchers found that people who ate eggs every day had a 30% lower risk of stroke death than those who did not eat eggs. People who ate 1-4 eggs a week had a corresponding risk of death from stroke. reduce. In a study of more than 130,000 adult subjects aged 40-69 in South Korea, researchers from Seoul National University found that among female subjects, compared with consuming less than one egg per week, Consuming more than 7 eggs per week is associated with a lower risk of metabolic syndrome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, randomized controlled trials are the most effective and reliable method to verify the association between dietary cholesterol and cardiovascular disease risk. Most randomized controlled trials have proven that eating 1-3 eggs per day has little effect on serum cholesterol levels, even for some diabetics. In a one-year randomized controlled trial, researchers from Maastricht University in the Netherlands asked volunteers in the experimental group to drink a buttermilk drink containing 1.5 lutein-rich egg yolks every day, while the control group drank no A placebo containing egg yolk found that after one year there were essentially no differences between the two groups in total cholesterol, low-density lipoprotein, high-density lipoprotein cholesterol, and the ratio of total cholesterol to high-density lipoprotein cholesterol. On the contrary, there are some randomized controlled trials that show that eating eggs actually reduces the risk of metabolic syndrome. However, currently this type of randomized controlled trial has problems such as small samples and short observation time, and still needs further improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1995, the American Heart Association Guidelines, the National Cholesterol Education Program Guidelines, the Dietary Guidelines for Americans, and the U.S. Food and Drug Administration’s Nutrition Facts Table all set dietary cholesterol recommendations at less than 300 mg/ days, and it is recommended to reduce the intake of animal-source foods such as eggs with high cholesterol. However, due to the lack of sufficient scientific evidence to prove that consuming normal levels of eggs or other dietary cholesterol is harmful to the human body, since the beginning of the new millennium, relevant agencies formulating dietary guidelines have successively canceled recommendations on limiting the intake of eggs and dietary cholesterol. In 2002, the American Heart Association removed the specific limit of 3-4 eggs per week while maintaining dietary cholesterol guidelines of less than 300 mg/day. In 2013, the American Heart Association officially announced that &quot;there is insufficient evidence to determine whether lowering dietary cholesterol will lower LDL cholesterol&quot; and canceled the dietary cholesterol recommendation of no more than 300 mg/day. Both the 2015-2020 and 2020-2025 editions of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans have removed the recommendation that dietary cholesterol consumption be less than 300 mg/day. According to the &quot;Scientific Research Report on Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents (2021)&quot;, currently only a few countries in the world, such as India and Australia, individually recommend eggs, and most countries recommend egg consumption of about 3 eggs per week. The &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents 2022&quot; recommends 1 egg consumption per day, and also states that &quot;eggs are rich in nutrients, and the yolks should not be discarded when eating eggs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It turns out that there is a feedback mechanism in the body&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although most current dietary guidelines have canceled the intake limit recommendations for eggs and dietary cholesterol, the public is still concerned about the There are still doubts about eggs containing cholesterol, and they are worried that long-term eating of eggs will lead to increased cholesterol levels in the body and an increase in the risk of cardiovascular disease. Does high dietary cholesterol intake mean high serum cholesterol levels? Not entirely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research shows that only about 25% of the body’s cholesterol comes from dietary intake, and the rest mainly relies on its own biosynthesis. Since cholesterol plays an important role in the human body, almost all cells in the human body can synthesize cholesterol. The liver and intestines are responsible for synthesizing about 80% of the daily cholesterol required by the human body. The brain, adrenal glands and reproductive organs can also synthesize cholesterol efficiently. An adult weighing 70 kg synthesizes approximately 850 mg of cholesterol per day. Clinical feeding studies have shown that if dietary cholesterol changes by 100 mg per day, total plasma cholesterol levels will change by an average of 2.2-2.5 mg/dL, which is equivalent to eating an egg only causing a 2%-3% change in serum cholesterol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that scientists have discovered that the human body has a feedback compensatory mechanism for cholesterol. That is, when the human body consumes too much dietary cholesterol, the body&#39;s ability to absorb and synthesize cholesterol will be limited, and it will also accelerate. Excretion and removal of excess cholesterol, thereby maintaining the balance of serum cholesterol levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1991, the &quot;New England Journal of Medicine&quot; reported an extreme case of &quot;addiction&quot; to eating eggs. An 88-year-old male has been eating 20-30 eggs a day for at least 15 years, but the doctor found that his blood lipid levels were basically normal, and his serum total cholesterol was also maintained at normal levels, with an average of 5.18 milliliters. mol/L (normal range 3.12-5.72 mmol/L), and the patient did not suffer from atherosclerosis and other diseases related to excessive cholesterol intake. In order to further study this special case, the researchers conducted a randomized controlled trial. The experimental group added 5 eggs per person per day on the basis of the regular diet, and the group without eggs served as the control group. It was found that during the regular diet, the control group ate The absorption rate of ingested cholesterol reached 53%, while during the high-cholesterol diet, which included five eggs, the absorption rate of ingested cholesterol dropped to 46% in the control group, but the 88-year-old only absorbed 18% of ingested cholesterol. . At the same time, the patient&#39;s total bile acid synthesis rate was twice that of the control group, which shows that there is a very effective compensatory mechanism in the patient&#39;s body. In the case of a large intake of egg cholesterol, on the one hand, the intake of cholesterol will be reduced. Absorption, on the other hand, reduces the body&#39;s ability to synthesize cholesterol, thereby maintaining the balance of total cholesterol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, not everyone responds to dietary cholesterol in the same way. It generally varies depending on genetics, individual metabolic level, gender, age and other factors. Research shows that about 2/3 of people who consume too much cholesterol will not or only have a slight increase in serum total cholesterol. These people, like the above-mentioned 88-year-old man, have an effective cholesterol compensatory mechanism and can adjust the absorption, excretion and synthesis of cholesterol according to their dietary cholesterol intake. But other people may lack a similar compensatory mechanism, and consuming too much dietary cholesterol will cause a significant increase in serum cholesterol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is growing evidence that egg or dietary cholesterol intake is not associated with increased risk of cardiovascular disease, while egg intake addresses many nutritional deficiencies and may provide overall benefits across the lifespan. It makes an important contribution to health, so most people can eat eggs with confidence. Even some patients with metabolic syndrome or cardiovascular disease can eat them normally, but they cannot eat too much for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南武陟一中学发生踩踏事故，已致1死5伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 00:41:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At about 10 am on November 13, 2023, the first grade of Xinghua Middle School in Wuzhi County Two groups of boys fell and were injured due to crowding on the stairs while going to the toilet between mid-term exams. The students involved were immediately sent to the hospital for examination and treatment. Currently, one student died after all-out efforts to rescue him failed, one seriously injured student is being treated with all-out efforts, and four students with minor injuries are hospitalized for observation and treatment and will be discharged in the near future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the incident, the city and county immediately launched on-site rescue and organized medical experts from the province to provide treatment. At the same time, an investigation team will be set up to find out the cause as soon as possible and the relevant responsible persons will be dealt with seriously in accordance with the law and regulations. Our county will learn lessons deeply, draw inferences from one example, and comprehensively carry out investigation and rectification of school risks to ensure student safety. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Wuzhi County People&#39;s Government&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>; &lt;span>;November 14, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 01:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港屋宇署：没有针对霓虹灯招牌的大型执法行动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, the Buildings Department of the Hong Kong SAR Government responded to inquiries from Southern+ reporters and stated that&lt;strong>;the Department did not There have been no large-scale enforcement actions targeting neon signs. &lt;/strong>;At the same time, the Department also stated that the Hong Kong SAR government allows smaller and lower-risk signs, including neon signs, to continue to be used after safety inspection, consolidation and certification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Buildings Department stated that the SAR government has always attached great importance to the safety of outdoor signboards and adopted a &quot;risk-based&quot; principle to take a multi-pronged approach to deal with illegal, dangerous or abandoned signboards. The Buildings Department will take enforcement action to promptly ban signboards that pose a clear threat to life and property, and will also prioritize enforcement against illegal signboards that are under construction or newly erected. In response to the large number of existing illegal signboards, the Buildings Department will select certain busy street sections with a large number of illegal signboards every year to conduct &quot;large-scale targeted street operations&quot; to conduct comprehensive removal operations against illegal, dangerous and abandoned signboards. In addition, the Buildings Department will also launch large-scale operations against large-scale illegal signboards that pose greater risks to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering that most of the existing signboards are being used by merchants and helping to promote local commercial activities, the Buildings Department has implemented the &quot;Signboard Verification Scheme&quot; since September 2, 2013. The scheme allows smaller signboards with lower risks, which have been erected before the implementation date of the verification scheme and comply with the technical specifications of the relevant minor works projects, to be safely carried out by prescribed building professionals and/or prescribed registered contractors. After inspection, strengthening (if necessary) and certification with the Buildings Department, they can continue to be used. Thereafter, the safety inspection must be carried out again every five years or the signboards must be removed. The inspection scheme also applies to neon signs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Buildings Department also told Southern+ reporters that its staff had inspected No. 63 Temple Street, Kowloon, and found an existing wall attached to the exterior wall of the building facing the 1st floor to the 3rd floor of Public Square Street. The main wording of the illegal signboard is &quot;Meitu Restaurant&quot;. According to the current law enforcement policy, the relevant signboards are subject to ban. The Buildings Department then issued a clearance order to the signboard owner in accordance with Section 24 of the Buildings Ordinance on October 19 last year through the &quot;Large Scale Operation on Large Signboards&quot;. Order him to remove the relevant signboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, according to the notice of work commencement submitted by the registered minor works contractor appointed by the owner of the relevant signboard, the relevant demolition works have started in November this year. The Buildings Department will continue to follow up on the relevant clearance orders. compliance status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Previous report&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Is Hong Kong going to remove all neon signs? Fake! &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 13th, a mainland netizen posted an article saying that Hong Kong introduced the mainland’s urban management management methods, demolished all the neon signs, and replaced them with multiple neon signs that were loaded onto trucks and transported away. The picture attracted attention on the Internet. After checking, the reporter found that two of the three accompanying pictures were post-processed pictures and were not real photos. According to information from the Buildings Department of the Hong Kong SAR Government, small signboards (including neon signs) can be retained and used as long as they meet relevant safety requirements. Relevant sources revealed that &lt;strong>;the relevant departments have no plan to clean up the existing signboards, let alone “introducing the management methods of the mainland’s urban management”. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/c67ab3f2ae81a8d40205b81abe6ce266.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/c67ab3f2ae81a8d40205b81abe6ce266.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258277&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the 13th, some mainland netizens posted that Hong Kong had introduced the mainland’s urban management management methods and demolished all neon signs, which attracted attention on the Internet. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A picture posted by the netizen showed two moving trucks carrying more than a dozen neon signs. According to the reporter&#39;s verification, this picture is not a real photo, but a work created by Hong Kong photographer and graphic designer Tommy Fung through PS. Tommy Fung also posted this picture on social platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8f77ed5b36ca3c165898f9853aa2b66b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8f77ed5b36ca3c165898f9853aa2b66b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258278&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hong Kong photographer and graphic designer Tommy Fung created this image through PS and posted it on social platforms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another picture is full of colorful neon signs, which are moving through the traffic. This image is the work of British photographer Keith MacGregor. According to Keith MacGregor&#39;s personal website, this work was made by splicing multiple photos of neon signs from various parts of Hong Kong, and adding photos of Nathan Road in Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon. It is not a single real scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/7673d3fb33466a7e395ae148bf6a8da5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/7673d3fb33466a7e395ae148bf6a8da5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258280&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to Keith MacGregor&#39;s personal website, this work was made by splicing multiple photos of neon signs from all over Hong Kong, and added Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon. Nathan&#39;s photos are not individual real scenes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Meidu Restaurant&quot; sign in the other picture has indeed been removed recently. Metro Restaurant operator Wong Sing-fun had earlier received a demolition request from the Buildings Department of the Hong Kong SAR Government. On the day of construction, Huang Xingfen and her husband witnessed the disassembly and took the final photo with the signboard. Public information shows that Meidu Restaurant opened in 1950 and has a history of 73 years. Because of its old-fashioned decoration style, it has become a &quot;check-in&quot; spot in Yau Ma Tei, Hong Kong. Many TV series and movies have been shot here, such as the movie &quot;Kowloon Ice Room&quot; &quot;&quot;Chasing the Dragon&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/05d743f63a67bbfa463a1db75684ce10.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/05d743f63a67bbfa463a1db75684ce10.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258279&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On the day of construction, Meidu Restaurant operator Huang Xingfen and her husband witnessed the demolition and Take a final photo with the sign. (Picture source: U Lifestyle)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the reporter’s understanding, the Buildings Department of the Hong Kong SAR Government currently adopts the “Signboard Inspection Plan” implemented in 2013. Small signs (including neon signs) only need to It can be retained for use if it meets safety requirements. Relevant sources revealed that the &quot;signboard inspection plan&quot; has been effective, so the relevant departments have no plan to focus on cleaning up existing signboards, let alone &quot;introducing the management methods of mainland urban management&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to eliminate possible public safety risks, the Buildings Department of the Hong Kong SAR Government has issued statutory removal orders for illegal signboards that have not participated in the &quot;Signboard Verification Scheme&quot; since 2014 to urge the owners of the relevant signboards to If you participate in the verification program as early as possible, statutory removal orders or hazardous structure demolition notices will also be issued against illegal signboards or dangerous/abandoned signboards that are not eligible to participate in the verification program. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“重返巴厘岛，通往旧金山”中美元首会晤开启“史诗级APEC”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260607]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;From November 14 to 17, 2023, at the invitation of US President Biden, Chinese President Xi Jinping went to San Francisco Held a meeting between the heads of state of China and the United States and was invited to attend the 30th APEC Economic Leaders&#39; Meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This will be an important diplomatic dialogue.” In early November, U.S. White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre commented, “President Biden is full of expectations for this.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Epic&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;APEC&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Starting from November 11, the APEC Summit in San Francisco will last for one week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of this APEC session is the &quot;Xi Visit&quot; on November 15. A banner hung high in downtown San Francisco: &quot;APEC will be an epic event.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters saw from the organizer’s website that from November 11 to 17, the summit will hold senior officials’ meetings, finance ministers’ meetings, business leaders’ meetings and leaders’ informal meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The two heads of state will have in-depth communication on strategic, overall and directional issues related to Sino-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development.&quot; November 13, 2023, Diplomacy Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said that China has always viewed and handled Sino-US relations in accordance with the three principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation proposed by President Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;President Xi Jinping will attend the APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting on November 15. That evening, President Xi Jinping will serve as the guest of honor at a dinner hosted by the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations and the National Committee on U.S.-China Business and deliver a speech to U.S. business leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;APEC was established in 1989 as an informal dialogue forum to promote regional economic integration. APEC members include 21 economies in the Pacific Rim, which accounts for nearly 40% of the world&#39;s population and more than 60% of global trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This APEC Summit is the largest international conference held in San Francisco since dignitaries gathered to sign the United Nations Charter in 1945. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This week, leaders, ministers, business executives and journalists from 21 APEC economies will gather at the main venue, the Moscone Center, with nearly 30,000 people in attendance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Moscone Center is located in the center of San Francisco. It is composed of three buildings connected by overpasses and underground passages. Southern Weekend reporters learned from the San Francisco APEC organizer that in 2019, the San Francisco government spent US$551 million to expand the Moscone Center, increasing the space by 21%, and now the total area reaches more than 500,000 square feet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;San Francisco has a historic Chinatown, the largest Chinese gathering place outside Asia and the oldest Chinese gathering place in North America. According to the U.S. Census, San Francisco has 180,000 Chinese residents, second only to New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“The road to San Francisco will not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; be smooth sailing”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As we enter October, China and the United States High-level visits between the two countries are frequent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October 26th to 28th, Foreign Minister Wang Yi paid a three-day visit to the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three-day trip was short and intense. In Washington, Wang Yi held talks with U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken and U.S. President’s National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, met with Biden, and communicated with U.S. strategic figures and industrial and commercial representatives. Among them, during his first visit to Japan on October 26, Wang Yi held two rounds of talks with US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, totaling 7 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In all three events, Foreign Minister Wang Yi mentioned the keyword &quot;San Francisco&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Return to Bali, leading to San Francisco&quot;, according to CCTV, this expression has been widely known recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Return to Bali&#39; refers to last year&#39;s G20 meeting. President Xi Jinping and President Biden had a very good meeting in Bali, Indonesia, and reached important consensus.&quot; Cui Tiankai, former Chinese Ambassador to the United States, explained at the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum on October 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the G20 Summit in Bali a year ago, President Biden reiterated the &quot;four no&#39;s and one unintentional&quot; many times. The &quot;four no&#39;s and one unintentional&quot; means that the United States does not seek to fight a &quot;new Cold War&quot;, does not seek to change China&#39;s system, does not seek to strengthen alliances against China, does not support &quot;Taiwan independence&quot;, and has no intention of conflict with China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &quot;The &#39;road to San Francisco&#39; will not be smooth sailing and cannot rely on &#39;autonomous driving.&#39;&quot; On October 28, Wang Yi said during a symposium with people from the U.S. strategic community in Washington that for this reason , both sides should earnestly &quot;return to Bali&quot;, truly implement the consensus reached by the two heads of state, eliminate interference, overcome obstacles, enhance consensus, and accumulate results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This symposium was hosted by the highly official &quot;U.S. Aspen Strategy Group.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-US economic and trade relations are the &quot;ballast stone&quot; of the relationship between the two countries. As the world&#39;s top two economies, China and the United States have a total economic output of more than one-third of the world, a total population of nearly a quarter of the world, and bilateral trade volume of about one-fifth of the world. Data show that China-US trade volume will reach nearly 760 billion US dollars in 2022, a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From November 8 to 12, just before APEC, He Lifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, Vice Premier of the State Council, and leader of Sino-US economic and trade, visited the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his visit to the United States, Vice Premier He Lifeng and Treasury Secretary Yellen held multiple rounds of talks and had working dinners together. The total meeting time exceeded 10 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The purpose is to continue to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state on the basis of the talks between the two sides in Beijing in July, prepare economic results for the meeting between the two heads of state in San Francisco, and push Sino-US economic and trade relations back to the track of healthy and stable development. .&quot; On November 10, Vice Minister of Finance Liao Min said at a briefing in San Francisco, USA, that consensus was reached such as promoting the establishment of a Sino-US economic and financial working group and holding meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Yellen and her delegation arrived in Beijing in July, a rainbow appeared in the sky. When Premier Li Qiang met with Yellen, he mentioned, “After Sino-US relations have gone through a storm, we will definitely see more rainbows.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There are a thousand reasons for China-U.S. relations&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;We have a thousand reasons to improve Sino-US relations, and there is no reason for Sino-US relations to deteriorate.&quot; On October 9, President Xi Jinping met with the United States Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of &quot;Xi&#39;s visit&quot; in San Francisco, the United States sent a Senate delegation led by Chuck Schumer to visit China in early October; at the end of October, California Governor Gavin Newsom and his 23-member delegation visited China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, a congressional delegation of three Democrats and three Republicans, including Schumer of the United States Senate, flew to Shanghai. This is the first bipartisan delegation from the U.S. Senate to visit China in four years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China-U.S. relations are complex, with both cooperation and competition. We must establish a crisis management and control mechanism and resume dialogue.&quot; Michael Swain, chief director of the East Asia Program at the Quincy Institute of National Affairs, told Southern Weekend reporters , as the US election year approaches, many politicians will use anti-China issues to add political points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Key members of the U.S. Congress have important influence on China-related issues. Before visiting China, Schumer had repeatedly urged the Biden administration to take a tough stance against China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The United States has no intention of decoupling from China, but hopes that American companies can receive fair treatment in China.&quot; On October 7, Schumer mentioned when meeting with Shanghai Municipal Party Committee Secretary Chen Jining that the United States was not trying to provoke conflict, but was It is hoped that in the context of economic competition between the United States and China, we can obtain a level playing field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen believes that the United States should clearly abide by the &quot;One China Policy&quot;, express its willingness to let China participate in economic cooperation, and strive to improve the stability of the Asia-Pacific economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 U.S. Export to China Report&quot; released by the U.S.-China Business Council shows that more than 70,000 U.S. companies have invested and established business in China, and nearly 90% of their businesses in China have achieved profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“De-risking does not mean completely cutting off economic ties (with China), it just means there are restrictions.” Joseph Nye, a professor at Harvard University in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that the US national strategy has changed to “small &quot;We should not let this small courtyard expand&quot; to describe the China strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past month, China and the United States have undergone significant changes in agricultural economics and trade. On November 7, the U.S. Department of Agriculture sent 17 exhibitors to participate in the 6th Shanghai International Import Expo, and at the same time brought back 600,000 tons of soybean orders for the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as October 25, Chinese Ambassador to the United States Xie Feng came to Iowa, the &quot;Breadbasket of the United States,&quot; to participate in the China-US Sustainable Agricultural Products Trade Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Feng mentioned that Rick from Kimberley Farm told him that a modern agriculture demonstration project with an investment of 50 million yuan was settled in Zhejiang, and representatives of Chinese companies participating in the procurement signing today will sign more than ten agricultural product orders. Worth billions of dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;California Waterways&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;California Governor Newsom’s visit to China has a more diverse itinerary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The California Governor’s Office stated in a statement that Newsom’s team’s seven-day itinerary includes Hong Kong, Shenzhen, Guangzhou, Beijing, Yancheng, and Shanghai, focusing on topics such as ecological environment, climate change response, and clean energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Newsom led a delegation to Shenzhen. They went to the Antuoshan Smart Station of Shenzhen Bus Group to try out a BYD electric vehicle. &quot;This is a breakthrough technology! I want to buy two of them. We have to find a way to introduce them to the United States.&quot; After experiencing the in-situ U-turn function of the U8, Newsom praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Newsom visited Guangzhou on the same day, he discussed with relevant departments in Guangdong the successful climate cooperation between the two provinces and states over the years. Relevant departments of the two provinces and states also signed a memorandum of understanding on deepening cooperation in green development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The California Governor’s Office stated that this new memorandum of understanding is a supplement to the relevant memorandum of understanding signed by the two provinces and states in 2013. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 25, President Xi Jinping met with Newsom at the Great Hall of the People. President Xi Jinping once again emphasized that &quot;the foundation of Sino-US relations lies in the people, hope lies in the people, the future lies in the youth, and the vitality lies in the localities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to climate issues, Newsom&#39;s China trip has two major purposes. One is to &quot;Promote economic development and tourism and strengthen cultural ties&quot;, and the second is &quot;combat anti-Asian hatred.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having been in politics in California for many years, Newsom is an experienced witness and promoter of local economic and trade cooperation between China and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Newsom visited China three times when he was mayor of San Francisco. In 2005, when Newsom and the late U.S. Senator Dianne Feinstein visited China, it coincided with the 25th anniversary of Shanghai and San Francisco becoming sister cities. In 2008, Newsom specially set up a China office in San Francisco to serve Chinese companies in investing and cooperating there and local companies entering the Chinese market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, California connects the channels of exchange between China and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to U.S. Census data, more than 4% of Californians and more than 10% of people in the San Francisco Bay Area are of Chinese ancestry. The Port of Los Angeles is the largest port in the United States participating in Sino-US trade, and the Shanghai-Los Angeles route is one of the busiest shipping routes in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The more successful China is, the more successful the world will be.&quot; Newsom said in an interview with CCTV that he did not agree with the so-called &quot;de-risking&quot; and &quot;decoupling&quot;. He said that he could &quot;diversify&quot; from the world and look at it from the perspective of head-on competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一处回水丨事关告别]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260546]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/13/pOFXgYDzOTEV7i3fl7ax1TpBauQnnpPMM4B9TPhc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/pOFXgYDzOTEV7i3fl7ax1TpBauQnnpPMM4B9TP hc. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258154&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jinsha River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yangtze River changed color overnight. When I passed the Jinsha River Bridge in Yibin yesterday evening, it still looked green. This morning in Lizhuang, I lay on the railing of the riverside wetland and saw that it was already a dark yellow. The duckweeds washed down from the upper reaches were floating and sinking. I His swimming plan was temporarily scrapped. I don’t know why, I really want to swim this summer, to swim in open waters with no ceilings. Most of the reason for coming to Yibin is to swim in the Yangtze River. I saw the photos sent by my friends before. The Minjiang River is light yellow and the Jinsha River is green. I can’t get along with each other in Yibin. A long dividing line was drawn out, and I wanted to take a look at the dividing line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lizhuang has long been renovated. Except for a few quiet courtyards (such as the former site of Tongji Medical College), it is not easy to evoke the imagination of historical scenes. Instead, it is the former site of the Institute of History and Linguistics of the &quot;Academia Sinica&quot; in Banliao a few kilometers away. , because the resettlement conditions have not been agreed upon with the villagers, it has maintained a certain degree of &quot;authenticity&quot;. Of course, you can also say it is dilapidated. The roof of the courtyard called &quot;Tian 𡎚 Shang&quot; collapsed on the left side, so a few geese circled around and, together with the dogs hiding in the dark, issued impatient warnings to strangers. Walking inside is a courtyard with a bluestone floor, piles of firewood, bamboo poles and sundries. Old wires are wrapped around the black tiled wooden wall. A guinea fowl stands on the high threshold. Several &quot;This&quot; pictures are posted on the wall. &quot;Danger, please stay away&quot; warning sign. The eldest brother who lives here told me that there are four or five households in the yard. They are asked to move, but the compensation standard is only 750 meters per square meter. At this price, they cannot afford to buy a house elsewhere, so as long as the old house does not collapse, they will Live forever. If it weren&#39;t for the introduction on the sign at the door, I would never have known that this was once the library of the Institute of History and Linguistics - or &quot;the best Chinese liberal arts library during the war.&quot; Ah, I remembered, the reason why the Institute of Liberal Arts of Peking University wanted to leave at that time In Kunming, I came to Lizhuang with the Institute of History and Language Studies because of their rich collection of ancient books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outside the old house faces an acre of lotus pond, with overlapping lotus leaves and dotted lotus flowers. Together with the dense bamboos on the other side and the light blue sky, it is somewhat elegant. Did you ever &quot;talk and laugh&quot; here back then? Are there &quot;Hongru&quot;? But Hongru was probably like me, &quot;sweating like pulp&quot;. After the rain, the sun is fierce, everything on the surface is steaming, and the heat in southern Sichuan is revealed. In the summer of 1941, Mei Yiqi, Zheng Tianting, and Luo Changpei flew from Kunming to Chongqing to contact the Ministry of Education of the National Government about the affairs of Southwest Associated University. They then went up the river to Sichuan to visit academic institutions that had been moved to the rear area, and then walked to Lizhuang At that time, the diary kept complaining about the heat: &quot;The thermometer never dropped below 90 degrees (32.22 degrees Celsius) at night. It was so hot that I couldn&#39;t sleep all night long.&quot; &quot;The sweat shirt is soaked again&quot; (Luo Changpei), &quot;The sweat is all over the body, not just once&quot;, &quot;Taking off the coat and going naked does not make you cooler, but it is easier for the ears to sweat&quot; (Mei Yiqi). They did not leave any record of enjoying the Yangtze River, but their conversations with friends - listening to Liang Fangzhong talk about the inspection in northern Shaanxi, and listening to Ling Chunsheng talking about the story of demarcation of the Yunnan-Myanmar border - &quot;It was like taking Qingliang Powder, which eliminated a lot of... The heat of the summer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I took a bus back to Yibin and got off the bus in the old town. The so-called &quot;ancient streets&quot; were very boring. I turned to the Rongzhou Bridge to see the confluence of the Jinsha River and the Min River. The Jinsha River became even more muddy. The heat was unbearable and I was soaked to the skin. I chatted with the bridge watcher on the bridge (I forgot to ask him about his duties) about where to swim. He pointed me to a water bank under the bridge and reminded me to be careful when swimming—— He said a two-syllable word that I didn&#39;t understand. It was probably the watershed. After passing XX, the current would carry you far away from the shore, making it difficult to come back. I walked off the bridge and walked along the narrow stone stairs to the water. Two men and one woman who had just finished swimming had this place to themselves. They had brought lunch boxes for a picnic. I asked if the water was urgent. They seemed offended by this obvious question. , after a long while, he said in angry Sichuan terms: It’s not that it’s urgent, it’s that it’s very urgent! Further down is Hejiangmen, where the Min River merges into the Jinsha River, which is also the &quot;starting point of the Yangtze River.&quot; According to the introduction, the water depth at the confluence is 30 meters, what a guy. There is a square and the &quot;Pearl of the Yangtze River&quot; commemorative ball at the Hejiang River. At the bottom is a gentle backwater, dominated by the light yellow water of the Minjiang River. Occasionally, a few thin red water flows of the Jinsha River rush in, and some people swim underneath. It looks very safe, but it really doesn’t arouse my desire to go into the water. This place is more like a flooded overpass when the city is flooded. Who wants to swim under the overpass? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I decided to stay in Yibin for one more day and wait for the Jinsha River to clear up. During the day, I went to the museum to see an exhibition and saw the painter Lu Yanshao&#39;s &quot;Rock Perch Waiting to Visit&quot;. The meditator lived in seclusion in the mountains. His mountain house really looked like an air-raid bunker. Then I looked at the inscription. It was painted in Nanping, Chongqing in March 1941. , it was when the Japanese army concentrated their bombing. How does the creator feel and experience reality, and then complete the conception and imagination of the work? I curiously searched for Lu Yanshao&#39;s memoirs. In February 1938, he evacuated from Shanghai to Chongqing. &quot;I was afraid of bombings in the city, and I was afraid of bandits in the countryside, so I had no idea.&quot; He then worked at the arsenal farm and was responsible for keeping records of work. In his free time, he wrote, read and visited friends. He once went to Shapingba to visit Feng Zikai. The latter built several thatched houses on Pinggang, protected by low fences in the front and back, and also raised a few geese. &quot;Because no one introduced him, , I broke in on my own, but he didn’t take my presumptuous approach, and later wrote to me.” In 1941, when Lu Yan was 33 years old, his fourth child was born. He raised chickens, fed pigs, and grew vegetables to support the family, but due to the well, The water was unclean and it was difficult to drink. Fortunately, the arsenal later pumped water from the Yangtze River for the staff to drink, which made him understand what Du Fu wrote: &quot;What is the value of fighting for water?&quot; - When he entered Sichuan, he only brought one book in his luggage The book is Qian&#39;s poem about Du, &quot;I chant in my spare time, looking at the Bashan Shu River, the scenery before my eyes, once Du Gong points it out, I feel more friendly... Returning east without sun, with worries in my heart, is the same as Du Gong&#39;s feelings when he traveled to Shu, because Especially for Du&#39;s poems, he was too lazy to learn.&quot; After the victory of the Anti-Japanese War in August 1945, people from all walks of life returned to the east one after another. Lu Yanshao was eager to miss his hometown, but he couldn&#39;t buy a boat ticket. He happened to have a friend who was in the timber business, so he took a raft out. Although the gorge is dangerous, it also provides the opportunity to observe the water potential at close range. &quot;You can carefully examine its potential and understand the nature of the water. However, traditional landscape landscapes are all prepared by various schools and sects. It is really beyond the ability of a ship to speed up.&quot; Walking in the Three Gorges for more than a month has gained me more than studying for ten years... Because of the life experience of seeing the water in the Three Gorges, I used the hook line method to create a unique style of the dangerous water of the Gorge, which is only used in the sea. , which he has nothing in his family. From this he came to the conclusion that painting landscapes must go to the mountains and rivers. From the time of Wen Shen and the Four Kings, humans have been living in piles of old papers, and the situation has deteriorated over time. But after seeing it with your eyes, you must use your mind to think about it. , whether it is a big thing, it depends on its spirit, or a small thing, it is a tree or a stone. How to express it, you have to think about it... You must bring some new methods back... Otherwise, the trip will be in vain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5 p.m. The water in the Yangtze River has become muddier and faster. Near the Water Curtain Square, a long hydrophilic platform with red mud bathing on the shore is probably an excellent natural swimming lane when the water is clear. I took off my shoes and went down to feel the flow velocity. It was not knee deep, but the impact force was obvious. A cargo ship went upstream, and the waves spread to both sides. A few swimmers drifting down from the upstream with followers avoided it and laughed loudly. They were probably enjoying themselves. I walked upstream along the river and returned to the confluence of the two rivers. The Minjiang River rushed straight towards the other bank, creating another piece of backwater here. The two waters were not fully mixed, and there were many thread-like semi-clear water suspended in the mud. An elder brother was sitting on the pier. He also came to swim, but he thought the water was dirty. &quot;It became clear one night before, but it is still very muddy today. It may be due to the discharge of sand from the upstream reservoir.&quot; He also said that people drowned here a few days ago. There were three people, two of whom he couldn&#39;t escape and were photographed underwater by the big boat. &quot;They haven&#39;t been found yet.&quot; I asked him what it was like to swim at the junction of the two rivers. “It’s cool and warm for a while” – the Jinsha River is warm in winter and cool in summer, while the Minjiang River is the opposite, so locals like to swim in the Jinsha River, especially in winter, when the water is very warm, “ I don’t want to come up after soaking in it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the third day, the Yangtze River was still not clear. I decided not to wait any longer and went to see the rich water in the upper reaches. Shuifu belongs to Zhaotong, Yunnan, but is much closer to Yibin, Sichuan. The driver who took me there chatted with me and said that Shuifu and Yibin have similar accents and similar food, &quot;but they don&#39;t like eating and playing as much as we do.&quot; I asked her to go along the river as much as possible, so she chose an old road with bumps on the south bank. Didi Mini Program refused to accept this old road full of large trucks, shouting all the way, &quot;You have deviated, please turn around at the appropriate location.&quot; . It was a little annoying at first, but after listening to it for a long time, I suddenly became happy: Isn’t yaw one of the purposes of traveling? Without yaw, how could there be any surprise? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surprise will come soon. The car was near the river, and I saw irregular blue-green colors on the turbid river surface during the bumps. I thought I had seen it wrong. After all, the sun was glaring and it was constantly blocked by shrubs. But the driver said she saw it too. After a while, we both confirmed: there is indeed a thin blue line on the other side, that is, the north bank of the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it because there is a clear tributary flowing into the north bank? As the car drove forward, the blue line grew bigger and bigger, until it was evenly matched with the dark yellow line. I clicked on the map on my phone and finally realized that the Jinsha River had always been blue because there was a large tributary, the Hengjiang River, pouring in from the south bank in front of it, bringing with it billows of sediment that dyed the entire main stream yellow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When crossing the border between Sichuan and Yunnan, the driver became nervous. Someone in her WeChat group reminded her: There is a transportation management team ahead. Check online for a taxi. It is said that if you catch a car, you will be fined 3,000 to 10,000. Although she has only been running Didi for more than ten days, she already feels &quot;a lot of pressure&quot;. We went around and around and avoided it. When we reached the end, she breathed a sigh of relief and said, &quot;I&#39;ll be safe when you get there.&quot; Then she ran to the trunk and brought me two big pears, saying they were grown in her hometown. When I checked in at the hotel, I chose the room type facing the Xiangjiaba Hydropower Station, but I didn’t see the Gaoxia Pinghu Lake I imagined. The dam is 162 meters high. From the 10th floor where I was, it was impossible to even see the top of the dam. , if we take the surface of the reservoir lake as a benchmark, I am now more than a hundred meters underwater, which gives people a strange feeling of having a water basin above their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The river under the dam is so blue that it’s mesmerizing, and a dozen egrets are looking for food on the bank. After eating a pear, I went out to look for food. The taste here is indeed similar to that of Yibin. One or two plain noodles, one or two mushroom noodles, and a bowl of iced white fungus soup, a total of 16 yuan. Satisfied to see the river, the nearest one is Xiangjiaba Bridge. I was a little shocked when I got on the bridge. Today&#39;s high temperature is 35 degrees Celsius, there are not many trees and water, and the whole city is covered in white from the sun, but it cools down as soon as we reach the bridge. This should also be attributed to the water basin above the head: the temperature in the deep water area of ​​the reservoir is low all year round, and the water under the dam is cold, so the downstream valley naturally becomes a freezer. After standing for a long time, my legs even felt cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than one kilometer from the bridge, the red mud-colored Hengjiang River flows into the right bank, so the more than one kilometer of blue Jinsha River before it has become a big swimming pool for the water rich. I stepped on the big rocks that were hot in the sun and went down to the water. A kind brother saw that I was following me and repeatedly reminded me to pay attention to safety. The water here is deep and fast. It is the territory of the swimming association. All the experts are swimming in the middle. Adults will ask the children who come to play in the water: Where are your parents? I swam close to the shore for a while. The water was really fast and I was still in the same place after swimming for a long time, but I finally embraced this lovely river. Cool, but not as cool as expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I thanked my elder brother and continued to walk downstream. I passed a real backwater area. The water near the shore moved upstream at an extremely fast speed. I also passed a tidal flat, and the water was filled with tidal flats. Schools of small fish change into different shapes when frightened. Further down, there is a man-made cement platform, which is waist-deep in the river water and serves as a shoal. The water flow here is slow and there are the most swimmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the bridge and at high places, you can easily see many white swirls in the middle of the river where the flow is the fastest, like rolling away, drawing circles from the inside out, large and small. But when you go down into the water and your eyes are level with the water, what you see more are lines, light or dark lines, disturbing ripples, and water light. The water light sprinkled with gold powder is so charming. When your whole body is soaked in this cool blue water, your consciousness seems to disappear, and you only feel great freedom and happiness. After a long time, a nonsensical sentence popped up in my mind:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am willing to drink a lot of water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I smelled the faint smell of freshwater grass that I was familiar with when I was swimming in the Xiangjiang River when I was a child. The sparkling waves in the sky when I looked at the water also seemed familiar. There was a whistling sound in the middle of the river, like a god sifting beans, and occasionally there was a rush of water. Come here and let your body feel refreshed. free. Freedom stretches endlessly from all around. The deeper you go, the more free you feel. It&#39;s a pity that I can&#39;t write poetry - I thought in the water - only poetry is worthy of the rhythm here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Let people swim!&quot; This is the title of a column for the New York Times by Berlin-based writer Paul Hockenos. This hot summer, he visited Munich and found that almost everyone in the city was swimming in the Isar River to cool off. This tributary of the Danube River was once seriously polluted. In 2000, when the climate crisis had not intensified and the summer in Europe was not too harsh, Munich presciently carried out a large-scale restoration of the Isar River. This project lasted 11 years and cost 38 million. The $100 million project includes cleaning up the river, expanding its floodplain, and transforming its banks to accommodate the surge of spring snowmelt flooding from the Alps. Today, the river serves as an important public space, providing a place for people to escape the heat. &quot;I don&#39;t have a balcony, I don&#39;t have a garden, but I have the Isar River.&quot; said a friend of Paul Hockenos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I realized later that the reason why I wanted to swim in a real river so much was to say goodbye to a feeling of fear, a feeling of scaring myself that had accumulated over the past few years. The pure freedom and joy I felt in the water was something I hadn’t seen in a long time. “Healing” is overused these days, but it’s still true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remembered that when I studied extensively at the Southwest Associated University a few years ago, I certainly had various perceptions of that period of history, but the one that impressed me the most was nothing more than three words: &quot;not afraid.&quot; I also remembered that many years ago when I was a reporter, I interviewed a scholar. He talked about &quot;listening to drinking&quot; and said, &quot;Listening to drinking is a slave. But now there are people who voluntarily listen to drinking. With a wave of their hands, everyone leaves, and that&#39;s it.&quot; I was too inexperienced at the time and could only literally understand the damage that &quot;listening and drinking&quot; can do to a person&#39;s integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was immersed in joy and happiness the whole day after swimming, and walked along the Jinsha River for half a day in the evening. It seems like people all over the city are walking along the river. Cities with big rivers are indeed blessed. On the way back to the hotel, I saw a row of lights on the dam from a distance, like a city wall. I finished watching the last day of the World Swimming Championships while eating a 4.99 yuan spicy chicken drumstick, and my mind kept replaying the blue that I saw, touched, and immersed myself in in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校领导被举报收实习回扣应调查，职校不能把学生当“猪仔”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, anti-counterfeiter Wang Hai publicly reported through the Internet that the leader of a vocational school in Jiangxi made huge profits from student internships. aroused great public concern. On November 13, Xinyu City, Jiangxi Province, where the vocational school involved is located, announced that a joint investigation team had been formed by the Municipal Education Bureau, Human Resources and Social Security Bureau, etc. to investigate and verify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Jimu News, Wang Hai posted on the Internet that Teacher Zhang from Jiangxi New Energy Technology Vocational College accidentally discovered that his ex-wife Yan Moumou, who was also responsible for student internships at the school, had a huge deposit of 6 million yuan. , and also discovered an account book involving tens of millions of yuan, recording the details and distribution ratios of funds transferred by multiple human resources agencies to multiple leaders of the school. One page shows that a four-month internship with 39 students received nearly 130,000 yuan in &quot;management fees&quot;. His ex-wife received more than 14,000 yuan, and another leader received more than 114,000 yuan. . The bank statements provided by the whistleblower also show that since 2017, multiple human resources companies have frequently transferred money to the account of a person related to Yan in the name of &quot;employing companies paying training fees&quot;, with amounts ranging from several thousand yuan to tens of thousands of yuan. No wait. The money finally went to Yan Moumou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The figure of more than 6 million is a bit shocking. From the article, it seems that this is only a small amount allocated to the assistant dean. Whether Wang Hai&#39;s report is true or not depends on the investigation results of relevant departments. However, it is no secret that in the name of organizing student internships, vocational schools actually engage in &quot;labor export&quot;, collect fees from internship companies, and even deduct students&#39; internship remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, because some manufacturing companies had difficulty recruiting workers, vocational school students became the targets of some labor agency companies. Vocational schools then found a way to make money: they cooperated with labor agencies, organized students to work in companies in the name of internship, and collected management fees, training fees, etc. In a Jimu News report, a former vice president of Jiangxi New Energy Technology Vocational College admitted that when students go to companies for internships, the school does receive a management fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, companies will not spend this money in vain. In some places, in addition to schools collecting money, school leaders and intern teachers can also receive kickbacks. In this incident, a page of account books provided by the whistleblower showed that students from the school went to an internship in a company in Suzhou. For every hour they worked, the students were paid 15 yuan, the school could get 4 yuan, and the assistant to the dean could also receive it personally. 5 cents. Of course, the truth of the incident remains to be investigated. However, there have been precedents for similar incidents before. In 2021, it was revealed that Guizhou Aluminum Technician College arranged student internships through an intermediary company and collected fees ranging from 1,500 yuan to 2,000 yuan per student per month from the remuneration given to students by the internship unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vocational school students go to companies for &quot;internships&quot;, and the pay is low, but the labor intensity is not low. In 2021, Hunan Linwu County Vocational High School organized students to intern at a company in the county, where they had to work 11 hours a day. In the same year, some students from Hanjiang Science and Technology School in Danjiangkou City, Hubei Province were arranged by the school to intern at a technology company, working more than ten hours a day. And these &quot;internship&quot; jobs often have nothing to do with the majors they studied. Students majoring in computer science were assigned to &quot;move boxes&quot;, while those majoring in nursing were assigned to beauty salons and hair salons. These so-called internships are actually pure physical labor and have no effect on improving professional skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long hours and heavy labor are unbearable even for adults, let alone vocational school students who have just become adults or even minors. Many people have been severely damaged physically and mentally, and some have even become disabled due to work-related injuries due to fatigue at work and other reasons. Xiaopeng, a student from Linwu County Vocational High School, was pinched by a machine during his internship, resulting in the amputation of two fingers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In people’s minds, ordinary college students will also do internships before graduation, but the school usually does not organize arrangements. At most, it provides relevant information and requires students to contact the internship unit themselves. But vocational schools are different. Vocational education regulations require that students &quot;should&quot; participate in internship training, and internship experience has become a necessary condition for graduation of vocational school students. Some vocational schools use the precious sword of graduation certificates to force students to participate in &quot;internships&quot; organized by the school. &quot;If you don&#39;t go to the internship, you will not be given a diploma.&quot; The internship time is too short and cannot bring enough &quot;value&quot; to the school. No.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most vocational schools are at the technical secondary level and recruit junior high school graduates. Because of the &quot;50-50 split&quot; in the high school entrance examination, about half of junior high school graduates go to vocational schools. Most of these students are only 15 or 16 years old. At the age of 10, they have just finished the education stage that focuses more on discipline, and their minds are not fully mature. Compared with these immature students, schools and teachers are undoubtedly in an absolute advantageous position. These powers have become transformed in the hands of some schools and teachers. The sickle that cuts students&#39; leeks. These schools are not thinking about how to improve the quality of teaching and teach students real professional skills, but they are thinking hard about how to squeeze more money out of students.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a profession Education, no wonder parents and students abandon it like worn-out shoes. To do a good job in vocational education, we must first break this abnormal power structure and let vocational schools return to their role as education service providers. Students can come and go freely without being restricted by their student status. If you feel that a certain school or a certain major is not good, you can leave at any time and go to other schools or majors. As long as you study enough courses and learn enough skills, you can graduate. This will encourage vocational schools to compete in the education market. Win the favor of students and parents based on indicators such as teaching and employment quality, rather than treating students as cash cows and lambs to be cut.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>