<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[大账高企小账不绝  银保业务何以常年畸形？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259167]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the channel business that contributes the largest premium to insurance companies, bancassurance is facing a new round of high pressure from regulations and new policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, Liu Sheng, the person in charge of the personal insurance supervision work of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, said that the regulatory authorities will consistently do a good job in the work of &quot;unifying reporting and banking&quot;; insist on catching up early and small , grasp the typical cases, continue to strictly supervise and strengthen accountability, rectify industry chaos, and effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of insurance consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 22, the Personal Insurance Department of the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration issued the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products through Bank Agency Channels&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;) to all personal insurance companies, requiring all When filing products, insurance companies should clearly state the cost assumptions and fee structure in the product actuarial report, and list the commission ceiling; each insurance company should truthfully list the commission rates paid to the bank, and the actual fees such as commissions should be compared with the filing materials. Stay consistent, that is, &quot;unity of reward and action.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot;, the Shanghai Insurance Association has issued an industry self-discipline convention. Following the Notice, insurance industry associations in Guangdong and other places also issued a self-discipline convention for bancassurance business. Self-regulatory conventions in various places target stubborn problems such as high fees and disorderly competition in bancassurance channels, and strictly prohibit vicious price competition, commercial bribery and other illegal activities that disrupt the order of the bancassurance market. We promise not to covertly increase bancassurance business fees through other channels and methods, and resolutely put an end to small accounts in bancassurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the pressure of supervision, it is imperative to reduce bank insurance fees. But why does the bancassurance business always suffer from the chronic industry problem of high large accounts and constant small accounts? It seems to be getting more and more popular as it becomes more banned. As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand any benefits other than those agreed in the agreement in any way from insurance companies and their personnel.&quot; Under this round of high pressure, will the chaos in the banking and insurance channels end? Will the bank insurance premium rate difference that plagues insurance companies turn into a fee difference from now on? How do bancassurance alliances develop internationally? What are some lessons worth learning from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center reviewed the development history of bancassurance at home and abroad, and used horizontal comparative research methods to find that the root cause of the &quot;big and small account problem&quot; lies in the profit distribution mechanism caused by the loose cooperation between insurance and banks. imbalance. Under this cooperation model, banks are driven by unilateral profits, and the overall business falls into a dilemma of incremental growth but no efficiency gain. Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center also visited different bank outlets as policyholders and conducted unannounced visits and found that the professionalism of bancassurance sales staff needs to be improved. Only when banks and bank employees transfer their focus on sales fees to professionalism will bank cooperation enter a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The stubborn problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank insurance refers to a business model in which banks mainly sell insurance on their behalf. Together with personal agents and group insurance, it constitutes the main sales channel of insurance companies. Bancassurance is the core business of life insurance companies and the leading business of many small and medium-sized companies. In order to compete for premiums,&amp;nbsp;many small and medium-sized insurance companies have always maintained high-priced large accounts and various forms of small accounts, and many large companies have been passively involved in price wars. This is what the industry calls &quot;big and small accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;big and small accounts&quot;? The &quot;big account&quot; refers to the handling fee agreed in the written contract between the insurance company and the bank, which is the bank&#39;s official income from the agency sales of insurance; the &quot;small account&quot; refers to the sales incentives privately given by the insurance company to bank staff, in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2019, when talking about strict management of violations of regulations and disciplines at an internal meeting, the president of a joint-stock bank said that the one thing he could not tolerate the most was employees receiving kickbacks from insurance companies. In fact, regulatory agencies have also cracked down on small accounting issues many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand from insurance companies and their personnel in any way other than what is agreed in the agreement.&quot; any benefit”. Over the past few years, rectification has continued, but no significant results have been achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Big accounts are high, small accounts are endless&quot; Why does it become a chronic disease? On the surface, the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is due to the strong position of banks and bancassurance cooperation due to their huge channels and strong customer resources. However, the root cause is that the interest distribution mechanism under the short-term and loose cooperation model between banks and insurance companies is insufficient. Reasonably caused. Banking and insurance are independent entities and there is no basis for equal cooperation between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons for the strong position of banks are complicated, but in the financial market structure dominated by banks, it does not necessarily lead to the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;. For example, in Europe, where the bancassurance business originated, in countries such as France and Italy, the bancassurance business not only accounts for a high proportion, but also makes a large contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is related to my country’s bancassurance cooperation model. Except for bank insurance companies and some giant insurance companies, the cooperation model between most banks and insurance companies is a &quot;many-to-many&quot; distribution agency model, that is, banks sign distribution agreements with insurance companies, and banks sell insurance through agency insurance companies. Products earn fees and commission income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this model, the determination of business philosophy, development of bancassurance products and insurance claims settlement are all undertaken by the insurance company, and both bancassurance and bancassurance parties only carry out superficial cooperation based on channel-level factors such as marketing channels and customer resources. cooperation. From the perspective of contract theory, it is essentially a simple principal-agent relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, outside the bank, the insurance company serves as the principal and the bank acts as the agent. The two define each other&#39;s rights, obligations and interest distribution methods by signing a cooperation agreement. The main incentive mechanism of the contract is that the bank earns handling fees from the bancassurance agency business, while the insurer transfers part of the benefits in exchange for rapid expansion of premium income, thus forming the first level of entrustment-agency between the bank and the insurance company. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within the bank, sales tasks are distributed layer by layer in the order of head office - branch branches - outlets, and the products are ultimately sold directly by bancassurance specialists at each outlet. According to the &quot;About Further Strengthening the Compliance of Commercial Banks&#39; Agency Insurance Business&quot; &quot;Notice on Sales and Risk Management&quot; stipulates that commercial banks shall not allow insurance company personnel to be stationed in bank branches. Therefore, relevant personnel of the insurance company can only supervise and assist bancassurance sales in the form of patrol points. A second principal-agent relationship is formed between the bank and its employees based on the sales of bancassurance products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the sales intensity of sinking channels determines the amount of premiums to a large extent. Moreover, because of the existence of a double principal-agent relationship, the two parties have conflicting goals. Specifically, banks tend to sell single payment or short-term regular payment insurance products with high commission rates, simple terms and simple benefit demonstrations. As for the compatibility between customers and products, agents are not particularly concerned. However, regular payment insurance with long payment period and comprehensive protection functions is the type of insurance that insurance companies hope to sell because of its high intrinsic value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, insurance companies compete fiercely for banking channels. The &quot;Measures for the Administration of Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; promulgated in 2019 (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;) stipulates that each branch of a commercial bank can only cooperate with no more than 3 insurance companies in the insurance agency business in the same fiscal year, that is, &quot;1+ 3&quot; mode. The quality and configuration of banks’ sinking channels have become the focus of competition among insurance companies. Therefore, the Measures have to a certain extent intensified competition among insurance companies for banks’ high-quality channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of serious product homogeneity, large accounts and small accounts have become an alternative competitive weapon. Liu Sheng commented that in recent years, the personal insurance industry has experienced severe homogeneous competition, and insurance companies generally have extensive expense management, resulting in actual expenses exceeding the level at the time of product filing, resulting in &quot;inconsistent reporting&quot;. High fees not only disrupt the market order, but are also the root cause of problems such as false fees, false insurance applications, and false surrenders. They are also the breeding ground for &quot;black agency products&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent are bancassurance channel fees exaggerated? Liu Sheng revealed that as of October 20, the vast majority of banks carrying out bancassurance business have re-signed contracts with insurance companies in accordance with the requirements of &quot;unification of banks and banks&quot;. Preliminary estimates show that the commission rate for the bancassurance channel has dropped by about 30% compared with the previous average level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the results of the competition between &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the fragmentation of market share. According to statistics from Guolian Securities, judging from the scale of bancassurance channel premiums of personal insurance companies, the market share of the top ten companies in bancassurance channel premiums has dropped from 59.9% in 2017 to 52.1% in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the intertwining of various reasons, the bancassurance channel has formed a status quo of &quot;high cost and low value&quot;. The bancassurance channel is also one of the channels where policyholders complain more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the intersection of history and reality, and is the product of the extensive development of the insurance industry in the past. In recent years, the insurance industry has received great attention in supporting economic and social development, and regulatory authorities have promoted deepening reforms in multiple key areas, including comprehensive system construction and core areas such as corporate governance, solvency, capital utilization, and consumer rights protection. The &quot;Notice&quot; releases a signal of reform, which will curb the industry&#39;s &quot;big and small accounts&quot; problem to a certain extent. However, whether the stubborn problem of &quot;big accounts, high prices, small accounts, and constant supply&quot; can be completely eradicated still depends on industry self-discipline, deepening cooperation between banks and insurance companies, and improving long-term incentive mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Window period&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why are the temporary management agencies stepping up their efforts to rectify the bancassurance business at this time? A researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that the insurance industry has undergone major changes under the new situation, and this is a window period for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the insurance industry is concerned, the agent team continues to shrink, and the growth rate of original premium income of the personal insurance industry is hovering at a low level. In 2022, the personal insurance industry will continue to be under pressure and enter a period of deep adjustment. That year, the original premium income of life insurance was 2.45 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 4%, accounting for 71.6% of personal insurance premiums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the public’s awareness of social security is gradually increasing The trend of aging and social aging still creates demand space for the development of the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of consumer behavior, insurance consumption has changed from &quot;should I buy it&quot; to &quot;is it good or not.&quot; The &quot;2022 China Internet Insurance Consumer Insight Report&quot; shows that consumers aged 31-40, mainly those born in the 1980s, spend more on insurance, and 75% of households spend more than 5,000 yuan on annual insurance. It can be seen that young consumers’ awareness of insurance and willingness to pay have increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an operational perspective, some small and medium-sized insurance companies have relatively aggressive product pricing strategies, and some products have risks of long-term insurance and short-term insurance. At the same time, in the context of declining long-term interest rates and declining corporate investment yields, incremental whole life insurance with the function of locking long-term interest rates will expose insurance companies to the risk of spread losses. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the life insurance version of “interest rate cuts” has been implemented. Supervision has clearly provided window guidance. Before the end of July 2023, the predetermined interest rates for new personal insurance products will be adjusted. After dealing with the interest rate loss in the short term, how to solve the fee difference loss has become increasingly urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of bancassurance channels is a key measure to alleviate fee differences. What conditions are met for channel purification at this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found through statistics and comparison that as of the end of 2022, the total number of agents of Ping An, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and New China Insurance was 1.59 million, down from 1.64 million in 2010 Thousands of people. The efficiency-improving reform of personal agency channels continues to show no significant results. At the same time, since 2020, major domestic listed insurance companies have been actively developing bancassurance channels, promoting the strategic transformation of &quot;new bancassurance&quot;, and have introduced a series of measures to strengthen the depth of cooperation with banks, hoping to achieve Growth in scale and value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Ping An Life as an example, financial report data shows that, From 2019 to 2022, the growth rate of new policy premiums in the bancassurance channel was as high as 19.1%, significantly ahead of the individual insurance channel and other channels. The premium growth rates of the two during the same period were -10.1% and -7.5% respectively. The proportion of the company&#39;s new premiums increased from 4.2% in 2019 to 9.2% in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also shows that the agent channel that can best bring high intrinsic value policies to life insurance companies is still being adjusted. However, small and medium-sized insurance companies are basically unable to cultivate a large-scale agent team. In other words, the importance of the bancassurance channel has increased, highlighting the need for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks are also facing performance pressure. In a situation where interest spreads have shrunk, wealth management products have been depleted and trust products have become scarce, the agency insurance business has become a performance highlight. Take China Merchants Bank as an example. In 2022, China Merchants Bank&#39;s fund agency business revenue dropped by 46.4% year-on-year, and its proportion of non-interest income also dropped from the highest value of 13.0% in 2015 to 6.6%, while insurance agency sales revenue has remained at around 50% for two consecutive years. positive growth, and its proportion in non-interest income also increased significantly to 11.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;974&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the depth of both banks and insurance companies The window period for cooperation has arrived, and regulatory agencies and associations have the “right time, favorable location, and harmonious relationship” to crack down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that from the perspective of insurance companies’ profit models, among the “three differences”, death and fee differences account for relatively small proportions. The &quot;Notice&quot; aims to standardize sales expenses and prevent unfair competition. It is one of the important measures to standardize insurance sales behavior in a multi-dimensional and systematic manner. Following the &quot;Notice&quot;, the &quot;Insurance Sales Behavior Management Measures&quot; recently issued by the State Administration of Financial Supervision will be implemented from March 1, 2024. The &quot;Measures&quot; echo the &quot;Plan for the Construction of the Sales Ability Qualification Grading System for Insurance Sales Practitioners&quot; previously issued by the Insurance Industry Association, and aim to guide insurance companies to establish a product grading and channel grading system that matches customer needs. With the combined efforts of multiple measures, the results of this round of bancassurance channel rectification are worth looking forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Overseas Bancassurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Close&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Type&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank Insurance It has existed abroad for more than 60 years. What can we learn from it? Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found out that there are two theories about the origin of bancassurance: one is Britain in the 1960s; the other is France in the 1970s. However, the development of bancassurance business in Britain and France is quite different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;New Bancassurance Era: The Beginning of Value&quot; released by Deloitte in 2023 shows that bancassurance channels in France, Italy and Spain account for 64%, 74% and 60% of all premiums respectively. %. Among Asian countries, South Korea accounts for 50%, Indonesia accounts for 48%, Singapore accounts for 30%, and India accounts for 25%. The UK bancassurance business has developed slowly and mainly relies on insurance broker channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the evolution of cooperation models in various countries, four bancassurance business cooperation models, namely agreement agency, strategic alliance, capital cooperation and financial group, have proven to be quite successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1535&quot; height= &quot;3358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take France as an example. Banks enter the bancassurance field mainly by controlling insurance companies. Banks control insurance companies in two ways: establishing self-owned subsidiaries and acquiring other insurance companies, with the former being the main form. In terms of products, simplified and standardized life insurance or savings products are the main products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banking and insurance in Hong Kong, China also implement mixed operations, and large banks build their own insurance companies to achieve bancassurance synergy. The same is true for Taiwan, China. Bancassurance is mostly carried out in the form of a financial holding company. Its insurance product sales channels mainly include joint marketing through financial holding companies and strategic alliances, that is, business cooperation promotion through financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overseas experience shows that the development process of bancassurance is a process of banks and insurance companies jointly exploring consumer needs. It is a common choice for banks and insurance companies to choose the path of bancassurance cooperation and provide bancassurance products that meet the diverse needs of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development experience, the global bancassurance industry has experienced three stages: bancassurance, insurance banking and universal finance. They are essentially the cross-penetration, mutual integration, mutual complementation and common development of banks and insurance companies in many aspects such as product research and development, sales channels, organizational forms and business strategies, that is, the mixed operation of banks and insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the development models of bancassurance vary in different countries and regions. In other words, there is no universally applicable bancassurance development model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that my country’s bancassurance started relatively late but is developing rapidly. Data from the &quot;Insurance Yearbook&quot; show that in 2010, China&#39;s bancassurance channel premium income accounted for 50% of life insurance premium income, which was the highest in history. However, the cooperation between banks and insurance companies has always been based on the sales agreement model, and the cooperative relationship between banks and insurance companies is relatively loose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This model has obvious shortcomings. First, bancassurance cooperation is limited to the sales level, and there is a lack of motivation to jointly develop products; second, banks only act as agents for insurance products to obtain agency fees, and the cooperation between the two parties is short-term and unstable. Third, driven by short-term financial goals, both parties lacked enthusiasm in cultivating bancassurance professionals, resulting in low bancassurance service levels and frequent misleading sales problems. Therefore, my country’s banking and insurance cooperation model needs to be further deepened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Explore new ways of bancassurance cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to establish a healthy and win-win bancassurance ecosystem? The development experience of overseas banking and insurance shows that the financial legal environment and the form of organizational cooperation are crucial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the banking and insurance industries are under the unified supervision of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the regulatory coordination of the two industries will be smoother. At the same time, banks’ huge channels and strong customer resources are excellent channels for bancassurance to acquire customers. In addition, after years of market education, people generally have insurance awareness. Bank customers are naturally aware of financial management, and the question has changed from &quot;whether to buy&quot; to &quot;which product to buy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for insurance companies and banks, the customer acquisition cost advantage of the bancassurance channel will exist for a long time, and it will still be the main channel for insurance companies, especially small and medium-sized insurance companies, and it is not to be underestimated in banks’ collection business. field of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to build a new cooperation method for banks and insurance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that judging from overseas experience, the four models each have their own merits. At this stage, we can appropriately promote the development of in-depth bancassurance cooperation models. Those who have the conditions can try it at a higher level. my country&#39;s bancassurance development model has transformed from a sales agreement model to a strategic alliance model. In the future cooperation between bancassurance and insurance, the following points should be implemented: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. In terms of business philosophy, both bancassurance and bancassurance parties should completely transform the extensive operation that puts scale first, and truly shift from &quot;sales-centered&quot; to &quot;sales-centered&quot; Customer-centric&quot;. This will help both banks and insurance companies reach a consensus and shift to long-term business goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. In terms of cooperation methods, promote the transformation and upgrading of bancassurance cooperation. On the one hand, through strategic alliances between banks and insurance companies, &quot;capital integration&quot; and other methods, the constraint mechanism for the distribution of interests between banks and insurance companies will be reconstructed, and the &quot;discourse power&quot; of insurers in bank-insurance cooperation will be enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of laws and regulations, it is recommended to further optimize relevant laws and regulations. Objectively speaking, under the &quot;1+3&quot; model, the collaborative business relationship between banks and insurance is not stable, which increases the coordination costs between the two parties and exacerbates the inequality between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技之手点燃梦想之火——访杭州亚残运会主火炬手徐佳玲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259159]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the lighting ceremony of the opening ceremony of the 4th Asian Para Games in Hangzhou on the evening of the 22nd, the last torch bearer , disabled swimmer Xu Jialing stepped onto the main torch stand and changed the torch &quot;laurel crown&quot; from her right hand to her left hand in front of everyone&#39;s attention - her smart bionic hand lit the main torch of this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, I only found out through the news that I was the last one.” Before the rehearsal of the opening ceremony, Xu Jialing had already worked with Intelligent Bionics with the help of the research and development company Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. It took me a while to get my hands on it and I can control it pretty well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“A staff member previously informed me that I was the infield torchbearer for the opening ceremony, but I didn’t know which torchbearer I was.” Until I saw Sha Xiao, the chief director of the opening ceremony, in the news. Lan revealed how to light the main torch, and Xu Jialing realized that she, who had been working with the intelligent bionic hand, would bear the final blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, I felt that I was very honored to be given such an important task.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height= &quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Beh In Chinese language, this is called &quot;controlling with thoughts.&quot; &quot;Actually, I am already accustomed to life after amputation, but the smart bionic hand allows me to hold the torch with both hands and light the sacred flame. It is also very convenient in life. I can hold a water cup and twist the bottle cap.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smart bionic hand that looked very technological at the opening ceremony has actually undergone improvements in appearance design. &quot;At the beginning, we made a skin-colored version of the hand and socket for Xu Jialing. In order to make the overall visual presentation more technological, the team replaced her with a space gray hand and a carbon fiber socket. She also said she liked it very much. .&quot; revealed the intelligent bionic hand engineer team of Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My prosthesis is very cool!” Xu Jialing’s tone revealed happiness and pride. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;729&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Bei He&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, Xu Jialing’s cheerful and optimistic words often make people forget that the “cool” high-tech product we are discussing is being worn on her slightly defective left arm. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, 4-year-old Xu Jialing was involved in a car accident and her left arm was no longer intact. By chance two years later, her mother discovered that Xu Jialing liked to play in the swimming pool, so she considered sending her to learn how to swim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coach thought that Xu Jialing might be good at swimming. Coupled with the recommendation of the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, Xu Jialing trained in her hometown of Ningbo for 6 years, successfully entered the Zhejiang Provincial Disabled Swimming Team, and went on an expedition with the national team. Rio 2016 Paralympic Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1019&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, 2016, at the Rio Paralympic Games, Xu Jialing (middle) won the S9 championship in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yang Lei&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rio, 14-year-old Xu Jialing, as the youngest competitor of the Chinese delegation at the time, won 1 gold and 2 bronze medals, which can be said to be &quot;the peak at her debut.&quot; After that, she won 7 gold medals and 2 silver medals at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Para Games. Although she experienced a trough in the subsequent Tokyo Paralympics, Xu Jialing&#39;s mentality is now very calm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I won the gold medal in Rio, the journey may have been too smooth. At that time, I felt that it was not too difficult to stand on the podium. In Tokyo, I was not able to get on the podium even once. There will be disappointment, but it is also expected, because the state was not very good at that time.&quot; Xu Jialing said, &quot;The mentality now is more about training well and letting nature take its course.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only cheerful Optimistic, Xu Jialing often shows maturity beyond her years in conversations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the Rio Paralympics, 14-year-old Xu Jialing said in an interview: &quot;I think my life is very exciting, no worse than my able-bodied peers.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 2, in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly S9 final of the Para Swimming World Championships held in Manchester, England, Chinese athlete Xu Jialing won the championship with a time of 1 minute, 08 seconds and 34 seconds. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo by Jon Hupper)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years have passed, looking back on the growth process, Xu Jialing’s youth can indeed be described as “wonderful”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to her dazzling competition results, Xu Jialing also likes to travel during her limited holidays. In addition, she trains and competes with the team overseas, allowing her to leave precious memories around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jialing is currently a student in the &quot;Championship Class&quot; of Beijing Sport University. Her major is sports training. &quot;I&#39;m very happy to be back in school.&quot; Xu Jialing, who has been training for swimming for most of the past ten years, said, &quot;Studying in college can not only learn knowledge, but also better understand the major you are engaged in. I think this is The chances are good.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, lit the main torch at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Xu Jialing has become the main torchbearer of the Asian Paralympic Games. With the help of technology, she lit the main torch in the spotlight and illuminated her youth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development of science and technology, more and more devices and equipment such as smart bionic hands help people with disabilities make up for their physical deficiencies, igniting their belief in pursuing their dreams. But in Xu Jialing&#39;s view, the word &quot;equality&quot; may be as important as technological assistance to the disabled group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Personally, I don’t want everyone to look at us with a pity and want to cry. Our ability to stand on the Asian Paralympic Games, just like any athlete, is a result of hard work. The result of training. Maybe our training will be harder and it will be more difficult at the beginning, but we still hope that everyone can treat us with a normal mind.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传“前台实名制”将落地：能有效改善网络空间的现实生态吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259112]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it has been reported online that the &quot;real-name system at the front desk&quot; is about to be implemented, causing concern and discussion. &quot;Come and Go&quot; (Wang Gaofei, CEO of Sina Weibo) quoted a media comment &quot;&quot;Real-name system at the front desk&quot;, big V should have taken off his vest long ago&quot;, which showed that the rumors were true. He also stated in a reply: The real-name system at the front desk is aimed at It is a self-media account with 1 million fans, which will be reduced to 500,000 fans in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Management of &quot;Self-Media&quot;&quot;. Among the 13 articles, there is a requirement to &quot;standardize account operation behavior&quot;: website platforms should strictly implement the &quot;one-person According to the regulations on the number of account registrations for &quot;One Number, One Enterprise and Two Numbers&quot;, individuals or companies are strictly prohibited from manipulating the &quot;self-media&quot; account matrix to publish and disseminate illegal and harmful information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current network platform implements a &quot;backend real-name system&quot;, and the front-end real-name and pseudonym are decided by oneself. If you really commit a crime on the Internet, you cannot go unpunished. The police will find you very quickly. Because the phone number used for registration itself is a real-name one; the IP addresses of Internet users are recorded in the background. However, even if real names are used in the background, as long as the person does not actively expose his or her information, the anonymity of online accounts is still quite strong, and online moral constraints are far inferior to offline ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for some people, if they want to maintain the quiet handsome man/demure lady personality that the large account has established, or if the large account exposes private information, they can just create another small account, go there Say something that the big one won&#39;t say. In this way, a person&#39;s personality can be divided into three: the offline one, a normal person in the eyes of colleagues and family members; the large one, an image with an ideal personality; the small one, another one, All kinds of darkness and nastiness appear. Seamless switching between ego, superego and id. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bigger problem with anonymity is that some self-media, in order to create topics and traffic, have no bottom line at all, and use all kinds of opposition to mobilize, engage in &quot;team building&quot;, and brush up comments and hot searches. Using a small power to create a huge voice in an organized manner to create public opinion and influence the legislative and judicial process; the same party opposes dissent, and organized super-saturated attacks, harassment, and threats against individuals and institutions that disagree with their actions and values. This is It has become a public nuisance, constantly dissolving the consensus and values ​​on which society relies for survival, and greatly deteriorating the ecology of public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, can these problems be solved by allowing self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans to have real names at the front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We might as well do a model analysis. There is a group of people, each of whom has a voting right. So which one is better, anonymous voting or real-name voting, so that everyone can express their true opinions and make the results more fair? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think it is better to vote anonymously: this way everyone can express their true opinions without pressure. But the disadvantages of anonymity are also obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, some people may be bribed or asked privately, because the final result is anonymous. Except for people who are colluding with each other, others have no way of knowing how they voted and no moral pressure can be exerted on them. , in this case, the vote he cast probably cannot be called &quot;expressing his true thoughts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, even if some people have not been bribed or accepted private requests, their voting tendency may not be fair. For example, they may not want to let others go because they have personal grudges. Or maybe it&#39;s purely because of the &quot;Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma&quot;: No matter you vote for or against my favorite, I will always vote against it, at least without losing money. In this way, unanimously opposing it becomes an advantageous strategy. Having a significant number of people think this way can significantly skew the overall voting results. Although these voters &quot;expressed their true thoughts,&quot; they had nothing to do with fairness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it is not ruled out that there are some people who are pure in nature and will not be bribed or accept private requests under any circumstances. They will put aside their personal grudges during the voting process and do not bother to conduct sophisticated calculations of interests. There are some people who objectively judge candidates based on their own merits, but they are probably few. In addition, it does not rule out that the above two types of people will vote fairly under certain circumstances. If the candidate is too good/bad, they cannot resist their conscience by insisting on voting against/for voting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people also think that real-name voting is good and can effectively reduce the above two unfair situations of anonymous voting. Everyone&#39;s voting results will be seen by others, thus making it easier to vote for favors and vote for personal grudges. Exposing the behavior of calculated votes to the public will significantly constrain such behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But real-name voting is not without problems. First, some weak-minded people are afraid of offending others and do not dare to truly express their wishes and cast a fair vote when voting with real names; second, voting with real names will make the differentiation of factions from vague to clear. After factions or cliques are formed, conflicts will become apparent and may intensify. These two points are also the main reasons for implementing anonymous voting: to allow everyone to vote without pressure, thereby limiting the intensity of conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, whether to vote anonymously or with a real name ultimately depends on which values ​​the institutions involved prefer and which issues need to be urgently resolved. How to apply this model analysis to whether the real-name system at the front desk should be implemented and the scope of implementation? If we want to solve the two problems of organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and harassment of individuals and institutions, we should undoubtedly implement a real-name system at the front desk to expose these organized and dark behaviors of self-media to the public and accept them. The scorching heat of the moral sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if only self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans require front-end real names, it may not be enough to curb the organized and dark behavior of self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there is the question of how far the front desk needs to be real-named. Is it the real person in charge or the editor of the operation? How to solve the problem of letting people without decision-making power to top the tank and deal with the real-name front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and nuisance have become highly evolved. The main account with hundreds of thousands or millions of fans will not be left alone at first, allowing some peripherals or fans to send malicious messages or mobilization messages through small accounts, and then instigate or patiently wait for some accounts with fewer fans to forward them, in addition to layer upon layer of forwarding. , the main account will then follow up and forward, thus minimizing the risk of the main account. This method of &quot;wearing multiple layers of cover&quot; is difficult to break the real-name system at the front desk of some self-media accounts with many fans, because small accounts and accounts with fewer fans can still do their own thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访广东省卫健委：基层诊疗“不仅要有大楼，还要有人才”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259151]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 23/9c64b58a94.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lantang Town Central Health Center, Hospital, Zijin County, Heyuan City, Guangdong Province In the lobby of the outpatient clinic building, there are promotional roll-ups by the chief health expert. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Letting high-quality medical resources sink and allowing people to see famous doctors at their doorsteps has attracted the attention of governments at all levels. The 2023 Government Work Report mentioned “promoting the expansion and decentralization of high-quality medical resources and balanced regional layout.” The 2023 Guangdong Provincial Government Work Report also proposed “in-depth implementation of a new round of grassroots medical and health service capacity improvement plans to effectively increase rural and underserved areas. Medical resources in developed areas”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To improve grassroots medical and health service capabilities, the most important thing is to fill the gaps in talent. In March 2023, the &quot;Opinions on Further Improving the Medical and Health Service System&quot; issued by the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council emphasized that we should increase support for the training of grassroots, remote areas and urgently needed professional talents, and narrow the gap between urban and rural areas, regions, and majors. The gap in talent allocation among enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to open up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving people&#39;s health and provide more convenient, high-quality and efficient health services, Guangdong launched the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts&quot; Grassroots Program”. The plan recruits 100 retired doctors from across the country who have senior professional titles and meet job requirements to serve as chief experts in 47 upgraded central health centers in Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the construction of the grassroots diagnosis and treatment system in Guangdong Province and the new round of implementation of the &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level&quot;, Southern Weekend reporters exclusively interviewed the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Support the horse and give him a ride&quot; to speed up the formation of service capabilities&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Guangdong is the country&#39;s largest province in terms of economic aggregate, but unbalanced development is the biggest shortcoming of Guangdong&#39;s high-quality development, which is also reflected in the grassroots health system . In recent years, Guangdong has invested a lot of money in comprehensively developing primary medical and health service capabilities. What is the current progress? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Since 2017, Guangdong has invested 50 billion yuan in facilities, equipment, talents, etc. Comprehensively carry out capacity-building in primary-level medical and health services and consolidate the grass-roots foundation. It also regards the upgrading and construction of 47 central health centers as the &quot;number one project&quot; to strengthen the grassroots level, and plans to &quot;build it in three years and form service capabilities in five years.&quot; By the end of 2020, 47 central health centers have successfully completed the &quot;three-year construction&quot; target task. Primary medical and health institutions have taken on a completely new look, and a path of primary health and health services with Guangdong characteristics has gradually taken shape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three years to complete&quot; is just the completion of phased tasks and a new starting point. In the coming time, the ultimate goal is to continue to complete the &quot;five-year service capacity formation&quot;, reach the mid-level county-level hospital capacity, and provide better basic medical and basic public health services to the local people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hardware facilities are the foundation , grassroots diagnosis and treatment must &quot;form service capabilities&quot;, and talents are very critical. How does Guangdong solve the dilemma of building a talent team for grassroots diagnosis and treatment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;After the hardware facilities are improved, if the relevant supporting systems still adhere to the rules and do not implement them in a timely manner Adjustment is likely to lead to a situation of &quot;only buildings but no talents&quot; and &quot;a good start but insufficient stamina&quot;, which deviates from the original intention of the provincial party committee and the provincial government to make great efforts to build a tight grassroots medical security network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To this end, the Provincial Health and Health Commission has issued corresponding support policies to &quot;support and give a ride&quot; to grassroots medical and health institutions to promote their accelerated formation of service capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Primary health and health talents are the main body of primary health care resources and the providers of basic medical and health services. The construction of primary health and health talents is important for improving the ability and quality of primary health care services. Quality is of great importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the three-year action plan (2018-2020) to strengthen the construction of grassroots health talents, we have also issued the &quot;Increase of Grassroots Health Talents in Guangdong Province&quot; &quot;Quality Improvement Implementation Plan&quot;, &quot;Guangdong Province&#39;s tertiary-level public hospitals and county-level public hospitals to carry out medical and health &quot;group-type&quot; close assistance action plan&quot;, &quot;Guangdong Province&#39;s 100 chief health experts&#39; grassroots plan implementation plan&quot;, etc., many measures At the same time, we have made every effort to strengthen the construction of grassroots medical and health talents, promote the reform of the incentive mechanism for training and use of doctors, and effectively improve the professional service capabilities of provincial grassroots health talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The number of outpatient clinics has increased year by year, and residents have high awareness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The &quot;One hundred chief health experts at the grassroots level&quot; has been implemented. How are the chief experts selected? ? What are the characteristics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>; The &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level&quot; is based on the actual needs of the grassroots. We will recruit 100 retired doctors from across the country who have senior professional titles and meet job requirements to serve as chief experts in the 47 upgraded central health centers in the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being hired, the chief expert serves as the subject leader of his unit. He is mainly responsible for guiding and improving medical staff in the diagnosis and treatment of common diseases and frequently-occurring diseases, preventive health care, rehabilitation and Capacity levels in chronic disease management, emergency response to critical conditions in specialist diseases, etc., to achieve the &quot;Three Ones&quot; - building a specialty specialty, developing more than one new business and new technology, and &quot;passing on, helping and leading&quot; to create a Specialist team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The provincial finance provides a subsidy of 200,000 yuan per person per year, every three years. The first round of the project was officially launched in December 2018, attracting more than 500 experts in the medical and health field from all over the country to actively sign up. After selecting the best from the best, the list of 100 first batch of chief experts was finally determined. Among these 100 chief experts, the average age is 62 years old and they have a total of 22 professional backgrounds in clinical disciplines. The ratio of retired experts inside and outside Guangdong Province is roughly 3:2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Just mentioned &quot; &quot;Three Ones&quot;, the first round of the plan has ended. What results have been achieved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;The chief expert assists the Central Health Center in carrying out specialist construction, and helps the Central Health Center establish and Improve relevant specialties, and at the same time, through training and guidance of grassroots medical staff, teach a group of medical staff for the central health center where they are located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Statistical results show that 65.2% of central health centers have established departments including obstetrics and gynecology, traditional Chinese medicine, pediatrics, general surgery, and gastroenterology with the help of chief experts. Internal medicine and other specialty specialties, among which central health centers that have established two or more special specialties account for 39.1%; more than half of the chief experts have developed one or more new technologies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On grassroots health In terms of the talent team, what changes has the chief expert brought to the hospital? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;The chief expert gave full play to the role of mentoring and guidance, and systematically conducted Professional technical training enables them to master advanced medical technologies and methods and improve their professional level and service capabilities. At the same time, the hospital is guided to formulate standardized operating procedures, optimize service processes, improve the efficiency and quality of diagnosis and treatment, and continuously improve the service capabilities of primary medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The average annual outpatient volume of 47 central health centers in Guangdong Province increased from 114,000 to 149,000 in three years, with an average annual growth rate of 9.3%. Affected by the COVID-19 epidemic, compared with 2019, the total number of visits to primary medical institutions in Guangdong Province decreased by 20.2% in 2020, while the average outpatient volume of the 47 central health centers participating in the project only dropped by 1.5%, fully demonstrating that the central health centers participating in the project The medical services provided by the hospital have been fully recognized by local residents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, the Langtang Central Health Center of Zijin County, Heyuan City is one of the project implementation units. With the support of the local health administration department, the Central Health Center selected a general surgery department , two retired doctors from the Orthopedic Surgery Department serve as chief experts. Under the leadership of the chief expert, the hospital&#39;s general surgery department has established a laparoscopic minimally invasive center, and the orthopedic surgery department has carried out third- and fourth-level surgeries such as femoral head replacement and hip replacement, effectively improving the hospital&#39;s service capabilities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The chief expert also proactively invited familiar professors and scholars to the institute to conduct academic lectures and exchange activities, providing opportunities to grasp the development prospects of the discipline, cutting-edge theory, advanced technology and professional experience, and promote While improving the level of primary diagnosis and treatment, the number of outpatient visits at the central health center has also increased significantly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Has the Provincial Health Commission conducted relevant surveys, such as how satisfied are residents in the area where the planned hospital is located? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;Our survey of patients at the grassroots level showed that residents’ sense of gain from medical treatment scored 88.9. 75.9% of the respondents stated that they were clearly aware that the local central health center has provided diagnosis and treatment services by chief experts, and 92.8% of patients expressed their preference to receive diagnosis and treatment from chief experts. The survey results show that the health centers participating in the project provide better medical and health services to patients and have high awareness among the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a66f76cb29.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Patients visiting the emergency department at the Central Health Center of Liuhuang Town, Fengshun County, Meizhou City, Guangdong Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Establishing an assessment system and carrying out professional construction are the focus of assessment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with the past, how is the new round of &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level plan&quot; different? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;First, accurately set up positions based on local realities. The new round of &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Working at the Grassroots Level&quot; actively absorbs the work experience of the previous round and continuously adjusts and improves the implementation plan. Regarding the position setting, each central health center will comprehensively consider the urgently needed majors, departments with weak foundations, and leaders in the units. Based on the actual situation such as the establishment of the teaching team, we put forward the professional requirements for the position of the chief expert of the unit, implement on-demand appointment and on-demand recruitment, and promote accurate matching and compatibility of personnel and positions in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Second, develop and improve the project management system to assist project implementation with informatization. Focusing on informatization assistance, we developed a project management system and adopted an informatization management model to achieve full-process integrated operations such as job setting, personnel registration, qualification review, interview announcement, agreement signing, personnel withdrawal, and subsidy calculation. At present, the use of the management system has basically reached expectations, and the results of project management efficiency, information electronics, and communication network have been initially demonstrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, strengthen communication and coordination and establish a good communication mechanism. In order to facilitate the efficient advancement of the project, a work communication group has been established to answer problems encountered during work as soon as possible. During the registration and qualification review stages, give full play to the role of coordination and consultation, and actively communicate and coordinate with experts and relevant health centers for specific positions, understand the specific situation of experts, introduce position information in detail, and provide a more accurate two-way selection between experts and health centers. match. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;New round of &quot; What is the progress in recruiting experts for the &quot;Grassroots Plan&quot; of &quot;One Hundred Chief Health Experts&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;According to statistics, 46 central health centers (Gaozhou Second People’s Hospital have Merged into Gaozhou Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital in 2021, the number has changed from 47 to 46) 100 positions are set up in 23 professional categories, and a total of 186 people&#39;s registration information was received. After review, 144 people entered the interview stage, and finally all 100 positions were admitted, with an admission rate of 100%. Among them, 73% have a bachelor&#39;s degree or above, 48% have senior professional titles, and 17 are first-round experts. On July 1, the chief expert arrived at his post to start work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hiring experts is a two-way street In what aspects will the chief expert be assessed during the selection process? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>;In order to better assess the effectiveness of the experts’ work, we did this at the beginning of the project After completing the baseline survey, we can comprehensively understand the quality of medical services in the hospitals and departments where the experts work, and provide a basis for decision-making in the next step of scientifically evaluating the effectiveness of expert performance and the overall effectiveness of the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, a reference indicator system and standards for project performance evaluation are established, and the chief expert&#39;s assistance in specialty construction, teaching medical staff, and new business expansion are the focus of the assessment. The satisfaction of patients and employing units with the chief expert will be promoted to promote scientific and standardized assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;New round of &quot; The &quot;Grassroots Plan with 100 Chief Health Experts&quot; will also last for three years. How will the National Health Commission ensure that the plan meets expectations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission:&lt;/strong>; We will strengthen supervision and guidance and guide all local units to follow the implementation plan and other requirements. Implement various tasks and requirements, do a good job in daily management and service of experts, and select some central health centers to carry out &quot;four no-two directs&quot; (no notification, no greeting, no listening to reports, no need to accompany reception, go straight to the grassroots, go straight to the On-site) field investigation to understand the work of the chief expert. At the same time, it guides each unit to do a good job in the annual assessment of experts, and implement expert protection and remuneration accordingly. It also conducts publicity work for outstanding chief experts and creates a good working atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Through the implementation of the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Go to the Grassroots Plan&quot; project, it not only meets the public&#39;s demand for medical resources, but also satisfies the grassroots doctors&#39; learning of appropriate medical technologies. It has effectively provided grassroots people with more convenient, high-quality and efficient health services, opened up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving people&#39;s health, and allowed grassroots people to enjoy high-quality medical services at their doorsteps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层：三年会带来什么改变？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259149]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层：“最希望留下技术”，乡镇也能看大病]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259147]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/23/3408881631.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 23/3408881631.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Central Health Center of Liantan Town, Yunan County, Yunfu City, Guangdong Province, Li Junming, chief expert of traditional Chinese medicine, is doing rehabilitation training for patients. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Jianzu has just filled out his application as chief health expert at the Central Health Center of Liantan Town, Yunan County, Yunfu City, Guangdong Province (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as Liantan Health Center&lt;/span>;) called. Yao Jiaxin, secretary of the party committee of Liantan Health Center, who has been on the clinical front line and has just retired, thinks Liu Jianzu is the best candidate. &quot;We should consider those who are too old. The one who has just retired is the best.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;61-year-old Liu Jianzu has just retired for a year. He was previously the director of general surgery at the hospital where he worked. After being introduced by his colleagues, he learned that hundreds of chief health experts in Guangdong Province were working at the grassroots level. project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Together with Yao Jiaxin, there is another Central Health Hospital that &quot;favored&quot; Liu Jianzu. However, when the hospital director called to &quot;recruit people&quot;, Liu Jianzu was already sitting in the office of Liantan Health Center drinking tea with Yao Jiaxin. &quot;The call came a few minutes late. I had just promised to come here, and it would be hard to be a good person if I regretted it.&quot; Liu Jianzu recalled to a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Retired famous doctors from other parts of the country were also &quot;robbed&quot;. In order to open up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving people&#39;s health and provide more convenient, high-quality and efficient health services, in 2018, Guangdong launched the &quot;100 Chief Health Experts to Go to the Grassroots Plan&quot; to recruit 100 retired doctors nationwide to serve as central The chief expert of the health center, this move is the first of its kind in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In February 2023, the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for the Grassroots Plan of One Hundred Chief Health Experts in Guangdong Province (2023-2025)&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Implementation Plan&quot;&lt;/span>;), launching a new round of implementation of the plan. The 2023 Guangdong Provincial Government Work Report also proposed to “deeply implement a new round of grassroots medical and health service capacity improvement plans to effectively increase medical resources in rural and underdeveloped areas.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Different from the group assistance provided by tertiary hospitals, chief health experts will directly work full-time in 47 central health centers in Guangdong Province to carry out the &quot;Three Ones&quot; - —Build a specialty specialty, develop more than one new business and new technology, and build a specialized team through mentoring and guidance, so as to alleviate conflicts such as insufficient talent and weak service capabilities in grassroots medical and health institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A 14-year-old left-behind child living in Fengan Town, Heyuan, Guangdong, a rural area in northern Guangdong, has become one of the beneficiaries of the above project. He suffered from flat feet. Due to foot problems and inconvenient transportation, it was difficult to go to Huizhou Hospital, 80 kilometers away, for medical treatment. Until the chief health expert came to the Central Health Center of Langtang Town, Zijin County, Heyuan City, 7 kilometers away from his home (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hereinafter referred to as Langtang Health Center&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The operation was very successful. Repeated treatment in other places like his may not have good results. Now we can treat him nearby and solve the problem.&quot; The chief surgeon, Chen Xiulun, a retired orthopedic expert from the Eighth Affiliated Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University, told Southern Weekend reporters. Chen Xiulun is the chief orthopedic expert selected by Lantang Health Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not only the real ability, but also the ability to speak Mandarin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Being selected by 47 primary health centers is the first step, but if you want to get To get the appointment letter from the chief health expert, you still need to go through an interview. The &quot;Implementation Plan&quot; stipulates that during the interview, relevant experts from tertiary hospitals in prefecture-level cities should be invited to evaluate the applicant&#39;s professional and technical level, and at the same time, full consideration will be given to the actual situation of the local language, culture, eating habits, customs and other customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Common technical issues include: how to perform an operation, what is the treatment plan for a certain disease, how to lead a surgical team for 1-2 years, etc. After the interview, the expert team will provide corresponding recommendations to the hospital. Different hospitals also have different priorities in selecting candidates. For example, Langtang Health Center and Liuhuang Health Center pay special attention to the laparoscopic and minimally invasive surgical capabilities of surgical experts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to medical technology, language, family, etc. are also the focus. &quot;It is not required to speak the local language, but Mandarin must be passable.&quot; Compared with the first round of the grassroots plan for chief health experts, the new round of plans has attracted a lot more experts from outside Guangdong Province, and Guangdong has Cantonese, Chaoshan, Hakka, etc. A surgical expert interviewed by the Liuhuang Town Central Health Center of Fengshun County, Meizhou City (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the Liuhuang Health Center&lt;/span>;), technical He was a good person, but his accent was too strong, and the Mandarin he spoke was difficult for even experts to understand, so he had to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Doctors are very practical, and interviews cannot make deans completely reassured. &quot;Recruiting experts is not recruiting college students. At this age, those who can do it will be good, and those who can&#39;t will just be incompetent.&quot; Central Health Center of Yangcun Town, Boluo County, Huizhou City (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Hereinafter referred to as Yangcun Health Center&lt;/span>;) Director Wu Kaifeng told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before signing an employment agreement, many health centers hope to see the experts’ true abilities first. Chen Weigao, the director of Langtang Health Center, specially asked Hu Yuhui, the chief surgical expert, to perform two surgeries. He also asked professionals to discuss with him the key points of common third- and fourth-level surgeries such as ureteral stones. After checking at all levels, he felt comfortable hiring them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Cracking the dilemma of &quot;the hospital has equipment, but no one knows how to use it&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;When primary health centers hire surgical experts, they insist on endoscopic and minimally invasive techniques because &quot;the hospital has equipment, but no one knows how to use it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not many people can use the equipment introduced during the expansion of Langtang Health Center. &quot;In our case, doctors who can&#39;t use laparoscopy are ordinary doctors, and those who can use laparoscopy are high-end doctors.&quot; Dean Chen Weigao told Southern Weekend reporters bluntly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hoping to hire experts in areas that are in short supply in hospitals is a common wish of many central health centers. For example, the Department of Orthopedics and Neurosurgery of Liantan Health Hospital previously had assistance experts from Yunfu and Zhaoqing, but there has always been a shortage of general surgery experts. Although it signed a contract with a tertiary hospital to provide assistance and solved the urgent need, two or three days of consultation per week still cannot meet the needs of the grassroots people. Needed, so this time a general surgery expert was specially hired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangdong Provincial Health Commission told Southern Weekend reporters that after the hardware facilities are improved, if the relevant supporting systems still stick to the old rules and do not make timely adjustments, it is likely that &quot;only building, no talent&quot; and &quot;a good start but insufficient stamina&quot;. In July 2023, chief surgical expert Ding Shengwen performed more than a dozen laparoscopic surgeries as soon as he came to Yangcun Health Center. From now on, local villagers will no longer have to go out for laparoscopic surgeries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The lack of a complete teaching staff is our biggest confusion at the grassroots level.&quot; Yao Jiaxin, secretary of the party committee of Liantan Health Center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the Air Force Hospital of the Southern Theater Command of his original unit, Lu Shuwen, the chief orthopedic specialist, performs operations as a team operation. He only needs to perform the most critical part of an operation. When he first came to Yangcun Health Center as the chief specialist, he personally performed every operation from disinfection to draping, teaching the management practices of large hospitals to the grassroots doctors in Yangcun Health Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The arrival of the chief expert can help grassroots hospitals continue to improve their standardization level. Wu Kaifeng, director of Yangcun Health Center, lamented that the chief expert demonstrated the management level of the higher-level hospital where he worked. During the period when the experts came to the health center, the appearance of the entire department has changed a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, under the advice of chief experts, grassroots hospitals also supplement relevant drugs according to diagnosis and treatment needs to better meet the needs of patients. Yan Xinzheng, chief physician of geriatrics, came to Liuhuang Health Center and found that some drugs were missing. With the support of the director, the hospital replenished more than 20 kinds of drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/f41522b8f2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/f41522b8f2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Central Health Center of Liuhuang Town, Fengshun County, Meizhou City, Guangdong Province is one of the 47 central health centers upgraded and constructed in Guangdong Province. The newly completed campus building It covers an area of ​​25,771 square meters and is equipped with 250 beds. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Let experts identify with the hospital culture with heart and emotion”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Relate to the hospital where retired famous doctors used to work There is indeed a big gap in the new working environment, and leaving your family in an unfamiliar place will inevitably make you feel uncomfortable. How to retain people is a problem faced by many health centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The salary that primary health centers can provide to chief experts is not high, but everyone is trying their best to work hard. For example, they provide delicious food and a clean and comfortable living environment. Some health centers are even more meticulous - they are exposed to the sun in summer, reserve a separate indoor parking lot for experts, and arrange dedicated personnel to help experts familiarize themselves with the information management system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Preserve people first and save their stomachs first. There is no canteen in Liuhuang Health Center, so we specially hired chefs to cook for the experts, including local dishes and dishes from the experts’ hometowns. After get off work, colleagues in the hospital will also invite experts to their homes for dinner, so that they can feel the respect of the staff and the family atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For many chief experts, whether the dean is a &quot;doer&quot; is one of the important reasons for choosing to come to the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Kaifeng, director of Yangcun Health Center, believes that to retain experts, you must first know what the other party wants. The wish of surgical experts is to continue their craftsmanship and pass on the technology. . Therefore, the hospital handed over the surgical team to chief surgical expert Ding Shengwen to lead him, making him feel that his work was meaningful and that leading a discipline would give him a sense of accomplishment. &quot;In order for experts to have cultural identification with the hospital, it is necessary to create a cultural atmosphere in which disciplines are well developed, employees are well developed, and patients are considered.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Weekend The reporter learned that many retired experts gave up their salaries of well over 200,000 yuan and came to some health centers in Guangdong to apply for chief experts. &lt;p>; Worried that &quot;as a surgeon, if I continue to be idle like this, it will be wasted&quot;, I saw the recruitment news in Guangdong and filled out the application form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Fengyun, who previously worked in Sichuan, lamented that &quot;Hakka is more difficult than English.&quot; In order to overcome the language barrier, Liuhuang Health Center assigned a local doctor as an interpreter. , working with Zhang Fengyun on medical consultations and ward rounds, and learning knowledge while doing a good job of translating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;An expert hired by Lantang Health Center who is capable of minimally invasive surgery, laparoscopy and management has to postpone his working hours at the hospital due to personal reasons. Chen Weigao For fear of something unexpected happening, I took turns calling experts with the vice president and the hospital office. It was not until I changed my practice to Langtang Health Center and finalized the time of joining that I finally felt relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The service period of the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Under Grassroots Plan&quot; is three years. The hospital can sign a one-year agreement with the experts or sign a one-time three-year agreement with the experts based on actual conditions. Each hospital has its own considerations. For example, Liuhuang Health Center chose a one-year contract to leave room for both parties and &quot;don&#39;t tie everyone up&quot;; while Langtang Health Center directly signed a three-year contract in order to retain experts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Guangdong Provincial Health Commission told Southern Weekend reporters that in the new round of &quot;100 chief health experts working at the grassroots level&quot;, a total of 186 people submitted registration information. After review, , 144 people entered the interview process, and finally completed the recruitment process for all 100 positions, with an admission rate of 100%. On July 1, 2023, the chief expert has arrived to start work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/97d2c32be2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/97d2c32be2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Patients queuing up to get medicine at the Central Health Center of Liantan Town, Yunan County, Yunfu City, Guangdong Province. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;From 3 minutes to 20 minutes, use services to retain patients&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even for experts, it is not easy to gain the trust of patients immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the first day that Li Junming, the chief expert of traditional Chinese medicine, came to Liantan Health Center, he only saw three or four patients in the outpatient clinic, including hospital employees who came here because of their reputation. In the hospital where he originally worked, he could see more than 30 patients in half a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the grassroots level, patients are generally older and have relatively weak awareness of medical treatment. When they feel unwell and go to see a doctor, they often miss the best time for treatment. &quot;The patient had severe stomach pain, and it looked like he was in an advanced stage. Others saw that the hospital couldn&#39;t cure this disease, and they would never come back to the hospital in the future.&quot; Ding Shengwen told Southern Weekend reporters that he often encounters surgeries for late-stage intestinal cancer, obstruction, and perforation. There are fewer diseases in the early and middle stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This also indirectly affects patients&#39; trust in primary hospitals. Zhang Fengyun once met a patient who did not believe in the anesthesia capabilities of Liuhuang Health Center and asked to be transferred to Meizhou City Hospital for surgery. The same plan was ultimately adopted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Yao Jiaxin’s view, the biggest advantage of the Central Health Center is its service. He hopes that the doctors in his hospital will have a good service attitude, especially in a society of acquaintances such as villages and towns, where 300,000 people spread the word by word of mouth, and the social benefits of attentive service cannot be underestimated. Technology comes second. As long as the patient stays, the doctor can consult experts or invite experts to perform surgery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are many patients in large hospitals, so the treatment time is naturally less. Yan Xinzheng found that the treatment time for a patient in his original unit was only about 3 minutes, but at Liuhuang Health Hospital Hospital, can spend 15-20 minutes on a patient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Especially if the patient is an elderly person with underlying diseases, many historical problems must be solved in one visit, and many rural elderly people are not aware of their own diseases. I don’t know. I have poor health awareness. I need the doctor to ask more questions. Zhang Fengyun once asked a patient if he had high blood pressure. The patient said no, but when he tested it, his blood pressure was extremely high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, each central health center has a population of 300,000 to 500,000. “If people from the surrounding area can go directly to the central health center for medical treatment, they don’t have to go to Yunfu, In Huizhou, you can save two to three hundred on the fare.&quot; Chen Weigao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Chen Weigao&#39;s preliminary statistics, after the introduction of experts, the outpatient volume, hospitalization volume, and surgical volume of Langtang Health Center increased by more than 30%. The average outpatient volume of Liuhuang Health Center in July and August 2023 was 6,000, which was nearly 1,300 more than the average outpatient volume from January to June, and an increase of 50% compared to the same period in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c130c1b752.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c130c1b752.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chief experts Yan Xinzheng and Liu Jiang hired by the Central Health Center of Liuhuang Town, Fengshun County, Meizhou City, Guangdong Province, led the hospital&#39;s young doctors to conduct ward rounds and inquire about the patients&#39; recovery status. (Southern Weekend reporter Song Bingchen/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I hope experts will leave the technology to us. This is the cost of food.”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hospital still has You have never practiced orthopedics, will you be able to work smoothly here?&quot; When Chen Xiulun, the chief orthopedic specialist hired by Langtang Health Center, first came to the hospital, the director was still a little hesitant. &quot;Orthopedic patients account for more than 40% of surgical patients. Precisely because it has not been developed, the market is huge and the future is bright.&quot; Chen Xiulun is very confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first orthopedic equipment was even brought by Chen Xiulun himself, and other equipment was purchased later. Facts have proved Chen Xiulun’s judgment. After the establishment of the Department of Orthopedics, there has never been a shortage of patients. Other doctors also referred patients with orthopedics-related diseases to Chen Xiulun. Patients who had been missed or transferred before stayed in the hospital, and the referral rate increased from the past. of 100% dropped to 30%-40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is what the &quot;Hundred Chief Health Experts Go to the Grassroots Plan&quot; most hopes to see - to build a specialty specialty and develop more than one new business and new Technology, &quot;pass, help and lead&quot; to create a professional team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Jianping, a professor at Guangzhou Medical University, is one of the first batch of grassroots experts. After retirement, he built a rehabilitation department in Liantan Health Center as a &quot;second venture&quot;. When he first joined the job, the hospital lacked equipment and could only spend 300,000 yuan for Chen Jianping to buy consumables. He made simple rehabilitation consumables by himself. Today, the Rehabilitation Department of Liantan Health Center is able to carry out 58 items of 6 categories of appropriate traditional Chinese medicine rehabilitation techniques, and the annual number of rehabilitation treatment patients has increased from about 10,000 in 2017 to 40,000 in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We most hope that the experts will leave their skills to us. This is the cost of eating.&quot; Compared with outpatient visits, Ye Bizhen, Secretary of Liuhuang Health Center He told Southern Weekend reporters that in the final analysis, the hospital still wants to obtain the expertise of experts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Statistical results from the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission show that after the first batch of plans, 65.2% of central health centers established services including gynecology and gynecology with the help of chief experts. Obstetrics, traditional Chinese medicine, pediatrics, general surgery, gastroenterology and other specialties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zeng Zhongbo, a cardiovascular medicine expert hired by Lantang Health Center, previously practiced at Huizhou First People&#39;s Hospital, which is only more than an hour&#39;s drive from Lantang Health Center. The hospital thought that his patient base was good, and many residents from the town made a special trip to Huizhou to see him. It is hoped that he can guide the management of hypertension and diabetes, bring new technologies and treatments, and add a special specialty on cardiovascular disease in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Fengyun described his idea to Southern Weekend reporters: in the first three months, doctors will be familiar with breast surgery, and in the next three months, they can start simple breast surgery. Suturing, and after half a year of further training, we strive to gradually separate the breast department from surgery. Only with professionalism can patients trust me. &quot;Breast surgery costs less and does not require complex equipment, so it is very suitable as a new specialty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Doctors are a profession that is always learning. Yan Xinzheng found that grassroots doctors usually accumulated experience in consultation and lacked systematic theoretical training. He planned to organize common diseases in rural areas, such as hypertension and diabetes, into several 30-minute mini-lessons to train young doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Shengwen hopes to slowly transplant the work style of large hospitals to Yangcun Health Center. He requires doctors to come to the hospital half an hour early one day a week and brings training materials from the original unit to the doctors. Lecture, &quot;Young people are good at editing surgical videos and looking up information, but they need a little push to form a habit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百位名医下基层]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>; Hundreds of retired famous doctors in Guangdong have worked at the grassroots level, and nearly half have senior professional titles. With skillful hands and kind hearts, we bridge the “last mile” of diagnosis and treatment.</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[揭秘杭州亚残运会开幕式背后的“大脑总动员”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259161]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;The sweet-scented osmanthus is blooming, come on, come to Hangzhou!&quot; On the bank of the Qiantang River on an autumn night, Hangzhou Olympic Sports The central stadium became a stage where golden osmanthus bloomed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony of the 4th Asian Paralympic Games in Hangzhou on the evening of the 22nd, the last torchbearer used an intelligent bionic hand controlled by the brain to hold the torch &quot;laurel crown&quot; high to pay tribute to the audience. Light the main torch. When technology and dreams meet, all the impossible will become possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/77778ecca21227f5f10525d7e580640c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/77778ecca21227f5f10525d7e580640c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255028&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, lit the main torch at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony of the Asian Para Games continued the cultural confidence, scientific and technological warmth and touching emotions of the opening and closing ceremonies of the Asian Games, showing the spirit of &quot;sunshine, harmony, self-improvement and sharing&quot;. &quot;The way to light the main torch at the opening ceremony of the Asian Para Games is a combination of technology and temperature.&quot; Sha Xiaolan, chief director of the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games, said in the &quot;Spoiler&quot; that technology makes up for the shortcomings of the body and strengthens the body. The belief in chasing dreams gives athletes a dazzling sense of the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the dazzling sense of the future is a &quot;brain mobilization&quot; based on brain-computer interface technology. &quot;Whatever action the brain wants to make, the bionic hand will perform that action.&quot; Sitting in his office in the Artificial Intelligence Town in the west of Hangzhou, Han Bicheng, founder of Zhejiang Qiannao Technology Co., Ltd., slowly revealed the mystery behind the smart bionic hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;post-85s&quot; PhD from Harvard University, who has long been immersed in exploring the mysteries of the human brain, explained that this type of rehabilitation assistive device that combines non-invasive brain-computer interface technology and artificial intelligence algorithms collects and processes the human body&#39;s The electromyoelectric and neuroelectrical signals generated by movement identify the user&#39;s movement intentions and simulate the bionic neuromuscular control pathways of the human hand to achieve movement control and meet the needs of common gestures in people&#39;s lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4ff22a3516fc62ed0c7a12617573cac8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;992&quot; height= &quot;1024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4ff22a3516fc62ed0c7a12617573cac8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Zongzhi&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the core technical problems that need to be solved in the development of intelligent bionic hands? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Data collection.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Bicheng admitted that the human brain is called the &quot;three-pound universe&quot; and contains about 100 billion neurons, and the bioelectrical signals are very weak. This makes it difficult to understand the internal conditions of the human body through the skin, such as information attenuation and noise aliasing, making it difficult to capture and collect information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Bicheng said that this is like trying to collect the sound of a mosquito flapping its wings at Beijing Capital International Airport in Hangzhou and analyze its flight conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2015 when more than a dozen people worked hard on key problems in the Harvard University laboratory to now setting up offices in Hangzhou, Shenzhen, and Boston to research brain-computer interface technology technology companies, Han Bicheng has always led his team to take the lead in technology. On the road to innovation and application expansion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5c8f2d48399a74a6ecd29ef36d739842.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height= &quot;1020&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5c8f2d48399a74a6ecd29ef36d739842.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255029&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Jiang Han&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games was not the first time that smart prosthetics appeared in the public eye. At the Beijing Winter Paralympics, disabled swimmer Jia Hongguang wore a smart bionic hand to complete the torch relay. Not long ago, on the shores of Qiandao Lake, archery athlete Ye Jinyan, the torchbearer of the Asian Paralympic Games, completed the torch relay with a smart bionic leg painted in deep space gray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we explore the &quot;Three Pound Universe&quot; in depth, how far are we from the world presented in mainstream science fiction films? Han Bicheng responded that 70% to 80% of the effects in mainstream science fiction films can be achieved with the help of brain-computer interfaces. He believes that in the not-too-distant future, &quot;following your heart&quot; will be &quot;at your fingertips.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the wall opposite Han Bicheng&#39;s desk, there is a portrait of Einstein, in which the &quot;most powerful brain&quot; shows a mysterious smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 18:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[豪宅152处，公司数十家，“奢侈品巨量” 谁在新加坡“洗”148亿元？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259123]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Haijin, who usually loves to show off his wealth and travels in a high profile, finally played &quot;out of the blue&quot; Circled.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of August 15, 2023, after hearing the call of his eldest son, Su Haijin jumped from the balcony on the second floor and fell into the backyard of the villa. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Eight Singaporean law enforcement officers found him beside the drain behind the villa. In the photos released by the Singapore police, Su Haijin was only wearing short-sleeved shorts and bare feet. The leg was also broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Haijin, whose ancestral home is Anxi, Fujian, settled in Singapore in 2017. &quot;He is not tall, speaks with a Hokkien accent, lives in a mansion in Bukit Timah, and is picked up and dropped off by a Rolls-Royce.&quot; described the author of &quot;Singapore Eyes&quot; who has met Su Haijin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singapore court records show that Su Haijin and Wu Qin married in 2019. At first, the family lived in the Gramercy Residence duplex near Orchard Road, and soon rented a villa at Yoho Gardens in Bukit Timah, Singapore. The latter’s monthly rent is as high as 80,000 Singapore dollars (equivalent to over 400,000 yuan in RMB). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This villa is surrounded by green trees, and few people can see the home from the outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;His villa is like a recreation room, with a mini golf course in the courtyard and a karaoke OK in the basement.&quot; An insider told Singapore&#39;s Lianhe Zaobao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Haijin behaves like a boss. In recent years, he has done a lot of &quot;business&quot; in Xiamen, China and Cambodia. Su Haijin is also a member of Sentosa Golf Club in Singapore. Active Golf Services, a golf membership service agency, revealed that Sentosa Golf Club is the most expensive golf club in Singapore, with foreign membership fees as high as S$1 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Haijin’s luxurious life was suspended on August 15. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On this day, more than 400 Singapore police officers also arrested 9 other foreigners, including Su Baolin (41 years old), Su Jianfeng (35 years old), Zhang Ruijin (44 years old), Lin Baoying (43 years old), Wang Shuiming (42 years old), Chen Qingyuan (33 years old), Su Wenqiang (31 years old), Wang Baosen (31 years old) and Wang Dehai (34 years old). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They are accused of money laundering, fraud, online gambling and forgery of documents, etc. They may be relatives, lovers, or partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Singapore’s Minister of Home Affairs and Law Shanmugam said in an interview that “this is one of the largest anti-money laundering operations in Singapore.” According to statistics from the Singapore police, the 10 suspects involved in the case amounted to SGD 2.8 billion (equivalent to RMB 14.8 billion). &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of press time, the Singaporean court has not yet accepted the bail request of any suspect due to concerns about the suspect&#39;s absconding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The place where the suspect in the money laundering case was arrested&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/52eaa57e8d.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1156&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/52eaa57e8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254954&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The location where the suspect in the money laundering case was arrested&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Money Laundering Case&quot; puzzle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;The Singapore police have been preparing for nearly three years to arrest 10 suspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Some documents for forging bank account amounts, suspicious financial reports, etc. were first discovered, and (the Singapore government) launched investigations one by one.&quot; October 3, 2023 On the same day, Singapore’s Minister of Communications and Information and Second Minister of Home Affairs Yang Liming said in Parliament. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Suspicious financial reports come from the suspect&#39;s corporate transactions, bank deposits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After moving to Singapore in 2017, Su Haijin spent money like water, buying a house, a yacht, and starting a company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/dec5d214d5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/dec5d214d5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A single-family house on Orchard Road, Singapore. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lou Xiaoxi/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters inquired about Singapore Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority (ACRA) documents and found that Su Haijin has successively served as CEO of Aihai Investment, Daily Glory International, Yihao Network Technology, Meining (Asia) International E-Commerce and SG-Gree in Singapore. A director or shareholder of a company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Singapore&#39;s &quot;Business Times&quot; report, Su Haijin bought two sea-view single-family villas in Cove Drive, Sentosa Island, for S$36.4 million in 2021. , combine them into one building (to avoid the restriction on foreigners owning multiple suites on Sentosa Island). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Also in 2021, the Singapore police detected some suspicious financial activities, such as providing forged documents to banks. In early 2022, the Singapore police launched a comprehensive investigation and targeted a group of related people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, the Singapore police will only send a small group of investigators to investigate, so as not to alert the enemy. &quot;If the suspect is aware of it, he may abscond with the money, and the investigation will be in vain.&quot; Yang Liming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was not until early 2023 that the Singapore Attorney General&#39;s Office assessed that the police had sufficient information and had sufficient reason to suspect that this group of people was suspected of engaging in criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So on August 15, the Singapore police dispatched 400 police officers to launch an island-wide arrest operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Police believe that 41-year-old Su Baolin and Su Haijin are brothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Baolin and Su Haijin are both from Anxi, Fujian, and they have close financial ties. An investigation by the Singapore police found that the two properties on Beach Road under Su Haijin&#39;s name were purchased by Su Baolin in 2021, with a total price of approximately S$2.285 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Baolin is also a high-net-worth individual recognized by Singapore real estate website 99.co. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Su Baolin, Su Haijin and two other people jointly purchased a yacht with a total price of SGD 5.45 million. The yacht is named &quot;Family&quot;, has a total length of 38 meters, can carry 10 passengers, and flies the flag of the South Pacific country Cook Islands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In early September, a Singaporean court stated that the Family yacht had left Singapore and was currently in Phuket, Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8ab322f176.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8ab322f176.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023, Sentosa Cove Marina in the eastern part of Sentosa Island, Singapore. The yacht purchased by Su Haijin and Su Baolin had already left Singapore after the money laundering incident. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lou Xiaoxi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the two men’s lawyers denied the police’s kinship accusations . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Southern Weekend reporters discovered that Su Haijin and Su Baolin have close business ties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Baolin is also a shareholder and director of Su Haijin-related companies Meining (Asia) International E-Commerce and SG-Gree. He is also a shareholder of Xinbao Investment Holdings, Xinjiamei Investment Company and Sentosa Project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of press time, the money laundering case is still under investigation, and new evidence is still emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After another suspect Su Jianfeng (35 years old) was arrested, the police discovered that he had a total of S$17 million in cash while investigating three insurance institutions. But when the money laundering case was brought to court on October 18, Su Jianfeng changed his story and claimed that the S$17 million was kept for others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Opening a company is the first way to launder money&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;10 The financial gains obtained by the suspects through illegal online gambling and Internet fraud are &#39;black money&#39;, and the act of hiding and disguising the source of illegal funds and making the black money appear to be legal is money laundering.&quot; Yan Yan, director of the China Anti-Money Laundering Center at Fudan University Lixin explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/428c19b966.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2469&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/428c19b966.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Opening a company is the first way for suspects to launder money. In Singapore, 10 suspects have successively opened investment companies, technology companies, construction contracting companies, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Haijin and Su Baolin jointly serve as senior executives of nearly 20 companies. However, most companies are shell companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters compiled industrial and commercial records and found that three of them are still in operation. The registered addresses of these three companies are all #15, Suntec City One, Temasek Avenue, Singapore. -02. There is no trace of the registration places of the other 11 companies, and the other six are located in private residences with restricted access. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Jianfeng admitted during the confession that he did not know the address of the company An Xing Technology under his name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Singapore, foreigners frequently open companies and have also cultivated a group of &quot;nominal persons&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The threshold for foreigners to open a company alone in Singapore is relatively high.&quot; Wang Jian, director of Singapore DMC Consulting Company, explained to Southern Weekend reporters that without an Entrepreneurship Pass (Enter When a foreigner holding a business license opens a company, he or she must have a Singaporean or Singapore permanent resident as a director or secretary of the company. &quot;Currently, Singapore has no restrictions on the number of locals who can serve as nominee directors and legal secretaries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the records of the Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority, there are 20 &quot;nominee persons&quot; &quot;It&#39;s related to the suspect&#39;s company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These &quot;nominee persons&quot; serve as secretaries, shareholders, and directors of hundreds of companies continuously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;They asked me to invest and take care of their company. But I never got a penny and I don&#39;t have any shares.&quot; A 41-year-old Singaporean originally from Shanghai Wang Yuan told The Straits Times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some money laundering gangs will also &quot;tempt&quot; regular companies to &quot;act as shells&quot; to launder money on their behalf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yue Siqiu, a native of Sanming, Fujian, has been doing business in Singapore for 10 years. She has come into contact with money launderers in Singapore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The other party wants to hire a member of their team in my company, and then use my company to buy a house. They will pay for the house purchase and give me 10 % remuneration.&quot; Yue Siqiu told Southern Weekend reporters that the other party targeted her company just because the company&#39;s accounts were clean and the bank would not suspect it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yue Siqiu rejected the money launderer, but was harassed for a long time. &quot;Because of the generous rewards, some Chinese businesses on Orchard Road will agree to these people&#39;s requests,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 10 suspects hold a large amount of assets in their names. As of October 3, the Singapore police had issued prohibition orders on as many as 152 real estate properties. The prohibited properties belong to the suspects, their spouses or their companies, including 7 single-family bungalows in Sentosa Cove, 79 apartments (19 of which are still under construction) and 19 pieces of commercial land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It can be said that there are as many ways to launder money as there are ways to make money.&quot; Yan Lixin told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies Currency, gold, jewelry, precious metals, luxury goods, collectibles, etc. are often used as tools for money laundering because of their small size, high value, easy portability or transportation, and easy liquidation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;In recent years, many real estate professionals have come into contact with &quot;tycoons&quot; who spend a lot of money. Singaporean real estate agent Tian Xin confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that he has sold high-end apartments and single-family houses to Fujian residents in Singapore. &quot;Some rich people with a southern Fujian accent can buy two or three houses from me at once.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As long as there is a team of accountants and lawyers to do a good job in bookkeeping, the money laundering behavior of real estate can be concealed. &quot;If you encounter a bank asking about the source of funds, as long as the fake accounts are done perfectly, you can be deceived.&quot; A real estate agent told Singapore&#39;s Lianhe Zaobao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the luxury goods seized by the Singapore police from the suspect&#39;s house, there are many luxury cars, watches, famous paintings and trendy building blocks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, a Mercedes-Benz AMG luxury car priced at SGD 500,000; a Patek Philippe platinum astronomical tourbillon watch worth SGD 8 million; multiple bottles of 30 Years of Maotai and 100 bottles of Macallan whiskey...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Making money in Cambodia, living in Singapore? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend reporters sorted out the information of the 10 suspects and found that most of them are from Anxi County, Fujian Province, and spent their early years in the Philippines, Cambodia and other countries. Open an online gambling park and engage in online fraud business. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of their &quot;black money&quot; is obtained through illegal online gambling and Internet fraud in countries such as Cambodia and the Philippines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, they forged documents and transferred their illegal gains into Singapore through banks in Singapore, where they purchased and rented multiple luxury properties, luxury cars and luxury goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;42-year-old Wang Shuiming is the suspect with the highest total assets in the money laundering case. He was accused of forging documents, possessing illegal loan proceeds, etc. He holds passports from Turkey, China and Vanuatu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Singapore court revealed that Wang Shuiming’s assets in Singapore exceed S$200 million, while his assets in other countries are about S$35.5 million, of which Cambodia’s assets are as high as S$24.53 million. SGD. Ong Shui Ming owns 11 apartments in Singapore, ten of which are located in Canninghill Piers, which faces the mountains and the sea, and the other is a Park Nova apartment on Thomson Road, Orchard Road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/d9f6d933d6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/d9f6d933d6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Park Nova Apartment at Tong Lin Sang Road, Orchard Road. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lou Xiaoxi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Cambodian government records, Wang Shuiming, Su Baolin, Su Jianfeng and The four of them, Su Wenqiang, obtained citizenship in 2019. The other five people all became Cambodian citizens between August 2018 and March 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While they obtained their status, they lived in Singapore most of the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The suspects became Cambodian citizens one after another, and other Chinese people were naturalized at the same time. Most of these people were the &#39;heads behind the scenes&#39; of Cambodian online gambling companies. ” believes the nonprofit Internet Fraud Watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters asked many Chinese people living in Cambodia. Many of them could recognize Su Baolin and Su Haijin, and some people had &quot;dealt with&quot; Wang Shuiming. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Wang Shuiming is a well-known Fujianese in Cambodia&#39;s online gambling circle. More than 90% of Chinese people in Cambodia know him.&quot; Lu Zeyuan, who lives in Cambodia, told Southern Weekend reporter also called Wang Shuiming a &quot;character&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ten years ago, Wang Shuiming started his business by relying on gambling websites in the Philippines. He was one of the first batch of Fujianese to open online gambling in the Philippines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At its peak, Wang Shuiming had 10,000 employees. After accumulating funds in the Philippines, Wang Shuiming went to Cambodia to expand online gambling business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cambodian Chinese media person Lin Xiao told Southern Weekend reporters that Wang Shuiming entered the online gambling industry early. The fund disk &quot;Dafa System&quot; developed by their team is used by online gambling companies in Cambodia, Myanmar, Dubai and other places. This system is &quot;relatively fair and will not &#39;kill pigs&#39; easily.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally, online gambling companies regard participating online gamblers as &quot;pigs&quot;. When gamblers recharge in large amounts, the company&#39;s backend will be locked Gamblers&#39; account funds are cut off from them to achieve the purpose of &quot;killing pigs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the industrial and commercial information of Cambodia and Singapore and found that Wang Shuiming is the chairman of Cambodia’s Daming IT Services Company and is also an outstanding figure in Singapore. Director and shareholder of Zhuo Chi Technology. The above-mentioned companies all claim to be “mainly engaged in software development”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Shuiming is also one of the eight directors of Cambodian SCWD Construction Company. The company was registered in 2016. The company letters correspond to the directors’ surnames: Su, Chen, Wang, Deng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Dehai, another suspect in this money laundering case, is also one of the eight directors of SCWD Construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 15, Wang Dehai was arrested at an apartment near Paterson Hill on Orchard Road and charged with money laundering. Singapore police found more than S$2.2 million in cash, 35 luxury watches, 51 pieces of jewelry and several designer bags in his apartment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lv Zeyuan has lived in Cambodia for nearly ten years. He told Southern Weekend reporters that after the Internet fraud business became big, the bosses behind the scenes set up offices in the Philippines, Malaysia, and Thailand. Companies, some &quot;big bosses&quot; even have private jets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These people ultimately prefer to go to Singapore to change their lives.&quot; Lu Zeyuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the online gambling boss living in Singapore will not stop his online fraud business in Southeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These online gambling company owners will manage the company&#39;s affairs remotely. They may fly to Cambodia two or three times a year and only deal with major matters. Small matters will be left to the general manager of the park.&quot; Lin. Xiao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Almost the entire village is in Singapore”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Fujian Gang in Singapore was also exposed with the money laundering case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Hokkien gang in Singapore ranges from dozens to hundreds. Among them, gangs are divided according to their surnames. Su, Wang, Hu and Chen are the major ones. The main gang,&quot; an anonymous real estate agent told Singapore&#39;s Lianhe Zaobao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Su Haijin and another suspect Wang Dehai are considered to be the bosses of two gangs surnamed Su and Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Singapore’s Fujian Gang has always been generous. &quot;They usually live a high-profile life, driving Lamborghinis, Ferraris, etc., and when they go to high-end nightclubs to spend money, they are accompanied by Chinese girls.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fujian gangs attach great importance to geography and clan. Guanxi, prefer small circle culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A friend of Lin Xiao lives in the same village as Wang Shuiming. &quot;They have a small circle culture. He helps Wang Shuiming act as an agent (for fraud). They will make a list themselves.&quot; , the villagers play by themselves.&quot; Lin Xiao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of September 2023, Su Haijin’s defense lawyer Zheng Huilong stated in court that Su Haijin’s four children, his parents, father-in-law and mother-in-law, and even several Brothers, sisters and relatives are all in Singapore. &quot;Almost their entire village is in Singapore.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Fujian Gang likes to find outstanding young men as lobbyists and invite local Chinese to meet and discuss cooperation.&quot; Liu Yanan, a Chinese from Singapore, told Southern Weekend reporters that he was The lobbyist invited me several times, &quot;but I didn&#39;t agree.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Singapore government has adopted a &quot;zero tolerance&quot; attitude towards this money laundering case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In mid-September, Singapore’s Minister of Home Affairs and Law Shanmugam said in an interview with Singapore’s Lianhe Zaobao that anyone who does anything illegal in Singapore, or If you do illegal business overseas and try to launder money in Singapore, they will take action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, when Wang Shuiming appeared in court for the third time, a Singaporean judge rejected him on the grounds that he &quot;may abscond&quot; and &quot;collude with other suspects.&quot; bail application. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Shuiming and many other suspects in money laundering cases have criminal records in China and are fugitives in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In May 2022, the Public Security Bureau of Boshan District, Zibo City, Shandong Province cracked a &quot;Hengbo Bao.com Gambling Case&quot; and arrested criminal suspects of opening gambling websites and making illegal profits. 131 people were arrested, and more than 10 million yuan of funds involved in the case were recovered. Wang Shuiming is the most wanted person recorded by the Boshan District Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are still nine people involved in the above cases who are illegally staying abroad. Except for Wang Shuiming, the other eight people are all from Anxi County, Fujian, and most of them have the surname Wang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Dehai, the leader of the Fujian gang surnamed Wang, was wanted by the Guiyang County Public Security Bureau in Hunan Province at the B level in 2018 for being suspected of an online gambling case. Also wanted at the same time were Su Jianfeng and Su Wenqiang in this money laundering case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Singapore court investigation found that Wang Dehai joined a gambling company from the Philippines in 2012 and gradually expanded the business from customer service to promotion. Currently, the gambling website where Wang Dehai worked before is still in operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5177e81064.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/5177e81064.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Marq on Paterson Hill condominium on Orchard Road. The place where money laundering suspect Wang Dehai was arrested. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lou Xiaoxi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The ten suspects belong to a larger criminal group, and they are inextricably linked to each other. Contact.&quot; In September 2023, the Singapore Police Commercial Affairs Department (CAD), which is responsible for money laundering cases, admitted in a court affidavit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Singapore police have not discovered any business connections between Wang Baosen and the other nine suspects. However, Wang Baosen’s name has long been associated with Southeast Asian fraud gangs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the judgment document website and found that as early as 2013, Wang Baosen joined the Philippine &quot;Hongli International&quot; online gambling website established by Wang Bin, a native of Anxi, Fujian. , responsible for financial work. 2014年网站团队迁入柬埔寨边境城市巴域（越南称木排），随后王宝森逐渐负责鸿利国际网站的全面管理工作，底薪为1万元人民币，另有奖金提成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;该网站涉赌资金高达9.8亿元人民币。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了被指控的10名嫌疑人，目前还有多人正协助新加坡警方调查，包括企业服务提供商、房地产经纪和金融机构等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月28日，新加坡律政部向宝石和贵金属经销商发出的一份34人审查名单中，王宝森的妻子何惠芳、“鸿利国际”网站创始人王斌刚赫然在列。该审查名单旨在提醒宝石经销商及时通报可疑交易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;案件不断发酵，9月初新加坡法庭宣誓书显示，王宝森一位表兄弟的1亿资金被冻结，此人已逃出新加坡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为了在他国生活，嫌疑人多持有多国护照。新加坡法庭10月18日揭露，唯一一名女性嫌疑人林宝英曾分别支付13万美元和16万美元，购买了多米尼克和柬埔寨的护照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“小国家护照可以通过移民中介买到，并不难获得。”新加坡DMC咨询公司董事王俭告诉南方周末记者，洗钱案曝光后，新加坡就推出了一个政策，凡是拿着小国护照的中国人很难在银行开户、开设公司。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“除非这些人可以出具放弃原籍证明。”王俭说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至发稿日，10名嫌疑人仍在寻求法院保释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;新加坡法律规定，犯有洗钱罪的人可被判处最高10年监禁、最高50万新元的罚款，或两者并罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尚穆根坦言，10名洗钱案被告一旦治罪，将在新加坡服刑，服完刑期后遣送回他所持护照的国家，或被送回跟新加坡有引渡协议的国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而中国与新加坡没有引渡协议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中王源、刘亚南、林啸、吕泽源、田鑫、岳思秋为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[致3死17伤的弥勒坠梯事故被提级调查，当地称伤者状态趋稳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259119]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月18日，云南省弥勒市佛城商都发生电梯坠落事故。截至目前，共造成3人死亡，4人重伤、13人轻伤。 23日，云南省人民政府办公室工作人员告诉南都记者，该事故已被提级调查，由云南省市场监督管理局负责。该工作人员还称，当前伤者状态趋于稳定。云南省市监局工作人员表示已派人前往事发地进行调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/04f086e7662ba541a8337c36e6aca659.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/04f086e7662ba541a8337c36e6aca659.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;事故现场。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故现场视频显示，事故现场有救护车、消防车等，医生、消防员在一栋楼下搬运担架，多名市民在现场围观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18日，据弥勒市政府新闻办发布通告，当天12时许，弥勒市佛城商都发生电梯坠落。弥勒市立即组织力量全力救治伤员，截至目前，共造成3人死亡，4人重伤、13人轻伤。坠落原因调查等工作正在紧张开展中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23日，南都记者从云南省人民政府获知，该事故已被提级调查，由云南省市场监督管理局负责。云南省市监局表示已派工作人员前往事发地，调查工作正在开展。此外，云南省人民政府办公室工作人员告诉南都记者，当前伤者状态趋于稳定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都此前报道，19日，佛城商都的两位商户告诉南都记者，事故电梯于2015年投入使用，为货梯，主要用于进货。其中一位商户表示，商都里有客梯和货梯，“货梯不载人”，之前没有出过事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;云南省特种设备安全技术协会工作人员向南都记者表示，“按规定来说，货梯客梯不能混用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据云南省市场监督管理局官网介绍，佛城商都市场是弥勒市最大的农贸市场，日均人流量可达到2至3万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又逢九九重阳节，你都知道哪些重阳习俗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259133]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今日是农历九月初九，又是一年重阳佳节。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;重阳节又称“重九”，因为在《易经》中把“六”定为阴数，把“九”定为阳数，九月九日，日月并阳，两九相重，故称“重阳”，又称“重九”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于重阳节，唐代诗人王维九月九登高时写下的《九月九日忆山东兄弟》&lt;span>;我们都耳熟能详，登高望远、祭祖、佩茱萸则是我们熟知的重阳习俗。而经过两千多年的变迁，重阳节还伴随着其他形式多样的习俗活动。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;登高、祭祖&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;重阳最重要的活动之一，即是登高，故重阳节又叫“&lt;/span>;&lt;a>;登高节&lt;/a>;&lt;span>;”。九月初九秋意渐浓，天高气爽，正是适合远眺美景、登山健身之时。而重阳节与除夕、清明、中元节三节，为中国传统四大祭祖节日。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;尊老敬老&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因“九”是数字中的最大数，是久长久远的谐音。九九重阳含有长长久久，长寿多福的寓意，&lt;span>;1989年，我国把每年农历九月九日定为老人节，提倡尊老、爱老、敬老、助老。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;除此之外，&lt;strong>;插茱萸、簪菊、赏菊、饮菊花酒，放风筝，食重阳糕&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;也都是比较常见的民间习俗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这么多的重阳节习俗，哪些是你每年都会参与的呢？关于重阳节你还知道哪些诗词典故？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;欢迎在评论区和我们一起分享，马上送你上热评！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（资料来源：中国非物质文化遗产保护中心）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>