<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国际足联：沙特是2034年足球世界杯唯一申办方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:55:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;FIFA announced on October 31 that the Saudi Arabian Football Association was the only one to submit a proposal to host the 2034 Football World Cup before the deadline. Apply to the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FIFA confirmed that it has received Saudi Arabia’s application to host the 2034 World Cup, and Saudi Arabia is currently the only country that has expressed interest in hosting the 2034 World Cup to FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256476&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, FIFA announced that the only application for hosting the 2030 World Cup was jointly submitted by the football federations of Morocco, Portugal and Spain. Currently, these three countries have confirmed their intention to bid. Since the centenary celebration of the World Cup will be held in 2030, FIFA plans to hold a World Cup match in Uruguay, Argentina and Paraguay. These three countries have also confirmed their intention to host FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saudi Arabia, like Morocco, Portugal and Spain, still needs to pass the review of FIFA. If these bidding countries can meet the requirements put forward by FIFA, complete the entire bidding process and pass, then FIFA will determine its hosting rights at the FIFA Congress at the end of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总部人去楼空，国美无力回天？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT9aftX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT 9aftX. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, the Gome headquarters was empty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pengrun Building, located at No. 26 Xiaoyun Road, East Third Ring Road, Beijing, was once a The top-level office building with the largest single area in Asia is close to the Embassy District and Chaoyang Park. This is also where the headquarters of Gome Electric Appliances is located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its opening in 2000, this 36-story light blue building with an apron on the top floor has witnessed the founder of Gome Huang Guangyu become the richest man in China three times, and now it has witnessed the rise of Gome The embarrassing situation of electrical appliances due to losses, payment arrears, and wage arrears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, on the lottery page of the Gome APP, a pop-up window targeting Gome founder Huang Guangyu and current Gome Chairman Huang Xiuhong appeared, including &quot;arrears of wages and arrears of payment.&quot; In fact, issues such as wage arrears at Gome have already emerged as early as 2022, and angry employees clashed with Huang Guangyu in Pengrun Building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;To what extent have employees been forced to do pop-up windows? Now Gome is in a state of no one&#39;s supervision, and employees can only find windows by themselves.&quot; Leaving Gome in Beijing in March 2023 Zhao Qiang, an employee at the headquarters, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Headquarters&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Empty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Gome Retail (0493.HK) Financial report data shows that Gome Group has a total of approximately 32,000 employees in 2021. As of the first half of 2023, the number of Gome Group employees is 3,609. This means that in one and a half years, Gome has lost 90% of its employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pengrun Building used to be full of American people. There was no place to park in the morning, and the cafeteria was full of people at mealtime.&quot; Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters, but when he left , most floors of the building were deserted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of Monday, October 30, Southern Weekend reporters came to Pengrun Building. It is divided into two buildings, A and B. The 3rd to 36th floors of Building B are the offices of Gome Electric Co., Ltd., and the only building in Building AB is The difference is that only Building B has strict access control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I walked into the Gome headquarters, the corridor lights were still on. The biggest feeling was that it was &quot;empty&quot;. Conference rooms, office areas, and reception rooms of all sizes were locked, and there were only a few staff members. Walking around with the cleaning staff, I saw strangers visiting me, but no one came up to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 18th floor of Pengrun Building, banners hanging on both sides of the elevator read &quot;Become a trusted world-class retail enterprise&quot; and &quot;Lead the survival and development of enterprises with &#39;faith&#39;&quot;. The black background wall in the middle is printed with &quot;Gome&quot; is two big words. On the right side of the background wall is the publicity room of Gome Group, which is densely packed with various certificates and trophies from Huang Guangyu, Du Juan and Gome Group in the past. But the time is mostly concentrated before 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conflicting with these past honors, there are now A4 papers posted everywhere here saying &quot;No entry to non-staff members of this floor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The 18th floor is the place where Gome receives merchants and suppliers. There are several large VIP conference rooms, and there used to be many people every day.” Zhao Qiang said. Southern Weekend reporters observed this floor for nearly half an hour, but no one came except one or two cleaning staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gome supply chain companies responsible for providing support to merchants and suppliers are concentrated on the 16th floor. They used to include Gome Customization Company, Ningbo Gome Zhenxuan Technology Co., Ltd., etc. The original office areas of these companies have been locked. And was removed from the floor guide board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. He made a high-profile statement that he would strive to restore the company to its original market position in the next 18 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His biggest move after his return was the launch of the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP, which represents Gome&#39;s retail strategy. The financial report shows that in 2021, Gome spent 962 million yuan on advertising on this APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Traces of &quot;True Happiness&quot; appear intensively on the 17th floor of Gome&#39;s headquarters. The red banner of &quot;Let&#39;s fight for a better career together and create a better life together&quot; is still hung in the office area, and the words &quot;12.24 9 :00-12:00 The room for the scheduled meeting of &quot;Home Appliances Division, Life Electrical Appliances&quot; has been locked. Zhao Qiang lamented, &quot;&#39;True happiness&#39; is earned by how many Gome employees work hard, work overtime and stay up late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth floor of the headquarters includes the national third-party logistics company established by Gome Group in 2012.&quot; The office area of ​​&quot;Anxun Logistics&quot;, a logistics company that had previously been rumored to be planning an IPO. It&#39;s pitch dark here now. At the end of 2022, news has emerged that Anxun Logistics and its subsidiaries owed more than 3 million in freight to multiple carriers in Henan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be said that after 2023, the entire country and the United States will fall into a state of deathly silence.” Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The traces of &quot;really happy&quot; are still there. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where did the money go&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The top 36 floors of Pengrun Building were Huang Guangyu’s office in previous reports. However, a former employee of Gome who had successfully &quot;climbed&quot; told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Boss Huang also lives here, and there is a villa on the 36th floor that he renovated in a Chinese and Western style.&quot; If you want to climb to the 36th floor, You need to take the exclusive elevator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past, many employees came to ask for their wages and climbed up one level at a time, causing trouble twice. Later, in order to prevent people from going there again, we couldn’t enter that level.” Zhao Qiang remembered that there had been The supplier came to ask for payment, and squatted at the door of Pengrun Building until Huang Guangyu, and &quot;followed Boss Huang to the 36th floor, but I don&#39;t know how to deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, many media reported the news that Daqing Gome suddenly closed down and nearly 20 home appliance dealers begged for payment but &quot;didn&#39;t know who to ask for it from.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Judgment Documents Online, Gome was involved in 268 lawsuits in 2022, and this number reached 1,219 in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year’s lawsuits include an electrical equipment company in Foshan City, Guangdong Province requiring Foshan Gome Electric to pay a payment of 1.26 million yuan, a company in Zhejiang requiring Zhejiang Gome Electric to return rent and liquidated damages totaling 2.2 million yuan, and a construction company in Ningbo The decoration company requires Gome Electrical Appliances and Gome Retail to pay 2.4 million yuan for the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was March and April 2022 when employees who resigned began to discover problems in the company. &quot;The biggest problem is the funding problem, which means we can&#39;t settle the account,&quot; Zhao Qiang told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former employee who was directly involved in Gome’s sales and purchase still remembers that in the past, his work did not require consideration of billing issues, but starting in 2022, he was in a “pay here, then that” situation. I just can’t pay” situation. &quot;It&#39;s very intuitive to feel that cash flow is very tight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, he checked Gome&#39;s daily sales. &quot;I remember that the daily sales at that time could still reach tens of millions to 100 million or even higher, so I personally felt that it would not be overwhelming, but I don&#39;t know where the money went when it came back.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2022, &quot;employees&#39; basic salary is still there, but the performance part is rarely paid&quot;, and the situation gradually becomes more and more serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, at an all-staff meeting held in Pengrun Building, Huang Xiuhong, chairman of Gome Electric Appliances, publicly stated, “The company will only provide social security to employees and will not pay wages until the end of December. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome also requires employees to sign a commitment letter, which mentions that “starting from October 2022, we understand that the company may delay the payment of employee wages in the next six months to one year... Commitment adjustment Have a positive attitude and believe in the company... As employees, we promise to work hard, deliver business results on time, with high quality and quantity, and achieve performance goals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I also read this commitment letter at the time. If I don&#39;t sign it, does it make sense that I still owe back wages?&quot; Zhao Qiang said that some employees have already had zero income for a year. After his salary appeal failed, Zhao Qiang also filed for arbitration. According to the judgment, Gome owed him more than 200,000 yuan in salary plus provident fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another manager of a relevant Gome department told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;I am not owed wages, but all the children under me are owed wages. 200,000 yuan is a lot.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more unacceptable to Zhao Qiang is that starting from May 2022, Gome will no longer pay social security provident funds for its employees. &quot;But our personal contribution was deducted, and the company did not hand it over to the Provident Fund Management Center. This is the case for all employees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is equivalent to using our money, but we don’t know where it was used. .&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee of the Lianyungang branch of Gome Electric Co., Ltd. told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Since October 2022, we have realized that Gome has begun to have financial problems because wages have not been paid on time. , it was postponed until the store closed in March this year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employees all filed for arbitration, but they did not have much confidence. &quot;There is no money in Gome&#39;s account, so it will end in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome Electric Appliances has 3,895 chain stores across the country and more than 200 million members. However, starting in 2023, news of Gome store closings appeared one after another. In October, some media reported that all Gome stores in Guangdong were closed. Later, the company responded that not all Gome stores were closed. However, published data showed that Gome reduced its self-operated stores in Guangdong Province by 12 in the third quarter. There are 74 franchise stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome employees and consumers in Beijing, Shanghai, Lianyungang and other places also told Southern Weekend reporters that Gome stores in their cities are also gradually closing. Many interviewees said, “Gome stores across the country are basically closed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the process of store closures, situations that were unacceptable to consumers emerged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A consumer in Shanghai purchased a 7,200 yuan washing machine at the Shanghai Gome Changning Head Office in December 2022. Gome did not deliver the goods and did not refund the money. The consumer sued Gome and then mediated. Gome promised Refunds will be issued before August 2023, but there has been no news so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although I know that Huang Guangyu has been in and out of prison, it does not affect my shopping at Gome. I have never thought about not shipping the goods after paying,&quot; the above-mentioned consumer told the Southern Weekend reporter. Among the thousands of lawsuits involving Gome in 2023, there are a large number of similar sales disputes, employee wage arrears lawsuits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the funding problem, in Zhao Qiang’s impression, the second change in the company is the frequent changes of direct leaders, which means that there is a problem in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, dozens of core executives including the former Gome Online CEO, Gome Electrical Appliances CEO, and Gome Retail President have resigned since 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How did you get to where you are today&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Huang Guangyu was born in Chaoshan, Guangdong, and is 54 years old. According to official information from Gome Group, Huang Guangyu established the first &quot;Gome Electrical Appliances Store&quot; with an area of ​​less than 100 square meters on Zhushikou Street, Qianmen, Beijing, in 1987. Gome&#39;s retail road officially started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Gome tried a new supply and marketing model, breaking away from middlemen and directly underwriting customization with manufacturers, launching a &quot;direct sales&quot; home appliance model. In 1993, Gome unified its store names, product display methods, store after-sales services, and publicity, becoming the prototype of China&#39;s retail chain model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Gome Electric Appliances was successfully listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange through a backdoor approach. Huang Guangyu used this to reach the top of the Hurun Report as the richest man in mainland China with a net worth of tens of billions, and he aspired to the top spot again in 2005 and 2008. , personal wealth once reached 45 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2008, Huang Guangyu, who was at his peak, was detained by the police on suspicion of economic crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, Huang Guangyu was sentenced to 14 years in prison for illegal business crimes, insider trading and unit bribery. In June 2020, the Beijing No. 1 Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled that Huang Guangyu should be paroled in accordance with the law. In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huang Guangyu’s past honors are still on display at the Gome headquarters. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang joined Gome the second month after Huang Guangyu was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have some understanding of Gome’s glory days, and I think its foundation is pretty good and its market share is huge. At that time, I thought that after Boss Huang came out, he would definitely have some new measures and methods that would bring Gome to the forefront. After vigorously developing it again and combining it with my resume, I joined.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Huang Guangyu returned in 2021, he first renamed Gome APP &quot;True Happiness&quot; as the &quot;total platform&quot; of Gome&#39;s retail ecosystem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to past media reports, when Huang Guangyu was in prison, he still communicated with company executives by writing letters. Gome executives even used drawings in their letters to try to make Huang Guangyu understand intelligence. The principles of mobile phones and APPs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhao Qiang said frankly, &quot;Until the day I resigned, I didn&#39;t know what the positioning of this APP was.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the &quot;True Happiness&quot; platform, there are three major scenes: competition venues, shows, and entertainment venues, as well as multiple sections such as content sharing communities, short video live broadcasts, event lists, and e-commerce shopping platforms. gather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang doesn’t know how to position this APP. Is it a community e-commerce, a hobby e-commerce, or a traditional e-commerce? In his opinion, this APP, which the boss has put all his efforts into, has no core and focus from design, product production to experience, which has a negative impact on communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a problem for decision-makers.” However, Zhao Qiang also mentioned that by the beginning of 2022, the basic functions of the “True Happiness” platform will already be in place, and consumers can buy things and return goods normally. . As long as there is a burst point in one plate, this route can still be followed after the overall tilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The serious internal friction within Gome made him begin to doubt the company&#39;s prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gave an example. Generally, the supply chain of e-commerce platforms is relatively concentrated, but within Gome, there are several companies that are engaged in supply chain at the same time. The same product of a brand may cooperate with many supply chain companies in Gome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These supply chain companies have only one output port, which is the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This brings a huge waste of manpower. Each supply chain company has dozens or even hundreds of people, but multiple teams do repetitive work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Every team must survive. Everyone is constantly asking for money from the group and dividing it up. The boss may want to compete, but this kind of competition is not external, it is scattered and internal.&quot; Zhao Qiang Speaking to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome has also built a shared and co-construction platform internally that is not open to the outside world. Small businesses and suppliers can access this system after paying a certain usage fee. &quot;The biggest problem with this platform is that no one uses it. If merchants want to open a store, they can just open a store on another platform.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;True Happy&quot; APP, Huang Guangyu has also continued to It has launched a number of apps such as &quot;Decorate Home&quot; and &quot;Zheshangzhe&quot;, which puzzled the market. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A mid-level person from Gome Group told Southern Weekend reporters, “In addition to the decision-making issues of company leaders and lack of understanding of the market environment, they are also affected by the epidemic.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Chinese Enterprises Home&quot; reported that in late October 2021, on the 36th floor of the Pengrun Building, Gome held high-level meetings for five consecutive days. Huang Guangyu was sitting in the main seat, but staring at the iPad lying flat on the table, playing the game &quot; angry Birds&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang said, &quot;Sometimes Boss Huang sleeps during the day, and meetings are held late at night, and the executives go crazy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Can it still be &quot;resurrected&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted a retired vice president-level executive about Gome’s current situation, but the other party refused to discuss the matter. In addition, all members of the public relations department of Gome Group have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the domestic official website of Gome Group cannot be opened, and the “Dressing Home” and “Zheshangzhe” apps have been removed from the Apple App Store. After spending a huge amount of promotion fees, in January 2023, “True Happiness” changed its name back to “Gome” APP. At present, some brands of Gome APP have been withdrawn, and some categories such as TVs and refrigerators have been removed from the shelves. In addition, the live broadcast sales list is blank, the cleaning, repair and other services that could have been provided have been deactivated, and no one has responded to customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the financial report, in the first half of 2023, Gome’s retail revenue was 415 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 95.74%; it achieved a net loss attributable to the parent company of 3.539 billion yuan. During the same period, Gome Retail&#39;s current assets were only 5.326 billion yuan, and cash and cash equivalents were 146 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Gome Retail’s total liability balance is as high as 37.313 billion yuan, with an asset-liability ratio of 106.55%, making the company insolvent. Among them, current liabilities were 36.106 billion yuan, accounting for 96.78%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, starting from the second half of 2021, Huang Guangyu and Du Juan have frequently reduced their holdings of Gome retail stocks, from 60.98% of their holdings at the end of 2021 to the current 10.79%. Cashed out nearly HK$2 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, when Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence, Gome’s stock price experienced a surge. It was once nicknamed the “release concept stock” by the market. As of press time, Gome’s retail stock price was only The remaining price is 0.037 yuan per share, which is 97% lower than when he was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the past ten years, Gome&#39;s development strategy has been mainly reflected in two words - conservative, and try not to spend as much money as possible. This is Du Juan&#39;s point of view.&quot; Liu Buchen believes that in e-commerce, In an era of dominance, the decline of traditional home appliance chains is inevitable. It is just a matter of speed or slowness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of former employees, the decline and end may be more dignified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang sighed, &quot;Looking back, I feel regretful. We joined Gome in the hope of helping the former myth to reshape another myth. You gave me the opportunity and I contributed my ability, but now it is difficult to come back to life. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gome&#39;s headquarters office remains in the Christmas atmosphere of 2022. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(should At the request of the interviewee, Zhao Qiang is a pseudonym in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海上危机专家谈：“我们需要的不是排外战略，而是包容的战略”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259713]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the ocean has become an emerging development space that countries are paying attention to, and a new ocean order is taking shape. At the same time, new issues such as maritime military crises and marine ecological security have also emerged. Are we ready for the new order? How should maritime disputes be managed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now that we are entering a new maritime order, we should do our best to maintain maritime security and avoid entering a state of disorder.” Jayanath Colombaj, former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy, said. He believes that many countries rely on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2023, at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control&quot; group meeting, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on issues such as maritime crises, maritime risks, maritime order and rules, etc. Discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, 2023, a number of Chinese and foreign scholars held discussions at the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing around &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Conflict-prone Period&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is facing tremendous changes, and maritime security issues have been affected A variety of factors influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Ding Yiping, former deputy commander of the People’s Liberation Army Navy, judged: “Various risk factors are superimposed, linked, and amplified, and the maritime situation is affected by them and enters a period of conflict-prone situations.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the one hand, there are traditional maritime security issues, sovereignty disputes, usage disputes, resource development, fishery and other issues.” Ding Yiping mentioned, “On the one hand, there are at least 60 countries involved in maritime usage disputes alone. More than 200 maritime disputes have arisen.” On the other hand, “criminal activities such as piracy, robbery, and terrorist attacks occur frequently.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are living in a maritime crisis.” Jayanath Colombaj is a retired lieutenant general and former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy. He is particularly concerned about maritime security issues in the Indian Ocean and its littoral countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean is the third largest ocean in the world, rich in fish and seaweed resources, and maritime trade is very developed. However, Colombaj noted that countries surrounding the Indian Ocean are still troubled by security issues, &quot;human trafficking, illegal immigration at sea They all occurred in the Indian Ocean, posing a great threat to the maritime order. In addition, there are a large number of military operations in the Indian Ocean,&quot; Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the increasing security crisis, the deterioration of the marine ecological environment has increasingly become a problem for marine governance. In recent years, climate change has led to frequent marine disasters. Melting glaciers, rising sea levels, and rising ocean surface temperatures have caused serious harm to marine and coastal ecosystems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, &quot;Some countries discharge industrial sewage and dump garbage into the ocean, resulting in seawater pollution and serious damage to marine ecology, while disorderly and uncontrolled development has caused the rapid decline of marine resources.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean that Colombaj is concerned about is also facing ecological damage. &quot;There is a 60,000 square kilometers area in the southern Indian Ocean, and there is a large area of ​​garbage.&quot; Colombaj is worried that if it is not dealt with in time, the environmental problems in the Indian Ocean will become more and more serious. serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the frequent maritime security issues, there are also more complex national games, which are not easy to solve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, “Because maritime disputes involve historical roots, national sentiments, economic and security interests, the countries involved are unwilling to compromise, and some major foreign countries intervene in other countries’ disputes for their own interests, resulting in disputes and confrontations. It has seriously affected the security and stability of some regions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Colombaj said that whether it is marine security management or marine environmental governance, countries are facing cooperation difficulties. &quot;There are several major obstacles to ocean governance, including a lack of trust, a lack of financial resources, a lack of political vision among leaders, a lack of public awareness, and a lack of broad policies,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;New Maritime Order&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are many &quot;strategies&quot; regarding the Indian Ocean. Colombaj believes that these strategies have led to strategic competition, strategic tightening, strategic dilemmas and strategic differences among a large number of countries surrounding the Indian Ocean, making the Indian Ocean unsafe. Similar to these strategies, there are a large number of joint initiatives in the Indian Ocean region, many of which remain on paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do we, a small country, need so many strategies? What goals are these strategies going to achieve? Can they bring great development to the Indian Ocean region?&quot; Colombaj believes that these strategies are about &quot;order and rules.&quot; The definition is controversial; what the Indian Ocean needs is not an exclusive strategy, but an inclusive strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When things go in the wrong direction, we can look back to the starting point. For example, with the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea adopted in 1982, we need to return to the original consensus.&quot; Colombaj believes that many The country relies on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. For example, &quot;sustainable and integrated ocean governance and enforcement are needed&quot; and &quot;military means cannot be used once a dispute arises on the ocean.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called on governments, non-governmental organizations, business and the private sector to unite together, because &quot;we can go fast alone, but we can go far together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We often hear that we live in an unpredictable world. Yet it is our (researchers’) job to anticipate the ‘unpredictable’. Now, we are entering a new ocean order. To prevent There is disorder, and we need to find order in disorder,” Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Shekhar Sinha, former Chief of the Joint Defense Staff of India, believes that after the end of the Cold War, more and more countries have improved their economies and strengthened their military strength, and the center of gravity of the balance of world power has shifted from the West to the East. , which in turn brings more great power competition. &quot;The intensity of military conflicts at sea will increase and will continue,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar is worried that violations in the military field will inevitably draw out the military, especially at sea, such as warship collisions. At the same time, the operation of military or military assets overseas involves disputes over maritime jurisdiction. The parties involved’s different understandings of history, regulations, conventions, etc. will also intensify the disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar proposed that global commerce is very important and conflicts should not affect the navigation of commercial ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that only 10%-15% of the world&#39;s ships are warships, and the rest are commercial ships. Whenever the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea is violated or violated, there must be a global warning and a law enforcement mechanism to stop such violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Warships account for a very small proportion of global ships. We must abide by relevant rules and protect commerce and trade. Conflicts between major powers are more reflected in maritime conflicts than trade conflicts.&quot; He said . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;China Plan&quot; for Crisis Management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said that the focus of the maritime security concept advocated by China can be summarized into three aspects - jointly safeguarding maritime and territorial security, and jointly responding to Maritime security threats, respect the maritime rights and interests of all countries, and oppose maritime hegemony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the ocean is public domain, and its security needs to be safeguarded by all countries in the world.” Ding Yiping proposed that we must maintain the maritime order based on international law, respect the peaceful maritime interests of all parties, and oppose the use of The oceans contain, contain, and suppress other countries, and use conflicts in other countries’ maritime interests to stir up trouble. Practice has proven that only by trusting each other, strengthening communication, active cooperation, positive interaction, and joint maintenance can we effectively ensure maritime security and maximize common interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to prevent and control maritime military crises? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping proposed that the first suggestion is to announce a strategy to prevent maritime disputes from escalating out of control and to stop inappropriate behavior by maritime military forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The current extraterritorial maritime military forces, dominated by the United States, conduct high-frequency reconnaissance, surveillance, and measurement activities in the waters surrounding China, especially the provocative acts against sovereignty in the South China Sea and the East China Sea, to control the intensity of the crisis. The increase has posed a serious obstacle to the prevention and control of maritime crises,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, U.S. warships have frequently transited the Taiwan Strait, stimulating tensions in the Taiwan Strait and constantly provoking China. Zhang Yazhong, the president of Sun Wen School in Taiwan, spoke at the meeting and said that the most fundamental and necessary way to establish a cross-strait military mutual trust mechanism, or to prevent and manage cross-strait maritime military crises, is that both sides of the strait must have a &quot;political consensus.&quot; Taiwan should return to the position of the &#39;1992 Consensus&#39;.&quot; He expressed the hope that both sides of the Taiwan Strait would have the wisdom to get rid of foreign influence, and that the two sides would resolve cross-Strait political and military problems on their own and work together to create peace across the Strait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Zhai Huan and Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[保障“外嫁女”合法权益，最高检、全国妇联联合发布6件典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 1, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the All-China Women’s Federation jointly issued a Typical cases of administrative prosecution of legal rights and interests in land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are a total of 6 typical cases in this batch, including Zhi Moulan v. the Natural Resources and Planning Bureau of a certain city in Shandong Province, collective land registration inspection and supervision case, Zhang Moujia v. Jiangsu Province A case of prosecution and supervision of the town people&#39;s government&#39;s decision not to accept the land ownership decision, a case of prosecution and supervision of the people&#39;s procuratorate of a certain district in a city in Hunan Province to protect the rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in land expropriation in accordance with the law, Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi sued a certain sub-district office in Zhejiang Province Cases of prosecution and supervision of failure to perform expropriation, resettlement and compensation responsibilities, cases of Yu suing the people&#39;s government of a town in Jiangsu Province for illegal demolition and administrative compensation, and cases of Zhou suing a village committee of a certain city in Hainan Province for the prosecution and supervision of membership confirmation of the collective economic organization of a villager group . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Procuratorial organs and women’s federations have been studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, proactively strengthening contacts, and establishing information sharing, case transfers, case notifications, and joint supervision. and other mechanisms to strengthen all-round judicial protection of women’s rights and interests. From January 2022 to September 2023, the procuratorial organs handled more than 4,000 administrative prosecution cases involving the protection of women’s rights and interests. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of my country’s urbanization process, rural women have experienced changes in marriage relationships, household registration, etc., which involve the identification of members of rural collective economic organizations, land contract management, land acquisition compensation, or Disputes over expropriation compensation and homestead use are more complex and have become issues of widespread social concern. This batch of typical cases focuses on the protection of the legitimate rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in collective economic organizations related to land, adheres to the basic national policy of gender equality, increases supervision of administrative litigation and administrative non-litigation enforcement cases involving the legitimate rights and interests of rural women, and strengthens investigations Verification, through integrated case handling, case management by hospital leaders, government inspection linkage, procuratorate and law linkage, etc., we can properly resolve disputes and promote the resolution of women&#39;s urgent, difficult and anxious issues with high-quality and efficient legal supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; pointed out that the basic national policy of equality between men and women should be adhered to and the legitimate rights and interests of women and children should be protected. The person in charge of the Seventh Procuratorate of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate said that this year is the first year to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and is also the first year of the implementation of the newly revised Law on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests. The administrative procuratorial departments of the procuratorial organs at all levels will adhere to Xi Jinping&#39;s Guided by the thought of the rule of law, we will thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on women and children, implement the Law on the Protection of Women’s Rights and Interests, continue to deepen cooperation with relevant departments such as the Women’s Federation, and work with sincerity and sincerity. Make greater efforts to handle every case with high quality and efficiency, further strengthen the equal protection of rural women&#39;s property rights, promote source governance, effectively enhance rural women&#39;s sense of gain, happiness, and security, and promote the high-quality development of women&#39;s and children&#39;s undertakings make new contributions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;About issuing and protecting rural women&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;Typical cases of administrative prosecution involving legal rights and interests in land&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Notice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;各省、自治区、直辖市人民检察院、妇女联合会，新疆生产建设兵团人民检察院、妇女联合会：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近年来，随着我国城镇化进程的加快，涉土地征收征用纠纷呈现增长态势。农村妇女因婚姻关系、户籍等发生变动，涉及农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、土地征地补偿或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面的争议更为复杂。为全面贯彻党的二十大精神，深入学习贯彻习近平法治思想，贯彻执行新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》，加大对涉及农村妇女合法权益的行政诉讼、行政非诉执行案件的监督力度，更好维护妇女合法权益，最高人民检察院、中华全国妇女联合会共同选编了6件维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例，现印发你们，供参考借鉴。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;最高人民检察院&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;中华全国妇女联合会&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2023年9月7日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;行政检察典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例一&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;支某兰诉山东省某市自然资源和规划局集体土地登记检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女宅基地使用权登记抗诉&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;支某兰与支某瑞系姐弟关系，其父支某（2011年去世）在山东省某市某村有宅基地一处。 2015年，支某瑞向某市国土资源局（现更名为某市自然资源和规划局）申请案涉宅基地使用权的变更登记，市国土资源局同意并向支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证。 2018年10月12日，支某兰以某市国土资源局为被告、支某瑞为第三人向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求依法撤销该局为支某瑞颁发的集体土地使用证。某区人民法院于2019年4月25日作出行政裁定，认为支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，不能获得案涉土地使用权，该土地颁证行为不影响支某兰权益，裁定驳回支某兰的起诉。支某兰不服一审生效裁定，向某市中级人民法院申请再审。市中级人民法院于2020年6月4日裁定驳回支某兰的再审申请。支某兰向某区人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法受理。经听取当事人意见、调取法院卷宗和案涉土地登记原始档案、听取原审法官意见，查明：某市国土资源局主要基于案涉宅基地上房屋的《房屋继承协议》，认定支某瑞因继承房屋获得土地使用权，从而为支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证，但该继承协议列明了宅基地上房屋的5名继承人，并未写明仅由支某瑞一人继承。另查明，支某兰原系该村集体经济组织成员，婚后因孩子上学原因将户口迁出，目前生活较为贫困。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院经审查认为，根据国土资源部、中央农村工作领导小组办公室、财政部、农业部《关于农村集体土地确权登记发证的若干意见》，非集体经济组织成员因继承房屋占用农村宅基地的，可按规定登记发证。本案中，虽然诉讼时支某兰并非该村集体经济组织成员，但其系支某的合法继承人，与案涉宅基地登记行为存在利害关系，法院以支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，以土地颁证行为不影响其权益为由，裁定驳回起诉，适用法律确有错误。某区人民检察院提请市人民检察院抗诉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;市人民检察院经审查，依法提出抗诉。市中级人民法院采纳抗诉意见，于2021年11月17日裁定撤销原审裁定，指令某区人民法院继续审理本案。某区人民法院于2022年9月26日作出行政判决，撤销案涉集体土地使用证。某市自然资源和规划局、支某瑞不服一审判决，提出上诉。市中级人民法院于2023年3月6日判决驳回上诉，维持原判。同时，某市人民检察院审查认为支某兰符合司法救助条件，协助其申请司法救助。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;集体经济组织中的“外嫁女”权益保护问题成为社会普遍关注的问题。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，妇女享有与男子平等的继承权，妇女依法行使继承权，不受歧视。申请农村土地承包经营权、宅基地使用权等不动产登记，应当在不动产登记簿和权属证书上将享有权利的妇女等家庭成员全部列明。户口迁出的“外嫁女”虽然不再是原集体经济组织成员，但其通过取得宅基地上房屋的继承份额，可以登记为宅基地的使用权人。针对法院以“外嫁女”与被诉土地使用权登记行为无利害关系为由裁定驳回起诉的案件，检察机关围绕争议焦点，强化调查核实，厘清事实、准确适用法律，以高质效法律监督促进司法公正，维护妇女的合法权益。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例二&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;张某甲诉江苏省某镇人民政府土地权属不予受理决定检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女土地权属行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;张某甲原系江苏省某镇某社区居民，其父母曾建有瓦房四间，并育有四女，后四女因婚嫁户口均从某社区迁出。张某甲父母先后去世。 2005年，某社区将张某甲父母的宅基地、承包地收回，重新发包给张某甲堂兄张某乙经营并签订土地承包经营合同，某市人民政府向张某乙户颁发了农村集体土地承包经营权证书。 2007年3月，张某甲离异后，户口迁回某社区。 2013年5月，张某乙夫妇将张某甲父母所建房屋拆除。张某甲等四姐妹将张某乙夫妇诉至法院，要求恢复房屋原状，未获法院支持。后张某甲的其他姐妹均出具书面申明，自愿放弃继承权。 2015年12月，张某甲向某镇政府递交宅基地使用权确权申请书，请求确认其父母原宅基地、承包地的土地使用权归其享有，确认张某乙与某社区签订的土地承包经营合同无效。 2017年3月，某镇政府对张某甲的确权申请作出不予受理决定。张某甲不服该决定，提起行政诉讼。一审法院认为，案涉土地已被某社区收回并发包给张某乙承包经营，根据《土地权属争议调查处理办法》第十四条规定，农村土地承包经营权争议案件不属于土地权属争议受案范围，某镇政府作出不予受理决定，符合法律规定，张某甲可依法另行寻求权利救济，遂判决驳回张某甲诉讼请求。张某甲提出上诉、申请再审，均未获支持。张某甲不服，向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员实地调查取证&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经审查原审卷宗，检索关联案件，实地走访调查，查明：自2013年以来，张某甲因案涉房屋及土地争议提起财产损害赔偿、不当得利返还、土地登记行为违法等13件民事、行政诉讼，其诉求均未获支持。相关生效判决虽已确认张某甲因继承取得案涉房屋所有权及宅基地使用权，亦指出某镇人民政府应当针对张某甲多年反映的宅基地被侵占问题妥善做好协调工作，但均未对该问题作出具体明确的裁决，导致案涉争议始终“诉而不决”。目前案涉社区已整体搬迁，张某甲回其父母原宅基地处重新申请建房不具有现实可能。张某甲常年在外务工，居无定所，多次诉讼实质是为求得其今后回原籍生活的“容身之所”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，本案为土地承包经营权争议，不属于人民政府土地权属争议受案范围，终审判决并无不当。但某社区未经张某甲等法定继承人同意，以自然闭户处理收回案涉土地，侵犯了张某甲等人的继承权，且张某甲户口迁回某社区后，作为村民亦应享有相应宅基地使用权。案涉争议持续近十年，历经多轮诉讼，张某甲的合法权益一直未能得到有效维护，且有引发新诉讼的可能，两级检察机关遂决定一体开展化解工作，彻底解决其多年“程序空转”难题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院致函某镇人民政府，指出张某甲权益受到侵害客观存在，镇政府应重视张某甲合理诉求，处理好当事人房屋土地问题，避免争议激化上行，保障妇女合法权益。同时，向当地妇联通报该案情况，共同至某镇政府开展化解工作。镇政府充分听取检察机关和妇联意见后，召集政法综治中心、某社区等部门商讨解决方案，最终确定张某甲可凭村民资格，以拆迁安置价格购买一套安置房用于解决居住问题。同时，检察机关向张某甲说明重新建房已不现实，应尽早从诉累中解脱，开始新生活。张某甲感受到人民政府的诚意，同意某镇政府方案。 2022年10月11日，张某甲与某镇政府签订和解协议，张某甲向检察机关撤回监督申请。该案的行政争议与民事纠纷得到实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在土地承包经营、宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。涉及村民利益事项的决定，不得以妇女未婚、结婚、离婚、丧偶、户无男性等为由，侵害妇女在农村集体经济组织中的各项权益。在办理争议历时长、关联诉讼多、民行交叉的涉损害“外嫁女”权益案件时，检察机关针对“案结事不了、程序空转”等问题，坚持人民至上、检察为民，聚焦群众急难愁盼问题，准确把握法律关系实质，统筹考虑法理情，综合运用实地走访、工作函告、协同属地妇联共同化解争议等方式“一揽子”化解行政争议与民事纠纷，切实维护农村妇女的合法权益，促进社会公平正义。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例三&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;湖南省某市某区人民检察院依法保障“外嫁女”土地征收权益检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政类案监督外嫁女征收补偿安置标准诉源治理&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2016年以来，湖南省某市自然资源和规划局某区分局（下称某自然资源和规划分局）在履行土地征收管理职能过程中，对在公安户籍管理系统单独登记立户的“外嫁女”张某及其子、王某及其女、易某及其子，分别纳入张某、王某、易某的近亲属户进行补偿安置。张某、王某、易某均不服，提起行政诉讼。 2017年6月，在张某行政诉讼案中，某区人民法院判决某自然资源和规划分局应按单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，某自然资源和规划分局依法履行了判决确定的义务；2018年12月，在易某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局主动按单独一户标准计算了安置补偿费；2019年4月，在王某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局当庭发表“外嫁女”不按单独一户进行补偿安置的答辩意见。上述三起案件，某自然资源和规划分局对“外嫁女”是否按照单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，认定标准不统一。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院在开展“全面深化行政检察监督依法护航民生民利”专项活动中，以张某、王某、易某等三起具有典型性的案件为切口，通过数据检索，发现全区涉“外嫁女”土地征收补偿行政诉讼多达上百件。某区人民检察院经研判，决定开展类案监督。通过走访行政机关、人民法院及村民委员会，调取案卷、查看资料，发现行政机关对“外嫁女”征地补偿安置标准不统一的问题较为突出，还存在行政诉讼答辩“同案不同辩”应诉不规范等问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员就检察建议整改内容与行政机关进行沟通&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年3月29日，某区人民检察院向某自然资源和规划分局发出检察建议书，建议该局：1. 对“外嫁女”进行补偿安置时，要充分保障妇女合法权益，以是否依法登记所在地常住户口作为形式要件，以是否实际在本集体经济组织生产生活为实质要件，综合判断其是否具有集体经济组织成员资格。 2. 对“外嫁女”是否按单独一户进行补偿安置，制定统一的补偿认定标准。 3. 完善行政应诉机制，提升依法行政水平，维护政府公信力。检察建议发出后，某区人民检察院与某自然资源和规划分局、某区妇联多次召开联席会，交流意见，共商整改重点。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年4月27日，某自然资源和规划分局书面回复，表示进一步完善征地拆迁安置政策和补偿认定标准；严格落实“三轮会审”机制，及时梳理总结涉拆案件情况；提升自身应诉能力水平。 2022年5月，某自然资源和规划分局制定新的《征拆安置政策和补偿认定标准》手册，对“外嫁女”制定了统一的身份认定、户型认定的补偿标准，按单独一户标准对符合规定的王某等“外嫁女”及其子女计算安置补偿费。聘请4名专职律师负责行政应诉工作，从源头堵塞行政应诉不规范问题。某区人民检察院与某区妇联会签《检察监督保障妇女权益协作配合机制意见》，在线索移送、支持起诉、行政争议化解、司法救助等多方面达成合作意见，建立长效机制。 2022年6月以来，该区未再发生因“外嫁女”补偿安置标准不统一而引发的行政诉讼。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;征地拆迁补偿，事关民生民利。 “外嫁女”应否予以补偿安置，以及补偿安置标准是否一致，事关妇女群众切身利益。在土地征收补偿安置中，农村集体组织单独登记立户的“外嫁女”，应当平等享有安置补偿权利，以单独一户按照统一标准进行补偿安置。检察机关在履行法律监督职责中，对于侵害“外嫁女”补偿安置权益，已被人民法院判决纠正后仍得不到有效落实的多起同类不当行政行为，注重类案监督，找准深层次问题，推动完善制度构建，确保同类案件在同等条件下得到同等处理，促进诉源治理，充分彰显了检察机关敢于监督、善于监督的责任担当。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例四&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;钱某娟、季某熙诉浙江省某街道办事处不履行征收安置补偿职责检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格安置补偿社会治理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;钱某娟系浙江省某镇（现某街道办事处）某村村民，婚后仍落户在其父钱某户内，育有一女季某熙，亦落户在钱某户内。 2015年9月，钱某娟与其夫季某离婚，季某熙随母共同生活。 2017年，钱某娟、季某熙所在的某镇某村列入拆改范围，钱某的房屋在征收范围内。 2017年9月11日，钱某与某镇人民政府签订《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，钱某娟、季某熙未被计入安置人口。钱某娟、季某熙提起行政诉讼，请求撤销《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，并重新签订；附带审查并确认某区政府安置补偿实施方案中“虽户口在册，但已嫁于外村且无独立合法产权房屋，不计入安置人口”的规定违法。某区人民法院判决驳回诉讼请求。钱某娟、季某熙不服，提出上诉、申请再审，未获支持。钱某娟、季某熙向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理，并根据一体化办案规定，成立两级院办案组，由某区人民检察院检察长包案办理。经调阅法院卷宗材料，调取钱某的户籍信息及某村集体经济组织成员情况，咨询区集体土地征收安置人口认定政策的制定背景及实践情况，查明：钱某娟、季某熙的户籍自始在某村，未变动，二人一直与钱某夫妇在该村生活。钱某娟系某村集体经济组织成员，享受股权6.21股，有股权证。钱某签订房屋征收安置补偿协议后，房屋被拆除，钱某娟、季某熙面临住房困难。安置补偿实施方案中的“已嫁于外村”，在实践中解释为“与外村人结婚”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;经过检察人员的努力调解，钱某娟撤回监督申请&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，钱某娟、季某熙自始系某村集体经济组织成员，二人也未在其他农村集体经济组织中享受宅基地分配使用、安置补偿。安置补偿实施方案损害妇女、儿童权益，不应作为否认“外嫁女”及其子女获得安置补偿待遇的依据。考虑到提抗、审判、执行周期长，且可能引发新一轮诉讼，增加当事人的诉累，为从根本上保障当事人的权益，某市人民检察院牵头召开府检、法检联席会议，研判“外嫁女”安置补偿案件的司法裁判规则，某区人民检察院与区房征办、信访局、街道办事处等共同研究解决方案。经多方协调联动，最终达成对钱某娟、季某熙补偿50万元的方案。 2022年11月14日，钱某娟、季某熙领取补偿款后，向检察机关申请撤回监督申请。该案行政争议得到实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关由该案进一步推动行政机关制定科学、合法、可行的土地征收安置补偿政策。目前，某区政府已修订土地征收安置补偿方案，涉“外嫁女”安置政策得以调整。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;男女平等是我国的基本国策。党的二十大报告强调“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”，充分彰显党中央对妇女儿童事业发展的高度重视。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》也要求检察机关在履职中加强对妇女权益的保护。检察机关在履职过程中，坚持问题导向，针对将“外嫁女”土地征收安置补偿权益排除在外，违反男女平等基本国策及相关法律规定的现象，通过一体化办案、成立联合办案组、院领导包案、府检联动、法检联动等方式，依法开展监督，妥善化解争议，有效维护妇女合法权益。同时，通过案件办理，推动地方政府在行政管理中重视妇女权益保障，完善土地征收安置补偿政策，有力提升社会治理法治化水平。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例五&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;俞某诉江苏省某镇人民政府违法拆除及行政赔偿检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女拆迁补偿独立基本户行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;俞某系某镇村民，婚前与其父、兄共同居住。 2007年俞某结婚，户口未迁出，并一直居住在本村。因俞某属于与村集体经济组织以外人员结婚但户口未迁出的“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不符合单独分户条件，俞某同其丈夫（外地人）在俞某父亲宅基地翻建房屋240平方米，并多次申请宅基地及建房手续，但一直未能办理。 2017年，当地政府作出房屋征收决定公告，对俞某所在“城中村”改造项目内的居民房屋实施征地拆迁。房屋被镇政府拆除后，俞某向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求判令按照拆迁安置补偿的标准，以房屋产权置换方式对房屋灭失损失进行赔偿。某区人民法院审理认为，俞某与其父亲并未分户，其翻建房屋使用的是其父亲宅基地，未办理房屋建房手续。根据有关规定，案涉房屋不能按照拆迁补偿的标准予以赔偿，鉴于房屋确系俞某所建，可按照房屋重置价予以赔偿（每平方米500元）。审理中，某镇政府表示可以赔偿90万元，法院予以准许。俞某不服一审判决，提出上诉、申请再审，均未获法院支持。俞某向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经调查核实查明：俞某房屋被拆除后，一直没有经济能力购买商品房，长期在外租房居住；俞某丈夫在原籍集体经济组织无住房、无宅基地；拆迁部门认为俞某是“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不同意按照“独立基本户”进行拆迁安置补偿；俞某认为其一直在该集体经济组织享有权利和承担义务，系当地村民，在父辈宅基地上分户建房并一直居住，应以“独立基本户”对其进行拆迁补偿安置。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，并进行释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，因俞某未分户且所建房屋未能办理审批手续，终审判决并无明显不当，但俞某的权益并未得到充分保障。本案系历史遗留问题，涉及村民自治规则的正当性、传统观念根深蒂固等问题，争议化解难度大。为此，检察机关联合当地妇联，多次组织当事人协商，赴政府商谈，引导当地政府切实增强男女平等意识，依法保障妇女在农村土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面享有与男子平等的权利。同时，多次赴俞某家实地开展联合走访慰问，为俞某提供心理疏导和关爱帮扶，减少其对立情绪。为进一步厘清外嫁女的相关法律、政策问题，2022年6月23日，检察机关就该案召开听证会，并邀请具有市区两级妇联代表身份的听证员参与。会上，双方围绕争议焦点充分表达意见、听证员现场提问，明晰案件事实，就和解方案进行全面评估与多次磋商。最终镇政府一次性补偿数十万元，合计先前赔偿的90万元，俞某得到的补偿与拆迁补偿的标准基本接近，双方达成和解协议，俞某撤回监督申请。长达五年的行政争议得以实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，国家采取必要措施，促进男女平等，消除对妇女的一切形式的歧视，禁止排斥、限制妇女依法享有和行使各项权益。妇女在土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等权利。针对历史遗留问题，检察机关在办案过程中，坚持系统思维，统筹考虑拆迁安置争议形成的法律问题、社会成因和历史因素，为避免给当事人增加诉累，纾解其面临的现实困难，通过公开听证、联合商谈、入户走访等方式，推动当地政府研究制定合理的补偿方案，促成当事人达成和解协议，实质性化解行政争议，实现政治效果、社会效果、法律效果有机统一。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例六&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;周某诉海南省某市某村委会某村民小组集体经济组织成员资格确认检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格确认行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周某于1979年10月6日出生，户籍登记在某市某区某村其父亲周某驹为户主的家庭户口中。周某的父母以家庭承包的方式，承包该村土地11.31亩，承包期限至2027年12月31日。 2018年6月13日，周某与外地的冯某登记结婚，但户口未迁出，未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款。 2020年10月，某村决定给户口在本村的每个农业人员发放征地补偿款共计人民币80246元，村民小组以周某属于在本集体没有承包地的“外嫁女”，不具有集体经济组织成员资格为由，拒绝向其支付上述征地补偿款。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2021年1月6日，周某以村委会某村村民小组侵害其集体经济组织成员权益为由向某市某区人民法院起诉，法院判决确认周某未丧失村集体经济组织成员资格，仍系某村集体经济组织成员。某村村民小组应向周某支付土地补偿费80246元。该村村民小组不服，提出上诉、再审申请均未获支持。期间，周某两次请求某镇人民政府、某镇农业服务中心帮助解决确认集体经济组织成员资格问题，镇政府一直未处理，某村村民小组一直未支付土地补偿款。周某向某市某区人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关监督情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，现场释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法审查认为，某区人民法院判决认定事实清楚、适用法律正确；某镇政府应当依法履行对某村委会某村村民小组不予确认周某集体经济成员资格、侵害其合法权益行为的监督管理职责。 2022年8月22日，某区人民检察院向某镇政府发出《检察建议书》，要求及时协调、监督某村委会某村村民小组确认周某的集体经济组织成员资格，并加强对辖区农村集体成员身份确认工作的指导，避免出现类似侵害“外嫁女”合法权益的情形。同时，某区人民检察院组织公开听证，商请某市某区某镇政府代表、村民小组代表出席听证，邀请人大代表、人民监督员、律师担任听证员，摆事实讲道理，促进实质性化解本案争议。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年9月7日，某镇人民政府作出书面回复，已采纳检察建议，协调村小组人员确认周某集体经济组织成员资格，并已将周某录入集体经济组织成员身份系统，向其出具了集体经济组织成员股权证，并按程序分期向周某支付土地补偿款。 2022年11月1日，周某签署了息诉承诺书。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、集体经济组织收益分配、土地征收补偿安置或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。认定“外嫁女”是否具有集体经济组织成员资格，应当结合户籍、土地承包经营权、权利义务关系等综合认定，确保“外嫁女”应当享有的利益不落空。与他村村民结婚，但户口未迁出，在本村承包土地、履行村民义务，且未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款的“外嫁女”，依法具有集体经济组织成员资格，享有相关合法权益。检察机关履行法律监督职责中，对行政机关不依法履职导致“外嫁女”合法权益长期得不到解决的行政检察监督案件，综合运用检察建议、公开听证等方式，解决实质诉求，促进争议化解，有效维护妇女合法权益。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省教育厅要求：严禁“萝卜刀”等有害玩具进入校园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259751]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:09:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南都记者获悉，广东省教育厅发布《关于加强有害玩具教育管理的通知》。其中提到，各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园。同时，学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具；关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，近期一款名为“萝卜刀”的新型玩具在中小学生（幼儿）群体中走红。该玩具是一种外形酷似胡萝卜的彩色塑料玩具刀，由于该玩具本身具有攻击性，存在一定的安全隐患，又会形成心理暗示，激发孩子暴力倾向，对未成年人安全健康成长产生不良影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，广东省教育厅要求，加强对学生的安全教育。各地各校（园）要进一步加大安全教育力度，让学生（幼儿）认识到“萝卜刀”等玩具的危险性，自觉拒绝“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具，做到不购买、不携带、不玩耍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对家长的安全提醒。要采取多种形式提醒家长认真履行监护责任，务必选择正规厂商出产的、适合孩子年龄阶段、有益身心健康发展的儿童和学生用品，不要为孩子购买“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具。在玩具使用前，要仔细阅读包装上的警告和提醒内容，做好孩子使用时的安全防范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;严格对校园的安全管理。各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园，在进行安全教育的基础上，对仍带入校园的此类有害玩具，要清查封存。被封存的危险性有害玩具，要通知学生（幼儿）家长到学校接受教育，在作出承诺之后可由家长领回，并督促其销毁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对校园及周边的治理。学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具。要关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各地教育部门要会同相关部门深入开展儿童和学生用品安全治理，以“萝卜刀”等存在物理危害、化学危害、可燃性危害、心理暗示等危险性有害玩具产品为重点，加大校园周边商铺和流动摊贩管理力度，一旦发现存在售卖危险性玩具产品和学生用品的，要严肃查处。各地级以上市教育局于11月10日前，将排查治理工作情况反馈省教育厅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[间隔六年，茅台为何突然提价？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259745]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 17:18:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the early morning of November 1, 2023, Kweichow Moutai (600519.SH) issued an announcement on major matters: decided after research , starting from November 1, 2023, the ex-factory price of the company&#39;s 53%vol Kweichow Moutai (Feitian, Five Star) will be increased, with an average increase of approximately 20%. This adjustment does not involve the market guidance price of the company&#39;s products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time in nearly six years that Kweichow Moutai has raised its ex-factory price since New Year’s Day 2018. The ex-factory price of Feitian Moutai, the core single product of Kweichow Moutai, will increase from the previous 969 yuan/bottle to about 1,169 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This blockbuster news instantly detonated the wine circle. Many industry insiders told Southern Weekend reporters in the early morning of November 1 that they were a little shocked that Kweichow Moutai raised prices at this time, and it exceeded expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spurred by news of the price increase, on November 1, Kweichow Moutai’s collective bidding opened 9.82% higher, with a transaction value of over 1.2 billion yuan. After the opening, Kweichow Moutai&#39;s share price pulled to 1,850 yuan/share from 1,684.58 yuan/share on the previous trading day, changing its recent slightly sluggish trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height= &quot;843&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Starting from November 1, 2023, the ex-factory price of Feitian Moutai, Kweichow Moutai’s core single product, will increase from the previous 969 yuan/bottle to approximately 1,169 yuan/bottle. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1499&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; market The guide price has not changed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I don’t care about the ex-factory price, but I care about whether the price of 1,499 yuan will increase.” After Moutai issued an announcement late at night, some Moutai consumers said so. On New Year&#39;s Day 2018, Kweichow Moutai announced that it would adjust the ex-factory price from 819 yuan/bottle to 969 yuan/bottle, and at the same time increase the market guide price from 1,299 yuan/bottle to 1,499 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement issued by Kweichow Moutai mentioned: This adjustment does not involve the market guidance price of the company&#39;s products. This price adjustment will have a certain impact on the company&#39;s operating results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 1, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the Kweichow Moutai Board Secretary Office as an investor. The relevant staff responded: &quot;Our announcement is very clear. The adjustment this time is the ex-factory price, which is 1,499 yuan.&quot; The market guidance price has not changed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to why the price was raised at this point in time, the above-mentioned staff member said: &quot;Since we have not made price adjustments for nearly six years, we have fully considered the macroeconomic environment. , changes in market supply and demand and other factors, we insist on being market- and customer-centered, taking into account the long-term development of the enterprise, and adjusting the ex-factory price of products based on the long-term stability of the market. This is a normal and reasonable business behavior.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, this is the eighth price adjustment for Kweichow Moutai since it was listed in 2001. Previous price adjustments were in 2001, 2003, 2006, 2008, 2010, 2012, 2018. The interval between this adjustment is the longest since Moutai was listed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huo Dongjie, chairman of Hexi Investment, who has long studied Moutai, told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Previous Moutai price increases usually occurred when the liquor cycle was on the rise, but recently the price of Feitian Moutai is higher than the same period in recent years. Weak, for example, historically, prices increased during the Mid-Autumn Festival, but this year they fell.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data provided by wine merchants at Bairong Market, the country&#39;s largest liquor wholesale market, show that on October 31, 2023, 53 The bulk Feitian price of %vol Kweichow Moutai is 2,650 yuan/bottle, and in late June 2023, the bulk Feitian price is 2,820 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that with this price increase, some dealers’ profits will be transferred to Moutai, and the main impact will be on the channel profits of dealers and wine merchants below dealers. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhanfu, general manager of Zhengzhou Xiyun Industry, believes that the current core products of famous liquor brands except Moutai in the liquor market are seriously upside down. This price increase is not only the responsibility of the industry boss, but also the group&#39;s 2023 Effective release of growth pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Dealer profits are huge profits for Puma, so this price adjustment will not have a big impact on dealers, not to mention that dealers will push up the circulation price. This is the strong brand tension of Kweichow Moutai. It’s decided, other brands don’t have it,” Wang Zhanfu told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a senior wine merchant in Zhengzhou, Wang Zhanfu was also paying close attention to the circulation price of Feitian Moutai on the morning of November 1. However, as of press time of the Southern Weekend reporter, he said: &quot;Currently wine merchants will most likely not ship. I&#39;ll take a look.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other interviewees said that this price increase means the improvement of Kweichow Moutai&#39;s efficiency and the redistribution of channel profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From January to September 2023, Kweichow Moutai achieved operating income of 103.268 billion yuan, and the net profit attributable to shareholders of the listed company was 52.876 billion yuan. The price adjustment at this time means that the last two months of 2023 will bring more revenue and net profit to Moutai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huo Dongjie told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Our preliminary assessment is that this price adjustment will increase Kweichow Moutai&#39;s profit by 6% next year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to estimates from Founder Securities, Moutai will leave the factory this time After the price increases by 20% from 969 yuan, the revenue in 2023 will increase by approximately 6.2 billion yuan, an increase of approximately 4.2%, and the net profit will increase by approximately 4.1 billion yuan, an increase of approximately 5.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Xuefei, an expert in China’s wine industry think tank and general manager of Zhiqu Consulting, believes that this price increase will help boost confidence in the currently sluggish industry. Reasonable price increase expectations will also stimulate and drive related consumption growth, and at the same time echo long-term capital market needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Behind Moutai’s price increase&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees expressed that they were surprised by Moutai’s price increase. It was unexpected. After all, nearly six years have passed since the last time Kweichow Moutai raised prices. During this period, when Moutai will raise ex-factory prices has always been the focus of market attention. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the liquor industry set off a wave of price increases, but Moutai did not follow up. At Kweichow Moutai&#39;s 2022 and first quarter performance briefings and the shareholders&#39; meeting in June 2023, Moutai Chairman Ding Xiongjun also responded to the price increase issue many times. He once said that Moutai liquor must be determined in accordance with relevant laws and regulations such as the Price Law. The price will also consider factors such as supply and demand. &quot;We will definitely follow the laws of the market and respond to market demand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the liquor industry who did not want to be named told a Southern Weekend reporter: “Moutai’s special status and economic influence determine that Moutai’s price adjustments are extremely sensitive and often involve enterprises and governments. Waiting for opinions from many parties, and having a strict demonstration and confidentiality process.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person pointed out that the price increase was indeed sudden, but it was obviously intended to boost confidence. Another head of an investment institution who has invested in Moutai for more than 20 years told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;This price increase is part of the policy to protect the capital market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the company itself, In recent years, Kweichow Moutai has continuously increased the proportion of direct sales revenue by reducing the number of dealers, expanding direct sales channels, increasing directly-operated stores, and launching the iMoutai platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2017, the total number of Kweichow Moutai dealers has decreased from 3,083 to 2,082 as of the end of the third quarter of 2023. The reduction of thousands of dealers has led to the continued growth of Kweichow Moutai’s direct sales business. In 2022, Kweichow Moutai&#39;s direct sales business will account for 40%. In the first three quarters of 2023, Kweichow Moutai&#39;s direct sales revenue increased by 44.93% year-on-year, reaching 46.207 billion yuan, accounting for approximately 44.92% of total revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博士过剩愈演愈烈，读博值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the one hand, the number of people enrolling and graduating with doctoral degrees in China hits new highs every year; on the other hand, the &quot;PhD surplus&quot; is highlighted and intensifying . News about &quot;PhDs in nuclear physics working as urban management&quot;, &quot;Doctors in medicine applying for school doctors&quot; and &quot;PhD students vying to become primary and secondary school teachers&quot; appear frequently, showing the embarrassment of doctoral students being &quot;overqualified for their talents&quot; in the job market. After more than ten years of hard work, is studying for a Ph.D. still a good option?</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当世界科幻大会来到中国：“许多超出以往经历的东西”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Chengdu Science Fiction Museum, which will be built in 2023, will be held from October 18th to October 22nd. The main venue of the World Science Fiction Convention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Chengdu Pidu District Science and Technology Innovation City Management Committee/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention in 2023 ——Chengdu Science Fiction Museum is located in the center of a two-kilometer radius area called &quot;Science Fiction Avenue&quot;. When Chengdu&#39;s bid to host the event was successful two years ago, it was still a wilderness. This plot of land in Pidu District, Chengdu, which was originally planned as a &quot;Science and Technology Museum&quot;, was quickly upgraded to a &quot;Science Fiction Museum&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This science fiction pavilion designed by Zaha Hadid Architects continues its pursuit of curves and a sense of the future. In the jungle of horizontal and vertical straight lines in the suburbs, several artificially shaped curved surfaces are implanted. According to the official statement, it was a nebula from the universe, but science fiction writer Liu Cixin said that it also looked like an alien spacecraft that landed on the lakeside. Anyway, this is the World Science Fiction Convention and it needs a visual imagery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that the World Science Fiction Convention has come to China. Initially, the World Science Fiction Convention was just a whim created by a few young people under the age of 20 in Chicago, USA - to create a gathering platform for science fiction fans around the world. In 1939, they held their first convention in Chicago. Through gatherings and autonomy of science fiction fans, people from all over the world who like a certain science fiction work gather together to chat about their reading experiences, exchange handicrafts, and commemorate the dead of science fiction... For eighty years, the World Science Fiction Convention has inherited such a loose and rich tradition The gene of imagination has grown a unique and lasting science fiction culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering the Chengdu Science Fiction Museum through the huge dome-style entrance requires you to go through multiple security checks. The opening ceremony showed some common elements of a Chinese-style evening party - the host&#39;s high-pitched recitation, the colorful stage, and the group dances that filled the space. However, the organizers added as many science fiction elements as possible to highlight the conference&#39;s atmosphere. The theme is &quot;The Era of Symbiosis&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China&#39;s science fiction fan culture has not had extensive exchanges with the culture I was exposed to when I grew up for decades. I still have many things to learn beyond my previous experience.&quot; Co-chairman of this conference Ben Yarrow said, &quot;Of course, Chinese science fiction fans also have a lot to know about the culture of the World Science Fiction Convention.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Member Culture&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chengdu in late October The chill has already set in, and the summer vacation for students has passed early. When Chengdu applied to host the World Science Fiction Convention in 2021, many student science fiction fans spent money to register as members of the 79th Washington World Science Fiction Convention (approximately more than 600 yuan) to vote for Chengdu in order to see the science fiction event during the summer vacation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;World Science Fiction Association Constitution&quot;, various memberships with different titles can be purchased. If you purchase the membership for the current year, you can vote for the city that will bid for the next two years, and you can also vote for the Hugo Award. Vote for the shortlisted works. This approach is similar to &quot;crowdfunding&quot;. The vast majority of the budget of previous World Science Fiction Conventions comes from the purchase support of members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a unique membership culture among science fiction fans in the world. In the 1950s, soon after the Hugo Awards were established, fan awards were added. Science fiction fans who wrote their own works and amateur magazines could also stand on the podium of the Hugo Awards and compete with those &quot;big names&quot; The works complement each other. The three traditional core issues of the World Science Fiction Convention - Hugo Award voting, business meetings and future conference site selection votes - are all closely related to the participation of ordinary science fiction fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Its charm lies in that it is a spirit based on a community of creators. Everyone is both a participant and a creator. This is something given to it by cultural traditions and cannot be replaced or replaced casually. Copied.&quot; Chen Shi, co-chairman of this conference, told Southern Weekend reporters that he regretted that for many fantasy fans, this was a conference that they could not reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 20, 2023, the Chengdu Organizing Committee announced on Twitter that the date of the event would be postponed from August 16, 2023 to October 18. &quot;At least a hundred of my psychedelic friends can&#39;t come,&quot; said Qianxing, a college student. His school is far away from Chengdu, and he is one of the few people who can take leave. Qianxing came to the venue wearing a silver-blue cosplay costume, which was very conspicuous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these fantasy fans can come to the Chengdu Science Fiction Museum, in this huge, hollow building, they will first see a 9-meter-high giant &quot;Benben&quot; statue in the hall (movie The robot in &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot;), at night, the spotlights surrounding it make the colors on its surface begin to flow, creating &quot;clumsy&quot; in various states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two large exhibition halls on the first floor are the enterprise exhibition hall and the science fiction fan exhibition hall. Most of the dozens of booths in the corporate exhibition hall are Chinese companies. Some sell science fiction cultural creations, some make projections, and more are engaged in science fiction publishing. The sound and light effects of their booth are eye-catching, which is obviously different from the psychedelic exhibition area next to it. The corporate exhibition hall is a unit that has never been seen in previous World Science Fiction Conventions. The support of the government, the participation of enterprises, and the brand promotion of a large number of sponsors have given the conference more official color and commercial value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vicinity of the Science Fiction Hall cannot meet the travel and catering needs of so many exhibitors. An exhibitor told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;What kind of tickets should be used, how to arrange the buses, and how to distribute the agenda&quot; were all figured out after coming here; there are still very few businesses around this brand-new venue. If you don&#39;t want to To eat at the venue&#39;s restaurants, such as KFC and Subway, you have to go several kilometers away to find food at noon every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the coolness of the corporate exhibition area, the science fiction fan exhibition area looks much simpler. A table, a flag, an introduction card or a QR code. They come from university clubs, foreign science fiction organizations, and unfamous amateur authors... It&#39;s a bit like a recruitment scene for university clubs. On the table of the Tibetan science fiction club, there are Tibetan science fiction works published over the years. A Tibetan young man patiently introduced the history of Tibetan science fiction to curious onlookers. This kind of atmosphere is more like the previous World Science Fiction Convention. Science fiction literature research scholar Yan Feng once participated in the 2019 World Science Fiction Convention in Dublin. He recalled that the atmosphere there was &quot;free and loose.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The conference rooms on the second and third floors of the Science Fiction Museum are used to hold various &quot;salons&quot;. The so-called &quot;salons&quot; are various seminars organized by science fiction fans themselves. Science fiction fans invite their own guests and choose their own topics. After submitting the submission to the organizing committee, it is usually approved. Then the organizing committee arranges the time and venue and does not interfere with other matters. The number of salon sessions at previous World Science Fiction Conventions has been stable between three and four hundred. There were more than 400 salons registered for the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention, and more than 230 salons were eventually reserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time the Chengdu Organizing Committee invited a total of more than 600 guests, including more than 180 overseas guests (more than 150 people were present), who formed the main group of the salon. In the past World Science Fiction Convention, only a small number of officially invited guests were invited by science fiction fans themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Shi also applied for a salon at the World Science Fiction Convention in Chicago. &quot;I just bring a form, and the organizing committee directly tells me the location and time. You can just do it yourself, and they won&#39;t care about you.&quot; Chen Shi said, &quot;In China&#39;s cultural background, this may not be the case. Suitable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The foreign World Science Fiction Convention is very attractive to the fantasy fandom, but if you don&#39;t leave the fandom, their core members are more than 20,000, and the number of people who come every year does not change much. It has formed its own community culture. There are cultural thresholds to enter this community. If we completely copy that, it may be very miserable. It is difficult for this thing to enter various circles.&quot; When Chen Shi first thought about what to do At some kind of world science fiction conference, he had already decided to take a different path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Feng is the CEO of the science fiction publishing company Baguangfen. The &quot;Oral History of Chinese Science Fiction&quot; she edited was also shortlisted for the 2023 Hugo Award. She has participated in several World Science Fiction Conventions. She recalled the previous salons and exhibitions to Southern Weekend reporters, “It was like a party for science fiction fans, with not many ‘high-end’ designs and full of various cosplayers (two-dimensional image imitators). When walking around the market, there are also people who gather in a small circle and play guitar all day long.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes her linger here is the former flea market. Every year, science fiction fans sell their collections, handicrafts, The second-hand books were auctioned at the flea market at the World Science Fiction Convention. Everyone wrote their desired price on a small sign, and the one with the highest price got it. &quot;Almost every time I take pictures at the convention, I get something I like.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Business Meeting&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;of&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;query, debate&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;voting&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Hello, your speech is not related to the question of yes or no, but another topic.&quot; &quot;Hello, your time to speak is up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Qianxing’s speech was interrupted from time to time by the timekeeper on the podium. This is Qianxing&#39;s first time at the World Science Fiction Convention, and like most Chinese science fiction fans, it is his first time to experience an affairs conference. Many Chinese science fiction fans hang out in exhibition areas and salons, but often ignore this important meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But old science fiction fans all know that &quot;only by attending business meetings can you have a deep understanding of the organization and participation methods of the World Science Fiction Association and the World Science Fiction Convention, and you will feel some interesting things.&quot; place.&quot; Chen Shi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Business Meeting&quot; is an important agenda of every conference, even the core agenda. During this four-to-five-day meeting, members supervised various affairs of the World Science Fiction Congress through questioning, debate, and voting, and were also responsible for revising certain provisions of the World Science Fiction Association Charter, the cornerstone of the World Science Fiction Congress. . In English, this charter is called a constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The practice of this conference seems new and even a bit exciting to most Chinese science fiction fans. &quot;What is a sunset clause?&quot; When they encounter legal terms they don&#39;t understand, they will express them candidly on the spot. Their questions are listened to carefully by people from all over the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have personally experienced the process and debate of the business meeting, it is not difficult to understand why the fandom calls the meeting a &quot;constitutional amendment meeting.&quot; The business meetings of the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention are held in the Meteor Hall of the Science Fiction Hall, which is a small hall independent of the main hall. People with membership can enter to listen, express opinions and vote at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qianxing is the most active speaker among the Chinese members present. He has to express his own opinions on almost every topic. When he gets selfless, he often exceeds the speaking time and is asked to stop speaking. This is A meeting in which speeches and debates were conducted strictly in accordance with Robert&#39;s Rules of Order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are fewer people coming this year, but it was more lively in previous years.” Xixia, director of Baguangfen Film and Television, told Southern Weekend reporters. There will be a preparatory meeting before the annual business meeting to discuss the specific arrangements for the business meeting. The preparatory meetings in previous years were also very lively. Often within a few minutes of the host&#39;s speech, a member would jump out and question various arrangements. &quot;Some people said how many translators should be provided, and some people said how the screen should be displayed. In the end, both sides debated Do you want to start the two-minute preparatory meeting?&quot; Chen Shi recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the small number of people coming, Deputy Adjudicator Kevin Stanley revealed to Chen Shi that 2023 should be the year with the least &quot;wrangling&quot; in the preparatory meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Meteor Hall is far from full. There are two thick books at the door, the Chinese and English versions of &quot;Robert&#39;s Rules of Procedure&quot;. If members have any opinions on the debate process, they can check it at any time. Xixia brought his own &quot;Constitutional Amendment&quot; this time. He wants to add a Hugo Award to be awarded to science fiction films produced by independent filmmakers. He believes that the current &quot;Best Dramatic Performance (Feature Film)&quot; The awards pay too much attention to commercial blockbusters and ignore independent films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most fantasy fans in the 1950s were fans of science fiction novels, so the first Hugo Award was established for the best novel in 1953. Since then, fan magazines and theater performances have been slowly added. and comics awards. If you look at the award-winning films over the years, you will find that most of them are Hollywood commercial productions. Xixia believes that it is necessary to change this situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For example, in terms of novel awards, we have already awarded awards to the most commercially successful and famous novels, but there are also some fan-created novels that have not received commercial attention but are considered well-written by the industry. For very good novels, the Hugo Awards will award them with Best Fan Author, Best Fan Magazine, and Best Fan Podcast. There should also be such an award in the film category,&quot; Xixia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It will take at least two years to pass new amendments at the &quot;Constitutional Amendment Conference&quot;. If the proposal can be debated and passed at the first year&#39;s conference, it will become a formal amendment proposal. It will be debated for a second time in the second year. Only after it is passed can the &quot;constitutional amendment&quot; be considered successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two proposals for second-instance debate in 2023, one of which is &quot;whether to add a Hugo Award for the best game or interactive work.&quot; The Chinese members present seemed to be generally cautious about this proposal. They questioned the definition of &quot;game&quot;, especially since the boundaries of science fiction games seemed not to be clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The debate time is over. Those who support this proposal please stand up...those who oppose this proposal please stand up...&quot; Adjudicator Donald Eastlake said. The final voting result was 10:3, and the amendment was passed, which means that this award will be added to the Hugo Awards in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qianxing’s most exciting speech was about a new proposal for 2023. This new proposal put forward by Kevin Stanley calls for the future World Science Fiction Convention to be held preferably between August 1 and September 30. If it exceeds this range, it should be held with the next one. Negotiations with the host city. Qianxing’s opinion is that in addition to negotiating with the next organizer, we also need to discuss with the members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Participants of the membership meeting have the right to know that the date of the meeting is to be changed. They negotiate with the organizing committee. The organizing committee may not adopt the member&#39;s opinions, but there must be such negotiation. There must be a stage for expressing opinions.&quot; During a break in the business meeting, Southern Weekend reporters interviewed Qianxing. He looked a little excited and strode up to the podium. He spoke slowly but forcefully, hoping to add the terms negotiated with members to Kevin&#39;s proposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After voting, Kevin’s proposal was passed, but Qianxing’s supplementary clause was not passed. However, the entire meeting was recorded on video, and Qianxing&#39;s speeches and opinions have been recorded and become the permanent historical archives of the World Science Fiction Convention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xixia’s proposal also passed the preliminary review. At next year&#39;s World Science Fiction Convention in Glasgow, Kevin and Xixia&#39;s proposal will be reviewed, debated, and voted on by members again. In this way, the &quot;World Science Fiction Association Charter&quot; allows the World Science Fiction Conference to respond to the changes of the times and the demands of fantasy fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Setting records and making history&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 21, 2023, the 81st Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference awarded this Hugo Award. Prior to this, many faces of color have been added to the nominations for this year&#39;s awards, and the Chinese finalists are eye-catching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese illustrator Zhao Enzhe won the Best Professional Artist Award, &quot;Zero Gravity&quot; edited by Chinese science fiction fans He He and Ling Shizhen won the Best Fan Magazine Award, and science fiction writer Hai Miao&#39;s novel &quot;Time and Space&quot; The Painter&quot; won the &quot;Best Short Novella Award&quot;. According to the tradition of the Hugo Awards, the organizing committee of the conference will disclose the voting details and data after the awards. For example, the data of the 2022 World Science Fiction Convention in Chicago can still be found on the official website. After the conference, the official website of the Hugo Awards wrote: &quot;Currently we do not have the details of this voting data. We will announce the data as soon as we obtain it.&quot; The official Chinese website of the Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference is also temporarily unavailable. this data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dave McCarty, head of the Hugo Award Selection Committee, told reporters after the awards night: &quot;Hai Miao&#39;s &quot;The Painter of Space and Time&quot; does not have an English translation. It has created a complete novel without an English translation. The history of winning awards for Chinese works.&quot; This means that most of the members who voted for &quot;Painter of Time and Space&quot; may be Chinese readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the second day after the awards, the &quot;Galaxy&#39;s Edge&quot; (mook) which published &quot;The Painter of Space and Time&quot; was sold out in the science fiction museum. Because there were so many people asking, the bookshelf in the science fiction fan area had to wait Put up a &quot;Sold Out&quot; sign. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course Liu Cixin’s works are also selling hotly. Liu Cixin’s autograph session will be held at 2 pm on October 20. Other writers’ autograph sessions are usually only arranged for 20 minutes. The organizer gave Liu Cixin a preview. Three hours were left for signings. Fans packed the signing hall on the third floor early. The queue stretched from the third floor to the first floor, and then snaked half a circle around the venue. Many fans whose legs were sore from standing sat on Liu&#39;s book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy for the publishing organizations participating in the exhibition to sign and sell their books at this venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Xi is an editor of a publishing organization. This time he brought an author&#39;s science fiction novel to Chengdu and organized a salon, hoping that science fiction fans can have a good chat with the author himself. Host a book signing. At first, Xixi reported the entire process to the organizing committee, but a few days before the opening, she received a notice that the salon could not be placed together with the autograph signing. &quot;In normal book fairs, there are book signings after the exchange between authors and readers, but here the two venues must be separated and the time periods must be separated,&quot; Xixi said. This means that readers who are interested in the author have to make two trips to get a signed copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various salons, forums, and summits at the World Science Fiction Convention, but in addition to the opening and closing ceremonies and the Hugo Award presentation party, there is also an &quot;Industrial Development Summit&quot; where almost all major guests are invited The summit was attended with a lineup worthy of Hugo Awards night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time an industry development-related conference has been held at the World Science Fiction Convention. At the meeting, a number of plans related to the development of the science fiction industry were announced, including the &quot;Chengdu Consensus on the Science Fiction Industry&quot;, the &quot;Tianwen&quot; Plan, the &quot;2023 China Chengdu Science Fiction Industry Report&quot;, etc., and there was even a centralized signing ceremony for science fiction industry projects. According to According to statistics, there are 21 signed projects with a total investment of 8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this &quot;Industrial Development Summit&quot;, Liu Cixin no longer talked about literature, but talked about industrial development: &quot;Chengdu has long planned the layout of the science fiction industry, related industrial planning and industrial policies , talent policies, etc. have all been implemented.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Science fiction industry chain ecosystem&quot;, &quot;IP creation&quot; and &quot;strengthening the image of a science fiction city&quot;. Faced with these various fresh vocabulary, Canadian science fiction writer Robert Sawyer said, “I am very shocked to see you turning science fiction into an industry.” He said that those who do these things in North America may be publishers, and science fiction is a career that is random, aimless, and without long-term planning. These industry figures were generally not invited to previous World Science Fiction Conventions, and most of those who came were writers and editors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This area where the Chengdu Science Fiction Museum is located will also be built into the science fiction highland of Chengdu. According to a person close to the local government, a reporter from Southern Weekend said that a science fiction industrial park may be built here in the future. “That street is a science fiction themed block, and science fiction companies may move in in the future. This area is said to be A science fiction camping base, there will be training camps for science fiction writers and summer camps for students every year, and the science fiction museum itself is a large-scale consumption + public welfare space. This circle will be built into a science fiction themed tourist destination.&quot; He stood On the high platform, his fingers drew a large arc from one end to the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The local government has done support work such as venues and transportation, and also mobilized many volunteers,” Chen Shi said. “The core of the appeal is two points. One is to enhance Chengdu’s city brand image, and the other is to support Science fiction industry.&quot; This conference also set a record - it attracted the most sponsors ever. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;What makes Chinese young people like science fiction?&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The fantasy exhibition area in the afternoon was extremely noisy, even though this One day is already the last day of the World Science Fiction Convention. A robot drummer was beating the drums in a loop in the corner. Parents took their children on public transportation for two hours, and now they have just entered the museum. The children were holding notebooks with stamps and clocks in their hands, and they were screaming and shuttling through various booths. between. There is also a science fiction fan who is promoting his own book: &quot;The book I wrote is completely opposite to Liu Cixin&#39;s world view...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sea of ​​noise, there is a person taking a nap on a chair . He had white hair, a cowboy hat on the table, and his eyes were lowered, as if he had entered another world. His name is James Joseph, from Australia. He is in his seventies and has been a science fiction fan for nearly fifty years. In 1975, the World Science Fiction Convention was held in Oceania for the first time. He was moved by the atmosphere of science fiction and has been to the World Science Fiction Convention 15 times so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James told Southern Weekend reporters that this conference is the most special one he has ever been to. He has never seen so many enthusiastic and young science fiction fans in Europe or the United States before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Youth is a key word of this conference. &quot;I signed more names today than in the past 56 years combined.&quot; Nicholas White seemed a little flattered when he was surrounded by primary school students looking for his signature. The students walked along the booth and checked in one by one, asking for autographs. The organizing committee has reached cooperation with many primary and secondary schools in Chengdu and organized many students to attend various salons and forums. There was almost no silence in the science fiction museum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan Brandt, a member of the 2025 Seattle Fantasy Organizing Committee, told Southern Weekend reporters that the scale of the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention is the largest he has ever seen. The previous record holder was held in London in 2014, with around 10,000 participants. According to figures released by official media, the number of participants in Chengdu exceeded 20,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the West, the golden age of science fiction literature was the decades after World War II. At that time, the United States and the Soviet Union were competing for hegemony, and the Western economy was developing rapidly. Science fiction literature followed the trend and became the spiritual home of many young people at that time. More than half a century has passed, and the science fiction fans of those days are getting older. Old Western science fiction fans like James Joseph, whose silver hair is the highlight of the Chengdu Science Fiction Museum. &quot;For American science fiction works, many readers are gray-haired, that is, only middle-aged and elderly people read science fiction works. But in China, on the contrary, young people prefer science fiction works. This is my confusion, what makes Chinese young people like it? Science fiction?&quot; Robert Sawyer asked this question in Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every previous conference would set up a memorial area. This is a place for middle-aged and elderly science fiction fans to reminisce and reminisce about the past. In 2017, the British science fiction writer Brian Aldiss passed away. There was a small space at the World Science Fiction Convention that year, which displayed his works and photos during his lifetime, as well as some of his treasures, a simple A black and white TV plays interviews with him during his lifetime. In 2023, Aldis&#39;s daughter Wendy also came to Chengdu. She told Southern Weekend reporters that the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention was originally going to hold an exhibition for these photos, but it was not possible &quot;because of lack of space.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Feng originally planned to hold a commemorative exhibition at the conference. The person being remembered is Michael Resnick, the former editor-in-chief of the American science fiction magazine &quot;Galaxy&#39;s Edge&quot;. After Resnick&#39;s death in 2020, his collection and books were put up for online auction, and Baguangfen bought a large number of his collections. &quot;Look, this glass showcase is full of his things.&quot; Yang Feng pointed to a glass Cabinet said. At the beginning, the organizer promised an exhibition area of ​​70 square meters. Worried about missing the exhibition, the collection &quot;spent tens of thousands of yuan on freight to be shipped back.&quot; Later, the exhibition area was occupied by many technology companies, and Yang Feng was only given a glass showcase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Their golden age has indeed passed.&quot; Yan Feng said, &quot;And China&#39;s science fiction craze has many characteristics of the Internet. I see a lot of people chasing stars here and hear a lot of screaming. Especially for people like Liu and Guo Fan. The development of Chinese science fiction has its luck, and the boost from Internet culture is very powerful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xi, a local science fiction writer in Chengdu, believes that the current Chinese science fiction Science fiction is in the early stages of its third wave. &quot;The first time was the prosperity of all industries at the beginning of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the second time was the &#39;Spring of Science&#39; in 1979, and now is the third time.&quot; He said. Wang Jinkang, another science fiction writer who has stopped writing, also recalled the low ebb of Chinese science fiction in the 1990s. “At that time, Chinese science fiction was wild and wild and received little attention from society. However, there were also many science fiction fans. When we went to universities to participate in activities, they all I used chalk to write &quot;Welcome Mr. Wang Jinkang&quot; on the blackboard, and started communicating like this. The simplicity back then had its charm, and I still miss it very much. It is indeed different now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Can you There was a faint sense of a conflict between science fiction cultures in the conference venue,&quot; Zero Gravity News editor Ling Shizhen told a Southern Weekend reporter about his observations, &quot;but I don&#39;t think this conflict is harmful. Or things that are meaningless, this is a necessary process. Since you want to embrace a truly diverse world, this step cannot be escaped.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a university teacher, Yan Feng has not been in the classroom for a long time. He has met so many international friends at domestic academic conferences, which moved him quite a bit. “The divided world is becoming more and more isolated from each other, even confrontational and hostile, but science fiction must transcend national boundaries to think about the human level. Problem, this is also the valuable part of science fiction.&quot; As Liu Cixin has emphasized on different occasions, &quot;In science fiction, human beings appear as a whole.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan Brandt said Seattle The World Science Fiction Convention has secured the venue, but the local science fiction association is still negotiating with the hotel in order to get a lower price. Nicholas White said that he was a little &quot;jealous&quot; of Chengdu. He estimated that next year&#39;s World Science Fiction Convention in Glasgow would not be able to attract so much sponsorship: &quot;Obviously, the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention has received huge support from the local government, which is difficult to achieve in Europe. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Xi Xi and Qian Xing are pseudonyms, and Southern Weekend intern Chen Quanxin also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[试管婴儿纳入医保：不孕不育是医学问题，也是社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259718]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region Medical Insurance Bureau and other departments issued the &quot;About the Inclusion of Some Therapeutic Assisted Reproductive Medical Services&quot; &quot;Notice on the Payment Scope of Basic Medical Insurance and Work-related Injury Insurance Funds&quot;, which includes assisted reproductive projects such as egg retrieval, embryo culture, and embryo transplantation into the payment scope of basic medical insurance. The reimbursement ratios of employee medical insurance and resident medical insurance are 70% and 50% respectively. The new regulations will take effect on November 1, 2023. According to Li Rong, director of the Reproductive Medical Center of Nanning Second People&#39;s Hospital, according to the above notice, women with fertility difficulties can be reimbursed for first- or second-generation in vitro fertilization, ranging from more than 4,000 yuan to more than 10,000 yuan, depending on the type of insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This move once again aroused attention and discussion. Previously, several provinces have included assisted reproduction projects in basic medical insurance. Since July 1 this year, Beijing has included 16 therapeutic assisted reproductive technology projects, including in vitro fertilization and artificial insemination, into the scope of basic medical insurance reimbursement; Liaoning has also included 18 assisted reproductive technology projects such as embryo culture and embryo transfer this year. Reproductive projects are included in the catalog of maternity insurance. It is conceivable that more provinces will follow suit, and assisted reproductive technology will be included in basic medical insurance or become standard equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are mainly two types of families that benefit from this medical insurance policy: one type of family is for elderly mothers who have reproductive needs but have difficulty conceiving naturally, and the other type of family is for infertility (not caused by age factors) , such as congenital factors, reproductive history, lifestyle or environmental factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xuehong, an expert from the National Human Assisted Reproductive Technology Review Group, said: It is generally believed that the physiologically ideal reproductive age for women is 22-28 years old, or at least no more than 35 years old, because fertility or ovarian function cannot be achieved before the age of 35. It reaches a peak and then declines rapidly, and the risk of over-age childbirth will also increase; and, according to her clinical experience, the average age of patients seeking assisted reproduction has tended to become younger in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The demand for assisted reproduction in the first category of families stems from the fact that as marriage and childbirth continue to be postponed, the number of infertile people due to age is increasing. According to the 2017 Fertility Situation Sample Survey data, from 2006 to 2016, the average age of first childbirth for Chinese women increased from 24.3 years old in 2006 to 26.9 years old in 2016. In big cities, the age of first childbirth and childbearing is even later. For example, in Shanghai in 2022, the average age of first childbirth will be 30.36 years old, and the average age of childbirth will be 31.18 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the second type of infertile families, in addition to congenital factors, reproductive history is also a major factor that cannot be bypassed. In 2021, Qiao Jie, Dean of Peking University Third Hospital, released the &quot;Lancet Special Invited Major Report on Maternal and Child Health in China&quot;. The report stated that between 2007 and 2020, the incidence of infertility in my country increased from 12% to 18%. In terms of reproductive history, miscarriage, especially repeated miscarriage, may lead to postoperative salpingitis, endometritis, or even fallopian tube adhesions and uterine cavity adhesions, which may lead to infertility. The above-mentioned report shows that from 2005 to 2017, China’s induced abortion rate increased from 20.2‰ to 27.3‰. Among women in China who have experienced at least one miscarriage, the repeat miscarriage rate is 65.2%. The high miscarriage rate and repeated miscarriage rate are highly positively correlated with the infertility rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turning to assisted reproductive technology, such as in vitro fertilization, because of a strong desire to have a child is not an easy matter. Basically, it is a matter of luck to succeed once and for all. From eggs to embryo culture and then to embryo transplantation, problems may occur in every step and the success may fail. The pain suffered by the body and the pressure endured by the spirit cannot be explained to outsiders. The cost is not only money, time and energy, but also mental burden and wear and tear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, the inclusion of IVF in basic medical insurance can only partially cover the financial costs borne by these families, but it cannot fundamentally solve the problem of infertility, because infertility is both a medical problem and , is also a social issue. Generally speaking, if a problem is taken seriously before it appears or is in its infancy, the cost is the lowest if it needs to be prevented and solved if it needs to be solved. Waiting until it becomes a large-scale social problem before dealing with it will not only increase the cost exponentially. rise, and the effect is unsatisfactory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, the infertility problem that can be solved is: pushing the age of first childbearing forward to fall within the optimal childbearing age range, which requires early marriage and childbirth; reducing the miscarriage rate, especially repeated miscarriage rate, which means reducing or even avoiding unplanned pregnancies. This is better than resorting to assisted reproductive technology in the future. For individuals and families, it is obvious that they can consider and make decisions in this way. However, once a problem becomes a social problem, it is not that simple, because the essence of this social problem is a problem of values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people attribute the delay in the age of marriage and childbearing, the decline in fertility rate, and the rise of unmarried and childless people to the high cost of childbearing. But when it comes to fertility, the benefit side is obviously more important than the cost side. Nowadays, many young men and women ask &quot;What is the meaning of getting married, forming a family and having children?&quot; This in itself means a sudden change in the fertility instinct and the values ​​of marriage and childbirth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today we live in an era of unprecedented peace and prosperity. Material abundance is unprecedented. This will first lead to the reduction and disappearance of selection pressure. At this time, the population is more inclined to enjoy self-enjoyment rather than sacrificing self-enjoyment. , go through all kinds of hardships to raise offspring; secondly, it will lead to the rise of the concept of non-marriage and childbearing, which in turn will further suppress the desire to marry and have children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the high abortion rate, especially the repeated abortion rate, from a technical perspective, it is nothing more than a question of strengthening contraceptive measures; from a moral perspective, there is also a question of how to strengthen sexual morality. Parents should care about their children&#39;s values ​​and teach them by words and deeds to have a serious and prudent attitude towards sex: men should of course respect women&#39;s rights and wishes and assume due responsibilities; women, as the first person responsible for their own physical and mental health, should protect Regarding one&#39;s own body and reproductive health, in Chinese judicial practice, reproductive rights or reproductive decision-making rights are unique to women. The other side of this right means the ultimate responsibility to oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[茅台宣布涨价20%，你会考虑买吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR5qcV1BCEtlztjt7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR 5qcV1BCEtlztjt7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31, Moutai announced that it would increase the volume of Kweichow Moutai by 53% starting from November 1 (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Feitian, Five Star&lt;/span>;) ex-factory price, &lt;strong>;the average increase is about 20%&lt;/strong>;. This adjustment does not involve the market guidance price of the product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Moutai’s first price increase in the past six years. The last time was in January 2018, the ex-factory price of 53-degree Feitian Moutai 500ml was increased from 819 yuan to 969 yuan, and the retail price was adjusted to 1,499 yuan. According to this 20% increase estimate, the ex-factory price of Feitian Moutai may reach about 1,162.8 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moutai’s price increase also has a certain impact on the stock price. On November 1, Kweichow Moutai’s bidding opened 9.82% higher, with the stock price at 1,850 yuan, approaching the daily limit. Although it fell back quickly after the opening, as of 11 a.m., Kweichow Moutai was still up 4.74%, with an intraday turnover of 13.4 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June this year, Ding Xiongjun, chairman of Kweichow Moutai, said at the shareholders’ meeting that one must be wise when and how to raise prices. “If Feitian Moutai can raise prices, there will be more profits.” , the management thinks so too.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a price inversion in the famous liquor market, and Feitian Moutai is almost unique. Combing the ex-factory price and retail price of 53-degree Feitian Moutai from 2004 to 2020, it is not difficult to see that the ex-factory price has been rising all the way, and the retail price has increased by 757%. Among them, there are both the influence of market supply and demand, and consumers’ psychology of “hoarding goods to increase prices”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, Ji Keliang, former chairman of Kweichow Moutai, said, &quot;Young people don&#39;t drink Moutai because it&#39;s not time yet.&quot; Will the price increase announced this time have an impact on people’s purchasing intentions? When &quot;Moutai ice cream&quot;, &quot;sauce latte&quot; and &quot;wine-filled chocolate&quot; are released one after another, how many people will pay for that expensive sip of Moutai? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在3260米的香格里拉高山植物园，普通比浪漫重要]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259715]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden at an altitude of 3,260 meters. Visual China|Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is it like working in a botanical garden? This has intrigued me for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the countless late nights when I was incompetent in writing, I wanted to resign and go to the botanical garden to be a gardener. The dream soon came true, and the location was actually Shangri-La. In September 2023, I became an intern gardener at Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shangri-La, formerly known as Zhongdian, is located in Diqing Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Yunnan. At 3,260 meters, it is the highest botanical garden in the world. It protects about a thousand species of higher plants on land equivalent to 1/5 of the Summer Palace. There are many endemic species named after Zhongdian, such as Zhongdian rose, Zhongdian hawthorn, etc. Some of them are nationally protected wild plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The strange thing is that hundreds of plateau plants are bred here, and they are basically not exotic flowers and plants, or even &quot;ordinary and common&quot;; most botanical gardens belong to The Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden is a public institution with financial allocations, but it is a private non-enterprise organization with &quot;three noes&quot; - &quot;no money&quot;, &quot;no one&quot; and &quot;no establishment&quot;. It was planned to be established in 1999 and opened in 2005. It relies on itself to find a way to survive. road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All this gives Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden an independent and romantic color. However, after the short internship and interview, the romance had long since dissipated for me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a story about finding the meaning of ordinary seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Romantic&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Along the Yunnan-Tibet Highway, starting from Shangri-La County and heading northwest, the buildings gradually recede, and large tracts of golden highland barley suddenly burst in. Come into view. In early September, the Napa Sea formed by the melting of summer snow is gradually turning into the green Yila grassland, with horses roaming and white Tibetan-style houses glowing under the clouds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;View of Napa Sea from Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a corner of this paradise-like scenery is the place where I want to intern: Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 9 o&#39;clock on September 1st, I started from the east gate of the Botanical Garden, walked through the wild mountains, passed by fungi, climbed over the wooden fence, and almost fell, and I reached the mountainside. nursery. My task today is to move the indoor hypericum seedlings outdoors, and then transport the hypericum to the maze area of ​​the botanical garden on the top of the mountain with a tractor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tractor loading hypericum in the nursery. Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sounds so simple. The first step is to change equipment. I put on a red and black plaid bear apron that reached my ankles, put on plastic gloves, and held a big pink basin. The second step is to enter the nursery. A nursery is 24 meters long and 8 meters wide, which is equivalent to a classroom. There were hundreds of black bags on the ground, containing hypericum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 24, 2023, Huaian, Jiangsu Province, hypericum flowers were in full bloom in Jiulong Lake Park. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hypericum is a common flower in parks and greening projects. When it blooms in June and July, the slender bunch of stamens on the top are as bright as gold threads. The bottom petals look like butterfly wings, so they are also called golden thread butterflies. The hypericum I see now has been sown for two years and has not yet bloomed. It has slender branches and oval leaves. It is fragrant when you get close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I found that this botanical garden is different from the ones I have been to before. There are neither weird potted plants nor collections of treasures from around the world. On the contrary, there are many native plants similar to Hypericum in the botanical garden, including pink-flowered Zhongdian thorn rose, blue-purple Zhongdian aconitum, red-fruited Zhongdian hawthorn, standing Yunnan pine and alpine pine...their names Just carry local labels, such as &quot;Zhongdian&quot;, &quot;Yunnan&quot; and &quot;Gaoshan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhongdian Delphinium. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong, the founder and former director of the Botanic Garden, also has a picture of a native plant - Trichosanthes versicolor hanging in his office. He is 59 years old, of medium build, with drooping eyebrows, gray hair, and cheekbones that are black and red rendered by ultraviolet light from the plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong is from Weixi, Diqing. The local area lacks biological talents. His college entrance examination application was changed from the mathematics department to the biology department. After graduating from Yunnan University, he returned to Works at Diqing Institute of Plateau Biology. Later, he traveled throughout the mountains and valleys of Diqing and wrote the book &quot;Wild Flowers in the Hengduan Mountains of Yunnan, China&quot;. When he was almost 35 years old, Fang Zhendong wanted to build a world-class botanical garden in Shangri-La. This was also a romantic thing for him at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong was on an inspection trip to Niru High Mountain Area. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yunnan is the base camp of horticultural plants and has been known to foreign &quot;plant hunters&quot; more than a hundred years ago. There are at most 12,000 plant species in Europe, while Yunnan has 17,000 species, and Shangri-La alone has more than 5,000 species. Alpine valleys with large vertical elevation gradients became a refuge for plants during the Ice Age and a breeding ground for biodiversity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Scotsman named George Forrester was sent to China by the Edinburgh Botanic Garden. Starting in 1904, he conducted seven botanical expeditions in the Hengduan Mountains. . He hired eight Naxi people in Baisha, Lijiang, to move a rhododendron with a diameter of more than one meter from Gaoligong Mountain out of the mountains and transport it to the British Museum for display; he used mules to transport 31,000 Yunnan plant seeds and wax leaf specimens, which were recommended To gardens around the world, specimens are used by taxonomists at the Royal Botanic Gardens in Edinburgh to rename and publish new species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The azaleas and primroses brought back by Forrest from Yunnan are still being bred in the Edinburgh Botanic Garden, and the specimens are kept in the herbarium. In the 1990s, Fang Zhendong went to Edinburgh Botanic Garden. Looking back now, he is still very touched, &quot;Our local plant resources are valued by foreigners, but what about us?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While talking about this, Fang Zhendong suddenly stood up , found his copy of &quot;Wild Flowers in the Hengduan Mountains of Yunnan, China&quot;, pointed to a passage written by his mentor, the late botanist Mr. Qin Renchang, and read word for word:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yunnan The rich source of plants has contributed to the progress of European and American civilization far and wide. It is a pity that our country is backward in science. The Chinese people did not know how to use the treasures of talent to enrich their lives. Instead, they cultivated them in public and private courtyards in large cities and towns. The flowers that are being viewed are almost all imported and have been common in European and American gardens for hundreds of years. Once they enter the country, those who like them flock to them like birds of prey, sacrificing themselves for others, which is a shame. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This passage was written in the 1930s, but even in the 1990s, native species were not valued and were even threatened by alien species. The situation remains. Fang Zhendong still remembers that at that time, a kind of Eupatorium adenophora native to South America entered from southern Yunnan and approached Diqing along the Yunnan-Vietnam Railway. He worries about the impact of invasive alien species on the local ecosystem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Land use is also changing, with natural pastures being converted into cultivated land, and hillsides being exposed due to sand and stone quarrying. Fang Zhendong discovered that Diqing was originally the area with the richest wild orchid resources in China. In the 1980s, it was not difficult to find orchids every time he entered a ravine. But in the 1990s, the orchid craze took off, and outside owners bought the orchids by the truckload. Since then, wild orchids have been hard to find anywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So Fang Zhendong wants to build a botanical garden. &quot;The first is to conserve local species; the second is to develop and utilize local plant resources for garden construction and cultivation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1999, the Alpine Botanical Garden was approved as a project after discussion by the Yunnan Provincial Development and Reform Commission and the former Environmental Protection Department. A preparatory office was first set up, and Fang Zhendong was appointed as the director. In 2001, construction of the park started, and plants were planted on the exposed scars of sand and stone excavation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today, green trees grow from the sand pit in the Alpine Botanic Garden. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After I changed my clothes in the nursery, I said two words Don&#39;t talk, let&#39;s do it. I squatted down, used a shovel to dig Hypericum out of the bag, cut off the roots on the ground, and put it into the pot. One bag of Hypericum with seedlings and soil is about 4 pounds, and one pot can hold two bags. After installing it and getting up, I used the strength of my lower back to pick up the pot, walked 10 meters to the outside of the nursery, took out the seedlings, arranged them, and returned. Repeat this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Transporting Hypericum seedlings. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2, 4, 6... Every time I transport a pot, I count it silently. The number rises and I feel a sense of accomplishment. But starting from the 10th basin, it was a bit difficult to stand up, and my back began to strain. By the 16th pot, it was no longer a problem. I was gasping for air and my heart was pounding. Do you think I&#39;m weak? But I was doing weight-bearing exercises on a plateau three thousand meters above sea level, moving soil in a place where my speaking speed slowed down significantly and I avoided running and jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;20, 22, I can’t hold on anymore. At 10:36, it started to rain and the greenhouse leaked. More than an hour of moving work was stopped. I don’t know how grateful I am for this rain. When I stood up, my vision went dark. The light and the romantic imagination of the botanical garden disappeared in this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When building a botanical garden, will there be a moment when romance disappears?&quot; I asked Fang Zhendong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Yes, when it&#39;s time to find money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1999, the office to be built in the Botanical Garden was only It is a temporary agency and cannot pay insurance for newly hired employees. In 2004, the Botanical Garden Office invited relevant departments to a meeting to discuss the management system and came up with two options: one is to jointly build a public institution. The Xishuangbanna Tropical Botanical Garden of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the local government will each establish several establishments to jointly manage it, and it will be operated by central or local financial funds. , which is also a common system in domestic botanical gardens. The other type is private non-enterprise, which is responsible for its own profits and losses, has no financial budget and no establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We recommended the first set of co-construction plans to the government, but at that time the government&#39;s finances were still relatively difficult and the staffing may be tight, so we proposed the second plan. Take care of it first.&quot; Fang Zhendong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This plan paved the way for subsequent operating pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Botanical Garden was established as a private non-enterprise, the first board of directors was also established, and Fang Zhendong became the legal representative, chairman and executive director. The pressure came like a mountain, including finding construction funds, paying employees, and also needing to bear ecological compensation for the local community. In total, the annual cost of maintaining the botanical garden is no less than three million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although it is a tourist attraction, it is difficult to make money from tourists. At 17:28 on September 1st, there were still 2 minutes before the park closed. A total of six people bought tickets to enter the botanical garden throughout the day, two foreign tourists and four local tourists, and the total fee was 80 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some employees once felt that tourists now like to check in and take photos, and suggested that &quot;we should keep up with the times and create a cherry blossom avenue.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong denied it very directly, &quot;If you want to see cherry blossoms, go to the park to see them. We are not a park.&quot; He felt that the more important thing &quot;is to show the cherry blossoms.&quot; Domesticated local native species, (this is) our original intention.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Botanic gardens are often in debt. A friend of Fang Zhendong always lends him money. &quot;He is a scientist, not a businessman. He can only write scientific research reports and take on greening projects. Some (projects) still cannot collect money.&quot; Most people&#39;s stress lasts for a month or two at most, but Fang Zhendong persisted for twenty years, relying on scientific research and engineering projects to support it. The situation only eased two or three years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 24 years since its establishment, the botanical garden, with the efforts of 20 employees, has built many plants including the Fragrant Snow Medicine Garden, Linzhi Spruce Seed Garden, and Alpine Pine Seed Garden. A specialized garden. Although the business situation has improved, some ideas still remain on paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The sign near the south gate of the Botanical Garden says &quot;dry heat type&quot; and &quot;humid type&quot; exhibition greenhouse. Follow the direction and you will see two exposed greenhouses. Crushed limestone. Fang Zhendong made a calculation and found that there are two major parts in greenhouse construction, first is infrastructure construction, and then is species collection and cultivation. The initial investment is estimated to be more than 10 million, and subsequent maintenance will be even more expensive. &quot;Warmth preservation, temperature control, and humidity control must all be considered.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The greenhouse is still stuck on street signs and planning. &amp;nbsp; Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Tired.&quot; Fang Ye, the current director of the Botanical Garden, had tired eyes. Three years ago, he took over the botanical garden from his father Fang Zhendong. He wanted to build a smart scenic spot and improve the explanation system, but he was stuck because there was no one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local young people are more willing to work within the system, while outsiders find it too remote. Fang Ye finally found a person born in Guangxi in 1995 on Weibo. A college student who stayed for 4 years and left &quot;without saying anything&quot;. Four years is already a long time, and Fang Ye is recruiting people now and he doesn&#39;t expect to stay that long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Ye still hopes that the botanical garden can be merged into a public institution. Before the merger, this private non-corporate organization has to find its own way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the rain stopped, I counted more than a hundred bags of hypericum on the wall. A master gardener took off his apron, I saw him wrapped around a white jockstrap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Seeds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first step in raising hypericum seedlings in the Alpine Botanical Garden Nursery is naturally to have seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The gardener took me to see the seeds of Hypericum. As soon as I walked into the seed warehouse on the second floor of the nursery, the scent of rosin hit my face. This is the first time I have seen so many &quot;dry goods&quot;: the cones of alpine pine are like elastic brown balls, the seeds of lupine are like thumb-sized lotus pods, and the fruits of Nyingchi spruce are like hard and sun-dried roses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He grabbed a handful from a large sack and said, &quot;These are the seeds of Hypericum.&quot; I looked closer and saw that they were lighter than sand and smaller than sawdust. They ran away when the wind blew and multiplied with the wind. This is the natural law of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But it is difficult for humans to collect seeds. When hypericum planting season comes in November, the botanical garden will invite villagers to collect hypericum seeds in the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But not all seeds can be obtained from villagers. Employees of the botanical garden also have to go to the wild to collect seeds, while also inspecting very small populations and collecting specimens. Extremely small populations refer to wild plants that have a narrow distribution area, are severely disturbed by the outside world, and are on the verge of extinction at any time. It&#39;s extremely difficult to find them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;256377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Botanical Garden collects the seeds of S. truncatula. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The diary of an employee named Haixian recorded an &quot;ordinary day&quot; during the inspection:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 17, 2020, an ordinary day. Many major events happened in the world, but they have nothing to do with us for the time being. We walked in the back mountains of Naixia Village, Gyirong Town, Gyirong County, Shigatse Prefecture, the Pure Land of Tibet. We focused on field investigation work and were far away from the hustle and bustle of information. It seemed that all rumors had lost their carriers and became nameless islands. In such an environment, we seem to have a lot to say every day, and we seem to say the same thing every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Are you hungry?&quot;... To be honest, I am also a little hungry, but This is nothing...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s just that the body is like a sponge absorbing the fog and water on the mountain top. It&#39;s full of water, so wet that it feels like it&#39;s been stuffed in a refrigerator when it&#39;s taken off. A cold chill shoots out from your spine. Then the stove was stuffed into the lungs, and the cold air was sucked in, which made the lungs hurt. foot? I don’t have much hope for it anymore, I just hope there won’t be a strike before returning to my residence...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today I went too long and went too far. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Rising from an altitude of 2,800 meters to an altitude of 4,000 meters, just to look for Huopanglian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you can collect seeds, all this hard work will be reduced to a short line in the worksheet. For example:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Haixian, Fang Ye and other high mountain monitoring teams, In the back mountain of Jilong Town, Coptis chinensis seeds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unlike ordinary seeds that are packed in sacks, those seeds that have been collected with great difficulty are locked in a small room and stored with dignity. In each glass jar or plastic box, here is a seed bank - &quot;Noah&#39;s Ark of plateau plants&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Seeds in the seed bank. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The green velvet seeds in the small box are like crushed sesame seeds, at the 4786-meter Mangdongda Mountain in Qamdo, Tibet on August 7, 2022 Picked from the pass. Green velvet, also known as &quot;alpine peony&quot; and &quot;dream flower&quot;, grows on flowstone beaches or on the edge of glaciers at an altitude of more than three or four thousand meters. The whole plant is covered with downy hairs or bristles, and its color is clear and eye-catching. Three species of green velvet have been designated as national secondary key protected wild plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green velvet. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After harvesting, the seeds need to go through a process of soaking and seed selection. Empty or underfilled seeds will float up and be fished out and thrown away. . But Liu Lin was reluctant to soak the seeds of green velvet because it was too difficult to collect. &quot;It would be a pity to throw them away if the seedlings can emerge even if they float.&quot; The deputy director of the botanical garden is tall and has two blushes on her face. The table is full of plant tables. She manages the collection, breeding, domestication and utilization of seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are very few examples of successful breeding of green velvet. On December 5, 2022, Liu Lin and her colleagues planted a batch of green velvet. One month later, the emergence rate was less than 50%. Green velvet &quot;is most likely to die when it grows two leaves. It will die if there is too much water, and it will die if there is too little water, so it is very difficult.&quot; I asked her how many seedlings survived in the end. She pointed to the pile of soil in the distance and said, &quot;Look, half of them are already dead.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After working for more than ten years, Liu Lin has long been accustomed to accepting the death of plants. After many battles and difficult passes, there is still the process of tempering the seedlings after they emerge - taking measures such as ventilation, cooling, and proper water control to train the seedlings. She still remembers the Nepalese yellow flowers she planted for the first time. They were raised in a nursery greenhouse for half a year and moved out to refine the seedlings. All of them died in one winter, and only two or three of the 20,000 trees were left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We can only start over. They figured that maybe it was too cold and the transplanting season was wrong. So while the Nepalese yellow flower seedlings are still in the greenhouse, occasionally put them out to practice in the sun for a while, and then transplant them when they are firmer. There is no previous experience in the breeding of these plateau native plants, so &quot;we can only try to do it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Like the hypericum I moved today, the seedlings sprout easily, but for some reason, the seedlings tend to die when transplanted. So they came up with a new plan: fill the bag with soil, put the seeds in the soil, and when the seedlings grow up, just tear the bag open and plant it into the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我能看到的每棵纤纤金丝桃都是奇迹，历经生死。然而金丝桃并不属于珍稀物种，也没有进保护名录，刘琳、园丁师傅们费尽心力繁育的本土植物，最终要去哪呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;修复&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月30日，我跟着绿色和平团队在离香格里拉不远的一条公路看到，一些为修路炸开的山，裸露的地块上种了整整齐齐的杉树，可叶子发蔫发黄，在高寒的山里耷拉着。绿色和平的研究员不无惋惜地说，“这些树估计都是活不成的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘琳说，很多生态修复都是买外来树种，价格便宜，容易扦插，但很难适应当地环境，后期的维护管理也比较难，严重影响成活率。方晔解释，很多人觉得生态修复，就是一两年内检查验收时绿起来就够了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;香格里拉在1980、1990年代遭遇过大规模商业采伐，2010年后，大家意识到了生态修复的重要性。但是方震东感觉，最初的生态修复“根本没有好的理念和思路，绿化公司按现成方案找现成树种，也不管植物能不能适应（环境）”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;8月28日，我在香格里拉参加了一场关于生态修复的研讨会，来自云南大学、中国林业科学研究院的专家们也认为真正的生态修复不是单纯种树和绿化：在黄土高原不顾一切地种树，不让间伐，森林过密会给水源少的地方雪上加霜； 火未必是“万恶之源”，对于有的森林，火只是把表层烧焦，种子在火烧后给予时间，则会焕发生机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;研讨会后，方震东带我们去看大果青杄——松科云杉属乔木，国家二级保护植物。他说，政策规定谁砍伐谁恢复，大果青杄被大量用来造林。建植物园时，有课题组也申请退化林地的植被恢复课题，在植物园种了300亩的大果青杄。刚种上时生长很慢，到一米后快速生长，果实红而光滑，观赏性很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;方震东忽然停下讲解，寻找记者，提醒我记下来。他接着说，香格里拉一处景点有一片大果青杄林地，相继出现病害、虫害。有一种云杉鳃扁叶蜂会把这个树的针叶全部啃光。另外有一种真菌病害，树叶莫名其妙开始黄，紧接着整个树干就干枯，树成片死亡。香格里拉高山植物园也发生过虫害，但后来没有了，也许被其他的生物控制住了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但在很多地方，整片云杉被病害侵蚀，传入当地的落叶松。然而，本地云杉不会长这种病害。 “我们跟林业部门建议，今后造林了不要用这个（大果青杄）种，要用我们本地的云杉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;植物园里的大果青扦梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2006年，方震东领会到生态修复演替理论：植物群落是动态变化的，随着时间的推移，一个植物群落被另一个植物群落代替。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从裸露地表开始，草种飞进来演变成草本植被；鸟兽把灌木和乔木种子通过粪便排在这里，演变成灌丛；乔木十几年后长成优势植被，变成森林；不同种类的乔木经过幼龄、中龄慢慢成熟，上百年后成为顶级植被。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;采伐开矿则是重新将顶级植被打回原始的裸露地表，如果没有人为干预，自然依然会重来一轮演替。而方震东团队尝试把上百年的演替时间缩短，比如依靠风鸟兽传播种子要数十年，人工播种插苗则只需几天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;演替的过程中，有的植物被称为“先锋植物”，它们很快萌芽，覆盖住地表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“比如我搬运的金丝桃？”我问方震东。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“对，它算是一种先锋植物，在2000-3300米的海拔范围，在火烧地上能自然生长起来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;香格里拉植物园里的本土植物适应了高寒、恶劣的环境，在生态修复中，后续维护费低，也不容易受到病虫害影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近年来，生态修复失败的项目纷纷到植物园请教经验。困于经营的植物园也找到生存之道，不再负债。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1129&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;生态修复案例地恢复前后。 &amp;nbsp; 受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我去了一片生态修复的案例地。这里曾经因造桥而成为裸露的荒地，石灰岩、碎屑、碎石遍布。从2006年起，借助自然演替的理论，植物园培育的高山松苗、尼泊尔黄花木、皱叶报春、云南沙棘已渐渐成为先锋植物，“占领”了裸露地表。现在，被风吹来的杨絮也在此落了根，长成杨树。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;远处，天葬台的人骨已成碎块，红嘴鸦在松赞林寺盘旋。被人破坏的山野植物慢慢恢复，普通种子在这里生根发芽，岁月漫长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>