<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[总感觉自己被封印在床上？你不是一个人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the blink of an eye, the balance during the National Day holiday has been cleared. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The workers of this generation expressed their inseparability from the bed with jokes, &quot;I don&#39;t want to get up, I want to sleep until the sea is gone&quot; and &quot;The only thing I can afford now is The only thing I can&#39;t put down is the chopsticks, and the only thing I can&#39;t get out of is the bed.&quot; It seems that lying down all the time during holidays and having difficulty getting up during the workday is a post-holiday syndrome among young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of the pace of life and the increase of social pressure, more and more people are sleeping poorly and unable to sleep. Poor sleep has become a modern urban disease, and sleeping at night Lack of time and poor sleep quality means staying in bed until the next day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Staying in bed has gradually become a disease of modern people. The sound of roosters, the system&#39;s built-in ringtones, songs you like or hate, mixed ringtones... Various songs with different styles will always sound at the same time at the same time every day, but none of these can wake you up from your sleep. of you. &quot;Give me two more minutes to freeze my memory.&quot; Jay Chou&#39;s lyrics may represent the voice of many seriously bedridden patients. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Where does bedridden syndrome come from? Is it a unique product of modern society or has it evolved from ancient times? Will staying in bed affect your life? How do we say goodbye to &quot;sleeping in bed&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Crowing of cocks doesn’t work, even the ancients also stayed in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s not just modern people who like to stay in bed Beds, our ancestors more than 2,000 years ago actually loved to sleep in. The situation and conversation between them lying in bed may seem familiar to people today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two sentences in &quot;The Book of Songs·Zheng Feng·The Woman Said Cockcrow&quot;, the woman said: &quot;Cockcrow&quot;, and the scholar said: &quot;Meudan. Zixing looks at the night , stars have bad days.&quot; Meaning, the heroine said: &quot;The rooster has crowed.&quot; The subtext is that it&#39;s time for you to get up. The male protagonist struggled in bed and said: &quot;It&#39;s not yet dawn. If you don&#39;t believe me, open the window and look at the sky, the stars are shining brightly.&quot; Does the male protagonist&#39;s answer sound like what modern people say, &quot;It&#39;s still early, let me sleep for five more days.&quot; Minutes&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reasons our ancestors had when getting up are the same as those of modern people. In &quot;The Book of Songs, Qifeng, Cockcrow&quot;, another bed-ridden lover&#39;s answer is believed to have touched the hearts of many modern people. He said: &quot;It is bright in the east, the light of the moonrise.&quot; Oh, it is not bright in the east, it is the light emitted by the moon. This justification for staying in bed is equally applicable to modern people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the common people who love to stay in bed, sometimes the emperor will stay in bed according to his temper. It is often said in the play: &quot;The courtiers are waiting for the cold weather at the fifth watch.&quot; The ministers have to go to court every morning at the fifth watch, waiting to see the emperor. But the emperor sometimes didn&#39;t want to get up early when he went to court so early to listen to politics. The most famous one is probably the sentence in Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Song of Everlasting Sorrow&quot; describing Tang Xuanzong and Yang Guifei, &quot;The spring night is short and the sun is rising, and the king will not go to court early from now on.&quot; Tang Xuanzong was so obsessed with beauty that he stayed in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another emperor who was famous for staying in bed should be Ming Shenzong Zhu Yijun. During the middle and late periods of Zhu Yijun&#39;s reign, he rarely went to court. He did not attend the early dynasty for more than thirty years, becoming the emperor with the longest period of &quot;passive sabotage&quot; in the history of the Ming Dynasty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253245 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;There are a thousand reasons for those who stay in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Shu Guozhi wrote in &quot;Lying in Bed&quot;: &quot;Lying in bed, I have already woken up, but I have no intention of Get up. The body that lay flat for eight or nine hours the night before has rested enough, and the dream of traveling thousands of miles while sleeping the night before has also stopped. However, this lazy body is still willing to lie down, and the hairspring after the dream is still there. I want to float.&quot; I believe that seriously bedridden patients will sympathize with this statement. Everyone knows that staying in bed is a bad habit. But why can&#39;t I get up once I fall into bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The imaginative person said: &quot;On the first day, my quilt was sick, and I had to take care of it in bed. On the second day, although the quilt&#39;s disease was cured, But the bed was infected, and I had to take care of it together with the quilt. On the third day, they all recovered, but I was sick, and my quilt and bed had to take care of me...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;At this time, the psychological school influenced by Freudian theory jumped out and said: &quot;No, no. This is the desire of the id. People have id, ego and superego. When lying in bed, the id It is believed that the body needs more adequate rest in bed, and the superego requires it to get up out of compliance with the rules. People are always contradictory when staying in bed, because the desires of the id conflict with the norms of the superego.&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Scientists tell us that sleeping in bed is actually related to melatonin and light. A gland called the &quot;pineal gland&quot; at the bottom of the human brain secretes melatonin, a hormone that promotes sleep. Its secretion principle is related to sunlight: exposure to sunlight will inhibit the secretion of melatonin, making people in a state of wakefulness; when there is no exposure to sunlight, melatonin begins to be secreted, making people drowsy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Moreover, the time and body temperature when people enter deep sleep can also affect how quickly people get up. As shown in the figure, the higher the body temperature, the more awake the person is, and vice versa, so exercising more can ensure full energy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;245&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253247 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(Zhihu/Screenshot)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, Lai The relationship between bed and work efficiency is also very subtle. Milgram pointed out in his research that staying in bed is a unique type of procrastination behavior compared to other procrastination behaviors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Traditional research believes that the procrastination behavior of staying in bed will only have a negative impact on individuals. Research by domestic scholar Wang Lingzhi shows that students&#39; procrastination behavior will make them unable to complete academic tasks within the prescribed deadline, resulting in poor academic performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the traditional academic view is that procrastination will bring a series of negative impacts to individuals, some researchers have recently proposed that procrastination can also benefit individuals at some level. Bring about some positive behavioral consequences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Choi&amp;amp;Chu used a questionnaire method to divide procrastinators into active procrastinators and passive procrastinators in their research. They proposed that active procrastinators can do some things during procrastination. Make more thoughtful decisions and have higher arousal levels under stress levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t worry, staying in bed can be “cured” &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although, staying in bed is not a cure It&#39;s a disease, but if it happens while staying in bed, the consequences may be more serious than getting sick. So, how to “treat” this bad habit? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First of all, we must develop correct sleeping habits and develop correct waking procedures. For example, if the temperature in the bedroom is suitable, ideally the temperature in the bedroom should not be too low. Especially in winter, if the temperature difference between the inside and outside of the bed is too large, it will take a lot of courage to climb out of the warm bed. Don’t keep the room temperature too warm, as this will make it easier for people to fall asleep and feel groggy when they wake up. The ideal temperature is 16℃-21℃, and put a small basin of water in the room to prevent the air from being too dry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, the room should not be too dark. Research by Professor Maas of Cornell University in the United States has found that sunlight sends a signal to the biological clock, stops the secretion of melatonin that makes people sleep, and activates the awake neurons in the brain to help us wake up. Before going to bed, you can leave a small crack in the curtains, so that the morning sunlight can shine in through the window, telling the body that a new day has begun and it is time to get up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Be prepared and prepare an extra alarm clock. For some people, one alarm clock is not enough. If the alarm clock goes off, you will continue to sleep after it, and when you wake up, you will find that it is already late for work. Then prepare two alarm clocks. The set times should not be too close to each other, preferably 30 minutes apart. The second alarm clock should be set for a time when you must wake up. One is placed at the head of the bed, and the other is placed a little further away. You have to get out of bed to turn it off. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s no wonder that alarm clocks that deduct money if you don’t get up are so popular among young people. This alarm clock called Kello limits the number of &quot;naps&quot; the user is allowed to do after setting the alarm in a week. If the user does not get up and turn off the alarm after the preset time, Kello will deduct money from the subsidy in the APP. , are you still staying in bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, you must regain consciousness as soon as possible and massage your face. When you have just woken up and haven&#39;t opened your eyes, you can use massage to increase blood circulation and help you wake up slowly. First, use the palms of both hands to press around the eye sockets from outside to inside, then the forehead, cheeks, and ears. Use your fingertips to gently tap with different intensity until the entire face is touched. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The most important thing is to adjust the sleep rhythm. Getting up at a regular time and sleeping for as long as you need is the most basic and effective way to get rid of bed rest. Try to get up on time every day for a few days, and you will find that the time you go to bed is quietly advancing every day. Slowly, your body will establish a new sleep and wake-up pattern. You will feel sleepy at the fixed time, and you will feel sleepy when you get up early in the morning. Much more awake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, dear friends, don’t be reluctant to leave the bed. Start a new day by refusing to stay in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上交所、深交所：现阶段A股市场实行T+0交易的时机不成熟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange’s WeChat official account, some self-media said recently that A-share trading will be extended after the holiday. Time, and trial T+0 trading on some stocks. How do the exchanges comment on this? The Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange said that we are aware of the above rumors and the relevant content is not true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 18 this year, the relevant person in charge of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, when answering reporters’ questions about activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence, proposed to study the appropriate extension of the trading hours of the A-share market. This work involves a wide range of areas and has a large impact. The exchange is conducting in-depth research and demonstration in accordance with the unified deployment of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. In addition, the relevant person in charge made it clear in answering reporters’ questions in the early stage that the time for implementing T+0 trading in the A-share market is not mature at this stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;699&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253263&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;721&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大尺度、马赛克，十月新片要爆啊]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;Coincides with the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day At the end of the day, the movie theater also became lively. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Military films, suspense films, romance films, comedies, literary films...&lt;/span>; Various genres, you can choose from them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Let’s take a look at October’s theatrical films! &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(All new films released on National Day are included here)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Volunteers: Heroes Attack&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Chen Kaige&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Zhang Ke&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Tang Guoqiang/Wang Yanhui/Liu Jin/Xin Baiqing/Zhang Songwen/Huang Xiaoming/Zhang Ziyi, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-28 (Mainland China) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/c28d601678bf06f8d10cfb28c1142f6c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/c28d601678bf06f8d10cfb28c1142f6c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253145 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;To commemorate the 70th anniversary of the victory in the War to Resist U.S. Aggression and Aid Korea, the film series &quot;Volunteer Army&quot; will be gradually released within a few years. &quot;Volunteer Army: Heroes Attack&quot; directed by Chen Kaige is the first in the series. It tells the first and second stages of the War to Resist US Aggression and Aid Korea. It comprehensively presents the battle of Liangshui Cave, the Battle of Sansuoli and the Songgu Peak Blockade from a grand and multi-dimensional perspective. war. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1b2f09e4376f33ab2c5233934434c083.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1b2f09e4376f33ab2c5233934434c083.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253141 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is also the most difficult creation that Director Chen has encountered in his forty years of filmmaking. The film uses a 1:1 restored set and was filmed for more than 300 days. It was a star-studded film and the cast members underwent strict military management. The military images of Zhu Yilong, Zhang Zifeng, Chen Feiyu, Zhang Youhao, Ou Hao, Wei Chen, Yin Fang, Wei Daxun and other actors also raise expectations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a21b4613b57a8e548919228e1489d071.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a21b4613b57a8e548919228e1489d071.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253140 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;Director:&amp;nbsp;Zhang Yimou&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter:&amp;nbsp;Chen Yu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring:&amp;nbsp;Lei Jiayin&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp ;Zhang Guoli&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Yu Hewei&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Zhou Dongyu&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Sun Yizhou&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Li Naiwen&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Xu Yajun&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date : 2023-09-28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e160e0b32e17fd75dccf30e271c38f17. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ e160e0b32e17fd75dccf30e271c38f17.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253142&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; was completed in 2019, the first trailer was released in 2020, and it was finally finalized three years later. &quot;In addition to money, there is money, and there is also officialdom&quot; implies that the film tells the story of cracking down on gangs and eliminating evil. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Su Jianming&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Lei Jiayin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Li Huilin&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhou Dongyu)&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Work together to investigate a difficult criminal case, with countless overt or covert forces colluding behind it. Su Jianming ignored the dissuasion of his father Zheng Gang (played by Zhang Guoli), a high-ranking official, and rushed to Li Zhitian (played by Yu Hewei), a wealthy businessman involved in organized crime. >; Hongmen Banquet. But the closer you are to the truth, the closer you are to the abyss. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/25acfd48f6e17ba30bbcef85ad7c2cff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/25acfd48f6e17ba30bbcef85ad7c2cff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253143 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7486b93a340448da8353db5b00dc7a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7486b93a340448da8353db5b00dc7a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253144&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Due to the large scale of the crime-related content, including restricted scenes such as hands soaking in hot pot and corpses hiding in the wall, even the trailer is mosaic-ed in many places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5fd5a6c3edae13490ef3d2969add2ade.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5fd5a6c3edae13490ef3d2969add2ade.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253146 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The movies of &quot;National Master&quot; Zhang Yimou have always been a must-see. The urban crime theme involved this time is very topical, gathering &quot;men seeking men&quot; and &quot;women seeking&quot; They are also all capable actors. Judging from the high-contrast tones of the trailer, Zhang Yimou is playing with a very new neon aesthetic, which is very suitable for presenting Steel Forest and Vice City. I believe that &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; will have good box office results during the National Day season. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/65b7d4ac6d31a57187a9bc13294176b4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/65b7d4ac6d31a57187a9bc13294176b4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253147 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Ex 4: Marry Young&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Director: Tian Yusheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Da Kuan/Da Guang/Tian Yusheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Han Geng / Zheng Kai/Liu Yase/Zeng Mengxue/Yu Wenwen/Zhang Tianai/Zhu Yan Manzi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/590fcbd06d686fc86456a42ece892f3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/590fcbd06d686fc86456a42ece892f3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;Who would have thought that the &quot;Predecessor&quot; series would actually get a fourth installment. Although the ratings were basically below the passing mark, the box office of &quot;Exes 3&quot; unexpectedly soared to 1.9 billion, giving birth to &quot;Ex 4&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/628a1e9f5d40368b687090ad04439d49.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/628a1e9f5d40368b687090ad04439d49.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253148 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Exes 4&quot; tells the story of a new emotional problem for the brother who pursues love: Meng Yun who is experiencing the sequelae of a breakup&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Han Geng)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Embarking on a journey to find true love; and Yu Fei (played by Zheng Kai) and his girlfriend began a cooling-off period rehearsal before getting married. The lovable thing about urban romantic comedies is that their connection with realistic emotions can easily attract the target audience, and the box office base is there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d21e67fec5c8c78d8ace10fb3ba7981e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d21e67fec5c8c78d8ace10fb3ba7981e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253150 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t seem that passionate&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;Director: Gao Hu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Xing Wenxiong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Wei Xiang/ Wang Zhi/ Yue Liang/ Allen/Zi Yi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09- 28 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a6d02ac610771ec214e4cfd6e91b7ee5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1724&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a6d02ac610771ec214e4cfd6e91b7ee5.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;253152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is adapted from the Spanish film &quot;Basketball Champions&quot; and tells the story of the basketball coach&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Wei Xiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The story of leading a basketball team composed of mentally retarded people to realize their dream of winning the championship. The original version scored 7.2 points on Douban, ranking among the top 10 Spanish comedy films. The Chinese version is produced by the Happy Twist Team. Original scripts are their weakness, but the lovable actors give it a wide audience base. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a99c6f209d0af950695c835e1e4aee2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a99c6f209d0af950695c835e1e4aee2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253151 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the comedians we are familiar with, the film also uses some amateur actors. They are all &quot;young men&quot; with mental disabilities. This actually brings more difficulties to the filming, but It is of great significance from the perspective of a public welfare film. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;93 International Train Robbery: Operation Moscow&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Qiu Litao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Chen Daming&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Zhang Hanyu/Andy Lau / Huang Xuan/ Wen Yongshan/ Gu Jiacheng&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Producing country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-09-29 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a747b34e1648a3d415554da4b9df156.jpeg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1510&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3a747b34e1648a3d415554da4b9df156 .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1993, on a train from Beijing to Moscow, four groups of robbers carried out serial robberies on passengers. Chinese police infiltrated the train and arrested gangsters disguised as international gangsters. This film is adapted from this shocking case and restores the cross-border manhunt drama of the 1990s. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e0850332c4a8fa4301a24100b1856425.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e0850332c4a8fa4301a24100b1856425.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253154 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This film is directed by Hong Kong&#39;s talented director Qiu Litao. He is not only good at cult movies such as &quot;Human Barbecued Pork Buns&quot;, but he can also control action blockbusters such as &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; and deal with detective themes. It’s also very handy, and the whole story is very well completed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another highlight of the film is: Andy Lau and Huang Xuan break through their &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; images, playing tough gangsters and challenging villain roles; while Zhang Hanyu plays the role of a plainclothes policeman , sparks fly in the male group drama. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/675e7deb9ee73e86c1a9e27257c33a3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/675e7deb9ee73e86c1a9e27257c33a3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253156 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f045cdb7b213f74670a132de9c58c2aa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f045cdb7b213f74670a132de9c58c2aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253155&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Best Encounter&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Director: Ha Zhichao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Qiu Yan/Lin Yongzhu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Jin Shijia/Qiu Ze/Junning Zhang/Jiang Peiyao &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10-20 (China Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a9c1e4599b9b3a4b61ad4608c3b96103.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1547&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a9c1e4599b9b3a4b61ad4608c3b96103.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;253158&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the drama version of &quot;Detective Chinatown&quot;, Qiu Ze and Zhang Junning play a pair of equally matched high-IQ players. The combination of handsome men and beautiful women is very good-looking. In the movie &quot;The Best Encounter&quot;, they took off their fancy makeup and returned to simplicity, playing the role of a mentally retarded couple who want a child. The doctor played by Jin Shijia tried his best to persuade them to give up this unrealistic fantasy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ae56084ac971137609b18630672fe173.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ae56084ac971137609b18630672fe173.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253159 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/7b6c0d45f3ccb981dd5b9330b0907713.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/7b6c0d45f3ccb981dd5b9330b0907713.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253157&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Proving your acting skills through disfigurement is a path to transformation that is usually chosen by heroes and goddesses. But while paying attention to the differences between actors on and off the screen, we also need to realize the film&#39;s focus on social issues. According to the director, the inspiration for the film came from the welfare home he visited. He wanted to present his mixed feelings to the audience, so that more people can hear the forgotten voices of the disadvantaged groups in society. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Trapped Beast&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director: Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Deng Andong/Wang Qian/Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Starring: Chung Han-leung/Francis Ng Chun-yu/Cheung Siu-fai/Myolie Wu/Zhao Yanguo-zhang&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Producing country/region: Mainland China/Hong Kong, China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span>;Release date: 2023-10-27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 07/92caa33d628e6b4b38d0d39d145e6101.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/92caa33d628e6b4b38d0d39d145e6101.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to restore order in Hucheng, the government launched a thunderous operation to eradicate underground industries. Fourth Master &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhang Siu-fai) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Director Zuo of the Commercial Investigation Department &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Wu Zhenyu) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; secretly muddied the water. Trying to fight for management rights. Police Officer Jiang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhong Hanliang)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; led a team and started a black and white showdown with them. Myolie Wu and Zhao Yanguo Zhang also play important roles in the film, and we can see a group of veteran actors performing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e45ec8dddacc2a1f214a370bf963e4ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e45ec8dddacc2a1f214a370bf963e4ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253161 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2d69730a24d1cc138e7bb7d2fd8e24be.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2d69730a24d1cc138e7bb7d2fd8e24be.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253162&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Trapped&quot; is the most common crime genre film in Hong Kong. It is easy to make a living but not easy to produce a high-quality film. I wonder if director Peng Fa&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&quot;Hell&quot; and &quot;Ten Ways to See Hell&quot;) who is an editor can be meticulous in his script and make a &quot;loan to support&quot; movie. The scale and intensity of gambling and swallowing bones. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Second Hand Masterpiece&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Director: Wang Zizhao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Xu Luyang/Liu Xiaodan/Zi Zhao&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Yu Hewei/Guo Qilin/Ni Hongjie/Xu Enyi/Zhang Zixian&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10-27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/96fbf1663ba435465ccff8eb02a3b2ae.jpeg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/96fbf1663ba435465ccff8eb02a3b2ae .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is adapted from the American movie &quot;The Greatest Father in the World&quot;. It is a warm comedy with a rather absurd style. High school Chinese teacher Lao Ma (played by Yu Hewei) has reached middle age, but his literary ambitions have not yet been fulfilled. His son Xiao Ma&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Guo Qilin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; fell down a building and &quot;committed suicide&quot;. Unexpectedly, the suicide note Lao Ma wrote for him to save face became famous overnight. Lao Ma began to pursue his dream in the literary world, using Xiao Ma&#39;s name to realize his self-worth step by step, but Xiao Ma&#39;s sudden awakening made the whole thing get out of hand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1362bbbbf00003905f01af70b99fce60.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/1362bbbbf00003905f01af70b99fce60.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253164 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film is produced by Ning Hao and Yu Hewei and produced by Bad Monkey Pictures. Yu Hewei and Guo Qilin&#39;s comedy partnership is more eye-catching. Yu Hewei has demonstrated his skillful acting skills in films such as &quot;Above the Cliff&quot; and &quot;I&#39;m Not Pan Jinlian&quot;, and has also made a mark in dramas such as &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; and &quot;The Age of Awakening&quot;. With his classic image, he can be regarded as a top actor in the entertainment industry; Guo Qilin has attracted countless fans in variety shows and dramas with his lovable image, but his screen shaping ability remains to be seen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Director: Zhang Lu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Screenwriter: Zhang Lu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Starring: Xin Baiqing/Huang Yao/Tian Zhuangzhuang/ Li Qinqin/Wang Hongwei&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Production country/region: Mainland China&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Release date: 2023-10- 27 (Mainland China)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cbba5fa45c8752e7d6890f745a246d32.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cbba5fa45c8752e7d6890f745a246d32.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;253167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; is a literary drama film written by director Zhang Lu and tells the story of Gu Wentong, a middle-aged man who lives alone&lt;/span>;&lt; The story of span>; (played by Xin Baiqing)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and the young female photographer Ouyang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Huang Yao)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; met and got to know each other. Ambiguous feelings surged between the two, and they also re-examined the relationship between gender and parent-child. The film inherits Zhang Lu&#39;s consistent roaming style. He is good at photographing flowing spaces and capturing flowing emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a01a67d6e67658a9a06cdda0d3d2b942.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a01a67d6e67658a9a06cdda0d3d2b942.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253163 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Here, Director Zhang chose to work with Xin Baiqing, who had stunning performances in &quot;The Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; and &quot;The Long Goodbye&quot;, and Huang Yao, who had a stunning appearance in &quot;Over the Spring&quot; . &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; was shortlisted for the main competition of the Berlin Film Festival and won numerous awards at the Beijing International Film Festival. Audiences who like literary style should not miss it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f6043ccb6ef92433ad90b5ccabbe897d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f6043ccb6ef92433ad90b5ccabbe897d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253166 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The above are the new films we have selected for theaters in October, hoping to take over the summer vacation and ignite the film market in the second half of the year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;And which movie do you most want to go to the cinema to watch? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[张镇麟突破暴扣，中国男篮夺亚运铜牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258196]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Chinese men&#39;s basketball player Zhang Zhenlin broke through and singled out in the game Hand dunk.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/51777940be.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/51777940be.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253232&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese male basketball player Zhang Zhenlin broke through and dunked with one hand during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 6, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games men’s basketball bronze medal match was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium. The Chinese men’s basketball team trailed the Chinese Taipei team by 3 points in the first half and finally won. Completed the reversal at 101:73 and won the bronze medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，两名中国男篮球员在篮下防守中国台北队球员阿提诺。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a86bb3bb82.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a86bb3bb82.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，两名中国男篮球员在篮下防守中国台北队球员阿提诺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国男篮与中国台北队在9月28日的小组赛阶段曾有过交手，当时中国男篮89:69大胜。在那场比赛当中，中国男篮几乎全场占据主动，并没有给对手太多机会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员张镇麟在传球。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e879f8dc10.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/e879f8dc10.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253234&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员张镇麟在传球。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员王哲林在比赛中抢断。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2e5de377ce.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2e5de377ce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253235&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员王哲林在比赛中抢断。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月6日再次迎战中国台北队，中国男篮派出了赵睿、朱俊龙、崔永熙、杜润旺、胡金秋的首发阵容。但是整个上半场，中国男篮都显得不在状态。虽然开局赵睿命中两记三分共得到8分，但中国男篮并没有很快拉开分差，首节以21:29落后。第二节，中国台北队进攻成功率下降，而中国男篮凭借胡明轩、杜润旺和赵睿的三分逐渐追近比分，在上半场结束时仍以46:49落后3分。到了第三节，中国男篮加快了转换进攻的节奏，里突外投多点开花，单节打出34:10的攻击波后，中国男篮以80:59领先中国台北队。第四节比赛，双方在场上的进攻效率均不高，张镇麟连续得分还大秀暴扣，率领中国男篮进一步扩大领先优势。最终比分定格在101:73，中国男篮成功拿下亚运会铜牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员赵睿在比赛中上篮。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7f8bf600a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d7f8bf600a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253236&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，中国男篮球员赵睿在比赛中上篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，中国男篮队长赵继伟在比赛中上篮。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/925390d346.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/925390d346.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253237&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，中国男篮队长赵继伟在比赛中上篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，中国男篮在亚运会上的表现没有达到预期，尤其是在半决赛半场领先18分的情况下末节崩盘，以1分之差不敌菲律宾队，输掉了这场关键之战，未能实现赛前目标，对于整个中国篮球的影响都非常大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，赛后，中国男篮球员依次与中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明拥抱。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2706b7987e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/2706b7987e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253238&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，赛后，中国男篮球员依次与中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明拥抱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国男篮主帅乔尔杰维奇在半决赛结束后表示：“中国队现在最需要做的是团结在一起，在下一场比赛中抬着头走出来，去争取胜利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，颁奖典礼结束后，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明来到男篮球员们身边，献上鼓励的话语。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/30a055e785.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/30a055e785.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，颁奖典礼结束后，中国篮协主席、男篮领队姚明来到男篮球员们身边，献上鼓励的话语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，杭州亚运会篮球项目男子组金牌赛中，菲律宾队以70比60战胜约旦队，获得冠军。菲律宾队球员在颁奖典礼上挥手致意。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8ff1697e5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8ff1697e5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，杭州亚运会篮球项目男子组金牌赛中，菲律宾队以70比60战胜约旦队，获得冠军。菲律宾队球员在颁奖典礼上挥手致意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据统计，从1974年至2018年，中国男篮参加过12届亚运会，获得8金2银1铜，最差成绩是2014年的第5名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月6日，全场比赛结束之后，中国男篮球员绕场一周，与现场观众击掌致谢。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3f92f1a93c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3f92f1a93c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月6日，全场比赛结束之后，中国男篮球员绕场一周，与现场观众击掌致谢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这两年，奢侈品销量为何逆势上升？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258122]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2022年全球奢侈品市场进一步复苏，获得17%的同比增长，市场规模达25450亿元。而在中国，奢侈品销售额达9560亿元，占全球奢侈品市场的38%，国人依然是全球奢侈品消费的最重要力量。根据国际咨询公司贝恩公司预计，2023年的个人奢侈品市场预计将增长5%-12%，这是继2022年创纪录的增长之后的又一高峰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么全球经济有放缓的趋势，奢侈品的消费反而没有受到什么影响，甚至还逆势增长，这是一个比较有意思的问题。而且有的奢侈品品牌还逆势提价，保持其品牌的竞争力。比如，LVMH、爱马仕、开云集团三年来都进行了提价，其中，LVMH2019年至2023年3月份提价次数超过5次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于这个现象，美国经济学家凡勃伦提出了一个概念，叫作“炫耀性消费”。他认为，要获得并持久地保持一种荣耀感，光有钱还不够，你还得让别人知道你有钱。所以，炫耀性消费的主要目的不是商品本身，而是用这种消费把自己和其他人区分开。比如你要戴一块特别贵的名表，显然不是单纯为了看时间，而是同时为了向人炫耀，彰显你的经济地位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于奢侈品而言，恰好具备这样的炫耀功能。很多时候，奢侈品就是购买者给自己出具的财富证明。同时，涨价让能够买得起的人更少，买得起的人就越有优越感。这就有点像我们小时候的心态“别人有的我不能没有”，而长大后这种心态就变成了“别人有的我不要”，我必须要保持一定的优越感，不能让自己降低到那些人的层次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我们看到的现象便是，有些奢侈品价格越高，反而越受欢迎，因为这个时候它炫耀的功能越高，隔离的作用也越强。 2022年劳斯莱斯在全球约50个国家中，总共只交付了6021辆汽车，这是劳斯莱斯品牌118年历史上，销量首次突破6000辆。但是就这个销量，他们从来都没有担心过生存问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了炫耀性之外，奢侈品还具有其他几个特性。它会特别强调稀缺性，比如强调是限量版，强调使用的是名贵稀缺材料，或者强调纯手工打造等工艺的复杂性。另外奢侈品还具有社交属性和可模仿性，拥有同一奢侈品的人更容易相互认可，形成一个圈子，人们也很乐于模仿比自己更高阶层的人的生活方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奢侈品的消费不仅仅是一个经济问题，还是一个社会问题。所谓的奢侈品牌，是一个现代概念，但奢侈品本身并不是现代人才有的。即便是原始社会或者今天亚马孙雨林的原始部落，他们的首领就会在服饰上体现出与其他人的不同。这些服饰装饰，就是他们身份地位和权力的象征。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类历史长河的很长时间内，奢侈品主要跟权力挂钩，而不是跟财富挂钩。儒家的“礼仪”更是直接的体现，君君臣臣、父父子子，什么阶层穿什么衣服、佩戴什么服饰、行什么礼，都有明确的规定，都要按规矩来，不能乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只是到了近现代，随着工业化的进程，物质生产的繁荣，社会形态总体上从一个权力社会转向市场社会。消费水平也逐渐跟权力脱钩，并和财富水平挂钩。奢侈品的作用也逐渐从权力的象征，转变为财富的象征。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但奢侈品一贯呈现着其自上而下的特性，可以说它一直处于审美秩序的顶端，由社会上层定义和传播。在原来权力秩序更强的社会中，这种定义权来自权力的顶层。在现代社会中，这种审美的定义权同样来自顶层，只不过更多表现为企业或设计师的概念设计上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业家不断挖掘人们更深层次、更丰富多样的需求，然后市场在不断分层过程中形成分化，处于顶端的便是今天的众多奢侈品品牌。豪车名表、钻石翡翠，豪华品牌的衣服鞋子、化妆品，应有尽有，处处通过品牌和调性，彰显个性和身份的不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;富人或权贵通过奢侈品给自己贴上标签，既不能脱离这个圈层，也不能让别人随随便便进入这个圈层，这样才能维系他们的社会地位。所以即便奢侈品涨价，只要还在他们的承受范围之内，他们也会毫不手软，眼睛都不眨一眨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过这种奢侈品文化的形成，也满足了部分普通人的幻想，误以为拥有了一个名牌包包、高档的衣服，就真的跨入了那个阶层。这个时候，奢侈品就成为一个阶层靠近另一个阶层的道具。有时候这个道具是有用的，但很多时候其实作用不大，只是一种被刻意引导的高消费需求罢了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们都知道，造假要造全套，一个谎言需要用另外一百个谎言来圆。同样，挎上了名牌包包，身上的其他行头就不能太寒酸；而一身名牌，车也不能太一般。这些东西叠加起来，如果不是真有一定的财力，恐怕真要打肿脸充胖子了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年轻人需要当心这种精心构造的幻象，不要被奢侈品文化牵着鼻子走。很多时候，并不是你拥有一个名牌包包，别人就一定会高看你一眼。这些东西也许对建立第一印象有帮助，但更重要的是包包背后的那个人，其真实实力怎么样。高手过招，三两句话可能就知道对方深浅，而不会轻易被那些身外之物所迷惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实任何个人和社会经济体一样，一个社会想要发展经济，都必然要经过储蓄和投资的阶段。一个年轻人想要成就自己，到达一个更高的平台，更多时候也需要储蓄和投资自己，蓄势待发。名牌包包作为奢侈品，可以作为一定的手段，但它不应成为最终的目的和目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育的基础，在于如何理解“人”丨议教]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/AsoQGwZYVctwwR0mp5ZTs1EoJZsltI3cB1m4DK4e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;906&quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/AsoQGwZYVctwwR0mp5ZTs1EoJZsltI3cB1m4DK4e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月6日，浙江湖州，长兴县吕山乡中心小学，学生在捉迷藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为从事教育媒体工作，旅美教育学者、迈阿密大学亚洲/亚-美研究学科部原主任黄全愈的文章，我从2014年读到2023年，仍时时有不同感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“教育”其实有非常复杂的维度，从不同维度触及教育的问题，看待教育的方式就会完全不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最初从事的教育媒体，是面向家长讨论教育话题的类型。那时我对教育的困惑，或是反思，完全出自一种家长立场：为什么孩子会在教育中受苦？为什么家长会如此焦虑？如果教育就是要在一条漫长的逆流中，通过自我压抑与不断刻苦来安放“不被淘汰”的恐慌感，那么这条路走到尽头，我们的孩子会成长为什么样的人？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这样一种立场中，黄全愈的文章给我打开了一扇窗：也许有一种教育的范式，它主张孩子自由、快乐、散乱，但也有很好的成果，而且这种自由与成果的关系还并非“无心插柳”，而是有着与我们的认知完全不同的教育学内涵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是他的文章给我的第一种“读法”：教育有不同的视角。那么第二层的维度随之而来——我们可以学吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们的确学了很多新概念，比如STEM、PBL项目式学习、跨学科、大概念、元认知、探究式学习，等等。伴随着这些新概念的涌入，我自己也经历了一些转型，从面向家长的媒体，转向面向教育政策研究、学校组织或战略研究的专业媒体，因为我实在很好奇，家长抱怨和质疑的问题，学校到底怎么看？在各种试图“优化”教育的概念旋涡之中，学校到底在做些什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一脚踏进专业领域，我很快发现，学校可能比家长还要无奈，还要无辜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天的学校确实处于两难之中。一方面，素质教育喊了几十年，最近两三年演变成“素养”教育：2022年4月国家发布义务教育新课标，对学生素养的描述与要求，与全球最领先的教育理念基本一致。也就是说，无论在教育理想层面，还是在教育政策落实层面，我们的教育看起来都要向他所描述的那种景象靠拢了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于“另一方面”。我们的学校教育，在每一个节点都要考试。考试本身并不是一个问题，但考试的结果是一张门票，它决定一个孩子接下来将进哪一扇门，走哪一条路。也许对95后、00后而言，“门与路”的意义都不再有70后、80后那种决定命运的意义，但一种惯性的社会心态不这样想，反而为考试赋予了更刻板的意义：为了考高分而教育，为了不丢分而学习。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;素养与考试矛盾吗？这其实是一个很难想明白的问题。难道素养的发展不需要评估阶段性结果，不需要考试吗？ no.黄全愈在他的文章中明确说，他不是反对考试，而是反对“应试思维”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当考试只是一种学业评估时，它就好像是学生自己发出去的一张调查表，收回来看看自己还要在哪些方面发力，哪些方面需要寻求帮助解决问题。而应试思维实际上是一种评判思维，它由老师、家长、学校、社会……总之除了学生自己之外的一切人发出来，然后决定你是个成功的学生，还是个失败的学生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为由教育专业人士构成的组织，学校并非不了解素养学习与应试思维之间发生的抵牾，但问题在于，学校也必须做一道不由它自己发出来的试题，比如这样一个典型问题：“你们做项目式学习（或是素质教育、跨学科学习等），可以让学生成绩更好吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个问题看起来还挺合情合理，对不对？事实上，这个问题足以把一所有理想、有情怀，希望做点儿教育变革的学校打翻在地。因为一旦考试、分数、成绩成为“素养”的准则，那么把学生“养”出来的那种从容、耐心、支持、接纳的教育心态就会一扫而空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;追求结果的应试思维，本质上需要一些“反人性”的操练，比如机械化的准确率、高密度的时间管理，都需要这种操练。而素养需要的是一种生态，尊重孩子生长的节律，可能在很长一段时间内看起来无所作为，但成长最终会走向“自然熟”。然而，升学考试随时可以切断自然节律。无数例子告诉我们，在一种确定性的寻求中，孩子的天性和意志，成了最轻易被忽略的一环。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在教育内卷这件事上，利弊是很容易看清楚的，难的是取舍。对，孩子很苦，但孩子上了985；或是“你们都&#39;素质&#39;去吧，留我家孩子悄悄刷题”；学校也是一样，“家长只认升学率，所以升学率就是王道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育的症结，正如黄全愈在谈STEM教育的文章中提到的，“中国教育当前要解决的是素质教育的底色问题，而不是STEM 的具体课程问题”，更不是各种教育概念“加加减减”的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不断反思教育，最终就难免要接近一个终极问题：教育的意义到底是什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果教育是为了让少数孩子出人头地，那我们会迎来一个什么样的社会？如果教育是为了一种社会整体的向善与福祉，那么这样道德理想式的教育，对“我家的孩子”又有什么好处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为工作领域，我会看到各种各样的教育文章，看多了发现，教育本身存在一种个体与社会的张力。如果你只关注家长立场，看输赢，算得失，“制造焦虑”会是必然结局；而如果只站在专家、学者立场，看理论的推演、教学法的介绍，概念往往不接地气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《教育的基础》这本书中，有一句话让我特别有感触：“我们一方面说世界的未来属于孩子，但另一方面，世界却不属于孩子。”为什么这么说？因为我们的教育往往是凭着成年人的策略与计量、想象与设计，去规定孩子的动作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最近跟一些专家、校长聊到“拔尖创新人才培养”的话题，这也是接下来的国家人才战略。那么拔尖创新人才培养，会不会成为学校的任务、学生的试题？很有可能。会不会成为新一轮家长焦虑的靶点？也很有可能。那如何避免这种情况发生，而且能在一种积极的环境中实现拔尖创新人才培养呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄全愈写得明白：“创造性不是技能，而是潜伏在人的生理和心理层面的特质，教不出来，更遑论训练！”“只有当科学思维盘活科学知识时，知识才是力量。从这个意义上说，&#39;减负&#39;就是要培养科学思维，去减轻长辈的权威和人为的标准给孩子的负担，把死知识激活为青春洋溢的创新动力。”“孩子的智慧不是用来重复别人，而是用来创造自己的！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些金句散落在书中。创新本质上是一种破局，破除现有格局去探索未知世界，创新能力不可教，但可以培养，培养方式恰恰是创造环境，让老师“少教”，让孩子探索，然后“多悟”，从碎片化的多悟，变成系统化的认知，形成个性化的判断，最终是创造性的行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育不是非要逼自己的孩子站在某个不属于自己的潮头。这可以看作这本书的第三种“读法”——从教育中领悟人的价值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作者系《看教育EnsightEdu》主编&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[让纳米技术拥有绚丽色彩——透视2023年诺贝尔化学奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258218]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/FQYbemG8URIyG2yv7slZL84HQntDrXd8lGABUf3o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/FQYbemG8URIyG2yv7slZL84HQntDrXd8lGABUf3o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年10月4日，瑞典斯德哥尔摩，在瑞典皇家科学院宣布2023年诺贝尔化学奖得主时，实验室用烧瓶进行解释。周三，出生于法国的蒙吉·巴文迪、美国的路易斯·布鲁斯和出生于俄罗斯的阿列克谢·叶基莫夫因对被称为量子点的微小粒子的研究而获得诺贝尔化学奖。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京时间2023年10月4日下午，瑞典皇家科学院宣布将2023年诺贝尔化学奖授予美国麻省理工学院蒙吉•G•巴文迪（Moungi G. Bawendi）、美国哥伦比亚大学路易斯•E•布鲁斯（Louis E. Brus&amp;nbsp;）和美国纳米晶体科技公司阿列克谢•伊基莫夫（Alexei I. Ekimov），以表彰他们在量子点的发现与合成方面的贡献。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;量子点是什么？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;量子点，别名为半导体纳米晶，是由成千上万的原子构成的尺寸一般小于20纳米的半导体晶体颗粒。量子点具有特定的三维结构，通常是球形或椭球形，一般的量子点由镉硒或铅硫化物等半导体材料组成“核”；有时量子点的核会被另一种材料包裹，形成“壳”，以改善其光学和电子性质。量子点是纳米技术中最小的组成部分之一。一般来说，一种元素的性质取决于它有多少电子。当物质缩小到纳米尺度时，量子现象就出现了。这意味着元素的性质将由物质的大小决定，而不是由它所拥有的电子数量决定。量子点仅由一千个原子组成，相比之下，一个量子点之于足球，就像足球之于地球一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1937年，物理学家赫伯特·弗鲁里希（Herbert Froehlich）曾预言，一旦粒子足够小（即所谓的纳米粒子），它们就会受到量子力学奇特魔力的影响。为了解释这种量子现象，美国化学学会主席朱迪思·乔丹（Judith Giordan）在接受法新社采访时表示，“把它想象成一个小盒子，当粒子缩小到足够小时，电子会撞到盒子的侧面。”在一个更大的盒子里，电子撞击侧面的频率更低，这意味着它们的能量更少。对于量子点，较大的盒子发出红光，而较小的盒子发出蓝光。也就是说通过控制粒子的大小，科学家们可以把他们的晶体变成红色、蓝色和介于两者之间的任何颜色。但在弗鲁里希预测之后的40年里，才有人能够真正观察到这种现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;超小粒子的大发现&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;量子点是一种不同于分子的新型材料，由于量子力学的作用，只要调整这些纳米粒子的大小，就可以改变它们的性质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1937年，物理学家推测纳米颗粒中可能出现与尺寸有关的量子效应。然而当时似乎不可能在现实世界中重现这种效果。要做到这一点，研究人员需要一种完美的晶体材料，并且需要非常精确地控制纳米材料的大小，一层一层地进行雕刻，所以很少有人相信这一研究的可行性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在20世纪80年代初伊基莫夫和布鲁斯分别证明了这是可以做到的。伊基莫夫在有色玻璃中创造了尺寸依赖的量子效应，通过熔融玻璃的温度和加热时间，他发现能够改变产生颗粒的大小，颗粒越小，它们发出的光就越蓝。这个丰富多彩的实验让伊基莫夫成功地在有色玻璃中实现了与大小相关的量子效应。他的实验结果证明了纳米颗粒的尺寸可以通过量子效应来控制材料的性质，为后续的研究和应用奠定了基础。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎在同一时间，布鲁斯成为第一个在液体溶液中发现这种彩色量子效应的人，他展示了在溶液和气体化合物中自由漂浮的纳米颗粒的大小和颜色之间的联系。这些发现引发了人们对如何利用这些小点进行各种应用的强烈兴趣。布鲁斯也成为首个证明自由浮动纳米颗粒具有与大小相关的量子效应的科学家。他的研究为理解和利用纳米颗粒的量子特性提供了重要的实验证据，并推动了纳米技术的发展。他的工作对于电子学、光学和生物医学等领域具有广泛的应用前景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但要让量子点变得真正有用，则需要能够在溶液中制造它们，并精确控制它们的尺寸。1993年，巴文迪在麻省理工学院的实验室里，彻底改变了量子点的化学生产方法。他开发了一种方法来精确控制晶体在溶液中的生长速度，并找出了当晶体达到所需尺寸时如何阻止它们的方法。他首先向溶液中注入化学试剂，使其瞬间形成微小的晶体，然后迅速调整溶液的温度，阻止它们的生长。巴文迪革新了量子点的化学生产方法，使得量子点的质量大幅提高，并为其在各种应用中的使用铺平了道路。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;广泛的应用前景&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;量子点是纳米材料的“尺寸效应”的代表性材料，它在越来越多的领域得到了更加广泛深入的应用，从光电器件到光催化再到生物检测，几乎涵盖了人们当下以及未来的日常生活需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;量子点现在在基于量子发光二极管技术的计算机显示器和电视屏幕上发光。它们还为一些LED灯的光线增添细微差别，并且生物化学家和医生使用它们来绘制生物组织的图像。例如量子点使得非常精确地改变LED灯的颜色并显著提高其效率成为可能。这种发光的荧光点被注射到体内，附着在聚集到癌组织的免疫细胞上，可以帮助外科医生区分甚至很难看到的肿瘤。调节吸收不同波长的光的能力也可以制造定制的太阳能电池，在不同的情况下效率很高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;量子点给人类带来了巨大的益处。在未来，他们可以在柔性电子、微型传感器、更薄的太阳能电池和加密量子通信方面作出贡献，因此我们刚刚开始探索这些微小粒子的潜力。通过2023年诺贝尔化学奖的遴选和颁布可以发现，诺贝尔奖委员会不仅关注过去的贡献，还关注一项发现对未来可能产生的影响。通过改变纳米颗粒的大小或表面性质来调节纳米颗粒的能力，可能会带来各种各样尚未被探索的可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任殷美根被“双开”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258198]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;经中共中央批准，中央纪委国家监委对江西省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任殷美根严重违纪违法问题进行了立案审查调查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经查，殷美根丧失理想信念，背离党性原则，毫无纪法意识，对抗组织审查，搞迷信活动；无视中央八项规定精神，违规接受礼品礼金、出入私人会所；不按规定报告个人有关事项，在组织谈话、函询时不如实说明问题；借用管理和服务对象钱款、住房，道德败坏，搞权色、钱色交易；违规干预插手市场经济活动和执纪执法活动；对配偶、子女失管失教；与不法商人结成利益共同体，伙同亲属大搞权钱交易，利用职务便利为他人在职务提拔、工程承揽等方面谋利，并非法收受巨额财物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;殷美根严重违反党的政治纪律、组织纪律、廉洁纪律、工作纪律和生活纪律，构成严重职务违法并涉嫌受贿犯罪，且在党的十八大后不收敛、不收手，性质严重，影响恶劣，应予严肃处理。依据《中国共产党纪律处分条例》《中华人民共和国监察法》《中华人民共和国公职人员政务处分法》等有关规定，经中央纪委常委会会议研究并报中共中央批准，决定给予殷美根开除党籍处分；由国家监委给予其开除公职处分；终止其江西省第十五次党代会代表资格；收缴其违纪违法所得；将其涉嫌犯罪问题移送检察机关依法审查起诉，所涉财物一并移送。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[自由的健康的创作，很好丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;176&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（相关报道详见《&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/257431&quot; title=&quot;导演王沐和他的“温柔壳”&quot;>;导演王沐和他的“温柔壳”&lt;/a>;》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我采访青年导演王沐时，他反复说起自己以前算不上职业编剧——从2010年退出戏剧圈，到2018年他想拍自己的电影前这段时间，他是一个电影、电视编剧。他不喜欢改稿、开会，不认可、也不讲那套也许夹杂了电影编剧工具书理论和互联网平台“打法”的话语体系。他甚至不见演员，不去片场，也不比较自己的剧本和最终的成品之间有何区别。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为文字工作者，我对他的做法实在感同身受：只做自己想做的事，不做任何不想做的事；同时又觉得他能在自己设立规定的小世界里活着、赚钱，是多么难，同时又多么幸运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在为这个题做李霄峰导演的周边采访时（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他与王沐几度合作&lt;/span>;），我更加羡慕那样的氛围。大家在创作观上有共鸣，对彼此的人格和才能抱着信任——这是基础，在此之上，李霄峰给了个通俗的形容，“谁掌刀子谁吃肉”，这一稿谁写，就带着谁的特点。大家不需要拧在一块儿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李霄峰说，创作自由特别重要，它也许不稳定，但能保证身心健康。我能理解李霄峰说的“不稳定”指什么。他导演、王沐参与编剧的《少女哪吒》和《灰烬重生》的豆瓣评分都不特别高，但我很喜欢。充分尊重每个人的意见和创作脾性，效果不一定够好，但是参与者一定很舒畅，有的观众也会看得很开心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王沐和李霄峰还有过一次合作。王沐写的剧本《被水催眠》在釜山国际电影节拿了个剧本奖，因为缺乏资金，没有拍出来。但当然，是否成功不是最重要的，至少不是唯一有效的标准。在这点上，我认为他们的创作回归了创作本体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对王沐的采访不如我想象中顺利。他不是一个迷影型的导演，而我是戏剧的门外汉。采访他本人时，几经来回，我还是没能全然理解，戏剧在他心中的分量远重于电影，意味着什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周边采访帮助了我。李霄峰讲起，王沐是个严肃的创作者，他喜欢契诃夫，他的小说文字风格很凝滞，他的家里摆着鲁迅的半身像。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李霄峰还讲起他们的第一次合作是《灰烬重生》的剧本。这部戏里，2010年代的人不得不回望1990年代，那时伦理关系巨变，震荡发生在人的内心。剧本以前叫《追·踪》，王沐加入时已经有七稿。主角之一徐峰，李霄峰他们设想过好几种身份，修理厂职工、邮递员，等等。王沐把徐峰的职业改成工人。李霄峰顿时觉得准确，“那个电影其实是包含了很多对社会形态的思考，王沐把徐峰写成受家庭、社会变迁影响很大的年轻人，又很纯真，把徐峰那种纯净和我们对工人阶级的情感统一起来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我又想起《温柔壳》，王沐给那对精神创伤、互相救赎的年轻男女主角寻找形象参考，戴春是彼得·谢福《伊库斯》里的艾伦，觉晓是索福克勒斯写过的希腊神话里的安提戈涅。李霄峰说他看《温柔壳》，感觉到“有一点点凝滞的东西，王沐笔下的人物，灵魂的质量和密度比较高”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在想来，作为青年导演的首作，没有流量明星，没有像这几个月的电影一样跑无尽的路演，能拿到超过1200万票房，算很不错。我希望好的作品能够让更多人看到，好的导演可以走更远，自由的创作可以彰显其价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国银行原党委书记、董事长刘连舸严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:21:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;经中共中央批准，中央纪委国家监委对中国银行股份有限公司原党委书记、董事长刘连舸严重违纪违法问题进行了立案审查调查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;经查，刘连舸丧失理想信念，背弃初心使命，落实党中央决策部署不坚决、打折扣，弃守金融风险防控职责，大肆违规插手信贷项目，违法发放贷款，造成重大金融风险，履行全面从严治党主体责任不力，严重破坏所在单位政治生态，私自携带违禁书刊入境，处心积虑对抗组织审查；无视中央八项规定精神，违规收受礼品礼金、出入私人会所、接受滑雪和旅游安排，长期借用管理对象车辆；不按规定报告个人有关事项，在组织函询时不如实说明问题，徇私录用调整提拔干部；违规经商办企业；违规干预资金借贷，私自留存涉密资料；道德败坏，家风不正，对亲属失管失教；毫无纪法底线，擅权妄为，“靠金融吃金融”，利用职务便利为他人在贷款融资、项目合作等方面谋利，并非法收受巨额财物。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;刘连舸严重违反党的政治纪律、组织纪律、廉洁纪律、工作纪律和生活纪律，构成严重职务违法并涉嫌受贿、违法发放贷款犯罪，且在党的十八大后不收敛、不收手，性质严重，影响恶劣，应予严肃处理。依据《中国共产党纪律处分条例》《中华人民共和国监察法》《中华人民共和国公职人员政务处分法》等有关规定，经中央纪委常委会会议研究并报中共中央批准，决定给予刘连舸开除党籍处分；按规定取消其享受的待遇；终止其党的二十大代表资格；收缴其违纪违法所得；将其涉嫌犯罪问题移送检察机关依法审查起诉，所涉财物一并移送。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[救援队分析上海4岁女童走失情况：事发地系泥沙滩，沙质不好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月4日，一名4岁女童在上海浦东南汇新城海滩走失，至今已失联超60小时。当地警方、消防和民间救援队等多方力量连日搜寻，7日，参与搜救的上海蒲公英救援队队长李晨光告诉南都记者，6日晚上海水退潮后，救援队沿退潮后的海岸线在防浪堤中搜寻女童身影，但目前仍未找到。其介绍，女童走失的沙滩是一个离岸流冲击出的泥沙滩，并非景区，“一直不鼓励大家进，但是天气好的时候的确每天都有人在这里玩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于女童走失时距离海岸究竟多远的争议，李晨光向南都记者分析，如果女童是17时30分左右走失，女童父亲离开时离岸边并没有其所说的两三百米那么远，按照近日水文情况估计，事发位置距离岸边约100米左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据浦东警方通报，女童父亲称事发时其返回岸边取手机，将女童独自留在沙滩上，十余分钟后返回未找到女儿。监控显示女童在原地等候约10分钟后，向水边走去，在水边摔倒后消失在海浪中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;走失的女童。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4岁女童消失在海浪中&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月5日凌晨，女童父母在社交平台上发布求助信息，称其女儿于10月4日17时20分左右在南汇新城海滩上走失，4岁半，身高108cm，身穿蓝色艾莎公主连衣裙，未穿鞋袜，头顶两侧各梳一个蝴蝶结，发尾各两个小辫子，头戴黄色蝴蝶发带。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据上海市公安局浦东分局6日发布的警情通报，10月4日18时40分许，女童父母到浦东公安分局临港新城派出所求助，称其4岁的女儿在海边游玩时走失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;女童父亲称，当天携家人至海边游玩，其带领女儿黄某某到达离海水约20米左右的沙滩玩耍。过程中，其返回取手机，将女童独自留在沙滩上，十余分钟后，其回到沙滩后未找到女儿，因天色昏暗找寻未果，遂向警方求助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接报后，浦东警方立即组织大量警力沿海边展开拉网式搜索，消防部门出动了红外感应无人机，相关人员进行了彻夜搜寻，始终未发现女童踪迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次日，浦东警方会同消防救援总队，组织蓝天、厚天等6支救援队伍近200人开展全方位搜索。同时，组织人员对海滩周围20余个监控探头逐一排查，初步排除了女童被他人带离海滩的可能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因现场探头距离很远，人在图像中只能显示为模糊的白点。直至傍晚，其父最终在监控中指出了自己和女童分开时的准确方位，民警据此在图像中的近百人里发现了疑似女童的身影，其在原地等候约10分钟后，向水边走去，在水边摔倒后消失在海浪中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通报称，目前，浦东警方已协调上海海洋大学和海事大学的水文专家分析水流走向，以进一步开展搜寻工作。广大市民如有相关线索，请及时与警方联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;搜救队员称事发时女童距岸边约百来米&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月7日，上海蒲公英救援队队长李晨光告诉南都记者，他们从5日上午接到求助，5日、6日连续两晚，前后大概有6支救援队共200多人参与了搜寻工作。“昨天下午公安确认了小朋友是被海水卷走，我们外围的搜索就停止了，之后的搜寻工作集中晚上6点多退潮之后，沿着退潮的海岸线在防浪堤里搜寻，因为女童有可能被冲回来，卡在防浪堤里面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晨光告诉南都记者，当地公安和消防在4日晚上已经搜索过一遍，5日、6日两晚的搜索还是没有找到女童。“昨天海警也到了现场，可能下一步主要政府的力量多一些。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据李晨光介绍，事发沙滩是一个离岸流冲击出的泥沙滩，沙质并不好，并非景区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这个滩涂现在是不让进的，其实一直以来都不鼓励大家进，包括这个事主他们也是翻过去的。这边海岸线比较长，天气好的时候，的确每天都有人在这边玩，包括我们自己有时候也会在这里玩，但海水还是挺危险的，这次也提醒大家注意安全，特别是看管好孩子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于女童走失时距离海岸究竟多远的争议，李晨光向南都记者分析，如果女童是17时30分左右走失，女童父亲离开时离岸边并没有其所说的两三百米那么远。“因为根据最近的水文情况，这个时间段露出的海滩面一共也只有一两百米，（他们所在的地方）大概离水面是20米，离岸边应该是在100米左右。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>