<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[傅首尔与老刘闹离婚说明了什么？“全职丈夫”难以得到尊重]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257545]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The divorce between Fu Seoul and Lao Liu on the show made the variety show earn enough traffic, but it still It is a soap opera in life. Although it cannot be said to be a bad drama, it is also a plot that many people like me don&#39;t like to watch at all. Even so, we can still learn enough &quot;lessons&quot; from this incident. One of them is that men should be &quot;full-time husbands/full-time dads&quot; because society&#39;s acceptance of this is too low and it is difficult to be respected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Seoul and Lao Liu have experienced &quot;poor and lowly couples suffer all kinds of sorrows&quot; and can be regarded as a couple in need. After Fu Seoul rose to prominence through &quot;Qi Pa Shuo&quot;, Lao Liu began his career as a complete &quot;full-time husband&quot; and the source of Fu Seoul&#39;s jokes. In terms of the height an individual can achieve, Fu Seoul is definitely a strong woman and a successful person who uses knowledge and eloquence to embark on a unique track. There is no doubt about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Lao Liu returned to the family and became a full-time husband, the good stories about their marriage have existed on the Internet for a long time. Every time he participates in the show, Fu Seoul will almost always talk about how good Lao Liu is to him. Fu Seoul and Lao Liu had divorced once before. Later, they remarried. The reason was that Fu Seoul, who was on the rise in his career, had a mess in his work and life after the divorce. Fu Seoul also publicly described this marriage as &quot;the best marriage I could ever encounter.&quot; If this is the case, then why should we go to that step again at this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because, the status and relationship between the two people are no longer what they used to be. The ancient saying that &quot;time and status change people&quot; must also exist in marriage relationships. The &quot;economic ability determines family status&quot; that today&#39;s people lament is actually the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Lao Liu has advanced in the life of a stay-at-home husband to the point where Fu Seoul kicks him and &quot;knows it&#39;s time to pour out the water&quot;, and Fu Seoul asks Lao Liu to throw away the garbage even though there is a trash can next to him. , they will never &quot;go back&quot;. Regarding the happiness of marriage, there are only feelings left. &quot;I can guarantee that my husband is very happy to be a stay-at-home dad, and I can make money to support the family.&quot; When Fu Seoul said this, Lao Liu was experiencing the most difficult time. This shows that Fu Seoer no longer understands his husband. And Lao Liu also lost himself in being misunderstood and became a symbol. Although he said that he didn&#39;t mind being used as a joke and ridiculed by Fu Seoul on the show, the subtext I realized was: The premise is that you have to respect me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, what did Fu Seoul say? She said: Do you know why a person keeps making salted fish? Because he is suitable to be a salty fish. Once the belief of not seeking improvement is formed, he will even breathe slower than others. You should not push him, because there is no harm if there are no expectations. Of course, there is an element of &quot;program need&quot; in such a statement, but too many details have already revealed that Fu Seoul is increasingly intolerant of Liu&#39;s &quot;not seeking to improve&quot;. She may not even realize that she has regarded Liu as a Stephen Chow It&#39;s a waste of words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger wrote: Lao Liu was forced to struggle by Fu Seoul. Which full-time housewife has experienced this? Lao Liu became the material for Fu Seoul&#39;s jokes. Which full-time housewife has experienced this? Lao Liu needs to report accounts to Fu Seoul. How many full-time housewives have experienced this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is indeed not necessarily true. For example, some jokesters will also &quot;operate&quot; on their wives, but overall, Lao Liu&#39;s experience is indeed the real experience of &quot;full-time husbands&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago, an old acquaintance quit his job and became a full-time &quot;housewife&quot; because he had to take care of his children. Although he talked about the pleasure of having a lot of free time when he was drinking with us, in his heart, he became increasingly intolerable to a life where he had to look at his wife&#39;s face even for pocket money and clothes. This is the same thing as the case where Lao Liu wanted to buy clothes he liked but because Fu Seoul didn&#39;t like them, his expectations were wiped out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All the shocking details do not appear out of thin air and have no direction. To put it bluntly, whether it is Lao Liu or some &quot;house men&quot;, they have lost the respect of their wives and been rejected, which has become a normal feature of life. It’s hard to imagine how long this kind of lack of understanding and respect can last. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people didn’t understand Lao Liu’s complaints, thinking it was pretentious and something he did in his spare time. But if the identity were to be changed - if the husband had all kinds of dislikes and restrictions on the stay-at-home wife, wouldn&#39;t many people be upset? In addition, if a stay-at-home housewife complains that she is under great pressure, she is often sympathized with, but you see, after Lao Liu’s difficulties were revealed, many people accused him of not knowing how to be blessed despite being blessed, and of not being considerate of Fu who worked hard outside. Seoul. What a double standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between a full-time wife and a full-time husband exists objectively. Simply put, stay-at-home wives are more tolerated, while stay-at-home husbands are not. This nature has transcended the scope of a family. The pressure faced by that old acquaintance was not limited to his wife, but also came from the strange looks from the people around him. Some netizens also mentioned various bitternesses when commenting on Fu Seoul and Lao Liu&#39;s divorce. For example, no matter how you explain the &quot;force majeure&quot; of being a stay-at-home husband, you may still be regarded as a &quot;soft ricer.&quot; I would like to ask, have women been looked down upon as &quot;soft rice eaters&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When traditional social concepts have shaped men into &quot;family breadwinners and family responsibility bearers&quot;, in the eyes of some people, it is unforgivable for men to return to the family. This proves that men actually lack the public opinion environment to become full-time husbands. If you do it accidentally, you have to change it. A male compatriot I know started working odd jobs after being unemployed for many days and relying on his wife to support the family. He didn&#39;t make much money and was still looked down upon by his wife, but at least he could &quot;straighten his back a little&quot; in front of his neighbors. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that marriage is based on love. Isn’t marriage based on respect? First, if a man really needs to be a full-time husband, the prerequisite must be that he can be respected by his family and society. Since being a full-time wife is a job for a woman, it is also a job for a man to be a full-time husband. He should not be labeled as &quot;eating soft food&quot; or &quot;receiving charity&quot;. Secondly, since the concept that men cannot eat soft rice is still solidified, then a man must think clearly whether his choice is appropriate, whether he can withstand the pressure caused by it in the future, and whether there is a better choice than being a full-time husband. Options? The reality is cruel. When the subtlety and even contradictions in the relationship between husband and wife gradually become apparent due to one&#39;s &quot;full-time&quot; choice, can one calmly bear the consequences of being unhappy or even being confused? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[去珠峰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257428]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/gZ8MqmWkWhwE91TzmJdUkCKkearqzv7ohY6Hk2KN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2434&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/gZ8MqmWkWhwE91TzmJdUkCKkearq zv7ohY6Hk2KN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Dingri County, Shigatse, Tibet, overlooking Mount Everest from Rongbuk Temple&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going to Mount Everest requires a border defense permit. We submitted a letter of introduction from a magazine at the Lhasa Border Defense Building, but were told that letters of introduction from other places were invalid. When I was a little embarrassed, the window staff suddenly said, I am your reader, and I will help you tell the boss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SP0jcLsFlokPAIAuSB21cY5GvxRL2ntPaIhtjA3n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2505&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SP0jcLsFlokPAIAuSB21cY5GvxRL2ntPaIhtjA3n.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tibetans make a pilgrimage to Lhasa on foot, with ladders to heaven painted on the stone walls on the roadside&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The border defense permit was successfully obtained. The staff member stamped it and asked, &quot;When will this issue of your magazine be released? I want to go to the post office to buy it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to the Tibetans who were pilgrims at the Jokhang Temple, we set off first to Shigatse and then to the foot of Mount Everest. The sky was high and the clouds were thick along the way, first passing through sparse yellow-green grasslands and the Brahmaputra Grand Canyon, and then the continuous barren mountains. There are no plants on the mountain, and the hard rocks are exposed. The vegetation on the roadside is thin and yellow, as if it has a depressed face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bfte0vF0GhAwBdb19PvAnkX8T5g1rvRbBbnXQjfY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2523&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bfte0vF0GhAwBdb19PvAnkX8T5g1rvRbBbnXQjfY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lhasa Barkhor Street (also known as Bajiao Street), Tibetan pilgrims&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter&#39;s meal/picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is my first time to Tibet. This place is vast and magnificent, with nature’s generous gifts in inaccessible places, uncanny craftsmanship, and orderly order. But apart from these kind words, I was first shocked by the harsh natural environment in southwestern Tibet. It is vast but also desolate, strange mountains are also obstacles, and it is difficult to maintain its original style and economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I suddenly understood why I would enjoy honors and awards after returning from aiding Tibet, and why the Tibetan director Kashenga told the story of Tibetans and modernization. Here, modernization came late and moved slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3mE4xj0PsHTmDn1OEhldufpANHMOEVX1WjNOVpNX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height= &quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3mE4xj0PsHTmDn1OEhldufpANHMOEVX1WjNOVpNX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251353&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Hello tourists!&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter&#39;s food/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On National Highway 349, photographer Dashi suddenly stopped and saw a dead donkey on the roadside. He came closer to take pictures and told me to stay away. Lots of flies, he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know what the dead donkey looked like, but I was reminded of Tibetan director Wanma Tseden’s &quot;Killing a Sheep&quot;. This was originally his short story and was later adapted into a movie. It won the Best Screenplay in the Horizon Section at the 2018 Venice Film Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ctR4WMictrYBindrHHzzZmiDnEhoM0zXvSvIac3A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2490&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ctR4WMictrYBindrHHzzZmiDnEhoM0zXvSvIac3A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251361&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tashilhunpo Monastery, monks coming down the mountain&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&quot;I took another look at the sheep&#39;s body. The corners of the sheep&#39;s mouth were bleeding more, and the half-open eyes had lost their luster. I stood up, walked to the roadside and looked around, but there was nothing everywhere. , empty. There are only fluctuations of heat waves.&quot; Director Wanma wrote in the novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before arriving in Tibet, I had interviewed many members of the Everest scientific expedition team. One night, I was sitting and chatting with a geographer on the playground of Lanzhou University. He told a thrilling story about the scientific expedition on Mount Everest: a strong man with severe altitude sickness was lifted off a relay from an altitude of 6,300 meters. He got lost in the dark, snow fell on Mount Everest, and dangers arose one after another. He talked about the accident on the plateau, and I added: Wanma Tseden also died on the plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geographers were surprised that director Wanma passed away in May. At that time, they were conducting scientific research on Mount Everest and there was no signal. He had seen Wanma&#39;s movies and said that director Wanma was a good person and he filmed ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wanma and the new wave of Tibet he led are the window for many people to understand Tibetan life and culture. Looking from his movies, they are melodious, mysterious and contradictory Tibetans. story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/E5quYTxdMo071IYXlNf6A5LUYTJ9BqaBunC0AhEK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;724&quot; height= &quot;271&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/E5quYTxdMo071IYXlNf6A5LUYTJ9BqaBunC0AhEK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;349 National Highway Viaduct&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly Reporter Food/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leaving Shigatse After visiting Tashilhunpo Monastery, we walked on National Highway 318. The road is mostly smooth, with occasional bumps. This 5,476-kilometer-long ordinary road has a large altitude difference. Sometimes it spirals between hard mountains, and sometimes it rises in &quot;trough-shaped geologically broken sections&quot;. National Highway 318 was originally the Sichuan-Tibet Highway built from 1950 to 1954. Thirty thousand People&#39;s Liberation Army troops entered Tibet to build the road and more than 3,000 people died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the entrance of Mount Everest National Park, tourists lined up to take photos with the large-scale &quot;318 National Highway must be driven in this life&quot; ground painting. I was in a daze, and after searching on my mobile phone, I confirmed that the end point of National Highway 318 is indeed not at Mount Everest, but at the China-Nepal Friendship Bridge in Nyalam County, Shigatse. That night, at the tourist base camp at 5,200 meters in the Everest National Park, people sang loudly, sometimes &quot;March of the Volunteers&quot; and sometimes &quot;Broad Sea and Sky&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/W8spSjGms58H9uY0nGIVUg5Og01ZHiIg3bNMO8iV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height= &quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/W8spSjGms58H9uY0nGIVUg5Og01ZHiIg3bNMO8iV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251354&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A dead donkey on the side of National Highway 349&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the national park, you will see the famous &quot;Everest 108 Turns&quot;. The asphalt road winds and climbs 800 meters, overlooking four snow-capped peaks above 8,000 meters. Due to the wide span and large drop of Turn 108, aerial photography has been mostly done here in recent years. But Dashi is an old-school photographer and has little interest in drone aerial photography. He likes his Fujifilm camera, which has a wide-angle fixed focus and can shoot 108-degree continuous undulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We settled at the Everest Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. The webmaster wanted to take us to a good place, saying it was the best angle to photograph Mount Everest: from the high point of Rongbuk Monastery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rongbuk Monastery is the highest temple in the world. Its full name is &quot;Latucha Rongbuk Dong Aquling Monastery&quot;. It was founded in 1899 by the Red Sect Lama Ngawang Tenzin Norbu. According to &quot;Tibetan Family&quot;: &quot;He (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ngawang Tenzin Norbu&lt;/span>;) first built the His private residence was Rajang, and he built a temple, and then built houses for his growing number of disciples.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/J1CQ3U2BhU3gUoi9S8WtVER9xc9rzwQJhYvFIOR8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2519&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 20/J1CQ3U2BhU3gUoi9S8WtVER9xc9rzwQJhYvFIOR8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Monks are cleaning the courtyard in the early morning of Tashilhunpo Monastery&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Da Shi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ngawang Tenzin Norbu developed Rongbuk Monastery into a world-famous Nyingma monastery. Accept monks and nuns from the Himalayas to study. At its peak, the Rongbuk Temple had more than a dozen affiliated temples, some of which were still in Nepal, but were later destroyed due to historical reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rongbuk Temple is named after Rongbukou. Under the north slope of Mount Everest, there is a north-south Rongbuk ditch, which was washed by the Rongbuk River. The Rongbuk River is formed by partial meltwater from the East Rongbuk Glacier, the Middle Rongbuk Glacier, and the West Rongbuk Glacier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ysgmjcberZRv1P54zGkbT6jEbttPiggpyvG3n1Le.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2542&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ysgmjcberZRv1P54zGkbT6jEbttPiggpyvG3n1Le.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Greening project along the national highway&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter&#39;s meal/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Whether it is scientific research or mountaineering, you need to walk through the East Rongbuk Glacier to enter Mount Everest. In 1921, when the legendary mountaineer Mallory tried to scout out a climbing route to Mount Everest, he missed the intersection of the East Rongbuk Glacier. But one of their team members discovered the East Rongbuk route. Since then, all climbing teams climbing Mount Everest from the north slope have taken this route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/LuDSe8HweSQog5rP9TkaRw4lfOmc8e1SKPgzAzdm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2519&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/LuDSe8HweSQog5rP9TkaRw4lfOmc8e1SKPgzAzdm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251359&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;108 Turns&quot; leading to Mount Everest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the mouths of Western mountaineers, the road along the East Rongbuk Glacier to the advance camp is called the &quot;miracle highway.&quot; The scientific expedition team members of the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources of the Chinese Academy of Sciences were quite surprised by this name. They had walked it several times and always called it the &quot;Yak Trail.&quot; This road is easy for yaks and people to walk on. It only takes 5 hours at a fast pace and 10 hours at a slower pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Mallory missed the East Rongbuk Glacier, he took a precious photo of the Middle Rongbuk Glacier. During the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition, the Northwest Research Institute found Mallory&#39;s photo spot after three efforts. By comparing two photos spanning a century, they estimated that the Zhongrongbuk Glacier has retreated 4 kilometers from the past, or an average of 40 meters per year. The continued warming of the global climate will inevitably intensify the retreat of glaciers. In the event of an avalanche, excess melted snow will form a torrent and rush towards the mountain villa at the foot of Mount Everest. In the past 20 years, flash floods caused by avalanches on Mount Everest have washed away many Nepali villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Ppbwun05bkWz2O9tFNqnLd1Ov4tJoq8if0MEI2FY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2599&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Ppbwun05bkWz2O9tFNqnLd1Ov4tJoq8if0MEI2FY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251358&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The lady raised her fluttering silk scarf into the wind&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;This is the starting point of this trip, an observation of global climate change centered on the scientific expedition to Mount Everest. It is an inaccessible place, and the snow-capped mountains quietly record the natural changes over the past thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[穿越三江并流之地：雪线之下桃树下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;That is a scroll painting that has appeared countless times in my dreams&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From an aerial view, Shangri-La is just like what is written in geography books, with overlapping mountains and crisscrossing rivers: the &quot;roof of the world&quot; Qinghai-Tibet Plateau winds up, and the Hengduan Mountains are connected hand in hand in northwest Yunnan, southeastern Tibet, and western Sichuan. Between the mountains, the Nu River, Lancang River and Jinsha River flow side by side in three canyons with a horizontal distance of only more than 60 kilometers. Under the sunlight, they look like yellow veins. When the plane landed slowly, I saw Shangri-La in the green valley like a spilled palette, flowing beside the Napa Sea wetland. The flowing cloud shadows are reflected on the water surface of the wetland, which is like a dream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Lwz0dAOvw8iuPEN7OTb46QFWpvHn8s5f7SkFxZ2r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Lwz0dAOvw8iuPEN7OTb46QFWpvHn8s5f7SkFxZ2r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252052&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Napahai Wetland&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The center of Shangri-La City is An ancient city named &quot;Dukezong&quot; was originally built by the Tubo people and means &quot;Moonlight City&quot; in Tibetan. Since its construction, it has been abandoned and rebuilt several times, and its organizational structure, zoning and name have been changed several times, but its status as the political, economic and cultural center of Diqing, Yunnan has remained unchanged. For thousands of years, this place has witnessed not only the smoke of wars, but also the bustle of tea and horse trade. It has also been the link between Yunnan, Sichuan, and Tibet&#39;s &quot;Grand Triangle&quot; and a channel for frequent exchanges among various ethnic groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2014, an unexpected fire partially burned down the ancient city of Dukezong. Today, the ancient city has slowly recovered. Strolling along the stone road in the ancient city, you will see wooden houses on both sides, operating inns, restaurants, bars or handicraft shops. It reminds people of the &quot;quaint little town&quot; described by the British botanist Kingdon Ward. In 1913, in order to investigate the rivers and plants in the Hengduan Mountains, Kingdon Ward passed by this place and stayed in a house. He found that &quot;the house was extremely clean, and the copper cooking pots and tea utensils were polished to a discernible shine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kindon Ward was not the only one to leave written records for Shangri-La. Liu Manqing, the first &quot;female imperial envoy&quot; to Tibet in modern times and known as the &quot;Fantastic Woman of the East&quot;, wrote about the ancient city of Dukezong in a delicate way in &quot;The Campaign of Kangzang&quot; published in 1933:&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;When the sky dawns or the sun sets, the streets are full of people carrying water. The ladles for collecting water are made of folded bark. They are light in weight and large in capacity. , beside the spring, water seekers swarm like ants.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, at the foot of Dagui Mountain, the spring mentioned by Liu Manqing is still gurgling. Someone placed a water ladle next to the spring for passers-by to get water and taste it. The sun passes through the transparent water, and the waves dance under the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since ancient times, Shangri-La has been a legend on the Tea Horse Road. At that time, there were more than 190 businesses traveling between Shangri-La and Lhasa alone, and more than 20,000 caravan horses passed through each year. In the alley of Dukezong Ancient City, I met the handsome Kham man Zhabagdan. Zhabagdan&#39;s father is from Shangri-La and was a member of a caravan when he was young. In 1970, Zhabagdan was born in a small mountain village in India. He worked as a monk for seven years. When he was seventeen, he returned to his hometown with his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhabagdan’s life legend begins in Shangri-La. After returning to China, he started studying in the first grade of primary school and later studied in Austria and the United States. He speaks Tibetan, English and Hindi, as well as a curry-flavored version of Mandarin. He has worked part-time as a civil servant, a tour guide, and opened a travel agency and restaurant. In 2012, Zhabagdan created the first &quot;Arokangba&quot; B&amp;B in the ancient city of Dukezong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aruo Kamba&quot; is a sentence used by our fathers to greet each other while walking on the Ancient Tea Horse Road, which means &quot;Come on, friend&quot;. Creating &quot;Aro Kamba&quot; was not only Zhabagdan&#39;s father&#39;s dream during his lifetime, but also his own dream. Back then, the caravans walked on the Tea-Horse Ancient Road. Whenever they were exhausted, they would get a chance to rest in &quot;Naicang&quot; deep in the mountains. Every time my father mentioned the story of the caravan to Zhabagdan, he would always talk about the &quot;Naicang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fire in 2014 severely damaged the ancient city. Although Arokamba Manor survived, the memory left by the fire in Zhabagdan has never faded. He still clearly remembered the shops and houses shrouded in fire, falling tragically like defenseless giants. The sound of explosions of liquefied gas tanks came one after another, and clouds of fireworks rolled up. The flying fragments hit the broken walls and made various sharp sounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This was like a one-sided war. We were caught off guard in the face of the rapid fire.&quot; Zhabagdan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes Zhabagdan happy is that over the years, through the reconstruction of &quot;building the new as the old, replacing the old with the old, and imitating the old with the new&quot;, the ancient city of Dukezong has gradually restored its original appearance. What was once a devastated place has been replaced by a brand new look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone streets, unique Tibetan inns, handicraft shops with ethnic colors, cafes and bars full of literary and artistic atmosphere, indicate that the ancient Dukezong city is back.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;For Shangri-La, Zhabagdan has always had love and confidence. He still often thinks of the time when he and his father climbed over a pass and saw Shangri-La for the first time: &quot;That was a scroll painting that appeared countless times in my dreams.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/sbYkZP7IVmGI7grn25WnatoRXqkht9E7KSjwkhxB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/sbYkZP7IVmGI7grn25WnatoRXqkht9E7KSjwkhxB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Songzanlin Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Shangri-La is the imagination of the whole world&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After leaving Shangri-La, we headed towards Deqin along the Yunnan-Tibet Line and stayed overnight in Benzilan Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benzilan is located on the right bank of the upper reaches of the Jinsha River. It means &quot;little sand dam&quot; in Tibetan. It is a valley area between the surging Jinsha River and steep mountains. However, as the altitude decreases, the scenery of the valley becomes desolate: gravel and barren soil on both sides, and exposed rocks. Just now, you could still see tall broad-leaved forests, a lush scene, but gradually they turned into low shrubs and cacti. The wind blew on my face, it was hot and dry, making me feel like I was in the desert of Mexico. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;hot and dry valley&quot; scene is a typical geological landscape in the &quot;Three Parallel Rivers&quot; area, and it can be called a wonderful stroke of nature: the warm and moist airflow becomes cold as it climbs over the mountains on both sides of the canyon in the wind. It triggers precipitation, so rainfall is frequent on the top of the mountain and vegetation is lush. The airflow descends through the leeward slope and becomes hot, and when it reaches the valley bottom, it becomes a dry and hot &quot;Foehn wind&quot;. The &quot;Foehn wind&quot; intensifies the degree of dry heat, causing the vegetation to become sparser, forming a &quot;hot dry valley&quot; landform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;Hot Dry Valley&quot; is by no means completely desolate. Through the car window, you can see ocher-colored mountains studded with agate-like terraces. By transforming these terraces, local people have created local environments suitable for farming. Walnuts, citrus, grapes, watermelons and olives are planted on the platform, complementing the tawny Jinsha River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After passing Benzilan Town, we left the road, followed the stream, passed through the valley, and arrived at the peaceful Bairen Village. Cacti grow among the exposed rocks, and pepper and plum trees grow along the roadside. The person I want to visit is Estelle Achard, a French female architect. Nine years ago, this French woman from the foot of the Alps sold her hut in northern France, came to this Tibetan village deep in the river valley alone, and opened an inn called &quot;Tulu Lodge&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Dirt Road&quot; was renovated from an old Tibetan-style house in the village, and the original appearance has been maintained as much as possible: plum trees and pomegranate trees are planted in the small yard surrounded by earth and stone walls. , rosemary and mint grow in stone flower beds. Estelle went out to greet us, followed by two dogs (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​of them is a blind dog&lt;/span>;), spinning around our feet excitedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Estelle has ash-brown hair, glasses, and a Tibetan necklace hanging around her neck. Thirty years ago, when she was an architect, she came to Yunnan on a business trip for the first time and couldn&#39;t help but fall in love with the mountains and rivers here. Fifteen years later, she moved to Kunming. After working in hotel design for a few years, she moved to Shangri-La and finally settled in Benzilan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Estelle takes us through the rooms she designed and decorated one by one. Although each room has a different style, they all organically combine national characteristics with modern concepts, as if time has quietly settled here. When renovating the house, Estelle values ​​​​the most ecological and environmental protection concepts. She kept the wood as bare as possible and did not use chemical-based varnishes. She also deliberately preserved the &quot;dry toilet&quot; in rural areas: a hole was made in the ground of the toilet, a chair was placed above the hole, the seat was hollowed out, and there was a pile of sawdust under the hole, and the excrement fell directly into the sawdust and became Fertilizer for the vegetable patch outside the yard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having lived in Benzilan for nearly ten years, Estelle can communicate with the villagers in Chinese, and the villagers call her &quot;French Ajia&quot;. She likes local ghee, yak meat, and fresh vegetables and fruits, and she grows various herbs needed for French cuisine in the garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, we sat under the plum tree in the garden and shared a country dinner made by Estelle with a French family traveling to Diqing: tomato and watermelon cold soup, spice roasted chicken, mashed potatoes, served with Shangri-La products red wine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The corn leaves outside the courtyard swayed in the evening breeze, and the sound of the stream became louder. We talked about our respective experiences. Estelle said that she also thought about opening a B&amp;B in Provence, but Provence was already too saturated. She was very happy to settle down in Benzilan and open a small B&amp;B. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Provence is the imagination of the whole world, and it is the same here.&quot; Estelle said, &quot;Whenever I tell my French friends that I have settled in Shangri-La, they will exclaim!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Q1PcGm7rADXzIUj537SZW8Xgt8f84vX66AiWDkEi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Q1PcGm7rADXzIUj537SZW8Xgt8f84vX66AiWDkEi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jinsha River Big Bend&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Zichao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Xueshan Market Dunshiyang&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Early the next morning, we left Benzilan, left the dry and hot valley, and walked along the Jinsha River. The elevation of the road rises again, and the vegetation on the mountains becomes lush again. At the big bend of the Jinsha River, I saw the yellow river water turning around, like a man&#39;s bent arms, full of power - the mountains sandwiching the river water were like the guardian angel of the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is 86 kilometers from Benzilan to Deqin County. Although the mountain road is winding, it is in good condition. Before liberation, there were no roads in Deqin County, and it was not until 1959 that the Yunnan-Tibet Highway was built. At that time, it was necessary to climb the Baima Snow Mountain, which is more than 4,000 meters above sea level. From October to May of the following year, traffic was often blocked due to heavy snowfall. Now that the tunnel has been opened, it is no longer necessary to cross the pass of Baima Snow Mountain. Our car seemed to be gliding on the road, surrounded by dense forests on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The town of Deqin County used to be called Adunzi. It is said that during the Song and Yuan Dynasties, the eminent Tibetan Buddhist monk Karmapa discovered during meditation that Kawagbo, the main peak of Meili Snow Mountain, was the holy land of Chakrasamvara predicted by Padmasambhava. This started the pilgrimage of Tibetan Buddhists to Kawagebo. the first of its kind. Adunzi is not only the starting point and the end point of worshiping the sacred mountain, but also an important material distribution center and cultural exchange center on the Tea Horse Road. Therefore, it has the reputation of &quot;Snow Mountain Market&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a broader perspective, Adunzi is located in the contact zone between the Han and Tibetan peoples. As scholars say, just as Zhangjiakou&#39;s commercial development is due to its location in the contact zone between the Han and Mongolian peoples, Adunzi&#39;s commercial development is also due to the same reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Anti-Japanese War, traditional international trade routes were blocked, and merchants gathered in Adunzi, which became a bridge to maintain Sino-Indian trade and transport war preparation materials. Due to the large number of major business houses, in order to facilitate transactions, merchants used a &quot;Dunshiyang&quot; currency as a medium of circulation. This kind of currency can only be used in Adunzi market, which shows the prosperity of Adunzi in those days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Deqin has restored the appearance of a small mountain town, with buildings winding down the valley, with a drop of nearly 600 meters. Walking on the street, I can&#39;t see the prosperous scene of the Tea Horse Station back then. It looks more like an ordinary mountain city. Only the skin color of passers-by, their accents, and the attire of some residents made me realize that I was in a minority area inhabited by Tibetans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to its location in a narrow ravine, the biggest risk faced by Deqin County in recent years is mudslides. In 2003, the Diqing Prefecture government considered moving the county seat elsewhere. In 2010, a mudslide occurred in Zhouqu County, Gansu Province, which has similar terrain, which aroused people&#39;s concerns about Deqin. But local people told me that the mountains near Deqin are undulating, and it is very difficult to find a piece of flat land that is open enough. Therefore, the government’s latest consideration is to relocate the entire county seat to the adjacent Weixi County. If this is the case, the ancient city of Adunzi will also will become a piece of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DkyjOuuGVwfs4clUEE2QKRrwezqYeWvqNdy8pplL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DkyjOuuGVwfs4clUEE2QKRrwezqYeWvqNdy8pplL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252053&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kawagbo, the main peak of Meili Snow Mountain, and the Mingyong Glacier flows below the snow peak. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Mingyong Glacier is protected by Mingyong Village&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;In the early morning, we went to Feilai Temple to watch the sacred scene of &quot;Rizhao Jinshan&quot; - the golden sunshine hitting the Kawagebo Mountain Peak. Then we returned to Deqin County and met the poet Tashi Nyima in a Tibetan restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tashi Nyima was born in Mingyong Village under the jurisdiction of Deqin County. This village is located under the Kawagebo Snow Peak, which means &quot;mirror&quot; in Tibetan. It is named after the huge glacier pouring down from the snow-capped mountains behind the village. In addition to Mingyong Glacier, Mingyong Village is also the place where the late poet Ma Hua taught.在那里，马骅写下了诗集《雪山短歌》，被评论界誉为当代汉语诗歌中最明净、最澄澈的部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;午饭过后，我请扎西尼玛带我去明永村看看。我们坐上汽车，上了214国道，很快就看到了奔腾的澜沧江。这里同样是干热河谷地貌，但我发现，只要有台坎坡地的地方，就有田园民居，就能看到麦浪翻滚、瓜果飘香的景象。行驶在这条路上，一块块绿洲，一座座民居，镶嵌在雪山、峡谷与大江共同绘制的风景中，令人心旷神怡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一路上，在河谷两岸的隘口和田间地头，不时可以看到耸立的土碉楼，大都倾圮破败，充满了历史的沧桑感。我问扎西尼玛，这些碉楼建于何时？所为何用？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎西尼玛告诉我，由于年代久远，就连当地人也已经失去了对碉楼的记忆。它们究竟是出于战争的目的，亦或只是财富和身份的象征，历史学者和考古学者们各执一词。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/p9243QxUuIDpc0hJ7oun65LznBcxdNO3VKSmFwf8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/p9243QxUuIDpc0hJ7oun65LznBcxdNO3VKSmFwf8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252055&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;梅里雪山下的藏族村庄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通往明永村的公路是1998年4月开通的，以前进出明永村只能走崖壁上的小路。在扎西尼玛的记忆中，当时明永河的水声比现在更大。他去上学，步行要走半天时间，还要溜一道滑索。暑假时，他去山上放羊，饿了就烤从森林里采到的松茸，撒上盐巴和辣椒就吃。如今看来，这一切算是“生命中难得的体验”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时，明永村人的生活十分困苦。多数人家全家人共睡一个铺，家里甚至没有多余的碗。扎西尼玛记得，上初中时，有一次放假回家，他邀请同学到家里吃午饭。由于家里没有客碗，只好用家人的碗，还是只变形的碗——他父亲有一次上山砍木头，摔了一跤，把木碗压变形了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初中毕业后，扎西尼玛去师范学校读书，随后辗转在德钦县管辖的村镇。 1997年，他调入德钦县旅游局，参与编制了梅里雪山生态旅游区开发规划。正是那份规划把明永冰川作为优先开发的景区，而明永村的巨变也是从那时开始的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着政府大力度的推介，卡瓦格博峰和明永冰川开始吸引越来越多的游客。德钦县抓住时机，投资了七千多万元，为明永村修建基础设施，明永冰川成为迪庆州第一个国家4A级景区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冰川旅游开发中，明永村村民主要参与的是为游客提供牵马服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“骡马成了明永村的钱袋子。”扎西尼玛说，“1999年，牵马收入是平均每户八千七百元；到了2006年，平均每户突破了五万元。”村民在旅游业中致了富，家家户户都置办了卫星电视、电冰箱、洗衣机、高档音响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，县里又提出实施冰川索道项目。因为饲养骡马成本不小，修建索道则可能带来更多的游客。村民们认为，跟索道公司订合同，谈好分成办法，这样既可以舒舒服服地挣钱，又不用为喂养骡马和安全问题大伤脑筋。冰川索道投入运营以来，村民每户每年至少可以分到五万五千元的红利。明永村从过去的贫困村，变为德钦县乃至迪庆州的富裕村。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/28wqjxJHLY65YACM1aD5eZvh0cGqRmvFrKmzkn7e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/28wqjxJHLY65YACM1aD5eZvh0cGqRmvFrKmzkn7e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252054&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;德钦雨崩村&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;午后，我和扎西尼玛一起漫步在明永村。只见家家户户都盖起了两层带院子的藏式民居，白色的墙壁点缀在碧绿的森林和田野间。卡瓦格博峰近在眼前，冰川从主峰的胸口延伸下来，一直垂到海拔2660米的森林中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎西尼玛告诉我，据明永村的老人们说，以前推开窗户就可以看到冰川，感受到冰川的凉气。那时候的冰川很“强壮”，把山谷堆得满满的，整天听得到冰川开裂发出的巨响。 1913年，英国植物学家金墩·沃德也曾造访过明永冰川，看到“一根巨大的冰柱醉汉般摇晃，瞬间后便咆哮着滚落山谷，将树上一群绿色的鹦鹉惊起”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎西尼玛说，在他小时候，冰川的出水口会被掉落的冰块堵住，河水一下子断流了，村妇们就到冰川边上，亮着嗓门唱起“嘛呢调”。唱着唱着，冰块被冲开，河水哗哗地汹涌而出。然而，这些年冰川逐渐消融，这让扎西尼玛感到心情沉重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“每次回村，都会感觉冰川变小了一些。”扎西尼玛说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，他还拍摄了一部名为《冰川》的纪录片，从朝圣者、旅游者、村民三种视角，表达了藏族人对雪山的信仰，对外来文化影响的不同理解，以及他们在旅游开发浪潮中面临的种种困惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/S3QpLt5MKOUgTjgGiunNeUQ3OTyxymWfgcs0sdcy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/S3QpLt5MKOUgTjgGiunNeUQ3OTyxymWfgcs0sdcy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252057&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在香格里拉地区，桃花开在雪山下。 （视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村子的路边立着一块“马骅老师纪念碑”，正面和背面用汉文和藏文写着：“马骅，诗人、学者。1972年4月11日出生，男，汉族，天津人，毕业于上海复旦大学国际政治系，2003年3月到明永村小学义务支教。2004年6月20日不幸遇难，年仅32岁。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎西尼玛和马骅是同龄人，又都是诗人，当年很快成为朋友。他回明永村看马骅时，两人经常一起聊书聊音乐。马骅会拿起吉他，唱起民谣，长长的头发像一团黑色的瀑布。他们去附近的山上野餐，躺在一棵不知有多少年月的老桃树下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;微风时时拂过，花瓣沿着暖洋洋的阳光纷纷飘落下来。背后是在云雾里时隐时现的卡瓦格博雪山和雪山上伸展下来的巨大冰川，冰川在阳光的照射下发着蓝幽幽的光，偶尔会传来冰崩的轰响，山谷的两岸覆盖着茂密的森林，头顶上是蓝得醉人的天空和天空中变幻不定的云彩。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——扎西尼玛《雪线之下》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，站在当年的明永小学门前，往事依旧历历在目。扎西尼玛的眼眶中含着泪水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首例影视剧台词声音权纠纷案，孙红雷起诉游戏侵权]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“你这瓜保熟吗？” 知名演员孙红雷把一批人告了！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月25日，成都互联网法庭开庭审理了全国首例影视剧台词声音权纠纷案。上午11点20分左右，成都互联网法庭主审法官宣布该案改日宣判。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/f860448ada4c871e5650b5affb030247.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/f860448ada4c871e5650b5affb030247.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252102&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;庭审现场&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;因《西瓜摊主大战买瓜人》游戏软件中使用了演员孙红雷参演的电视剧《征服》经典桥段中的台词声音，游戏开发商和供应商成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司被孙红雷告上法庭。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/33179c84a6edb115936b3f5ae58605c1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/33179c84a6edb115936b3f5ae58605c1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;图源：《征服》电视剧截图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未经授权使用他人影视剧经典桥段中的台词声音，侵权吗？你怎么看？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;知名演员孙红雷起诉游戏侵权&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据红星新闻报道，在电视剧《征服》中，孙红雷饰演角色刘华强，因西瓜缺斤少两问题，刘华强与小贩产生争执，小贩连同同伙想要收拾刘华强，但最终反被刘华强收拾。近年来，这也发展为一个网络热梗“华强买瓜”，“你这瓜保熟吗？”也成为电视剧经典台词。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/f6b274559d85fe2e887cfcef908273e9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;452&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/f6b274559d85fe2e887cfcef908273e9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/421bd27ef2eeae39faa51c849900fd18.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/421bd27ef2eeae39faa51c849900fd18.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252106&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这款游戏软件《西瓜摊主大战买瓜人》在网上小有名气。游戏3D画面中，玩家扮演西瓜摊老板，凭借技能来抵挡买瓜人一众小弟捣乱的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游戏一开始，游戏角色的台词与电视剧《征服》中买瓜一幕雷同，“你这瓜保熟吗？”游戏中的道具金瓜粒子、吸铁石、生瓜蛋子等都在电视剧《征服》中出现过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙红雷认为，成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司未经其授权，以营利为目的开发、设计该款游戏，客观上构成对其声音权益的侵犯。另外，该款游戏中自己的人格元素被塑造成了在社会上打架、寻衅滋事的坏人形象，其人格尊严未被尊重，客观上构成对其一般人格权的侵犯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于上述理由，孙红雷请求判令成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司公开道歉并赔偿经济损失45万元及精神损害抚慰金5万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c47db5d4a6f90e07db4235935cd79aaf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c47db5d4a6f90e07db4235935cd79aaf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;全国首例声音权纠纷&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;案件择期宣判&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据四川在线报道，9月25日，成都互联网法庭开庭审理该案。在庭审中，法庭将该案的庭审争议焦点问题归纳为以下几个方面：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个问题，成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司认为孙某作为影视剧演员，该项权利应为表演者权。关于孙某是否有权就他人使用其影视作品主张声音权益和一般人格权侵权，成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司持有不同意见；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7512ab52f1003733db17a3efae83c07a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7512ab52f1003733db17a3efae83c07a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个问题，成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司对案涉游戏视频的声音是否具有识别性构成对孙某的声音权益侵权，以及案涉游戏的人物形象是否损害了原告的一般人格权持不同意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三个问题，成都睡神飞科技有限公司、北京睡神飞科技有限公司的行为如果构成侵权，应当如何承担法律责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过庭审，由于合议庭争议较大，法院最终决定改日宣判。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[铁路12306呛声“抢票神器”：高铁一票难求还会长久吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257613]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，中秋十一长假期间的出行购票话题成为热点，许多人吐槽“买票难”。也有不少人出行心切，使用第三方平台的“光速抢票”“抢票神器”，买到票一般都要额外加价。对此，铁路12306通过官方微博发布声明，表示：从未授权任何第三方平台发售火车票，也不可能给第三方平台所谓的“优先购票权”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该声明表示：“第三方平台在旅客朋友购票过程中会保留用户信息，不仅有附加费、加速包、捆绑销售服务等陷阱，还可能存在个人信息泄露风险。请旅客朋友一定要通过铁路官方渠道购票，认准铁路12306网站（含客户端），注意保护合法权益和个人信息安全”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何理解这个声明的真实含意？会令“抢票神器”之类失去市场吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先要理解为什么多年来，每逢长假诸多线路的高铁一票难求。不过先说一句，从今年开始，一些线路车票紧俏的状况可能会有所改观。且往下翻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同线路的高铁乘客使用强度是不一样的，有些线路比较热门，通勤、商务出行、旅游等需求常年不衰，每天班次很多，如珠三角或长三角区域内城市之间的线路，主要城市群之间的线路，以及去热门景点的线路；有些线路则不那么热门，班次就相对较少。到了长假，为了应对井喷式的出行需求增加，高铁会增开一些班次，但显然前者增加的绝对需求与相对需求都会多很多，但增开的潜力有限；后者增开的潜力大，但增加的需求有限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，长期以来，绝大多数高铁线路都是平时与长假期间一个价，往往导致这样的后果：平时需求较少时，票价高于市场均衡价格；长假期间需求剧增时，票价显著低于市场均衡价格，从而导致票一放出就秒光。对于这种情况，国铁是心知肚明的，所以也在改进，让票价更加市场化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年12月，京沪高铁就开始实行浮动票价，全程二等座最高票价598元，涨幅8%；最低票价498元，降幅10%，即上限调高、下限调低，是京沪高铁开通9年来，首次推行浮动票价机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2023年5月30日开始，铁路部门对沪宁城际、宁杭高铁、南广高铁、胶济客专、柳南客专等多条高铁线路“票价进行优化调整”，上限为公布票价，下限为公布票价的六六折，进一步上限调高、下限调低，且浮动幅度进一步放宽。以沪宁城际为例，南京站到上海站二等座公布票价为166元，即调整后的最高票价，较调整前的139.5元票价上涨19%；最低票价是110元，较调整前的139.5元票价下降21%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了对某些热门线路票价上限调高并实行浮动之外，铁路部门也推出了优惠票。中国铁路广州局集团宣布，“为方便城际旅客商务差旅和通勤往返出行”，自2023年6月20日起，长株潭城际铁路将正式推出定期票和计次票，旅客可在指定发到站乘坐线路上开行的S字头列车。以成都东到重庆西的售价5852元的60次/30天定期票为例，折合97.5元/次，接近普通票的最低执行票价，折扣最高达五八折。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总的趋势是，高铁定价策略正在向飞机看齐。除非有紧急事态，只要你提前一段时间买票，基本上都能买到机票，甚至价格还很优惠，这是因为飞机票会定一个高高的“原价”，远高于多数时候的市场均衡价格，没有上浮，只有下浮，打三折、四折，让乘客很有“获得感”，这是一种纯粹以市场为导向并且精准把握乘客心理的定价策略。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高铁动卧定价策略完全拷贝飞机票。从9月15日起，中秋国庆假期高铁开售，不少人在购票时发现，相比于平时，国庆期间部分高铁和动卧大幅上涨。有乘客在社交媒体发文称，北京到深圳的动卧，平日只需要1150元，但是在9月28日上铺涨到1860元，下铺涨到到2090元。同一天，北京直飞深圳最低票价为1100元（不含税）。官网上，北京至深圳动卧的公布票价为2264元，1860元与2090元折扣约为八二折、九二折。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，现在还不是在所有线路上实行浮动票价，你要是本次中秋十一长假抢不到票，只能说明票价相对于需求仍是偏低的，该线路或是仍在实行固定票价，或是实行浮动票价没有到位，从经济学的解释就是如此。而这意味着“抢票神器”还有生存空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“抢票神器”的本质就是数字黄牛，当一种商品的官方价格显著低于市场均衡价格之时，这差价就是“无主收入”，许多人就有动机争夺这收入，黄牛就是其中一种，勤快的早早排队赚辛苦钱，有门路的搞到内部票，所得与内部人分成。数字黄牛也是黄牛，不过如果第三方平台宣称有“优先购票权”，那是骗人的，你购买加速包，人家也是帮你去12306买票。在这个意义上，铁路部门的澄清是很有必要的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，用算法抢、用App抢肯定比手速快，这就是“抢票神器”的市场生态位。铁路部门的澄清也劝返不了归心似箭、求票心切的乘客。当然，12306可以封禁某些频频刷票的IP甚至App本身，但也很难把机刷买票完全排除，只留下手刷买票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓“道高一尺，魔高一丈”，只要有利益空间在，技术会不断进化的。所以治本之策，仍是票价进一步市场化，让乘客的出价尽可能反映自己的需求强度。这样一天都等不得特别想去某个地方的人总能去，觉得缓一两天无所谓的也能省一笔钱，各得其宜；高铁也能赚更多的钱，以支付高铁运行成本、造价乃至银行本息，数字黄牛自然没有了生存空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汪顺破纪录夺金：看看这个成绩，还行吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 18:57:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QlfWjfuC6wKHukCvJfShO65Zew6GziVEFjCHXCWb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QlfWjfuC6wKHukCvJfShO65Zew6GziVEFjCHXCWb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，杭州亚运会男子200米个人混合泳决赛，汪顺在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“1:54.62”，汪顺在泳池遥遥领先，伴随接连不断的加油和欢呼，大屏幕给出了更为精确的记录。2023年9月24日，杭州亚运会男子200米混合泳决赛，中国名将汪顺以1分54秒62破亚洲纪录夺金，覃海洋以1分57秒41排名第二，中国队再次包揽金银牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“家门口的亚运会，让国旗升起，国歌奏响，说到做到。相比于金牌，我更开心的是能够打破自己保持的亚洲纪录！29岁的年龄，只是个数字，说我不行的人，你们看这个成绩还行吗！”赛后汪顺通过微博发表感言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参加本次亚运会，汪顺是憋着一股劲儿的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/emEbmlTytFrG20Di9EvJIEIsqged7cFynD4e9Rz3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/emEbmlTytFrG20Di9EvJIEIsqged7cFynD4e9Rz3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年7月30日，东京奥运会男子200米个人混合泳决赛，汪顺庆祝夺冠&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;顺流逆流&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;说汪顺“不行”的声音，直到亚运会比赛前还存在。两个月前的游泳世锦赛，汪顺在报名的三项比赛中，均未能进入决赛，距离曾经的巅峰状态差距不小。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月24日，亚运会当天的预赛中，汪顺游出1分58秒84的成绩，这与世锦赛获得第11名的成绩(1分57秒97)仍有差距，而队友覃海洋以领先汪顺0.12秒的成绩位列第一晋级当晚的决赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后的决赛，汪顺一路领先获得金牌，同时打破由他保持的亚洲纪录(1分55秒00)，此前这一纪录是他在东京奥运会创造的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“就好像我（本来）就会游泳一样，”汪顺和这片蓝色泳池的故事，从5岁那年的夏天开始。他跟着父亲第一次去游泳馆戏水，看见父亲跃入泳池，他紧跟着往下跳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身体下沉，手忙脚乱，想抓住点什么，汪顺很快呛了水，但他不觉得害怕，“我没有觉得被水呛到了，就要远离它，反而很想去征服它。也许，我对水有一种天生的亲密感。在水里面，我感受到了前所未有的快乐、放松，如鱼得水。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪顺的过往战绩中的确有如鱼得水的标记：1994年出生于浙江宁波，2007年被朱志根教练选中，进入浙江省一队；2009年，跟随教练朱志根进入中国游泳队二队；2010年广州亚运会，成为男子200米个人混合泳亚军；2016年，国际泳联短池游泳世锦赛男子200米个人混合泳夺冠，获得男子混合泳中国首个世界冠军；2021年7月30日，获得东京奥运会男子200米混合泳冠军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在水里，并不可能总是顺流而下。东京奥运会夺冠后，汪顺一度失去了目标，觉得无法再从游泳中获得快乐。在奥运会的赛场上升国旗奏国歌，是汪顺过去二十多年运动生涯里的终极目标。他很早就说过，“做运动员一定要有清晰的目标”，从全国冠军游到世界冠军，再游到奥运冠军，他逐级提升自己的竞技成绩，“我一直给自己打气，好成绩得来不易，都是一步一个脚印。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/94Qa5dmkdhAtqoULhnGmN0ILcfn9fI6ezA4wBl7K.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/94Qa5dmkdhAtqoULhnGmN0ILcfn9fI6ezA4wBl7K.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，中国选手汪顺（右）在赛后与队友覃海洋握手&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢呼过后，是没有目标的迷茫。回望过去的荣耀时刻，汪顺说：“奥运冠军一直是所有运动员追求的终极目标。在拿到奥运冠军之前，我花了二十多年才树立起这个目标，朝着目标坚定不移地走。拿到冠军之后，我发现目标消散了，所有的动力源泉都会消失。我要重新去树立起新的目标，这件事比较艰难。我花了一年时间把目标重新树立起来，再去冲击高峰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，日本福冈游泳世锦赛。汪顺感觉找回了动力，希望忘掉奥运冠军的光环，继续超越自我，填补自己金牌大满贯（奥运会、亚运会、短池世锦赛和长池世锦赛）的最后一个缺口——长池世锦赛冠军。然而，汪顺在这次比赛的男子200米混合泳预赛中排名第16，差点被淘汰；半决赛排名第11，无缘决赛。在400米混合泳中，他因为犯规被取消成绩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪顺还行吗？这样的疑问来自外界，也来自他的内心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从福冈世锦赛到杭州亚运会，间隔时间只有不到两个月，汪顺一直在调整状态。他今年29岁了，这已经是他第四次参加亚运会。2010年广州亚运会时，汪顺还是新人，那是他第一次站在亚运会的舞台上，与亚洲对手们在同一个泳池竞技，今天回想起来“依然热血澎湃”。但汪顺不再是只有热血的新手，他有过巅峰，也经历了漫长时间里的起起伏伏，最终选择再次跃入泳池。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YyS7jrnSTVUFm4UEWNKEYfmq7BgIQNYuhlpP1dXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YyS7jrnSTVUFm4UEWNKEYfmq7BgIQNYuhlpP1dXn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，在浙江杭州奥体中心游泳馆进行的杭州亚运会游泳比赛男子200米个人混合泳决赛中，中国选手汪顺以1分54秒62的成绩获得冠军&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;他要仔仔细细地看着它&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;第一次面对关于泳池的选择时，汪顺还是个小孩子。那时他正在学习画画，表现不错，同时收到了游泳队的橄榄枝。要不要选择成为职业游泳运动员，家里没有过这样的先例，是本能也是冒险，他选了泳池。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“游泳一直给我一种前进的感觉。”成年后，汪顺这样解释自己的选择。当时间足够漫长，他经历并感受了越来越多游泳运动的另一面：枯燥、重复、与自我对抗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在长50米、宽25米、有着8条泳道的泳池里游泳，不厌其烦地一次次往返于起点和终点之间。他说：“游泳是一项比较枯燥的运动，在竞技过程中，在日常训练中，很少能够跟别人交流。唯一能够听到的是水流滑向你，流过耳朵的声音是我最亲密的伙伴。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪顺曾在一次采访中无意间说起，2022年有7个月的时间，他都在基地训练，就像搭积木一样，每天从基础训练开始，一堂训练课游13000-16000米，有时连续练上两三堂训练课，到边、转身、翻滚、折返，一整套的水中动作循环重复着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的手看上去瘦削，指节分明，掌心却结下了粗糙老茧。头两年刚训练的时候，他手上的皮肤会因在水中泡得太久而起皱。时间一长，身体逐渐适应，“表象的反应基本上没有了”。长期的、固定的训练也改变了他的日常。“我休假的时候，一天还好，如果第二天没有去游泳池下水，会浑身不舒服。只要到了泳池，我就会很舒服，现在对水会有这样的情感。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了身体的训练之外，面对自己的内心，同样是这条赛道的必修课。2019年世锦赛，汪顺非常渴望收获一枚金牌，但他甚至没有发挥出自己的正常水平。3个月后的世界军人运动会，汪顺渴望不减，“一定要证明自己。”他拼命增加训练难度，结果却因为训练过量导致肺部破裂，出现了气胸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时医生给他的治疗方案是每天吸氧一小时，而他却希望尽快恢复，为国争光，于是开始每天吸氧两小时。即便如此，医生还是建议他放弃那次比赛再休息一周.他不肯，在床上躺了五天之后，重新站回训练场，并在隔天的比赛中拼尽全力，拿到冠军。如今回忆起当时的情况他还是心有戚戚：“很多事情大家可能看不到，对我来说是玩命一样吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/AsLCsDTbaqPmWKVQyOVCdRSQGVkZkCEk6QA32Xzx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;774&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/AsLCsDTbaqPmWKVQyOVCdRSQGVkZkCEk6QA32Xzx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月23日，杭州亚运会开幕式，火炬手汪顺与数字火炬手共同点燃主火炬&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后的巅峰时刻，当数东京奥运会。夺冠当日，汪顺在微博上写道：“虽然我叫顺，但其实并不顺。今天我想对我的教练说，我做到了我们的约定！夺冠并非终点，走下领奖台，一切从零开始，我们巴黎见……”从里约铜牌到东京金牌，汪顺描述那种感觉“妙不可言”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我要仔仔细细地看着它，”汪顺说，那块（金牌）很重，这是对自己这么多年来的认可，“我要仔仔细细地看看它，我是为了什么——就是为了它我才一直拼搏。我觉得它比我想象的重量要重得多。大家虽然只是看到了一块金牌，但是我的人生都包含在这里面了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巅峰之后，经历低谷，杭州亚运会，汪顺再次证明了自己，以更加饱满的心态。赛后接受采访时，被问到有没有超预期，汪顺表示，“超预期了，原来预计56秒以内，没想到今天打破了亚洲纪录”，有记者调侃“是不是昨天点火给了你力量”，汪顺回答：是家乡父老给了我力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在夺冠前一晚，9月23日，杭州亚运会开幕式上，汪顺与“数字人火炬手”共同点燃亚运会主火炬，作为最后一名火炬手，他成为亚运史经典一幕的现场见证者。而赛场也见证了汪顺游泳生涯的起起伏伏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回望这漫漫长途，作为运动员得到的最大满足感是什么?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪顺曾在采访中这样回答，“在你竭尽全力后，提升了0.1(秒)或者0.01秒所带给你的快乐感，这是我能制造的最大的满足感。这种满足感不是连贯的，没有人能一直涨成绩，感觉是断断续续的，有好有坏的，就像心电图一样，有起有伏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他喜欢赛场上的一些微小时刻，“当你回头看向大屏幕上的成绩，发觉你的最佳成绩提升了那么0.1(秒)、0.2(秒)或者0.01(秒)、0.02秒的时候，那一瞬间，会感觉到这段时间的训练没有白白付出。0.1秒，可能挑战了自己的极限，也挑战了人类的极限。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在杭州亚运的赛前采访中，记者问：游泳对你来说意味着什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪顺回答：“对游泳，小时候是热爱，现在更多的是责任。奥运冠军只是个新起点，自己还要为中国游泳付出更多的努力，期待我能在家门口举办的杭州亚运会上取得好成绩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次的成绩过后，如汪顺所想，他还会在自己更加漫长的时间里，一直游下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;参考资料：《Glass Magazine》、《时尚先生》、《都市快报》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大凉山11网红锒铛入狱：虚假助农的流量骗局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/fCrq1aEqoZtFKFQvO3eQ2mgPihFz8XyVEf8mlo7M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/fCrq1aEqoZtFKFQvO3eQ2mgPihFz8XyVEf8mlo7M.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;四川凉山，昭觉县支尔莫乡阿土勒尔村，一位当地村民在下山途中进行直播。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;粉丝们最后一次得知这批突然消失的大凉山网红的命运，是在2023年9月20日凉山“系列网红直播带货案”的发布会上，他们已经不再能像往常一样更新生活视频了。近期，因虚假宣传、销售假货，四川省凉山州多名网红锒铛入狱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;震荡后的几天里，余波仍然影响着一些凉山主播的直播间。人们质疑，哪些是本地人？哪些是本地货？哪些是真实故事？哪些是剧本编排？短视频平台兴起以来，用户们好奇地将视角投向乡村，不必再在头脑中想象异地生活。在当地人的镜头里，人们看到了景色和人文，也吃到了从当地寄出的瓜果蔬菜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次，凉山州有关部门开展的“清朗·从严整治&#39;自媒体&#39;乱象”专项行动情况，披露了“摆拍卖惨”“虚假助农”“伪慈善”等违法违规行为；抓获犯罪嫌疑人54名，其中涉案网红主播11人，捣毁MCN机构5个，查封涉案公司14家等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，最为引人关注的是包括“小虞””“赵灵儿”“凉山曲布”“凉山孟阳”等粉丝量两百万以上账号被永久封停。这些主播拥有巨大的粉丝基础，一度收割了大量同情、眼泪和钱包。至今，在相关新闻的评论区，一些粉丝仍然相信他们是无辜的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家网信办等七部门于2021年4月16日颁布了《网络直播营销管理办法（试行）》，国家市场监督管理总局于2023年2月25日颁布了《互联网广告管理办法》。律师冯胜钒对南方周末记者解读：“这说明国家已经意识到直播带货行业的乱象及其带来的危害，相信在不久的将来会出台更高位阶的法律及相关政策。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;凉山大舞台，有“才”你就来&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;昭觉县公安局立案查明，2022年7月，成都小虞助农传媒有限公司（MCN机构）负责人张某来到凉山，物色到个体工商户赵某（女，汉族，27岁）、阿日某某（男，彝族，23岁）等“网红苗子”，开始精心孵化。不到一年的时间，“赵灵儿”“凉山曲布”两个账号粉丝量已破两百万，并带货变现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一些粉丝眼里，曲布是被蒙骗了。一位名叫“王二帅”的三农视频博主，熟悉这批大凉山网红，他在9月22日晚的直播中解释，“只是说被钱给收买了”“他们所有做的这些都是商量好的”。他举例，卖了一千万，公司到手三百万，大头被老板拿走，曲布拿五六十万，赵灵儿比曲布高一点，“你是一个素人，你什么都不是，以前是工厂拧螺丝的，给你这么个平台你干不干？拧一辈子螺丝也挣不了这么多钱”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从业多年的三农视频博主农哥告诉南方周末记者，他身边的一些三农博主会在当地雇用演员表演。这是圈内半公开的秘密，“花个几百块钱，请个演员，有些演员还挺贵的，几百块钱都请不到。（因为）随便叫一个农户或者老百姓，在镜头面前是看得出来的，很多有镜头恐惧症。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农哥介绍，一些专业演员拍一两个段子的费用约一两千元，但是“临时雇用”的比较多，这些段子大同小异：偶遇当地农民并善良地对话，表现出帮助别人的样子，配上悲惨风格的音乐。“音乐一响，大家觉得这主播真棒，真好。”用着同样的套路，博主们开始全国巡演，去海南岛卖菠萝、去福建卖柚子等，这样的直播间数据好、销量高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，大凉山的网红们不满足于此，在上述常规套路的基础上实现了“迭代升级”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年8月，赵灵儿第一次以返乡助农创业青年的人设出现，“偶遇”淳朴的凉山彝族青年曲布，从此开始了大凉山的故事。赵灵儿强调和曲布是“偶然相遇”，“没有团队，更没有大家说的资本和大公司的包装”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在三个月前，自称在大凉山拍摄的“公益博主”小虞，同样也是“误入藕花深处”，见到了淳朴勤劳的“凉山四妹”。对比几个网红的镜头、拍摄和剧本，相似之处颇多。两者都是偶遇单身少数民族青年，去陌生人家吃饭，都要杀鸡款待，拿出腊肉，吃饭过程中谈起贫穷的家庭状况，两者建立起深厚的友谊，打造了帮扶的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无独有偶，“小钟行中国”在2022年10月也发了一条视频，遇到了大凉山的彝族姑娘“十一”。据悉，与赵灵儿、曲布一样，十一同样签约于这家成都的MCN机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月，小虞曾在自媒体“真实人物采访”中发布了口述故事。他自称河南商丘人，2018年开始从事电子商务，一年便赚了100万元。他最初受到大凉山“悬崖村”故事的感染，去到当地后，发现藤条梯已变成了钢筋梯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在他后来策划的一系列视频里，昭觉县特布洛乡谷莫村那些当地无人居住的生产用房和破壁残垣反而成了他们的拍摄和直播地。当地村民海来哈曲在接受采访时说，“有一天上面没得住人的老房子突然灯亮起来，后面才晓得他们是在那里拍视频、开直播”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小虞在大凉山送物资的时候，有当地拍摄者请求拍摄。“让我感到吃惊的是，最后一批物资我只花了七八千块钱，但是网友们打赏或者送礼物总额大约一两万。”小虞自此尝到甜头，一头扎入大凉山。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年7月22日，成都小虞助农传媒有限公司成立。一个月后，赵灵儿账号发布了偶遇曲布的视频。曲布与2020年爆火的丁真有相似之处，他们都来自偏僻的乡村，有着黝黑的皮肤、帅气的面庞和纯真的笑容，他被认为具有网红的潜力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王二帅记得，刚来大凉山时，小虞还告诉他，想要真正了解山里的人，就要在这里吃住，“最好是农户家，睡在家、吃在家，给他们一点钱跟他们交上朋友”。据媒体报道，小虞的团队在大凉山和当地村民交流并不多，但是需要村民出镜时，会给他们一些钱。他们租了当地几间屋子，租下土地种植玉米，还会在山上烧火做饭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者在直播间询问王二帅如何分辨网红真假，王二帅回复说：“看多了就分得清楚了……你们去自己分析，现在爆出来的我可以给你们讲一讲，没爆出来那些我也不会去说，毕竟人家现在还要靠这个东西吃饭，要靠这个东西赚钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QgOxEPgrynEebvrA1wH3Ncg4n5GaWwYF4MRzSaUQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QgOxEPgrynEebvrA1wH3Ncg4n5GaWwYF4MRzSaUQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在短视频平台对助农内容的扶持下，大凉山成了流量热点。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;被流量选中的赛道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;小虞并不是最早的大凉山网红。凉山公安机关发现，2020年以来，成都澳维文化传媒有限公司（MCN机构）负责人唐某以剧本、摆拍等方式，在短视频平台孵化了有着三百多万粉丝的“凉山孟阳”（阿西某某，女，彝族，21岁），以及“凉山阿泽”（阿的某某，男，彝族，21岁）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《中国新闻周刊》此前报道，2019年有粉丝出于同情前往“凉山孟阳”所在的昭觉县比尔镇吉曲村，才发现孟阳经常拍视频的地方，实际上是当地农户养牛养羊的地方，且孟阳的家境不差，在村里算是富裕。孟阳早早辍学，曾在广东打工，村民认为孟阳的发家，离不开“遇到好老板”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凉山州警方表示，上述违法犯罪行为，组织严密、迷惑性强、涉案地广，形成了前端打造人设、孵化网红，中端剧本拍摄、电商运营，末端农产品供应、流量变现的制假售假灰色产业链。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年，为什么这些MCN机构如此热衷“掘金”大凉山？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农产品电商的资深从业者王惠林分析，大凉山是天然的产品和流量的蓄水池。首先，大凉山的产品有不少网红“爆品”；其次，大凉山的话题迎合了流量，“大凉山有少数民族，风景也比较漂亮，又有文化的底蕴。人们稀罕这种少数的东西，这就解决了最大的流量问题。”王惠林告诉南方周末记者，“大凉山的经济发展比沿海地区相对缓慢，又有这种助农的属性，这个事情就更顺理成章地发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是大凉山，包括新疆、内蒙古在内，“有产品、有风景、有人情、有文化”的地方都受到追捧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农哥认为：“去那边拍摄有更高的可信度，肯定是有选择的，怎么没有人选择去浙江助农？”据他多年在乡村的带货经验，像孟阳这样的短视频博主，不少有过度渲染农村悲惨之嫌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位来自北方某山区的三农从业者告诉南方周末记者，人们总是对山区有想当然的偏见，实际上包括营商环境在内，当地的一些东西可能比发达城市要好，但这些没有关注和流量，“xx山区没有通电”，这个主题便有了流量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;助农扶持已经成为短视频平台的重点。9月12日，首届“快手追光大会”宣布，启动快手村播“繁星计划”，将在未来三年投入100亿流量、5000万现金，培养100万村播、1000名乡村创业者，为160个国家重点帮扶县输送人才。9月21日，抖音电商发布《2023丰收节抖音电商助农数据报告》，抖音电商里挂车售卖农产品的短视频数量为2186万条，直播间里农特产商品讲解总时长达3778万小时，福建、河南、云南、安徽和四川成为平台中农货商家来源前五省份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凉山州警方公布了MCN机构的三农视频脚本，其中包括“收山货”。例如，十一和表姐带着秤、袋子、背篓等去当地村民家里收山货。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三农的剧本变相迎合了短视频平台的流量算法。山东某电商集团的董事长聂文昌在临沂做了最早一批直播基地，他对南方周末记者分析，“做剧本之后人气是高的，根据平台的一些规则做人气，把人气顶起来。”他说，乡村生活的主题拥有广泛共鸣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王惠林认为，这些视频之所以火爆，原因在于触发了平台的机制，“数据反馈，而非人为反馈”。数据指标判断这是一个“好”视频，更多的流量便会注入。大凉山网红的粉丝积累速度，从平台的逻辑来看，是正常的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王惠林告诉南方周末记者，这些剧本缺乏正常的生活逻辑，套路也不新鲜，但是刷短视频往往是感情驱动，不需要思考逻辑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于此次大凉山网红事件，南方周末记者拨打多个助农文化传媒公司电话，或无法接通，或缄默不言。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;看似助农，实为卖货&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;利用虚假人设吸引到粉丝后，上述公司会开设网店和直播带货，打着“助农”“优质原生态”等旗号，从外地食品公司低价购入蜂蜜、核桃等农副产品，假冒“大凉山特色农产品”商标，以次充好、以假充真在全国范围内销售。警方介绍，“凉山孟阳”所在的公司还雇用网络水军，在直播间制造爆款、抢单的假象，诱导消费者购买。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孟阳曾在直播间里兴奋地喊，“你们给我刷礼物的钱，你们买了核桃，相当于支持了我们这边很多的叔叔阿姨老百姓，知道吧？”事实上，上述公司带货的农产品只有极少数来自本地，大部分是从外地低价购得。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农哥不赞同这种助农的方式，他卖了几年的农产品，一直自称“贩子”。“在镜头面前说我们多可怜，利用别人的善良去挣钱，大多数人很容易相信”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冯胜钒分析，虚假人设、虚构产地等情形已构成虚假广告的范畴，而一旦涉及虚假广告，主播及其所在的MCN机构如存在明知的主观故意，则可能需要承担刑事、民事、行政三种不同的法律责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使带货产品确实来自产地，但是通过编造故事和立人设售卖的行为也可能违法。冯胜钒告诉南方周末记者，“虽然产品的产地是真实的，但是消费者是基于主播编造的故事及人设，产生助农的同情心才愿意下单的。所以主播编造故事、立人设同样构成虚假宣传中捏造、虚构、歪曲事实的误导性方式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷莫村的村书记俄的克布说，“我们谷莫村这么小的地方，没得那么多的蜂蜜，他是骗人的，没有帮助过，农户认都不认得他嘞！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直播电商企业辛选集团的有关人士告诉南方周末记者，一些地方出现农产品滞销问题，分销渠道也较少，公益助农项目旨在帮助当地打开销路，带动就业、助力振兴。农产品相比于其他品类，更容易出问题，利润率偏低，还需要投入大量的人力、资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相对于头部企业，地方供应链质量参差不齐。王惠林介绍，业内常见的模式是，网红公司找到当地合适的供应链，谈好合作后，通过短视频平台建立链接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者了解，网红直播带货抽成，农产品一般抽成大概在20%左右，高一点的产品能到30%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些大凉山网红带货的产品来自于成都蒲江县的供应链，王惠林提醒，这并不意味着这些供应链商的货品不是来自于大凉山，或许是为了节约物流成本，“新疆的哈密瓜有可能是从西安发货”。据凉山州警方披露，入狱的凉山网红选择的供应链并非真正从大凉山拿货。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外一种常见的模式，是由供应链商培育网红和发掘网红。《中国新闻周刊》披露，多位凉山大网红曾和供应链商任彦兵合作，售卖其产品。南方周末记者以合作者身份联系上了任彦兵，他称，“这生意不好做，准备改行了”。这位供应商并未受到此次凉山网红事件的波及。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聂文昌说，比起其他品类，农产品有特殊性，农民手中的农产品质量参差不齐，即使消费者拿到异地农产品也难辨真假。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，部分网红的违法行为对大凉山特产已造成负面影响。面对质疑，一些销售者不得不做出特别解释。一家主打售卖大凉山农家纯燕麦粉的店铺，其营业资质却显示在云南省昆明市盘龙区。主播解释，店铺是粉丝给办的，但发货地址就是自己家。而另一家号称售卖四川大凉山丑苹果的店铺，经营地址在海南省海口市。商家在直播间解释说，这是之前在海南卖凤梨时注册的地址，并且掏出手机询问“Hi，Siri，现在的海拔高度是多少”？Siri给了一个2515米的回答。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，农哥为匿名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家医保局：半年追回“救命钱”63.4亿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/oJQaF1ux6W8TBXvy8GF7pGHv9ricnuyACau5xl3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/oJQaF1ux6W8TBXvy8GF7pGHv9ricnuyACau5xl3g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252110&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年度国家医保基金飞行检查已于8月下旬正式开始，聚焦医学影像检查、临床检验、康复3个群众反映问题比较集中的领域。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医保基金是市民看病的“救命钱”，如何做好监管备受各界关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“2023年上半年，全国医保部门共检查定点医药机构39万家，处理违法违规机构16万家，追回医保相关资金63.4亿元。2018年以来累计追回835亿元。”2023年9月22日，国家医保局基金监管司副司长顾荣在2023年下半年例行新闻发布会上表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据悉，2023年度国家医保基金飞行检查已于8月下旬正式开始。2023年国家飞检将覆盖全国31个省份和新疆生产建设兵团，聚焦医学影像检查、临床检验、康复3个群众反映问题比较集中的领域。同时，首次将定点零售药店纳入检查对象。截至目前，已先后赴贵州、陕西、四川、新疆、上海等15个省份开展飞检工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾荣透露，不少省份也参照国家模式开展了省级飞行检查，今年上半年省级飞检已覆盖84个地市的488家定点医疗机构、30家医保经办机构，处理违法违规机构298家，追回医保相关资金2.1亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;监控&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;用上&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大数据、人工智能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国家医保局已连续5年联合公安、卫健部门开展打击欺诈骗保专项整治，2023年检察机关和财政部门也加入进来，联动惩戒优势更加突显。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顾荣介绍，2023年的专项整治聚焦“骨科、血透、心内、检查、检验、康复理疗”等重点领域，聚焦医保结算费用排名靠前的重点药品耗材，聚焦虚假就医、医保药品倒卖等重点行为，力争做到查处一批重点案件、打击一批违法行为、规范若干专项领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医保数据庞大、繁杂，大数据和社会监督的作用不可忽视。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，国家医保局在全国选取11个省份和53个统筹区，开展医保反欺诈大数据应用监管试点，鼓励各级医保部门运用大数据、人工智能等新技术，力争尽快实现智能监管子系统在所有统筹地区全覆盖，形成全国智能监控“一张网”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年上半年，全国智能审核和监控拒付、追回医保资金9.8亿元，通过办理群众举报，追回医保基金4233万元，并处行政处罚765万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/F36lzS8lXFKnQqOk4HvBKv1gN3lkCinLbyl5yVQf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/F36lzS8lXFKnQqOk4HvBKv1gN3lkCinLbyl5yVQf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252109&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月22日上午，国家医保局举行2023年下半年例行新闻发布会。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（国家医保局官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;3至8月&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;谈判药品已为患者减负1097亿元&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与此同时，每一次国家医保目录的调整，亦牵动万千家庭的心绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年版国家医保目录于2023年3月1日正式实施，至今已运行近七个月。这版目录新增了111种药品，涉及肿瘤、免疫、罕见病、抗感染等多个治疗领域，其中奥雷巴替尼、赛沃替尼、利司扑兰等91种药品以谈判准入的方式新增进入目录，协议期内的医保谈判药品合计达到346种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“2023年3至8月，346个协议期内谈判药品累计报销1.23亿人次，医保基金支出491.7亿元，平均实际报销比例为69.7%。叠加降价和医保报销双重因素，3至8月的半年时间，346种谈判药品已为患者减负1097亿元。”国家医保局医药管理司司长黄心宇介绍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2023年8月底，全国已有23.4万家定点医药机构配备了协议期内的谈判药品，其中定点医疗机构6.5万家、定点零售药店16.9万家，91个2022年新增的谈判药已在5.5万家定点医药机构配备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年版国家医保目录调整工作也在进行之中。7月1日申报启动，9月初通过形式审查的申报药品名单公布，包括224个目录外药品、164个目录内药品在内，共计388个药品通过了形式审查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们将按计划开展评审、测算和谈判等工作，预计于12月初公布今年目录调整结果，从明年1月1日起执行新版目录。”黄心宇说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《关于依法惩治网络暴力违法犯罪的指导意见》出台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;网络虽是虚拟空间，但绝非法外之地，那些在网络上针对个人肆意发布谩骂侮辱、造谣诽谤、侵犯隐私等信息的网络暴力行为，必须受到应有的法律制裁。9月25日，最高人民法院、最高人民检察院、公安部联合召开新闻发布会，正式发布《关于依法惩治网络暴力违法犯罪的指导意见》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《意见》共20条，主要包括十个方面的内容：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是明确网络暴力的罪名适用规则。《意见》根据刑法和相关司法解释规定，对网络暴力行为的性质认定作了指引性规定。具体而言，在信息网络上公然侮辱他人或者捏造事实诽谤他人，情节严重的，以侮辱罪、诽谤罪定罪处罚；组织“人肉搜索”，违法收集并向不特定多数人发布公民个人信息，情节严重的，以侵犯公民个人信息罪定罪处罚。此外，对借网络暴力事件实施的恶意营销炒作行为，可以适用非法利用信息网络罪；对所发现的网络暴力信息不依法履行信息网络安全管理义务的行为，可以适用拒不履行信息网络安全管理义务罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是明确网络暴力违法行为的处理规则。对网络暴力行为，应当坚持多元共治，完善行政执法和刑事司法衔接机制。《意见》规定，实施网络侮辱、诽谤等网络暴力行为，尚不构成犯罪，符合治安管理处罚法等规定的，依法予以行政处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是明确惩治网络暴力违法犯罪的政策原则。《意见》要求，对网络暴力违法犯罪，应当体现从严惩治精神，让人民群众充分感受到公平正义。坚持严格执法司法，对于网络暴力违法犯罪，依法严肃追究，切实矫正“法不责众”的错误倾向。要重点打击恶意发起者、组织者、恶意推波助澜者以及屡教不改者。《意见》同时规定，具有针对未成年人、残疾人实施网络暴力，组织“水军”“打手”等实施网络暴力，编造“涉性”话题侵害他人人格尊严，利用“深度合成”等生成式人工智能技术发布违法信息，以及网络服务提供者发起、组织网络暴力等情形的，依法从重处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四是明确网络暴力违法犯罪与合法行为的界限。《意见》规定，通过信息网络检举、揭发他人犯罪或者违法违纪行为，只要不是故意捏造事实或者明知是捏造的事实而故意散布的，不应当认定为诽谤违法犯罪。针对他人言行发表评论、提出批评，即使观点有所偏颇、言论有些偏激，只要不是肆意谩骂、恶意诋毁的，不应当认定为侮辱违法犯罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五是明确公安机关协助取证的工作要求。根据刑法规定，对于被害人就网络侮辱、诽谤提起自诉的案件，人民法院经审查认为被害人提供证据确有困难的，可以要求公安机关提供协助。《意见》重申刑法规定，同时明确公安机关应当根据人民法院要求和案件具体情况，及时查明网络侮辱、诽谤的行为主体，收集相关信息传播扩散情况以及造成的影响等证据材料。网络服务提供者应当依法为公安机关取证提供必要的技术支持和协助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六是明确网络侮辱、诽谤刑事案件的公诉标准。根据刑法规定，实施侮辱、诽谤犯罪，严重危害社会秩序和国家利益的，应当依法提起公诉。《意见》规定，对网络侮辱、诽谤案件，具有下列情形之一的，适用公诉程序：（1）造成被害人或者其近亲属精神失常、自杀等严重后果，社会影响恶劣的；（2）随意以普通公众为侵害对象，相关信息在网络上大范围传播，引发大量低俗、恶意评论，严重破坏网络秩序，社会影响恶劣的；（3）侮辱、诽谤多人或者多次散布侮辱、诽谤信息，社会影响恶劣的；（4）组织、指使人员在多个网络平台大量散布侮辱、诽谤信息，社会影响恶劣的；（5）其他严重危害社会秩序的情形。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七是明确网络侮辱、诽谤刑事案件自诉转公诉的衔接程序。《意见》规定，对于严重危害社会秩序的网络侮辱、诽谤行为，公安机关已经作为公诉案件立案，被害人同时向人民法院提起自诉的，人民法院可以请自诉人撤回自诉或者裁定不予受理；已经受理的，应当裁定终止审理，并将相关材料移送公安机关，原自诉人可以作为被害人参与诉讼。被害人在公安机关立案前提起自诉，人民法院经审查认为有关网络侮辱、诽谤行为严重危害社会秩序的，应当将案件移送公安机关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;八是依法支持针对网络暴力的民事维权。《意见》规定，针对他人实施网络暴力行为，侵犯他人名誉权、隐私权等人格权，受害人请求行为人承担民事责任的，人民法院依法予以支持。权利人有证据证明行为人正在实施或者即将实施侵害其人格权的违法行为，不及时制止将使其合法权益受到难以弥补的损害的，人民法院可以根据权利人申请，依法作出人格权侵害禁令。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;九是明确网络暴力案件的公益诉讼规则。《意见》规定，网络暴力行为损害社会公共利益的，人民检察院可以依法向人民法院提起公益诉讼。网络服务提供者对于所发现的网络暴力信息不依法履行信息网络安全管理义务，致使违法信息大量传播或者有其他严重情节，损害社会公共利益的，人民检察院可以依法向人民法院提起公益诉讼。人民检察院办理网络暴力治理领域公益诉讼案件，可以依法要求网络服务提供者提供必要的技术支持和协助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十是能动履职促进网络暴力综合治理。《意见》要求，办理网络暴力案件，应当依法及时向社会发布案件进展信息，澄清事实真相，消除网络暴力的不良影响，以减轻对被害人的伤害，帮助被害人走出困境；开展法治宣传，充分发挥执法办案的规则引领、价值导向和行为规范作用，教育引导广大网民自觉守法，引领社会文明风尚；深入分析滋生助推网络暴力发生的根源，促进对网络暴力的多元共治，从根本上减少网络暴力的发生，营造清朗网络空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙一文止步八强，新旧交替的女子重剑队亟待历练]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257567]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEzLcs4MrEYLK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEzLcs4MrEYLK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，在杭州亚运会击剑项目女子个人重剑四分之一决赛中，中国选手孙一文（右）以12比14不敌韩国选手宋世罗&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12比14，9月24日杭州亚运会首个正式比赛日，在杭州亚运会击剑项目女子个人重剑四分之一决赛中，中国选手孙一文不敌韩国选手宋世罗，止步八强。至此，该项目上的中国选手已全部出局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是孙一文的第三次亚运之旅。此前两次，她和队友一同蝉联了女子重剑团体冠军。上届雅加达亚运会，孙一文也曾冲入个人项目决赛，但最终不敌韩国名将康英美，收获一枚银牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这项运动非常讲究百变、平衡、博弈和精准。”一场比赛最多持续9分钟，若同时击中，须早于对方1/25秒方能得分。一次眨眼是0.75秒，足以扭转乾坤，或将胜利拱手相让。为此，击剑运动员需要“走一步算三步”。优秀的击剑运动员往往处于“人剑合一”的状态，即在各种情况下，都能以最快速度、最近路线击中对手暴露的有效部位（包括躯干、腿脚、手、臂以及头盔）。一次次“下意识”的剑刺背后，是经年累月培养起的肌肉记忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东京奥运会冠军孙一文是中国女子重剑的头号选手，素来擅长“以静制动，后发制人”。“坚定、沉稳、有爆发力”是她对自己比赛风格的总结。然而，在东京奥运会及西安全运会夺冠后，孙一文一直困于伤病，直到2022年10月才恢复训练并系统性参加赛事。要“寻找重新出发的感觉”，道路崎岖。孙一文一度感叹自己“都不会打比赛了”，“非常生疏”。直到2023年2月的国际击剑联合会世界杯巴塞罗那站才逐渐找回状态，连夺个人、团体两枚铜牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年7月24日，孙一文（右）在东京奥运会击剑项目女子个人重剑决赛夺冠后与教练庆祝&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前在接受媒体采访时，孙一文就曾表示，这次复出并非一定要拿金牌。在复盘上届奥运会的赛程表现后，她和教练组发现，虽然夺金，但过程中仍暴露出很多问题和不足，如果能加以完善，状态会比之前更好。“队中有新教练补充进来，教给了我许多新想法和动作，现在的我很敢在比赛中去尝试新动作，去开拓新的领域，这是最让我感觉有趣的地方，也是让我决定再坚持一个奥运周期的原因，我还在一直学习。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东京奥运会后，中国击剑队正面临队员新老交替、教练团队调整的过渡期。本次参加亚运会的选手当中，有四分之三都未曾在东京奥运会出战，杭州亚运会被视作这支年轻的队伍备战巴黎奥运会的一次重要的练兵机会。按照比赛计划，杭州亚运会击剑比赛将在9月24日至29日进行，共产生12枚金牌。9月27日，孙一文还将率领年轻的队友在女子重剑团体赛上继续向奖牌发起冲击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如杭州亚运会中国体育代表团秘书长、国家体育总局竞技体育司司长张新所称，杭州亚运会是巴黎奥运会前的“中考”。不足一年后，32岁的孙一文将在巴黎迎来自己的第三次奥运之旅，而在此之前，她和年轻的中国击剑队还需刺破重重阻碍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月20日，在江苏无锡举行的2023年亚洲击剑锦标赛女子重剑团体赛季军争夺赛中，中国队战胜日本队，夺得铜牌。中国队选手唐君瑶（左一）、林声（左二）、朱明叶（左三）与孙一文在赛后合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“决一剑”背后&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;孙一文从不认为自己属于“天赋型选手”。她将自己在职业生涯中的收获归功于认真和倔强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1992年，孙一文出生在山东烟台栖霞市王格庄村。年幼时，她体质很差，每逢冬日便会感冒缠身。孙一文的父亲孙洪明是当地村医，在父亲的督促和陪伴下，她从小就养成了跑步锻炼的习惯。长期的坚持收效颇丰。小学时，孙一文已经成了学校的体育尖子生。11岁那年，孙一文被栖霞市体育竞技学校选中，主攻中长跑。两年后，她已经长到1米66，立定跳远的最好成绩超过两米五。因为个子高、臂展长、瞬间爆发力强，又是左撇子，她被时任烟台市击剑队总教练许昭伟相中，正式踏上击剑的道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;击剑是一项对能力要求非常综合的项目，“力量、速度、爆发力、耐力、协调、柔韧，还有思维”，一个都不能少。最初的训练是艰苦而枯燥的。晨训始于凌晨5点半，基础的步伐和移动，一练就是几个小时。为了培养耐力短板，小队员们还需要接受额外的跑步训练。周一到周五，早晚各跑3000米，周末还会进行6公里越野赛。若规定时间内完不成，就要加罚，用时越多，罚得越多。白天高强度的训练结束后，晚上还要学习文化课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一周过后，孙一文就想放弃。为了宽慰和鼓励女儿，孙洪明特地从老家赶到烟台，陪了女儿两天。度过了最初的适应期，身体素质过硬、善于思考的孙一文开始逐渐崭露头角。“每练习一个动作，做不到时，我会仔细去复盘和思考为什么。每赢一次比赛或输一次比赛，我也会去深挖底层逻辑。”2010年山东省运动会上，18岁的孙一文代表烟台击剑队和队友一同收获了8枚金牌。赛后，她成功入选省击剑队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可日子并未就此平顺。很长一段时间，因为在省队没有编制，孙一文需要自行支付外出比赛的费用。有时候一场比赛就要花掉父亲小半年的工资。当时，家中还有弟弟在读书，孙洪明夫妇在老家的生活十分拮据。由于技战术突破面临瓶颈，孙一文曾两度被省队退了回来。忧心于练习击剑无法出头，孙一文一度跟父亲提出要放弃击剑，外出打工，尽快补贴家用。父亲深知女儿的心思。和小时候一样，孙洪明一方面在心理上疏解，一方面积极和教练沟通，最终大家都没有放弃。幸运的是，在教练的建议下，孙一文开始尝试将枪柄剑改为直柄剑，此后她的苦练终于守得云开。一时间，在省内已经没有女队员能与之匹敌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，孙一文入选国家击剑队。同年，21岁的她完成了个人国际赛事首秀，收获了女子重剑世界杯大奖赛团体冠军。两年后，她在意大利击剑世界杯上斩获首个个人冠军。不过，真正让孙一文走上职业巅峰的还是2021年的东京奥运会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年的里约奥运会，作为“黑马”的孙一文就曾获得女子重剑个人铜牌、团体银牌。但随着里约奥运会落幕，国家女子击剑队也发生了天翻地覆的变化。彼时，对孙一文在思想和技术上影响颇深的“伯乐”勒瓦瓦瑟主教练离任，许安琪和孙玉洁等主力队员退役。新团队领军的担子一下子落到了孙一文身上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;孙一文&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，孙一文习惯于“二次意图”的打法，即先用假动作迷惑对手，再出其不意地进攻。然而，继任的主教练雨歌·欧伯利擅长直接进攻的战术，这恰恰是孙一文的短板。在长达一年左右的磨合期，孙一文的赛事成绩一直平平。她觉得自己仿佛回到了15岁刚刚进入击剑队的状态，一切都要从零开始，“当时的思路和思绪是完全混乱的，就像一团打结的麻绳。”经历过太多坎坷的孙一文只能默默鼓励自己，“这种状态一定是暂时的，人生总会有低潮，就要看你怎么跨过它。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幸运的是，由于东京奥运会推迟了一年举办，孙一文及时地在奥运会积分赛期间调整回了状态。通过融会两套技术思路的长处，她形成了新的作战风格。2021年的夏天，她在东京奥运会女子重剑个人决赛上“一剑光寒定九州”，击败了当时世界排名第一的罗马尼亚选手波佩斯库，绝杀夺金。唯一遗憾的是，在随后的团体赛上，孙一文受伤被换下，中国女子重剑队最终止步团体四强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东京奥运会结束后，孙一文因伤病接连缺席了2022年的数次大型赛事。在2022年初接受媒体采访时，她这样描述自己的伤病，“我现在是左腿后交叉韧带撕裂和积水、膝盖囊肿、半月板磨损，右腿后群到膝盖有一条很长的拉伤。平时哪怕简单动几下，或者天气不好的时候，我的膝盖还是会一直疼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和许多其他的运动项目不同，很少有人能在击剑领域保持绝对统治力。最近一年，由于腰骶始终压迫着腿部神经，孙一文一直处于带病参赛的状态，她一直在摸索着如何在技术和心理上与伤病共处。在7月举行的米兰世界击剑锦标赛中，孙一文夺得了女子重剑个人赛铜牌，这是她首次摘得世锦赛个人项目奖牌。在接受赛后采访时，孙一文表示，这枚铜牌对她而言是一剂“强心剂”，让她明白自己在有伤病的状态下“也是可以的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我对输赢无所谓，但我有一个劲儿，别人能做到的事情，我觉得我也可以。伤病、困难和问题摆在面前，我从不会逃避，也不会畏惧，我一定去解决它。越往上走的时候，遇到的问题就会越多。”在孙一文看来，18年击剑生涯教给她最重要的一课就是“不服软，不服输”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：《博客天下》《GQ报道》、潮新闻、大众网烟台频道、福布斯中国、《精彩OK》《齐鲁晚报》、中国新闻网、《北京日报》、上观新闻等。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从北京、广州到杭州：33年3届亚运会见证中国经济社会发展与国民精神进化丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月23日，第19届亚运会在杭州开幕。点火仪式上，一个巨大的“数字人”从场外飞奔而至，与现场的真人一同点亮主火炬，让这场充满科技感的开幕式达到了高潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅仅是数字人点火，这场开幕式，可以说是迄今为止科技感最强的一场运动会开幕式。空中悬垂下来一张总长185米、高20米的“网幕”，地上一块6000平方米的地屏，让杭州奥体中心体育场“大莲花”成为一个巨大的立体显示屏幕。另有裸眼3D、AR等数字技术的加持，数字烟花灿烂夺目，开幕演出虚拟与实景融合，未来感十足。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是中国三十多年来第三次举办亚运会。而这三次亚运会的举办，也正体现了中国经济社会与国民精神心态的发展历程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年，第11届亚运会在北京举行。这是中国第一次承办大型国际综合性体育赛事，那时也正是中国改革开放初期。1983年中国提出承办亚运会的申请，希望展现对外开放的形象。经济上，当时中国的发展刚刚起步，到亚运会举办的1990年，全国GDP总量只有1.89万亿元人民币，不到3609亿美元，人均GDP在全球排名更在130位之外，在亚洲也并不靠前。当时，甚至连筹办亚运会也缺少资金，不得不面向全国开展了募捐活动，全国数千万人参与，共捐款2.7亿元，超过北京亚运会全部投入的十分之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国第二次举办亚运会是2010年的广州亚运会。20年间，尤其是新世纪初加入WTO、融入全球市场让中国成为世界工厂，经济获得了突飞猛进的发展。尽管2008年受到金融危机一定影响，但中国经济迅速恢复了发展速度。2010年，中国GDP总量超过40万亿元人民币，折合美元超过6万亿，首次超过日本，跃居亚洲第一，世界第二。这次亚运会的举办地选在广州。广州是千年商都、改革开放的前沿，珠三角也是中国外向型经济最活跃的地区，是中国最重要的制造业与外贸基地之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而这次杭州亚运会，距离广州亚运会又过去了十多年。这十多年间，中国经济又增长了近2倍。更重要的是，中国经济的科技含量也得到了很大的提升，尤其是在数字经济领域引领全球。而杭州正是中国电商巨头阿里巴巴大本营所在地。杭州亚运开幕式上那些华丽的数字人、数字烟花，正是中国高端数字技术的集中展现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这三次亚运会引起的关注度也有所不同，相信稍年长的朋友会更有体会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京亚运会从申办成功到筹备和成功举办，都引起了举国空前的关注。记得当时电视机在中国还没有普及，尤其是在农村，黑白电视机也不多见，彩电更稀罕，有些村只有村委会有一台彩电供村民们观看。农民白天要忙农活，没时间看亚运直播，到了晚上，村委会的彩电前就挤满了看比赛的农民。当然，更多的比赛消息，是从第二天早上村里大喇叭的广播里听到的，每一次有中国队获胜的消息，都会引起一阵狂欢。长城图案组成的会徽、吉祥物熊猫盼盼、宣传曲《亚洲雄风》都成为一代人的记忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州亚运会的开幕式匠心独运，非常出彩，“白云之帆”，显示出开放、开拓的宏大气象，不过，论关注度恐怕比不了北京亚运会那种全民参与的炽热状态。我2010年10月份从北京来到广州工作，正是广州亚运会举办前夕。就在前两年，中国刚刚举办了2008年奥运会。全球参与的顶级赛事都举办过了，国人的心理阈值自然上升了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而现在，移动网络已经成为传播的主渠道。每个人的手机上都装着各式各样的短视频、新闻App，就连支付宝这样的支付工具上也有亚运视频报道，随时随地都可以接收到亚运会的信息。在这样便捷的传播环境下，亚运会数字火炬传递活动得到了1亿多人的参与。不过随着生活方式的不断进化，我们也再没法见到全民端坐电视机前的那种状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚运会关注度的变化，也是中国经济社会与国民心态精神发展的必然结果。北京亚运时，中国经济仍然比较落后，亚运会是一次凝聚国人力量、展现民族自豪感的机会，官方媒体的大力宣传，让北京亚运人人皆知。而到广州亚运和这次的杭州亚运，随着中国经济水平的提高，在中国举办的世界级体育赛事已经多得数不过来。普通人也有更多渠道接触更多的信息，他们的注意力被分散了，当然，这也是好事，那些爱好体育的人，会初心不改地关注亚运会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十年三届亚运会，正是中国发展与国民精神进化的见证。在这个意义上，亚运会开幕式科技含量上升，关注度不比当年，恰是丰富多彩和发展进步的体现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>