<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[乾隆资助北美独立战争？封建帝王的眼界和见识不值得吹嘘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258644]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 16:15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Not long ago, a certain big V posted on Weibo saying: &quot;After the gunfire in Lexington, Emperor Qianlong should At the invitation of King Louis XVI of France, he funded the North American militia with 1,000 taels of gold... It turns out that the Qing Dynasty contributed a lot to the independence of the United States.&quot; In order to prove that what he said was true, the blogger also listed the sources of relevant historical materials: &quot;The Ministry of Internal Affairs Manufacturing Office File Volume 27. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qianlong, who has always been regarded as a man of great achievements and self-proclaimed, actually had such &quot;far-sightedness&quot; as &quot;joining France to support the United States and resisting the British and barbarians&quot;. This anecdote aroused the interest of many netizens, and many believed it to be true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this seemingly novel story is actually a very low-level rumor. The blogger listed the words in the so-called letter from Emperor Qianlong to King Louis XVI of France in the comment area, &quot;Bederi &quot;Use money and get wet with rain and dew&quot;, and based on this, he categorically claimed that Qianlong did not use treasury funds, but chose to use private funds to fund the North American militia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this sentence comes from the second sentence in the &quot;Emperor Qianlong&#39;s Edict to King George III of England&quot;. The original text is: &quot;The products of the Celestial Empire are abundant and everything is available. Originally, they did not borrow goods from foreign countries. Whether there is anything or not. Especially because the tea, porcelain, and silk produced by the Chinese dynasty are indispensable to Western countries and your country, so I showed my kindness and sympathy and opened a foreign business in Macao to provide daily necessities and make a profit.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, this passage has been cited by historians to explain that Emperor Qianlong in his later years was closed-minded and short-sighted, and was ignorant of the drastic changes in the external world. It is completely ridiculous that such a paragraph was cut off by the blogger and placed on the head of King Louis XVI of France to prove that Emperor Qianlong was a far-sighted strategist with an international vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why so many netizens believe this crude &quot;wonder&quot; is not only because it is indeed a gimmick, but also because of the aura around Qianlong. So does this &quot;King of the Prosperous Age&quot; really have the kind of &quot;international vision&quot; that netizens believe? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Grandfathers who are not far apart&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the Opium War, when Emperor Daoguang ordered Yijing to interrogate British prisoners, he asked him a series of ridiculous questions. It became a joke in history:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How far away is Kashmir (now Kashmir) from the country? Is there a waterway accessible? Does the country have any contact with the British? Why should we comply this time? To Zhejiang?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How many places are around this country? How many are there in the country it belongs to? How many are the most powerful and independent of the country&#39;s rulers? Is there a dry road from Yingjia to Huijiang? Are there any exchanges? Is there a border with Russia? Is there any trade connection?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Daoguang, who was devastated by the war, could not understand the concept of &quot;world colonial empire&quot; at all. Although the old and shabby intelligence network left to him by his emperor Ama and his grandfather was still working, the intelligence they continued to send from Kyaktu, Manila and Kashgar about the &quot;British barbarians&quot; not only failed Asking him to figure out who his enemies were made the emperor even more confused. He couldn&#39;t understand why &quot;British barbarians&quot; appeared in all directions of the Qing Empire at the same time, so he asked whether there were any enemies in Britain and Xinjiang. There are issues such as being connected by dry road and whether it borders Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, these ridiculous questions asked by Emperor Daoguang are not worthy of ridicule. The vision and knowledge he displayed were only the normal level of the emperors of the Qing Dynasty. In terms of understanding the world as a whole, he is certainly not better than his father and grandfather, but he is not far behind. Because the system through which they receive education and the channels through which they perceive the outside world are essentially the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the world is changing too fast, the concept of &quot;the empire on which the sun never sets&quot; is indeed a bit &quot;over the top&quot; for Emperor Daoguang. So Emperor Qianlong couldn&#39;t figure out where the two cities of Nerchinsk and Yaksa in the &quot;Treaty of Nerchinsk&quot; were, and whether they belonged to the Qing Dynasty or Russia. This only shows that the &quot;international vision&quot; of his grandfather and grandson was not far from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fifty-seventh year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1792), Emperor Qianlong ordered a letter to the then Heilongjiang General Mingliang: &quot;During the Kangxi Dynasty, in order to capture the cities of Yaksa and Nerchinsk, they fought with Russia for several years. The two cities are there. But are these two cities now under the jurisdiction of Heilongjiang? If they are under the jurisdiction of Heilongjiang, who will manage them and who will be stationed there? Send a message to the general and others so that Russia will not notice, quietly find out, and use a toilet Please do not make any announcement. Please accept this. Send a letter in compliance with the order.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Treaty of Nerchinsk&quot; was the first diplomatic treaty signed by the Qing Dynasty within the framework of the Westphalian order. , was also the first time the Qing Dynasty came into contact with the modern international diplomatic system. The treaty not only delineated the national boundaries between China and Russia in the east, but also demarcated the spheres of influence of China and Russia in Northeast Asia. It can be said that the signing of the Treaty of Nerchinsk was a crucial event in establishing the basic territory of the Qing Dynasty. However, a hundred years later, the supreme ruler had no idea where Nerchinsk and Yaksa were. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s even more interesting is that Emperor Qianlong’s idea of ​​​​solving this problem was not to retrieve the text of the Treaty of Nerchinsk for review, but to ask the Heilongjiang generals, and the Heilongjiang generals also discussed with Emperor Qianlong Similarly, he was completely confused about the location of Nerchinsk and Jaxar. Similarly, he did not check the treaty, but &quot;ordered people to check&quot; and reported to Qianlong. It can be seen that the emperor and his ministers did not take this crucial international treaty seriously. To them, the Battle of Yaksa was just a border conflict where &quot;foreigners were looking for trouble.&quot; The signing of the treaty was just a means to solve this minor trouble. It was not a code of conduct for the Qing Dynasty in diplomacy, and once the troubles were resolved, the treaty was shelved and completely forgotten over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The established national policy of &quot;preventing internal affairs and financing external affairs&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of indifference and ignorance of the outside world by the Qing monarchs and ministers actually came from the political tradition and political tradition of the ancient autocratic emperors of &quot;preventing internal affairs and financing external affairs&quot; With established national policies, they always believed that the source of their core interests was not outside the empire, but that factors that could threaten and shake their rule were within the empire. Foreigners come from afar, and even if they are tyrannical for a while, in the final analysis they are people without roots. As long as they win over them from the massive benefits obtained from squeezing their own people, they will be able to live in peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, it is entirely possible for the nationals of this country to repeat their path to power and threaten their rule. This kind of political tradition and established decision-making determines that the attention of autocratic kings, including the emperors of the Qing Dynasty, is always inward and not outward. Therefore, when some of them, such as Emperors Kangxi and Qianlong, occasionally became interested in some &quot;strange skills and tricks&quot; in the outside world, it was only as personal hobbies and pastimes. These hobbies and pastimes could neither change their views on The way they perceive the world makes it even less likely that they will have an &quot;international perspective.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most typical example is that during the Qianlong period, Zheng Xin, a Chinese military leader in Southeast Asia, seized power in Siam during the war and requested for canonization from the Qing Dynasty. From an international political perspective, this was a An excellent strategic opportunity, the Qing Dynasty may gain a firm and reliable ally and strategic fulcrum in Southeast Asia, and once and for all eliminate the threat from Myanmar to the Qing Dynasty&#39;s southern border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Emperor Qianlong&#39;s response to this opportunity was: &quot;(Zheng Xinhe) The king of Siam should be a monarch and his ministers. Now that the country is in ruins and people are perishing, they dare to take advantage of the crisis and no longer care about it. Therefore, he asked his descendants to restore the country and take revenge, and he often thought of self-reliance, and he wanted to grant the imperial edict in vain, thinking that it was a great contract, but it was actually an act that violated the rules and violated the rules.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Zheng Xin&#39;s act of taking advantage of the chaos and seizing power in Siam as a courtier reminded Emperor Qianlong of the story of the founder of the Qing Dynasty who took advantage of the chaos and robbed the world as a courtier of the Ming Dynasty. He was worried that accepting Zheng Xin&#39;s regime would threaten the Qing Dynasty. The legitimacy of the founding of the country thus gave rise to feelings of disgust and rejection. It can be seen that the thinking mode of an autocratic emperor always comes first to consolidate his rule internally. In this case, how can there be any talk of &quot;international vision&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier in the fifth year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1740), the Nanyang Chinese, who had been oppressed by the Dutch colonists, rose up in resistance in Indonesia and were massacred by the Dutch colonists on the banks of the Red Creek outside Batavia. Nearly 10,000 overseas Chinese died. After some discussions between the Qing emperors and ministers, they came to the conclusion that &quot;(the Chinese who were killed) were originally native to that place and were no different from the Ban people.&quot; Emperor Qianlong finally approved the disposal plan that &quot;the Bans in Nanyang are still allowed to trade as usual.&quot; Nothing happened and no sanctions of any kind were imposed on the Dutch colonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above historical facts show that what makes an autocratic king truly superb is his internal skills of protecting, governing, weakening and exhausting the people. To brag about the vision and knowledge of an autocratic king is obviously a lie. It would be even more stupid to misdirect their efforts and spread rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[复旦人体科学馆馆长：与标本“交谈”，让人体不再神秘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258640]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/XcjddVb9DUbrdQ7P2UiaoVzt3pUZ4emkQcuY9TuQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/XcjddVb9DUbrdQ7P2UiaoVzt3pUZ4emkQ cuY9TuQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254082&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhou Guomin often personally introduces visitors, and volunteers do so when he is in class or out. Visitors explain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A human science museum hidden in the Fenglin Campus of Fudan University has become popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people came here after reading Xiaohongshu and Dianping. Everyone is curious about how a place displaying human specimens has become a &#39;niche check-in place&#39; and an &#39;Internet celebrity museum&#39;.&quot; In order to Not to miss every consultation call, director Zhou Guomin specially bound the landline of the science museum to his mobile phone number. Therefore, Zhou Guomin&#39;s mobile phone almost never stopped ringing throughout the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What few visitors know is that being the curator of the Human Science Museum is just one of Zhou Guomin’s many jobs. He served as the head of the Department of Anatomy and Histoembryology at Fudan University School of Basic Medicine for nearly two decades. , at the beginning of the fall semester of 2023, he will also be responsible for teaching more than 20 class hours/week, and he also has many anatomy-related positions and titles outside the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This year is my tenth year at the Human Body Science Museum. I also want to do a better job in popularizing science and discover more stories so that ordinary people can feel the warmth of medicine.” Zhou Guomin said to the South reporters said over the weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is compiled based on the dictation of Professor Zhou Guomin:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;Tell children how new life is born&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although the Human Science Museum is small, it has a long history and a rich collection, such as tissue sections labeled with Yenching University, a micromanipulator produced in Germany in 1930, a complete skeleton and whole-body plastinated specimens. But the most conspicuous place upon entering is the baby specimen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1944, Professor Yan Fuqing’s daughter-in-law gave birth to a pair of twin baby girls, who died due to premature birth. For a long time, Chinese people have believed that &quot;the deceased is the most important&quot; and there are few body donors. However, Yan Fuqing selflessly donated the bodies of his relatives to medical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/aruBfaepCDnnJMJ5gjgYQiBs6u5QTNFXISupbcvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/aruBfaepCDnnJMJ5gjgYQiBs6u5QTNFXISupbcvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254081&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, Zhou Guomin introduced the specimens of twin baby girls to visitors and the story behind the specimens. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Fuqing is the former National Shanghai Medical College (the predecessor of Fudan University Shanghai Medical College) and the Chinese Medical Association The founder of the company is known as the &quot;Father of Modern Chinese Medicine&quot;. For nearly eighty years, these baby girls have been studied and admired by generations of medical students, and are now placed where they can be seen at first sight when entering the museum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Fuqing’s grandson Yan Zhiyuan is also studying and working in medicine. Similar to his sister, he is also a twin, but his brother unfortunately died at birth. In order to fulfill his grandfather&#39;s last wish, Yan Zhiyuan decided to donate his body to his alma mater for autopsy after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some baby specimens in the Human Science Museum with brain malformations, which are very distressing to see. This was actually because some pregnant women at that time lacked necessary vitamins, resulting in poor fetal brain development. Later, after folic acid supplementation was advocated, the incidence of fetal brain malformations was greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the people who visit the Human Body Science Museum are parents who bring their children to learn about human body science. I like to tell children how new life is born, starting with the production of sperm and eggs. Every child is a champion, healthy, strong, hard-working, living in the dream palace provided by his mother, and comes into this world with love and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many doctors are working hard for the birth of new life. If any of these interested children are willing to engage in medicine in the future, I will be even happier. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Both an &quot;alumni&quot; and a &quot;mentor&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Every time a visitor comes, I want to ask them where they come from and why they think of it. Gotta visit this place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Shanghai’s museum resources are really rich, and the name of the Human Body Science Museum seems a bit scary at first glance, but they come all the way here and have to make an appointment to enter the school, which is more cumbersome; On the one hand, I am also looking for potential connections between visitors and this pavilion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the visitors, some are engaged in medical-related work themselves, some have relatives who are ill and are seeking treatment in nearby hospitals, and they come to visit and study while accompanying them, and some want to learn about body donation. A visitor surnamed Wu once added me on WeChat to learn how to donate a body to his seriously ill mother, which was her mother’s wish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who studies medicine knows that without corpses, there would be no anatomy, and without anatomy, there would be no modern medicine. Without visible and tangible human specimens, it would be difficult for medical schools to train excellent doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So we are full of respect for body donors and call them body teachers. These general teachers are both our &quot;alumni&quot; and &quot;mentors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, I have been collecting older body donation certificates. There are many application and volunteer forms from the 1980s and 1990s taped to one wall in the museum. The papers have turned yellow, but the handwriting is still beautiful and clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest note that can be found is on September 23, 1981. An old man named Zhao Leshi expressed his willingness to contribute his body to the cause of medical science after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/1UFIGjNIY2RPt6417kNBRkbOgxLLYYV6m1FDoNcT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/1UFIGjNIY2RPt6417kNBRkbOgxLLYYV6m1FDoNcT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The earliest body donation record that can be found was on September 23, 1981. An old man named Zhao Leshi expressed his willingness to contribute his body to medical science after his death. cause. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for some experts and professors, most of the donors were ordinary people. There were no telephones at that time. Now can I find the relatives of these early donors and express my gratitude to the doctors? If their family members knew that the name of Teacher Da Ti had been engraved on the monument in Fushou Garden in Shanghai, would they want to pay homage to the deceased and tell them about the pain of separation for thirty or forty years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have found one, and I hope to find more in the future and record the story of Teacher DaTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Science popularization should also be innovative and interesting&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many people, the body is like a blind box. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The onset of the COVID-19 epidemic has made everyone more concerned about their health and more willing to understand their bodies. For example, people know that infection with pneumonia may lead to &quot;white lungs.&quot; Look at the male anatomy teacher in the corner. His lungs are black and gray. This &quot;black lung&quot; is caused by smoking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fudan University has always had a tradition of attaching importance to science popularization. In 2013, the school allocated millions of yuan in special funds to carry out large-scale reconstruction and upgrade of the two original exhibition halls (referring to the Human Science Museum and the Pathological Specimen Museum, founded in the 1930s). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called collections and treasures of the museum are of course important, but I care more about everyone’s experience of coming to this exhibition hall. In addition to various microscopes, we also introduced VR, 3D printing, digital human systems and other equipment to enhance the sense of technology and interactive experience. Some children lingered and came several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to popularize science more interestingly, we have also engaged in several cross-border cooperations. Currently going on is &quot;Open Your Blind Box - Human Anatomy Art Exhibition&quot;, where the creators combine medicine and art. After the opening, the number of visitors who made reservations online increased significantly, and some people came specifically for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/n9Kvb9iJFI4HrfBABGoZDm5i6mOZaYDDAwc40BVW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/n9Kvb9iJFI4HrfBABGoZDm5i6mOZaYDDAwc40BVW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In April 2023, the &quot;Open Your Blind Box - Human Anatomy Art Exhibition&quot; at the Human Science Museum of Fudan University officially opened. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Imagine painting each bone with colorful patterns such as giraffes and Garden of Eden. A blood vessel or nerve can have different colors. Each specimen is sketched with a black pen to form a volume of pictures. At this moment, the human body becomes no longer mysterious and becomes more exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that the same object and the observation perspectives of different disciplines and fields will bring different discoveries and experiences. Art is the constant experimentation and innovation of viewing angles. More importantly, art can give people the courage to observe from conventional angles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[旋转的白森林]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258574]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniNqZbJhv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniN qZbJhv. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Grassland Sky Road Observation Deck&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All things are one and connected to each other. The signs appear, but their meaning is difficult to decipher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent the whole morning roaming in the wilderness. On the rolling hills, oats and sunflowers sway in the wind, waiting to be harvested. Autumn has come to Zhangbei grassland again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under a cement pole, I took off my backpack and sat down to rest. It&#39;s quiet around here. Occasionally a car would pass by silently on the road in the distance. Listen carefully to the hum of wind turbines grinding the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number &quot;76&quot; is affixed to the pole. This number has special meaning to me - the birthday of a close relative. A few black feathers and a dried neck bone were scattered on the grass. Seven years ago today, I was driving her on the highway and killed a magpie. The night before, she slept in an orchard near the China-North Korea border and had a nightmare - an eye stared at her in the night sky. After waking up, she heard a woman crying all night on the mountain - an eagle owl was crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;362&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mature sunflowers&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the hill Opera and the sound of tractors came from the villages. I looked away from the feathers. The village square became a threshing floor, and shelled oats were spread on the cement floor like kraft paper. Oats like cold, tolerate drought, and are resistant to salt and alkali. They have been cultivated by Guansai border people since ancient times. They are easy to feel full after eating and difficult to digest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon, I passed a poplar forest and faintly smelled the scent of sheep. There are a group of sheep in the forest, heads gathering together, as if they are performing some kind of silent ceremony. I sneaked into the woods quietly, fearing to disturb them. Unexpectedly, the owner of the sheep suddenly appeared and startled me. A woman wearing pink sneakers holds a mobile phone and a whip in her hands, and a baseball cap on her head is embroidered with the Chanel logo. I asked her what the sheep were doing together, and she said they didn&#39;t like to move when they were full. I said: There are thirty of them, right? She said there were more than seventy of them, clustered in a pile so they couldn’t be counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White impeller, circular pointer. Rotating, without beginning or end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253668&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Oats waiting to be harvested&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wan On the winding country road, I met another shepherd. He was old and walked slowly. He was leaning on a dead branch in his left hand and holding a ewe in his right hand. The ewe has a stubborn character and keeps wrestling with the old man, trying to break free. The reins connecting them are stretched straight. The old man told me that he went to his daughter&#39;s house in a neighboring village to tend sheep early in the morning. The ewe was two years old and had given birth to two litters of two lambs. One lamb was sold for six hundred. The ewe seemed to be eavesdropping on our conversation, nibbling on the sunflower trays on the roadside and looking at us sideways with her yellow eyes. The old man tightened the reins again and made another circle in his hand. He wore several layers of clothes, and his red baseball cap was embroidered with the logo - ×× Fertilizer. &quot;It will take an hour until we get home,&quot; he put the tip of his tongue against his sunken lips, with a hint of complaint in his tone, &quot;I forgot to put on my dentures when I went out, and my daughter stayed to eat...&quot; I glanced at his dark mouth, with only the lower gums remaining. A loose crooked tooth is like a stone monument in the dark night. I think of another &quot;mouth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the poplar forest, well-fed sheep&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The autumn wilderness is colorful and full of temptation. Not long after driving out of Zhangbei County, I couldn&#39;t wait to leave the main road and drove toward the distant hills, dragging the yellow dust cloud behind the car. Went around several old elm trees covered with moss, turned two turns, and finally reached a plateau. A van was parked next to a wheat field, with black film on the windows and half-open side windshield of the cab, without a driver. The view here is wide and unobstructed: countless white windmills are spinning lazily; harvesters are raising puffs of dust and smoke in the wheat fields; a box of &quot;Gatling&quot; fireworks tubes are lying quietly on the grass after being discharged. Accompanying them are drink bottles, cigarette boxes, grocery bags and tissues with lip gloss stuck on them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The van started suddenly, turned around suddenly, and drove towards the road at an unusual speed. After the van drove away, I noticed that there was a commanding point on the high ground - a hill covered with grass. The hills are surrounded by wheat fields. I stepped over the wheat stubble and patrolled around the mountains. The locusts in the fields were flying like shrapnel. This is an &quot;artificial mountain&quot; about 4 meters high and nearly 8 meters in diameter. The moment I climbed to the top of the mountain, I was glad I stopped in time. There is a hole the size of a wellhead in the middle of the top of the mountain. The entrance of the cave is circular, and the cave wall gradually becomes a trapezoid as it goes down. When it is close to the ground, the tunnel turns into a side cave. The hole was dug cleanly, with no residual soil around it. The entrance of the cave is like an open mouth, shouting silently towards the sky. I turned up my collar and carefully walked down the hill. A civet cat scurried past me with a black bird in its mouth. I was stunned for a moment, then quickly got into the car and drove towards the highway at the speed of a van. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253669&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Villers drying oats&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two Soldiers were running cross-country on the road. The short one was leading and the tall one was lagging behind. They gasped and turned to look at me. The confusion on their faces flashed across their faces. A pair of middle-aged men and women with oily hair and powdery faces seemed to have improvised. They were carrying shopping bags. They lower their heads in the forest, pick mushrooms, and shoot videos; groups of well-fed Dauri jackdaws sit on the roadside wires, chattering and quarreling. They like to forage among the domestic animals in the pasture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hills on the highlands&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Past Two villages later, I turned onto another dirt road to see what lay behind the hills. I parked my car halfway up the mountain and walked to the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some cold-resistant vegetation is still taking advantage of the short time in autumn to quietly grow: cold mugwort clinging to the ground; reborn dandelions; potted white daisy; and royal blue delphiniums whose petals are like birds spreading their wings... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Black feathers under the pole&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Sharp syncopation pierced the airflow - a peregrine falcon performed aerobatics in the air, sometimes hovering, sometimes fluttering high, sometimes spiraling into a dive... It seemed to be performing specifically for me. The peregrine falcon is the fastest hunting bird in the world, with speeds exceeding 300 kilometers per hour. I stood there, holding the telescope and not daring to move. Between the loss of focus and the pursuit of focus, I stared at this unpredictable gray-white elf with almost no blinking. I was completely shocked by its transcendent dance of wind, forgetting the existence of time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prop horse&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;Circular ruts created by drift&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are mountains beyond the mountains. After climbing two hills in a row, I saw the scenery behind the mountains - a basin as big as a playground that was very different from the surroundings. The flat ground was covered with a layer of black stone chips that looked like volcanic ash, and there was no grass growing on it. A strange circular rut appears in the center of the basin. On a collapsed cliff, a wall made of masonry and reinforced concrete was exposed. I looked around and saw no other buildings except the towering windmill. I guess the purpose of this place is: mining factory, school, pasture, experimental base...it seems none of them. Another possibility suddenly occurred to me - fortifications. In the 1960s, Sino-Soviet relations broke down. In order to prevent a large-scale invasion by the Soviet Union, our country built a large number of defense fortifications along the borders of North China, Northeast China, and Northwest China. Fortunately, a large-scale war did not break out, and the useless fortifications gradually turned into historical relics that no one cared about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I regret not bringing a tent with me on this trip. This is an ideal camping spot. Open, hidden, leeward, silent, the surrounding scene is shrouded in a mysterious science fiction color. Funnel spiders swung back and forth between the rocks, searching for joints; ant ants dragged the dying wasps forward; white butterflies stood on the porous basalt and fluttered their wings. Every life is the crystallization of billions of years. A blue pebble shaped like a snake egg jumped into sight. After examining it, I knocked it against a rock. Miraculously, the 3 mm-thick &quot;eggshell&quot; split into two and fell off completely. There was a hard stone heart hidden inside, as black as a crow&#39;s feathers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiang Road Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rotating white Paddle, the wind catcher of all seasons. White forests of wind turbines spread across the wilderness. In the past decade, they have grown on a large scale in windy areas such as grasslands, Gobis, and oceans. It&#39;s like an extraterrestrial visitor invading the earth. It&#39;s so white that it&#39;s so cold, so white that it&#39;s unexpected. I stood under the wind turbine, looking up at this behemoth a hundred meters high, counting the number of revolutions of the blades, 1, 2, 3... turn - turn - turn - unknowingly getting lost in the superposition of numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Waiting in the wind&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wind energy, Electric energy can do anything. Returning to the parking place, the windmill in my mind was still spinning. I sat on the grass and made a pot of tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ancient time, original silence. In autumn in the north of Saibei, a fish-shaped floating cloud floated in the clear sky, and after a while, it was blown away by the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公共绿地还是私家庭院？维权五年，难拆除的违建]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258636]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/L5c5bK05T6tGtaLEzwH5N2HVFCyjZsQMUdg9OTBJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;816&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/L5c5bK05T6tGtaLEzwH5N2HVFCyjZs QMUdg9OTBJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254086&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The left side is the villa, and the right wall belongs to the commercial building involved. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to defend the right to repair the outdoor unit of the air conditioner, Lu Caiyun has defended his rights in Hefei High-tech Zone nearly 5 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The air conditioner in the shop was broken, and when it was time to repair the outdoor unit, he discovered that the exterior wall of his shop had become the wall of someone else&#39;s private garden. The large green spaces behind the shops along the street are also enclosed into courtyards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are constant disputes between shop owners and villa neighbors over the ownership of this green space. Some villa owners claim that this green space is the &quot;backyard&quot; listed on the property certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, Lu Caiyun and other shop owners have repeatedly complained to Hefei City Letters and Calls Bureau, Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, High-tech Zone Management Committee, High-tech Zone Shulu Community Service Center and other departments. Until 2022, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center admitted that the contents of the real estate certificates of villa owners were incorrect and needed to be updated. In May 2023, the mayor&#39;s mailbox replied that the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau had identified the &quot;backyard&quot; as an illegal construction in accordance with the law. But so far, these &quot;backyards&quot; have not been demolished.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businesses represented by Lu Caiyun wrote in the complaint letter: &quot;Repeated visits to the same problem have not only consumed a lot of government resources, but also affected the public health. We live a normal life. The relevant departments have also admitted their mistakes, and the facts are very clear. When will it be resolved?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Public green space has been included in the private property certificate&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;Xuhuihushanyuanzuo Community is located on Fushan Road, High-tech Zone, Hefei City. In 2016, Lu Caiyun purchased a street shop in the community and opened a Chinese restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to her recollection, after the shop was delivered, she installed the outdoor air conditioner on the south wall near the villa in accordance with the property management requirements. At that time, no one was living in the villa behind the south wall. The area between the two was planted with green plants and there was a stone road for people to pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, due to a malfunction of the air conditioner in the store, maintenance personnel needed to repair the outdoor unit of the air conditioner. At this time, the area between the shop and the villa has become the private garden of the villa area, and the south wall of the shop has become the &quot;wall&quot; of the garden. With the coordination of neighborhood committee staff, Lu Caiyun was able to enter her neighbor&#39;s &quot;garden&quot; to repair the air conditioner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Caiyun is not the only one who has disputes with the owners of villas because of the open space behind the shop. As early as 2018, some shop owners discovered that the vacant land had been turned into villa courtyards, and the east and west sides were blocked by walls, which seriously affected the use of the shops. They sued the developer Xuhui Group Co., Ltd., demanding that the 7-meter-wide space behind the shops be restored. Public land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shop owners lost both cases. However, according to the second-instance judgment (2019) Anhui 01 Minzhong No. 4059, the evidence provided by the shop owners in the second-instance trial showed that the open space between the shops and the villa area was green space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Basic Terminology Standards for Urban Planning&quot; formulated by the Ministry of Construction (later changed to the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development) states that green spaces refer to urban areas specifically used to improve ecology, protect the environment, and provide recreational areas for residents. and landscaping landscaping. The developer recognized this and stated that the actual construction was also constructed in accordance with the requirements of the green space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The general layout plan of the Xuhui Lake Shanyuan Project approved by the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau provided by Lu Caiyun can also support this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan map shows that there is a passage between the S5 commercial area where the shops are located and the villa area. There are clearly illustrations of multiple plants on the map, indicating that this is a green space in the residential area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 274 of the Civil Code stipulates that green spaces within building zones belong to the owners, except those that belong to urban public green spaces or that are expressly owned by individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Encyclopedia of Applications of the Chinese Civil Code (Property Rights Volume)&quot; compiled by the Leading Group for the Implementation of the Civil Code of the Supreme People&#39;s Court further explains: Roads and green spaces within building zones are usually owned by the owners. According to the legal theory of divided ownership of buildings, the roads and green spaces within the building zone belong to the common supporting facilities in the common property of the community. Under special circumstances, certain roads and green spaces within the building zone are not shared by the owners. As for the green space that is expressly owned by individuals, it mostly refers to the green space in front of the window of a first-floor building unit or the green space in a specific area adjacent to the building, and this part of the green space needs to be clearly sold together with the exclusive part of the building in the commercial housing sales contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the originally planned green space was divided into courtyards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since May 2018, 25 shop owners, including Lu Caiyun, have repeatedly reported to the Hefei High-tech Zone Shulu Community Service Center, the High-tech Zone Management Committee, the Hefei Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, and the Municipal Government. The Complaints Bureau, the Mayor&#39;s Mailbox and other departments reported that the owners of more than 20 villas in Buildings C55, C56 and C57 had occupied green space (8 households in one building) and set up private basements. Some of the problems were solved, but there has been no substantial progress in the encroachment of green space. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local media reported that the owner of the villa produced a property certificate, which stated that the land was indeed his backyard. Southern Weekend reporters were unable to contact the owner of the villa. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Multiple consultations failed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August 2021, the then Party Secretary of Shulu Community Service Center in Hefei High-tech Zone was interviewed by local official media It said that Lu Caiyun submitted materials to the community on June 9, 2020, reflecting the problem of encroachment on public areas. After receiving the report, community staff went to the developer’s Shanghai headquarters to interview him and required the developer to respond within 3 months. Areas related to public access were set back, and the developer also signed a letter of commitment in this regard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months later, because the developer failed to fulfill its concession promise, the community and urban management bureau planned to demolish the illegal building in the villa. However, the owner of the villa showed the property certificate on the spot, which contained the word &quot;backyard&quot;. area. Out of respect for legal and valid documents, the community temporarily suspended the demolition. At the same time, the Hefei Municipal Party Committee inspection team present was also aware of the situation and stated that it would investigate issues related to the real estate certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the problem could not be resolved, Lu Caiyun and others complained to the Anhui Provincial Letters and Calls Bureau in November 2021, requesting to find out why the green space was registered in the property certificates of more than 20 villa owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22 of that year, the Anhui Provincial Letters and Calls Bureau stated in a return visit that the Hefei Real Estate Registration Department had teamed up with relevant departments to investigate and verify the marking of the community’s personal property rights certificates, and was currently studying and handling opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 16, 2022, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center also issued an announcement requiring the owner of the villa involved to correct the real estate certificate. The announcement stated that according to Article 81 of the &quot;Implementing Rules of the Interim Regulations on Real Estate Registration&quot;, because the owners of Buildings C55, C56 and C57 of Hushan Yuanzuo Community have incorrect content in the real estate certificates, they need to wait until they receive the notice. Change the registration and renew the real estate certificate within 30 working days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the fact that the green space is occupied has not changed. On May 9, 2023, Lu Caiyun once again reported the situation to the mayor of Hefei’s mailbox. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 23, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center responded, saying that based on the previous request of city leaders during the interview, the High-tech Zone Management Committee organized an inspection of Buildings C55 and C56 of Xuhui Lake Shanyuan Building. An investigation into illegal construction was launched in the north yard of Building C and Building C57. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, in response to the illegal construction of fences that encroach on public green space and other issues, the Urban Management Bureau of the High-tech Zone has submitted investigation materials on the illegal construction of fences in some buildings to the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau for identification of illegal construction. , Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau has determined it to be an illegal construction in accordance with the law, and the High-tech Zone Urban Management Bureau is handling it in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Caiyun said that they still don’t know the handling of the property certificates that were previously registered incorrectly, and there are no signs that the villa owner’s garden will be demolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend contacted Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau and Hefei Real Estate Registration Center many times, but received no positive response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted Linxi Community of Shulu Community Service Center. The staff informed, “The community and self-regulatory bureau, the real estate registration center and the villa owners have negotiated many times to no avail, and it is difficult to Promote the demolition of illegal constructions.&quot; In addition, according to his understanding, the property certificate of the villa owner has been corrected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters checked the relevant regulations and found no clause that requires the consent of the illegal builders to demolish illegal buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted the Urban Management Squadron of Shulu Center of Hefei High-tech Zone. The staff said that they were already going through law enforcement procedures against the courtyard walls built privately by the villa owners. “Previously, Use drones to take photos and collect evidence, and after the planning department approves it, the parties will be allowed to dismantle it by themselves within a time limit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 13:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突又起，中东“和解大潮”难再续？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258634]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 11:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, 2023, local time, the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement (Hamas) launched an attack on Israel in recent years. The Israeli Defense Forces launched the largest rocket attack in the country, sent a large number of militants into southern Israel, and broke out in street battles with Israeli security forces. The Israel Defense Forces quickly launched a counterattack and launched a &quot;comprehensive siege&quot; of Gaza. The situation between Palestine and Israel suddenly escalated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has aroused widespread attention and concern from the international community due to its sudden outbreak and the huge casualties it caused. It is in sharp contrast to the &quot;reconciliation trend&quot; in the Middle East this year. It reveals the complexity and variability of the Middle East issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The intensity of the conflict is limited&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the past, this round of conflicts has more obvious high-intensity characteristics, as well as the amplification effect of war news in the Internet era, causing It has raised people&#39;s concerns about whether the sixth Middle East war will break out, but at present, it is highly likely that the scope of this round of conflict will be limited to Hamas and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Egypt, Jordan and other Arab countries surrounding Palestine do not have sufficient motivation or reason to go to war with Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2022, Egypt’s economy has continued to slump due to the spillover effects of the Russia-Ukraine conflict. Exporting natural gas to Europe through the Arab Gas Pipeline and Israel’s Leviathan Gas Field has become an important channel for earning foreign exchange income. At this time, if Egypt is at odds with Israel, its economic development will undoubtedly fall into huge difficulties; Syria, in the north of Pakistan, is in jail, and its limited resources will also be prioritized for domestic economic reconstruction; Lebanon is experiencing a severe economic and financial crisis, and there is no are willing to participate in the war; the Gulf Arab countries with strong economic and military strength should only provide moral support and humanitarian assistance to Palestine as long as their core interests are not affected; Fatah, which represents the legitimate Palestinian regime, chooses I watched from the sidelines. Therefore, without the actual participation of other sovereign states, this round of conflict will eventually return to become a stage in the spiral evolution of Palestinian-Israeli relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Infinite Vicious Circle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The conflict between Israel and Palestine continues. To be precise, it is a confrontation with the radical factions dominated by Hamas. It is the inevitable result of the long-term deterioration of the relationship between the two parties, and the explosive manifestation of crossing the critical point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, surrounding issues such as Palestine&#39;s pursuit of statehood, the &quot;legalization&quot; of Jewish settlements, and the competition for holy sites, the tense situation between Palestine and Israel has never changed, and has even become more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since January 2023, the conflict between Palestine and Israel in Jerusalem has continued to intensify. The Israeli military and police have repeatedly forcibly expelled Palestinian residents near the Al-Aqsa Mosque; in early July, the Israeli military carried out A large-scale military operation was launched in the Jenin region, causing a large number of casualties and displacement of Palestinians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Radical factions such as Hamas and Jihad, which firmly advocate armed struggle, continue to promote the spread and expansion of their political and military power, causing the Palestinian-Israeli relationship to gradually deepen into an infinite vicious cycle of &quot;reacting violence with violence&quot; , and laid hidden dangers for larger-scale conflicts and crises that may occur in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Against the background of extremely disparity in power between the two sides, the living space of the Palestinian people has been continuously compressed. The Gaza Strip has been under strict blockade and surveillance by the Israeli military for a long time, and the population density has reached approximately 10,000 people per square meter. kilometer. According to the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) statistical report, 57% of households in the Gaza Strip have experienced a significant decrease in income in 2022, the local unemployment rate has increased by 49%, and 65% of the population is in poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The continued economic downturn has brought infrastructure construction in the Gaza Strip to almost a standstill. When former United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon visited Gaza, he said that Israel&#39;s policy of blocking Gaza was &quot;unacceptable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the relations between Arab countries and Israel have become increasingly easing, especially the recent continuous exchanges between Saudi Arabia and Israel, and the possibility of even reaching a peace agreement, the Palestinians&#39; insecurity has been infinitely magnified. As the Palestinian issue becomes increasingly marginalized, the Palestinians have no choice but to rely on their own strength to survive. At the same time, the continued inaction of the Palestinian Authority, which legally represents Palestinian sovereignty, has actually created more public support for Hamas within Palestine, making it a &quot;firm defender&quot; of Palestinian national consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, the current conflict between Pakistan and Israel is also the product of the collision between long-term conflicts that have not been resolved and changes in the game situation inside and outside the region. In fact, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict has been experiencing cyclical ups and downs since its existence, which makes it almost impossible to achieve a lasting and fair solution. The call for national self-determination and the restoration of legitimate rights and interests has been circulated among generations of Palestinians. As Israel&#39;s &quot;most right-wing government&quot; comes to power, the way Israel and Palestinian radical factions get along will also be full of violence and hatred. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Highly complex&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the short term, this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict will still have a greater impact on peace and stability in the Eastern Mediterranean, and at the same time promote The game relationship between the various forces has undergone a series of changes. It is worth noting that the various conflicts in the region and the intricate interest relationships between countries determine the impact of this incident on the Middle East and even the world, and will not be presented in a simple linear rise or fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the reconciliation process between the Arab-Islamic world and Israel will enter a state of suspension or even regression in the short term. On October 10, local time, Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman said when answering a call from Palestinian President Abbas that Saudi Arabia will continue to support the Palestinians in realizing their legitimate rights, which means that the Saudi-Israeli reconciliation process has attracted much attention. It has been &quot;temporarily terminated&quot;; as Iran announced its support for Hamas&#39;s actions in Israel, its relations with Israel will also fall &quot;below the freezing point&quot;. Although Turkey will actively play the role of mediator between Israel and Palestinian forces , but it is almost impossible for its relationship with Israel to return to its original state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the reconciliation process within the Arab world will be accelerated, and Palestinian affairs may become the glue to curb the &quot;fragmentation&quot; of the Arab world. In the past few months, as the crisis of Qatar&#39;s severance of diplomatic relations has been completely resolved, and Syria has returned to the Arab League family, there is a glimmer of an end to the divisions and internal strife that have lasted for more than ten years in the Arab world after the &quot;Arab Spring&quot;. Under this situation, the Arab world&#39;s political sympathy for Palestine will further promote the ill-fated Arab countries to unite and strengthen themselves, and give them the spiritual motivation to achieve true strategic independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, the main contradictions in the Middle East may change. In the past few decades, the contradictions between Arab Islamic countries and Israel, the contradictions between Sunni and Shia forces, and the contradictions between regional countries and external interference forces have intertwined and superimposed, thus shaping the current geopolitical pattern of the Middle East— —Changes in the structural proportions of any set of contradictions will rewrite the geopolitical demands of the relevant forces. Against the dual background of the Saudi-Iranian reconciliation and the continued strategic contraction of the United States in the Middle East, this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict will undoubtedly further highlight the contradictions between Arab Islamic countries and Israel, resulting in a series of chain reactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the conflict itself, whether it is Hamas armed raids on Israeli targets or Israel&#39;s violent counterattacks with revenge, it has caused huge casualties and economic and property losses to both sides - a large number of Israeli hostages Being hijacked by Hamas affects the nervousness of Israeli residents. At the same time, the Gaza Strip&#39;s only power plant ceased operations due to Israeli bombing and siege, which also means that despair will spread to every street in the area. However, hatred and violence can never fundamentally solve the problem. It is difficult for both Palestine and Israel to make concessions to each other on issues involving their core interests. The Palestine-Israel issue may become even more difficult in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an associate researcher at the Economic, Trade and Industry Investment Research Center of the Mediterranean Research Institute of Zhejiang International Studies University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国籍女子在新加坡被控罪：入乡应随法，别搞“舆论化妆师”那一套丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258632]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 10:47:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to Singapore&#39;s &quot;Lianhe Zaobao&quot; report, a Chinese woman was suspected of being hit by a driver and injured her foot. While receiving medical treatment at the Central Hospital, he allegedly insulted a nurse and refused to cooperate with the police in taking a statement. In addition, he was suspected of verbally abusing a security guard earlier. He was charged with six counts, including one count of public nuisance, two counts of contravening the Prevention of Harassment Act, and three counts. One count of contravening the Private Security Industry Act. If convicted, the woman involved may face a penalty of &quot;a fine of up to 7,500 yuan, or imprisonment of up to two years, or both.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The matter is not complicated and the facts are clear. In the early morning of October 10, the woman involved went to the emergency room of Singapore General Hospital (SGH) to seek medical treatment. She said that she was hit by a substitute driver and requested rapid treatment. The medical staff noticed that she was not wearing a mask, so they handed it to her and reminded her that she must wear a mask in the hospital. Not only did the woman refuse to cooperate, she cursed and insulted the nurse, complaining that she had &quot;waited for three hours.&quot; The hospital had no choice but to call the police, who sent police officers and investigators to the hospital to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the video released by the woman involved, she not only refused to cooperate in recording a confession and let the investigator &quot;guess&quot;, but also changed the topic many times, accusing the nurse of discriminating against her, and also swore at the investigator. , and tried to pull the ID of an investigator, but was firmly stopped by the latter. According to an announcement from the Singapore police, the woman in question even had a criminal record. On October 3, she was drunk, pushed and pulled the security guard who sent her home, and used insulting and abusive language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prosecution pointed out in court on October 13 that if the defendant intends to plead guilty, they will conduct a trial on four of the charges, and the remaining two charges will be taken into consideration by the judge when sentencing. The defendant directly said, &quot;I plead guilty and I apologize.&quot; When the judge asked the defendant whether he would hire a lawyer, the defendant asked if he could get a lighter sentence by pleading guilty early without hiring a lawyer. The judge explained that pleading guilty early would help mitigate the crime. The defendant expressed his understanding, and the judge postponed the case to October 25 and approved her bail of 15,000 Singapore dollars. In addition to the bail, a Singaporean citizen was required to vouch for her. From the news, it seemed that no one came forward to vouch for her, but she was taken back to the police station&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case seemed to be a trivial matter, but it turned out to be more and more troublesome. Not only are the legal consequences extremely serious, but the public opinion effect can also be called &quot;full of influence&quot;. After carefully examining the timeline of this case from the incident to the aftermath, the words and deeds of the woman involved are a living lesson in the rule of law, worthy of analysis and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the words and deeds of the woman involved during the incident may have been &quot;scripted&quot; in advance, but they hit a brick wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman in question refused to obey hospital regulations, did not wear a mask, and was impatient to wait for medical treatment. This is all true; shouting obscenities at the nurse was her intention to vent and engage in emotional blackmail. ; When facing investigators, she denied and insisted that &quot;the nurse discriminated against her&quot;, hoping to &quot;preemptively draw a portrait&quot; to take the initiative in public opinion; recording the video and publishing it on social media was also intended to launch a public opinion offensive to influence the judiciary and escape punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the investigator acted strictly in accordance with the law and stated that the trip was only to investigate &quot;whether the woman in question swore at the nurse.&quot; At the same time, the investigator warned the woman in question three times not to record the video. Facing the investigator&#39;s official business, the woman involved not only ignored him, but also had an extremely arrogant attitude. While speaking incoherently and swearing again, she also made hilarious remarks such as &quot;please bring all the police in Singapore here.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case has aroused a lot of resonance in the domestic public opinion field. &quot;Distorting facts,&quot; &quot;preempting portraits,&quot; and &quot;recording videos and posting them online&quot; are common tricks used in similar public opinion incidents in China, and those involved have tried them repeatedly. There are endless news stories such as &quot;Shijiazhuang woman attacks subway security guard from behind&quot;, &quot;Chongqing woman slaps security guard&quot; and &quot;Woman leads dog into elevator and posts video slandering security guard&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the woman involved encountered trouble when she tried this trick in Singapore: the nurse did not give in, the investigator did not reconcile, and the police complaint afterwards was carried out in accordance with the law. Afterwards, the woman involved confessed in court, showing that the accusation she made that &quot;the nurse discriminated against her because she was not a Singaporean and could not see a doctor&quot; was definitely a slander. She recorded a video despite three warnings and failed to gain public opinion. Instead, she got herself into trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the attitude of the woman involved that she &quot;no longer defends herself, but only seeks a reduced sentence,&quot; she has realized that the &quot;script&quot; is not working and can only stop losses. At the time of the incident, he attempted to seek privileges through emotional blackmail. During the incident, he recorded a video to deny the incident in order to escape punishment. Afterwards, he finally confessed and surrendered in the face of fair law enforcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this case also shows once again the importance of law as &quot;clear rules&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singapore’s Health Minister Ong Ye Kung posted a message on social media to thank the police for their fair enforcement of the law and reiterated Singapore’s zero-tolerance attitude towards such behavior. “This is exactly the behavior we want to protect medical staff from.” According to the emergency regulations of Singapore General Hospital, patients coming for treatment are divided into four types according to their priority. The woman&#39;s minor injuries were originally considered non-emergency &quot;P3&quot; level. Medical staff give priority to using medical resources for &quot;P1&quot; and &quot;P2&quot; patients. If the woman in question is dissatisfied with this, she can go to a private hospital to spend money on medical services instead of clamoring for privileges or making up stories. Denied on the grounds of “discrimination”. At the same time, the woman involved transferred her emotions about the traffic accident to the nurses and investigators who had nothing to do with it, which was even more of a giant act without asking right from wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance of all parties in the incident once again proved the significance of the law as &quot;clear rules&quot;. According to Section 6 of Singapore&#39;s Prevention of Harassment Act (POHA), &quot;using insulting words against public officials&quot; is a criminal offense; the woman involved did not wear a mask, spoke rudely to the nurse, and took the video without permission, which itself has violated the law. It’s not just the understatement of some marketing accounts that “just cursed a few words”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the woman involved’s verbal attacks and filming, the police investigators did not retort, exercised a high degree of restraint, did not exceed their authority and used violence, and did not make peace with the woman involved because of her exaggerated words and deeds. , but to initiate a complaint according to the normal process; if the woman involved is not satisfied with the interview between the investigator and the police, she can also complain about it afterwards, instead of doing the words and deeds in the video that clearly violate the law. Judging from the &quot;Code of Conduct&quot; of the Singapore General Hospital, if the woman in question really encounters discrimination, she can make a complaint through normal channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Just because you waited for three hours does that mean you can swear at the nurse?” The investigator’s words in the video made many medical staff “relieved” because the investigator emphasized an essential point. It should be consensus common sense: the woman involved should act according to the rules and the law, and should not try to use emotional blackmail, manipulate public opinion and other unforeseen tactics, bypass the clear rules to seek privileges for herself, or kidnap justice to avoid punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The significance of law as a clear rule is that &quot;if a person only needs to obey the law, then he is free.&quot; The disastrous failure of the &quot;cultural export&quot; of the woman involved also proves once again that only by adhering to the principle of the rule of law and discord can this kind of &quot;spin doctor&quot; behavior no longer succeed. In similar public events, Protect the interests of other parties and maintain social justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用“算法”找到的舍友是完美选项吗？丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258559]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/13/JJWJQrgM14LzNNBhaoDc1A8mfKbnkJfWIvlQ33Xb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/JJWJQrgM14LzNNBhaoDc1A8mfK bnkJfWIvlQ33Xb. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Nongjian/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For relevant reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/257236 &quot; title=&quot;Roommates are in the same camp? Behind a university dormitory allocation questionnaire including MBTI&quot;>;Roommates are in the same camp? Behind a university dormitory allocation questionnaire including MBTI&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the topic &quot;MBTI dormitory allocation statistics of Beijing Institute of Technology&quot; became a hot search topic, more and more universities refused to randomly allocate dormitories. People pay attention. However, each school has different criteria for allocating dormitories. It may be work and rest habits, major, student origin, or the most popular MBTI (Myers-Briggs Type Indicator). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question that has been lingering in my mind throughout the interview is, would using certain specific indicators to allocate dormitories be better than randomly allocating dormitories? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, a long time ago, when the department needed to recruit interns, I tried to use MBTI to find the most &quot;perfect&quot; interns. My definition of &quot;perfect&quot; includes the following three indicators: enthusiasm for news, reliability in work, and perseverance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, based on the definitions of the 16 personality types classified by MBTI, I summarized several ideal types. However, during the recruitment process of several consecutive interns, I was surprised to find that there was no one. &quot;Ideal type&quot; students send us resumes. Later, when I communicated with the editor of a magazine, she quickly found a suitable intern classmate after hearing me talk about these &quot;ideal types.&quot; One of my guesses is that when submitting resumes, she would be interested in newspapers and magazines with different styles. The preference is the manifestation of a certain personality type. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, my strategy became to observe among the existing intern students. If any of them showed the above three traits, then I would understand their personality type and then recruit intern students. At this time, you can follow the gourd and draw the scoop. Of course, since the sample size is far from enough, this exploration is definitely not statistically significant. In other words, it must not be generalizable to the population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recruiting interns is also a process of finding suitable peers. However, during the interview, we found that, unlike our definition of a “perfect intern”, each university’s definition of a “perfect roommate” The definitions are different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some schools hope that students can chat well, and some students hope that students with outstanding performance can &quot;get rich first and then get rich later&quot;, which leads to various distribution methods. Even if they all consider the distribution of MBTI personality types and how to consider the matching of different types, the key points considered by different schools are slightly different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If your university dormitory is randomly assigned, will you further think about this question? Why has having a perfect roommate become so important that each school needs to figure out its own &quot;algorithm&quot; &quot;Up?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible answer is that the context is changing. Some people who want to improve dormitory relationships spent their college life in the 1990s or 2000. At that time, roommates were the most important partners in life. And when these people became university teachers one after another, they discovered that today&#39;s college students will understand roommate relationships from another perspective. In the manuscript, an interviewee mentioned: &quot;Many children have very clear goals after entering college: to secure a postgraduate degree and go abroad... From the beginning of their freshman year, they will arrange their lives according to their goals and will not participate in dinner parties, etc. For group activities, the dormitory may just be your own resting place.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, are these &quot;algorithms&quot; really useful? This question will not get a definite answer in four years, or even further in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I only look at the &quot;perfect interns&quot; recruited, I will still ask each classmate about their personality type later, usually at the end of the chat, and will never refuse to let a certain classmate because of this. Come for an internship. I will also tell him my personality type. Knowing this information in advance can reduce a lot of friction in future communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MBTI attempts to simplify complex individuals with some specific descriptions. In reality, even the same personality type will have completely opposite responses to difficulties. It is just a slice of a certain stage of life. The lovely thing about people is that they change every moment. A certain difficulty or a pleasant experience will make people change a little bit. Therefore, &quot;perfection&quot; should also be a process. Any &quot;perfection&quot; found with a single indicator will cease to exist the moment it is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[证监会：调整优化融券相关制度， 取消上市公司高管、核心员工融券出借]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258614]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to further strengthen the countercyclical adjustment of the securities lending business, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has fully demonstrated and evaluated that based on the current market According to the situation, the system for securities lending and the lending of allotment shares to strategic investors will be adjusted and optimized in a targeted manner, and on the premise of maintaining the relative stability of the system, the securities lending and the lending of allotment shares to strategic investors will be tightened in stages. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;On the securities lending side, the securities lending margin ratio will be increased from no less than 50% to 80%, and for private securities The margin ratio for investment funds participating in securities lending will be increased to 100%, giving full play to the countercyclical adjustment function of the system. At the same time, securities companies are urged to establish and improve the allocation mechanism of securities lending sources, the penetration verification mechanism and the access mechanism, and strengthen the management of securities lending transactions. On the lending side, according to relevant regulations, the lending of shares placed by strategic investors can be adjusted. In order to highlight the focus of listed company executives on their main business, the lending of special asset management plans established by listed company executives and core employees by participating in strategic placements can be canceled and moderately restricted. The lending methods and proportions of other strategic investors in the early stage of listing. At the same time, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will increase the supervision of various improper arbitrage behaviors, tighten the institutional fence, further strengthen supervision and law enforcement, and investigate and punish various violations every time they are discovered, and impose severe penalties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission will continue to strengthen the supervision of the securities lending business, timely summarize and evaluate the operating effects of the securities lending mechanism, and conduct The situation will be adjusted in a timely manner to better play the positive role of the securities lending mechanism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[停更、逃离、迷茫：原创画师与 AI 绘画的抗争]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3 HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253661&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fantasy cyberpunk style work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Illustrator &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from August 2023, many illustrators have issued suspension notices. They questioned that Xiaohongshu&#39;s AI painting product TriK was used without permission , &quot;feeding&quot; his paintings to AI training, causing copyright disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident first started when illustrator Xueyu questioned whether the pictures released by Trik AI were very similar to his original works. A few days later, many illustrators discovered that their works were suspected of being fed and edited by AI. As the incident unfolded, some original artists announced that they would stop updating, and some users changed their avatars to a unified &quot;Resist AI&quot; pattern in protest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, ChatGPT has set off a carnival of large AI models in China. Generative AI has become unprecedentedly popular, and major Internet companies such as Baidu, Alibaba, and Byte have entered the game. Xiaohongshu is also preparing for an independent large model team and will launch &quot;Trik&quot; in April. The &quot;China Artificial Intelligence Large Model Map Research Report&quot; released at the end of May 2023 shows that 79 large models with parameters of more than 1 billion have been released nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The carnival brought about by generative AI continues, but many people are worried about whether AI will replace human jobs, and original painters are currently one of the professions most affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253662&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Original paintings under creation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Illustrator &quot;Durian Braised Pork Ribs&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;The artist is wandering&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first reaction of illustrator Lin Meng was anger. She believed that everyone who devoted time and energy to the work and seriously created original works would not be able to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng started painting at the age of 5 and has never stopped. When she was a child, her family conditions were average. She was sent to a painting preschool just because it was cheaper than kindergarten care at the time. It was this opportunity that paved the way for her future life. During her childhood, she was a quiet child who would not make any noise and could sit still. Drawing was a means of venting and expressing for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she had no beautiful clothes to wear and longed to have them, she drew them; she secretly bought expired magazines and copied character sketches in fashion magazines, feeling happy in the process. She knew about the existence of the Academy of Fine Arts at a very young age. , that is a &quot;longing for place&quot;. According to the art teacher, she is a child &quot;born for the Academy of Fine Arts&quot;, and she probably knows that she will definitely be admitted to the Academy of Fine Arts when she grows up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From graduating from Tianjin Academy of Fine Arts to becoming an illustrator, everything has followed the ideal pace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as two years ago, she tried using AI painting. The technology at that time was limited, &quot;very childish and not very mature&quot;, but the birth of AI painting itself exceeded her imagination: cold electronic information could complete a painting through algorithm training. Later, these technological breakthroughs became more like a necessity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Meng does not reject AI, and science fiction themes have always been her preference in creation, just like she believes in the existence of aliens. &quot;Every field needs technological development, just like when we were children, everyone drew on paper, and later on electronic devices.&quot; From the current era to the era of artificial intelligence, how to live in harmony is a need during the transition period Something that everyone should deal with together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矛盾在于和谐相处是困难的，“因为它确实触犯到了我们的利益，其实也是尊严问题，别人偷了你的成果，你很难会大方地让它拿去。”林梦觉得，AI的不公平之处也在于，创作者要花一个月或者更长时间创作的作品，AI可以在几分钟内画出来差不多的效果，虽然细节不足，但已经能达到圈外人乍一看还不错的效果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一个没有情感的AI，之所以能够达到这个效果，是因为有大量的原创作品“投喂”，对原创作者来说，这是一件不公平又难解决的事情。没有规则，没有相关法律约束，虚拟与现实就会产生冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，林梦入驻小红书，以“榴莲煲排骨”的笔名陆续发布原创作品。事件发生之后，她宣布停更，去其他网站重新开始。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原创画师李可也和林梦一样，在知晓小红书和TriK的这一做法之后，决定停更，并把自己的头像更改为“拒绝AI”的图案。在聊到这一话题时，他仍然气愤，觉得这种做法是拼接、投喂、训练而非创造，“只是剽窃前人的辛苦努力拼接而成的尸块，所以我不会认可AI，更不会把AI当成工具，它本质上是剽窃。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开了平台，去别处似乎也只是一个暂时的容身之地，未经授权的作品用于AI训练的现象普遍存在。浪潮卷向所有角落，似乎是早晚的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年11月，插画师洛柒也在微博质疑二次元AI绘画应用Niji·journey涉嫌抄袭，该应用生成的许多图片与一些画师的原创作品相似。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，网易旗下LOFTERAI绘画功能也被质疑使用用户作品进行AI训练，导致不少原创画师逃到了其他平台。随后，LOFTER下架相关产品，并发布官方致歉信。而如今，其他平台也无法保证这群“流浪”的画师能够找到一个庇护所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月，B站也因涉嫌用AI绘画洗稿、侵犯网易游戏《一梦江湖》版权而登上热搜。当时，在B站主页更新的“七夕夜”活动宣传图被网友怀疑使用AI制作，还融合了另一位原创画师的作品，甚至留有细节bug：凹进去的手，只有一半的鞋子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前，风头正劲的OpenAI和微软收到了一份长达157页的集体诉讼书，被指控未经允许而使用数以亿计的互联网用户的个人信息。原告律师引述了OpenAI安全部门负责人的一段公开发言，该发言指出，它们的AI产品是“一项相当不成熟的技术”，如果没有足够的安全防范，激进地部署AI模型将是非常鲁莽的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像画师们停更、逃离，或者在作品上标注“禁止AI”，或学习防止被AI训练的方法，都只是暂时，他们非常清楚，这将是一场漫长的挑战。 AI浪潮滚滚向前，众生皆被裹挟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;插画师“榴莲煲排骨”的工作台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“榴莲煲排骨”/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;AI冲击：一些人拥抱，一些人被裁员&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;职业画师Zela从业两年，是AI绘画最早的一批尝试者——最开始她并不认可AI，但现在已将AI作为工具运用到绘画中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她日常的工作流程是：在构图上借鉴AI，画好草图后，根据AI的一些图片进行配色，把AI当作一个素材库或导师，绘画步骤没有明显变化，但找素材的速度更快了。对她而言，耗费时间的步骤不是细化，而是前期出多种方案供甲方挑选，调整方案直到定稿，可以省下大量重复工作的时间，但因为她与AI还在磨合阶段，总体效率目前没有提高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从早期不认可AI，到接受和拥抱，最关键的原因在于，Zela发现它可以做到辅助作画，而且AI生成的作品有一半有可取之处，“我可以从中学习、吸纳。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她看来，AI绘画目前还只是工具，但以后将是绘画的趋势，“因为太便宜太方便了，尤其最底层的人受影响最大。视觉中国、Artspace、Pixiv已经开通AI供稿渠道，AI图也已经在商用，主要集中在新媒体、活动海报等设计工作中，对动漫和游戏的影响还需观望。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游戏行业从业者林源告诉《南方人物周刊》，游戏原画师包括场景原画、角色原画、美术宣发原画等，不少公司会将游戏原画设计需求外包给专门的公司去负责。外包是按照每张画的金额来付费，可以节省人力成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我所在的游戏项目，已经很明确地用AI做了一些角色设计。据我所知，还有其他几家类似的游戏公司也用了一部分AI绘画技术。最直观的影响就是，本来我们可能要发外包或内部人员去做的一个需求，直接用AI就可以解决了。”他提到，游戏领域的一些中小厂甚至大厂都有用到AI，只是运用程度和修改程度不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林源举例，比如原来画100张原画，要招5名原画师做3个月或更长时间。现在可能只需要一名原画师，100张图用AI出图，他来做修改，这是一套已经广泛商用的模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林源说目前AI的影响主要还在下沉市场，能够替代的是对质量和艺术造诣追求并不高的那部分市场，比如网页上的游戏广告，很多都是AI作画。一些对美术包装要求不高的游戏类型，也可以采用AI，但对一些要求较高的需求，需要花费时间设计打磨，目前AI是远远没有办法达到的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梦的观察与此类似，大厂也有在用AI，但大部分只是辅助参考，并不是完全取代。因为目前的技术还无法取代，但它的确会取代一些快速出单的小公司，“这样的市场需求一直存在，只不过以前画师东拼西凑出来还需要一段时间。AI可以非常快，几分钟或几秒钟，所以才会威胁到这样的一部分公司。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI冲击的范围正在越来越广泛，不少游戏公司的美术设计岗位开始裁员，也有不少公司减少原画师岗位招聘。一位二线城市游戏公司的原画师回忆，前几年找工作还很吃香，现在公司大裁员，只留了3位原画师岗位，其余全部被裁。大厂也有危机感，某位大厂画师提到，公司专门调教AI已经花了快一年时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“原画师去面试，工资很容易被压价，不会给太高。一些做原画外包需求的公司，明显感觉需求量变少了，之前一个月不愁单子，现在可能一个月只有这几单。因为有一些需求已经能够用AI来完成了，这是原画师的窘境。”林源所在的游戏项目美术负责人提到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“AI会先从替换劳动力开始，就像在工厂里机器人替换工人，如今AI就是创作工厂的机器人。那些偏向于重复的、技术含量不是那么高的工作会被替换掉。原画师会越来越卷，整个行业越来越精英化，岗位肯定会少。除非整体的市场规模变大了。”林源认为，AI的出现还是为了满足市场需求，哪些可以被现有的AI技术替换，自然而然就会被替换掉。随着未来AI技术的提高，画师这份职业的危机感也会更强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使未被AI波及的画师也发现，AI出现之后，客户对时间的要求越来越高了。某种程度上，这是一个快节奏时代催生出来的需求，也倒推了整个生产链条的变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253660&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;插画师“是雪鱼啊”的画作（左图）与Trik AI生成图片对比&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“是雪鱼啊”社交账号/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;侵权行为难举证&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生成式AI的训练数据库非常庞大，也导致保护知识产权成为现阶段的一个难题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海大邦律师事务所高级合伙人、知识产权律师游云庭告诉《南方人物周刊》，主要难点在于举证，作者没有办法证明平台使用了自己的作品进行训练。根据我国著作权法规定，使用他人著作权作品训练人工智能的，应当取得著作权人的许可，但训练的过程不透明，所以作者比较难维权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还提到，人工智能生成的作品哪怕与原作者的比较相似，如果在特征性文件（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指作品的特有元素&lt;/span>;）上不一致的——比如腾讯的logo是两只企鹅，企鹅的围巾或蝴蝶结就是特征文件，如果特征文件不一致的，仅仅是一只黑白相间的企鹅——不会被认为构成著作权侵权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海曼昆律师事务所律师刘红林亦指出，根据现有法律和原则，如果平台未取得著作权或著作权授权的作品，擅自使用作者的原创作品进行AI训练、生成内容，存在侵犯著作权的风险。难点在于我国《著作权法》并不保护诸如风格或理念等抽象的“思想”，而仅保护绘画中的具体元素等“思想的表达”，但也恰恰是“思想”方能体现作者的独创能力。在此背景下，若作者发现AI绘画作品与其本人作品存在相似的画风，则维权的难度较大；只有在AI绘画作品存在明显抄袭的情形时，才可以向其主张侵权责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;493&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;小红书上不少原创画师发布停更通知&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在如何证明AI对原创者的侵权行为上，刘红林指出，当前AI技术发展迅速，对素材的选择随机性强，算法的计算规则复杂多样，使得生成式作品的“抄袭”痕迹容易从技术角度去规避。因此，要想证明AI图片生成器侵犯了他们的版权，就要证明具体哪一件作品被复制到AI的算法系统中。然而，算法的“不透明”，让这一证明思路在实践中并不容易落地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，平台用户协议也可能在用户并没有仔细阅读的情况下，同意平台用于AI训练。此次小红书事件引发画师抗议的原因之一也在于：根据小红书的用户协议，该平台有权直接使用用户作品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游云庭认为，平台如果使用用户的作品训练人工智能，应该取得原作者的单独同意，而不是仅凭一个用户协议就可以取得授权。 “这个用户协议哪怕签了平台，可能也会因为没有提供对价，而被认定为排除另一方主要权利的格式条款，也就是俗称的霸王条款。”刘红林也指出，一些对用户权益有重大影响的条款，平台有义务重点提示用户。对于存在明显的不平等、免除自身责任而加重对方责任的条款，用户有权主张合同无效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有效的修改，可以避免AI的痕迹太重，可以达到避免侵权以及避免质量太低的问题。”林源觉得，侵权的问题很难解决，如果只用自家图片或商用图投喂AI，学习的范围就比较窄一些。避免侵权，目前更多的做法是做二次修改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过也有比较谨慎的公司。一位海外游戏公司场景美术从业者告诉《南方人物周刊》，这个问题主要看公司，不同公司对待工具的态度不一样，“我们公司禁止AI作图只是因为AI软件的素材来源我们没法控制，可能会遇到潜在的版权纠纷。与其卷入这类诉讼，不如事先就禁止。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘红林指出，人工智能深度学习所引发的知识产权问题较之一般著作权侵权更为复杂。传统著作权法中所适用的侵权判定原则，不能充分回应人工智能深度学习的侵权问题，相关的法律法规需要逐步完善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI与画师之间的矛盾，刘红林认为关键在于“目前双方之间缺乏一个合适的利益分配机制，AI数据库使用了作者的作品进行数据训练，却没有对应的激励机制。这也是AI行业未来需要着重考虑的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5岁开始学画的林梦，家中有一个角落专门属于绘画，存放着从小到大厚厚的几本画册。有时候，翻一翻过去的画作，成长中的某个情景便如电影般重现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她记得，有幅画是高中时候的一张静物水粉画，被老师批评有“很大问题”，“当时觉得有点天塌下来的感觉。”但也是老师的那次指点，也让她决定主攻色彩，用色彩表达情感，那张画是她成长当中的关键一步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;绘画与情感的连接，是AI无法取代的部分。她现在的画作，以赛博朋克风为主，但并非紫色、蓝色这类冷色调的机械感，她选用了粉色为主的色彩欢快的颜色，一种高饱和度的赛博朋克。林梦说，“我希望科技和机器，不要那么冰冷，天真烂漫和温暖，可以和赛博朋克联系在一起，也是对科技的一种期待吧，相信它能够和人类达到一个平衡点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护采访对象隐私，文中李可、林梦、林源为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以新一轮冲突已造成双方超过3500人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258616]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Statistics released by the Palestinian health department show that as of 11:55 local time on the 14th, a new outbreak in Palestine and Israel Since the first round of conflict, 2,215 people have been killed and 8,714 injured in the Gaza Strip; 54 people have been killed and more than 1,100 injured in the West Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; In addition, according to a report by the Jerusalem Post on the evening of the 13th, data from the Israeli Ministry of Health showed that since the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the number of Israeli deaths has exceeded 1,300, and the number of injured has reached at least 3,484. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This round of conflict between Palestine and Israel has killed more than 3,500 people on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[诺贝尔文学奖得主格丽克逝世：她的诗有超越创伤与丧失的力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258626]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/20/10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;Picture/Katherine Wolkoff&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The word &#39;poet&#39; must be used with caution; it names a desire, not a profession.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Years ago, Louise Glick wrote in an autobiographical essay: The desire to make art produces an ongoing experience of longing, a restlessness that sometimes ends in a romantic or sexual way. There always seemed to be something ahead, the next poem or the next story, visible but out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To fully understand it is to let it haunt and torment; a certain sound, a stone, becomes a torment - the poem that symbolizes this sound seems to be somewhere, completed, It is like a lighthouse, but the difference is that when you swim towards it, it retreats.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his nearly 60 years of poetry career, he has accumulated 13 poetry collections, which are stacked in the corner of the room. Occasionally, Glick would deliberately suppress some &quot;sneaky&quot; complacency and lament that he &quot;didn&#39;t waste time.&quot; Now, a new stamen has been added to her crown - the Nobel Prize for Literature. The award citation praised her &quot;unpretentious poetic voice that universalizes individual existence.&quot; Her first reaction after winning the award was: Oops, I won’t have any friends! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps in response to the suffering and shadow of the current global epidemic, jury chairman Anders Olsen quoted &quot;Snowdrops&quot; in his speech, which was the novel that won Glick the Pulitzer Prize. Award-winning poetry collection &quot;Wild Iris&quot; (1992). It depicts the miraculous return of life after winter and seems to symbolize the poet&#39;s &quot;radical transformation and rebirth,&quot; who, despite being constantly troubled by life&#39;s mistakes and changing circumstances, is still able to &quot;make leaps from a profound sense of loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She saw a vision of death at the age of seven, and was choked by anorexia as a teenager. The precocious girl shouldered the destiny of the poet to &quot;witness&quot;. With the help of myths and religious fables, she traveled between the holy and the underworld, transcending the &quot;confessional poets&quot;. As predicted in the poem, she is indeed more like Lazarus than Joan of Arc - the person in the Bible who was saved and resurrected by Jesus, whom the poet Sylvia Plath wanted to &quot;imitate&quot; but ended up The lost road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In her poems, the self listens to its remaining dreams and fantasies, and no one is stronger than her in the face of its own fantasies.&quot; Olson said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hungry is not for experience, but for understanding​&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I was born cautious, in Taurus under the sign./I grew up and thrived on an island,/in the second half of the twentieth century;/the shadow of the Holocaust/barely touched me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1943 Glück was born in Long Island, New York, to a Hungarian-Jewish family. These few words are the &quot;autobiography&quot; she wrote for herself. As the title of her second collection of poems suggests, this &quot;house on the swamp&quot; is not stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her father is a successful businessman with a long-cherished wish to be a writer, and he often tells her legends and historical anecdotes such as Joan of Arc. My mother graduated from Wesleyan Women&#39;s College, where many ladies were born, and served as the &quot;arbiter&quot; of the family&#39;s art education. She also had a sister who would become a banker in Manhattan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Glick&#39;s writing is not Cold War-style politicization, but personal politics. Her writing returns to the identification of human identity. This is a key point. All the women in her works are Looking for my own voice.&quot; Fan Jinghua, the translator who first introduced Glick to China, pointed out that the rise of personal writing in the American poetry tradition, including the rise of Western feminism, is the reason why Glick has won many important awards over the years. background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Glick, family seems like her &quot;concentration camp&quot;. &quot;I have a strong desire to speak, but this desire is often thwarted: my sentences, if interrupted, are completely altered—transformed rather than interpreted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short , &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;She does not meet the definition of a child: full of hope for everything.&quot;&lt;/span>; As an adult, she wrote in her poem Wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All the defense, spiritual stubbornness, persistence/taking off the mask of ordinary people and revealing the tragedy,/these are actually the The ignorance of the world./Means that which is partial, changeable, capricious -/everything that is excluded from the &#39;absolute&#39;.&quot; (&quot;Birthday&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the real The family trauma occurred 7 days before her birth, when her &quot;sister&quot; died unfortunately. &quot;Her death is not my experience, but her absence is; her death made me born.&quot; Glick later realized that she made such a dazzling declaration in her first collection of poems: &quot;Birth, not birth.&quot; Death is the unbearable loss.&quot; (&quot;Cottonmouth Snake Country&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tension between mother and daughter turns into a zero-sum game between the two sisters competing for maternal love in fantasy. In &quot;Ararat&quot;, the &quot;Book of Death&quot;, Glick wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;When my sister dies,/my mother&#39;s heart changes Very cold, very hard, like a tiny iron pendant./ Later I felt that my sister’s body/ was a magnet. I could feel it sucking/ my mother’s heart into the earth,/ so that it would grow.” (“Loss” &quot;Love&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also rewrote the story of Solomon&#39;s verdict. When two mothers fight for one child, the mother is torn between the two daughters, and she is &quot;willing to destroy herself&quot; to prove who is the righteous child and cannot bear to split her mother apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mental symptom is related to the early realization of the &quot;destiny&quot; of writing. Not only out of the overwhelming will to get rid of her mother, but also the &quot;obsession with purity and control&quot;, when she was a teenager, Glick began to strictly implement a diet, from 85 pounds to 75 pounds, to some extent, she also imitated Zhen. De&#39;s asceticism eventually developed into anorexia, and he almost starved to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It quietly begins/in some girls/the fear of death, in the form/of devotion to hunger, / Because a woman’s body is a tomb; it will accept / anything. I remember / lying in bed at night / touching soft, discrete breasts, / touching, at 15 / the disturbing flesh / that I would have sacrificed / until Limbs no longer / blossom and escape: I feel / what I feel now, align these words - / the same need for perfection, / death just a by-product.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The need for perfection Linked to forms of resistance, body and mind are both unified and separated, leading to a &quot;metaphysical hunger&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Hunger is not for experience/ It is to understand as if it were available in the abstract.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years of psychoanalytic treatment saved Glick. After dropping out of high school, she interrupted her formal professional education and entered a poetry seminar at Columbia University, where she studied under two American poet laureates, Leonie Adams and Stanley Kunitz. Under the influence of the latter, she changed from being arrogant and arrogant to being humble and restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said frankly, &quot;Psychoanalysis taught me to think. It taught me to use my ideological tendencies to oppose the clearly expressed parts of my thoughts. It taught me to use doubt to check my own words and discover (self-expression It gave me the intellectual task of transforming paralysis—an extreme form of self-doubt—into insight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot; 656&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Some works by Louise Glick&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When I feel safe , I can love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Glick viewed this experience in a positive light, &quot;The feeling of hunger helped me control my greed, which was very helpful in gaining an independent self.&quot; And this seems to be It also established her own &quot;poetics of desire&quot;: in love, nothing is desired. She expresses her desire for someone or something in the world that she wants to possess by saying &quot;no&quot; instead of &quot;yes.&quot; What is undoubtedly revealed here is the finitude of human beings. Just like &quot;Ripe Peaches&quot;, from the door to the dining table, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Certainty, a dead thing/...accompanied by that obscene mouth/ Hungry for love -/it&#39;s like love&quot;&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, because love is as scary as death, this has been planted since childhood: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Fear, of loss The fear of disease; / the fear of disease wearing the bride’s white dress” (&quot;Joan of Arc&quot;)&lt;/span>;; and the mother who “knitted red scarves of various colors” also said to her grown-up son: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s not surprising that you are like this, / afraid of blood, your women / are like brick walls after brick walls.&quot; (&quot;Poetry of Love&quot; )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the representative work of his mature period, the collection of poems &quot;Averno&quot;, Glick reinterpreted the story of Persephone in Greek mythology: she accidentally ate Pluto&#39;s pomegranate, Kidnapped as a wife and returning home &quot;stained with red juice&quot;, she realizes that &quot;she has been a prisoner since she was born a daughter&quot;; Pluto wants to say, &quot;I love you and nothing can hurt you&quot;, But he thought it was a lie, and what he finally said was, &quot;You are dead, nothing can hurt you.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Burning Heart&quot; and Dante&#39;s &quot;Divine Comedy: Inferno&quot; The protagonist Franziska&#39;s dialogue explains the power of the &quot;male gaze&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Both fire and eternity/... even when I am touched Before, I already belonged to you;/You only need to look at me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A more controversial poem is &quot;Mountain Plum Blossom&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I hate them./I hate them as much as I hate sex,/that man&#39;s mouth/it blocks my mouth, that man&#39;s body/it makes people limp&quot;&lt;/span>; , the upper and lower positions of the body during sex, are as conventional as choosing which flower to &quot;light up the yard,&quot; but are essentially rooted in forced silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Glick has always refused to be labeled as a &quot;hyphenated poet&quot;, and &quot;feminism&quot; is the most prominent prefix. Glick once emphasized that she and her sister were raised &quot;to reorganize, to achieve and to aspire to glorious achievements... We were never asked to believe that such achievements were impossible, either because of our gender Or our historical period.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is logically puzzled by the determination of some women today to write as women, since this appears to be an existing notion of ambition being constrained by gender differences. Rather than gendered distinctions, she cares about a &quot;bigger distinction&quot; between symmetry and asymmetry, harmony and homophony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we cannot forget that Glick calls herself an &quot;untrustworthy speaker&quot; in her poem. In her case, language is a medium that switches between frankness and disguise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother suffering from postpartum depression in &quot;First Born&quot;, the emotionally numb and silent daughter mourning her father in &quot;Ararat&quot;, the anger in the face of cheating and broken marriage in &quot;The Pasture&quot; The provocative wife... These images more or less reflect the loss and isolation that Glück constantly encountered in his life: he was divorced twice, and a house was burned down by fire. From then on, she became &quot;a dreamer and a viewer&quot;, an author &quot;obsessed with loss&quot;, &quot;waiting for 20 years to endure the inescapable loss&quot;. &lt;p>; /span>;This straightforward spoken language suddenly appears at the end of the entire collection of poems &quot;Rebirth&quot;, leaving a blank space with an aftertaste, which is also humorous and spicy. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I once told myself/From nothing/Nothing can be taken away./But can you still love anyone?/When I When I feel safe, I can love&quot;&lt;/span>; - this is the answer given by &quot;New Life&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Greek mythology, Dido committed suicide because of the loss of Aeneas; when they reunited in the underworld, he asked for her forgiveness, but she walked away without saying a word. In Glick&#39;s writing, she asked the goddess of fate to allow him to repay her passion, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;Even if the time is short. What is the difference between a short time and a lifetime: Indeed, in these moments./They are all the same, all eternity.&quot; (&quot;Queen of Carthage&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poem was included in the book &quot;America&#39;s Favorite Poems&quot; 》Anthology. In his introductory work on Glück, scholar Daniel Morris noted with interest this anecdote: An administrative assistant in Kansas City, Missouri, described in detail how the poem spoke to her and helped her gradually come out of it. Intense intimacy with a scientist, moving on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individualistic and universalistic, ordinary and oracular, ephemeral and mythical, tragic and comic...&quot; Daniel Morris pointed out that Glick&#39;s &quot;subject status&quot; in contemporary literature ” has enough room for malleability, it’s hard to think of another American poet since Bishop who has attracted such a wide range of critics, readers, and contemporaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick&#39;s early &quot;Garden&quot; poems include &quot;fear of birth&quot;, &quot;fear of love&quot; and &quot;fear of burial&quot;, which are always Glück&#39;s The core theme, but the song &quot;Garden&quot; mixed in it still overflows with the true desire for love: &quot;But still/there is something you need,/your body so soft and alive, among the animals of stone./Admit it: being like them is scary,/more than hurts.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No wonder the poet Zhou Yan said: After Plath, how do women love? I recommend reading Glick. &quot;For a poet like her, if you are deceived by the surface coldness, aloofness, repulsion, and even the rudeness from time to time, you will be stupid. This kind of poet does not waste energy on the surface. What she focuses on is Human emotions, spirits and symbols. So it must be compassionate and warm inside. It is not the kind of poet who is cold or numb inside. This is the fundamental difference.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This voice is in &quot;The Triumph of Achilles&quot; 》 is even more firm: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;He is already a dead person, sacrifice/because of the part that can love, the part that can die.&quot;&lt;/span >;Translator Liu Xiangyang summarized Glück&#39;s expression as &quot;love is greater than death.&quot; Desire goes beyond the trappings of self-protective life and is connected to the recognition of virtue and glory. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let more voices fall off the paper&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It was from &quot;The Triumph of Achilles&quot; that Glick drew inspiration from mythological characters, those who were abandoned and abandoned. The voice of punishment and betrayal was re-contextualized in modern society and became her personal and universal &quot;mask&quot;. In the words of poetry critic Helen Vendler, &quot;give experience a permanent mythical form&quot; instead of turning your autobiographical experience itself into mythology like Plath, Lowell and other confessional poets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick regarded the first collection of poems with the imprint of the &quot;Confessional School&quot; as a &quot;failure&quot;. Although the Nobel Prize committee complimented her by saying that &quot;in her own severity and unwillingness to accept simple principles of faith, she is more like Emily Dickinson than any other poet,&quot; Glick said that Dickinson was just her &quot; One of the Early Heroes,” which later became unreadable, like chalk on a blackboard or scratches of fingernails, or the voice of a crazy little lady—like a kitten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;American Narcissism,&quot; she pointedly pointed out the seductive misleading nature of Rilkean romanticism, &quot;In our poetry, narcissism reaches its most terrifying definition: It is not an extension of the self but a substitute for it, as if the lifeless mirror somehow allowed the surviving boy to survive.&quot; The end result: &quot;He reaches the end of his insight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;There is an automatic sentence pattern in Glick&#39;s mind, starting with &quot;Poets should not...&quot;, and the following blanks can be filled with anything. Originally, teaching also fell into this category. But she unexpectedly accepted a teaching position, taught poetry classes at Yale every fall, and served as a judge for the Yale Young Poets Prize. She was grateful for this and believed that it inspired her creative motivation. The rhythm and structure of one of the young poets gave her great inspiration. She also apologized to him specifically for this, fearing any suspicion of &quot;plagiarism&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is as strict with her students as she is with herself. The technique for preparing new poems is to completely forget the previous one. Each book is a resistance to the previous one. &quot;I have nothing to do with polishing milestones.&quot; Interest.&quot; Glick said in the interview, &quot;What I am thinking about is how to make the poems live longer. In these ever-expanding poems, he needs to reach different destinations from different starting points.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Typical Glick, with a language style that is &quot;alloy-like&quot;, always with coldness and restraint. However, different from the gloomy image on paper, she would imitate horse braying when reading poetry and also liked to laugh loudly. Humor itself has become a weapon for her style renewal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick said she always tries to &quot;let more voices fall onto the page&quot; in order to shift gears at any time. She likes poems like this: you think you are reading one poem, but you are actually reading another, and then a third. &quot;Each sentence itself is not derived from the previous sentence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of musical The polyphony has already appeared in &quot;Meadow&quot;, and Mozart&#39;s opera has become the aria in the poem. Poet Nicholas Kristof commented on the collection of poems &quot;Averno&quot; and said that the 18 poems are rich and harmonious, &quot;with complex interrelated images, recurring characters, overlapping themes, forming a unified collection, but among them Every part counts as a whole.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And all her collections of works are not a unified collection? When the translator Liu Xiangyang contacted Glick in 2007 to discuss the publication of the Chinese version of &quot;Selected Poems&quot;, Glick was reluctant at first and hoped to publish it in full. In the United States, &quot;Poetry 1962-2012&quot;, which was published in 2012, was not titled &quot;Complete Works&quot;. It did not make any modifications except for proofreading, and there was no personal introduction. &quot;Poetry is the only thing she left to the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the collection of poems &quot;Village Life&quot; ten years ago, the 66-year-old Glick seemed to declare some kind of impossible truce: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Body, thinking that we won&#39;t be together for much longer, I/begin to feel that I have a new kind of tenderness for you, which is very raw and unfamiliar, / Just like the love of my youth that I can remember.&quot; (&quot;Crossroads&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is still writing, and she is not writing slowly. The 2014 collection of poems, &quot;A Night of Faithfulness and Virtue,&quot; continues to approach the theme of death with extraordinary grace and lightness. The latest collection of poems is also expected to be published in the United States next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, &quot;hunger&quot; was always present. This is Sisyphean drudgery, &quot;The artist lies because he is haunted by arrival, he feels that the pinnacle is where he will dwell forever, a place where his burdens are transposed: Every moment of my life, I stand At the top of this mountain. My hands are empty. And that stone has increased the height of the mountain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s very different now - there&#39;s no rush at all.&quot; Glick in recent years In the interview, she admitted that she could sit on the terrace and write trivia while thinking, &quot;This is the most beautiful thing in life, the sweetest thing.&quot; Just change the sentence and think, oh, this is okay. That sense of joy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It was a beautiful summer, everything was growing in the garden, and there were no obligations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Reference: Louise Glück, &quot;Alloy of Moonlight&quot; and &quot;Until the World Reflects the Deepest Needs of the Soul&quot; (translated by Liu Xiangyang and Fan Jinghua); Louise Glück, &quot;American Originality&quot; &quot;; Daniel Morris, &quot;The Poetry of Louise Glück: A Thematic Introduction&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>