<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[金融合规榜：万余条罚单中，哪家银保机构在坚守底线？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:24:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the financial industry with strict supervision and strong supervision, compliance Rules are the bottom line that must be adhered to. As the world&#39;s largest banking market and the second largest insurance market, China&#39;s banking and insurance industries have always been the focus of supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Today, financial institutions’ compliance will be elevated to a new level. The Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that &quot;financial chaos and corruption problems continue to occur, and financial supervision and governance capabilities are weak&quot; and emphasized that &quot;financial supervision must be comprehensively strengthened to effectively prevent and resolve financial risks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Compliance has thus become a core consideration for the soundness of financial institutions’ operations. Which financial institution often commits crimes? Which financial institution frequently charges sky-high fines? Which financial institution has the most business lines involved? This is not only the key regulatory orientation of regulatory agencies, but also a concern of every financial consumer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to monitor the compliance of various financial institutions in real time, the relevant departments of Southern Weekend worked together for nearly a year to build the &quot;Shepherd-China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud&quot; Platform” (hereinafter referred to as the “Sheepdog Platform”). After continuous iterative upgrades and improvements, the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; now collects in real time the administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and their national offices, and simultaneously performs manual correction. test. In order to ensure the accuracy of the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; data, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared the recorded data with the information released by the three institutions one by one. The comparison results show that the accuracy of the penalty information data collected by the Shepherd Platform is as high as 100%, with no omissions or errors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively present the compliance of 20 systemically important banks and nine major life insurance companies in 2023, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; &quot;More than 10,000 pieces of data collected were mined and analyzed to construct the 2023 China New Financial Compliance List. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Penalty information from three regulatory agencies, two dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; in real time Includes administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, and their national offices. Therefore, this data information basically covers all regulatory penalties for the banking and insurance industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also conducts statistical analysis on the number of fines and the amount of fines received by financial institutions, because the number of fines and the amount of fines respectively reflect the extent of violations. How many and whether the violation is serious or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to statistics, from January to October 2023, 20 Chinese systemically important banks and their branches received a total of 802 fines, with an average of 802 fines per bank. and its branches received 40 fines; the above-mentioned fines totaled nearly 1.127 billion yuan in fines, and each bank and its branches were fined nearly 56.3548 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Nine major life insurance companies and their branches received 287 fines, with an average of 31 fines per life insurance company and its branches; the total of the above fines The fine was nearly 52 million yuan, and each life insurance company and its branches were fined nearly 5.73 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From a mean perspective, banks have higher values ​​than life insurance companies in terms of both the number of fines and the amount of fines. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that this is related to the bank&#39;s large scale and business volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center collected 10,467 pieces of penalty information (including institutions) issued by the three major regulatory agencies from January to October 2023 on the Shepherd Platform Penalty information and personal penalty information) conduct data mining analysis and construct a new financial compliance list for 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Which bank was fined the largest amount? Which company has been punished the most? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank compliance list shows that China Construction Bank, Minsheng Bank and Shanghai Bank took the top three spots. Among them, China Construction Bank and China Minsheng Bank were fined more than 200 million yuan each, far exceeding the 98.544 million yuan imposed by Bank of Shanghai. The list of the number of penalties imposed on the bank compliance list shows that the five major state-owned banks of Industry, Agriculture, Postal Service, Construction, and China are among the top five in the list, and the number of institutional penalty information is more than 70, far exceeding the sixth place Minsheng Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness Ranking - Bank Compliance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banks in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, from January to October 2023, the number of institutional fines received by each bank is basically the same. They are arranged in order of state-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks. There is no obvious pattern in the amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For state-owned banks, during the time period included in this list, compared with the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, and Postal Service Bank, Bank of Communications The degree of compliance is relatively good. In terms of the amount of fines, Bank of Communications ranked twelfth, while the other five state-owned banks were all ranked in the top ten. At the same time, the number of fines received by Bank of Communications is also relatively small, and it is the only bank that is not in the echelon of state-owned banks in terms of the number of fines. The bank received 41 pieces of penalty information during the time period of this statistics. The number of penalty messages is only higher than that of China Minsheng Bank, a joint-stock bank in the echelon, with 42 messages. China Construction Bank became the bank with the largest amount of fines at this stage due to a fine of nearly 200 million yuan issued by the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission (now the State Administration of Financial Supervision) on February 16, 2023. In addition, the amount of each fine of ICBC, which ranked first in the number of fines, did not exceed 6 million yuan. Therefore, its total amount of fines ranks low among state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The compliance status of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks is relatively similar. During the statistical time period of this list, one bank from each of the above two categories ranked in the top three in the list of fines imposed, and the reason was that they received large fines exceeding 60 million yuan. Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu are the two banks with the best compliance during the statistical period of this list. The fines imposed on the above two banks did not exceed 10 million yuan, which were 600,000 yuan and 8.601 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that because the four major banks have large business scale and many branches, a high number of penalties does not necessarily mean that their compliance is lower than that of other banks. bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Loans are still the hardest hit area for violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Analyzing the types of violations, the statistical time of this list During this period, the violations of the 20 systemically important banks were concentrated in three areas: loans, external guarantees and customer identification. Among them, the loan business is the hardest hit area for bank violations. The above-mentioned fine of nearly 200 million yuan from China Construction Bank involves a total of 38 violations of laws and regulations, 15 of which are related to violations of loan business. Among the top ten in terms of the amount of fines received, except for Shanghai Bank, which only had one fine for &quot;violating the handling of domestic guarantees and overseas loans&quot; and seven other fines involving illegal handling of foreign exchange business, the fines received by the remaining nine banks all related to loans. Business violations. In fact, according to penalty information over the years, loan business violations have always been an &quot;old disease&quot; in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Illegal handling of domestic guarantees for overseas loans and illegal external guarantees are the largest fines imposed on banks by the State Administration of Foreign Exchange during this statistical period. Bank of Shanghai and China CITIC Bank were fined 98.544 million yuan and 11.7544 million yuan respectively for the above-mentioned issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, customer identification issues were the third highest fine imposed on banks by regulatory agencies during this statistical period. Among them, the highest fines received by Ping An Bank and Postal Savings Bank during this statistical period both involved &quot;failure to perform customer identification obligations as required&quot;, and the fines for these two tickets were 53.4117 million yuan and 31.86 million yuan respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above analysis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that banks need to focus on the compliance of loan business, guarantee business and payment and settlement business. How to eradicate old diseases and ensure the compliance of loan business is an issue that major commercial banks need to think about urgently. Today, some banks have applied artificial intelligence technology to assist manual loan review and other processes. Therefore, improving the accuracy of artificial intelligence technology in assisting in reviewing loan information may be one of the feasible solutions to rectify the &quot;old disease&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance companies urgently need to strengthen the implementation of internal control systems&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance compliance list shows that regardless of Ping An Life ranks first in terms of both the amount of fines and the number of fines it has received. Taikang Life ranked third and second respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The second place in the list of the amount of fines and the third place in the list of the number of fines are Taiping Life and China Life respectively. It is worth noting that AIA Life Insurance Co., Ltd. performed better in this compliance list. During this statistical period, AIA Life was the only financial institution among all participants in the list that did not receive any fines from the three major financial regulatory agencies and their dispatched agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness List - Life Insurance Compliance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the perspective of the types of violations, life insurance companies’ violations are mainly fraud, deception and inducement of policyholders and system management issues . According to the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, from January to October 2023, there were 453 pieces of information about penalties for life insurance companies. Among them, 187 involve fraud, 105 involve deceiving or inducing policyholders, and 130 involve internal control systems and management issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, most of the fines involving &quot;inadequate implementation of internal control systems&quot; involve &quot;preparing false information&quot; and &quot;inciting and inducing insurance agents to engage in acts that violate integrity&quot; voluntary activities”. &quot;Instigating and inducing insurance agents to engage in activities that violate their fiduciary obligations&quot; is the root cause of &quot;deceiving or inducing policyholders&quot;. This may be related to the business value concept of the company and its branches. If the design of the company&#39;s assessment indicators is unreasonable or the implementation is deformed, or the managers of relevant departments behave inappropriately, it will be difficult for their subordinates, especially grassroots personnel, to ensure business compliance when conducting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, the compliance issues of life insurance companies this year can basically be attributed to the unscientific design of the indicator system and the inability to implement the internal control system. The Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recommends that leaders of life insurance companies should adhere to the strategic focus of high-quality development and should not ignore compliance for temporary performance impulses, let alone engage in fraud that affects the image of the company or even the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿险效能提升榜：谁现在领先？谁拥有未来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2023, China’s life insurance industry will continue to undergo difficult transformation. In a complex and ever-changing market: Life insurance was a hot seller in the first half of the year due to high interest rates, but the twists and turns in the equity market made life insurance investments suffer. &quot;Integrating newspaper and bank into one&quot; (see Southern Weekend App for details) Perennially deformed? &quot;>;&quot;Big accounts are high and small accounts are constantly rising. Why is the bancassurance business deformed all year round?&quot;&lt;/a>;) The new regulations have made the bancassurance channel under pressure even more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, life insurance companies are still determined to continue transformation, pursuing efficiency improvements, and are more committed to the blue ocean market of pension insurance and insurance +, and are competing for more considerate customer service upgrades . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Who is leading the race to transformation? Who sticks more to the &quot;customer-centric&quot; strategy? Which company is more transparent and open to the media and the public? Which company pays more attention to compliance? Which company pays more attention to innovation? Based on the principles of objectivity, fairness and science, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed an evaluation index system for life insurance performance improvement rankings and evaluated the performance of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight major dimensions&amp;nbsp;Fourteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Life Insurance Performance Improvement List&quot; Quantitative The qualitative evaluation index system consists of six first-level indicators and fourteen second-level indicators. Among them, the first-level indicators include three quantitative dimensional indicators of &quot;operational capabilities, customer service, and regulatory compliance&quot; and three qualitative dimensional indicators of &quot;business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecology, and product innovation.&quot; The secondary indicators are refined into fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of the quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on the special research on the above-mentioned life insurance companies, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the participating life insurance companies. The company conducts independent real-name scoring. Both scores have a weight of 15%. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the life insurance company under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2087&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a.png&quot; data-key= &quot;260503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now The specific description of quantitative and qualitative indicators is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(1) Business capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How to judge the management ability of a life insurance company? From the perspective of business model, the business logic of life insurance companies is to collect premiums to form insurance liabilities, use insurance liabilities to invest to form investment assets, and the investment assets generate investment income. Therefore, to evaluate the operating capabilities of a life insurance company, one is to look at its ability to obtain premiums; the other is to look at its investment asset management capabilities. Original premium income is commonly used in the industry to measure the liability capacity of life insurance companies, but the premium income of nine life insurance companies accounts for about 3/4 of the life insurance industry. The life insurance performance list aims to select the best among the best, so the new indicator insurance service income is included in the statistics&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is insurance service income? According to the explanation in China Ping An’s semi-annual report, insurance service income refers to recognition during the insurance period based on the provision of services, and excludes investment components. Insurance service income reflects the income obtained from engaging in insurance business. In accordance with the provisions of the &quot;Accounting Standards for Business Enterprises No. 25 - Insurance Contracts&quot; (Finance [2020] No. 20) revised and issued on December 24, 2020, listed insurance companies will implement it from January 1, 2023. This regulation is also called the &quot;Chinese version of IFRS 17&quot;. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found in its survey that, except for China Life and Taikang Life, seven other life insurance companies have applied the new insurance contract standard IFRS17. Under the new accounting standards, insurance business income is replaced by insurance service income, which also leads to a significant reduction in the recognition of premium income of life insurance companies. Life insurance companies with a large proportion of investment savings products and a high proportion of single premiums will be more obviously affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, new business value and embedded value measure the insurance company&#39;s value, profitability and sustainable development, and the total investment return rate measures investment performance. These three indicators are commonly used indicators in the industry. In summary, the total weight of the four secondary indicators in this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(2) Customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The insurance industry is a typical service-intensive industry. How to implement the &quot;customer-centered&quot; development concept, meet the diverse needs of customers, and improve the service quality of the insurance industry are key issues for my country&#39;s insurance industry to achieve high-quality development. From the demand side, the age composition and demand of insurance customer groups have changed significantly, and young customers have increasingly higher requirements for insurance services. From the supply side, my country&#39;s insurance products are highly homogeneous, with little difference in product pricing and basically similar scopes of liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the life insurance industry cannot sell insurance as a &quot;fast-moving consumer goods&quot;. Otherwise, large-scale surrenders may occur, and the service attributes of &quot;slow experience&quot; and &quot;slow decision-making&quot; of insurance should be returned. Risk protection is the core function of the insurance industry. To implement &quot;customer-centric&quot;, on the one hand, insurance must be renamed insurance and return to the protection function; on the other hand, insurance must be made &quot;value for money&quot; insurance. In other words, we need to make it affordable, worthwhile, convenient and reassuring for consumers. Based on this, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has set up three secondary indicators to measure claims settlement amount, average claim settlement timeliness and surrender rate in the customer service dimension. The total weight of the three indicators in this dimension is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(3) Compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, &quot;standardization&quot; has become the key word for the development of the insurance industry. At present, institutional supervision, behavioral supervision, functional supervision, penetrating supervision and continuous supervision have gradually formed. In 2021, the focus of supervision will be on the top-level design of the reform. In the fields of corporate governance, solvency, and insurance capital utilization, the &quot;Corporate Governance Guidelines for Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot;, &quot;Insurance Company Solvency Supervision Rules (II)&quot; and &quot;On Modifying the Parts in the Areas of Insurance Capital Utilization&quot; were released Notice of Normative Documents&quot;. In 2022, regulatory agencies will deepen supervision of consumer rights and interests and issue the &quot;Management Measures for the Protection of Consumer Rights and Interests of Banking and Insurance Institutions.&quot; This is a basic and programmatic document in the field of consumer rights protection in the banking and insurance industries. In 2023, supervision will shift to the regulation of bancassurance and individual insurance channels, and the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products in Bank Agency Channels&quot; and &quot;Measures for the Management of Insurance Sales Behavior&quot; will be issued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sets four sub-indicators in the compliance dimension, among which core solvency adequacy ratio and comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio are key regulatory indicators; insurance The service quality index refers to the 2022 insurance service quality index released by China Banking and Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Banking and Insurance&quot;); the data on the number of administrative penalties comes from &quot;Sheepdog&quot; - China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud Platform Regulatory data collected by the system from January to September. The total weight of the four sub-indicators of this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(4) Business cross-penetration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension reflects the synergy and cross-selling capabilities of life insurance companies between different business lines. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the growth logic of life insurance institutions has shifted from &quot;scale&quot; to &quot;quality.&quot; The “insurance + service” development strategy has become an industry consensus. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(5) Healthy ecological construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The development of pension finance is inseparable from the construction of a comprehensive health ecosystem, because &quot;the elderly are provided for and the sick are treated&quot; are inseparable. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the development of life insurance companies in the field of big health business based on the annual reports or other public information of each life insurance company. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(6) Product innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension mainly reflects the product development and innovation capabilities of life insurance companies. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life leads the way&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above dimensions and indicator system, and integrating the 2023 results of various life insurance companies Mid-year reports and announcements, as well as data from third-party rating agencies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated 9 insurance companies and obtained a total score of quantitative and qualitative indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on media factor weights and external expert review weights, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed a life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked the top three. Among them, China Life and Ping An Life have a clear lead and are the only two life insurance companies on the list with a total score of more than 60 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/1da3a7600f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1188&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1da3a7600f.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify ;&quot;>;Sub-indicator system observation shows that in the quantitative and qualitative indicator scores, China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked in the top three, and there was a wide gap between the scores of the other six life insurance institutions. There is a nearly ten-point difference in scores between AIA Life in third place and Taiping Life Insurance in fourth place. This shows that the first-tier life insurance companies have a larger lead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the scores of the expert jury, the expert judges favored Ping An Life Insurance. The company was the only life insurance company to receive a score of 9. In the media factor, AIA Life, PICC Life and China Pacific Insurance failed to respond within the limited time for some reason and did not score, which in turn affected the overall score to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed from different dimensions, China Life, Ping An Life and PICC Life ranked the top three. China Life&#39;s 2023 interim report did not apply the new insurance contract standards, but replaced insurance service income with insurance business income, so there is an overestimation to a certain extent. However, China Life’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that its insurance service revenue reached 136.439 billion yuan, only slightly lower than Ping An Life’s 168.945 billion yuan. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center calculated and found that the adjustment did not affect China Life&#39;s ranking in the life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Why does China Life top the list? China Life has obvious advantages on the liability side. China Life&#39;s third quarterly report shows that in the first three quarters of 2023, the scale and growth rate of premium income, new policy premiums, and first-year regular premiums all hit new highs for the same period in the past three years. First-year regular premiums with ten years or more were RMB 44.639 billion, a year-on-year increase of 15.4%, accounting for 42.12% of first-year regular premiums; new business value continued to grow in the first three quarters of 2023, with a year-on-year increase of 14.0%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From an asset perspective, declining investment returns are a common problem in the industry. Against the backdrop of downward shifts in interest rates and fluctuations in the equity market, investment returns in the insurance industry have generally declined. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the life insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. Therefore, the overall score for this indicator is low, with PICC Life scoring the highest because it uses group data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life performs well in the customer service dimension. In terms of sub-indicators, China Life’s three indicators are all at the leading level in the industry. Data from the company&#39;s 2023 interim report show that the average claim settlement timeframe is 0.39 days, a year-on-year increase of 17%; &quot;claims prepayment&quot; exceeded 74 million yuan; &quot;claims direct payment&quot; exceeded 3.41 million; &quot;one-day critical illness compensation&quot; compensation amount exceeded 5.4 billion yuan, an increase of 50% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, China Life does not fall behind in terms of regulatory compliance. In terms of sub-indicators, the company&#39;s core solvency adequacy ratio reached 140%, and its comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio reached 204%, both well above regulatory requirements and at the average level among the nine life insurance companies. In the 2022 Insurance Service Quality Index released by China Banking and Information Technology, China Life received a high score of 94.61, which is higher than the average level of 85.28 in the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, according to data from &quot;Sheepdog&quot;, a compliance cloud platform for China&#39;s financial industry, China Life was fined 47 times (including branches) in the first three quarters, a high On average 29 times. Because China Life has a large business volume and many branches, this indicator does not mean that the company&#39;s compliance is lower than that of other peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Develop pension finance and cultivate new growth poles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the midst of high-quality transformation of life insurance companies Nowadays, as the core component of the third pension pillar, pension insurance is becoming a strategic insurance type. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that pension finance has huge potential. The three-dimensional indicators of business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecological construction and product innovation reflect the development of pension finance of life insurance companies to a certain extent. However, the disclosure standards of various life insurance companies are not uniform because they are in the exploratory period. Therefore, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducts evaluations based on the annual reports of each life insurance company and with reference to various information such as announcements and publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that although Ping An Life ranks second in the total score of the list, it scores first in the three qualitative indicators. China Life Second, AIA Life, Taiping Life and Sunshine Life tied for third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also found in its survey that nine life insurance companies are actively participating in the construction of pension finance. Among them, China People&#39;s Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., China Life Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., and Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd. are the first batch of pension insurance companies designated by the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau to participate in the commercial pension pilot. The pilot is about to be completed for one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Other life insurance companies are also actively exploring pension finance business. For example, Ping An Life relies on the resources of Ping An Group of China to continue to make efforts in the direction of &quot;insurance + services&quot;. In terms of &quot;insurance + health&quot;, Ping An Life launched the &quot;Ping An Zhenxiang RUN&quot; health service plan. In the first three quarters of 2023, Ping An Life has served more than 19 million customers, a year-on-year increase of more than 10%; in the &quot;insurance + high-quality health care community&quot; In terms of &quot;Ping An Life Insurance&quot;, Ping An Life has teamed up with other professional companies within the group to build a high-quality health care brand &quot;Zhen Yi Nian&quot;. In October 2023, Ping An Zhenyi Nian officially released Wellness Care 3.0, launching two new benefits: residence and CCaH (Continuing Care at Home). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of &quot;insurance + home care&quot;, Ping An Life continues to explore home care services. As of the end of September 2023, Ping An&#39;s home care services have covered 54 cities across the country, with a total of more than 70,000 people qualified for home care services, and more than 50% of policyholders in 54 cities have activated their home service rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Taikang Life has formed a collaboration with 20 &quot;Taikang Homes&quot; across the country and has become an industry benchmark. Sunshine Life will start with the Sunshine Family (Guangzhou) health care community and gradually deploy a chain of CCRC senior care communities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the integration of medical and nursing care is a general trend, and &quot;insurance + services&quot; is becoming a new blue ocean. All life insurance companies should continue to innovate in products and services. On the one hand, they should enrich product connotations and expand the coverage of insurance products; on the other hand, they should extend the value chain of insurance services and provide comprehensive services such as health management, medical services, and long-term care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欠发达县1个在编身后1.8个临聘：转移支付保“吃饭财政”难以为继]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot;, the reporter was in a county in Wumeng Mountain District During the investigation, it was found that the county’s total wage guarantee budget expenditure for the year was 2.63 billion, including 2 billion for in-service personnel, 170 million for retired personnel, and 460 million for temporary personnel. The number of temporary employees is 1.8 times that of in-service employees, but the total salary budget of the former is less than a quarter of the latter. In addition, the county&#39;s total salary expenditures for temporary employees have exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue. In several neighboring districts and counties of the county, the average number of temporary employees is 1.7 times that of in-service employees. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Specifically, the per capita annual income of temporary employees in the county is about 16,100 yuan, and the total number of employees is 28,806; the per capita annual income of current employees is about 12.83 million, and the total number of personnel is 15,580. The per capita annual income of current employees is eight times that of temporary employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How do you view this phenomenon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First of all, the county has been completely reduced to &quot;food finance&quot;. The total annual salary budget for temporary staff is 460 million, which has exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue, which means that the county&#39;s economic strength and endogenous fiscal capacity are very weak. Against the background that the sluggish housing market has stalled land finance, especially in small localities, the total annual budget expenditure of 2.63 billion on guaranteed wages will most likely come from transfer payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for the economically developed areas that currently provide sources of transfer payments, their finances are not sufficient or even very difficult. It is impossible to maintain the &quot;food finance&quot; for a long time by relying on transfer payments. , the county may have to slim down: reductions in personnel, staff, budgets, and expenditures are inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, the so-called on-the-job personnel are formal workers with a formal establishment; the so-called temporary personnel are temporary workers and contract workers without a permanent establishment. If we have to reduce headcount, which category of people will be eliminated first? From the perspective of effectiveness and efficiency, how should redundant staff be eliminated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The answer to the first question is obvious. In the case of financial difficulties, unemployed personnel will be laid off first. This is also a common practice everywhere. It’s called “clearing out temporary workers.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason is very simple: the principle of minimum action. In theory, there is no iron rice bowl anymore. The current &quot;Civil Service Assessment Regulations (Trial)&quot; has annual assessments, and the results are divided into four grades: excellent, competent, basically competent and incompetent. &quot;The annual assessment for two consecutive years is determined to be Those who are found to be incompetent will be dismissed.&quot; But in fact, unless a major principled error is made, it is very difficult to lay off an employee with a civil servant or a public institution, and few leaders are willing to be evil and &quot;smash people&#39;s jobs&quot; and are worried about being sacked. The job holder or his family may cause trouble, be unsightly, and have a &quot;bad influence.&quot; But it&#39;s different for temporary workers without official establishment. They are mentally prepared to be laid off due to the company running out of money or the superior&#39;s request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, should temporary workers be eliminated (first)? Before answering this question, you must understand why the company recruits temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Temporary workers are different from temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​is that there is a relationship, but the relationship is not strong enough and it is not enough to get the establishment in one step. First, recruit people to make a temporary transition and wait for the internal opportunity to become a regular employee. Banyuetan reporter&#39;s investigation found that the recruitment and management of most temporary personnel are not handled by a unified department and are basically carried out according to the principle of &quot;who employs people, who recruits them&quot; without approval or approval from the establishment department, finance department, organization department, human resources and social security department. The registration and recruitment procedures are relatively haphazard, with the phenomenon of disorderly growth in quantity and unguaranteed quality, and it is difficult to eliminate recruitment based on personal relationships and relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The other type is irrelevant or almost irrelevant. They are recruited to do the dirty and tiring work that regular workers are unwilling to do. , hard work and troublesome work, you may be pushed out to take the blame if something goes wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also many internal contradictions in such units: on the one hand, formal workers get more money, good benefits, but work less, and there are various ways to obtain honors and Opportunities for promotion; on the other hand, temporary workers who work receive less money, poor benefits, and more work. If something goes wrong, they will be pushed out to take the blame. With such a close contrast, the latter&#39;s psychology will be very unbalanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, if we look at the logic of the market, temporary workers are paid market prices; for the same position, regular workers are paid more than temporary workers. Part of it is the premium brought by the preparation. When multiple people compete for an organization, they compete for the premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public people think that when &quot;retiring temporary workers&quot;, the first type of eviction is to let those who do not work leave to improve efficiency, but in fact The second type is often eliminated, which is to let the temporary workers leave. It doesn&#39;t matter and they are hardworking, so there is the least resistance to the elimination. However, after they are dismissed, the regular workers often complain because someone has to do the work. After laying off these many people, work can still be done. In this sense, efficiency has been improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, government functions should be viewed from the perspectives of government and market/society. Government management should also be quantified: a county&#39;s tax revenue of less than 500 million yuan a year, with a total salary budget of 2.63 billion yuan, and a fiscal meal has been eaten by the county. It really needs so many people, spend so much money, and care so much? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It should be sorted out: which management and service functions are absolutely necessary and can only be performed by the government, how much budget and personnel are appropriate; which can be delayed and allowed Socially managed itself; which belongs to excessive control and improper control instead of stifling the economic vitality; even, if the net flow of a county is too large, the population and the economy are constantly shrinking. There have been practice in many places in the township, which has reduced the government scale and released market vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition, because the civil servants have become the actual iron rice bowl, the premium brings by the preparation is very high, so everyone will have such a large and compilation of the examination and compilation of the examination public examinations. enthusiasm. If the annual assessment of civil servants and public institutions can be implemented, and dare to dismiss the old fried dough sticks that do not work like a market -oriented enterprise, so that the premiums brought by the preparation will be zero. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In order to compress and eliminate the premium brought by the preparation, there is another way: market salary is market-oriented, depending on the temporary working salary from the market, Then the formal work&#39;s salary should be aligned as much as possible to squeeze the premium premium. A cleaners are prepared in a certain place, and the cleaner employees who have edited to do their own work, and then enjoy the difference. This difference is the premium brought by the preparation. The government or taxpayer became a big head and spent more money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:25:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：目前流行的急性呼吸道疾病均由已知病原体引起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261726]]><description> &lt;DIV>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 15:16:28 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; The National Health and Health Commission will hold a press conference today to introduce the situation of the prevention and control of winter respiratory diseases. Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, said that at present, the National Health Commission, together with the State Administration of Traditional Chinese Medicine and the State Administration of Disease Control and Prevention, continue to carry out winter respiratory disease monitoring and research and judgment, and are doing a good job in allocating medical resources, optimizing the medical treatment process, and playing a central role. Medical functions and other work are deployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to monitoring, the current popular acute respiratory diseases are caused by known diseases, and there are corresponding mature treatment methods. No new virus or bacterial new hair infectious diseases are found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To further increase the supply of medical services, promote the pediatric clinics of various medical institutions such as traditional Chinese medicine hospitals, maternal and child health hospitals, etc., &quot;should be opened&quot; according to the number of patients. Service time, expand the hospital bed, and continuously optimize the process of registering, inspection, payment, etc. to facilitate the masses to seek medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is necessary to do a good job of hierarchical diagnosis and treatment, unblocked referral channels, cross -section and inter -hospital adjustment personnel, ensure the supply of medical supplies, promote Internet medical care, and maximize the ability to take care of the diagnosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is necessary to give full play to the role of traditional Chinese medicine, combine traditional Chinese and western medicine, and target common diseases in the winter respiratory tract, popularize the knowledge of traditional Chinese medicine prevention and treatment of diseases, and improve the effect of prevention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To do a good job of supply and vaccination services such as influenza, the elderly, children and other key groups are vaccinated as soon as possible to reduce the risk of disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Persist in masks, wash hands, and often ventilate, which is very effective for preventing the spread of respiratory diseases. It is necessary to take good personal protection, go to work without illness, go to school without illness, and adhere to good personal hygiene habits and a healthy lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪后长城，巨龙伏纱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261720]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 15:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[订阅号的爱情陷阱：老年人深陷“互联网弟弟”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261694]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 12:35:21 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;The 51st&quot; China Internet Network Development Status Statistics Statistical Statistics Report released &quot;It shows that as of December 2022, groups 60 and above accounted for 14.3%of the total number of netizens, and the size of elderly netizens reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly netizens lacks attention. (Visual China Picture)&quot; SRC = &quot;HTTP: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d215d9ba31.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 721 &quot;data-src =&quot;/iMages.infzm. COM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/12/01/D215d9ba31.jpg &quot;Data-key =&quot; 260410 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; China Interconnection The 51st &quot;China Internet Development Statistics Statistical Report&quot; released by the Network Information Center shows that as of December 2022, groups 60 and above accounted for 14.3%of the total netizens, and the size of elderly netizens reached 153 million. The emotional world of over 100 million elderly netizens lacks attention. (Visual China Map) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At three in the morning, Rui Di was insomnia again. He sent a greeting to the sister of the Internet, just like the &quot;good morning&quot; and &quot;good night&quot; that was repeated almost every day. comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rui Di said that his encounter with his sister was a hit arrangement. He reminded his sister to take care of his body and take care of his body. After each day with his sister, he complained about each other, and his thoughts were &quot;a ray of sunlight&quot;, &quot;the moonlight in front of the window will always accompany her.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The video from Rui Di showed that he was a man with a 30s and forty years old, a gentle voice, and his back exactly like Jin Dong. Recently, his parents suddenly became ill. In order to win the bonus, he decided to participate in the singing competition. On the night before the competition, he talked about his difficulties: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; You can be shortlisted when you meet the requirements ... If you support your younger brother, can you help your brother to improve a popular data? ... Sister, you help your brother like the author to appreciate it, and you can help your brother in 188 or 256. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p >; At the end of 2020, the phenomenon of &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; surfaced, and a large number of false accounts disguised as actor Jin Dong, using short videos and live broadcast methods to collect wealth to middle -aged and elderly fans. Two years later, the &quot;fake Jindong&quot; incident continued. In September 2023, tens of millions of fan Internet celebrities who specialized in the elderly were reported on tax evasion and fraudulent fans, and their accounts were banned. In October 2023, the Shanghai Jing&#39;an District Procuratorate filed a public prosecution on the eight fake Jin Dong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Today, the &quot;fake Jin Dong&quot; position has shifted from short video to the public account. These accounts that claim to be &quot;Dongdi&quot; and &quot;Rui Di&quot; first use the video number to drain to induce fans to pay attention to the subscription number, and then continue to make stories in the public account and win the sympathy of fans to reward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A new round of emotional harvesting, the means are more private. After adding a fan WeChat through a large -scale public account, the interaction is transferred to a private chat or a circle of friends. The emotions of over 100 million elderly people, let them fall into the trap, more than one show or Jin Dong? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;video ID = &quot;Contents-Video-0&quot; Data-FileId = &quot;327083501236170&quot; data-media = &quot;Video&quot; data-resource = &quot;TENCENT&quot; Data-FILENAME = &quot;Public&quot; &quot;Dongyin&quot; accompanied by &quot;The latest video released, telling that my younger brother encountered setbacks in the singing competition and asked for help. This is a common routine of such a public account ..mp4&quot; data-cover = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/12/02/2tqweem14d2kolec4n5miwe3fglywxjv5g77zm1b.jpg &quot;data- url =&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02F2B5C2VODCQ1251434550 7/63e6b5923270835012371236170/Ahsmlylmff0a.mp4 &quot;Poster =&quot; &quot;Controls =&quot; Controls &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;Height =&quot; 360 &quot;>; &lt;Source src =&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqCloud.com/02F2B5C2VODCQ1251434507/63E6B592371236170/Ahsmlylmfff 0A.MP4 &quot;Type =&quot; Video/MP4 &quot;>; &lt;/video>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4 >; I was in love &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Dong Xueru found the secret behind the subscription number under accident. At that time, the 71 -year -old 姥 had been trapped in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;My life is so busy every day, know? Do you know? Nothing to sleep, watch the video, and just pass it. Of course, how do you want to see you? You miss me, I too, I too I miss you. &quot;微 said in WeChat to a person who called&quot; I love my life &quot;in WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Xueru looked at the list of attention and found a large number of public accounts and video numbers with similar names- &quot;Brother Ruidong accompanied you&quot;, &quot;East brother accompanied his sister&quot;, &quot;Rui Di warm&quot;, &quot;Rui Rui&quot;, &quot;Rui Rui Always accompany you &quot;and so on. The title of the public account article is very long. For example, &quot;Sister, brother is really anxious. If you can&#39;t even catch this opportunity, your brother will be sad for a long time.&quot; The picture is usually a man&#39;s photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the public account interface of &quot;Ruidong&#39;s brother&quot;, he claimed that he would participate in the top 20 singing competitions, and Dong Xueru&#39;s uncle encouraged him to cheer. Then the public account sent a two -dimensional code, and attached a sentence: &quot;Brother will accompany his sister to stay with your sister.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Looking at these pushes, you will find that this Ruidong brother is really I am very busy: I will help the game promotional video for a while, and I have been promoted successfully for a while. I went to the TV for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This handsome and thoughtful fake brother occupies an important position in some people&#39;s lives. From the message, you can see the fans&#39; hot heart. They are &quot;Lotus&quot;, &quot;Caiying&quot;, &quot;Ping An and Happiness&quot; or &quot;Tomorrow will be better&quot;. They said, &quot;Sister knows, my sister knows you in my life, my sister is the happiest&quot;, &quot;Thank you for caring me&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In their minds, this younger brother who speaks to them can be anyone. Dong Xueru discovered that he regarded the other party as his secret love object in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I am from Sichuan. Living in Beijing, there are very few friends. For more than ten years, a man often organized two or three hundred people to dance with two or three hundred people near her residence. The iron teacher often wore a flower coat with English letters, dyed in blonde, and would turn a little makeup, becoming an idol of middle -aged and elderly people, calling them &quot;sister&quot;. Later, I moved, I couldn&#39;t go to dance in the square, and changed to participate in the online dance class, and I could only watch videos in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He firmly believes that the news was sent by Teacher Iron, because the iron teacher, who was eight years younger than her, would be called her sister and brother. &quot;These (public accounts) different names are the pseudonym of Teacher Iron, all of which are his net name ... All these articles are written for her.&quot; Dong Xueru told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I want to send a lot of information every day. On one occasion, my brother sent a message saying that he had come to his sister&#39;s city and saw a back of a sister, and found that it was not disappointed. I comforted, &quot;Fool, what are you disappointed, I miss you too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Xueru and his family have persuaded him many times, and he was annoyed. They took the uncle to the local public security bureau and received network security education, but they couldn&#39;t listen to it, but asked the police whether they could find people online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Xueru&#39;s mother and uncle had to ask Teacher Tie himself to clarify. Teacher Tie denied that it was herself, and it was clear that she would not like her without time to fall in love. The family put the recording to the uncle, but the uncle determined that the children were obstructing her and forcing the iron teacher to be too tight. &quot;He is immature and he is also naive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After speaking on the Internet, Dong Xueru&#39;s post received nearly 4,000 replys. Many netizens have said that their families have encountered similar situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A girl sent a private message to Dong Xueru, saying that her uncle was also obsessed with such public accounts and corporate WeChat. In addition to rewarding, she would also buy high -priced goods sold by the other party. After the mother discovered, she deleted these accounts in anger. Soon, she re -added again, accusing her daughter from obstructing her pursuit of happiness. Mother and daughter relationship is deadlocked. The girl said to Dong Xueru, I really don&#39;t know what to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;A large number of younger brother accounts use subscription numbers, enterprises and personal WeChat and friends circle to communicate with the elderly to induce rewards. src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;663&quot; data-src = &quot;/// /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/6c68bb17d4.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 260411 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style: #9999999; text-align: center &quot;>; A large number of younger brother accounts use subscription numbers, enterprises and personal WeChat, and friends circle to conduct false emotional exchanges with the elderly to induce rewards. (Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui screenshot) &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; After the fake younger brothers come back, &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After Dong Xueru&#39;s posts have attracted attention, the platform has banned some younger brother accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Speaking of these Dongdi and Rui Di, Ma Kai fired. Ma Kai operated a group of emotional public accounts, and was recently implicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ma Kai&#39;s public account is similar to emotional radio, the largest number is 34 million followers, and a six -seven -minute emotional chicken soup is released every day. &quot;If you feel tired, what should you do and wait for this. If you are emotional, &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ma Kai emphasized the southern weekend that his account number is different from the fraud. Dong Di Rui&#39;s account account, &quot;I won&#39;t tell you any emotional quotes, and I won&#39;t send you any songs, so I will directly kill the pig plate&quot;; and my &quot;brother&quot;, rely on emotional copywriting to seek rewards, Do not create false identity, make up false stories or deceive feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He paid attention to these younger brothers&#39; public accounts very early. They were unified and roughly divided into two categories: one is that the younger brother participated in the concert and needed popularity. Medical expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the video number to the public account to the start of the harvest, the operator leaves the link of the public account in the video number comment area, and places the payment code in the public account article, or leaves the corporate WeChat or private personnel. WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most of the registered subjects of these public accounts are enterprises. Southern Weekend reporters found that a large number of registered companies with similar accounts are several department stores located in Haikou, named &quot;Xiucai Singing Department Store&quot; and &quot;Rui Rui Department Store&quot;. According to industrial and commercial information, many department store operators are different, but they use the same mobile phone number when registering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Southern Weekend reporters contact one of the operators Y. There are four Hainan Department Stores under the Y name, which are specially used to register for the public account of the younger brother. WeChat stipulates that an individual industrial and commercial households can register two public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Y told the southern weekend reporter that his team has a total of three people in total and registered a total of 12 individual industrial and commercial households. It has been engaged in this industry for the past year. Diversion and accumulation through the video number. He refused to disclose his income, only saying &quot;not earning much.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the e -commerce platform, only 100 yuan is required. Some merchants provide individual business license agency business, upload ID card information and mobile phone numbers, and remote real -name authentication. The store said that a person does not limit the number of registrations, does not need to pay for money after applying, and there is no need to worry about the inspection of the industrial and commercial department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Using false individual industrial and commercial households to register to increase the number of WeChat public accounts, it is no longer secret in the trip. These public accounts have become a weapon for batch information and batch operations. Y proves this, he is in Guangzhou, but the registered store is in Hainan. Ma Kai added that compared with the complex materials that general enterprises need to submit, individual industrial and commercial households only need to spend dozens of yuan per year for annual reports. The above -mentioned merchants also provide agency services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A small program called &quot;praise&quot; provides appreciation services for the younger brother account. Unlike the direct reward of WeChat, the third -party program is rewarded by jumping links, which can avoid the risk of being frozen by the user after being reported by the user. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are still a large number of sisters&#39; messages from the comment area of ​​this applet, &quot;Hello dear baby brother! Good at noon! Sister gives you like the author, brother, sister, sister, I miss it especially You, my sister has happened to the family in the past few days, so there are few messages to my brother. I hope my brother understands forgive sister. Sister really likes you and loves you, and it hurts you and you. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; On November 14, the &quot;praise&quot; announced that the platform could not know whether the user who received the appreciated users had fraud, and revealed that from October 9th to November 4th, 2023, A complaint user received a total of more than 250,000 yuan. &lt;/span>; The amount of deception may be amazing. In the early days, these numbers used WeChat to reward. The number of rewards was publicly visible. Ma Kai observed that a team of Ruidong Division Subscribe to Fujian. At the peak, at least 400 rewards are received every day. 10,000 yuan; the other subscription number from Hebei has about 7,000 or eight thousand daily reading. There are not many fans in the public account. According to his understanding, this type of account started from Fujian and has spread to Guangdong, Jiangxi, Chongqing and other places, which lasted about a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After these public accounts were banned by WeChat, they had to start looking for new means. Their corporate micro -signal is still playing. The public account link was originally sent to the &quot;Tencent Content Creation Platform&quot; link. In the content interface, the payment code can still be placed. Moreover, if users have added their company WeChat before, they will still receive push messages every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, Ma Kai has been reporting these companies WeChat, but the effect is not good. He turned out the historical record, &quot;What you see is only a superficial chat and reward. Is there any chat behind, do you have any transfers, can you imagine it?&quot; He believes that corporate WeChat is the true concentration of traffic. &quot;Enterprise WeChat is originally a marketing tool, you can add more people. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Y to the reporter of the Southern Weekend claimed that the two -thirds of the market are gone. He no longer does a similar account and intends to prepare for live broadcasts to bring goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/glkoxsp2ndafokixmqdviyfz8uzlqcsfo82.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;2078&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/glkoxsp2ndafokixmqdviyfz8uzlqcsfo82.jpg&quot; data- &quot;260438&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On December 1st, the public account&quot; East Sound Accompanied &quot;published a new article, continuing the false younger brothers and telling stories in the video to induce rewards. As of 10 o&#39;clock that night, 38 people had rewarded. The author of the article has previously released similar content, deleted, and account cancellation. Now it appears in the new public account. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui screenshot/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;She needs love, really not lonely&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Xiao Lin has operated an emotional public account for young people. Recently, there are often some strange messages in the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the changes in the WeChat public account push mechanism, the platform will recommend the content that they may be interested in to those who do Emotional tree hole. Most of their messages are scattered and unknown, so they seem to show their hearts to someone: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Do you know? I have forgive you for a long time, waiting for your sincerity to pick me up?&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &quot;You have gone from me for more than three years. It is normal for marriage to become a family, but I still have your shadow in my heart.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A Northeast woman has sent voice messages almost every day since September. At first, it was a long -sized scolding, and then the tone became gentle. She seemed to fall in love with a man and regarded the public account as each other. Sometimes, she speaks fast, with a crying cavity, and always &quot;dear baby&quot; at the beginning. The content is repeated: Why don&#39;t you come back? Why not return my information? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xiao Lin dare not reply, worried about breaking her talk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From her love, Dong Xueru realized her delicate side. He lost his first husband more than 20 years ago, and then experienced two failures. She followed her child to Beijing, and she had little time to learn. She started literacy through the Internet and liked to watch video numbers and public accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Xueru grew up with his sister -in -law, and he would not type when he was in love. When he said, Dong Xueru said: &quot;Dear husband, I miss you, I love you, when will you come back to see me and see me. &quot;Sometimes, I don&#39;t know how to express it in words. Dong Xueru helped her write some templates-&quot; dear, eat more to pay attention to the body &quot;&quot; dear, go to bed early &quot;, and the uncle is transferred to each other as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;No matter how old is men or women, they will be lonely, especially the situation of single. As a relative, the care you can give him is just a part. She needs love and is really lonely.&quot; Dong Xueru said that he was more and more fascinated by him, and he was still obsessed with the conversation with the iron teacher in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Wenhan&#39;s sister -in -law is also obsessed with short videos. In her description, is a simple and compassionate person. She has been deceived many times in her 80 -year life. She always believes in the stories of crying poor and selling miserable. After the death of Grandpa five years ago, his uncle suddenly leaned down. Life surrounded his children. After moving to a big city, he broke contact with friends and rarely socialized. Soon, she started to brush the short video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She often saw that she slept with a short video and continued after waking up. She cooperated with AI dubbing in the short video and said to herself. The short video said, &quot;Can I call your mother?&quot; I murmured and answered, &quot;Of course, a child.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Wenhan is majoring in the elderly when studying abroad. According to her observation, many elderly people abroad live in the elderly community and have their own social circle, and the elderly in China seem to need emotion and sustenance. &quot;They need to be provided with some emotional value, that is, they are needed, or they are still attractive,&quot; Wang Wenhan said. For a while, she told her that she always dreamed that she was leaving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the &quot;Research Research Report on Emotional Care and Short Video Use of Elderly People&quot;, Peng Hua Mao, a professor at the psychology department of Beijing Normal University, investigated the 2,000 elderly people across the country. The research team found that the elderly who chased the Internet celebrity in the Internet was still &quot;too lonely and lacking attention.&quot; During the investigation, Peng Hua Mao asked the elderly interviewed, did the elderly still need love? Most answers, need, most of them are children&#39;s love, and of course there are love of the opposite sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Hua Mao told reporters from the Southern Weekend that the elderly and short videos on the Internet are always about obsessed and earthy, and most of them are negative impressions. An old man chasing stars or live broadcasts will always be considered deceived. &quot;The senior psychological needs of the elderly are always ignored. The needs of love, the needs of respect, and the needs of self -realization.&quot; One of the results of the survey is that the vast majority of the elderly have the ability to control, and understand that this compensation is actually not really satisfying, but the transfer of attention or the time of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under Dong Xueru&#39;s online post, a user commented that her auntie encountered the same situation, caught in the public account of her brother and secretly rewarded. After his wife found the abnormal money, she confiscated her mobile phone and asked relatives to persuade them. The aunts who have handled housework for a lifetime have become almost crazy, crying, and do not believe this is a scam. The policeman found by the family was an actor by her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The final solution, the family registered a fake younger brother WeChat signal to chat with her aunt in a &quot;destruction&quot; way. The younger brother is no longer perfect, becoming rude, breaking the fantasy of his aunt. In the end, my auntie darkened the younger brother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Dong Xueru, Ma Kai, Xiao Lin, Wang Wenhan as the name) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子编排“老头强奸孙女致怀孕”被拘留：可比照“老夫少妻”造谣案入刑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261716]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &quot;Tell everyone a story, a old man brings a granddaughter and a granddaughter at home. I was pregnant for three months at the age of twelve, and was finally discovered by the teacher. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 27, a video spread on the Douyin platform, which caused public attention. On November 29, the Chongqing Hechuan Police issued a notice: The video is a rumor that illegal officer Liu (female, 46 years old) In order to earn the gold coins of the Douyin platform, unusted rumors are published through Douyin. Facing netizens&#39; questioning failed, it has not been questioned. The rumors clarified that as of the deletion of the information, it was commenting and sharing nearly 700 times by netizens, causing adverse effects. At present, the police have punished the woman in the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the police notification, the woman in the case of the party should constitute Article 42, paragraph 2 of the &quot;Penalty Penalty Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, &quot;blatantly insults others or fabricated the facts slandering others&quot;, and accepted the &quot; Administrative penalties for detained for less than five days or fines below 500 yuan. &quot; Judging from the behavior of the woman in the case, the suspected illegal crimes are probably not only &quot;fabricating the facts slandering others&quot;, but still there is still room for discussing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the point of view of this case, the video uploaded by the woman in the case can be said to be &quot;not related to graphic and text&quot;. Just picking up the video pictures of the citron of the victim and granddaughter, and began to get to the wall to the wall The fictional &quot;played&quot;, weaving a &quot;incest tragedy&quot;, the faint tone, the bad nature, and the poor technique, all made netizens look sideways. As netizens questioned, the woman in the case did not delete the treatment for the first time, nor did she clarify the apology, which caused the video to continue to spread and ferment. At the time of the incident, 700 comments and sharing had accumulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is unclear what the woman is used to obtain the information of the elderly and granddaughter in what way the woman is in the case, but this move first infringes the personality rights of the victim&#39;s grandchildren and the naked violation of the naked violations Their portrait and reputation right. The particularity of this case is that in addition to seeking the benefits of the gold coins of the Douyin platform, the woman in the case of the woman was stolen. &quot;Creating yellow rumors&quot; or &quot;slander slander&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Douyin platform can be regarded as public places. The woman in the case of the woman issued such a specific and &quot;below limit&quot; allegations in public. Responsible. Therefore, in addition to violating the law of public security management punishment, the woman in the affairs is also suspected of other illegal criminal acts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Article 1 of the &quot;Explanation of the Application of Laws in the Application of Criminal Cases and other criminal cases such as the use of information networks&quot;, &quot;the content of the original information involved in the information network is tampered with The behavior scattered on the information network, or the &quot;scattered&quot; behavior scattered on the information network, shall be identified as &quot;fabricating facts slandering others&quot; stipulated in Article 246, paragraph 1 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The woman&#39;s behavior in this case obviously meets this element, and its video reviews released in Douyin have reached 700 times, which is in line with Article 2 of the two high judicial interpretations. The &quot;serious plot&quot; standard of more than five hundred times. According to Article 246 of the Criminal Law, the woman in the case constitutes a crime of defamation and the circumstances are serious. They should be sentenced to less than three years in prison, detention, control or deprivation of political rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, compared with similar cases before, the illegal criminal act of women in the case may be more criminal punishment, rather than just administrative penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the case of &quot;Women&#39;s Women&#39;s Wife&quot; in 2021, the man involved in the incident Wu Moumou took a group photo of the woman and grandfather&#39;s grandparents as &quot;old husband and young wife&quot;. Rumor content. After the incident, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Dongguan First City was prosecuted with defamation. In September 2023, the court ruled that Wu Moumou slandered the facts on the information network to slander others, and the circumstances were serious and seriously endangered social order. Comprehensive defendant&#39;s crime and confession and punishment were comprehensively sentenced to one year in prison for defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Moumou&#39;s behavior constitutes a crime of defamation. It should be the relevant definition of the court&#39;s adoption of the two high judicial interpretations. In fact, scattered on the information network. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In all fairness, even if the &quot;old man and young wife&quot; are true, they did not violate any law in the marriage and family editor of the &quot;People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, and even the so -called moral ethics issues. Pu news can cause the curiosity and onlookers of netizens at most. In contrast, the rumors of women in this case are even more indexed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is not difficult to imagine that if the men&#39;s charges are true, then such a cold &quot;Grandpa incest&quot; has violated the criminal law and constituted a crime of rape, and it is in line with the &quot;less than fourteen weeks old. &quot;The standards are also in line with the&quot; Opinions on punishing sexual assault on sexual assault in accordance with the law &quot;and the standards of&quot; those who have a common family relationship with the minors must be punished in accordance with the law &quot;. The &quot;old man&quot; involved may face severe punishment for more than ten years in prison, life imprisonment or death sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the woman in the case of the person who put forward such a serious and open and false allegations was suspected of being framed beyond the crime of defamation. Article 243 of the Criminal Law also stipulates that the fabrication of the facts to framed others, intending to cause others to be held criminally investigating and constituted a crime of framing. If the circumstances are serious, in prison, detention or control of less than three years, the imprisonment of less than three years or less than ten years caused serious consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this case, if the life of the victims and grandchildren encounters a greater impact and has caused bad consequences, the woman in the case of a person should also bear greater responsibilities. Therefore, there is a situation of inconsistent proportions in this case. The woman in the case is suspected of criminal crimes. Public power can continue to investigate their criminal responsibility, ask them to apologize to eliminate the impact and attach civil compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[婚礼上听“常识课”：“互免模式”下，老家变时尚了丨回乡偶书]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261680]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 11:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Old Friends Spring and Autumn Brother asked me to go back to my hometown to drink a happy wine. wedding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Letting go of the phone, suddenly remembering the appearance of the younger brother in Spring and Autumn, remembering that the spring and autumn brothers were busy running when I operated the wedding banquet. At that time, he was a reporter of the newspaper and made a guest appearance for wedding photography. In a blink of an eye, our children also walked into the palace of love, and the &quot;oath&quot; was like a husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Think about the routine of the newlywed dinner in my hometown, which is actually a bit annoying: first, late, wait for endlessly; second, noisy, endless program. However, I went back to find out recently that my hometown has also changed, becoming young and fashionable. There are happy events at home, and now there are no parts and no red envelopes. The &quot;exemption model&quot; allows civilians to &quot;happy&quot; and &quot;love&quot; to worry -free, and also allows the first batch of experimental area selected for the national marriage customs reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The wedding of Brother Spring and Autumn, simple and cheerful. The subtle place is shiny and surprised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The highlight is in the gratitude of the parents of the newcomer. Cute Brother Spring and Autumn Brother, a bite of Mandarin, the first paragraph &quot;thanks&quot;, the second paragraph &quot;gratitude&quot;, the third paragraph is two &quot;speech&quot;, specially gift to your son and daughter -in -law: In the sea of ​​more than one billion people, you meet, phase, See, love each other. I hope you will cherish the fate of thousands of miles, the fate of thousands of years, and respect, mutual forgiveness and mutual assistance. As the parents of the newcomer, I also want to remind you: First, the person who is always kind and helps people who need help in time; the other is to always be grateful and never forget to care for us ... Jiangsu guys and Hunan girls marry, the real is The love of &quot;Jiang, Lake&quot;, I look forward to you to break the waves and laugh &quot;Jianghu&quot;! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These golden sentence expressions are sensational enough. At the wedding scene, the newcomers of the newcomers simultaneously hanged the big red couplet of &quot;always good&quot; and &quot;always gratitude&quot;. Eight characters attracted the audience&#39;s mobile phone The banner of &quot;Xiao Aojiang (Su) Lake (South)&quot; was launched, pushing the atmosphere of the night to a new climax. For a moment, many people switched to &quot;hilarious mode&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The most sense of ritual is &quot;paying tribute moment&quot;, and the groom&#39;s 99 -year -old grandmother appeared. The old man came from more than 4 hours of drive to congratulate the newcomer for a long time. The groom and bride made a red envelope with a special trip and shouted in the old man&#39;s ears: Grandma, healthy for a long time! Happy for a long time! ! This is the fourth time the elderly attended the wedding of the grandchildren, but when she received the blessing red envelope of the newcomer, she was the first time that she laughed like a child. According to reports, red envelopes are auspicious: 999 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Interestingly, Professor Zhu of Shanghai Big Hospital Zhu: I am a cardiologist, and I have a talk with &quot;Heart&quot; for a lifetime. First, in a small family, new people have to be loyal to each other and care for each other. Entering the marriage hall today means the beginning of the chai oil, salt, and pans and pans. In the future, small families will inevitably encounter small difficulties and small setbacks. You must be patient! Second, in the workplace, professional problems must be humbly, adhere to the post, and be enthusiastic about treating colleagues! The third is to have kindness and filial piety to relatives, friends, parents, and elders in their hometown, and more attentive places at the end of the branches -parents do not ask you how much contribution to you, every three forks, five -one Victoria videos, send them every day in the family group every day. A smiley face, enough! As long as you have a caring, we can rest assured in our hometown! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wedding is the highlight of the new people. The protagonist of the wedding is the groom and the bride, and they are their growth background, love story, and future vision. However, the protagonist is not necessarily the highlights of the scene, hi, the family or friends of the newcomer, and those who appear with supporting actors sometimes can win strangely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This full of positive wedding, no vulgar, no preaching, grounding. The only bad thing is that people finally forgot to put on a few dishes and drink a few glasses of wine. Some people say that marriage is a school that teaches people to learn tolerance, learn to understand, and learn to share. Well, the wedding may be the &quot;first lesson of school&quot;, a person who is a person, takes the lesson, and pays the old lesson. In the final analysis, it is a common sense lesson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (the author is Jiangsu media) &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; Share what you see and hear the villages and hears. Submitting mailbox: nfzmreams@163.com) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿拉伯的劳伦斯：传奇、神话和现代中东诞生记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261702]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-02 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwoPm87.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;715&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ThTVOHpLZEEqEjcJ1Fv3uuQCXll8CmOVLMwoPm87. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;托马斯·爱德华·劳伦斯&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年的一天，伦敦西敏寺一座私宅里，T·E·劳伦斯正沉浸在战争回忆录的写作中。一年前被逐出巴黎和会后，这位声名响彻英伦的“一战”英雄正挣扎于持续的抑郁中，只有写作才能让他暂时从绝望的沼泽中拔脱出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寂静被一阵铃声打破，是从伦敦白厅打来的电话——对方是将出任殖民大臣的温斯顿·丘吉尔，他想邀请劳伦斯来协助自己处理中东事务。这位五年前因中东战场失利而沦为“政治贱民”的争议人物东山再起，正想办法处理大英帝国在中东地区的一团乱麻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一战”已结束，奥斯曼帝国被肢解，和平没有到来：在巴勒斯坦地区，得到英国支持的犹太复国主义者和当地阿拉伯人之间的矛盾迅速激化，最终升级为流血冲突；更严重的是在英国控制的产油区伊拉克，爆发了全面的反英起义，有上万人在流血中丧生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;盟友们也没好日子过——在外约旦的沙漠里，来自哈希姆家族的阿卜杜拉王子一直在凶狠地进攻控制叙利亚地区的法国人。几个月前，法国人刚用武力从这个家族的另一位王子费萨尔手中强夺了这块地盘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1919年6月，争吵了半年之久的巴黎和会画上句号。在被胜利者瓜分的中东，到处是仇恨、流血和冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管遭到劳伦斯的拒绝，丘吉尔丝毫没有放弃的打算。这位未来将跻身于20世纪最重要政治家之列的不凡人物清楚：“阿拉伯的劳伦斯”是解开这一团乱麻的钥匙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两个都不走寻常路的“政治贱民”即将携手塑造中东历史。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/JQGwRMz0I9faA6cyJmqWkJTwlimow6j76NZC5o42.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1913年，劳伦斯（右二）与英国考古学家伦纳德·伍利参与奥斯曼帝国境内赫梯王国古城卡尔基米什（Carchemish）遗址的考古行动&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;聪明的“私生子”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;他是一个爱尔兰贵族与情妇私奔的crystallization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了躲避社会压力，劳伦斯的父母隐姓埋名避居乡下，频繁搬家，几乎不与周围邻居来往。直到为了五个儿子的教育和前途，才大着胆子搬到了热闹的牛津郡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在老师眼中，这个男孩非常聪明，性格安静，喜好书籍，但又热衷搞恶作剧。他尤其喜欢玩各种测试自己极限生存忍耐力的游戏，譬如不喝水、不吃饭、不睡眠，凭意志力总能坚持到昏厥崩溃的地步。牛津公立学校校长回忆说：劳伦斯和同龄男孩很不一样，颇有些古希腊斯多葛派的作风，“对肉体的愉悦和痛苦都不在意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;少年劳伦斯学习成绩优异，尤其痴迷于中世纪骑士文学，对军事史和考古感兴趣。每到假期，他会和好友骑着自行车探索英格兰的古迹，还到牛津的阿什莫林博物馆当助手。他后来考入牛津大学耶稣学院主修历史。大学期间，他曾骑行2400英里考察欧洲的古城堡和军事遗迹，一路风餐露宿到地中海。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1909年1月，为了搞清楚中世纪军事史上的一桩学术公案，他单枪匹马到叙利亚地区考察。在烈日之下，他从贝鲁特出发，穿过黎巴嫩群山，到达巴勒斯坦北部；三周后返回贝鲁特，再北上继续更为艰苦的考古。回来后撰写了论文《12世纪十字军东征对欧洲军事建筑的影响》，获牛津最高一等优秀奖。此外，还被授予一笔用于研究生阶段的奖学金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1910年，大英博物馆启动对今天土耳其和叙利亚交界地带的卡尔基米什古城遗址的考古挖掘工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯担任初级助理，并很快成为挖掘现场负责人，管理两百多个当地雇佣的工人。他做得很出色，平时常用阿拉伯语和工人们聊天，到他们家拜访、做客，记录下他们的民间传说、家族内部和部落间的结构关系，以及他们对政治的看法。工人们对这个年轻的欧洲人也很有好感，因为他是真正尊重他们的习俗、文化，也乐于接受款待。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以说，在当时，没有比劳伦斯更了解叙利亚地区的西方人了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卡尔基米什，劳伦斯和一个13岁的叙利亚少年形影不离，非常亲密。这个在回忆录中被他唤作达霍姆的少年，真名赛利姆·阿赫迈德，即劳伦斯把战争回忆录《智慧七柱》献给的“SA”。达霍姆聪明俊美，脸上有两个深深的大酒窝，笑起来天真灿烂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了学者的好奇心，劳伦斯在与当地社会的接触学习中，对近东文化产生了真正的欣赏和敬意。他开始反思西方关于“西方启蒙和教化落后民族”那种傲慢的帝国主义意识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为真正深入到叙利亚腹地的学者，劳伦斯已清楚看到奥斯曼帝国分崩离析的大势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，统治阿拉伯半岛四个多世纪、疆域横跨亚非欧的奥斯曼帝国已步入黄昏，被人称为“欧洲病夫”。随着世界范围内民族主义的崛起和国际商贸的发展，奥斯曼面对的国内外挑战越来越多。在外部，经历工业化的欧洲诸强在不断地蚕食着它的领土和主权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/EA0uVznH9pUk8pS2iktOaARUYAcUBK0W02Ldofh1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/EA0uVznH9pUk8pS2iktOaARUYAcUBK0W02Ldofh1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1917年11月，英国埃及远征军突破奥斯曼军队防线，攻占巴勒斯坦地区；12月，英军进入耶路撒冷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在帝国内部，推动改革、要求现代化的力量也一直存在。 1908年，一群被称为“青年土耳其党”的年轻军官发动政变，逼迫哈米德二世恢复议会宪法。 1913年，该党的民族主义激进派掌权，建立了以“三寡头”为核心的中央集权独裁体制，他们把改革方案调整为推行现代化、保卫伊斯兰以及泛突厥主义，以争取团结帝国疆域内的每个群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，在一个多语言多族群、社会构成异常复杂的庞大帝国里，任何一项改革纲领都不可能安抚到所有群体：世俗化的努力大大激怒了人数众多的传统穆斯林；鼓吹泛突厥主义又让非土耳其人的其他族群，如阿拉伯人、亚美尼亚人心生芥蒂……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此刻，年轻的考古学家醉心的，是脚下的土地、工作、友谊，还有爱情。当他决心把未来四五年都投入到对古城遗址的发掘和研究，坏消息传来：大英博物馆项目经费已耗尽，发掘工作必须暂停，直至有新的资金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但有另一个工作的机会：受一家基金会资助，英国皇家工兵的一个特遣队要对巴勒斯坦南部的寻漠地带进行一次考古探险，要招募两名考古学家，问他们是否有兴趣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯和同伴欣然接受了。 “寻漠”在今天以色列的南部，据《旧约》记载，它是古犹太人在先知摩西带领下出走埃及、旷野流浪四十年的最后停留之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聪明如劳伦斯，他很快就猜到这个打着基金会名义的探险行动，实则是一次秘密军事地理勘探。当时，英国出兵占领了苏伊士运河及西奈半岛的缓冲带，和奥斯曼帝国的关系因此一直很紧张。到“一战”爆发，因为担心奥斯曼人一旦和德国结盟就会进攻埃及、夺取运河，英国人想摸清楚苏伊士运河东侧缓冲带另一侧——从巴勒斯坦海岸东南到亚喀巴湾之间的沙漠地带的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责这次行动的是英军上尉斯图尔特·纽科姆。他对这个毫不在意享受、忍耐力惊人甚至到受虐狂地步的牛津学者产生了好感，对他的怪癖印象尤为深刻——总的来说，劳伦斯是个生性极为羞涩的人，但是一旦有人企图阻扰或糊弄他，他就会变得坚决而大胆。在寻漠探险途中，因为处处受到奥斯曼军警的监视、阻挠，劳伦斯把这种带着孩童恶作剧般的突破能力展现得淋漓尽致。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一战”爆发后，他把劳伦斯带进了英军在开罗的军事情报机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1914年6月28日，奥匈帝国皇储费迪南大公及其夫人在萨拉热窝遇刺，第一次世界大战爆发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月，刚满26岁的劳伦斯被派到英国总参谋部地理科担任地图绘制师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;置身于帝国的军政高官之中，这个自负的年轻人依然一副邋里邋遢、自由散漫的样子，对各种规章制度漠然视之。在他眼里，这些装腔作势的高官们统统是腹中空空的傻叉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因着一位将军想让有身份的军官给自己做汇报，劳伦斯戏剧性地被提拔为少尉。但他渴望的是到前线一展身手。劳伦斯身高不足1.65米，低于英国陆军最低标准，所以唯一能上前线的机会是需要他的特殊才能的地方——中东战场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1914年11月2日，奥斯曼帝国最终加入同盟国，正式参战。 On December 15, Lawrence came to Cairo with a French carboat and reported to the military intelligence unit led by Newkom.此时的开罗喧嚣嘈杂，已是“一战”中人员、物资的重要中转枢纽，几十万来自印度、澳大利亚和新西兰的英属殖民地军队从这里开往欧洲战场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Of9gtmLeIhFGX1qVqGIyxmTuHCLtIjZQWHSZct3r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;632&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/Of9gtmLeIhFGX1qVqGIyxmTuHCLtIjZQWHSZct3r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1918年，劳伦斯在德拉一带领导、发动了对汉志铁路最凶猛的袭击。图为劳伦斯查看被摧毁的火车&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“欧洲病夫”的百万裂缝&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在开罗的英国情报机构里，劳伦斯的工作内容之一是为伦敦高层撰写描述奥斯曼帝国地形地貌、文化和民族构成的报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年深入叙利亚社会的经历，让劳伦斯看到了这个老帝国内部的无数裂缝——在土耳其人过往鼎盛时期凭武力拼凑起来的庞大疆域里，存在着很多根本不想和这场战争扯上关系的族群；他们本来就对土耳其统治者充满怨恨，战争使得这种恨意越发加深。在这个帝国中，人口最庞大的是信仰伊斯兰教的阿拉伯人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1908年，青年土耳其党上台后所推行的现代化和世俗化改革，激怒了控制阿拉伯半岛汉志地区的宗教政治领袖侯赛因·伊本·阿里。他是著名的哈希姆家族的头领，先知穆罕默德的直系后裔，世代守护麦加圣地。作为“圣裔”，侯赛因是伊斯兰世界里地位最崇高的宗教领袖之一，拥有强大的影响力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥斯曼帝国加入“一战”后，双方关系越发恶化。对官方发动的所谓“圣战”宣传，身为宗教领袖的侯赛因保持沉默；奥斯曼帝国要求他派兵助攻夺取苏伊士运河，他也只是派次子阿卜杜拉带领一小队人马敷衍了事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在“一战”爆发前的1914年2月，阿卜杜拉借着到访开罗的机会，拜会时任英属埃及总督的基钦纳勋爵，他试探性地问：如果汉志地区爆发阿拉伯起义，英国会作何反应。基钦纳小心地回避了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等1914年11月奥斯曼帝国正式参战后，出任英国陆军大臣的基钦纳立刻给开罗发了一份密电，让老部下斯托尔斯派人跟阿卜杜拉秘密接触，去摸清侯赛因的真实态度。这一回，侯赛因谨慎回复说自己会保持中立，但同时暗示：如果英国人提供外部援助，同时保证不干涉阿拉伯的内部事务，他也许会率领他的追随者发动起义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这让基钦纳非常高兴，他给侯赛因的信里写道——“从今天开始，我们将与高贵的阿拉伯人为友。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得知这些秘密来信后，劳伦斯感到宛如“神启”——到开罗后，他一直在研究在叙利亚地区发动阿拉伯起义的可能性。中东战场离欧洲路途遥远、获得的资源相对缺乏，因此劳伦斯认为英国需要采取一种非常规战争，即利用奥斯曼帝国内部的社会、民族矛盾和分裂，与其中的不满分子联手，帮助他们发动起义来颠覆土耳其的统治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5TneGpF03MprbuQRXwbRsHtN9q7Q15l7j7YPZAYv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;743&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5TneGpF03MprbuQRXwbRsHtN9q7Q15l7j7YPZAYv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1919年，巴黎和会期间的费萨尔（前排）和劳伦斯（第二排右二） &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重重密约里的起义&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从1915年7月至1916年1月，侯赛因与英国驻埃及高级专员亨利·麦克马洪（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;即“麦克马洪线”划定者&lt;/span>;）秘密地往来信函，就合作进行讨价还价。而叙利亚地区的几个阿拉伯民族主义秘密社团也在暗中联络侯赛因，希望联手发动起义抵抗土耳其人，由英国提供支持，并以他为起义的精神领袖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但让侯赛因最终决定倒向英国的，是一则流言——当时传闻君士坦丁堡方面有意废掉他，让扎伊德家族的首领取而代之。 1916年5月6日，奥斯曼“三寡头”之一的杰马勒帕夏在大马士革公开处决了21名阿拉伯民族主义分子，侯赛因派其子费萨尔去说情，遭到拒绝和恐吓，这让他越发加重了对未来命运的不安感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这些秘密通信中，英国人向侯赛因保证：如若他率军协助英军的中东战事，战后英国人将协助他建立一个地处埃及和波斯之间，但不包括科威特、亚丁及叙利亚海岸地区的阿拉伯帝国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，麦克马洪在信件中还插入一个不起眼的条件：这些承诺仅在“英国可以自由决断，而不危害其盟友法国的利益时”生效。其中，有关巴勒斯坦的部分未被谈及。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当法国得知英国和侯赛因在商谈密约，立马提出了权利主张。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1916年1月，一位贵族出身、名叫马克·赛克斯的“业余政治家”和法国外交官弗朗索瓦·乔治-皮科在伦敦达成一份关于战后中东愿景的草案，后来在俄国的彼得格勒正式签署，史称《赛克斯-皮科协定》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据这份秘密协定：独立的阿拉伯国家被大致限制在阿拉伯半岛的荒漠里，法国直接控制大叙利亚，英国则占领产油的整个伊拉克；另有两块飞地，侯赛因所治的汉志王国以北、其余内陆的全部地区为“半独立区”，则由英、法间接控制；而巴勒斯坦则是“国际共管区”，将由英、法、俄三国共同manage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一系列“乌龙”事件究竟是如何在默许中一步步成为既成事实的，历史学家们至今还为此争论不休。总之，英国政府分别和阿拉伯人、法国人签署的这两份内容互相矛盾的承诺文件，将为中东未来的动荡不安埋下祸根，也因此把劳伦斯推向古典悲剧般的个人命运。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1915年6月5日，在圣地麦加，侯赛因·伊本·阿里爬上了宫殿里的一座塔楼，用一支旧火枪朝城内的土耳其要塞开了一枪.当日，他的两个儿子阿里和费萨尔率先行动，1500名阿拉伯骑士在麦地那对空鸣枪。之后，侯赛因的追随者在汉志境内朝土耳其驻军据点发动了袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;侯赛因向全世界穆斯林发表宣言：公开谴责土耳其当局“迫害和屠杀阿拉伯民族主义者，背离伊斯兰教精神”，并宣布阿拉伯脱离奥斯曼帝国而独立。他自封为汉志王国国王。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中东现代史上著名的“阿拉伯大起义”爆发，以劳伦斯为主角的舞台正式启幕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;寻找先知、拥立君王的“兔崽子”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“阿拉伯半岛的炽热，如同一把出鞘的利剑，打得我们张口结舌。”1916年10月16日的晨光中，当劳伦斯陪同英国驻埃及东方文化秘书前往侯赛因起义后控制的重要港口吉达时，他在日记里记录下这一刻的感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;踏上汉志之前，他心中已为阿拉伯起义设计了一个新航向，以及对自己所扮角色的定位——“为起义寻找尚不为人知的主宰灵魂，并测量他将起义推进到我为之设想的目标的能力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;侯赛因打响了第一枪之后，起义军和奥斯曼军队经过一个月的血腥巷战，进入僵持阶段。而且，麦加神圣守护人的首义，并没有如预想的那样——在阿拉伯半岛上激起更为广泛的民族起义，在叙利亚和其他地区都没有反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯认为问题的核心在于缺少一个领袖。和西方政治文化不同，阿拉伯起义所需要的，不是高明的政治家，而是一位先知人物，“不是智识，不是判断力，不是政治智慧，而是能够点燃沙漠的激情火焰”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当他的长官和起义军领袖商讨合作细节时，劳伦斯找机会在一旁仔细观察着侯赛因的四个儿子：长子阿里，次子阿卜杜拉，三子费萨尔和幼子扎伊尔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他先见到了除费萨尔外的三位王子：阿卜杜拉生性快活，因为贪图享乐而早早发福，个性“太审慎、太冷静、太幽默”；长子阿里看上去忧伤、疲惫，没有什么明显的雄心壮志，且很容易受到身边人的影响；至于扎伊尔，年仅20岁，喜欢骑马、闲逛和搞恶作剧，此外他有土耳其血统、外貌有别于阿拉伯people.劳伦斯断定：他们都难以成为那种“历史上在革命中取胜的武装先知”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到劳伦斯骑着骆驼行100英里，穿越由多个敌对部落控制的地区，见到了带着另一支部落兵驻扎在沙漠绿洲里的费萨尔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我见到他的第一眼就感到，这就是我来阿拉伯半岛寻觅的那个人，那个将给阿拉伯起义带来全副荣光的人。”费萨尔瘦削颀长，有一种奇异的沉静，说话时的激情洋溢和言辞背后透露出的铁一般的决心深深吸引了劳伦斯。这是他在另外三位王子身上所没有找到的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯还在他的营地里转悠了许久，用流利的阿拉伯语和战士们聊天。他发现：费萨尔召集起来的六千多人里，几乎包括了汉志西部所有的部落。尽管刚刚经历一次败仗，他们士气高涨，对胜利有着毫不动摇的信心。把他们团结起来并一直鼓舞他们的，就是费萨尔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他越加坚定费萨尔就是他要找到的“先知”——“比我们希望的要好，我这次旅行的目标已经达到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汉志之行，使得劳伦斯成为第一个深入阿拉伯半岛内陆观察战场的外国人。回到延布等船回开罗时，他用五天写下1.5万字的报告，提出两个重要判断：一是英国只向汉志地区派驻少量军队；二是领导起义的真正“先知”是费萨尔，而不是英国人熟悉的阿卜杜拉。他还指出：合作的唯一办法，是英国人必须接受阿拉伯人打仗的方式，并相应调整自己的战略和期望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯的这份报告根本地改变了英国对阿拉伯半岛的政策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大英帝国庞大的官僚系统里，每天都有许多聪明的想法被埋葬。在开罗办公室写了近两年报告后，劳伦斯慢慢找到了游戏规则，他极擅长利用官僚体制和派系内斗来达成自己的目的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从汉志回来后，在劳伦斯一番眼花缭乱的操作下，通过备忘录、报告、汇报，有意引导，绕开甚至破坏“障碍物”，最终他对中东战场的战略设想得以被全部采纳，在从埃及到伦敦的军政高层中获得一路绿灯。不久，英国阿拉伯局局长克莱顿通知劳伦斯：将派他到阿拉伯半岛，担任费萨尔身边的临时联络官。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上级和同事很愉快地送走了这个“狂妄自大，乳臭未干，惹毛了所有人的兔崽子”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eV9ShS7BygqFQ730yztxT16FkKgaDyLvqICW4kpj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/eV9ShS7BygqFQ730yztxT16FkKgaDyLvqICW4kpj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1921年，丘吉尔（前排中）和劳伦斯（第二排右四）在开罗会议期间&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;成为“沙漠之子”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1916年12月，当劳伦斯以英国联络官身份再次来到费萨尔的营地，在费萨尔的建议下穿上了费萨尔本人的一件纯白真丝长袍。在整个战争期间，他都尽可能地和阿拉伯部落的战士们住在一起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿拉伯部落营地，典型的一天是这样度过的：清晨，一位伊玛姆用祷告唤醒营地，然后是漫长的早餐时间。每天上午，任何人都可以来找费萨尔鸣冤、请愿、定夺纠纷。一天中，他大部分时间都是在和幕僚、部落领袖们吃饭、喝茶、闲聊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯本人一直以急躁和严于律己著称，但他意识到：这些耗时漫长、漫无目的的闲聊，正是阿拉伯人处理战争与和平的方式。费萨尔以此为黏合剂，把这些松散的部落、氏族团结并维系在他的周围。整个作战期间，他同时还在充当各部落之间的调解仲裁人，倾听、建议，必要时进行哄骗，并常常自掏腰包让发生利益纠纷的双方尽快和好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自起义以来，几乎所有被派往汉志的英国军事顾问对阿拉伯人的战斗力都非常鄙夷。劳伦斯也认同，但在和他们一起作战后，他得出了一个重要观点：不能拿欧洲的战争标准来衡量阿拉伯人，而且，也很难把他们组织、训练成为欧洲那种作战部队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们真正擅长的是游击战，加上对地理环境了如指掌，机动性很强。在战争中，当兵力和武器装备明显不如敌人时，弱势的一方不应该和对方正面短兵相接，而应该“像空气一样四处飘荡”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从起义的第一天起，无论是侯赛因和其追随者，还是英国人，都把夺取伊斯兰教第二圣城麦地那作为主要目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但劳伦斯认为：正确的战略是放弃重兵把守的麦地那，让奥斯曼军队几乎无限期地留在那里，让他们勉强维持补给线，既无力撤退也无力进攻，就等同于是起义军的俘虏了。最终，他说服了起义军把战略重心转移到对汉志铁路沿线地区的骚扰和破坏上。这迫使土军派重兵保卫铁路的同时，还得承担持续的维修工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿拉伯大起义中，劳伦斯所制定的新目标和新策略，使局面得以扭转，打击变得有效，伤亡大幅减小。整个“一战”期间，阿拉伯起义军不断发动的游击战，有效迟滞了奥斯曼军队的行动，帮助协约国最终击败了奥斯曼帝国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/RU2VlcM0z8CZJ9I6semM5HpKZiTMLQynW01DmZsl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;769&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/RU2VlcM0z8CZJ9I6semM5HpKZiTMLQynW01DmZsl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259976&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;劳伦斯（左）与美国旅行家兼记者洛维尔·托马斯在阿拉伯&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;成为传奇——攻取亚喀巴&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;亚喀巴湾位于西奈半岛以东、阿拉伯大陆以西，是红海北部的一个海湾。亚喀巴港就在其北部的末端。从平面地图看，它是从埃及进攻巴勒斯坦南部的理想集结地，往东进60英里就是奥斯曼军队在阿拉伯半岛上的生命线——汉志铁路。在未来历次中东战争中，这里都是阿、以之间攻防的战略要地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1914年，当时劳伦斯还是一名大英博物馆的考古学家，曾经在亚喀巴湾做过探险。从亚喀巴港到内陆，则是海拔一路攀升的陡峭山地，接着是内陆沙漠。从亚喀巴港通往内陆的唯一通道是峡谷，奥斯曼人在那里沿线修筑了一个由碉堡和战壕构成的网络系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于如何处理这个明显具有重要战略地位的红海港口，英、法有着各自的算盘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年1月底，在劳伦斯的联络和英军的配合下，费萨尔带领其部落军夺取了位于红海中北部的重要港口沃季赫。法国代表就开始游说英国一起出兵进攻并控制亚喀巴，这样能在右翼保护英国埃及远征军自该年1月发动的巴勒斯坦战役。另一个更隐秘的动机，是借此把势头正猛的阿拉伯起义压制在汉志境内，按需要来指挥他们作配合行动，如果他们不服，就以停止武器和黄金的支持来威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯一直反对费萨尔进攻亚喀巴的计划。他清楚协约国的算盘：如果阿拉伯人只是为英法部队的进攻作配合，亚喀巴就会成为他们的“死亡陷阱”，最后落得两手空空。为此，他不惜冒“叛国罪”的危险，于1917年2月把英法密约透露给费萨尔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，如果是阿拉伯人自己控制了这座红海最北端的港口，一旦起义军北上叙利亚地区作战，物资补给线可以大大缩短，从原本的300英里缩短至60英里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年3月，上司克莱顿从开罗给劳伦斯发来一道密令：不要让阿拉伯人出现在亚喀巴。他读懂了其潜台词——克莱顿在给一位将军的信上则说得更明确：鉴于亚喀巴对埃及防御的重要性，英国人必须在战后牢牢控制这座海港城。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该年4月，劳伦斯在盘问英军送来的十来个土耳其战俘时，得到一个新情报：亚喀巴驻军刚发生变动，人数很少超过100人，且从亚喀巴到内陆的汉志铁路枢纽——马安镇之间的这段公路，驻守的土军只有200人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯迅速作出一个大胆的冒险决定——抢在英法军队染指亚喀巴之前，联合沙漠各部落势力召集起一支阿拉伯武装，然后闪电般翻山越岭，从内陆公路末端的马安镇攻取亚喀巴港。通过这场阿拉伯人自己争取的胜利，把欧洲诸强势力在该地区的影响压缩到最小。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也是劳伦斯在“一战”中最大胆也最著名的军事行动。他用轻描淡写的借口搪塞了身边的其他英国军官和远在开罗的上司，“于是，我不管有无命令，都去走自己的路。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年5月7日，劳伦斯和45名沙漠勇士从沃季赫出发，带着价值2万英镑的金币和一些来复枪，骑着骆驼进入东北内陆的胡尔沙漠，计划到沙漠深处的霍维塔特部落去招兵买马，并鼓动叙利亚部落，为起义军北上、解放叙利亚打前站。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在进入叙利亚地带的瓦迪西尔汉绿洲，他们停留下来。越来越多的部落代表前来和起义军商讨结盟、加入阿拉伯独立事业。当劳伦斯在接受一轮又一轮的部落盛宴款待时，他的罪恶感也越来越深。他清楚自己是在欺骗——取得胜利之后，协约国必然会背叛阿拉伯人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一种极为复杂的痛苦心态下，他做了一次自杀式冒险——独自北上叙利亚，在敌境内迂回400英里，最北抵达黎巴嫩和大马士革的郊区，秘密会见并争取潜在的起义盟友，包括部落领袖和城市阿拉伯民族主义分子。当时，大马士革是奥斯曼军和德军的联合司令部所在地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一个沙漠绿洲里，他见到了有崇高威望的埃米尔（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;阿拉伯世界的贵族头衔&lt;/span>;）努里·沙拉昂。当身居沙漠深处的老酋长拿出一堆内容互相矛盾的文件副本，问他到底该相信英国人哪一个承诺时，劳伦斯只好建议选择日期最近的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老酋长被说服了，劳伦斯感到羞愧难当，“我用谎言为自己谋来了声誉，成为诈骗集团当仁不让的首领。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯说自己真正醒悟过来，有了活下去的动力。 “我发誓要不遗余力，直到带给阿拉伯人最后的胜利，要求尊重阿拉伯人的诉求，协商公平合理的解决之道。而只有保全性命于眼前的乱世，方可在未来的谈判桌上与人分庭抗礼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沼泽般的处境，每每激发出劳伦斯最不可思议的勇气、智谋与忍耐力。 “一战”期间的传奇战役——攻取亚喀巴之战——发生了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年6月18日，劳伦斯和“传奇沙漠武士”奥达·阿布·塔伊带着招募到的500名骆驼骑兵从瓦迪西尔汉出发，向西南行进。到达贝尔时，他们发现奥斯曼军追踪而来的足迹——沙漠行军最重要的水井全部被炸毁，并已经猜到起义军的目标是亚喀巴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯随之指挥、领导阿拉伯人摆下一个堪称神级的迷魂阵——早在十多天前，他在北上叙利亚时就做了铺垫，带着一个当地小分队炸毁了大马士革以北的汉志铁路上的一座小桥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6月21日，他又带领100名战士北上150英里前往铁路上的安曼，速战速决摧毁了一座铁路涵洞，然后迅速返回。在叙利亚南境，起义军发动了一系列打了就跑的游击战。这让土耳其军队完全找不到规律，只得分散兵力、四处奔忙追踪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个好消息传来：他们在几天前派出的一支队伍刚刚攻下、并摧毁了土耳其人的军事据点富维拉，从内陆通往亚喀巴的道路基本敞开了。当他们急忙绕过马安镇赶往亚喀巴时，又传来了坏消息：当天上午，约有五百多名奥斯曼士兵赶往富维拉增兵支援，就在他们前方道路上的某at. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过一番思考后，劳伦斯做出一个决定：必须主动找到并歼灭奥斯曼援军。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月2日黎明时分，在富维拉以南的一条山地狭道里，他们找到了正在呼呼大睡的敌人，经过残酷厮杀，最终打死300人、俘虏160人.然而，当战俘们透露马安镇防守空虚，土匪出身的部落武士高兴得嗷嗷大叫，想趁机去洗劫这个富饶的交通枢纽。劳伦斯又竭力劝说，并许诺给予他们更多补偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当他们沿着公路快速西进，经过了一座又一座空荡荡的土耳其堡垒和战壕防线——这证明了劳伦斯一直不被上司们认可的计划之高明，“敌人从来没有想到，我们会从内陆发动攻击。他们所有的大型防御工事中，没有一座战壕、没有一座哨所是面向内陆的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过两天的僵持，劳伦斯带领的部队几乎兵不血刃地拿下了亚喀巴港。次日，他又动身前往埃及，骑着骆驼穿越150英里沙漠到达苏伊士运河，通知英军赶紧增派援军和运送粮食等物资补给。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年7月10日，已“失踪”两个多月的劳伦斯穿着一身邋遢的阿拉伯长袍，突然出现在英国情报机构的开罗办公室里。数日内，他的英雄事迹在埃及、伦敦的军方高层里传开了。在西线战事不利、法国军队哗变之际，这场英国人在中东战场获得的胜利显得尤为令人振奋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对普罗大众，这更是一个能激起无穷无尽浪漫想象的孤胆英雄传奇——一位年轻的、蓝眼睛的英国军官身着异族长袍，骑着骆驼，单枪匹马地深入敌境腹地，秘密会见并争取潜在的密谋者，在利欲熏心的人中游走，随时都可能被出卖、处死。然后，这位英雄又率领部落武士，兵出奇谋、以少胜多，夺取一连串不可思议的胜利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英国埃及军总司令温盖特向伦敦高层提议：向劳伦斯上尉授予英国最高军事荣誉——维多利亚十字勋章。很快，他被提拔为上校，并提名授予三等骑士爵位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一回，桀骜不驯的劳伦斯却谦卑恭顺地接受了——官方的认可和荣誉也可以成为一种强有力的工具，去影响军事高层的决策，以实现他在沙漠里发下的誓言：突破法国人所设的“红线”，把战火一直烧到叙利亚，让英国人帮助阿拉伯人解放叙利亚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;站在新任英国埃及远征军总司令埃德蒙·艾伦比面前，他描绘了一番激动人心的战况和未来前景。随即，艾伦比给帝国总参谋长威廉·罗伯逊拍去一份洋溢着乐观情绪的电报。最终，这位视西线为重中之重的总协调人答应给中东增兵5万，用于巴勒斯坦战场的攻势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是阿拉伯大起义的一个关键转折点。撬动齿轮的人，正是劳伦斯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在高层要求下，这位“当红炸子鸡”写下了供海外作战军官参考的经验总结，是为《二十七条建议》。他最重要的心得是：抛弃英国人的习惯，让自己完全沉浸到当地环境，要熟悉“当地的家庭、氏族和部落、朋友和敌人、水井、山丘和道路”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006年，美国对伊拉克发动军事行动，美军总司令戴维·彼得雷乌斯将军就命令高级军官们阅读《二十七条建议》，向劳伦斯学习如何赢得伊拉克本地的People&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/2GoBfcYcaBhBupnkcwvtvyN6jtzDWoOVshoucg6i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;717&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/2GoBfcYcaBhBupnkcwvtvyN6jtzDWoOVshoucg6i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;骑着骆驼的劳伦斯&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被污损的英雄&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1917年10月起，一些接近劳伦斯的人发现他处于安静的沮丧状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从担任阿拉伯大起义的英方联络官，他一直过着高度紧张的生活，就像一个伟大的演员，马不停蹄地进行“惊险表演”。这在智力、体力、精神上都是巨大的消耗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更主要的原因，是越来越升级的杀戮。在《智慧七柱》里，他记录下第一次近距离处决一个人，然后他病倒了。起初，他带领阿拉伯人四处打游击战，尽量避免杀戮无辜。一次伏击行动中，他们抓住了一个撞见他们的牧童，劳伦斯把他绑在树上，以防他去给土军通风报信，战斗结束撤离前，再把他释放。随着战争越来越紧张、残酷，他已经顾不上很多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等到亚喀巴战役的富维拉峡谷之战结束，他用极为诡异、凄美的文字描写了在月光下看到几百具被剥走衣服的土耳其士兵的尸体，看上去年轻、白皙、宁静，令人心生悲悯，“于是我把他们全都摆放整齐，一个一个地摆好。我自己也很疲惫，渴望成为这些宁静的人中的一员，而不是回到山谷高处那群没有片刻安宁、吵闹、苦痛的暴徒当中去。那些人还在为战利品而争。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对越来越频繁的杀戮，他似乎越来越冷漠，越来越无动于衷。但在给牛津密友的信里，他倾吐说：“我希望噩梦结束，我能够醒来，重新活过来。杀人，杀土耳其人真是太可怕了”，“我知道自己已经干过这种事情几百次，如果可以的话，还要再干几百次”，“我在这场游戏里撑不了多久了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上司克莱顿已经注意到这位最得力干将的精神状态，他承认对劳伦斯的状态非常担忧，“我们会尽快把他撤下来的，不要继续让他冒险，但时间还没有到，因为现在还需要他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年11月，为配合埃及远征军对巴勒斯坦的攻势，劳伦斯带着一名护卫去勘查叙利亚境内铁路枢纽德拉附近的情况时，他被奥斯曼的一支部队逮捕了，然后被押到当地总督那里。劳伦斯谎称自己是高加索一个山地民族的平民，这个民族以皮肤白皙、眼珠浅色著称，且免于兵役。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后是他整部回忆录里最恐怖的场景，劳伦斯用了整整五页的篇幅描述自己所遭受的暴行细节——他先是被土耳其总督施以弥漫着血腥气息的暴力性侵；然后被四个士兵鞭打，接着是被刑讯军官反复踢打；他又被拖回总督的房间。后来他被扔在一个庭院里，一个亚美尼亚人过来为他清创、包扎。这群人随后扬长而去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天微亮时，劳伦斯清醒过来，跌跌撞撞地走出镇子。在一个骆驼商人的帮助下，他找到了同伴，然后讲述一个“通过贿赂和计谋逃脱敌人魔掌的欢乐故事”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们发现：从德拉回来后，劳伦斯身上的一些东西变了，他更加孤傲冷漠。从那以后，这个过往胆大包天的人给自己组织了一支50人的精锐卫队，时刻陪伴在他身边。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10个月后，等他率领阿拉伯战士再次回到这座铁路城镇，他带着复仇的火焰下令进行了一场血腥大屠杀，共有四千多人丧生，史称“塔法斯屠杀”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德拉事件给劳伦斯留下的精神创伤是永久性的——“一战“结束后，对被他视为忏悔神父般的存在的萧伯纳夫人，他倾吐了内心的被污损感和强烈的自我憎恶，“那件事”之后，他发誓从此“弃绝过体面的生活”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7QS17IxA1tkbMuvRygpq9jt1YSkqDU2uuPS7uUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;747&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/v7QS17IxA1tkbMuvRygpq9jt1YSkqDU2uuPS7uUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1962年电影《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;越缠越多的乱麻：贝尔福宣言，魏茨曼和劳伦斯&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1917年11月，英国埃及远征军顺利地突破奥斯曼军队防线，攻占巴勒斯坦地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，劳伦斯已得知一个将使未来局面越发乱成一锅粥的消息：英国政府内阁在10月底初步通过了支持犹太复国主义者在巴勒斯坦建立“民族家园”的《贝尔福宣言》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“锡安主义”，我国一般称之为“犹太复国主义”，是一种犹太民族主义思潮，号召散居世界各地的犹太人返回故国——巴勒斯坦，重建犹太国家，复兴犹太民族。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到19世纪末，欧洲出现新一轮反犹太主义浪潮后，犹裔奥地利记者西奥多·赫茨尔提出了现代犹太复国主义的理论和纲领，并于1897年举行第一次锡安主义代表大会，创建世界锡安主义组织。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1916年底，英国新首相大卫·劳合·乔治上任，他和外务大臣贝尔福都是锡安主义运动的同情者，并和该运动核心人物、著名化学家哈伊姆·魏茨曼有交往。除宗教同情之外，这也有现实政治的考量：“一战”陷入僵持后，交战双方都意识到犹太复国主义者的广泛影响，都希望得到他们的帮助；但德国碍于巴勒斯坦地区是盟友奥斯曼帝国的领地，无法许诺过多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年10月31日，英国政府内阁通过支持性决议，随之而生的《贝尔福宣言》正式宣布：支持锡安主义者在巴勒斯坦建立犹太人“民族之家”，条件是不伤害当地已有民族的权利，但是政治权利除外。当时巴勒斯坦仍然是奥斯曼帝国领土，犹太人只是当地的少数民族。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《贝尔福宣言》是大英帝国的中东政策和以色列建国史上一个重要文件。它促成了巴勒斯坦托管地的建立，这后来成为以色列和巴勒斯坦领土，所以宣言也被视为是导致巴以冲突的一个原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在8个月前，劳伦斯在《阿拉伯公报》上发表了一篇对叙利亚现状的分析。他谈及了导致该地区四分五裂的原因，包括部落、民族、宗教之间种种矛盾，以及任何外来者企图把自己的意志强加于叙利亚，必将面临诸多挑战。劳伦斯还指出：巴勒斯坦南部对犹太复国主义运动者怀有莫大仇恨，包括穆斯林和基督徒，近来事态更是加剧了这种天生仇恨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，这篇文章写于两年前，劳伦斯完全预见到了未来中东地区的无数动荡、冲突和不安。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年2月，这篇文章引起了一位名叫威廉·耶鲁的美国驻中东代表的特别兴趣。这位年轻的前美国石油巨头雇员一心想让自己国家参与到中东事务中来，他于是去拜会劳伦斯，想得知更多相关情报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会面时，劳伦斯堪称毫无保留，甚至还透露了阿拉伯起义军下一步的军事行动目标。他还预言了《贝尔福宣言》的后果：“如果的确在巴勒斯坦建立了一个犹太国家，只能是通过武力来建立，并且要在充满敌意的人群当中通过武力维持下去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有传记作者分析认为：劳伦斯是有意为之，他是想通过耶鲁去影响并引导加入协约国不久的美国政府，进而采纳他所认可的、对叙利亚和巴勒斯坦的政策。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而威尔逊总统在1919年的巴黎和会上无甚作为。直到第二次世界大战后，美国彻底取代英国成为世界头号霸主，同时接手其在中东的势力，成为现代以色列建国后最坚实的盟友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《贝尔福宣言》的公布，连同被曝光的《赛克斯-皮科协定》，在阿拉伯世界点燃了愤怒之火。在开罗，一向温顺的埃及穆斯林民众爆发了群体性抗议行动。叙利亚流亡者也越来越担心未来将有一个犹太国家会强加给巴勒斯坦地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汉志国王侯赛因在阿拉伯半岛的最大对手伊本·沙特借此发起新一轮舆论猛攻。伊本·沙特来自控制内志地区的沙特家族，代表着伊斯兰教复古主义势力——瓦哈比教派。他一直有雄心一统阿拉伯半岛。他对外宣称：侯赛因国王是西方基督教的傀儡。但事实上，他本人也依赖于大英帝国殖民分支英属印度的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿拉伯世界的强烈反弹，让英国大为不安。他们向侯赛因施压，要求他公开表态支持。克莱顿则要求劳伦斯去向费萨尔做劝说工作，尽管劳伦斯一直反对英国政府和犹太人之间的协定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年3月，在英国人的陪同下，由魏茨曼带队的“犹太复国主义委员会”对埃及、巴勒斯坦地区进行访问。在埃及，他向英国人、流亡的叙利亚人展开魅力攻势，一再表达犹太复国主义事业的善意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该年6月4日，魏茨曼又亲自到亚喀巴拜访费萨尔。会面气氛十分融洽，魏茨曼甚至带上了阿拉伯头巾；费萨尔则避免做出任何实质性承诺，推说一切决定权都在他父亲那里。劳伦斯找借口避开了，不管上司如何来电施压。他已判定：英国人强加的和谐，只会使得费萨尔和老侯赛因在阿拉伯世界遭到更大的反对声浪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10天后在埃及，他还是见到了魏茨曼。这位世故练达的犹太政治领袖很清楚：和阿拉伯起义领袖是否能达成谅解，关键就在于这位娃娃脸的小个子英国军官。高手过招，也生出了惺惺相惜——劳伦斯也很佩服魏茨曼的玲珑手腕，一面相当成功地消解了阿拉伯人的担忧，一面又用另一套言辞激发犹太人的斗志。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个聪明人达成一个共识——如果犹太人希望能在巴勒斯坦建立一个“民族家园”，就必须先让英国人打赢这场战争，这也就意味着他们应该先支持阿拉伯人的起义。魏茨曼还主动提出一项颇具诱惑力的“支持”：让国际犹太复国主义运动组织来资助阿拉伯独立事业，包括资金、武器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;魏茨曼的魅力攻势取得了成效，他说服了大多数曾因《贝尔福宣言》而对巴勒斯坦未来感到担忧的英国官员，让他们相信：在巴勒斯坦，犹太社区可以和人口占多数的阿拉伯人在政治上和经济上共同生活、和谐相处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让上司们高兴的是，劳伦斯对犹太复国主义运动似乎不再那么抵触。但他也没有这么天真。在一份秘密报告中，他犀利地指出了这位犹太领袖的真实愿景——“50年之后犹太人将完全控制巴勒斯坦，而当前的目标是犹太人在英国幌子之下控制巴勒斯坦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1930年代，希特勒在德国上台后，纳粹党徒对犹太人进行惨绝人寰的种族大屠杀，摧毁了欧洲多数犹太族群，犹太复国主义运动因此高涨，于1948年达到顶峰。当年5月14日，现代以色列正式建国，魏茨曼为首任总统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一切比劳伦斯预见的还早了20年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;徒劳的最后一搏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年7月，劳伦斯开始策划耽搁许久的阿拉伯起义军北上叙利亚作战。随着事态发展，他越发清楚一个道理：只有在阿拉伯人自己解放的地区，他们的独立才能得到保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在劳伦斯万般促成之下，安曼和约旦河以西聚集起一支由阿拉伯部族武装、阿拉伯北方军士兵、英法顾问和专门的炮兵、装甲车单位组成的混合部队，人数为几千人。一同到场的，还有重要的起义领袖：费萨尔、奥达，以及沙拉昂在内的主要部落酋长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大战前夕，传来一个令人心碎的噩耗——劳伦斯在卡尔基米什时期的伙伴、爱人达霍姆，那个有着灿烂笑容的叙利亚少年死于一场肆虐于叙利亚北部的伤寒疫情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《智慧七柱》的扉页上，他写下一首献给达霍姆的情诗：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我爱你，故我将这千军万马掬于手中/在繁星灿烂的天空里写下我的心愿，去为你赢来自由…/当我长驱直入，你的眼睛将因此熠熠生辉…/你的微笑令其（死神）妒从悲起，抛下我，将你掳走，囚入他死寂的幽冥。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对劳伦斯而言，对达霍姆的爱，是他为阿拉伯人赢得自由和独立的最初动力。当梦想即将实现，爱人已逝，一种巨大的痛苦和虚空感把他压倒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战争还在继续。 1918年9月，劳伦斯从英军司令部得到命令：让阿拉伯人彻底切断德拉以南的铁路线，但不可以北上冲向大马士革，以配合英军在约旦河西岸的北上行动。他们也转达对费萨尔的暗示：如果阿拉伯人在这个关键时候保持忠诚，将会得到很好的补偿，甚至将会允许他在大马士革建立一个政府。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得到政府的口头保证后，劳伦斯在德拉一带领导、发动了对汉志铁路最凶猛的袭击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月27日，在德拉附近那个给劳伦斯留下过严重创伤的名叫塔法斯的村镇，他和阿拉伯部队看到了一支撤退下来的同盟国军团留下的暴行：到处是残缺不全的尸体，姑娘和妇女们则裸露着带血污的身体，显然是被奸杀；在一堵矮墙上，倒着一具被刺刀穿透的裸身孕妇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯随后下令：不接受任何俘虏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;屠杀进行了一整夜，延续到第二天，共有四千多名被俘的同盟国士兵死于杀戮，是为“一战”中著名的“塔法斯屠杀”。次日清晨，劳伦斯进入德拉镇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位英军将领率部稍晚赶到这里，他目睹的是肮脏、野蛮和残忍，阿拉伯战士如何折磨、打劫医护列车上痛苦呻吟着的土耳其病员，“任何一个普通的文明人都无法忍受这样的惨景”。当他向劳伦斯控诉时，劳伦斯平静温和地告诉他：这就是阿拉伯人的“战争观念”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过德拉之战，奥斯曼军队已经全线崩溃。艾伦比将军给费萨尔发来热情洋溢的贺信说：“我向殿下表达我的祝愿，以及我对于您部队伟大成就的诚挚祝贺……多亏了我们的共同努力，现在土军正全线溃退。”他随后下令：把首先攻入大马士革的荣誉留给费萨尔的军队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年10月3日，在大马士革维多利亚饭店，英军总司令艾伦比和费萨尔会面了。劳伦斯充当翻译。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦比将军宣布：阿拉伯人作为参战国的地位，得到协约国承认；在叙利亚独立问题上，费萨尔没有选择，法国将成为保护叙利亚的“宗主国”；费萨尔作为侯赛因国王的代表，“将拥有叙利亚的管辖权”，但是“在法国的指导和财政支持下”，且他的管辖权“仅限于叙利亚内地”，不包括巴勒斯坦和黎巴嫩；法国将给费萨尔配一名联络官，他将与劳伦斯一同工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯和费萨尔惊呆了。费萨尔一开始激烈反对，但在艾伦比的施压下，最终只得屈从。在疲惫和失望中，劳伦斯转而向将军告假。将军最终同意了。次日，他离开了大马士革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;谈判桌上的溃败&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年12月，巴黎和会召开之前，英国首相劳合·乔治与法国总理乔治·克里孟梭用了五分钟就中东愿景达成一致意见：英国人控制美索不达米亚和巴勒斯坦；法国人则有权处置叙利亚。除了《赛克斯-皮科协定》的基本结构被确定外，他们还大大超越了它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴黎和会上，身着阿拉伯长袍的劳伦斯担任费萨尔的顾问，为阿拉伯独立事业继续奔走，以翻译身份参与演讲和谈判，组织新闻发布会以及引导报纸舆论。这给同在会场的著名历史学家阿诺德·J·汤因比留下难以磨灭的印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，恼怒万分的克里孟梭去英国代表团那里告了劳伦斯一状，并把这个年轻人叫来当面训斥。有“猛虎”绰号的法国总理劈头盖脸地问：“劳伦斯上校，你知道自从十字军东征以来，法国在叙利亚就有利益吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯回答：“是的。我知道。但是叙利亚人打败了十字军，我们永远不会忘了这一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;克里孟梭被驳得哑口无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个饱受折磨的灵魂。我觉得劳伦斯在巴黎时已经意识到，尽管他在阿拉伯事业上取得了很多成功，但仍没有赢得胜利。”汤因比写道. “这让劳伦斯很苦恼，但痛苦并没有消磨掉他的幽默感，他有点伟大，还有点调皮。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英法的勾兑，摧毁了劳伦斯发下誓言为之奋斗的理想——阿拉伯人的民族独立。而对大英帝国的大人物们，“英雄劳伦斯”已经成为一个麻烦。在一份备忘录上，他们称其为“有害影响”，“很大程度上是我们与法国在叙利亚问题上麻烦的根源”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯最终被剥夺了参加巴黎和会的资格，同时被禁止在会议上协助费萨尔。他输掉了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，他仍做出一个堪称了不起的努力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1918年12月巴黎和会前夕，在他促成下，作为阿拉伯世界代表的费萨尔和犹太复国主义运动领袖魏茨曼拟定一份联合声明，宣布双方的合作意愿.其中第四条为：“应采取一切必要措施，鼓励和促进犹太人向巴勒斯坦大规模移民”，然后是一个关键性条件句——该协定“仅在叙利亚区独立的情形下有效；如果不满足这个条件，就完全无效。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，费萨尔还友好地谈到阿拉伯人和犹太人之间的“种族亲缘关系和古老纽带”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在巴勒斯坦地区，水火不容的阿拉伯人和犹太复国主义者也曾携手起来想建立一个阿拉伯-犹太人的联合国家。然而，劳伦斯的努力真有现实可能性吗？ ——如果他在1918年成功了，一个独立的泛阿拉伯国家会因此诞生吗？如果历史如费萨尔和魏茨曼之间协议的那样发生了，阿以/巴以会彼此和谐地相处吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为和劳伦斯相隔一个世纪的后人，我很难乐观——纵观中东现代史，每回出现和解的曙光，都会有极端势力发起针对性的暗杀、破坏行动。在遇害者名单上，有侯赛因次子、约旦首任国王阿卜杜拉，埃及总统萨达特，推动“以土地换和平”的以色列总理拉宾……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现代中东的诞生——划定疆域、拥立国王之人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1919年秋的巴黎和会上，失去劳伦斯帮助后，费萨尔不得不接受法国人给出的条件。等回到大马士革，他发现自己被谴责为向欧洲帝国主义出卖祖国的叛徒。他转而利用民众的愤怒，于1920年撕毁了与法国人的协议，发动一场宫廷政变，自立为大叙利亚国王。同年4月，叙利亚被托管给法国。 7月，法国在麦塞隆战役中获胜，费萨尔流亡英国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，历史走向了另一条轨迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;控制了叙利亚地区的法国也没有好日子过——阿卜杜拉从外约旦对他们发动持续、凶狠的进攻。让英国人头痛的则更多：在巴勒斯坦地区，巴勒斯坦人和犹太定居者之间的冲突不断升级；在美索不达米亚，反英起义揭竿而起，到处都是流血和对抗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年，前海军大臣温斯顿·丘吉尔复出，后在劳合·乔治内阁转任殖民大臣。他向被打入冷宫的劳伦斯发出邀约，请他担任中东事务部负责人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;心灰意冷的劳伦斯推说自己忙于写回忆录，对政治再无过问的兴趣。丘吉尔于是再三保证：在即将召开的开罗会议上，授予他几乎完全自由的权力，以帮助英国重新塑造中东棋盘上属于英国的那一部分。劳伦斯答应了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他对一位传记作者透露：1921年3月的开罗会议只是走了一个过场，他和丘吉尔在会前“不仅确定了会议将审议哪些问题，还确定了将会达成何种决议”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据决议，英国将它所控制的两块前奥斯曼帝国领土交给哈希姆家族。双方同意：费萨尔王子成为美索不达米亚新国家国王，即伊拉克王国；他的兄长阿卜杜拉王子则统治约旦河以东、由部分巴勒斯坦组成的新国家，即今天的约旦王国. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这基于劳伦斯一直为之奋斗的两个想法：首先，阿拉伯人必须获得对自己土地的控制权。其次，被赋予这种权力的阿拉伯人，是起义领袖哈希姆家族成员：侯赛因国王和他的儿子们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳伦斯的努力，为中东地区带来一段时间和平，也部分兑现了他对阿拉伯人在大起义时的承诺。一般认为：在1921年的开罗会议上，劳伦斯的作用大过了丘吉尔——最终，他真的成为了在中东地区划定疆域、拥立君王的那个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在安纳托利亚地区，前奥斯曼将领穆斯塔法·凯末尔带领土耳其民族主义者，把所有企图瓜分者打得落花流水。 1923年，他和协约国签订条约，确定了现代土耳其的疆域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南方，汉志国王侯赛因拒绝接受中东的现实政治，即使劳伦斯也无力说服。他的顽固和反复无常，最终让英国政府感到厌烦。老对头伊本·沙特利用了这一矛盾，于1924年带领瓦哈比战士逼近麦加。在众叛亲离之下，侯赛因避难塞浦路斯，后到新约旦首都安曼和次子阿卜杜拉团聚。 1931年6月，侯赛因去世，安葬于耶路撒冷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赢家伊本·沙特吞并汉志后，建立沙特阿拉伯王国。 1927年，英国人宣布承认其独立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过短暂的和平后，新的动荡又开始了。 1946年，法国人最终被迫放弃大叙利亚地区，但又从中分割出一个新国家——黎巴嫩。 1958年，伊拉克民族主义者发动军事政变，推翻了亲英政权，费萨尔独子费萨尔二世被处决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年代，西方殖民主义时代落下了帷幕。因为拥有占全世界六成的石油资源，中东如同被咒诅一般，继续成为地缘政治中最不安宁的角落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“当死神追上了我”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1921年，当劳伦斯在为丘吉尔奔走效力时，他给一位朋友写信说：“阿拉伯人就像是我翻过的一页，续集是我很讨厌的东西”。一战后，他一直患有严重的创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）,不断受到噩梦惊扰，多次陷于严重的抑郁，甚至萌生过自杀的念头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1920年起，劳伦斯根据笔记和回忆，重写自传，完成战争回忆录《智慧七柱》。他用手摇印刷机印了8本，分赠好友。后应公众的强烈要求，他做出妥协，在1926年出版了该书的删节版，同时又发行了大众版《沙漠中的起义》，后者取得了市场成功。劳伦斯把版税全部捐给慈善组织，并拒绝有生之年再版《智慧七柱》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他再也无法回归到一个学者的往日生活。 1922年，结束了在英政府殖民部的任职后，他化名约翰·休姆·罗斯，以普通列兵的身份加入英国皇家空军，但很快就被新闻界所发现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他又改名为托马斯·爱德华·肖，继续在军队服役，逃避对他穷追不舍的报界和公众。在生命的最后十多年，他过着离群索居的生活，用各种借口推掉朋友们的邀请，即使是最亲近的朋友。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成为伊拉克国王的费萨尔跟劳伦斯后来又见过两次，一次是1925年，面对曾经并肩作战的生死之交，劳伦斯无所适从，二人一度相顾无言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1933年费萨尔访英时再次提出要见劳伦斯，劳伦斯态度消极，后来费萨尔不得不借助军方的命令，才得以见到“列兵肖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1935年5月13日，劳伦斯骑着摩托车，去博文顿军营发一份电报。回程途中，遭遇一起交通事故。在部队医院昏迷六天后，于5月19日清晨去世，时年46岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“二战”阴云逼近，正陷于“困惑岁月”的丘吉尔前来悼念，写下一段政治家才有真正共鸣的悼词：“在我眼中，他是我们时代最伟大的人物之一……我担心，不管我们多么需要，像他这样的人都永远不会再有了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考书目及资料：《智慧七柱》T·E·劳伦斯著；《阿拉伯的劳伦斯：战争、谎言、帝国愚行和现代中东的形成》斯科特·安德森著；《交游录》阿诺德·J·汤因比著；Clio数字化历史博物馆网站。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[无尽的纷争：雷颐的2023年读书小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261708]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;以读书写作为业，2023年当然也读了不少书。如果用一个标题概括这一年的读与思，最恰当的应是其中一本书的书名：“无尽的纷争。”现实的冲突、战争，引发了从国际到国内“读书界”，或者说知识界、思想界的巨大纷争。惟愿这种纷争，带来的是更深刻的讨论和思想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/44ac2e1b69.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;朱正：《拾零新集》，花城出版社，2023年6月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;朱正先生是改革开放之后“破土而出”的编辑大家、文史大家，早先以编辑为主，后来以写作为主。 Editing, writing, writing editors, complement each other, make him a literary history everyone. His essays often have the sharp and sharp text, but there are many historical facts that are lacking. The &quot;Zero New Collection&quot; launched by Huacheng Publishing House brought together his main essays from 1987 to 2021. It was only in his early 200,000 words, but the chapters were based on solid historical materials. These dozens of essays constitute part of the history of contemporary culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/a2bc20a0b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[美]理查德·派普斯：《旧制度下的俄国》，民主建设出版社，2023年5月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;俄罗斯是横跨欧亚的大国，以俄罗斯为主体的“苏联”，曾是世界上两个超级大国之一，对世界产生了Tremendous influence.如此庞大的国家，形成并不算久。它不是欧洲国家，但也不是亚洲国家，独特的文化和辽阔的国土，形成了自己的统治模式、政治、经济制度。 《旧制度下的俄国》梳理了9世纪到19世纪80年代俄罗斯的演变，对复杂的历史作了清晰的描述与深刻的分析。理解它的过去，才能更深刻地理解它的今天与未来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/5ba0a22093.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260429&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;林辉煌：《花村肖像：转型中国的农民生活》，东方出版社2023年8月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“美丽乡村”是国家推进的重大农村建设工程，是精准扶贫的重要步骤。 “花村”本是个普通村庄，但被选为美丽乡村建设示范点后，社会生态发生重大变化，瞬间迎来了大量的项目资金。 《花村肖像：转型中国的农民生活》以真实的农村为案例，在个案研究中讨论了中国农村在发展中遇到的一些常见问题。作者通过讲述不同农民的故事，展开对不同主题的探讨，涉及种田、打工、机械耕种、作物种植冒险、农家乐、农业产业化、乡村治理、乡村振兴等方面。核心问题是，这些项目资金大多被用于县乡政府感兴趣的大事，而不是广大农民真正感兴趣的大事，这是为什么？形成这种局面的机理是什么。作者的提问，引人深思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/78109dddb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[美]沃尔特·艾萨克森：《基辛格传》，中信出版社2023年9月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2018年，中信出版社出版了美国历史学家弗格森的《基辛格：理想主义者》，对基辛格的早期思想作了研究，我写过书评，对从前了解无多的基氏早年思想，有所了解。今年，中信出版社又推出了美国著名传记作家艾萨克森的《基辛格传》，我感兴趣的，仍是基辛格的早年经历。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;基辛格是犹太难民，1938年11岁时随家人从德国逃往美国。此前，他在德国菲尔特市受到歧视、迫害，年幼的他感到不可理解。菲尔特市不大，全城除犹太孩子，几乎全是“希特勒青年团”成员，他和弟弟站在街头，看到他们身穿制服，列队高歌，步伐整齐地游行，不明白自己为什么无权参加。相反，他和弟弟还处处受到嘲讽奚落，不久就不能去游泳池不能去跳舞不能去茶馆……越来越多的地方有“犹太人禁入”的牌子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;移民美国后，父母给人打工，收入不高，基辛格在高中读了一年书，就不得不改读“夜校”，白天打工，晚上学习。他的工作，是在一家亲戚开的剃须刷厂上班，戴着厚厚的橡胶手套，挤净毛刷上的溶液和水。周薪11美元，后来升级为派送员，负责送货，周薪涨到30美元。同事回忆说，他工作时往往心不在焉，一有机会就看书或做夜校的作业。他的早年经历，颇为“励志”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;痛苦的童年经历，对他产生了刻骨铭心的影响。 “对基辛格而言，大屠杀破坏了神的旨意与历史进步之间的联系——这是犹太教的核心信念，是犹太教对西方哲学最重要的贡献。对有信仰的犹太人来说，历史的意义应该从它与神的旨意及天理之间的联系来理解。但在目睹纳粹的恶行后，基辛格就摒弃了犹太教信仰。在哈佛就读时，这位年轻学子就开始从学术方面探究寻找历史意义的其他方法。”他内在的学术“模块”始终是欧洲的而不是美国的，对康德、黑格尔、梅特涅、陀思妥耶夫斯基都很喜欢，但从未对代表美国创造力的原型人物，如马克·吐温、杰斐逊、富兰克林等表示过欣赏。童年经历，形成了他的基本思想：追求秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1588&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/49220d026c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;[美]佩里·米勒：《无尽的纷争：从革命到内战时期的美国思想生活》，东方出版社2023年7月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;近年来，东方出版社策划出版了“美国文明经典译丛”，丛书主编、中国社会科学院外文所研究员钱满素是改革开放后第一批留美学生，在哈佛大学学习美国文明史。这套丛书，选目精当，《无尽的纷争：从革命到内战时期的美国思想生活》是其中一种。此书于1965年出版，荣获1966年普利策历史奖，是米勒在《美国精神生活：17世纪》和《美国精神生活：从殖民地到行省》之后又一部宏大的美国思想史巨著.这本书出版近一甲子，经过时间的检验，成为经典。在这本著作中，米勒试图把握美国文化的宗教根源，阐述宗教精神与自由精神这两者在其他地方常常相互对立，但在美国却几乎融合在一起的原因。宗教与世俗的矛盾、冲突是世界性难题，在全球化时代，一百多年前的历史，能给人启发吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 09:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[六名中国公民被绑架杀害？海外华人华侨要团结以自保]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月11日，菲律宾警方在内湖湾一片建筑工地附近地区，连续发现多具遗体，警方怀疑为10月30日被绑架的6名中国公民：其中包括在菲当地华人慈善组织担任会长的曾先生夫妻二人、曾兄夫妻二人，以及曾兄年仅十余岁的儿子，还有一人身份不明。 On November 28, the Philippine police confirmed the identity of the 4 corpses, including the two brothers Zeng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近些年来，在海外一些国家发生了涉及华人华侨的恶性案件：2023年5月，中国情侣裸死巴厘岛酒店；2023年“3·31”中国留学生泰国遇害案……在这些凶残个案之外，缅北军阀的犯罪体系基本就是针对国人量身定制，其残害的国人数量之多、罪行之严重，真可谓罄竹难书。近期，专营电信诈骗的缅北“明氏家族”已到穷途末路、即将覆灭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着国家的经济发展，对外经济贸易和文化交流增多，海内外华人与世界的交往越来越多。而机遇永远伴随着挑战，矛盾、冲突、危险无处不在，如何确保自己的人身和财产安全，以及合法权利，变得越来越重要。海外华人华侨的自我安防、集体安全之典范，可以参详侨居北美的韩族群，以及散居于世界各地的犹太族群。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国人口本就不多，旅居世界的更少。但少量韩裔移民（主要是来自韩国的移民），却成为1992年“洛杉矶暴动”中的一缕亮色：美国警方暂时放弃对有色人种社区的保护之后，少量韩裔移民团结起来、武装自卫，拿起武器据守社区，抵抗暴徒冲击，一直坚守到国民警卫队进城平暴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几十年来，韩国人深深感到团结对外的重要性，其海外移民强化了内部团结，利用北美公民持枪的法律，武装自卫、强化尚武精神。所以，尽管165万韩族移民仅占美国人口的0.5%，但北美居民都知道韩人不好惹、危急时刻他们敢动枪。因此，“洛杉矶暴动”的暴徒们无法攻克韩人武装坚守的据点，便洗劫了华人的商店，因为华人在当时普遍缺乏自卫能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;犹太族群，在二战之前以不团结、一盘散沙、精明善财、斯文懦弱而著称。犹太自古有12支系之说，下面的派系、小团体多如牛毛，经营钱庄的犹太人贪财好利、不愿帮助他人，因此，也就很少有人愿意帮助他们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为更好融入欧洲社会，犹太不但接受了西方许多生活习惯，且在与原住民发生矛盾时尽量避免对抗。故此，长久以来欧洲各族群对犹太的武力值嗤之以鼻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二次大战，纳粹德国的大屠杀，将欧洲犹太近乎灭族，这改变了部分犹太人的精神、性格、心理。战后，部分犹太人形成了几项共识：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，要建立自己的国家，并使之强大，而不能只做世界游民。当再次发生涉及犹太族群的冲突时，所依靠的不能仅有金钱，背后要有国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，依然要保持犹太在世界各地的同时存在，以分散生存风险，以防一国战败、全族被灭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，仅有金钱是不够的，要生存，就要有自卫能力。 “富强”二字缺一不可，不富，就买不起先进武器装备、无法组建强大军队，就不可能强；不强，就不可能恒久地保住财富。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，犹太人在世界各地的许多社区都有自卫组织。尤其在北美，充分利用当地的法律和政策，进行准军事化训练，拥有相当多外籍储备兵员。 2023年10月7日，加沙战事爆发后几小时，就有北美和澳洲大批犹太青年飞往以色列参战，总计人数上万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;犹太通过艰辛努力，一定程度改变了自己族群之前一盘散沙、内斗不止、互相拆台的习俗（但其现代派系和“极端正统派”之间，仍泾渭分明）。不但在全世界搞“藏兵于民”，而且形成了联通世界的地下情报网络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列毕竟是仅几百万人口的袖珍微型国家，其情报机构“摩萨德”没有（CIA那样）充足资金。尤其在初建和发展阶段早期，堪称捉襟见肘，甚至穷得掉渣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年，抓捕纳粹战犯埃希曼；1970年代，在全球追杀“黑九月”恐怖组织。 “摩萨德”只能派出规模很小的别动队，且预算拮据，每人每天仅几美元伙食经费，住不起酒店、买不起汽车。他们在世界各地活动，都住在当地犹太人提供的旧房子里，有的连床都没有，只能打地铺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那点活动经费，不但下不起饭店，连外卖都点不起。只好把钱交给当地犹太联络人，由他们代为从商场购买食材，自己开火做饭。 “摩萨德”特工根本不可能像谍战电影里那样，潇洒地开着Aston Martin跑车，多次行动所用车辆，都是借用当地犹太人的旧车。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与韩族和犹太在世界上建立自己势力网络初期那种草台班子相比，现在华人在世界各地的人员数量、拥有的财富，实在是强得太多了。但很可惜，拥有巨大财富的华人侨民，甚至都难以有效保护自己的人身安全和财产安全，世界各地的恶意排华、针对华人侨民的犯罪屡有发生。而前文所述的大量针对华人的暴力犯罪，不少有华人歹徒参与其中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这实在令人感到遗憾和痛心，究其原因，海外华人侨民的依然存在内斗现象，力量内耗严重。有北美的华人朋友，绘声绘色地跟我讲如何在商业上互相拆台、在文化上相互攻讦，甚至勾结“鬼佬Cap（外国警察）”整对方。说者津津有味、眉飞色舞、手舞足蹈，兴奋时，唾沫星子都喷到我脸上，这实在是令人心痛的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如前文所述，海内外华人与世界的交往越来越多，矛盾、冲突、危险无处不在，如何确保自己的人身和财产安全，以及合法权利，变得越来越重要。这一切的基础，首先是族群自身团结，在这方面，我们真应该好好想一想了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>