<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[那些在互联网买“情绪”的年轻人，拜托醒醒吧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259422]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/a7605c3b1df672a8ea3cc792da571f45.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;957&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/27/a7605c3b1df672a8ea3cc792da571f45.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / picture）&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many people may have heard the melody of &quot;love trading&quot;, but they don&#39;t know that there is also a business of &quot;emotional trading&quot; now. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Emotional Tree Hole&quot;, &quot;Good Luck Spray&quot;, &quot;Scolding to Awaken Love Brain&quot;, &quot;Virtual Mosquito&quot;, &quot;Einstein&#39;s Brain&quot;... Nowadays, many young people are keen on As for purchasing emotional products online, there are more and more emotional products that can be purchased for just a few dollars. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, when you have an emotional breakdown, you can buy a chat service online, talk to strangers, complain a few words, and your negative emotions seem to be released; place an order for a &quot;Virtual Mosquito&quot; , there will be sellers role-playing who will &quot;buzz&quot; you from time to time; after breaking up, buy a copy of &quot;Scolding to Awaken Your Love Brain&quot;, and strangers will be your &quot;chat partners&quot; and treat you rationally and rationally. Move with emotion...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why are young people keen on buying emotions on the Internet? Can buying emotions really provide emotional value? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Young people are “emo” &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Behind the purchasing emotions are the emotions of many young people Emotion has encountered some &quot;problems&quot;. To use a popular word nowadays, it is &quot;emo&quot;. Emo was selected as the Internet Word of the Year in 2021. In this year alone, Bilibili users sent &quot;emo&quot; barrages 3.3 million times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;emo&quot; comes from the English word &quot;emotion&quot;, which means emotion. In the 1990s, &quot;emotional hardcore&quot; appeared in the field of European and American pop music, which is a kind of rock music with delicate emotions, melancholy and sentimentality. After being simplified to &quot;emo&quot;, emo also has colors such as impulsiveness, sensitivity, and melancholy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Emo, which is now a popular vocabulary, continues this core and emotional color, representing the decadent, frustrated, speechless and puzzled mood of young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Emo has become a popular word not only because of the principle of &quot;language economics&quot; - this short word accurately summarizes the mentality of young people, and it is not just popular. The &quot;herding effect&quot; in the spread of vocabulary - you use it for other people and I use it for you. What&#39;s more, emo is indeed a universal emotion of the times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Emo is a new variant of the previously popular words such as &quot;Buddhist&quot;, &quot;mourning&quot; and &quot;lying flat&quot;. It is related to some new changes of the times. For example, in the post-epidemic era, the global economy is recovering slowly and the economic downturn has put young people under greater work pressure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many people feel very tired under the &quot;involution&quot;; in the busy urban life, many young people do not have much time to socialize and stay in rental houses after work Here, they will inevitably feel lonely and cold as &quot;empty-nest youths&quot;... In addition to these universal dilemmas, young people also have different and specific confusions in their own lives, which more or less affect their emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In short, young people can emo about everything. I can&#39;t find a job, I&#39;m emo; I&#39;m under great pressure at work, I&#39;m emo; I have a conflict with my partner, I&#39;m emo; I&#39;m single and have no partner, I&#39;m emo; I&#39;m not ready for the exam, I&#39;m emo; my plan was rejected by Party A, I&#39;m emo...&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Compared with words such as mourning and lying down, emo has a hint of self-deprecation of joy in suffering. It is not so negative and pessimistic, but after complaining about &quot;I am really emo&quot; , will still clean up the mess of life and move on. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The comfort of &quot;emotional value&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After emo, you still have to embrace life. Therefore, young people will work hard to calm down their emotions faster and satisfy their emotional needs. They will seek &quot;emotional value.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, what is emotional value? Simply put, emotional value = positive emotion (benefit) - negative emotion (cost). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether a thing or a person has emotional value lies in its ability to bring positive emotional power to people, such as making people feel happy, secure, calm, and warm. , healing... In other words, emotional value is the ability to have a positive impact on our emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be companionship, sharing, listening, encouragement... In the end, it becomes a kind of comfort for emo emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On social media, young people also often use words closely related to emotional value, such as &quot;emotional stability&quot;, which has become the first criterion for many young people to choose a partner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;An emotionally stable partner can always handle things calmly and calmly, without losing control, without blaming each other, and without blaming each other, but working hard to solve problems. A partner who is emotionally stable will naturally bring strong emotional value to others - you will be wrapped in a sense of security, and no matter how chaotic the world is, there will be someone walking hand in hand with you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With this background, we can understand why many young people buy emotions on the Internet. What they essentially buy is &quot;emotional value.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If a person has no motivation to study, just join the &quot;virtual study room&quot;, and everyone will study together to have more atmosphere; if you want an illusion of good luck, buy &quot;Good &quot;Yuck Koi&quot;; if you want to get rid of loneliness and gain a sense of companionship, you can place an order for &quot;Virtual Mosquito&quot;, where a seller will role-play a mosquito and &quot;buzz&quot; you from time to time; buy it after a breakup A &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; is not so much about scolding you as it is about accompanying you, talking to you, and listening to you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/66f81e258e4ce4cd84843e25edeb22f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/66f81e258e4ce4cd84843e25edeb22f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255731 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Not want to buy Just buy it&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is human nature that people like people and things that can provide high emotional value. Keen merchants have also seized this business opportunity - young people need emotional value, and I will sell emotional value. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The question is, can you really buy emotional value if you want to? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If emotional value was such an easy thing to obtain, it wouldn’t be so scarce. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As mentioned above, emotional value is a kind of &quot;ability&quot;. It must really hit your emo point, bring you strength, comfort and help you. You transcend that depression. This is not something you can achieve by typing in a dialog box and the other party saying a few words of chicken soup for the soul; it is not something you can achieve by buying a &quot;Good Luck Koi&quot; or &quot;Einstein&#39;s Brain&quot; and you will be blessed with divine help. Falling from the sky; it’s not the other party “inciting emotions”, you will be emotionally liberated...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, those &quot;sell&quot; products on the Internet for a few cents or a few dollars &quot;Emotion&quot; is just a gimmick. The sellers do not have the quality and ability to provide emotional value. They are even more routine and perfunctory than the customer service of some merchants. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What young people buy is only a few minutes of freshness, which brings a few minutes of fun to the emo mood. Once the freshness is over, the emo is still the emo, and the problem has not been solved. If so, it&#39;s still not resolved. It&#39;s OK to think of &quot;emotional trading&quot; as a joke, but if you take it seriously, you may be deceived and make you more emo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the final analysis, if there is no one or thing to rely on, then the only one who can bring positive emotional value to yourself is yourself. If you haven&#39;t studied for a long time and feel that you have fallen, you will feel emo, and you think that joining the &quot;virtual study room&quot; will give you motivation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, such heteronomy is in vain. If you have more self-discipline and complete the goals you set every day, you will feel real happiness the moment you complete it - the better. Self-discipline brings freedom; if you don’t work hard at ordinary times, you will feel emo before the exam. You think buying a &quot;good luck koi&quot; will bring you good luck, but you still won’t during the exam. If you study hard and concentrate on preparing for the exam, you will Your hard work will be reflected in the exam, and what you gain is a real sense of solidity and accomplishment...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After all, the value of emotions cannot be bought just because you want to buy them. Buying emotions is a pleasure. Yes, but getting out of emo cannot rely solely on spiritual victory. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《芭蕾舞复仇曲》：韩影越来越套路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259234]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Among the new generation of Korean actresses, all Zhong Rui is an alternative existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She made her fortune in Li Cangdong&#39;s &quot;Burning&quot;. She stood out from thousands of auditions and performed a large-scale role in her first screen role. The cunning and alienation on Jeon Jong-seo&#39;s face, her inadvertent dodge, and a hint of cowardice constitute her rich facial aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her new work &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot;, she once again demonstrates this highly recognizable performance style. This is her second collaboration with emerging director Li Chongxian. The first time the two worked together was in the 2020 crime suspense film &quot;The Call&quot;, which caused heated discussions among movie fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/94cb079e77d0483c939911d74b3cbf15.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/94cb079e77d0483c939911d74b3cbf15.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Ballet In &quot;Revenge Song&quot;, although Jeon Jong-seo is not as crazy as in &quot;Telephone&quot;, the girl she plays, Ok-joo, is also a mistress who is not easy to mess with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Zhu once worked as a bodyguard in a security company, specializing in protecting high-level important personnel. Her superb skills and sharp mind were fully demonstrated in the opening supermarket robbery scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f3a9ec1f3da4106b7a1d835c84f48513.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f3a9ec1f3da4106b7a1d835c84f48513.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps for a long time Maintaining a high degree of vigilance, Yuzhu had no interest in life and was full of frustration all day long until she met her old classmate Minxi. The latter&#39;s natural affinity frees Yuzhu from the boring quagmire of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to show the contrast in atmosphere, the film specially uses colorful soft light to capture the relaxed and graceful friendship between the two girls when showing Minxi taking Yuzhu to celebrate her birthday, taking headshots and relaxing on the beach. . This is in contrast to the large number of night scenes and indoor scenes throughout the film, which basically use high contrast and low-key lighting to create dangerous and uneasy situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eeaf31229575a54a62fa9148e156c55f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;447&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eeaf31229575a54a62fa9148e156c55f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The turning point of the story , appeared when Minxi suddenly committed suicide, leaving a last word hoping that Yuzhu would help her take revenge. After Yuzhu followed the clues and found a man named &quot;Chef Cui&quot;, she discovered that Minxi&#39;s suicide had a lot to do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The many &quot;SM&quot; props in Chef Cui&#39;s home, as well as the large number of classified USB flash drives in the cabinet, all show that in the process of &quot;hunting for beauty&quot;, he often uses perverted methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0d1f535dabea0dc186b64630653fd1d4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;444&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0d1f535dabea0dc186b64630653fd1d4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And Minxi , after being targeted by Chef Cui, he was drugged and raped while being filmed on video. Chef Cui did this not only to satisfy his abnormal desires, but also to threaten girls like Minxi through videos and force them to &quot;accept customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This crime chain is not the work of Chef Cui alone. He also has a pharmacist who regularly cooperates with him, so he can succeed every time with drugs such as &quot;obedient water&quot;; his subordinates also run a peach store. Hotels specialize in soliciting prostitutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6d74c7ae51907124c4f2612d454f78b0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6d74c7ae51907124c4f2612d454f78b0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the most disappointing thing What people are afraid of is the power behind Chef Cui. Furthermore, Chef Cui, who looks vicious on the surface, is just a small leader of a gang organization, and behind this is a huge black industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3b9fa39ae346614fe6e4adea29bae5a6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;585&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3b9fa39ae346614fe6e4adea29bae5a6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9588ac4b4e3c43c214228f05c4f44c86.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;581&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9588ac4b4e3c43c214228f05c4f44c86.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This setting in &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot; comes from The &quot;Room N&quot; case caused a lot of controversy in South Korea in the past few years. The prisoner in the case, Zhao Zhubin, established a paid &quot;room&quot; on an online platform and used the threatened girls as bargaining chips to profit from it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s just that this film introduces gangster forces and makes sexual crimes bottomless, in order to amplify this despair and anger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some time ago, &quot;The Voice of Freedom&quot;, which was adapted from real events, brought to the table the rarely mentioned child abduction and sex trafficking. Although the quality of the film is not good, its discussion of this topic is worthy of recognition. It allows us to see a criminal phenomenon that is deep underground and widespread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back in &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot;, as Yuzhu deepens her investigation into Chef Cui and the organization behind him, she also only avenges her best friend at the beginning, but gradually transforms into avenging the victimized woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/268593f73416414dfafc55f5eebe2d6a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/268593f73416414dfafc55f5eebe2d6a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, The killing scenes and action scenes have become the second highlight of this film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Jeon Jong-seo cannot rely on physical confrontation and impact to create visual stimulation like Stallone and Jason Statham, nor can he use real kung fu techniques like Jet Li and Donnie Yen. Show off a pleasing figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The action design of &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot; absorbs the style of the &quot;John Wick&quot; series, that is, it gives full play to the advantages of &quot;gun-shaped&quot; action movies, allowing hot weapons and fists and kicks to be used alternately. Ammunition can create explosive scenes, and the head-on confrontation of fists, feet, knives and axes can highlight the thrilling effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49c05f887c4da2835039b1202d553252.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;447&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49c05f887c4da2835039b1202d553252.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is at the climax In the scene, Yuzhu used two pistols to fight against the entire gang, which was most obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this alone cannot make up for Jeon Jong-seo&#39;s complement in action scenes, so lens language and editing techniques have become necessary auxiliary means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quick swinging technique, the movement of the camera synchronized with the direction of the punch, and the extensive use of close-up and close-up shots, coupled with the fast and sharp editing style, make the entire movie have a clear rhythm every time it enters the action section. Accelerate and the atmosphere becomes wanton and arrogant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f93216844dc743bab519ed1dbdda4762.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;449&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f93216844dc743bab519ed1dbdda4762.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the director Li Chongxian is familiar with action films such as Hong Kong&#39;s &quot;The Fuse&quot;, Indonesia&#39;s &quot;The Raid&quot; and South Korea&#39;s &quot;Crime City&quot;, so he can create these action scenes with ease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the tilted and unbalanced camera images and the neon aesthetics with great color contrast make &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot; closer to the style of Hollywood crime films in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/78b1fd2e8b7e5919d612333b29603ec0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/78b1fd2e8b7e5919d612333b29603ec0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general In other words, the crime theme of exploiting women&#39;s bodies, good fighting scenes, and Jeon Jong-seo&#39;s character arc that is sometimes conservative and restrained, sometimes sensitive and angry, make this film have a sense of entertainment that is above the pass mark. However, when we finish watching &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot;, we can still detect its frivolity and frivolity based on big data algorithms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the character Ok-joo&#39;s emotions continue to deepen in the process of revenge, this delicate inner change relies more on Jeon Jong-seo&#39;s outstanding performance. Why did she become a bodyguard? Why are you so depressed in life? The film never explains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49aca55250b8bad1121f2886af777652.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49aca55250b8bad1121f2886af777652.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for her being Min Xi is infected and her heart gradually melts, but it is like going through the motions, and the filming is stereotyped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most puzzling thing is the pretentiousness of the underworld gang, which is strong on the outside but capable on the inside. The boss, who is full of gangster traditions, did not see anything done after he lectured Chef Cui. He neither saw through Chef Cui’s lies nor demonstrated his strategizing of the organization. Only in the contrasting section of &quot;die from talking too much&quot; does it play a role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/290aa6cfac3b8cb644611e61892284ca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/290aa6cfac3b8cb644611e61892284ca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, &quot;Ballet Revenge&quot; provides a framework for female revenge, especially in terms of revenge for best friends. It is exactly the same as the summer hit &quot;The Vanishing She&quot;. But when it comes to the specific levels of criminal psychology, social ecology, etc., it seems to be discouraged. It is not like Luo Hongzhen&#39;s &quot;Yellow Sea&quot;, which separates the dirty, angry and restless characters&#39; psychology and shows you in detail. Instead, it provides a visual pleasure for immediate consumption and caters to the public&#39;s emotional fast food. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the inevitable result of Netflix and other streaming media entering the Korean market. It has brought big data arithmetic and more routine formulas, and this may also become a trend in the next few years. , a signal of an overall decline in the quality of Korean films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳欢乐谷过山车追尾，有游客称前一天已遇故障]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259498]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 10:19:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project promotion picture. Picture from Shenzhen Happy Valley official website&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ca65ce211c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;646&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ca65ce211c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;&quot;Snowland Eagle&quot; project promotion picture. The picture comes from the official website of Shenzhen Happy Valley&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 18:27 on October 27, 2023, a vehicle collision occurred in the roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; in Happy Valley, a well-known theme park in Shenzhen, injuring 8 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was sitting on the second roller coaster at the time. The speed was very fast and the impact was very strong.&quot; At 22:17, Yu Qing, who witnessed the experience, just came out of the University of Hong Kong Shenzhen Hospital. Her test result was mild. Concussion, bruises and skin injuries on hands and feet. She recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that she didn’t know exactly what happened at the time of the incident. “I just felt that my car was sliding backwards, and finally I realized that it had hit the previous car that was discharging passengers.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At 23:25, Shenzhen Happy Valley officially issued a situation report stating that the injured have been sent to the hospital for treatment and are in stable condition with no life-threatening injuries. &quot;The cause of the incident is under investigation. The equipment has stopped operating. We will further conduct a comprehensive inspection of all equipment in the park.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the 28th, Shenzhen Happy Valley reported again that from the 28th to the 29th, The park will be closed for two days and a safety inspection of the entire park will be carried out. Visitors who have purchased tickets can receive a full refund through the original purchase channel. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Tourists said there was a &quot;system problem&quot; the day before&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I heard a loud noise at that time, and many staff members ran in and asked us to give way. We didn&#39;t know what happened at first What happened? I found out later that it was a car crash.&quot; Zhao Xin, a student who was queuing at the scene, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Xin said that several students from Shenzhen Huitong School were on the roller coaster where the accident occurred. “Several of them went up to play together. One of them had some stomach injuries because he didn’t have time to get off, and the other one It’s more serious and I passed out.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 23:00 on the 27th, a Southern Weekend reporter called the customer service of the University of Hong Kong Shenzhen Hospital. A staff member on the line said he was unclear about the situation, but said that the current queue time in the emergency department would be It&#39;s very long. &quot;There are more people waiting in the emergency department now.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Shenzhen Happy Valley, &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; has a five-star thrill level. It is a catapult roller coaster built with a huge investment of 200 million and is the tallest and longest catapult roller coaster in Asia, with a total length of 550 meters. &quot;Speed ​​up in 2 seconds, galloping at 135 kilometers per hour, falling vertically from 60 meters, heart-poundingly crazy for 90 seconds, 4G maximum acceleration, the experience of going to the sky, going to the ground, and going into the sea is thrilling to the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is It is a relatively popular event, and there were a lot of people queuing up today.&quot; Zhao Xin recalled that she had been queuing for nearly two hours. If nothing had happened, it would have been her turn to get on the next bus. Finally, she left around 19:00 At the scene, &quot;When my friend went over to play, he found that the project had been closed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, the day before the incident, Chen Yuangang played &quot;Snow Land&quot; with his friends. Eagle&quot; project. She told Southern Weekend reporters that there was a problem with the system at that time: &quot;The Snow Eagle made a loud sound when it ejected, but I didn&#39;t hear it at the time, and then I found that the car had returned to the starting position. After a while, , the roller coaster ejected again, and returned to the starting position after a normal run.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yuan recalled that the vehicle system activated the emergency protection device at that time, and tourists on the roller coaster were unable to get off. &quot;The staff used the microphone to inform the remaining people in line that there was a problem with the system and needed to be repaired, so they could not continue playing. They also issued speed passes to the remaining people in line.&quot; Chen Yuan said that everyone stayed on the stalled roller coaster again. After about ten minutes, the staff adjusted and the emergency braking mode was released and we were able to get out of the car. &quot;About two hours after the emergency repairs, Happy Valley notified Snow Eagle to resume operations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Maintenance is done every day&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Shenzhen Happy Valley has been open since 1998 and is a new generation of large-scale theme park of OCT Group. Among them, the catapult roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project was officially opened in July 2012. Its vehicle structure includes two trains (orange car and green car), each train has 6 carriages, and each carriage can accommodate 4 people. There are 24 people in the whole car and 48 people in the two cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, a rear-end collision involving an aerial sightseeing train occurred in Happy Valley. On November 1, 2018, while two &quot;Happy Main Line&quot; sightseeing trains were running over the Overseas Chinese Town tourist resort, the front train stopped due to a system failure, causing a slight rear-end collision with the rear train. There were about 20 passengers on the two trains, causing 2 People get hurt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information from the China Bidding and Bidding Public Service Platform, on March 21, 2023, Shenzhen OCT Happy Valley Tourism Company issued a bidding announcement for the overhaul service project of the Shenzhen Happy Valley Snowy Eagle Project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bidding announcement shows that the overhaul service project of Shenzhen Happy Valley&#39;s &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project includes professional evaluation of the overall operation situation, carrying out Snowy Eagle&#39;s service status evaluation, safety and reliability evaluation, large-scale Repairs, condition monitoring systems and other work will be carried out, and it will pass statutory inspections, regulatory filings, etc. The planned construction period is from April 20, 2023 to June 30, 2023. Finally, on April 25, 2023, Shenzhen Runchang Amusement Culture Group Co., Ltd. won the bid with an amount of 7.09 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have not done major repairs, we only do daily maintenance.” A person in charge of the bidding project told Southern Weekend reporters, “The daily conditions are normal and there are no problems. Maintenance is done every day. Weekly maintenance is done every week, monthly maintenance is done every month, and maintenance is done every year. It is impossible to say that there is any rust.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked about the cause of the accident, the person in charge said : &quot;Our company has a unified response to this aspect, and everything is now waiting for investigation and technical analysis.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(should be At the request of the interviewee, the interviewees in the article are all pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“美容腐败”Vs从“表哥”到低调腐败：性别偏好影响腐败模式丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, according to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, a former member of the Party Group and Vice Chairman of the Beijing Yanqing District Committee of the CPPCC Chen Guifen was expelled from the party and public office, and the suspected criminal issues will be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law. The notice specifically mentioned that Chen Guifen &quot;violated regulations in accepting gifts and arrangements for beauty activities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, expressions such as &quot;accepting beauty activities&quot; and &quot;addicted to beauty&quot; have appeared many times in official review reports on dismissed female officials. Chen Guifen&#39;s defeat this time has further brought the new term &quot;beauty corruption&quot; to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;beauty corruption&quot; refers to cases of corruption and bribery that occur due to accepting beauty activities. Among the typical cases reported in recent years, the high amount of money involved and the bizarre corruption projects of &quot;beauty corruption&quot; have been breathtaking. The former director of the Anshan Municipal Taxation Bureau Liu Guangming’s “500,000 butt plastic surgery fee”, the latter the former mayor of Manzhouli City Xu Ailian’s “150,000 yuan for a beauty needle”, and the former vice president of North China University of Technology Shen Zhili’s “single consumption of 690,000 yuan” &quot;An astonishing number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to infer from the term &quot;cosmetic corruption&quot; that certain types of corruption are indeed related to gender. Due to the different preferences of men and women, it is not difficult to understand that bribers will cater to them in a targeted manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;willfulness&quot; of power will find an outlet, just like life, to satisfy the individual desires of those who abuse power. Cash and real estate, gold and silver jewelry, luxury cars and watches, antique calligraphy and paintings, there is always something suitable for fallen officials, which is also a common feature of corruption among male and female officials. However, the difference in preferences between male and female officials in the form of corruption is also a visible phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, the ostentatious culture of men showing off their success also had an impact on the officialdom. There were many incidents where people were arrested for corruption based on photos. In view of this, in recent years, the corruption of male officials has mostly been &quot;low-key&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;, which is the &quot;lesson&quot; learned from certain &quot;cousins&quot; and &quot;brothers&quot; who were dismissed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, in terms of forms of corruption, the &quot;indirect&quot; and &quot;confusing&quot; characteristics of male officials are becoming more and more obvious, such as &quot;setting up offshore accounts&quot;, &quot;accepting bribes after retirement&quot;, &quot;shadow companies&quot;, &quot;option corruption&quot;, etc. There are endless means. The ancient &quot;elegant bribery&quot; has not completely gone into history. The high-end bribery and acceptance of bribes with the help of antique calligraphy and painting are still common in the corruption details of fallen male officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, male officials are also trying to hide their wealth and keep a low profile. They are no longer easily caught because of their public image as usual. Regarding the details of corruption, male officials also try their best to cover up and leave no traceable information, such as the &quot;$300,000 gift box&quot; codenamed &quot;Little Seafood&quot; received by Sun Lijun, and Zhang Qi, former member of the Standing Committee of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee and former Secretary of the Haikou Municipal Party Committee. The secret method of &quot;filling the home with 13.5 tons of gold bars&quot;. Male officials can often use their special interests and hobbies to satisfy their greed while hiding the fact of corruption: Yang Hongwei, former deputy secretary of the party group and deputy director of the Chongqing Municipal Administration for Market Regulation, is known as the &quot;ball secretary&quot; and is keen on playing basketball during working hours. , using playing ball to cover up his corrupt behavior of giving and receiving privately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that playing ball and other hobbies are more common among men. Judging from some female officials who have been dismissed in recent years, corruption that combines power and the love of beauty is not uncommon. From accessories, clothing and bags to luxury goods consumption, to the so-called &quot;beauty corruption&quot;. Just like the corruption record of Bai Hong, the former chairman of the labor union of the Beijing Municipal Health Bureau, &quot;the praise and jealousy of the people around him made Bai Hong immersed in the pleasure of a successful woman.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For bribers to pay for beauty treatments on their behalf, or to give high-priced beauty salon membership cards, this can constitute bribery of female officials, and even the development of novel money laundering methods. In real life, it is not uncommon for &quot;ordinary people to pay exorbitant prices for beauty treatments.&quot; However, once a female official&#39;s love for beauty is empowered by her desire for power, the resulting corruption will become even more like a torrential flood. &quot;Power keeps people young forever&quot; is not only a symbolic statement for female officials, but also a realistic statement that can be realized with the help of beauty consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not just officials who are corrupt. People in key positions can still be corrupt, and corruption tends to be younger. Young people tend to be bolder and more reckless in their corruption. Zhang Yujie, a post-1995 clerk at the Chuzhou Real Estate Registration Center, embezzled nearly 70 million yuan in public funds, tens of thousands of which were spent on game cards. After the incident, the card was auctioned for more than 80 million yuan. His hobby is playing games. In the 2016 &quot;Accounting Corruption Case of Four Young Women in Yangzhou, Jiangsu Province&quot;, Bai Ling, the former cash accountant of the Gaoyou Municipal Agricultural Committee, misappropriated 10.51 million yuan in public funds, of which more than 8 million yuan was used for beauty consumption. At the time of the case, she was only 29 Years old, it is really shocking to embezzle such a huge amount of money just for beauty consumption. Their preference is to love beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 34 of the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishment for Public Officials&quot; stipulates that &quot;those who accept or provide arrangements for banquets, travel, fitness, entertainment and other activities that may affect the fair exercise of public power will be given a warning, A demerit or a major demerit will be recorded, and if the circumstances are serious, the person will be demoted or dismissed.&quot; Beauty corruption, in terms of form, is a relatively hidden &quot;entertainment and other activities&quot;, and the amount involved is often in compliance with the &quot;Applicable Laws on Handling Criminal Cases of Corruption and Bribery&quot; of the two high authorities. The &quot;extremely huge amount&quot; standard in &quot;Explanation of Certain Issues&quot; can be called hidden corruption in the gray area. Therefore, to combat beauty corruption, we need to start from the source of corruption and curb the room for arbitrary power. This point is gender-neutral. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家数据局揭牌，年内落马中管干部达39人丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259490]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/26cYbymIzOStR24cc3LlYF4O4UW02DgWUpAEzt6F.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;617&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/26cYbymIzOStR24cc3LlYF4O4UW0 2DgWUpAEzt6F. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255790&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 25, 2023, the National Data Administration was officially launched. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than seven months of preparation, on the morning of October 25, 2023, a group of members of the preparatory team Witnessed by representatives from other ministries and commissions, the National Data Agency was officially unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the two newly established departments in the ninth institutional reform of the State Council have been completed. Previously, the newly established State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau had completed its listing on May 18, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new round of institutional reform plan of the State Council shows that the National Data Administration is managed by the National Development and Reform Commission and is specifically responsible for coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure systems, coordinating the integration, sharing and development and utilization of data resources, and coordinating the promotion of digital China, digital economy, Digital society planning and construction, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exploring the Blue Ocean of Data&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before the National Data Bureau announced its establishment, the importance of data had been emphasized many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the &quot;Overall Layout Plan for the Construction of Digital China&quot; was issued. Earlier, at the end of 2022, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Building a Data Infrastructure System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements.&quot; Both documents include content to accelerate the development of the digital economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong, deputy director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission, was more direct. In an exclusive interview with the media in April 2023, he once proposed that by the end of the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, the size of China&#39;s data element circulation market will reach one trillion yuan, which is a huge blue ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Existing data has confirmed this statement. The &quot;Digital China Development Report (2022)&quot; released by the Cyberspace Administration of China shows that the scale of China&#39;s data digital economy will reach 50.2 trillion yuan in 2022, ranking second in the world, accounting for 41.5% of GDP, and will continue to remain the same. With a high growth rate of 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Zhang Xianghong, a professor at the International Research Center for Information Management Theory and Technology at Beijing Jiaotong University, the current level of development of China&#39;s public data, corporate data and personal data is still low, and the level of utilization is not high. Problems of insufficient motivation and insufficient utilization of vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, unified data resource management and activation of data efficiency have become high hopes for the National Data Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a previous interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, Yuan Lizhi, a partner at Jingtian &amp; Gongcheng Law Firm and an expert in data law, mentioned that in January 2023, after a seminar on the circulation of data elements, the state Staff from the National Development and Reform Commission once worked with him to communicate on practical issues regarding the circulation of data elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two leaders made their early appearance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;They have clear development goals, which is also reflected in the personnel arrangements of the National Data Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 18, 2023, Liu Liehong, the first director of the National Data Administration, made his first public appearance at the high-level forum on digital economy of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resume shows that Liu Liehong was born in 1968 and has worked in industrial electronic information institutions for a long time. Since joining the workforce in 1990, Liu Liehong has served as an assistant engineer and engineer. In November 2004, Liu Liehong was appointed as the deputy general manager of China Electronics Technology Group Co., Ltd. through open recruitment. He later served as the president of China Electronics Information Industry Development Research Institute and president of Beijing Saidi Information Industry Group Co., Ltd., and director and general manager of China Electronics Information Industry Group Co., Ltd. , director and general manager of China Electronics Technology Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2018, Liu Liehong entered politics from business and was appointed deputy director of the Central Cyberspace Administration. During his tenure, he promoted the development of the mobile industry and 5G network applications. After becoming the chairman of China Unicom Group in August 2021, he also promoted China Unicom&#39;s transformation into a digital pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Liu Liehong, who actively embraces digitalization, Shen Zhulin, deputy director of the National Data Administration, who was appointed on October 11, also has extensive experience in digital economy, electronic information and big data promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Shen Zhulin has worked at the National Development and Reform Commission for a long time. He has served as deputy inspector of the High-tech Industry Department, deputy director of the High-Tech Department, and director of the Innovation and High-tech Development Department of the National Development and Reform Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Shen Zhulin proposed at a symposium held by the Central Cyberspace Administration of China that data resources should be truly treated as an important economic resource and some measures should be taken to truly open and share data. measure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to selecting &quot;professional counterparts&quot; for bureau leaders, the National Data Bureau also has relatively clear requirements for basic talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Recruitment Brochure for Civil Servants Recruited by Central Agencies and Their Directly Affiliated Agencies for the 2024 Examination&quot; published on October 15, 2023 shows that in this round of recruitment, the National Data Bureau has opened a total of 12 recruitment quotas in 5 units. Applicants are required to have at least 3 years of grass-roots work experience, and a master&#39;s degree or above in electronic science and technology, information and communication engineering, computer science and technology, applied economics, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the recruitment requirements, these talents will participate in research on data governance and development policies, international cooperation in the data field and digital economy, research on data basic systems and policies, and the formulation of development strategies, plans and policies related to the digital economy. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Li Shangfu and Qin Gang were dismissed State Councilor&#39;s Position]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;News Network&quot;, according to the decision of the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of the People&#39;s Republic of China on October 24, 2023 , removed Li Shangfu from the posts of State Councilor and Minister of Defense, and removed Qin Gang from the posts of State Councilor. Previously, on July 25, the fourth meeting of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress voted to remove Qin Gang as Minister of Foreign Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The new leadership of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation was elected, and 14 people including Zhang Guimei were elected vice-chairmen]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 25, 2023, the first meeting of the 13th Executive Committee of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation was held. The meeting elected the Chairman, Vice Chairman and Standing Committee members of the Women&#39;s Federation by secret ballot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the elected chairpersons of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation are State Councilor and Director of the State Council Working Committee on Women and Children Chen Yiqin, Huang Xiaowei, Sangding Dorjepam Deqing Quzhen, Zhang Xiaolan, Ge Xiaoyan, Yu Yanhong, Xu Xiaolan 14 people, including Ma Lu, Lin Yi, Feng Ling, Zhang Dongmei, Chen Hualan, Meng Man, Zhang Guimei and Wang Yaping, were elected vice presidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resumes show that the 14 vice-chairmen of the Women&#39;s Federation are outstanding female representatives in various industries. Among them, Xu Xiaolan is the vice minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, and Zhang Guimei is the principal of Huaping County Women&#39;s Senior High School in Lijiang, Yunnan. They are known as As the &quot;principal mother of a mountain girl&quot;, Wang Yaping is China&#39;s first female astronaut to perform extravehicular activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Xie Fuzhan, former Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, was elected chairman of the China Human Rights Development Foundation]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency, the first meeting of the fourth council of the China Foundation for Human Rights Development was held in Beijing on October 25. Xie Fuzhan was elected as the new chairman of the board of directors, Zhou Shuchun, the former president and editor-in-chief of China Daily, was elected as the executive vice chairman, and Zuo Feng, Huang Jin, Li Cheng Tenzin Nyima was elected as the vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Xie Fuzhan was born in Tianmen, Hubei in August 1954. He has a postgraduate degree, a master&#39;s degree in engineering, a researcher, and a doctoral supervisor. He enjoys special government allowances from the State Council. He joined the Communist Party of China in November 1974. , joined the work in March 1973. He served as Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee and former President of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/smX6GQKoiebtiNYeiTFpK6drDIsiTuqN9Pn2YA8g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/smX6GQKoiebtiNYeiTFpK6drDIsiTuqN9Pn2YA8g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xie Fuzhan, former secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, was elected chairman of the China Human Rights Development Foundation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【Tibet The Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region concurrently serves as the Principal of the Party School]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, the website of the Party School of the Tibet Autonomous Region Party Committee (Autonomous Region Administrative College) updated the &quot;Leader Introduction&quot; column. Wang Junzheng, Secretary of the Party Committee of the Tibet Autonomous Region, is currently concurrently serving as the President of the Party School The position of president of the Party School of the Autonomous Region Party Committee (Dean of the Autonomous Region Administrative College). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Transfer only one month, scholar type Leading cadres quit]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report from the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision on October 23, 2023, Cai Lecai, a first-level inspector of the Sichuan Provincial Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center, is being investigated for serious violations of discipline and law. Accept disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resume shows that Cai Lecai has worked in Sichuan universities for a long time, and has served successively as Secretary of the Party Branch of the Computer Science Department of Sichuan Institute of Technology, Director of the Science and Technology (Industry) Division, and Vice President, and Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee and President of Yibin University. Party committee secretary and other positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Cai Lecai had just transferred from school to serve as a first-level inspector of the Sichuan Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center, assisting a deputy director of the Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center. By the time he was investigated, he had only been in office for one month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ling Chengxing, the former director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was investigated, and the number of dismissed cadres increased to 39]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported that Ling Chengxing, the former party secretary and director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. Becoming the 39th central management cadre to be dismissed in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resume shows that Ling Chengxing was born in Jiangxi in 1957 and has worked in Jiangxi for a long time. He has served as mayor of Fengcheng City, deputy director of Jiangxi Provincial Economic Commission, director (manager) of Jiangxi Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), Assistant to the Governor of Jiangxi Province and other positions. In 2001, Ling Chengxing served as the vice governor of Jiangxi Province. In 2013, he was transferred to a member of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration until he resigned in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection concentrated on reporting the investigation and punishment information of four &quot;insiders&quot;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported information on the investigation and punishment of four cadres of the discipline inspection system. They are the former party secretary and director of the Legal Affairs Office of the Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, and the former director of the Hainan Provincial Department of Veterans Affairs. Wang Zhiqiang, member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director, Long Guangzhi, former deputy secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Qujing City, Yunnan Province, former deputy director of the Municipal Supervisory Committee, and second-level inspector, and Fan Renfu, former leader of the inspection team of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investigation information shows that, except for Fan Renfu, who is still under investigation, the other three were &quot;disloyal and dishonest to the party&quot;, resisted organizational review, and were unable to truthfully explain problems. At the same time, behaviors such as concealing stolen money, making wishes or platforms for others, intervening in economic disputes or engineering projects, and living a luxurious life are also common. Among them, Long Guangzhi also informed criminal suspects and provided conveniences to help them avoid punishment when he was responsible for cracking down on criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The former deputy governor of Hubei Province leaked insider information, causing others to make tens of millions of profits]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, the case of Cao Guangjing accepting bribes and leaking inside information was heard publicly in the first instance of the Intermediate People’s Court of Xuzhou City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Court information shows that in 2014, Cao Guangjing resigned as chairman of China Three Gorges Corporation and became deputy governor of the Hubei Provincial Government. During his tenure, Cao Guangjing was mainly responsible for industry, transportation, state-owned assets supervision, and provincial investment and financing platforms. He once led the bailout and reorganization of the holding company of a listed company in Hubei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, Cao Guangjing disclosed the inside information about the bailout and restructuring to others, causing others to buy the shares of the listed company before the inside information was made public, and then sold the shares for a profit of more than 10.42 million yuan. . In February 2022, Cao Guangjing announced his resignation, and the following month, Fu Limin, then party secretary of the Hubei Provincial State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, also announced his resignation. A follow-up report from the Hubei Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision stated that Fu Limin acted arbitrarily and made illegal decisions during the restructuring of state-owned enterprises, resulting in huge losses to public property and the risk of major losses to state-owned assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the trial, the public prosecution requested that Cao Guangjing be held criminally responsible for the crime of accepting bribes and leaking inside information. Cao Guangjing expressed his guilt and repentance. The court adjourned the hearing and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;p>; Fair access to education]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the regular policy briefing of the State Council Information Office held on October 25, 2023, the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Education introduced that currently, efforts are being made to provide financial assistance to students from families with financial difficulties. Achieve &quot;three improvements&quot;, that is, improve coverage, improve accuracy, and improve independent standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the country’s cumulative funding amount reached 292.273 billion yuan, and a total of 161 million students were supported. In the next step, the Ministry of Education will organize and implement the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; special education development and improvement action plan to address the issue of school security for students with disabilities in special groups, include more children with disabilities in the special education security system, and increase public funding per student for special education students. Increase to 7-10 times that of ordinary students, reaching 7,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology held the third symposium on manufacturing enterprises]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology held the third symposium for manufacturing companies, and 12 chain owners were invited to participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, regarding the development and difficult issues of key manufacturing industries, Jin Zhuanglong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, presided over and listened to the opinions and demands of business representatives, and deployed plans to promote the high-quality development of key manufacturing industry chains. Focus on work. &lt;p>; >;On October 24, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted and passed relevant resolutions, clarifying that the central government will issue an additional 1 trillion yuan in 2023 national debt in the fourth quarter to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and improve disaster prevention and reduction. Disaster relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance, although the budget has arranged relevant regular disaster relief and disaster prevention and reduction funds at the beginning of this year, it is still difficult to meet the needs for improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day after the news was released, on October 25, the Ministry of Finance launched a bidding and issuance of 16 billion yuan of treasury bonds to professional investors in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate announced the first three quarters of the country&#39;s Main case handling data of procuratorial organs]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate released the main case handling data of procuratorial organs nationwide in the first three quarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September 2023, procuratorial organs across the country approved and decided to arrest a total of 520,000 criminal suspects of various types, of which 392,000 were not arrested, with a non-arrest rate of 43%; a total of 118.2 people were decided to prosecute. Of the 10,000 people involved, 411,000 were not prosecuted, with a non-prosecution rate of 25.8%. Among all prosecution cases, the number of cases concluded under the leniency system for plea guilty and punishment accounted for more than 90% of the number of cases concluded during the same period, and the procuratorial organs’ recommendations on sentencing and sentencing accounted for more than 95% of the number of sentencing recommendations made. Among them, the number of people who adopted the court’s adoption accounted for more than 95% of the number of sentencing recommendations made during the same period. 97.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the person in charge of the Supreme People’s Procuratorate’s Case Management Office, my country’s criminal structure has undergone major changes over the past two decades. The proportion of sentences sentenced to three years or more in prison has dropped from 45.4% in 1999 to 2023. 17.2% from January to September, the crime structure shows a clear misdemeanor, and social governance has entered a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【114,000 economic crime cases investigated in the first three quarters】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 On March 24, the State Council Information Office held a series of press conferences with the theme of &quot;The Beginning of Authoritative Departments&#39; Talks&quot;. Yang Xin, director of the Research Office of the Ministry of Public Security, introduced that since the 26 measures to ensure high-quality development of public security services were announced to the public in August this year, the threshold for settling in various regions has been further lowered, and 29 provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities have achieved &quot;inter-provincial transfers of all types of household registrations&quot;. In the past two months, a total of more than 500,000 household registration transfers have been processed across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Vice Minister of Public Security Wang Zhizhong also stated at the meeting that this year, public security agencies across the country will focus on building a high-level socialist market economic system and severely crack down on various economic crimes. From January to September, public security agencies across the country investigated a total of 114,000 economic crime cases and successfully recovered economic losses of 18.37 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors&quot; was released]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October On the 24th, my country&#39;s first specialized comprehensive legislation on the online protection of minors was passed. The &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors&quot; will be officially implemented on January 1, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant persons in charge of the Ministry of Justice and the Cyberspace Administration of China mentioned in answers to reporters’ questions that the formulation of regulations follows the overall ideas of problem orientation, social co-governance, and legislative coordination, focusing on the online protection of minors. The outstanding issues faced by the work clarify the responsibilities of relevant government departments and enterprises, schools, families, industry organizations, news media, etc. in the online protection of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[70 years of establishment, Buckley Award Welcome Chinese winners for the first time]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Beijing time, the American Physical Society announced that Xue Qikun, academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, professor of Tsinghua University, and president of Southern University of Science and Technology, won this year’s Buckley Award. . This is also the first time in the 70 years since the award was established that a Chinese scientist has won the Buckley Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, the Buckley Award was established to commend scientists who have made outstanding contributions in the field of condensed matter physics, and is recognized as the highest award in the international field of condensed matter physics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2009, Xue Qikun has joined forces with multiple research groups from the Department of Physics of Tsinghua University, the Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and Stanford University in the United States to form a research team to conduct experimental observations of the quantum anomalous Hall effect. At the end of 2012, Xue Qikun and his team successfully overcame the difficulty and experimentally observed the quantum anomalous Hall effect for the first time in the world. The result was published in the American &quot;Science&quot; magazine in March 2013 and was called &quot;a landmark work in the field of condensed matter physics.&quot; Xue Qikun won the Buckley Award for this breakthrough research result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/jTgEU3YHSfataawS5yi421C64yY9mqj3FuUUsz0u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/jTgEU3YHSfataawS5yi421C64yY9mqj3FuUUsz0u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xue Qikun, professor at Tsinghua University and president of Southern University of Science and Technology, won this year’s Buckley Award. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（People&#39;s Vision/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【Shenzhou The launch of the Shenzhou 17th manned spacecraft was a complete success]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11:13:59 on October 26, Beijing time, the Shenzhou 17th manned spacecraft was ignited and launched from Jiuquan, Gansu. This manned mission consists of astronauts Tang Hongbo, Tang Shengjie and Jiang Xinlin, and still adopts the strategy of &quot;leading the new with the old&quot;. The second batch of astronauts Tang Hongbo serves as the commander. At the same time, this is also his second time to carry out the mission. Flying mission. In 2021, Tang Hongbo was selected as the first astronaut crew member to carry out the space station phase mission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, during this mission, the three astronauts will also conduct experimental maintenance operations outside the space station for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region: 97.02 issued in two years 100 million yuan to build high-standard farmland】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, the Department of Finance of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region announced that in 2022 and 2023, the autonomous region’s finance will issue a total of 97.02 yuan in subsidy funds for the construction of high-standard farmland. billion to support the construction of 7.95 million acres of high-standard farmland. Statistics show that the high-standard farmland that has been built in Inner Mongolia accounts for less than 40% of the region’s permanent basic farmland, but it produces nearly 70% of the region’s grain, providing the basis for building an important national agricultural and livestock product production base. Assure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sichuan: China&#39;s first natural disaster dynamic risk early warning platform is operational]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;According to Chengdu Daily, since July this year, the Pengzhou Municipal Committee of Social Affairs and Management and the Chengdu High-tech Disaster Reduction Research Institute have established a smart disaster reduction emergency warning project in Longmenshan Town, which has risks of earthquakes, flash floods, debris flows and other disasters. The platform is based on the results of the natural disaster risk census completed simultaneously in Pengzhou City and across the country this year, and integrates multiple disaster warning functions such as flash flood warnings, debris flow warnings, and earthquake warnings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the trial operation, the platform has generated risk warning information more than 100 times and issued 2 alarms. The accuracy of early warnings has gradually increased. On October 26, the project passed acceptance inspection and became China&#39;s first officially operational natural disaster dynamic risk early warning platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Qinghai: The first batch of 129 part-time inspectors were hired]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;According to Qinghai Daily, on October 26, the Qinghai Provincial Government’s appointment ceremony for part-time inspectors was held in Xining, and the first batch of 129 part-time inspectors were hired. The report mentioned that the part-time provincial government inspectors hired this time come from various municipal and state governments, relevant departments and bureaus, as well as the National People&#39;s Congress, the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, counselors and other fields, and the appointment period is two years. During their tenure, they will be responsible for supervising the implementation of major decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, the State Council, the provincial party committee and the provincial government, and promoting high-quality economic and social development in the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Xing Wei, researcher at China Institute of Macroeconomics : Adjusting holidays is better than not adjusting holidays, and it has to be adjusted]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the holiday schedule for 2024 was announced, and the arrangement of not having a holiday on New Year’s Eve triggered heated discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, the National Development and Reform Commission published an interpretation article written by Xing Wei, a researcher at the China Institute of Macroeconomics, on its official Weibo. Xing Wei explained that the statutory holidays for the Spring Festival in 2024 are from the first to the eighth day of the Lunar New Year, which is the longest holiday in history. This arrangement also takes into account the differences in the determination standards of the seven statutory holidays. If no adjustment is made, the holidays will be &quot;fragmented&quot;. At that time, it will not be &quot;tired and unloved&quot;, but &quot;tired and unloved&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally speaking, adjusting the holiday is better than not adjusting the holiday, and it has to be adjusted.&quot; Xing Wei wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from People&#39;s Daily, Xinhua News Agency, CCTV News, the official website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, the official website of the Ministry of Education, Industry and Information Technology Ministry official website, The Paper, Qinghai Daily, Chengdu Daily, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡杨林：大漠深处，最美金秋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259424]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn season, the Populus euphratica forest in Ejina Banner, Alxa League, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region has entered the best viewing period, with layers of trees dyed and colorful. gorgeous. As the location with the highest concentration of Populus euphratica forests in the country, the beautiful scenery of &quot;lovely flowers and autumn leaves&quot; attracts tourists to come and experience the most beautiful autumn colors in the depths of the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/dFC6dONkeVmBNgT85OraD2CS1nkyrIs7mUA7xbDT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/dFC6dONkeVmBNgT85OraD2CS1nkyrIs7mUA7xbDT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255745&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, sheep were foraging in the Populus euphratica forest. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Jinhai/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/27/hEY7P0OCQTUTsuniN56duKLZbuIQn4N6mc32qgxj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /27/hEY7P0OCQTUTsuniN56duKLZbuIQn4N6mc32qgxj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255744&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, sheep drank water in front of the Populus euphratica forest . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Kaiyan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/27/xCm3Gf9vN1opoVcD0bBqwEXQdfh3fg3hzTbIEEno.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/xCm3Gf9vN1opoVcD0bBqwEXQdfh3fg3hzTbIEEno.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023 in Alxa League, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Populus euphratica forest photographed in Ejina Banner. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Cuirong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/27/CA4SDVYkxefpwjywpaaVurbPi71FgJSmlJSYt9yA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/27/CA4SDVYkxefpwjywpaaVurbPi71FgJSmlJSYt9yA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255742&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ala, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region on October 18, 2023 Populus euphratica forest photographed in Ejina Banner of Shanmeng. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Cuirong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/27/NgEcWNZ6xpv84varQpMHiu2aBSQzCjirhd7PmKkj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/27/NgEcWNZ6xpv84varQpMHiu2aBSQzCjirhd7PmKkj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ala, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region on October 18, 2023 Populus euphratica forest photographed in Ejina Banner of Shanmeng. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Cuirong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/27/6Gy0j0xCiWryRXK8CDO4atIWVbRJAN7lYxrKLpJ4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;816&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/27/6Gy0j0xCiWryRXK8CDO4atIWVbRJAN7lYxrKLpJ4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the Populus euphratica forest on the bank of the Heihe River (2023 Photographed on October 24, drone photo). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency reporter Lian Zhen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/27/Hhz9W7Hksem7HLs5fvQOLOOgjt4Rc3uDXnw1NcCA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /27/Hhz9W7Hksem7HLs5fvQOLOOgjt4Rc3uDXnw1NcCA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the Populus euphratica forest taken on October 24, 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Kaiyan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/27/kMOxJkYWD01t2SgZCx272B5qIhiFxz9dxhxUAodc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;1903&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/kMOxJkYWD01t2SgZCx272B5qIhiFxz9dxhxUAodc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023 in Alxa League, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Populus euphratica forest photographed in Ejina Banner. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Cuirong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more Multiple RSS: &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[许倬云口述：中美之间的恩怨纠葛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259416]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;If we count the exchanges between China and the United States from the Opium War in 1840, it has been almost two hundred years. In such a long process, the ups and downs, grievances and resentments between China and the United States are a very complicated record. Since China switched to welcoming the world, the entanglement between China and the United States is probably more complicated than the relationship between China and any other country in history, and has far-reaching consequences.</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被渴慕的军训丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259426]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/A72oqQdD8BybPWTNg0BalhXWNoO5Mh57DFsDOpHt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/A72oqQdD8BybPWTNg0BalhXWNoO5Mh 57DFsDOpHt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guangxi Guilin University of Electronic Science and Technology 2023 freshmen military training demonstration&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For relevant reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https:/ /www.infzm.com/contents/258988&quot; title=&quot;How is hard-core military training accomplished&quot;>;How is hard-core military training accomplished&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interview with Guilin University of Electronic Science and Technology ( &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidian&quot;&lt;/span>;) and Guilin Institute of Aerospace Industry (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guihang&quot;&lt;/span>;) as a person in charge of military training, I wanted to understand the difficulties of organizing hard-core military training, but I always failed to do so. The two schools borrowed simulated weapons and combat vehicles without much trouble. The tactical training seemed to come naturally. The local garrison area and military training and education base are willing to open their doors to the school and can deliver realistic equipment and a sufficient number of active or retired military personnel to the new students participating in the training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in addition to these objective factors, I feel that there is a strong spiritual power that allows the hard-core military training in these two universities in Guangxi to be implemented smoothly. In the minds of students participating in special warfare training, military training is not an obligation that is forced to be completed, but a life experience that is desired. One kind of person looks forward to the sense of relief when everything ends from the first day of military training; the other kind of person hopes to pursue the intrinsic value of military training and is eager to continue it even after the military training ends. I think that when I participated in military training as a student, I belonged to the former; but many training students in Guilin universities fell into the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Shen Hong was interviewed, he was a little shy. Huang Yilong, chairman of the Patriotic National Defense Education Association, often said that Shen Hong was an outstanding representative of the Red Army&#39;s demining gunners. Upon hearing such compliments, Shen Hong would either bury his head in the ground or look at the street lights in the distance, deliberately hiding his smile from me. Different from the occasional erratic expression, even if the person had already stepped out of the queue, for more than 20 minutes, Shen Hong&#39;s simulated gun was fixed on his chest in a standard gun-holding posture from beginning to end, without moving at all. Two weeks of freshmen military training and two weeks of daily association training seemed to have carved his rock-solid movements into a habit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the hardships of special warfare training, Shen Hong always downplays: &quot;There are bruises on elbows, knees, legs, and feet, but they will be over with some medicine.&quot; &quot;While leaping forward, I suddenly heard something The body cannot react to the enemy&#39;s instructions on the left and right, so I keep practicing this movement and practice harder. I will do it wrong at first, but after practicing for three or four days, I can reach the standard.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these, the &quot;soldier&quot; Identity has more appeal to Shen Hong. He was born in Huanjiang Maonan Autonomous County, Guangxi. He is a freshman this year and has been following war movies and spy dramas for more than ten years. Recalling the time he spent watching TV with his father, Shen Hong&#39;s tone raised a few notches, &quot;Chinese soldiers are very handsome.&quot; The first time he knew that his father, a farmer, had been a soldier was because he saw his marching kettle. &quot;That&#39;s a unique kettle in the army.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Hong is convinced that if he meets the recruitment standards, he will definitely join the army after graduation. For him, this military training is not only a required course according to the syllabus, but also a serious preparatory exercise before officially joining the army. What attracted him to join the tactical company was not only the rich firearms training, but also the &quot;soldier&#39;s pride&quot; that comes with pressure. In Shen Hong&#39;s eyes, his teammates are also &quot;people with a strong sense of family and country, who speak directly and boldly.&quot; &quot;I like to be friends with people who can tell their true feelings.&quot; He also longs for the future life in the military camp: if he is bitten by ants during training on the grass, a comrade will happily hand him a dose of ointment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, it was already dark when the Guihang military training performance ended. The special operations team members who had no chance to ride in the armored vehicle during the performance climbed into the armored vehicle one by one in groups of eight or nine. They sat in a small circle on the roof of the car, arms around each other, singing songs as the chariot moved forward. Everyone&#39;s face was covered with tired camouflage makeup, but the singing was still loud. They were like battle-hardened soldiers returning in triumph. Marching to the center of the playground, the armored vehicle suddenly stopped, and the team members staggered, as if they were waking up from a dream. But when they climbed down from the car, they saw other team members sitting cross-legged under the street lamp in the distance, noisy and lively, so they ran over. The WeChat messages, photos, and words of their comrades remained forever in the camouflage-colored dream. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“最后一代务农人”：他们正在消失的技艺、生活方式与价值观]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259340]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of the fourth day after returning home during the National Day holiday, my mother and I went for a walk. We met Grandma Yang in a vegetable field near the river. She was planting radish seedlings with her hunched back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother told me that Grandma Yang is 81 years old and is the oldest person in the village. Grandma Yang’s wife has passed away many years ago. Her two sons are developing in Wuhan, the provincial capital, and she lives alone. I saw that there were daikon, carrots, beetroot, and cabbage planted in the field, so I asked Grandma Yang why she planted so many. She said, &quot;Four months later, the children all went home, and together they had 9 mouths.&quot; Zi realized that the Spring Festival would be in four months. She also added, &quot;Not only do they come back to eat during the Chinese New Year, I also have to prepare some for them to take with them when they leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the radishes I planted earlier were not growing very well, I asked Why, she told two reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Firstly, many farmers have gone to cities to work, many fields are deserted, bushes are everywhere, and there are many more wild boars, badgers and other animals than before. Just like the numbers of people, they have Instead of sneakily eating crops including vegetables at night, they can also freely invade vegetable fields, valleys, and sweet potato fields during the day. During the day, the old man can come to the vegetable fields with a stick from time to time to guard them and drive away wild animals. , at night, she had absolutely no choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, due to the long-term use of pesticides and chemical fertilizers, the soil structure of farmland has changed. The soil has become seriously compacted, fertility has dropped sharply, and the output of various crops, including vegetables, has dropped sharply. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In fact, we can’t go back&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After telling Grandma Yang to be careful, my mother and I continued walking. There was a large field of rice fields in front of me. My mother asked me which one belonged to my family. I guessed twice, but my mother shook her head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I suddenly felt ashamed. I didn’t even know where my own farm was. Probably since I started working in 2008, every time I go home, my parents rarely go to the fields to do farm work, but stay with me. Of course, I rarely have the opportunity to go to the fields. As time went by, I forgot the exact location of the fields at home. Seeing that the rice was golden yellow, I suggested harvesting it the next day and helped cut it. Unexpectedly, my mother was very worried about my rice cutting skills. &quot;It&#39;s better to wait until you return to Guangzhou. Your dad and I will take our time. If you haven&#39;t gone to the fields for many years, it will be bad if you cut your hands.&quot; I was speechless, because the fact is that although I go home often, I rarely work in the fields. I am no longer an important labor force in the family like when I was in elementary school and junior high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I work at a university in Guangzhou. I have a long summer and winter vacation. I go home for many more days every year than other young people in the village. For example, my brother started his working career after dropping out of school in his second year of high school at the age of 17. He basically works outside all year round, except for about half a month when he goes home during the Spring Festival. My brother is 44 years old and has been working for 27 years. Now, he has bought a house in Wuhan, and his sister-in-law and two nephews also live in Wuhan permanently. The eldest nephew is studying in college, and the sister-in-law takes care of the younger nephew who is in elementary school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, my family of four is in Guangzhou, and my brother’s family of four is in Wuhan. We have all been actively or passively involved in the wave of urbanization, and it is difficult for us to return. The hometown is developed or settled. In fact, we can&#39;t go back because we are no longer an &quot;agricultural population&quot; and have been engaged in &quot;non-agricultural industries&quot;, which has nothing to do with my brother&#39;s household registration in his hometown. No matter whether we enjoy the various benefits or treatment of authentic Guangzhou or Wuhan citizens, we are already veritable (new) Guangzhou people or (new) Wuhan people. Guangzhou or Wuhan is our permanent residence, and it is the place where we and our children A place to eat, drink, have sex, and have basic necessities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My brother and I are born in the 1970s. What are the people born in the 80s and 90s who are younger than us in the village doing? Where now? A small number of people have left their hometowns by studying, but most of them, like my brother, work outside all year round. What they have in common is that they are away from home all year round, and they only come home for ten and a half days during the Chinese New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are those born in the 1960s who are older than us doing? There are eight people born in the 1960s in my village. Four of them went to the city to work with their children, either taking care of their grandchildren who were in school or working for their sons who were construction workers. Two of them opened decoration companies, starting in Wuhan and Xining respectively. The last two are in the education industry. One is a teacher at a university in Wuhan, and the other is the principal of a village primary school in his hometown. It is not difficult to see that the eight people born in the 1960s have basically left the countryside and agriculture, and they all only go home during the Chinese New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people born in the 60s, 70s, 80s and 90s have all moved into the city and are currently working hard in the city. Do they have any plans or signs of returning to the village in the future? I feel minimal. They have been in the city for many years, and their food, culture, and habits have already been highly urbanized. The post-80s and post-90s generations have experienced the rinsing of urbanization. They can no longer live without these things in shopping malls, KTVs, cinemas, fast food, and game arcades. Even Uncle Xia, who was born in 1962, said, &quot;Although I have been farming in my hometown for more than 20 years, I am no longer used to going home because life in my hometown is too inconvenient and the city is too convenient.&quot; In Northeast China Brother Wen, who works part-time, also mentioned, &quot;The winter at home is too cold and I am not used to it. I have stayed in Harbin for 32 years. Although the outdoor temperature is low, the indoors are heated and very comfortable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Farmers Vs Peasants&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It goes without saying that the only people who are still farming in their hometowns are those born in the 1940s like Grandma Yang, and those born in the 1950s like my parents. As children have gone to the city to go to school, many women have also joined the migrant workers, and the post-60s generation who went out to make a living in the early 1980s have adapted greatly to urban life. In the past, the &quot;386199&quot; army, which mainly constituted the rural population , now only the lonely &quot;99&quot; is left, and the corresponding specific groups are those born in the 40s and 50s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I would like to express that this group of people is truly the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot;. In particular, the author does not use the concept of &quot;farmers&quot;. In my opinion, concepts such as &quot;farmers&quot; and &quot;workers&quot; have distinct political and identity attributes. In the context of the use of the word &quot;farmers&quot;, there are often several contrasting groups, such as &quot;which group does farmers correspond to?&quot; &quot;Farmers are in rural areas, and workers are In the city&quot;, this is not the case. In essence, they are just differences in industry or professional division of labor. There are no political or identity differences or oppositions. A similar situation exists with the word &quot;worker&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As times have changed, we are more willing to use concepts that are familiar and easier for ordinary people to accept, such as &quot;migrant workers&quot;, &quot;migrant workers&quot;, &quot;migrant girls&quot;, &quot;farmers&quot; and &quot;migrant workers&quot;. Whether they are &quot;farmers&quot; or &quot;laborers,&quot; they are all industrial workers/laborers in the true sense of the word. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The skills of farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As &quot;farmers&quot;, this group of elderly people are naturally well versed in various techniques and techniques of farming or rural areas and agriculture. They have been familiar with agricultural seasons since they were young. , know when to spring plow, when to raise seedlings, when to sow seeds, when to fertilize, when to weed, when to harvest, and what to use to store crops. They know how to use ashes from stoves or firewood piles as fertilizer, and they also know how to use human, chicken, pig and other manure as an important supplement for crop nutrients, instead of just relying on pesticides or chemical fertilizers to improve soil fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will use the corner land in front of and behind the house to grow some vegetables, or reclaim idle or abandoned land in the mountains that is full of rocks or has been deserted for a long time to grow things. Before building a house or choosing a cemetery, they would ask Feng Shui masters to take a look; they invented bamboo beds for cooling in the summer, drying cages for heating in the winter, and chamber pots for using the toilet at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of them have been standard rural craftsmen since they were young, such as blacksmiths, painters, oilers, carpenters, quilters, tailors, midwives, barefoot doctors, fortune tellers, and witch doctors. When the village was renovated, they reminded young people not to easily remove the ancient trees at the entrance of the village, and strongly recommended that the old ancestral hall in the center of the village be retained. When family members have stomachaches, diarrhea, or other three diseases and two pains, they will go to the fields to find Houttuynia cordata and mugwort leaves, and use them to soak their feet, bathe, smoke them, or boil them in water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is no exaggeration to say that there are countless skills that they are familiar with or master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the vast majority of them have a very low level of education, with a high proportion of illiterates or semi-illiterates, but this does not hinder their deep understanding and familiarity with agricultural technology, rural memories and agricultural civilization. They may have never spoken about circular economy, ecological agriculture, intensive and economical land use, intangible cultural heritage, etc. in textbooks or propaganda slogans, nor do they know how to express them, but they have been practicing them all their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This illustrates the truth that culture and civilization often or usually have little or not much to do with educational level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; has made significant contributions to the inheritance of agricultural technology, the continuation of agricultural civilization, the harmony of families, and the country&#39;s urbanization and modernization. It is they who have succeeded their forefathers and ancestors, passing on from generation to generation, that agricultural civilization can be carried forward and passed on; it is they who guard their hometowns and rear areas so that their children and their younger generations can enter the city calmly and confidently Work hard to create a new life for the new generation; it is the kindness and hard work of them and their children that created the miracle of China&#39;s low-cost industrialization, urbanization and modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The lifestyle and values ​​of farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In terms of lifestyle, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; generally have a thrifty character, such as eating as little as possible and eating as much as possible. How many people eat leftovers for pigs, dogs, chickens and other livestock and poultry? Although they are very pleased with the various express delivery out of filial piety and respect for their children, they occasionally complain. They feel that their children spend money like water and spend money lavishly. . The acquisition and cultivation of thrifty character is certainly related to the most difficult and difficult years they experienced, but in that era of extreme material poverty, without frugality and frugality, there was no way to achieve the accumulation of material and wealth, as well as capital accumulation. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;capital accumulation&quot; here can be understood as &quot;without money, unable to pay tuition, even if the children are admitted to college, they will not be able to go to college. As a rural person, the biggest ambition is to &#39;jump out of the farm gate&#39; , as well as the future glory of the family and the glory of the ancestors, naturally they cannot be fulfilled.&quot; The assumption of the above statement is that children are the most important investment area of ​​the family, the expenditure on raising children is the investment cost, and the future development and returns of the children are investment income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of values, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; are very &quot;selfless&quot; and &quot;selfless&quot; to the extreme. The whole meaning of their lives lies in contribution and dedication. Many of them spend most of their lives or their entire lives living for others and their families. They have gone through untold hardships and have been stuck to the land all their lives. They have never or rarely left their hometowns and have been doing farm work all their lives. The so-called &quot;face to the loess and back to the sky&quot; accurately refers to their generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of them have been the main labor force in their families since they were young. They work hard and save all their lives, build houses, marry and have children, and then live frugally to raise their children and provide them with education. When the children grow up, they still think about Give your children a subsidy to share the pressure of buying a house in the city or getting married and starting a family. A few people even endured the torture of acculturation and still chose to go to the city to cook for their children and take their grandchildren to and from school when they were in their twenties. Only when their grandchildren were older could they return home to the home they had been used to all their lives. . After returning home, they finally no longer have to be busy, but they find that they have already fallen ill. Some people choose not to tell their children because they are afraid of using their children&#39;s money. Some people simply do not go to the hospital for a physical examination, fearing that if the problem is found, it will cause trouble for their children. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since they are the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot;, they are the &quot;last generation&quot;. Just like many villages that have experienced and are experiencing decline and decline, the torrent of the times will not pity them because of their hard work or hardship. them, or keep them. The exit of the old and the emergence of the new has always been an inevitable law of historical development and evolution, and no one can stop it. We can feel desolate, but we still need to let go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡适之父胡铁花之死真相]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259328]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/cmE0watQ4X4hR3EdC4BMdX1zy6V3ZcKH0xoxzto7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;641&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/cmE0watQ4X4hR3EdC4BMdX1zy6V3ZcKH0 xoxzto7. png&quot; data-key=&quot;255537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Chuan (Hao Tiehua), the father of Hu Shi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1895, the Qing government ceded Taiwan. Hu Shi&#39;s father, Hu Chuan, was the magistrate of Taitung Prefecture at the time. Hu Shi recalled that his father was &quot;unable to &quot;Willing to release&quot; delayed medical treatment and died, and most academic circles gave a conclusion of &quot;death from illness&quot;. The author discovered from the diary of Yuan Chang, a disciple of Zhang Zhidong, that Hu Chuan was imprisoned and blackmailed by Liu Yongfu, which worsened his condition and died on the ship back to Xiamen. Liu Yongfu finally let him go because Yuan Chang asked Zhang Zhidong to intervene. Yuan Chang was killed in 1900 for speaking out. He was a loyal and upright person, and his record deserves attention. The content of Yuan Chang&#39;s record is consistent with Hu Shi&#39;s recollection, but the wording is slightly different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi&#39;s father&#39;s official name was Hu Chuan, also known as Shousan and Shoushan, also known as Tiehua and Blunt Man. He experienced twists and turns in his life. He went north to Ninggu Pagoda, south to Hainan Li District, and finally arrived in Taiwan. The governor of Dongzhili Prefecture. For a long time, people have been under the impression that Hu Chuan died of illness. Luo Ergang, a disciple of Hu Shi and the famous scholar who compiled &quot;Hu Tiehua&#39;s Manuscripts&quot;, also agrees with this theory. There are many people who hold this view. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author also believes that Hu Chuan died of illness, but he died of an aggravation of his illness due to delays in treatment in captivity, and did not die of a normal illness. Hu Shi recalled: &quot;My father was in Taitung in charge of the defense of Houshan. Telegraphs were blocked and his salary source was cut off. At that time, he had suffered from beriberi and could no longer move his left foot. He stayed there until the third day of the fifth lunar month before leaving. Back Mountain, when they arrived in Anping, Liu Yongfu insisted on keeping him for help and refused to let him go. By June 25, he could no longer move his feet, so Liu Yongfu let him go. On June 28, he arrived in Xiamen. He could no longer move, and he died in Xiamen on July 3rd.&quot; (Hu Shi&#39;s &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot;) Hu Shi later added: &quot;But in my &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot;, I stated that my father&#39;s death was due to beriberi. It can be cured. My father originally wanted to rush to Shanghai to seek medical treatment, but because Liu Yongfu refused to let him go, it was delayed for nearly two months. It was not until he was critically ill that he was let go. He arrived in Xiamen on June 28th and arrived in Xiamen in early July. He died at the age of three. My original intention (and the opinion of my late brother and late mother) is that my late father’s death was due to Liu Yongfu’s refusal to let him go.” (Hu Songping’s “First Draft of the Long Chronicle of Mr. Hu Shizhi”, Volume 1 Page 27) The person accompanying Hu Chuan that day was Hu Shi&#39;s second brother Shaozhi, who was also responsible for carrying the coffin back home. The situation described by Hu Shi should come from his second brother. Hu Shi&#39;s addition is extremely important and is consistent with Yuan Chang&#39;s diary records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/8eG93hRZLCT8OzKR3OWQNDJHsCTfvSs2GHoZ85hf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/8eG93hRZLCT8OzKR3OWQNDJHsCTfvSs2GHoZ85hf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Yongfu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading Hu Chuan&#39;s &quot;Taiwan Diary&quot;, he wrote to Tang Jingsong on the 6th of May, requesting &quot;to open a vacancy and return to his hometown for medical treatment&quot; and &quot;recover as soon as he obtains Yuan Shuangqiu&#39;s observation book from South Anhui Province.&quot; This diary entry proves that Hu Chuo&#39;s intention was to return to the mainland for medical treatment, and that he had frequent correspondence with Yuan Chang. Yuan Chang&#39;s official position at this time was Guangtai Road, Ningchi, Anhui Province, referred to as &quot;Wannan Road&quot;. Because he was stationed in Wuhu, he was sometimes referred to as &quot;Wuhu Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Yuan Chang&#39;s Diary&quot;, Hu Chuan was &quot;imprisoned and deprived of food&quot; by Liu Yongfu, which caused his condition to worsen. He died on the ship, and only a corpse arrived in Xiamen. Yuan Chang was a student admitted by Zhang Zhidong when he was the deputy chief examiner of Zhejiang Province in his early years. Yuan Chang&#39;s &quot;Diary of a Sanren in Bixietai Mountain&quot; collected in &quot;Diaries of the Past Dynasties&quot; has the same content as Sun Zhimei&#39;s punctuated version of &quot;Yuan Chang&#39;s Diary&quot;. It is an abridged copy of reading notes and a small number of notes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the diary, in the 22nd year of Guangxu (1896), he met Chen Wenluo (Chen Zhongying) and recalled what happened the previous year. Yuan Chang wrote in 1896: &quot;Chen Zhongying once guarded Tainan. He talked about how his late friend Hu Shousan (biography) was an official in Taitung Prefecture. He asked Liu Yongfu for a bribe of 20,000 yuan for the commander-in-chief Liu Yongfu, but he was not allowed. He was imprisoned and had no food. Yongfu originally surrendered to the thieves. It is a true act of thieves. I went to Xia to beg the governor Zhang Gong to interrogate Liu, and released Huzhou as a pastor. Before crossing the Taiwan Strait to Xiamen, he drank wine on a ship. He was so angry that he could not pursue his ambition and became ill.&quot; (Compiled by Sun Zhimei, &quot;Yuan Chang&quot; (Diary, Volume 2, page 1224) Chen Wenluo was appointed as the prefect of Taipei in 1892. He had never been stationed in Tainan, but he obeyed the order to cross over in May. Chen Wenluo is a colleague of Hu Chuan. His official experience makes his testimony irreplaceable and authoritative, and he is closest to the historical scene. Jiawu and Yiweizhangzhidong were in charge of the governor of Liangjiang, and Wuhu Road was under the governor of Liangjiang. According to the diary, it was Yuan Chang who asked Zhang Zhidong to call Liu Yongfu to release Hu Chuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the governors of the late Qing Dynasty, Zhang Zhidong paid the most attention to Yi Wei&#39;s surrender. Tang Jingsong, the governor of Taiwan, and Liu Yongfu, the assistant commander of Taiwan Defense Nan&#39;ao Town, were all supported and commanded by Zhang Zhidong during the Sino-French War. , Hu Chuanze inspected the Li District of Hainan in 1887 on the order of Zhang Zhidong. These three people all have deep connections with Zhang Zhidong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation in Taiwan during the Yiwei period was very complicated. Zhang Zhidong, the Governor-General of Liangjiang, ostensibly complied with the imperial court&#39;s decision to cede Taiwan. He also secretly supported Tang Jingsong and Liu Yongfu in resisting Japan and protecting Taiwan, and provided money and weapons. However, after receiving a telegram from the imperial court to challenge him, he stopped and left Tang and Liu to their own devices. Decide on orientation. Tang and Liu were originally famous generals who fought against the French, but were misled by their fame. They initially decided to stay in Taiwan to fight against the Japanese. However, their military strength could not last long. Tang Jingsong soon sneaked back to the mainland, while Liu Yongfu was &quot;overshadowed&quot; by others. Liu Yongfu felt that he had been tricked by Zhang Zhidong. When most of the local officials had been transferred inland, it was impossible to detain Hu Chuan, the magistrate of Taitung Prefecture, to demand payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Liu Yongfu cut off support from the mainland, it was a relatively simple way to obtain military pay from local officials. After careful reading of what Chen Wenluo said about &quot;asking for bribes,&quot; I feel that it is more reasonable to interpret it as &quot;asking for salary.&quot; Liu Yongfu detained Hu Chuan and &quot;deprived him of food and drink in captivity.&quot; However, Hu Chuan had no cash in his hands, and it was very difficult to raise wages as the Japanese troops advanced deeper and deeper. Yuan Chang from Wuhu Road asked Zhang Zhidong for help and called Liu Yongfu to release him. Hu Chuan died on the ship returning to Xiamen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Chuan died because he was imprisoned by Liu Yongfu and fasted, which delayed his treatment and his condition worsened. This was not a normal death. During the Sino-French War, Tang Jingsong took the initiative to sneak into Vietnam and fight side by side with Liu Yongfu. He had a deeper understanding of Liu Yongfu. In 1884, he reported to the court through Cen Yuying, the governor of Yunnan and Guizhou, saying that Liu Yongfu &quot;valued wealth too much, treated his subordinates with little kindness, and showed no mercy.&quot; No discipline.&quot; (Page 91 of Volume 1 of &quot;The Telegram of Duke Zhang Wenxiang (Unpublished)&quot;) Linking this phrase with the way he treated Hu Chuan in 1895, another side of Liu Yongfu&#39;s character becomes apparent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在何种情况下，以色列会使用核武器？丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259428]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/lPGP575q0cEcOl9oyhbIVi2CCvaUQuFNCyKKvSjE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lPGP575q0cEcOl9oyhbIVi2CCvaUQuFNCyKK vSjE. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The northern Gaza Strip was attacked in Sderot, Israel, on October 23, 2023. Thick smoke rising after Israeli air strikes &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Israeli Knesset member &quot;Tali&quot; Gotliff (Revital &quot;Tally&quot; Gotliv) actually told the media that Israel should use nuclear weapons to retaliate against Hamas&#39;s attacks on Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gotliff also wrote on her social media: &quot;Jericho missile! Jericho missile! Strategic alert. Before considering troops entering. Doomsday weapon (used)! This is mine Viewpoint. May God bless us with all our strength.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She later publicly declared that &quot;only an explosion that shook the Middle East can restore this country (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;means Israel&lt;/span>;) dignity, strength and security! It’s time to kiss the end of the world. Launch powerful missiles without limit. Don’t level a neighborhood, smash and level the entire Gaza…nothing Show no mercy! Show no mercy!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, this is an outright nuclear threat. Gottliff is a lawyer and an opponent of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Her remarks have always been known for being extreme and crazy, so her extreme remarks this time were not regarded by anyone as a serious nuclear threat. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we have to admit the fact that Israel is indeed the only country in the Middle East that possesses nuclear weapons, and it almost decided to use nuclear weapons to save the defeat in the 1973 Yom Kippur War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is now a lot of public opinion that if anti-Israel allies such as Iran and Lebanese Hezbollah join the war, Hamas&#39;s goal of completely destroying Israel is expected to be achieved. But even if we do not take into account the fact that the combined conventional military strength of these opponents is still far behind that of Israel, as well as the fact that two US aircraft carriers are within easy reach, and only consider the existence of Israel&#39;s nuclear power, if Israel is completely defeated, this war will be The possibility of escalation to a nuclear war cannot be ruled out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So is Israel ready to use nuclear weapons in reality? To answer this question, we first need to understand what kind of nuclear power Israel has and what is the positioning of its nuclear strategy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Israel does not accept the supervision of its nuclear facilities by the International Atomic Energy Agency, and the Israeli government has always implemented a vague nuclear strategy, neither admitting nor denying the possession of nuclear weapons, and has not announced the deployment of its nuclear weapons to the outside world, the outside world is very concerned. It is difficult to know exactly how many nuclear weapons Israel possesses and whether the nuclear weapons are in a state of war readiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The international arms control research community now generally believes that Israel possesses at least 90 nuclear weapons and also retains key nuclear materials that can produce 200-300 nuclear weapons. Although Israel&#39;s nuclear weapons are very small, it is one of the very few countries with a triad of nuclear strike capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel has the Jericho medium-range ballistic missile with a range that can cover the entire Middle East and parts of Africa and Asia. This system is considered the core of Israel’s land-based nuclear strike force, among which the latest Jericho The Type 3 missile has a range of up to 4,800 kilometers, enough to cover Islamabad, the capital of Pakistan, and even Moscow, the capital of Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both the Israeli Air Force’s F-16 and F-15 fighter jets are capable of carrying nuclear bombs. The outside world even generally believes that Israel’s customized F-35 fighter jets will have the ability to drop nuclear bombs. It is expected that the Israeli Air Force’s There are at least 30 aerial nuclear bombs similar to the American B-61 type in the arsenal. This is the core of Israel&#39;s first-hand nuclear strike force. It maintains a very high level of combat readiness and can launch nuclear attacks from the air at any time, posing a threat to surrounding hostile countries. Very big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel is also one of the very few countries with underwater nuclear forces. Although it is not equipped with nuclear-powered submarines, the Dolphin-class conventionally powered submarines in service in its navy are equipped with nuclear cruise missiles. The Israeli Army and Air Force Even if they no longer exist, the submarine force can still carry out doomsday strike missions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This triad of nuclear strike capabilities enables Israel, despite its small land area, to possess nuclear combat capabilities that surpass those of Britain and France. It is one of the few countries that can carry out preemptive nuclear strikes against major deterrence targets. If Israel really faces the risk of national annihilation, it is very likely to use nuclear weapons at the last moment in a desperate move. In fact, Israel&#39;s nuclear deterrent took shape after the Fourth Middle East War. This was also one of the strategic considerations for secular Arab countries such as Egypt to normalize relations with Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Congressman Gotliff’s statement that nuclear weapons should be used in Gaza is obviously just a personal statement. No matter how crazy Israel is, the radiation fallout after the nuclear explosion is an unacceptable and catastrophic consequence for Israel, which is very close. However, if the war expands and Iran directly participates in the war, then Israel&#39;s use of nuclear weapons is not an impossible option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Israel conducted a joint exercise with the United States to attack Iran&#39;s nuclear facilities, and Israel&#39;s combat plan is likely to include the option of launching a nuclear strike against Iran in extreme circumstances. This Hamas attack is generally considered to be the worst situation Israel has encountered after the Yom Kippur War. If Israel had prepared for a nuclear strike in 1973, it is not ruled out that there will be relevant plans this time. What&#39;s worse is that the number and means of use of the Israeli military&#39;s nuclear weapons have now far exceeded those of the past. Therefore, the international community should be alert to the possibility and harm of Israel preparing to use nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>