<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[教育部：中小学校要确保学生课间正常活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:11:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the problem of &quot;restraint for 10 minutes between classes&quot; among primary and secondary school students in some places has attracted widespread attention from the society. Xinhua News Agency &quot; A reporter from Xinhua Viewpoint interviewed the relevant responsible comrades from the Ministry of Education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsible comrade said that it is very important and necessary for primary and secondary schools to arrange breaks between classes, which is helpful for students to regulate their emotions, relax their body and mind, enhance their physical fitness and prevent and control myopia. The Ministry of Education attaches great importance to students&#39; recess. The &quot;School Protection Regulations for Minors&quot; (Ministry of Education Order No. 50), which will be implemented on September 1, 2021, clearly states that legitimate exchanges between students during recess and other non-teaching time are not allowed. Unnecessary restrictions are placed on the freedom of speech and behavior such as games, activities outside the classroom, etc. In actual work, primary and secondary schools are required to arrange 30 minutes of physical activities between classes every day, and students should be arranged to go out of the classroom for appropriate activities and relaxation during each class break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The responsible comrade pointed out that the Ministry of Education will further urge local governments and schools to strictly implement relevant national regulations, follow the laws of education and the laws of students&#39; physical and mental development, and resolutely correct the simple restriction of students on the grounds of &quot;ensuring student safety&quot; Necessary recess breaks and activities will be implemented; localities and schools will be guided to scientifically implement management and safety precautions, strengthen inspections of outdoor facilities and personnel on duty, strengthen students’ safety knowledge education, minimize the risk of safety accidents, and make children happy Activities with confidence. At the same time, schools will be required to work closely with home-school communities, strive for parents&#39; understanding and social support, and work together to ensure students&#39; normal activities during class and promote students&#39; healthy growth and all-round development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽武校投毒致7死案开庭：“26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the incident, seven families of the deceased took a group photo. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;After the incident, seven families of the deceased took a group photo. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I thought to myself that this case could not be solved, but I didn’t expect it to be solved.” On the afternoon of October 31, 2023, 61-year-old Diao Shanyun told a Southern Weekend reporter on the phone. 26 years ago, his son Qian Min was poisoned to death at the age of 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xiping learned that the murderer had been captured in June 2023, and her brother Yang Changwei died in the same poisoning case. &quot;It&#39;s been 26 years, and I finally have an explanation for my brother.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident happened at about 7:00 on June 30, 1997, after about 130 teachers and students from the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County, Ma&#39;anshan, Anhui Province had eaten breakfast. Symptoms such as vomiting and convulsions occurred. Seven students, including Qian Min and Yang Changwei, died due to ineffective rescue efforts. An investigation by the public security agency found that they were all poisoned by poisonous 424 ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-six years later, on October 29, 2023, the Ma&#39;anshan City Public Security Bureau held a briefing meeting on the collective poisoning case at the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts Schools in Hexian County, and announced the arrest of two suspects in the case, Fu Moujie and Zhu A certain forest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9:00 in the morning on November 1, the case was heard in Maanshan Intermediate Court. The Ma&#39;anshan City Procuratorate requested that Zhu Moulin and Fu Mojie be held criminally responsible for poisoning. More than 40 relatives of the defendant and the victim attended the trial, but the verdict was not pronounced in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Poisoning more than 130 people in retaliation for the director of the museum&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the lunch recess, Yang Xiping told Southern Weekend reporters, “The person who was interrogated in the morning was named Fu, and he said that he had taken someone named Zhu. 500 yuan was poisoned, and I am confused and still have something to say.&quot; Yang Xiping said that the court will continue the trial of Zhu Moulin in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to upstream news reports, in court, the two defendants denied premeditating the crime. The public prosecution recommended that the two be sentenced to more than ten years in prison, life imprisonment or the death penalty. The families of the seven victims proposed nearly 7.7 million yuan in civil compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before the trial, Yang Xiping took out the photo of his younger brother that he brought with him and looked at a little boy wearing a red sportswear. He looked thin and was forever frozen at the age of 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are four Yang Xiping sisters. Yang Changwei is the youngest son and the only boy in the family. As the eldest son of the family, Yang Xiping went out to work early in order to support his younger brother in school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She loved this younger brother and took him with him wherever he went while working at home. His younger brother loved to fight, so his family sent him to the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County to learn boxing. Yang Xiping only remembered that the tuition was not cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We made seven or eight thousand at one time.” Diao Shanyun said that in the past, he and his husband Qian Farong were in business and could not take care of their youngest son Qian Min, so they settled in the martial arts school and planned to wait until his son was 18 years old. So he joined the army, &quot;he served for less than two years, and finally brought back an urn.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The blow was too big and I couldn’t bear it.” 62-year-old Qian Farong still uses Qian Min’s photo as a WeChat avatar. He remembers that after receiving the news that his son was poisoned on the day of the incident, , I rushed to the hospital, but it was already too late. At 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon on July 1, 1997, Qian Min suffered from convulsions and passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Qian Min squatting on a wooden stake. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;256828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qian Min squatted on the wooden post. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Qian Farong and his wife did not expect that the murderer was Fu Moujie, a coach who taught at the martial arts school. &quot;The coach surnamed Fu likes my son the most. They live in the same room. Every time we go to see my son, we have to thank him.&quot; Diao Shanyun said that his son often talks about how good Fu is, &quot;Why does he not like my son?&quot; My son lived in the same room with him. I heard from my son that Teacher Fu was very good and had a good character. How could he do this?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The indictment from the Ma&#39;anshan City Procuratorate shows that this case The poisoning case originated from a competition between two martial arts gyms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 1994, the defendants Zhu Moulin and Peng Mouwei ran the He County Shaolin Martial Arts Gym in Buji Town, Wujiang Town, He County, with Zhu Moulin as the director and Peng Mouwei as the head coach. During the business process, the two had conflicts. Peng Mouwei left the martial arts hall and reopened Hexian North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in Xibu Town, taking most of the teachers and students with him. Zhu Moulin therefore harbored a grudge against Peng Mouwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1996, the defendant Fu Moujie went to teach at the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County run by Peng Mouwei. While teaching, he gradually became dissatisfied with Peng Mouwei due to trivial matters. Zhu Moulin and Fu Mojie met after being introduced by others. During the process of getting along, they both expressed their dissatisfaction with Peng Mouwei, so they decided to retaliate against Peng Mouwei together and bring down Peng Mouwei&#39;s martial arts school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June of the following year, Fu Jie and Zhu Moulin discussed and decided to use poisoning to retaliate against Peng Mouwei. After Fu Jie implemented it, Zhu Moulin paid Fu Jie 50,000 yuan. Lin paid a certain order 500 yuan on the spot. At the end of the month, Fu Moujie resigned from the martial arts school and returned to his hometown in Jianli, Hubei Province to buy two packs of rat poison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the night before the incident, on the evening of June 29, Fu Moujie ran from the south of the North and South Shaolin Martial Arts School in He County to the kitchen of the martial arts school, and put two packets of rat poison in a red plastic basin on the table on the south side of the kitchen. After mixing the salted cowpeas inside, he fled from the original road and left Hexian County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 7 o&#39;clock the next morning, more than 130 teachers and students in the martial arts school developed vomiting, convulsions and other symptoms after eating breakfast. Yang Changwei, Wang Jun, Xing Tao, Liu Wenbao, Tian Dan, Tang Yuye, Qian Min, etc. 7 students died. During the on-site investigation, items such as salted cowpeas and gauze masks were extracted, and the ingredients of Toxin 424 were detected. In addition, the causes of death of 7 students were identified. After identification, the 7 students died of 424 rat poison poisoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Fu Mojie and Zhu Moulin were missing, and it was difficult for the police to solve the case for a while. The Ma&#39;anshan Municipal Public Security Bureau introduced at the briefing meeting that after the case occurred, the public security agency set up a task force to conduct visits and investigations around the crime scene and analyzed that Fu Moujie and Zhu Moulin were suspected of committing major crimes. On July 14, 1997, the public security organs listed Fu Jie and Zhu Moulin as fugitives on the Internet, offered a reward for their arrest, and continued to pursue them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo of Fu Moujie playing with students. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A photo of Fu Moujie playing with students. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Finally we can give an explanation”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“We don’t know who to look for. The person who poisoned him has run away. What do you think we should do?” Yang Xiping received the news from her neighbor half a month after the incident. When she returned home, she saw a coffin in the yard. She remembered clearly, &quot;The moment I knelt on the ground, I saw that my father&#39;s hair was all white and he was so thin.&quot; It doesn’t even look like it anymore.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diao Shanyun still can’t figure out why his son was poisoned to death by his favorite coach. After the couple buried their son, they bought a tombstone with the words: &quot;My beloved son Qian Min, unfortunately died unjustly in the June 30 massacre in 1997.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the second half of 2022, this case that had been silent for many years There was a breakthrough in the poisoning case. The task force discovered traces of Zhu Moulin in Guizhou and basically locked his hiding place in early 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early May 2023, the police in Jinjiang, Fujian Province used big data analysis and found that a man working in a tannery factory had similar physical characteristics to the suspect Fu Moujie. After repeated comparisons and confirmations by the police in the two places, they immediately Keep it under control. The task force rushed to Jinjiang, Fujian Province on the evening of May 6. After preliminary interrogation, Fu Moujie explained the crime to the public security organs. On May 9, Fu Moujie was escorted back to He County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time as Fu Moujie was captured, in the early morning of May 7, the task force went to Guiyang City, Guizhou Province. With the assistance of the local police, Zhu Moulin, who had concealed his identity and opened a local bottled water production company, was arrested at the factory. Successfully captured. When he saw the police who came to arrest him, Zhu Moulin froze in place and was surprised. He didn&#39;t expect that the police would come to his door after so long. In the early morning of May 8, Zhu Moulin was escorted back to He County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, at the press briefing on the martial arts school poisoning case, the Maanshan City Public Security Bureau task force introduced: After interrogation, Fu Moujie confessed that after committing the crime, he had been hiding in Tibet with no fixed residence. He moved to Xinyu City in Jiangxi Province, Dehua County in Fujian Province, Putian City, Jinjiang City and other places to make a living by doing odd jobs. Because he was afraid that his identity would be exposed and investigated by the public security organs, he did not dare to register his identity information, and did not dare to get vaccinated or take nucleic acid tests during the epidemic. When applying for a job, I never choose a position or negotiate salary, just to have a place to hide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhu Moulin&#39;s account, in order to avoid attacks by the public security organs, he concealed his true identity and wandered alone during his absconding period. He first hid in Poyang County, Jiangxi Province for 2 years, and then moved to Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province to work. When I opened a bottled water production company in Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, and Guiyang City, Guizhou Province, I have been living a life of fear for so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In June, my dad received a notice saying that the murderer had been found, and I came back immediately.&quot; Yang Xiping said that when he heard that the murderer had been found, both he and his father cried on the phone. &quot;Finally, I can give him some help.&quot; My brother gave me the explanation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xi often thinks that if his brother is still here, this family must be different. She asked her sisters not to marry far away, &quot;because there is no younger brother and my mother is not in good health.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xiping said that his mother became seriously ill due to the loss of his son, and his father suffered a neurasthenia after suffering a shock. As a result, his third sister no longer wanted to study. &quot;My father often couldn&#39;t find anyone at night. He would either go to his brother&#39;s grave and cry, or he would go to the river or the bricks. We would search everywhere.&quot; Yang&#39;s father has been blaming himself for hurting his son and can&#39;t get out. Because it was he who sent his youngest son to an expensive martial arts school despite his family&#39;s objections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31, Yang Xiping rushed to He County with his family to prepare for the court session the next day. She hoped that Fu and Zhu would be punished as they deserved. &quot;If nothing happens to my brother, he will be 37 years old this year and it&#39;s time to start a family.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访俄专家安德烈·科尔图诺夫：俄乌冲突越早结束，对大家都越好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今秋的北方，为何又热又霾？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 03/bc2b2a112d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;On the morning of November 1, 2023, People&#39;s Park, Luancheng District, Shijiazhuang City , citizens wearing masks went for morning exercises in the haze. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The autumn in North China in 2023 is a bit hot and hazy. On November 3, with the arrival of cold air, diffusion conditions gradually improved, and pollution was gradually cleared from north to south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High temperatures have exceeded 40℃ for many days in a row in summer. At the end of October, temperatures in Beijing, Tianjin, Shandong and other places rarely warmed up again. The highest temperatures in Zhengzhou City, Henan Province even reached 30℃ on November 1st and 2nd. and 29℃. In early November in Beijing, there were still many people wearing short sleeves and shorts on the streets at noon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region and surrounding cities are plunged into smog. According to statistics from the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control, as of October 30, 20 cities in the region have initiated heavy pollution weather warnings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The pollution processes that have occurred in North China in the past two days once again remind us that China still has a long way to go to fundamentally improve air pollution.” He Kebin, academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering and director of the Carbon Neutrality Research Institute of Tsinghua University, said in the speech It was stated at the 2023 Annual Meeting of the China Clean Air Policy Partnership held in Beijing on November 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is it affected by meteorological conditions, air pollution is also inextricably linked to global climate change. Zhu Tong, academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and professor of the School of Environmental Science and Engineering at Peking University, said at the above meeting that as pollutants emitted from anthropogenic sources decrease, climate warming will also aggravate air pollution, such as smoke and dust brought by forest wildfires, near-ground The aggravation and generation of ozone pollution will further affect human health. Solving related basic scientific problems is the challenge and focus in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The overall situation is good, and the performance of key areas is average&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from late October, the haze in the north began to spread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I just came back from Hebei very late yesterday. Some cities have activated orange warnings for heavy air pollution, and some areas have worse air pollution than Beijing.&quot; Li Pei, a first-level inspector of the Atmospheric Environment Department of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment said at the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to monitoring data, at 17:00 on November 2, the real-time PM2.5 concentration in Beijing was 73 μg/m³, which was a &quot;good&quot; level, while Xingtai City, Baoding City, Handan City, and Shijiazhuang City in Hebei Province broke through 200μg/m³, reaching &quot;severe pollution&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39. gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/26e1d07d39.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;256942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;Daily changes in PM2.5 concentration nationwide from October 22 to 29, 2023 (Source: China Environmental Monitoring Station, Henan Provincial Ecological Environment Monitoring and Safety Center) National Joint Center for Air Pollution Prevention and Control/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2013 to 2017 and 2017 to 2020, our country implemented the &quot;Air Pollution Prevention and Control Action Plan&quot; (&quot;Ten Measures for Atmospheric Pollution&quot;). &quot;), &quot;Three-Year Action Plan to Win the War to Defend the Blue Sky.&quot; Since 2013, the average annual concentration of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; has maintained a downward trend as a whole, and the number of cities that meet the standards is also increasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, according to &quot;Atmospheric China 2023: China&#39;s Air Pollution Prevention and Control Process&quot; released by the Asian Clean Air Center, in 2022, the proportion of cities nationwide that meet standards will increase from 70.2% to 74.6%; nationwide severe and above The ratio of polluted days was 0.9%, a year-on-year decrease of 0.4 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the overall performance of the country is good, the performance of key regions is average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations in the Yangtze River Delta region remained the same year-on-year; Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding &quot;2+26&quot; cities and the Fenwei Plain both increased year-on-year, with increases of 2.3% and 9.5% respectively. %. Among the 168 key cities, the number of cities with PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations rising instead of falling has increased from 24 in 2021 to 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cold air activity is weak&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Meteorological conditions are the external cause of this round of polluted weather. Li Pei said that although my country&#39;s air pollution control has achieved certain results, the results are not yet stable. Generally speaking, it has not yet gotten rid of meteorological influences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The expert team of the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control analyzed that since October 22, the cold air activity in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas has been weak, and the surface temperature and relative humidity of the lower atmosphere have been higher than normal, which is easy to Form regional pollution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to popular science from the China Meteorological Administration, fog and haze are more likely to occur in autumn and winter, which are related to calm weather. The &quot;quiet&quot; in static and stable weather means that the wind speed in the horizontal direction is small, and &quot;stable&quot; means that the atmospheric stratification in the vertical direction is relatively stable, and there is little vertical exchange between the lower atmosphere and the middle atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The formation of stable weather is related to factors such as topography and circulation. Special terrains such as mountains, hills, and basins can hinder the circulation of air. The Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region is affected by the &quot;dustpan-shaped&quot; terrain of high in the northwest and low in the southeast. Pollutants are easy to accumulate in front of the Taihang Mountains and Yanshan Mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the circulation factor, if there is a temperature inversion in the atmospheric stratification (the lower layer is cold and the upper layer is warm), heavier air will be in the lower layer and lighter air will be in the upper layer. The atmospheric structure is stable and vertically diffused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Air quality is not only affected by short-term meteorological conditions, but also related to long-term climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fang Chong, chief forecaster of the Central Meteorological Observatory, generally speaking, mid-to-late October has entered the active period of cold air, but in 2023 the cold air will be significantly weaker and the temperature will be significantly higher. Currently, a total of 237 national-level weather stations have broken the historical extreme value of the highest temperature in late October, which is a rare situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In 2023, Canada&#39;s forest fires had a serious impact on New York&#39;s air quality. At a time when New Yorkers may have forgotten what air pollution is, the wildfires reminded them that climate change will bring extraordinary consequences. Serious air pollution will cause harm to human health.&quot; Zhu Tong said at the meeting that in addition to cases of wildfires, future climate change will also bring more frequent extreme climate events such as extreme high temperatures, droughts, and sandstorms. The harm caused will also be multiplied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010. JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5354fa2010.JPG&quot; data-key= &quot;256943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2023, severe air pollution occurred in Toronto due to the spread of smoke and dust from wildfires in Canada. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; CO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, CH&lt;sub>;4&lt;/sub>;, N&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O, etc.) and atmospheric pollutants (such as SO&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;, NO&lt; Sub>;x&lt;/sub>;, PM, etc.), the two are highly homologous, and most of them are generated by mineral combustion emissions. Therefore, when air pollution occurs, it may also represent an increase in greenhouse gas emissions; secondly, Many components of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; will affect atmospheric radiation, thereby affecting the energy balance and causing climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Qianyuan said that aerosol particles may also participate in the formation of clouds and rain, thereby affecting the weather system and climate conditions; on the other hand, climate change itself may lead to increased air pollution, such as rising temperatures may cause Increases in ozone concentration, such as changes in atmospheric circulation patterns, may affect atmospheric stability and diffusion conditions, leading to changes in PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; concentrations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pollution reduction and carbon reduction synergies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;He Kebin said that since 2013, the &quot;Ten Measures for Atmosphere&quot; have &quot;won the battle to defend the blue sky&quot;. , emissions of air pollutants have declined, but the annual emission reduction range has gradually narrowed. This reflects the marginal effect of air pollution prevention and control. “All the good things, the big profits, and the big emission reduction potentials have been done.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The internal cause of this round of pollution in Beijing, Tianjin, Hebei and surrounding areas is still man-made emissions. A team of experts from the National Joint Center for Atmospheric Pollution Prevention and Control explained that emissions from motor vehicles, industrial furnaces, etc. are the main sources of PM&lt;sub>;2.5&lt;/sub>; pollution in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas, and straw burning has a negative impact on local PM&lt;sub>; 2.5&lt;/sub>;Pollution contributes prominently. The activity level of industrial enterprises, heavy trucks and the number of straw fire points in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas increased month-on-month, and pollution emissions showed an increasing trend. In terms of industrial sources, since late October, regional industrial electricity consumption has increased by about 5% compared with early and mid-October; in terms of mobile sources, the traffic volume of heavy trucks in Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas is at a high level since autumn and winter, which is higher than that in October. The early to mid-term prices were about 14% higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Air pollution control needs to find new impetus, and the synergy of pollution reduction and carbon reduction is an important starting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After carbon peaks in 2030, the role of end-of-pipe governance will become smaller and smaller, and it will gradually shift to the adjustment and reduction of the four major structures (energy structure, industrial structure, transportation structure, and land use structure). Pollution reduction and carbon reduction will create synergies.&quot; He Kebin believes that whether it is for economic development or improving air quality, carbon reduction is the recent pressure and the driving force for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the National Development and Reform Commission and other ministries and commissions jointly issued the &quot;Pollution Reduction and Carbon Reduction Synergy and Efficiency Implementation Plan&quot;, stating that &quot;collaboratively promote pollution reduction and carbon reduction to achieve integrated planning and Integrated deployment, integrated promotion, and integrated assessment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Gang, deputy director of the Environmental Planning Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, introduced at the meeting that from the perspective of air pollutants and carbon emissions, two-thirds of cities have not achieved synergy during the &quot;Thirteenth Five-Year Plan&quot; period. Improvement; from an industry perspective, although pollutant emissions in most industries are currently showing a significant downward trend, carbon emissions are still growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Gang said that collaborative governance of pollution reduction and carbon reduction is not like other pollution control work in the past. There is a lot of international experience to draw from. At present, my country&#39;s pollution reduction and carbon reduction collaborative efficiency work faces some challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, there is still a lack of support in the theoretical system, and research on the characterization of pollution emissions should be strengthened to identify the homology and heterogeneity of emissions; in terms of regulation, target allocation, smart regulation, governance technology, etc. still need to be A series of studies will be carried out; relevant policies also need to be further coordinated. The other side of challenges also means opportunities. If we respond proactively, air pollution control and carbon emission control can achieve a win-win situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清剿电诈还是军阀混战？缅北果敢到底怎么了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259885]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/aLb8TNP0traIg28E2TC5ktDQUzChTKWZqcnqnO5f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/aLb8TNP0traIg28E2TC5ktDQUzChTK WZqcnqnO5f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 28, 2023, in northern Shan State, Myanmar, a missile struck from a Military base launch&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 27, 2023, Myanmar in Lashio, Gwei and other places in northern Myanmar Government military positions were attacked by armed forces and fierce fighting broke out. According to Myanmar&#39;s &quot;Kokang Information Network&quot;, the Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army issued a statement on the same day claiming responsibility for the armed attack and that the operation was to &quot;clear out the electronic fraud militia.&quot; At about 4 a.m. local time on the 27th, the Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army launched attacks on military deployment areas, police posts, toll stations and other strongholds in Qingshui River, Gunong, Lashio and other places in Shan State. At about 5 o&#39;clock, many strategic strongholds including Qingshuihe and Gunong were occupied by the Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, when the war broke out, at a regular press conference of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, spokesperson Mao Ning said regarding the military conflict that broke out between the Myanmar military and the Myanmar Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army (MNDAA): &quot; China pays close attention to the relevant conflicts and calls on relevant parties to cease fire and end the war as soon as possible, insist on resolving differences through dialogue and consultation through peaceful means, avoid escalation of the situation, and take practical and effective measures to ensure the security and stability of the China-Myanmar border.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In addition to the Myanmar Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army (MNDAA), the Ta&#39;ang National Liberation Army (TNLA) and the Arakan Army (AA) also participated in attacks against Myanmar government forces. According to information from the Kokang Allied Forces, the three anti-government armed forces have a total participation of more than 15,000 troops, and the fighting is mainly concentrated in northern Shan State. This is the largest battle that has broken out in the region since the Kokang War in 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the fighting site is close to the China-Myanmar border, there has been a wave of refugees at the border ports. Relevant departments of the Chinese government have begun to provide shelter and assistance to incoming refugees fleeing the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But how did the war break out? What impact will it have on the future situation of the region? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/igdn0q9Q3pCnq5i7gjYGwF7ElsJnrCTscTGLsPLA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/igdn0q9Q3pCnq5i7gjYGwF7ElsJnrCTscTGLsPLA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 27, 2023, in Shan State, Myanmar, Major General Peng Deqi (fourth from left) of the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army commanded the operation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The battle for survival under the political war&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although Myanmar is a close neighbor of China, the two sides share more than 2,100 kilometers of border, and Myanmar is the largest country in terms of land area and population among the Southeast Asian countries bordering China. However, for most Chinese, Myanmar is still a relatively unfamiliar country, and its presence is quite limited. There are far fewer Chinese people traveling to Myanmar than to neighboring Southeast Asian countries such as Thailand, Vietnam or Cambodia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the past two years, Myanmar has gained notoriety in our country&#39;s public opinion due to telecom fraud and &quot;Gayaozi&quot; (illegal organ harvesting and trade). With the dissemination of relevant social media information and film and television works, more and more Chinese people have learned that the northern region of Myanmar adjacent to Yunnan is an area where telecommunications fraud and criminal gang activities are rampant, and the local government is helpless and even complicit in this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day when the conflict in northern Myanmar broke out, the Kokang Alliance Army&#39;s social media immediately released a statement titled &quot;Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army, Ta&#39;ang National Liberation Army, and Arakan Army &quot;10.27&quot; Action Statement.&quot; mentioned, &quot;We will eradicate telecommunications fraud, fraud dens and their protective umbrellas across the country, including the China-Myanmar border areas. The three coalition forces decided to jointly carry out this military operation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement After the release, the propaganda of these three ethnic and local armed forces continued to contain content about destroying telecom fraud gangs and saving trapped compatriots. Among them, the Kokang Allied Forces even released a pre-war mobilization video of a unit of the Allied Forces on the short video social platform. The brigade commander who issued the mobilization order said in a solemn tone: Our mission is to eradicate the electronic fraud group, eliminate drugs, and rescue our compatriots. no confidence! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then the soldiers in uniform shouted in unison: Yes! have! have! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are not just a bunch of people who shout loud slogans. When it comes to fighting, the Kokang Allied Forces have always been good at attacking. As early as the Kokang War in 2015, the Allied Forces launched an attack under the eyes of the Myanmar government forces. Not only did the vanguard troops enter Lao Cai, the capital of the Kokang region, on the day the war started, but they also later sniped and killed a Myanmar Army deputy from a distance behind enemy lines. brigadier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the last moment of the Kokang War that year, the Kokang Allied Forces defended the Nantianmen Highlands at an altitude of more than 2,000 meters in the north of Lao Cai for two months despite the artillery fire and aircraft bombings of the Burmese army. In the end, the Burmese army launched a general offensive. , none of the more than 20 defenders who held on to the end surrendered and all died in the battle. Their fighting will shocked even the opponent Burmese army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the conflict on October 27, the Kokang Allied Forces performed even more rapidly. Within just a few days of the war, they quickly occupied the Qingshui River area adjacent to Lao Cai and an important port with China. , captured more than 60 Burmese army strongholds, successfully relied on light infantry to destroy 6 armored vehicles, and completely wiped out the Burmese airborne special forces who came to provide parachute support. Under the rapid offensive of the Allied Forces, a battalion of Myanmar government officers and soldiers organized and surrendered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Arakan Army and the Ta’ang National Liberation Army, which cooperated with the Kokang Allied Forces, fought on the outside. The Ta’ang Army not only attacked Denni Town, but also successfully destroyed the nearby Nanda River Bridge to prevent the Burmese army from using the road to reinforce the Kokang. area. The Arakan Army and the Ta&#39;ang Army attacked the Lashio area and once shelled the most important Lashio Airport in northern Myanmar, causing the grounding of civil aviation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the current situation, the Burmese military strongholds outside Lao Cai, the capital of Kokang, have basically been cleared. The attack and defense of Lao Cai will probably begin soon. Once the Kokang Allied Forces successfully regain control of Lao Cai Right, then this battle can basically be declared a victory. Compared with the Kokang war in 2015, the current Kokang Allied Forces are closer to their goal, which is to retake Lao Cai and regain control of the Kokang area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the political narrative of the ethnic local armed forces in northern Myanmar, they are the positive heroes, and there are also evil villains accordingly. The villains this time are the four Guogan families. The four major families are the Bai family represented by Bai Chengcheng, the Wei family of Wei Chaoren, the Ming family of Ming Xuechang, and the Liu family of Liu Abao. The representatives of these four families are all powerful figures in the Kokang area and are the mortal enemies of the Kokang Allied Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the anti-telecom fraud narrative, the four major families are well-deserved as the villains. The companies of these four families have been operating telecom fraud businesses under the name of entrepreneurial parks for many years. , thus gaining a lot of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real international politics or regional disputes, the image of justice is part of the application of power. War is a continuation of politics, and politics often requires the blessing of morality. Destroying telecom fraud to save compatriots is not necessarily just talk. For the Kokang Allied Forces, as long as they successfully recover Kokang and completely eliminate the disgusting industry of telecom fraud, it is not a problem. After all, this is not their source of income. However, if it is said that the Kokang Allied Forces are only going to war to eradicate telecommunications fraud, that is not consistent with the facts. After all, this is not the first war between the Kokang Allied Forces and the four major Kokang families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early on August 8, 2009, before northern Myanmar became a den of electronic fraud, Bai Suocheng, one of the later leaders of the four major families and deputy commander of the Kokang Alliance Army at the time, joined forces with the Myanmar army and other Three major families launched a coup and drove Peng Jiasheng, the first leader of the Kokang Alliance Army, out of the Kokang area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, after six years of dormancy, the Kokang Allied Forces launched a counterattack against the government forces in the Kokang region during the Spring Festival. At that time, the Kokang Allied Forces launched the attack in the name of returning home for the New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, not only was the last war not successful militarily, but it also did not have a high enough voice politically. It was even easily regarded by bystanders as a battle between warlords and interest groups. This time, the Kokang Allied Forces have grown for more than eight years. Their military, political, and propaganda capabilities are far better than before, and the results are likely to be very different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, regardless of whether it is counter-terrorism or not, for the Kokang Allied Forces, being able to fight back their hometown of Kokang and regain control of the old street is the basis for their survival. The leader of the previous generation, Peng Jiasheng, died of illness in February 2022. The current Kokang Allied Forces, under the leadership of the current commander Peng Deren (Peng Jiasheng’s eldest son), has left his homeland to fight guerrillas for many years. But this is not a long-term solution. Without the support of their hometown and a solid base, it will be difficult for the team to develop and grow. Therefore, the military conflict that broke out on October 27, 2023, is equivalent to a battle for survival for the Kokang Allied Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/njM3JUYhKJyfESN1197AS2088mFAwDbyciHIGs5A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/njM3JUYhKJyfESN1197AS2088mFAwDbyciHIGs5A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 4, 2023, in Naypyitaw, Myanmar, Chairman of the National Governing Council of Myanmar Min Aung Hlaing attended the military parade&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking at the Kokang from across Myanmar&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of those familiar with the background of the war in northern Myanmar, the Kokang Allied Forces this time It is expected to be invincible on the battlefield, because as early as 2021, an enemy far more deadly than the ethnic local armed forces in northern Myanmar appeared in Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 1, 2021, Myanmar political leader Aung San Suu Kyi was arrested by the Myanmar military at her home and was eventually sentenced to 33 years in prison. For Aung San Suu Kyi, who was already 78 years old at the time, this was tantamount to a life sentence. On the day Aung San Suu Kyi was arrested, large-scale street protests broke out across Myanmar. In the end, large-scale clashes broke out between demonstrators and military police. Many Western countries condemned the Myanmar military government and announced the restoration of comprehensive sanctions on Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Aung San Suu Kyi’s political party, the National League for Democracy (NLD), was also banned by the military government. This series of actions basically announced the complete break between the Myanmar military government and the National League for Democracy. This caused the core political elites of the NLD and their supporters to completely cut off the possibility of parliamentary politics. The military government&#39;s violent suppression of demonstrations also caused Aung San Suu Kyi&#39;s supporters believed that the only way to fight against the military government was through force, so they announced the establishment of the National Unity Government of the Republic of the Union of Myanmar (Burmese abbreviation NUG). Its political proposition is to overthrow the military government through force and regain power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The NUG can be regarded as the NLD&#39;s government-in-exile, which announced the establishment of a military organization in 2021: the People&#39;s Defense Forces (PDF in Burmese). On September 7, 2021, NUG announced the launch of a &quot;people&#39;s defense war&quot; against the military government and called on citizens across Myanmar to resist the military government. For the Myanmar military government, this is undoubtedly a greater threat than the local ethnic armed forces in northern Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since independence after World War II, Myanmar’s civil war has never stopped, but the armed forces of NUG PDF are different from the enemies faced by the previous Myanmar government forces. In past civil wars, the main enemies the Myanmar Army faced were ethnic minority armed forces in border areas, such as northern Myanmar and the Golden Triangle. Such armed forces may be powerful, such as the United Wa State Army, which has heavy equipment including anti-aircraft missiles and armed helicopters, or the Kachin Independence Army, which has sophisticated tactics and well-trained training. However, the characteristic of this type of army is that it is concentrated in areas where its ethnic groups are concentrated, and their political demands are only to maintain the independence and territory of their own ethnic groups. Therefore, the fighting between the Myanmar government army and these local ethnic armed forces is mainly concentrated in the northern region of Myanmar, which is the so-called Upper Myanmar. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Myanmar, also known as Lower Myanmar, is mainly dominated by the Bamar people. The Bamar people account for up to 68% of the population of Myanmar and are the absolute majority of the population. It is difficult for local armed forces of ethnic groups in northern Myanmar to penetrate Entered Burma to fight. Politically, ethnic local armed forces have no such demands. The core members of the NUG are themselves Bamar political elites, and their main area of ​​activity happens to be in Lower Myanmar. Especially after the NUG established the armed forces PDF, the core members were sent to the Kachin and other ethnic local armed regimes to learn how to fight, and at the same time, they used Its underground network in lower Burmese society continues to carry out propaganda and mobilization. A large number of soldiers and officers with combat experience were absorbed into PDF. In recent years, the Myanmar government military academies have not only had difficulty recruiting students, but there have even been incidents of graduates taking their equipment and defecting to PDF. So far, at least 16,000 Myanmar military and police personnel have defected and joined PDF. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to poaching and gathering intelligence, PDF began to engage in guerrilla warfare with the Burmese army in lower Myanmar, and its organized combat units even appeared near Myanmar&#39;s capital, Naypyitaw, and the largest city, Yangon. In May 2023, the NUG announced the establishment of about 300 battalions and columns, banned the government agencies of the military junta in 250 towns and villages in Lower Myanmar, and established its own regime. In June 2023, NUG announced the formation of the 5101st Battalion, which was actually established in the Yangon area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the PDF has not had any decent results since its establishment, and has not successfully annihilated any Burmese army troops, its direct threat to the political and economic center of Burma in Lower Burma has forced the Burmese government forces to allocate Spend a lot of resources to defend against PDF sneak attacks. The NUG&#39;s intelligence and mobilization capabilities have also greatly weakened the Myanmar military government&#39;s ability to control Lower Myanmar. The reason why the PDF is considered more deadly than any ethnic local armed forces is because their military goal is not to occupy territory or support themselves with troops, but to completely destroy the Myanmar military government and regain power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we look back at the Kokang conflict in 2015, we will find that the Myanmar government army could easily mobilize several brigades from Lower Myanmar to assist Kokang, while the air force could take off directly from surrounding airports to concentrate its forces. Attack the Kokang Allied Forces&#39; positions. However, after the conflict broke out this time, the intensity and equipment level of government forces in mobilizing reinforcements were far lower than last time, and even air support was quite limited. The fundamental reason is that the mobile forces at the hands of the Myanmar military government are already stretched thin. If a large number of troops are deployed to support Kokang, the PDFs around Yangon and Naypyitaw will definitely take advantage of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4lWn6pGSgtdzDnCKmw06nWYn9rgCT1PcPrrxBIvb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4lWn6pGSgtdzDnCKmw06nWYn9rgCT1PcPrrxBIvb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 8, 2023, in Shan State, Myanmar, the Ta&#39;ang National Liberation Army conducted military training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why is courage so important? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For the Kokang Allied Forces, Kokang is of course crucial, because that is the only goal of this army at the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the four major families of Kokang, Kokang is their political capital and a treasure trove of wealth. Losing Kokang means losing everything that two generations have worked hard for for decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the military government, Kokang is also crucial. The reason why the leader of the military government, General Min Aung Hlaing, stands out among many generals is because he successfully occupied Kokang and expelled Peng Jiasheng’s troops in 2009, making him He gained unprecedented prestige in the military and became the number one figure among the new generation of generals. Although Kokang is only the first special zone in Shan State with a permanent population of 140,000 and an area of ​​only 2,000 square kilometers, if it fails, the chain effect will be fatal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, from a political point of view, the Myanmar government forces will not give up Kokang easily, and will naturally try their best to support the local armed forces in Kokang to prevent the Kokang Allied Forces from succeeding in their counterattack. Therefore, although the Kokang Allied Forces made good progress in the early stage, it was still difficult to launch an actual offensive to retake Lao Cai. The price they are willing to pay to aid Kokang is the key to whether the Myanmar military government and the four major families can hold on to Kokang. If the level of military investment in the last Kokang conflict can be maintained, it may still be difficult for the Kokang Allied Forces to retake Lao Cai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“花西子事件”后，再谈美妆国货的初心与始终丨日化行业科创力榜单解读]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259879]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 12:45:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Huaxizi’s “79 Yuan Eyebrow Pen” has caused heated discussions, and domestic beauty products have become the focus. Some people think that domestic products have long deviated from &quot;high quality and low price&quot; and stay away from them, while others continue to support &quot;wild consumption&quot;, and more people feel dazzled and difficult to distinguish between reality and reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;What is the development and evolution trajectory of domestic beauty products? Can technological innovation empower product and market power? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Southern Weekend&#39;s Science and Technology Innovation Research Center recently released the 2023 list of companies&#39; science and technology innovation in China&#39;s daily chemical industry to find out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/118abecb6a445039e863364f0b716b02.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 100% ; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;1291&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/118abecb6a445039e863364f0b716b02.png&quot; data -key=&quot;256887&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;645&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Southern Weekend Enterprise Science and Technology Innovation Database, the daily chemical industry included in the database in 2023 There are 16 listed companies in total, covering cosmetics, detergents, oral products and other fields. Among them, 15 companies disclosed R&amp;D investment. Excluding 1 ST company, the total R&amp;D investment of 14 listed companies reached 1.154 billion yuan, with an average R&amp;D investment of 82 million yuan, of which 5 companies invested more than 100 million yuan in R&amp;D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bettany &lt;span>; (300957.SZ) &lt;/span>; ranked first with a score of 77.13. Its representative brand is Winona, with a score difference of 16 points from the second place. Twice as many as 10th place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Proya &lt;span>; (603605.SH) &lt;/span>; and Shanghai Jahwa &lt;span>; (600315.SH) &lt;/span>; ranked second and third with 60.93 points and 60.87 points respectively. name, Proya won by a narrow margin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Jahwa is a representative of old domestic products, with brands such as Herborist and Yuze. Mingchen Health &lt;span>; (002919.SZ) &lt;/span>;, which is also an established domestic product, ranked fourth. Its products are mainly detergents, representing the brand Youdihuazhixiu; Lafang Jiaqi, which has a similar business, &lt;span >;(603630.SH)&lt;/span>;, ranked tenth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shui Yang Shares &lt;span>; (300740.SZ) &lt;/span>;, Yixian E-commerce &lt;span>; (YSG.N) &lt;/span>;, Marumi Shares &lt;span>; (603983.SH) &lt;/span>;Three rising stars ranked fifth, sixth and seventh respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Research and development, it is the king of domestic products&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Basically looking at revenue, Bethany can only rank It ranks third in the industry, but it firmly occupies the top spot in terms of technological innovation in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend&#39;s enterprise scientific and technological innovation evaluation system covers R&amp;D expenditure, R&amp;D personnel, R&amp;D investment proportion, intellectual property rights, core awards, and operating income from the three dimensions of R&amp;D investment, R&amp;D output, and company development. , operating profit, net profit, company market value and other nearly 30 subdivided indicators. The score of each indicator item is based on the ratio of the company indicator value to the highest indicator value of the industry indicator item. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;R&amp;D investment, including R&amp;D investment amount, personnel and intensity, is the most critical indicator on the list and is also the competitive advantage of Bethany. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;In 2022, Bethany’s R&amp;D investment reached 278 million yuan, accounting for nearly a quarter of the entire industry, ranking among the top ten Among them, except for Shanghai Jahwa, the R&amp;D investment amount of the other eight companies is less than half of that of Beitani. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;In addition, its R&amp;D investment intensity exceeds 5%, and the sales revenue achieved by applying core technologies accounts for more than 95% of the company&#39;s main business revenue. Volume research and development, had to accept it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/4730fa2d8c9ef11b8664ea5dc8b5edc1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center; width: 100%; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;645&quot; height=&quot;1070&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03 /4730fa2d8c9ef11b8664ea5dc8b5edc1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256888&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;645&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1070&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beitaini was established in 2010, and its main brand Wei Nona was born in Dianhong Pharmaceutical &lt;span>; (now acquired by Germany&#39;s Bayer Group)&lt;/span>;. The background of a pharmaceutical company and the &quot;sensitive skin&quot; track it chose determined the path of research and development of Winona Roll, and also set the tone for Bettany&#39;s high-level research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, China&#39;s sensitive skin market segment has been dominated by big European and American brands. Winona&#39;s ability to take a share of the big European and American brands is inseparable from its insistence on independent research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Bethany Research Institute is the main platform for Bethany’s R&amp;D innovation. In 2022, Bethany Research Institute established an innovative raw material R&amp;D center based on the original functional cosmetics R&amp;D center, established a systematic Yunnan characteristic plant active substance screening and evaluation system, and carried out a large number of functional research based on Yunnan characteristic plants. Independent research and development. As of the end of 2022, the company has successfully independently developed 40 functional cosmetic plant raw materials, exported 40 technical standards, and industrialized 11 Yunnan specialty plant actives including purslane and green thorn fruit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Independent research and development has created the product strength of its core brand Winona, and also laid the foundation for telling its brand story and creating a brand image suitable for sensitive skin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Proya, ranked second, has been a &quot;constant winner&quot; in the domestic product list in recent years, but it missed the championship in the science and technology innovation industry list, mainly due to insufficient investment in research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Proya&#39;s revenue reached 6.385 billion yuan, ranking third in the industry after Shanghai Jahwa and Blue Moon Group. Its R&amp;D investment amounted to 128 million yuan, also ranking third. , but its R&amp;D investment intensity is only 2%, ranking fourth from the bottom. Even Yixian e-commerce, which is often criticized for &quot;emphasis on marketing but not on R&amp;D,&quot; has an R&amp;D investment intensity of 3.51%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Old domestic products, struggling to transform&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Jahwa, ranked third, is the first to develop in China The beauty and personal care group includes old brands founded in the 20th century such as Herborist and Maxam, as well as a new brand Yuze that focuses on sensitive skin. With a relatively complete product matrix, Shanghai Jahwa ranks first in the industry with revenue of 7.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the oldest domestic products, Shanghai Jahwa’s online channel layout and innovative marketing methods are not as good as those of new brands. In 2022, its online channels will account for less than 40% of total revenue, while cosmetics companies such as Bettany, Proya and Shuiyang Shares will account for more than 80% during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emphasis on offline channels may be closely related to the high market share of Shanghai Jahwa’s personal care and home cleaning brand. Compared with marketing, the old brand seems to be more willing to invest in product research and development than most new brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai Jahwa’s R&amp;D investment in 2022 will be approximately 180 million yuan, ranking second in the industry after Beitani. Its research and development directions cover a wide range of areas, including medical research co-creation, traditional Chinese medicine and herbal medicine, cell biology, safety and efficacy assessment equipment, packaging design, AI customization and beauty instrument platforms. In the annual reports of other companies, the content of AI is usually related to sales channels, but in Shanghai Jahwa, AI is truly related to products and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Shanghai Jahwa’s transformation and upgrading is the blessing of digital intelligence and biotechnology to its main business; the fourth-ranked old domestic product Mingchen Health is launching a dual business model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fiscal year 2022, Mingchen Health invested 110 million yuan in research and development, and also invested in daily chemical products and game business. Of the 23 R&amp;D investment projects disclosed during the same period, nearly half were game R&amp;D; R&amp;D personnel increased by nearly 80% year-on-year to 520, mainly due to new additions to the game business segment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mingchen Health developed the game business through acquisitions in 2020. In 2021, the revenue of the game business and the daily chemical business will account for 37%. In 2022, the ratio of the two will be very close, and the game business will account for 30%. 47%. The 2023 semi-annual report shows that the game business revenue accounts for more than 70%. Next year it will most likely be classified into the software and information services industry. However, this is also a transformation of traditional daily chemical companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 16 daily chemical companies, only 5 including Betteni, Proya, Mingchen Health, Pepperl+Jie, and Blue Moon Group achieved year-on-year revenue growth in fiscal 2022. In fact, the revenue of Mingchen Health&#39;s daily chemical products also declined year-on-year, but thanks to the doubling of game business revenue, the overall revenue increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gross profit margin of Mingchen’s health game business will reach 73.55% in 2022, while the gross profit margin of the daily chemical business will be only 33.75%. In a period of industry involution, decisively exploring new businesses is a new path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao Golden King, the largest source of revenue in 2022 will no longer be cosmetics, but new material candles, aromatherapy and handicrafts. Diversified development is another option. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Is high R&amp;D investment worth it? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>; Putting aside these transformations and career changes, focusing on the daily chemical industry itself, is high R&amp;D investment a necessary choice? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of business operations, R&amp;D investment is a cost account of the enterprise. Compared with industries with strong technological attributes such as software services and consumer electronics, the benefits that R&amp;D can bring to daily chemical companies are not immediate. At the same time, R&amp;D investment is not high, and there are many brands that have achieved substantial revenue through marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the annual reports of listed daily chemical companies, all of them have sales expenses higher than R&amp;D expenses. For example, Proya’s sales expenses are as high as 2.7 billion yuan, which is 21 times its R&amp;D investment. &lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;We cannot deny the importance of brand marketing for daily chemical products, but additional high R&amp;D investment has become an industry consensus in recent years. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;16 daily chemical companies also gave their answers using numbers. In fiscal year 2022, a total of 11 companies experienced a year-on-year decline in operating income, accounting for nearly 70%. However, among the 15 companies that disclosed R&amp;D investment, only 6 reduced R&amp;D investment, accounting for 40%. how so? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, R&amp;D is the basis for brand premium. In the &quot;79-yuan Huaxizi eyebrow pencil&quot; incident, someone calculated that its price per gram was even higher than gold. Of course, Huaxizi is not the only one with high prices. Many domestic products have quietly raised their prices in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although compared with big European and American brands, the prices of domestic cosmetics still have room to rise, but behind this incident is the fact that the &quot;hard work&quot; of domestic brand marketing cannot support their price increases. The reason why consumers don’t buy the “79 yuan eyebrow pencil” is ultimately because they question the value of the product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The value of consumer goods usually includes brand value and functional value. The formation of brand value requires the accumulation of time, but functional value can be obtained by latecomers through research and development. For domestic brands whose brand value has not yet been formed, strengthening research and development is not only to create the functional value of the product, but also is conducive to the formation of its brand image. Winona is an example of &quot;focusing on research and development&quot; as the direction of brand development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Secondly, R&amp;D is the only way to create new growth points. &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;This is especially true in the cosmetics industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, channels have always been king in China’s beauty and skin care industry. The focus of competition for market share ranges from offline stores to traditional e-commerce to social e-commerce. Thanks to the development of social media, the degree of information asymmetry between consumers and businesses has been greatly reduced. Consumers have begun to pay more attention to the efficacy of products. It has become a trend to buy skin care products based on their ingredients. The beauty and skin care industry has entered a stage driven by product efficacy. new era. Launching functional skin care products and creating a matrix of functional products have become a new battlefield for cosmetics companies to compete for market share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The efficacy of beauty products, especially skin care products, is closely related to product raw materials and formulas, and the discovery and invention of raw materials and formulas are undoubtedly inseparable from R&amp;D investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, as functional skin care has become a new selling point, coupled with the popularity of medical beauty, biopharmaceutical companies with inherent advantages in formula research and development and targeted &quot;medicine&quot; have also begun to join the &quot;involution&quot; of the beauty industry . &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Biotechnology, cross-border competition&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Some people may have noticed that holding Mibel, Huaxi Biotech &lt;span>; (688363.SH)&lt;/span>;, which owns cosmetics brands such as Quadi and Runbaiyan, did not appear on the list. Bloomage Biotechnology is classified into the biotechnology industry under the pharmaceutical manufacturing industry. It does not participate in the daily chemical industry rankings, but it is an important competitor of companies in the daily chemical industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloomage Biotech, founded in 2000, has entered the skin care industry since 2016 and has ranked first in the hyaluronic acid business in the industry. In 2022, its functional skin care products achieved revenue of 4.607 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 38.80%, accounting for 72.45% of the company&#39;s main business revenue. This revenue is even higher than the total revenue of Shuiyang Co., Ltd., the parent company of Yunifang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a20f11734e761e45cf14adcd5b0c615d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 559px; height: auto !important;&quot; width=&quot;559&quot; height=&quot;781&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a20f11734e761e45cf14adcd5b0c615d.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;256889&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;559&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to this, there are giant creatures &lt;span>; (02367.HK)&lt;/p>; span>;, one of its main businesses is functional skin care products. Its brands include Kefumei, Kelijin, etc. Its revenue in fiscal year 2022 reached 2.364 billion yuan, of which functional skin care products accounted for more than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the daily chemical industry is also actively moving closer to biotechnology. Marubi Co., Ltd. proposed a research and development plan based on recombinant collagen in the next ten years in 2022. It plans to successively launch recombinant collagen products with Class II medical device certification, recombinant collagen water-light injection products with Class III medical device certification, and Class III medical devices. Certified collagen-filling products and artificial corneas based on recombinant collagen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;In fact, the biotechnology and daily chemical industries are going in both directions. The intersection of medicine and beauty is getting closer and closer, and beauty and skin care products are moving closer to biotechnology from formulas and ingredients to technology to packaging. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; Technologies such as fermentation engineering and molecular biology enable the extraction and development of new active ingredients; technologies such as nanotechnology and micro-emulsification technology are used to overcome the problem of difficulty in skin absorption; degradable packaging materials play an important role in environmental protection policies promoted to the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Integrate product research and development with biotechnology in an all-round way, integrating industry, academia and research. In the fields of precision skin care, functional skin care and other fields, beauty and skin care brands have cultivated their own competitiveness by deeply cultivating biotechnology, and new brands are also seizing the opportunity. Technological changes are coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the development history of international beauty giants such as L&#39;Oreal, Estee Lauder, and Shiseido, their origins and the establishment of moats are all closely related to chemistry and biomedicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a time when consumption is downgrading and national trends are prevalent, domestic beauty and cosmetics companies that have always focused on &quot;high quality and low price&quot; are facing important competition points to narrow the gap with big European and American brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To seize this &quot;overwhelming wealth&quot;, domestic beauty products must examine and learn from the original research and development intentions of European and American brands, and must not use high marketing as a basis to increase prices at will. After all, the company is not in a In the advertising industry, what makes consumers perceive value is not the gorgeous packaging and advertising endorsements, but the genuine effects that the products bring to consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她研究在美中国本科留学生，发现高远志向下的挣扎和迷茫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259847]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[剁碎新鲜白菜凑厨余垃圾，涉事企业：正在整改]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259867]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小学老师因不堪非教育负担而自杀：当减轻乃至消除老师的非教育任务负担]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The suicide of a primary school teacher attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv, a female teacher at Jianxing Road Primary School in Guancheng District, Zhengzhou City, left a suicide note with the completion time marked at 23:44 on October 26. The suicide note said: Mom, I&#39;m sorry, I really can&#39;t hold it on anymore... I feel like I can&#39;t breathe. I never thought that being a primary school teacher would be so difficult... School work, school activities, and leadership inspections make us graduates who directly become class teachers without training feel like we are in a cage, and the cage is shrinking little by little. We go to work every day with our last breath in mind. When can teachers only do the job of teaching and educating people? How can unhappy teachers teach positive and optimistic children? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv is only 23 years old this year. He was admitted to the school in August to teach and serve as a class teacher. He has a &quot;normally cheerful personality&quot; and is in the best years of his life. What a tragedy for her family who loved her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, this incident has sounded a wake-up call for us. We must care and pay attention to our family members, especially their mental state and values. We should relax as a family regularly, have heart-to-heart conversations, and tell each other’s confusions. and weakness: If some problems can be solved, then help solve them; if some problems cannot be solved, then at least relieve the pressure. The &quot;normally cheerful personality&quot; may be true, or it may be that he forced himself to perform in order not to worry his family and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers within the system are regarded by many as &quot;iron rice bowls&quot;. They have a system and have a good social status, but in turn they may become barriers that restrict people: many people have passed the teacher certification examination, but find that they are not actually qualified. If you don&#39;t like or are not suitable for this job, and you don&#39;t dare to resign and look for another job, you are often worried that your family or outsiders will not understand you, and you feel that you do not cherish this hard-won opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only you know whether your shoes fit or not. Here, I would like to advise everyone, no matter what profession you are engaged in, you should respect your own intuitive feelings and don&#39;t care too much about other people&#39;s opinions. When it&#39;s time to change the track, change the track, and spend your life on meaningful and worthwhile things; holding on for dear life will only lead to greater and greater mental internal friction, consuming and annihilating your own vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, this matter will inevitably lead to a question: Don’t teachers only have a few classes a day and two three-month vacations in winter and summer every year? Isn’t it enough to be admitted to the teacher establishment? &quot;Going ashore&quot; can we not work so hard or even lie down? Why are we so busy and tired? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technically, this can be described as the dark side brought about by the popularity of smartphones and instant messaging tools. Various WeChat home-school groups and DingTalk groups allow the will of schools and teachers to reach every family and every parent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, the function of the home-school group was just that schools and teachers forwarded various educational tasks to parents, asking parents to help their children prepare for classes, check their children&#39;s homework, etc. This forced parents to invest time and resources. Go into your child’s learning. To a certain extent, the teacher is the leader of the home-school group. Their children are in the hands of the school and the teacher. How many parents dare to publicly refuse to cooperate? There is also competition among parents to please the teacher or at least not to offend the teacher. The benefit of this approach to teachers is that teachers and schools still have certain KPI performance, and parents’ input helps them achieve KPIs, so schools and teachers have incentives to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, this trick will become known to some departments, and the routine of &quot;little hands holding big hands&quot; will be summarized, which is to press down through the chain of education system-school-teacher. Ask parents to cooperate in completing various non-educational tasks, as these departments also have their own KPIs. As time goes by, more and more departments are found to be able to do this. Various non-educational tasks are handed down to parents through this chain, and occupy more and more time of schools and teachers. Parents Although it was unpleasant, the school and teachers also felt uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above sense, through home-school clusters, schools have become the third grassroots governance organization besides village committees and neighborhood committees. Each department has penetrated the tentacles of power into every student through the school-teacher transmission link. Families, and the frequency and intensity of intervention far exceed that of village committees and neighborhood committees. You may wish to recall, how many times can you interact with the village committee or neighborhood committee in a year? Many people may not even have one. But whenever you have children in primary or secondary school, you often have to complete non-educational tasks for your children that are communicated to you through the school-teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, other government departments will also second teachers to do various non-educational work offline. After all, teachers are public officials within the system and are more or less dependent on local finance, so they are easier to dispatch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Sanlian Life Weekly&quot; once published an article &quot;&quot;Squeezed out&quot; to have a teacher establishment, they regret it. The article interviewed Zhang Xiaohui, a primary school teacher born in the 1990s. She said: She was When I am a primary school teacher or head teacher, only 30% of my job is teaching, and the other 70% is social tasks. Another interviewee said: As a class teacher, you not only have to teach classes, but you also have to arrange class activities and class meetings, and connect with local communities, hospitals, fire stations, transportation bureaus and other government agencies. You will even be called up by the school leaders at two o&#39;clock in the morning. Volunteering and these heavy tasks made her feel physically and mentally exhausted, which was contrary to her original intention of becoming a teacher, so she chose to resign. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in order to reduce or even eliminate the burden of various non-educational tasks faced by schools and teachers, there are strategies to reduce the salary under the kettle. The first is to forcibly disband various home-school groups. Unless students get into trouble or get hurt at school, schools and teachers are not allowed to contact parents. In this way, various educational and non-educational burdens on parents can be eliminated at once, which is conducive to the normalization and harmony of home-school relations; schools and teachers may also be exempted from various online non-educational tasks. Second, it is explicitly ordered that other government departments shall not use teachers as temporary workers or use them for free as temporary workers. In short, a two-pronged approach will reduce the non-educational burden on teachers both online and offline, so that teachers can concentrate on teaching and educating people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[加沙的地道恐怕挡不住以色列的进攻丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259856]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/Erv2zTeF7MZqh7v93zNuSduQSLAT2P9rV1UjDIR9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Erv2zTeF7MZqh7v93zNuSduQSLAT2 P9rV1UjDIR9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 28, 2023, at the Israeli-Gaza border, the Israeli army fired artillery shells into the Gaza Strip &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Israeli-Palestinian conflict that has lasted for three weeks has entered a new stage, and Israel has begun to continuously launch attacks on the Gaza region Launch a ground attack. Major General Hagari of the Israel Defense Forces told the media that the Israeli ground forces are &quot;expanding the scope of their activities&quot; and &quot;taking vigorous actions... to achieve war goals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a video released by the Israel Defense Forces, a group of Merkava tanks can be seen running through the flat, open sand of Gaza, attacking distant buildings with their main guns. Hamas also confirmed that it was engaged in ground combat with the Israel Defense Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as predicted in my previous column, Israel’s ground operations will not involve large-scale penetration and encirclement, but will continue to slowly encroach from the edge with very cautious actions. Obviously, Israel is very aware that Hamas&#39;s army has established a very strong underground network inside Gaza. It will be a defense system full of death traps, just like the Japanese army prepared for the US Marines in the Battle of Iwo Jima. Those death potholes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To directly attack such an area, Israel may pay heavy casualties, which is of course the result Hamas hopes for. Does Israel have a way to deal with this authentic meat grinder that has been operating for many years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, compared with the era of the Battle of Iwo Jima, technological advancements have allowed today&#39;s military to use some new technological means to detect the underground world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is thermal imaging technology, which has been widely used in tunnel detection. Although the tunnel itself does not emit infrared signals, ventilation equipment must be installed in large tunnels to prevent people inside from being suffocated. At present, Israel has cut off the power supply to Gaza. Such ventilation equipment can only rely on its own generators to maintain operation. These generators and the vents of underground passages will be an identifiable thermal imaging signal. During peacetime, Hamas can still cover thermal imaging signals through some buildings and temporary facilities. However, once war breaks out, Israel will continue to destroy those ground buildings, forcing the exposure of heat sources such as vents and power generation equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another common tunnel detection method is synthetic aperture radar. This type of radar has the ability to detect underground metal objects at a certain depth, and can even detect the depth and position of underground tunnels. In 2021, the U.S. Army announced a new technology that can generate three-dimensional images of underground bunkers by simply comparing the images generated by synthetic aperture radar twice through an algorithm. Platforms including satellites, dedicated ground surveillance aircraft and drones can be equipped with synthetic aperture radar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also an advanced technology that has received high hopes in recent years, namely hyperspectral imaging reconnaissance. Hyperspectral detection equipment is an imaging method that can distinguish extremely subtle changes on the surface of objects. Different soil media, water flows and even air fluctuations can be imaged in front of hyperspectral imaging equipment. This method has been widely used in minerals and water resources. aviation wide area detection. In the military, this imaging technology can also be used to discover the opponent&#39;s bunkers, mines and hidden military forces. In recent years, hyperspectral imaging cameras have been integrated into drones and satellites. Israel has also done considerable research in this area and is at the leading level in the industry in several research directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that an almost science-fiction technology was also used in this conflict, that is, muon imaging technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1936, humans discovered the existence of a type of ray called muons in the universe, which can penetrate various materials including hard granite and marble. In recent years, with the advancement of particle mechanics, humans have discovered that the penetration properties of muons can be used to image the interior of objects. The principle is the same as X-ray photography. Nowadays, muon photography technology is widely used in engineering, geological observation and archaeological activities, such as detecting the direction of magma inside volcanoes or observing the internal structure of pyramids. Even after the Fukushima nuclear power plant accident, muon cameras were also used Find out what&#39;s going on inside the Fukushima Nuclear Power Plant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, muon imaging technology has rarely been used for military purposes in the past. The main reason is that this technology requires sensors to be deployed in at least two directions of the object being detected, otherwise imaging cannot be performed. Military facilities are often underground, and aerial reconnaissance alone cannot meet imaging conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the tunnels in the Gaza Strip are qualified for the use of muon imaging technology, because this is a small area, and Israel almost surrounds the Gaza area from three sides, allowing muon photography to be deployed in multiple directions. As for the conditions of the equipment, since this technology has been widely used in other fields, it can basically be used immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more technical reconnaissance methods on the battlefield, the better. In addition to obtaining means, the ability to comprehensively analyze and utilize reconnaissance results is also crucial. With the advancement of human science and technology, although underground bunkers have a certain degree of concealment, they are no longer impenetrable. With all technical means overwhelming them, tunnel combat alone may not be able to withstand the opponent&#39;s attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报网传抢中药事件 :村民误认为收割完毕遂进场捡拾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 11:32:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau of Zhoukou Huaiyang District issued a situation report on November 1:&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the afternoon of October 31, Qiu, a medicinal planter in Fengtang Township, Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City, Henan Province, was two-thirds of the way through the second harvest of Atractylodes macrocephala. Fault. The nearby villagers mistakenly thought that the grower had completed the second harvest, so they went into the field to pick up medicinal materials (after the second harvest of medicinal materials was completed, it has been a habit for many years for the growers to allow villagers to go to the field to pick up the leftover medicinal materials). After the growers tried to dissuade them to no avail. The police were called, and police from the local police station quickly arrived at the scene and persuaded the people to leave. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, our bureau will further strengthen the service and management of agriculture, rural areas and farmers, and effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of farmers and growers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0reZZbJvE7oiWSg0YTpVwKDlyjqmVtlnW4PGw59H.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;828&quot; height= &quot;555&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0reZZbJvE7oiWSg0YTpVwKDlyjqmVtlnW4PGw59H.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>