<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4 P4YXsf2grzoKpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (third from right) in his later years with friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu ended his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; with an encounter in middle age. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At night, he was driving on a narrow highway with only one car in front of him. He lacks confidence in his driving skills, so he uses the taillights of the car in front of him as a guide to gain a sense of safety and comfort. Suddenly the car flashed its right turn signal and turned into a country road. Visible to the naked eye, he was the only one driving on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;So, only my own headlights are left to guide the way. This light can only illuminate a very small area. It is a short road, but this road, farther away, is swallowed up in darkness.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Tuan is a famous geographer and the founder of humanistic geography. One of the people. He intellectually understands the relationship between people and place and considers himself a cosmopolitan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; was written in 1999, when Duan Yifu was 69 years old, and mankind was about to enter the new millennium. He sees &quot;Who am I&quot; as the fashionable question at the dawn of the new millennium. This issue actually received increasing attention as early as the 1960s, &quot;In order to generate a solid sense of self, a person needs the past, not just the present and the future.&quot; It is worth mentioning that &quot;Silent Spring&quot; combined poetry and science in the 1960s to jointly examine the relationship between man and the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu continued to think about it and wrote important works in the next twenty years. &quot;who I am? 》 is a good stage summary, showing sincere self-examination. He seems to be getting closer and closer to a location, but he is not sure when he will arrive, or even further away. The ideal position always changes with time, space and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early 1940s, Duan Yifu and his family were preparing to move from Chongqing to Australia. During the group photo, Yifu Duan (third from left) tried to squeeze away from his younger brother and stay close to his mother to gain more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The world in his eyes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is shrinking inward &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, Yifu Tuan quoted the words of Socrates: An unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before middle age, Duan Yifu had never lived in any city for more than five years. After leaving China, he continued to move around until he moved to Minneapolis at the age of 38 and stopped to engage in academic work. Migration is inseparable from both my father&#39;s work and historical events. He believed he was rootless and &quot;born to examine himself.&quot; He never married and could not fully integrate into American society, and the issue of identity was always there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He considers himself an optimist and &quot;often places the golden age in the future.&quot; He knows that he gained his confidence early, having been relatively unscathed by racism while living abroad, and that later in life he began to question its source. His various ways of dealing with the world are closely related to the events he has experienced and the environment in which he lives. The book reveals his own “sense of place”—emotions and judgments about specific places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his first interview at Indiana University in 1956, an Asian history professor was surprised by his family background. Duan Yifu recalled his childhood memories and was sure that the other party was not joking. According to what he heard, the Duan family was divided into two branches in modern times, both in Anhui. Duan Yifu&#39;s family belonged to the poor branch, and his father Duan Maolan relied on his uncle Duan Qirui from the Hefei branch to fully fund his studies at Nankai Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu was born in Tianjin. From the age of 7 to 10, he lived in a village on the outskirts of Chongqing due to the war. His family was financially distressed. The school is a single room belonging to a power station. The place smelled sour and rancid, and the fetid mud dragged at his shoes. He was disgusted and horrified. Occasionally he encountered a funeral procession, with the bodies of the guards wrapped in bamboo mats. There is a rooster tied to it, which will crow if the corpse is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1954, Yifu Duan conducted field research in Arizona, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small schools are different places, where students learn about the history, Culture and Technology. Wilde&#39;s work &quot;The Happy Prince&quot; left an indelible mark on him, and he knew: &quot;&#39;Good&#39; can no longer be limited to fulfilling social obligations.&quot; These realizations inspired Duan Yifu to think, and he was always exploring how to determine a person&#39;s position in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu mentioned some important historical figures in his narrative. Duan Maolan and his alumnus Zhou Enlai wrestled with each other&#39;s arms to test whether the other&#39;s injured arm was healed. Zhang Boling, the principal of Nankai Middle School, had a rare refrigerator and distributed trays of ice cubes to everyone. In order to keep them for him, his father used the folk remedy of spreading salt to delay melting. The adults are still thinking about how to treat their distant relative Wang Jingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu has conflicting emotions about his father. He longs for love, but is disappointed by his father&#39;s preference for his brothers; he remembers the tenderness of the difficult times, but is also traumatized by his father&#39;s severity or anger. The most profound memory of my father is even just a childhood nightmare, and the scene in the dream has remained for many years:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;I opened my arms and wanted to hug him... What happened? But a ghost stood in front of me. It could be seen that it was my father, but he was covered in mourning clothes. This ghost was in the ever-changing airflow It was moving in the middle, weightless. It was an evil ghost, a corpse, with yellow light in its empty eyes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impression his mother left on him was warm and tough. , it’s a pity that she passed away prematurely. At the same time, Duan Yifu became increasingly sensitive due to his physical condition, and he became very ill for a time. He confessed his cowardice and unwillingness to participate in social change activities. Even in the face of racism and rude boys who treat him as a &quot;little girl,&quot; he has no motivation to actively fight back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world in Duan Yifu&#39;s eyes is shrinking inward. When he was a child, he was exposed to all kinds of extraordinary events. When he grew up, the war ended and he had to face many personal problems. He summed up this growth experience as moving from the universe to the stove, and used beautiful writing to integrate life and academia. He quoted the words of the poet TS Eliot:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All of us, in our lifetime, have heard and seen , why does everything you feel (a bird singing, a fish leaping, an old woman walking on a mountain road) be reproduced with emotion, but other things are not?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;Youth Yifu Tuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you willing to be a lonely captain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Poetry can break through the barriers or boundaries of language logic.” Liu Su told Southern Weekend. He used this to describe the beautiful words written by Tuan Yifu. He translated &quot;Love Land Complex&quot; and &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;Two books by Yifu Tuan, and I am currently translating &quot;The Divided World and Self&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student around 2010, Liu Su often suffered from having no books to read. Many times he was attracted by the ideas mentioned in the book, but could not find relevant Chinese or even English translations. He tried his best to find the original work, went to Douban to ask Douban friends who had read the book, and also went to the library, but he might only be able to make half a copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I might as well translate it myself!&quot; Those experiences inspired Liu Su&#39;s enthusiasm. He thus embarked on the path of academic translation, and future college students will no longer face the dilemma of reading. At the same time, many scholars have also participated in the translation and introduction of geography classics. The Chinese translations of scholars such as Tuan Yifu and David Harvey are enough to be compiled into a collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2021, in the crowded Chongqing subway, Liu Su received a WeChat message from another translator Zhicheng, asking him if he was willing to translate &quot;Who Am I?&quot; 》. Even though the air conditioning was sufficient, he still broke out in a hot sweat: &quot;This book will finally be translated into Chinese!&quot; He had seriously considered that he was not willing to live a lonely life as a &quot;foreigner&quot; in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; ” resonated with Liu Su’s heart. He experienced a long single life. When he got married, the children of his classmates were almost in junior high school. He may have experienced Duan Yifu&#39;s loneliness and his self-statement: &quot;I spent a lot of time in poems and essays about the sadness of spring and autumn, and spent them in places like libraries and coffee shops.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su finished class, said goodbye to the students, and went to the library for a while after walking out of the teaching building. Even if I don’t write anything, I would still like to sit in the corner and experience what Yifu Duan said: “Living on campus almost all my life, surrounded by young people, makes me feel happy physically and mentally.” He sometimes goes to a nearby coffee shop and sits by the window, looking at the pedestrians, vehicles and street lights, feeling that loneliness is far away. The sensibility of exquisite language gathers together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-Fu Tuan in 1998, that is, &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;The previous year&#39;s work &quot;Escapism&quot; asked: What is the greatest escape? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you lower your head and manage the environment around you with a heart that loves your neighbor, you can also look up at the vast starry sky.&quot; Liu Su talked about his understanding of this sentence and added a more realistic side, &quot;As a scholar, like him, I often look up at the starry sky of metaphysical thoughts and theories. However, whenever I look down at my single life, I often feel like I&#39;m in a mess.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot; 1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (1930-2022), an internationally renowned Chinese geographer, was born in Tianjin and graduated from Oxford University. He returned to China in his later years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su is looking for descriptions of single life in books. Yifu Tuan made his apartment simple and warm, dressed modestly and appropriately, maintained good health and longevity, had good interpersonal relationships, and gained precious friendships. However, &quot;he once dreamed that he died alone at home, and no one found his rotting body.&quot; Duan Yifu always writes about his loneliness, a complicated feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps the reason is that loneliness is the most authentic way of human existence. The state of not being lonely is actually the product of escape.&quot; Liu Su quoted the saying of &quot;Escapism&quot;. There are three questions surrounding Yifu Duan&#39;s life: &quot;I am mortal&quot; that has lingered since childhood; &quot;Who am I&quot; related to individual consciousness; and &quot;What is a good life&quot;. Yifu Tuan wrote &quot;Geography saved me&quot;. Geography was like a road that led him to understand himself and the problems of human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Translation of &quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; also allowed Liu Su to gain &quot;a friendship worth cherishing.&quot; After the book launch, he, Zhi Cheng, editors and readers friends braved the heavy rain and went into a noodle shop to chat. Five people each signed five books and kept them. He also wanted to write his feelings into a longer email and share it with Duan Yifu. Before the email was finished, Duan Yifu passed away in August 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tuan Yifu published a new book that year, and finally wrote: &quot;I would like to advise you again, young traveler! You must be full of courage to operate your own ship like a captain, even though it is only Life&#39;s puzzling clues and stars serve as your guide.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su was devastated by his mistake, but would continue to translate classics of humanistic geography. He also asked himself if he was willing to be a lonely captain and walk on a narrow road. No matter what the answer is, Tuan Yifu&#39;s book &quot;will always be projected into the heart of every reader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where is the real home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu recalled in the preface of &quot;Going Home&quot; that people often asked him where he thought the real hometown was. . He answered lightly: &quot;In general, it&#39;s the earth.&quot; &quot;Where on earth is it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the meaning of the question is probably: there must be a place where he is most comfortable, The most yearning, can form the deepest sense of belonging. &quot;Some specific landscapes do have great appeal to me, such as a landscape that transcends aesthetics - the desert. I feel that I am very close to the desert psychologically, and I can even regard it as my home.&quot; Yifu Duan again and again Once I wrote about my love for the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in the winter of 1954, Yifu Tuan was conducting field research for his doctoral thesis in southeastern Arizona. The research object was the desert terrain called the foothill erosion surface. When optimistic British student David Harris joins the group, the physical and spiritual hardships of the wilderness thin out and are gradually replaced by friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This relationship brings me satisfaction, but it also causes insecurity—almost all relationships of any depth involve both. Why? Is there something wrong with me? ?&quot; Duan Yifu asked in the book. In 1962, they collaborated again. He remained single and became a teacher; David married and had two daughters. &quot;The David today is a broader, more elusive personality than I knew before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following description is sensitive and stinging, and such feelings appear repeatedly in the book . They each drove to Chaco Canyon to investigate, with Yifu Duan leading the way and David&#39;s family following behind. At dusk, maybe David knew the route, maybe the children needed care, David&#39;s car honked, kicked up dust and drove ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The distance between us became wider and wider, and soon, all that was left in front of my eyes was the raised The dust was gone, and in the end, even the dust was gone. I fell into a lonely shadow... When I tried to catch up with the Harris family, I felt lonely and painful for the first time. What&#39;s worse, I I even feel ridiculous. What on earth was I doing on a dirt road in New Mexico? Chasing a young family in a car?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yifu Tuan&#39;s eyes, friendship must meet two basic requirements: The conditions—like-mindedness and sympathy—should be balanced in an ideal friendship. &quot;If overly oriented toward shared interests and interests, these two people may become more like colleagues than friends; conversely, they may be more like lovers, staring into each other&#39;s eyes rather than into the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Shy people, unsociable people, or people like me who have their social needs suppressed by eccentric pursuits, perhaps should devote themselves to Nature...maybe only by staying in an inorganic environment, such as deserts and icebergs, can people feel relaxed and happy, and forget the good and the bad.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Duan also wrote about the German Alexander von Humboldt. Humboldt was the founder of modern physical geography. He “made outstanding contributions to the development of geodesy and was the first to use painting and poetry to develop human geographical experience-feelings, emotions and concepts, which are the core of humanities. The starting point of socialist geography”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt lived to be 90 years old and was full of energy throughout his life. In his sixties, he could still travel through Siberia and Central Asia. He enjoys socializing, but has never been married, and has been trapped in emotional entanglements with men three times. He wrote in a letter to the married soldier Reinhard von Haften: &quot;Even if you reject me and look at me coldly, like a stain, I still want to be with you. ...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I leave the universe, or to be precise, leave the harmony of nature and the joy brought by human beings&#39; ultimate achievements, my life will become miserable and I will not be able to survive.&quot; Yifu Duan listed He felt all kinds of human misery, &quot;But, I don&#39;t want to stay in those shadows for a long time...&quot; He believed in the light, the beauty of the universe, and the beauty and kindness of events. The next chapter is &quot;Geography Saved Me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, taking the opportunity of attending an architectural conference, Yi-Fu Tuan returned to China after 60 years of absence and deliberately stayed for a while. He wrote a book called &quot;Going Home&quot;, which was translated into Chinese by Zhicheng. During the trip to Chongqing, he once again mentioned the nightmare that had plagued him throughout his life. When his father passed away in Taipei in 1980, he did not go back to see him for the last time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the autobiography is the contrast between the dim light of the car lights and the vast darkness. That is not despair. Duan Yifu is still looking at himself. He asked the translator to attach his speech notes in 2012 as an updated understanding of &quot;who I am.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no so-called ordinary people in the world. The people you talk to every day are actually people with immortal souls... They joke with us, work together, and get married, but they are also ignored and exploited by us. All people are actually people with immortal souls. Among these people, some are immortal and terrifying, and some are immortal and brilliant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Maybe it has been too long, he I really forgot&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot;Yu Shiyi, the editor of &quot;WeChat,&quot; appeared somewhat silent - just like when communicating with text on WeChat - but soon opened up the situation, became talkative and humorous. His daily schedule was very regular and he even added a short period of time that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later he added that he should not talk too much about his own story, and autobiographers should be given more space. So, this part is an extra chapter of this article. People are always faced with questions such as &quot;Who am I?&quot; The questions and answers constantly change with the situation, each covered with attractive colors. For example, the great director Bergman claimed that he knew less about himself than he did ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi has unique feelings about discrete events. In early 1949, the Taiping shipwreck occurred in the waters west of Daishan Island where he was born. When he was a child, he had no idea about this tragedy. He only learned about it through documentaries when he left his hometown to attend college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, approximately 125,000 young men, soldiers, and 25,000 civilian personnel and civilians moved to Taiwan from Zhoushan, later forming the first generation of Zhoushan people of 20,000 to 30,000 people. The initiators of Taiwan’s Veterans Return Movement in 1987 were Zhoushan people. Before the “Three Direct Links”, it was very difficult for them to contact their homeland. The local historical materials exhibition hall uses an entire wall to display letters forwarded by the Red Cross at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Islands shape cognition. Yu Shiyi left Zhoushan for Ningbo ten years ago, and then went to Shanghai to study. When I was growing up, there was no cross-sea bridge in Zhoushan. When a typhoon came, the island became an isolated island, physically and psychologically isolated from the rest of the world. Compared to county towns, provincial towns, and cities, visitors from small islands seem to be “small” and marginal. At first he longed to merge from the margins into the mainstream, but now he wants to have subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As an immigrant, your regional identity is the first thing that is mentioned when you arrive in a new environment.” Yu Shiyi has a friend who was born in Hubei and grew up in Shenzhen, and later moved to Shanghai. He asked: What is the local accent of “other”? In 1973, 43-year-old Yifu Duan officially became a U.S. citizen. He has been living in the United States for nearly two decades, debugging himself as a &quot;cosmopolitan and a thinker writing about discrete subjects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the little grandpa - my grandfather&#39;s younger brother - talking about the past during the Chinese New Year. He claimed that he once drove a simple diesel-powered boat from Qushan Island to Dongjiadu, Shanghai, in one night. Alone, without a GPS, all I have is experience and a compass. Yu Shiyi could not imagine the plight of the fishermen. Wouldn&#39;t they be scared if they were wandering around without land? He wrote down his boundless imagination in his notes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The lanky man drove a small sampan from the island Set off and drive northwest, through night and day, to Dongjiadu. The lighting system at that time was not perfect, and there was no positioning system. Some waterways were almost dark at night, but he arrived at his destination safely without saying a word about the wind and waves he encountered. I think maybe too much time has passed and he has long forgotten the ups and downs along the way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I remember that there is a famous lighthouse on Flower and Bird Island. I wonder if he passed by it. Under certain conditions, There will also be the wonder of the fluorescent sea. I always feel that the waterway from my hometown to Shanghai is full of mysterious powers. I once took a ferry from the island to Shanghai. I landed ashore at dusk and landed at dawn. That was the first time I saw the waves gurgling like spring water and seagulls soaring in the sky. Looking out from the small round glass of the third-class cabin, there are faint lights. Maybe I have seen the lighthouse of Flower and Bird Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked the tribesmen, have you gone ashore? He said he had unloaded the goods but did not go up. I was so sorry. I wanted to get the secrets of Shanghai in the 1980s from him, but he said, it’s nothing. The Bund is just across the Dongjia Ferry Road. I can’t understand those Western things. At that time, everything could be bought by ticket, and the people were people on the water. , naturally cannot be obtained. He drove the sampan up the Huangpu River and finally reached Jiangyin. This was undoubtedly an adventure. As for what to do there and how to get back to the island, he stopped talking without saying a few words. Maybe it&#39;s been too long and he really forgot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Memories and narratives form fragments one after another, embedded in life. More than thirty years after my grandfather left Shanghai, Yu Shiyi also arrived in Shanghai. During the National Day holiday in 2022, he took a boat to the island with his father. The father was hesitant at first, after all, the house was no longer theirs. Many places are different. Old houses and new ones are popping up one after another. Fortunately, the road remains where it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi returned to the lane where he was born. The commercial house he bought more than 20 years ago was still there, but it was older. The back door was open, he went in and saw the washboard from many years ago. After all these years, it&#39;s still there, like a miracle. There was someone living nearby, and he was too embarrassed to disturb him, so he just wanted to go to the front door to take a look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the resident saw the stranger, he became alert and asked: &quot;Who are you?&quot; Yu Shiyi was stunned, silent for a few seconds, and instinctively replied: &quot;This is my home.&quot; He walked to the front door and took a photo Teru then left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have become the &#39;other&#39;.&quot; He recalled, &quot;There are physical things, and it used to be my home.&quot; He didn&#39;t know how many hands the house had changed. I felt relieved that I could finally say goodbye. For almost twenty years, he always thought of this home, worried about it, and was afraid it would be demolished. Now all the playmates and neighbors have left, leaving only photos and washboards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recognition and memory of your hometown, in turn, become the means for others to identify you. Not long after being asked &quot;Who are you?&quot;, in December 2022, Yu Shiyi took over &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;, the book will be launched at the Shanghai Book Fair in August 2023. The above is always a bit of an unexpected fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天安门下半旗悼念李克强同志]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259779]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:28:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKj lN5UvkjG6D. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Huanzong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 2, in memory of Comrade Li Keqiang, flags were flown at half-mast at Tiananmen Square in the capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”：是一种可鄙的价值观吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There are many serious and serious rumors circulating on the Internet. Some are old and constantly updated versions, and some are new. of. A relatively recent one is: The Chinese student&#39;s thesis &quot;You have to endure hardships to become a superior person&quot;. As a result, the New Zealand professor gave a zero point and asked the soul question, &quot;Why should you become a superior person while others are inferior?&quot; What do people do? Why do you divide your compatriots into three, six or nine grades? Shouldn’t everyone be equal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you do some Internet archeology, it is not difficult to find that this is A piece of Sanwu news concocted by a certain self-media, with no specific time, university or person. The motive of the fabricator is to use the words of foreigners who regard them as authoritative to show how low some Chinese people&#39;s words, deeds, and values ​​are, and how high their own preferred values ​​are. However, there are still many people who believe in this rumor that &quot;foreign monks like to chant sutras&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original version of &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The original version should be &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chapter 32 of &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. Tang Monk said: &quot;Disciples, be careful. If you encounter a high mountain ahead, you may be blocked by tigers and wolves.&quot; Sun Wukong said: &quot;Master, as a monk, don&#39;t talk at home. Do you remember the &quot;Heart Sutra&quot; written by Monk Wuchao, which says, &#39;If you have no worries, you will be free from worries.&#39; No fear, stay away from words that confuse dreams? But it is just to sweep away the dirt on the heart and wash the dirt on the ears. If you don&#39;t suffer in the suffering, it is difficult to be a good person. You should not worry, but there is an old man, even if the sky falls, you can Be safe. What are you afraid of?&quot; This was an education for the master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also from &quot;Warning Words to the World&quot;, &quot;It&#39;s Hard to Meet Your Husband after Spring Falls in the Yutang&quot;. I saw a couplet hanging on the door: &quot;After ten years of suffering in front of the window, he became famous all over the world.&quot; &quot;This is the couplet written by my father-in-law. He passed the national examination and became a minister: Later, our father was When I study here, I will become a minister. I am studying here now, and I also want to climb the dragon and the phoenix to carry forward the ambitions of my predecessors.&quot; I also saw a couplet on the second door: &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the hardships, it is difficult to become a master.&quot; The young master hurriedly returned. Study room...with my mind turned around and my determination to study diligently. This is a lot of self-motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between the two versions is: &quot;Only when you endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The first sentence is a necessary condition for the latter sentence; &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people&quot; is the probability. Expression. The latter seems more rigorous and allows exceptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this kind of saying? If you take &quot;You must endure hardships to become the best&quot; as a full judgment, then it is not difficult to find counterexamples. In a logical sense, this proposition has been refuted. However, after that, everyone thought this was wrong and discarded it? Obviously not, everyone will just think you are making excuses, because this is not the correct way to open the proverb. The use of proverbs is inherently situational: only when specific preconditions are added or placed in a specific context can the proverb be established and can be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a large number of sayings in various languages ​​with completely opposite meanings. Here is an example of Chinese: &quot;A powerful man cannot bend&quot; vs &quot;A man can bend and stretch&quot;; &quot;I will not offend others unless they attack me&quot; vs &quot;Strike first to gain strength, but to attack later will suffer&quot;; &quot;It is better to be broken into pieces than to be left intact&quot; vs &quot;to stay intact&quot; If the green mountains are there, you will not be afraid of running out of firewood&quot;; &quot;Take a step back and the sky will be brighter&quot; Vs &quot;The brave will win when you meet on a narrow road&quot;; &quot;To endure a moment of calm&quot; Vs &quot;It is tolerable, but what is intolerable&quot;; &quot;Everything is inferior, only reading is good&quot; Vs &quot; Three hundred and sixty lines, he will be the number one scholar&quot;; &quot;The blue is better than the blue&quot; vs &quot;The hair on the lips is weak, and the work is not solid&quot;; &quot;Three cobblers are better than Zhuge Liang&quot; vs &quot;Three monks have no water to drink&quot; ...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me, which sentence before and after is right, which sentence is wrong, or are they both wrong? In fact, as long as they are put into the appropriate context, these common sayings with opposite meanings can be used correctly. This is the correct way to use common sayings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become a superior person&quot; or &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer a lot of hardships, can you become a superior person&quot;, there are also common sayings with opposite meanings or different emphasis, such as &quot;One life. &quot;Second Movement and Three Feng Shui&quot;, &quot;Choice is more important than effort&quot;, &quot;Don&#39;t use tactical diligence to cover up strategic laziness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, success is determined by many innate and acquired factors. 1. Fate: when you were born in which country and family, this constitutes your initial conditions and boundary conditions; 2. Wisdom: intellectual endowment, the computing power and algorithm of the brain, which are also innate; 3. God: you Your knowledge system and values, as well as your vitality, motivation, courage and patience, have both innate and acquired components, but the acquired component is greater, because you can always choose your values ​​and choose to be a courageous person; 4. Luck: Factors you have no way of knowing or controlling because you are in a complex random system. In a specific process, &quot;god, wisdom, fate, luck&quot;, which factors are more important cannot be generalized. A person&#39;s success always resonates with the trend of history and personal destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, among the many factors that determine success, hardship, diligence or patience are certainly important, especially for people without background. Other statements such as &quot;The sharp edge of a sword comes from sharpening, and the plum blossoms bloom from the bitter cold&quot;, &quot;There are roads in the mountains of books, and diligence is the path, and there is no limit to the sea of ​​learning, and the boat is made by hard work.&quot; Do they sound more pleasing to the ear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What many people don’t like is “people superior to others”. This needs to be looked at twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, from the perspective of rights or rules, of course everyone should be equal. No one is above anyone else, and no one is subordinate to anyone. It is against anyone&#39;s privileges or slavery. , which is the basic principle of civilized society. In this sense, there should be no &quot;people superior to others&quot; and &quot;people inferior to others&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, there are always certain professions that are more respected in society and have higher social evaluation or reputation. For example, professionals such as surgeons enjoy a higher social status and are not considered &quot;human beings&quot;. What about &quot;Master&quot;? Also, some people are respected and admired by everyone because of their ability, knowledge or virtue, and they even have many followers. For example, people like Xinxiang Xian are the core of society. If neighbors come to him to resolve disputes, does he count? What about &quot;people superior to people&quot;? In a company or organization, whether it has a strict hierarchy or a relatively &quot;flat&quot; management, there is a chain of command and a superior-subordinate relationship. The subordinates must obey the instructions of the superiors to do things. Can senior executives and superiors be considered &quot;superiors&quot;? &quot;Woolen cloth? In a nutshell, from the perspective of power or influence, elites or those with higher social status are often called &quot;dragons and phoenixes&quot;, and there is nothing wrong with being considered &quot;superior&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if you want to be &quot;superior&quot; and pursue the privilege of overpowering others or trampling others under your feet, it is naturally a despicable value; What&#39;s the problem if you deepen your field, improve your talents and virtues, become popular, and gain a higher social status? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[书城伏案的侧影：写在刘世南先生百年诞辰之际]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259765]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3AasqhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;916&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3Aasq hT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Shinan took a photo in front of the Chongshao Library of Jiangxi Normal University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Taosheng)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;People who long for friends who fear friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Shinan Mr. (1923-2021) was a fighter. This is the first impression of him by people who are familiar with him and those who are not familiar with him. He dared to criticize various scholars, including those older than him, those of his generation, and those younger than him. His articles were scattered in various books and periodicals from the late 1970s to the new century, making readers People who feel the enthusiasm and persistence of his criticism are of course embarrassed by the critics, but they do learn from him, and many criticized scholars express their gratitude to him and respect him even more. His criticisms are actually aimed at problems, especially the style of study. His crisp and refreshing writing style contains a profound call for a sincere, simple, serious and down-to-earth style of study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not many people know that he is very eager to be criticized. He criticized Mr. Liu Mengfu (&quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; page 301), and Mr. Mengfu also criticized him. He invited Mr. Mengfu to write a preface to his &quot;Da Luo Ju Shi Cun&quot;. Mr. Mengfu wrote a long preface in which he included his own critical opinions. He criticized it with real swords and guns. Mr. Shinan did not think that Sorry, let it remain in the preface as it is. This is the style of sincerity and magnanimity.他在2005年7月26日给我的信里说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;刘梦芙君，人在中年，而诗学诗功，两臻其妙。以仆视之，瞠乎其后，诚畏友也。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他对“畏友”是尊敬的，期盼着的。当他听陶文鹏先生提出他的《清诗流派史》个别地方有些“旧”了时，专门写信请陶先生详细指出他的不足，陶先生回了信，世南先生把信复印了一份寄给我，并写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;寄奉陶文鹏君来札复印件，与先生书评对映，虽云先生与陶君多谬赏语，而陶君能抉其瑕疵，愿先生亦能如此也。昔陈思有言：“世人著述，不能无病。仆常好人讥弹其文，有不善者，应时改定。”又引丁敬礼语曰：“后世谁相知定吾文者邪？”下走甚望先生以《清诗流派史》责编身份，能抉吾书之失，以告后世治清诗者知所戒避，此即学术公器之意也。 （2005年1月12日）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见他对于陶先生的批评，仍不满足，希望得到更多更真实的批评，他是把批评当作了“学术公器”来看待的。这让我们更加明白他之所以一往无前地开展学术批评，真的是毫无私心杂念，只不过一心一意地为了学术更加健康、成熟地发展壮大。他对于批评的态度，不是只针对他人，还希望针对自己，这样有利于自己的改进，有利于学界清晰的认知。他身先示范，有着清风朗月的美好胸襟，令人感佩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘世南教授和他的《清诗三百首详注》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他对于别人对于他的指正，非常感动，并再三致意。我社断代文选陆续规划推出，当时的古典部主任周绚隆编审考虑到世南先生对清代文学熟悉，就诚邀他来选注《清文选》，他考虑到时间紧迫，便请他的学生刘松来教授协助，书稿到来之后，由实习生北京师范大学研究生文丽琛女士在我指导下初审，然后我再复审，写好两份修改意见之后，寄呈世南先生过目。他2005年10月1日在省图书馆写的信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;9月22日手示及审稿意见、书评复印件，俱收到，请释念。捧读之下，既惭且感！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由匡正与补苴各条，亦可见先生与文丽琛女史之学富功深矣，钦服之忱，何可言罄！窃谓《清文选》他日苟能略有裨于斯世，实吾四人合作之力，非松来与我区区棉薄所致也。拟于此书前言补缀数语，以明斯义，聊以示吾两人不敢掠美之意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他后来坚持在该书前言中，加入了表彰我和小文的文字，可见他闻过则喜、虚怀若谷的贤者胸怀，令人如沐春风。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘世南教授著作两种。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“生死书丛一蠹虫”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生的斗志主要体现在他自己勤奋读书和写作上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他藏书不多，主要因为特殊时期把他两代人的藏书都销毁了，使他极度伤心，他一般就不再买书（《师友偶录》117页）。他主要是跑图书馆，省图书馆、校图书馆里，他是常客。当1994年，历经十四年的艰苦卓绝的阅读、研究、撰写，终于完成了《清诗流派史》，在次年夏日校对书稿时，他欣喜地回顾了这段历程：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;忆昔每岁除，书城犹弄翰。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;万家庆团栾，独坐一笑粲。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;卡片漫盈箱，有得逾美膳。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;心劳十四载，书成瘁笔砚。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《清诗流派史》附录《甲戌岁盛夏校对〈清诗流派史〉书稿……》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自注：“每当春节除夕，余犹坐图书馆，与管理员一人遥遥相对。”我社预备出版简体版，我有幸担任责任编辑，在编辑过程中，向他问候，提到这个给人印象深刻的场景，他在2003年12月30日晚和次日在样书库给我写回信说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;谢谢您的关注，还记得我除夕仍坐图书馆的事。如果校图仍开放，我的确会那样干。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“生死书丛一蠹虫”，一辈子就是这样过来的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;的确，他仍放不过每一天，有年除夕，馆长跟他“遥遥相对”，倒是一景了。他写信给他的学生郭丹教授说：“现在是除夕下午近4点钟，图书馆阅览厅里只剩我和张馆长两人；张馆长亲自值班，微笑着陪我到4点钟关门。”（郭丹《治学的境界&amp;nbsp;人格的风范——记刘世南先生》，《师友偶记》237页）这样的馆长真是好馆长，这样的读者真是好读者，这称得上当代阅读界的佳话。他在2006年12月31日寄给我的明信片上写着：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;书城伏案茧丝怜，忘却匆匆岁月迁。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不是华筵此宵醉，谁知后日是新年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除夕仍在读书，的确是读书种子的风范。当然他不是只瞅准了除夕，其实每一天对他来讲都是宝贵的。 2004年6月4日的来信讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《清文选》忙得很，我从未如此紧张过，因为一放暑假，校图就要闭馆，我必须赶在放假前做完这事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是在与松来教授一起赶着选注《清文选》时的情景。而后来没有要紧的工作时，仍坚持不懈地去图书馆。过去革命者有句豪言壮语“把牢底坐穿”，世南先生耄耋之年，不顾病体，仍执著前往，真是有要把图书馆坐穿的气概。 2013年1月10日的信里说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;匆匆又一年，我近住院切除鼻疣，医言为基底细胞癌，已切除干净。我已实龄九十，齐生死久矣，故出院后，仍坐图书馆。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当郭丹教授在2015年乙未年春节正月初一上午给世南先生电话拜年时，听到的回答是“已在省图书馆看书了”！ （《师友偶记》再版后记）李陶生先生多年陪护世南先生，他在《自我肺腑出未尝只字篡》一文讲：“书本是他所有的精神寄托。”“无论风霜雨雪，他都会像工作人员一样准时出现在图书馆。他说他希望自己将来能死在书桌旁。”（《师友偶记》249页）可见他痴迷于书到了何等地步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“自万卷书中来”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生泛览群籍，对经史尤其精熟，因此他能对许多论著存在的误解、误断、误改，比较敏感，并能给予指正。他除了助人刊谬，主要的精力用在《清诗流派史》的研究、撰写上了。此外用功甚多的是《清文选》的选注。在承担这项工作之后，他全身心地投入到选文当中去。尽管邀请了松来教授参与注释工作，但是他仍是处处亲历亲为：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;由选文到标点到注释，我将全部通读并改定。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这些时候，我正忙于选定篇目，主要是从《四库全书》《续修四库全书》以及《存目丛书》中选择，少数还要另从线装书库去找。例如蒋士铨，《续修》中无文，而《鸣机夜课图》等必须选入。其他可以类推。选文之事颇费时间，选定之后，要先复印，再手抄成简化体字。 （2003年12月16日）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了集中全力做好《清文选》工作，他把几年来担任的江西省高校《豫章丛书》整理工作的首席学术顾问（即最后把关）一职也辞去了。可见他对《清文选》工作的全身心投入的决心。因为他对清代文集比较熟悉，加上昼夜兼程地翻阅，到2003年12月30日，他“逐页翻阅《续修四库全书》清人别集，188册中，已翻到154册，尚余30册，寒假前可翻完”,并说“然后看《四库全书》，文集不多。《存目》未看，不知多少”。在选文上“一定别出手眼，不因人热”（2003年12月30日来信）。在这封信里，他仍难以掩饰自己挑剔的眼光，对于几种书表达了自己的意见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天看曾国藩文集，顺便找了四本今人选注的，以《原才》一篇为例，涂小马本、来新夏本、郭预衡本，对“谓之不诬可乎否也”，都断为：“谓之不诬，可乎？否也。”倒是郑振铎《晚清文选》断为：“谓之不诬，可乎否也？”断对了。涂、来、郭三人……不知“可乎否也”的“也”其实是“耶”，《经传释词》等书说得很明白，而韩愈、欧阳修所作古文，摇曳多姿，常有这种咏叹句。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，对“众人君之而受命焉”之“君”的被误解，《召诲》“播为声气”的被误解，“虽圣人不免”“不”误改作“必”，也予以辨析。他没有否定诸位的贡献，他只是为了说明自己会借鉴他们的成果，但绝对不会简单地抄袭：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;即使我们参考这类选注本，也一定辨析毫厘，决不作模糊影响之谈，而是力求明白准确。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;类似的著作可以依傍的其实很少，即便参考，也一定是有鉴别地采用，这符合世南先生向来提倡的“自我肺腑出，未尝只字篡”的治学精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2004年6月26日，已是《清文选》收尾的阶段，他向我写信介绍该书前言的撰写情况：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前言可以证明，我们两人对清文的认识略有新意，并不人云亦云看，正是因为对作品注释下了一番功夫。例如“流派单一，风格多样”，我们不仅指出了“其然”，也说明了“其所以然”。这是我们做学问的特点。也是针对中国传统文学批评来的。传统手法是即兴式的、感悟式的，只指出了“然”，而不分析“其所以然”。我们接受了西方学术的影响，总喜欢追究一个“为什么”。因此，对桐城派（包含后来的阳湖派、湘乡派）的出现，以及“天下文章，其在桐城乎”的赞辞，我们企图透过这一现象找出它的逻辑的必然性，历史现象从来都是有规律可循的，其中的因果律最值得玩味，玩味的结果也最发人深省。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陶文鹏先生听说了这篇前言的情况，立即请世南先生先期发表在《文学遗产》上。世南先生于2005年1月12日的来信中讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;陶君嘱改写《清文选》前言为论文，已与松来君合作，然画眉未必入时，朱衣未必点头，而可自信者，则此文字字句句自我二人肺腑出，自万卷书中来，无剿说，无雷同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里所体现的自信，来自他踏实的阅读、长期的深耕。这在他的著作中和批评文章里，都体现了这样的精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;选本这种文化普及方式，是传统的，但却是千百年来行之有效的一种文化传播方式，但当下较少有人愿意承担这样的工作，因为它需要投入大量精力，需要有较高的鉴赏水平，需要具备广博的知识储备和深厚的文化底蕴。注释这门学问极其难做，动辄露出马脚。而世南先生却毅然决然地答应做《清文选》这一工作，可以看出他的自信和担当。此书出版之后，读者反映很好，世南先生非常高兴，并来信讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;贵社明年如有新课题，适合松来与我棉力者，尚希玉成。盖仆虽已耄耋，而神明未衰，时复技痒，不乐措手无为也。 （2005年10月1日写于省图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见他“老骥伏枥，志在千里”的雄心。因为考虑到他年事已高，不能过于劳累，所以我们没有邀请他再做一种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“年轻的思想者”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生稳坐图书馆，似乎是个书呆子，但是他实则是个“年轻的思想者”（陈骥《永远年轻的先生》，《师友偶记》）。除了《清诗流派史》《大螺居诗文集》之外，世南先生另有《在学术殿堂外》修订再版，还有《师友偶记》，这两本书不是“纯粹”的书，收录比较杂，形式很随意，但是主题鲜明，都是论学文字，都是“干货”，其中保存了大量来往论学信笺，汇集了一些书评，讲治学方法，更讲治学精神，有意思的是还收集了与世南先生有分歧的一些观点。他在《师友偶记》前言中讲：“&#39;其争也君子&#39;，绝非意气之争，在我是&#39;吾爱吾师，吾尤爱真理&#39;。”他再一次称道梦芙先生，赞他是“诤友”，“佩服他坚持真理的勇气”。关于这部以“我和我所理解的知识人”为主题的书，世南先生说：“这本书的性质，近似《国朝汉学师承记》，是学术性的，它可做现当代学术史、思想史的资料。”的确如此，它的内容超过了一篇篇独立的论文，它包含了当代学者思想交流甚至交锋的丰富材料，学术价值非常大，在形式上无疑也是一种突破和开创。 2004年7月18日来信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您会觉得这是一幅时代风云画卷，它反映出心灵搏击的轰轰烈烈。可以给后代留下一份宝贵的遗产，让后人知道我们这时代知识分子在怎样上下求索。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此书“外编”有一篇《当代知识分子是怎样继承和发扬中国古代士的优良传统的？ 》便体现了他在思想精神层面的探索，让人知道他并非书呆子，而他活跃的思想像他的身体超过了不少年轻人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在学术研究上，他有直接深入的讨论。在诗歌创作上，也寄托遥深，值得体味。 2005年1月12日他来信谈他的《大螺居诗存》：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;先生细加披览，便知拙诗迥非批风抹月之作，而皆痛哭太息之言。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在《诗存》序里说：“凡为诗，必有为而作，决不叹老嗟卑，而惟生民邦国天下之忧。”他的不少诗作直录现实，让人不胜感叹，也让人感动他胸怀的宽广。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有感于先生用了十四年撰成《清诗流派史》，我在该书编辑出版后，写了一篇书评，发表在《海南日报》上，后来修改发表在《光明日报》上。寄呈先生过目，他在2004年6月4日的信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;忙于《清文选》工作，一般信我都搁下以后回。没想到今天得到您的信，更没想到读到您的书评。仔细读了书评以后，我竟感极而泣。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您也许会奇怪：我怎么这样容易激动？关于《清诗流派史》的书评，大约有七八篇，我并没这样激动过。而您，显然是由于身为责编，认真看了《清诗流派史》，因此又细看了《在学术殿堂外》，加上您的高超的鉴赏力和丰富的人生经历，正确的思想认识，才能写出这样一篇使我激动的书评。大作并不长，可都说到了点子上，尤其人文关怀这点，只有您敢于指出。坦白说，我写《清诗流派史》实在是抱着孔子作《春秋》、马迁作《史记》的心态。这一点，只有本校王琦珍教授一篇书评指出了，但该文似尚未问世。而您却与王先生不谋而合，这是我最快慰的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;云波先生，请让我说一句衷心感谢的话：“君为鲍叔能知管，我傲虞卿不客蝇。”这是随手凑成的一联，俱用《史记》，自觉很切。也许有人会质疑：怎么可以人对物呢？那我要大言不惭说：就算自我作古吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先生对我写的书评加以肯定，我有这个自信，但是却想不到引他到了“感极而泣”的地步，还写“君为鲍叔能知管”云云的感谢话来；他径直吐露自己的抱负和追求，可见没有见外。先生2011年录制超星学术视频，讲“我与《清诗流派史》”（后收入《师友偶记》），提到“葛云波先生真是我的知音”。这些都让我非常感动，让我倍感前辈对后辈鼓舞的力量，让我感到踏实做编辑的荣光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上的经历，无疑增加了我们的亲近。当2018年10月6日，我们全家到南昌第一次拜访世南先生，宾主欢然，他有力地握着我的手，久久不放，根本不像96岁老者的手，他能自食其力，还常去图书馆，我们都相信他能轻松度过期颐之年，我们盼望再一次拜望先生。但不成想，2021年8月2日收到了松来教授的短信，获悉世南先生于前一日晚仙逝。我本想痛定思痛之后，写篇感念的文章，然而为出版项目所累，未能如愿。今年是世南先生百年诞辰，我下定决心要写，略表对他老人家的敬仰和感怀，便有了以上不够成熟的追念文字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[娄底7岁女孩遭性霸凌疑云：到底是夸大其词还是轻描淡写？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，湖南娄底一网民称自己7岁的女儿在学校午休时被同班十几名女同学霸凌，甚至伤及下体，引起网络极大关注。而当地通报称经调查确认有女学生短暂打闹，但未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月28日，湖南娄底一家长在社交媒体发帖，称女儿7岁，在湖南娄底某乡镇小学二年级读书，10月20日午休时间，被同班十六七个女同学在操场上霸凌，这些女同学不仅殴打其女，还对其进行性霸凌，导致女儿下体受伤，疼痛难忍。而校方和霸凌方同学家长都对解决问题态度消极。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二年级的小女孩就集体对女同学实施霸凌，尤其是涉及性霸凌，骇人听闻。让人不禁想起几个月之前曝光的山西大同某双语学校9岁小学生性霸凌事件。因此，事件很快成为网络热点，引起了极大的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日，事发地冷水江市（娄底市代管县级市）以联合调查组名义发布情况说明，称发现相关视频后第一时间成立了由市教育局、公安局等部门组成的联合调查组，经公安部门初查，当事女生张某与其他六名女同学为该市某小学二年级同班同学；10月20日中午，因为在操场跳绳时发生争执，发生“相互打闹”约1分钟，其间张某被其他几名同学“短暂围住拍打”；经过调取监控，“保护性”询问涉事女生，调查目击老师和学生，未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一官方通报对事件的定性与受害人母亲的指控天差地别，对事发过程的描述也用词模糊、语焉不详，没有对所指控的关键问题作出澄清。官方如果确有充分证据是女孩家长夸大事实，就应该公开证据反驳，否则，不仅无法消除公众的疑虑，反而会引起更大的质疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是女生张某下体有没有受伤。根据张某母亲发布的信息，张某身体有多处软组织损伤，下体也受到伤害，小便时疼痛难忍，为此被迫憋尿。但官方通报虽然确认发生了“相互打闹”，但对张某是否受伤只字未提。这也是此事中最受网民关注，也是让人最为气愤的一点。官方不应回避，应该对此进行调查并公布结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果张某下体确实受伤，那这是非常严重的侵害未成年人事件，必须查明受伤的原因，如果涉及犯罪行为，要严惩不贷。如果张某并没有受伤，那也要拿出有足够公信力的证据，反驳女孩家长的指控。比如可以在家长陪同下带张某到娄底市以外的三甲医院进行检查，并公布检查结果。如果张某母亲夸大其词或撒谎，也不应回避。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，对当时在操场上发生的事件经过，有必要公布相关视频，以正视听。张某母亲称，张某在操场上被十六七个同班女生殴打。而官方的情况说明则称除张某外只有6名学生涉事，而且多名女生“相互打闹”只有约一分钟时间，而张某只是被几名同学“短暂围住”“拍打”。双方的说法，不仅参与人数相差巨大，而且“殴打”与“相互打闹”之间也存在着性质的巨大差别。既然官方说明中提及警方调取了学校的监控录像，那就是说事发经过是有录像的，并不是张某母亲帖子中校方所说的“监控老化”。既然有录像，那就应该完整地公之于众，让公众自己判断到底是“殴打”还是“相互打闹”，到底持续了多长时间，有没有“故意伤害”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，出于保护未成年人的考虑，对录像中能够辨认的未成年人可以进行保护性技术处理，比如打马赛克、模糊面部等，但应该保证能看出有几个人参与了事件，以及“打闹”的程度到底是怎样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;才7岁的小女孩就会霸凌同学，而且还涉性，似乎有些不可思议。但也并非不可能。在山西大同某双语学校霸凌事件中，霸凌者也不过才9岁，而霸凌并非第一次发生，也是从二年级就开始了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一种刻板印象，好像学校中霸凌别人的就是男生。其实不然，校园暴力事件中，女性施暴的比例并不低。 2023年3月，海南曾爆出一名13岁女孩被一群同性同龄人殴打侮辱的霸凌事件。在大同事件引发极大关注时，刑法学教师蔡某也曾收到爆料，一位女同学被宿舍的其他女同学欺凌，同样有涉性行为，施害者还拍下了视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早年，央视曾报道过一份研究，发现网络上爆出的校园霸凌视频中，八成以上的施暴者是女性。当然这可能和女性霸凌者更倾向于拍下视频并上传到网上羞辱被害人有关，但也说明，校园暴力中女性施暴者绝不少见。而且在女性实施的校园霸凌中，不少是一群人霸凌一个人，而她们霸凌的对象，也是女性居多。还有，女性实施的霸凌中，涉性侮辱的比例不低，比如强制脱光衣服拍照之类。这或许是因为这样会给受害人带来更强烈的耻辱感。这些女性霸凌的特征，与娄底事件中受害人母亲所指控的十几名女生一起殴打、性霸凌其女儿相符。这也是网民更愿意相信受害人指控的原因之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事在网络上引起极大的关注，而官方目前轻描淡写的情况说明，显然难以服众。这不禁让人想起，在山西大同某双语学校性霸凌事件中，学校和主管部门也曾试图大事化小小事化了，但最终，霸凌事件被坐实。这次的娄底疑似霸凌事件也是如此。如果官方有足够的证据支持其情况说明，就应该及时公开，驳斥女孩家长的指控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬(1917-2009)，当代礼学宗师、著名经学家，一生潜心研习三礼之学，在礼学、经学史、文献学、甲骨金石学、版本目录学、古籍整理等诸多领域都有卓越建树，尤其是“三礼”研究，解决了礼学和经学史上许多悬而未决的难题，受到顾颉刚的高度评价。图片摄于1986年5月。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生（1917-2009）在杭州大学是个“隐身人”。 1978年10月，我进中文系读本科，他曾在“古代汉语”课时，给我们讲过几节“古代文化常识”，但大家对他没有什么印象。读研究生时，他是导师组成员，我才开始有所了解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪八十年代初的杭大校本部（今浙大西溪校区），面积不大，高大的法国梧桐树舒展地伸向林荫道，构成一道道穹窿，展示着这个校园所经历的岁月。东南角是几排青灰色砖块砌成的四层楼房，教师集体宿舍和研究生宿舍前后相望。两楼之间是锅炉房，早晨炉火轰然作响，我们每天都要去那里打开水。秋冬时分，梧桐叶已经灰败，锅炉房的行道上撒满了细碎煤灰，映衬着青灰色的砖墙，眼前一片灰蒙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时沈先生就住在一号楼第一单元一楼的一间房子里，大约十五六个平方米，对面是公共厕所，春季潮湿,夏日闷热，冬天阴冷。没有厨房，只能在走道生火，所以二十多年间，他一直吃食堂，偶尔才煮个蹄膀之类改善一下生活。直到1986年分到两居室的房子，搬离此处（那年7月他被国务院学科评议组批准为博导）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从未进过他的住处，只是每次路过时，会有片刻的伫视。后来多次在梦中到过他门外，从门上方的玻璃透过去，仿佛看到了墙上的条幅，却总看不清内里，就像他的为人与为学，十分神秘，望不真切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我经常在去食堂的路上遇见他。那时他年过花甲，宽广的额头，稀疏的头发，花白的胡子，脸色却十分红润。他个子不高，但很壮实。冬天时，他在老棉袄上套一件陈旧的灰色罩衣，左手挎着一个很浅的竹篮子，也像是个簸箕，那双大手，有着粗壮的指节。他总是面带笑容，仿佛挪动似的走在路上，口中略有“呼哧呼哧”的声音。若是遇到旁人注视的目光，他用眼中的笑意作回应，嘴巴似有牵动，并不说出话来。他看起来是温和平静，又如海似渊。他微笑时身上洋溢出能量，让路人也不禁受到鼓舞。所以我觉得那个时候他的心情很不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们这些“新晋”的研究生，那时经常谈论的便是自己的导师和对方的导师：主要做哪个领域，出版过什么著作，在哪里发表了论文，听闻有怎样的评价，对学生有哪些要求，有什么口头禅，在课堂讲了什么新鲜事……自豪地介绍对导师的发现，互相分享，并认真地听别人的补充与议论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;室友陈剩勇是沈文倬先生所带的第一个研究生。我对沈先生的了解，便是通过剩勇同学充满崇拜的解说和大家的议论，慢慢地丰富起来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左起：方建新、沈先生、李解民、王云路(摄于1997年)。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生，字凤笙，号菿闇，江苏吴江人。幼入私塾，长则自习，未获任何文凭。他早年从沈昌直学读古文辞，从金天翮、姚廷杰受文史之学。 1940年代初，从曹元弼专攻“三礼”之学，为其关门弟子，耳提面命达九年之久。曹元弼（1867-1954），人称清代最后一位杰出的经学家，时已年逾古稀，故寄厚望于沈文倬：“善守可望有成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年，他发表了《说高禖》《“蜡”与“腊”》等文章，引起顾颉刚的注意，破格聘其为国立编译馆副编审，主要负责校点经籍、编撰提要、草拟经学词典。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，被派往北京华北人民革命大学政治学院学习。次年6月，分配至上海图书馆，任编目部副主任。我们经常查阅的《中国丛书综录》，极厚的三册，叠起来有一尺多高，就是由他主持编成的。 1960年，《综录》编辑组被评为上海市先进集体，身为组长的他，作为代表出席了上海市群英会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1963年2月，应姜亮夫教授的邀请，调入中国科学院浙江分院的语言文学研究室（设在杭州大学，夏承焘为主任），为专职研究人员，只身赴杭州。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3月，甫抵杭，即往谒马一浮先生；4月下旬，再往。 “以后学求谒前辈学者之礼相见，主亲客敬，融洽无间”。有所悟，也有所思，撰有《蒋庄问学记》以记之。秋后到长春东北文史研究所讲《仪礼》，入冬回杭。欲再谒，未成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年，“谈论古学的风气戛然而止，而情趣也大减”。不久，即下乡参加“社教运动”，到了我的家乡诸暨县的某公社，驻留有时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前，他有多篇论文在《考古》上发表（1961，1963），传言时任中国科学院院长的郭沫若先生见后，评价颇高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“文革”发生后，研究室解散，他转入杭大中文系，在系资料室做资料员。因博闻强记，同事惊为“活字典”。他则独自默处，但从未停止礼学研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1974年，被安排赴安吉参加杭大最后一期“五七”干校“农林班”，白天做“鸭司令”，晚间仍探礼学之奥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1975年3月，将《武威出土&amp;lt;礼&amp;gt;汉简考辨》等四种，寄请顾颉刚先生审阅。顾复信称“台端实为今世治礼经者之第一人也”，同时又叹息，这些成果不知何时才能面世。以上这些话语，当时只是在一个很小的圈子内流传，并不为外界知闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;顾颉刚复沈文倬函。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到“文革”结束, 情况又有了变化。 1979年，他转到教师岗位。次年，评为副研究员，时已64岁。我们82级研究生，是他第一次招生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时杭大对中华书局的《文史》和上海古籍的《中华文史论丛》最为推崇，视为古代文史领域的顶刊，沈先生则是其中的常客。其中如《略论礼典的实行和〈仪礼〉书本的撰作》(《文史》15、16辑，1983)，提出“礼典的实践早于文字记录而存在”，由以阐明礼典与礼书的关系，后来杨向奎先生称此文是“鸿文巨制，成绩空前”。又如《黄龙十二博士的定员和太学郡国学校的设置》（1983）一文,对汉代建立经学博士的复杂史实条分缕析，正皮锡瑞《经学历史》之误，纠王国维《汉魏博士考》之偏，从而详判武、昭、宣三代各经博士官的兴废增缺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有后学称，沈先生的文章视野非常开阔，既有宏观的关照，贯通古今，又有微观的考证，心细如发。同时运用各种方法容纳材料，信息量极大。他对传统礼学中的任何问题，几乎都有独到的见解，文中的每一句话，几乎都凝聚着思考的结果。他的叙述语言非常典雅，几乎与引用文献可以无缝对接，是一种很难达到的境界。对此，我也深表赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，我那时并没有认真拜读过沈先生的著作与论文，也怕读，因为太深奥了。我只是读过他在《中华文史论丛》上的专栏，名为“菿闇述礼”，有时一期刊发数则，所占篇幅，不过一两页，所释则为一字或一物，都属疑难问题之解说，于文史研究关系颇大，而文字典雅凝练，令我叹服不已。这类短文，他从1946年就开始写作了,采山之铜，累积甚丰。很多年后，他汇集成书，仍取栏目之名，不过薄薄一册，十余万字，但甚得好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬先生在书斋中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我开始学写论文时，就知道短论文是最难写的，因为数百字、千余字，要提出一个真问题，罗列材料并且讲清楚，是多么的困难呵！据说沈先生的另一本著作《〈礼〉汉简异文释》，写成时有四十余万字，他并不急于发表，反复压缩，最后出版时，只有十六万字。在我们读研究生时（1982.9-1985.6），他除了一些论文，尚无著作出版。他的第一部专著《宗周礼乐文明考论》,其实是他的论文集，在1999年才问世，写作跨度逾40年，总数也才14篇。那时他已经是耄耋之年了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生一生淡于名利。他说：“治经治礼不易，只有心除&#39;魔障&#39;，胸臆如水，方能专注向学，趋于会通。”他一生的著述其实不多，学者却推许他为“礼学大师”，因为他的文章不靠量的堆积，而是以质取胜。他的每一篇文章都解决了历史上悬而未决的问题，累积起来，便令人叹为观止，且是仰之弥高了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非常幸运的是，沈先生专门为我们开了课。当时我们五名研究生，由五位导师指导，他们每人讲授三堂课，构成了一个学期的研究生课程。他的三堂课，连郭在贻老师也来听了，就坐在后排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生从小患有严重的口吃，连讲一句完整的话，对他而言，都是很吃力的事情。这也是他很少上课的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时老师们所讲的内容是自选的，也都是多年深思所得。印象中，沈文倬先生讲到了先秦诸子流派和古文今文有关问题。在我当时有限的知识里，《论》《孟》《老》《庄》作为独立的著述，稍有涉猎，《墨子》未曾读过，《礼》《书》则不敢碰，至于各家之间的关系，则全无了解。沈先生的课，却讲出了各派思想之间错综复杂的关系，特别是稷下学派、名家，这些几无著述传世的学派，原来也曾在与各家的角逐中占得大势，令其他各家不得不作回应与调整；某些消失的流派，其学说则为他家所融合而流传于后世。这让我忽然明白，原来每一家说法都不是在对某种理论来作完整系统的阐释，而是针对对手发表自己的观点，如果不知道这个论辩的背景，便会觉得其论极偏，像是对着空气作战，不知其所以然。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很像我在篮球场上打中锋，每一次强打，都必须用力把背后顶着我的那个人靠开，才能翻身把球打进。你必须知道那“顶”的力量有多大，才能明白我这一“靠”要花多少的气力。若是将我身后的人物虚化，人们在镜头中只见我对着空气用力地先靠后转，必然会嘲笑我过度使用了蛮力，即所谓“失之偏颇”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的课室里，沈先生“哧哧”地把一个个字从口中用力地迸出来，有些词花了两三次方才说得完整，就用手绢擦一擦汗水，口中依然不停。讲到开心处，他也会带着吃吃的笑声。他先用他自己的考证与解说，重新厘定了旧有概念，然后再作延伸，对一连串的问题提出新的界说，于是相关的人物事件、流派学说，被拂去久积的尘垢，露出了完全不同的容貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们所有人都肃然聆听，唯恐错过了一个音节。因为那一个个迸出来的字，如同一个个阵符在空中翻飞，构成了一个奇妙的阵法，从中显现出历史的真相。那阵势如此波诡云谲，力与力你来我往，波与波争相角逐，声与理相互呼应，这端的是百家争鸣的时代啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四十多年过去了，沈先生的具体解说，我只留下了若干印象，例如“礼书”晚于“礼典”；“古文”最初是指六国文字，“今文”则指汉隶，他从文本书写所用文字的角度，解释各经诸文本在汉代的传承情况；某人的解说，被立于学官，即是“师法”，未立之时，则是“家法”……其他具体的知识，如今大都已经忘记，只有他“哧哧”的声音，偶然还在我的耳边响起，于是他的讲解所引发的那种感触，再次如潮水般漫过我的脑回路，让我感受到一种莫名的震荡。更为重要的是，通过这些讲解，我懂得必须透过文献的表象，去感受时代背后那一道道的“力”及其相互作用，才能依稀看见上帝那只“无形之手”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生在谒见马一浮先生后，撰有一诗：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;儒经释典一炉熔，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;证得心同理亦同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;善美深微容别解，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;舒徐礼乐自圆融。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并记云：“（马）先生知予治姬旦之礼，颇申礼善乐美之旨，为之赞叹不已。予亦进&#39;舒徐&#39;一义，先生颔之者再，不以别解见摒焉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我回忆沈先生的三堂课，记录当时所见所闻的点点滴滴，敬取他的末句为题，以表怀念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解聘247名自聘科级干部：萍乡经开区“瘦身”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年， 2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者翟星理/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是我人生中的一次重大选择。”2023年4月，张世春选择放弃体制内身份，留在江西省萍乡经济技术开发区某大型国企工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，他已经在这家国企工作了4年，但保留着事业单位编制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月，萍乡经开区根据萍乡市委市政府通过的人事制度改革方案，宣布撤销19个自设机构，并解聘247名自聘科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被解聘人员中有相当一部分原本就是在编人员，经开区自聘的职务被解除后，他们可以选择保留编制、由经开区统筹安排新的工作岗位，也可以放弃编制到企业工作。原本就是编外人员的被解聘者，则可以参加全员竞聘上岗，也可以选择辞职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春就是一位由萍乡经开区自聘的科级干部，面对改革，他有两个选择，“想保留编内身份就要回机关，想留在企业就必须放弃编制”。召开一场家庭会议后，他决定留在企业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春成为自聘干部的成因并不复杂。作为中国最早设立的经开区之一，萍乡经开区经过31年发展，人口从最初的1万人增加到现在的约25万人，职能也由单一的经济开发拓展到兼顾社会管理和公共服务等，发展过程中自设管理机构、自设岗位、自聘人员，这其中既有客观原因，也有以前机构编制管理不规范、用人随意性较大等主观原因。而这也是国内开发区普遍存在的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，中共中央、国务院印发《党和国家机构改革方案》，明确中央和地方都要进行编制精简。在此基础上，多地开始清理编外人员，黑龙江省哈尔滨市、湖北省十堰市、云南省楚雄州、广东省惠州市、湖南省株洲市等地纷纷出台清理编外人员的方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区全面规范人事管理，在解聘的247名干部中，包含清退违规借用人员63人，辞退17人，另有8人放弃事业编制到企业工作。改革后全员推行“主办制管理”（一种人员管理方式，将在编人员和编外人员统一聘为各级主办），而非简单将编外人员“扫地出门”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;被解聘的副部长&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生于1970年的张世春，参加工作后先当了10年教师，本来的身份就是事业编制。离开学校后，张世春进入教育局工作，1997年又调到萍乡经开区，后来当上了经开区党工委党群工作部副部长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，因工作需要，张世春被调整到经开区一家大型国资企业担任党委副书记、纪委书记，编制还保留在经开区党群工作部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时像世春这样的情况还是比较多的。”党群工作部副部长喻志峰解释，即从经开区机关到企业任职，仍然保留着机关编制的这类人员，一共有七八位。国有企业都没有事业编制，但他们仍然保留着事业编制身份，属于经开区自聘的科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自聘，就是自行聘任，未经上级组织部门备案，上级组织部门并不认可。如果一个公务员或事业编人员经正常组织流程被任命为副科级干部，需要上级组织部门为其备案，但经开区根据工作需要，未经上级组织部门备案就聘为正科级，那么实际上他的级别仍然是副科级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年和2022年，江西省委巡视组两次巡视萍乡都指出这个问题。以2022年为例，当年4月省委第四巡视组巡视萍乡，7月28日，第四巡视组向萍乡经开区党工委反馈巡视情况，4条主要意见中第三条就是针对经开区的组织工作，“完善上下贯通、执行有力的组织体系差距较大”。巡视组提出整改意见建议，“聚焦解决好机构人事领域重点突出问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喻志峰介绍，经开区人事领域比较突出的问题就是自设机构过多、自聘干部过多：经过多年发展，经开区自聘的科级干部达到247人，主要有三类：经开区在编人员、上级机关或兄弟区县调入的干部、经开区自聘的编外人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人事改革工作启动后，经开区组织相关领导干部对这247名自聘干部进行一对一谈话，由经开区党工委主要领导牵头。喻志峰说，一对一谈话持续了几个月，主要是阐释政策和改革的紧迫性，“耐心细致地做解聘对象的思想工作”。对于原本就在编内的自聘干部，给他们选择权，可以放弃编制选择在企业工作或保留编制在机关任职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春更倾向于放弃编制留在企业任职，但他也对家人讲明了在企业任职的风险：一旦企业发展遇到困难，他的收入也会随之下降，甚至可能失业，“我们商量之后最终决定我留在企业，也是相信经开区改革后企业会发展得更好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，执行解聘工作的喻志峰本人也是自聘干部。被解聘前，他的职务是党群工作部党支部书记、副部长。解聘后，他还是事业编，但只保留了党群部副部长的职务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“小马拉大车”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;解聘247名自聘干部的同时，萍乡经开区还撤并了19个自设机构，包括区政法委、区国资委、区信访局等。喻志峰解释，“在多年经开区发展的历程中，随着不断增加的社会事务和服务人口，经开区在未取得上级同意的情况下违规自设了机构、聘任了大量干部。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年，1995年升格为省级开发区，2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区，2021年12月底调区扩容后辖区总面积119平方公里，常住人口约25万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2021年6月，国家级经济技术开发区有230个。萍乡经开区GDP已连续5年稳居全国百强经开区行列，2022年全国排名第62位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和全国其他经开区一样，萍乡经开区也是市政府的派出机关，为功能区而非行政区。 “设置之初，经开区的职能单一，主要是经济发展任务，因此上级部门给经开区核定的编制数不多。”萍乡经开区党工委党群部部长朱敏告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经开区提供给南方周末记者的材料显示，经开区设置之初并未划定具体区域范围，1995年升为省级开发区后，萍乡市政府决定将6个行政村划作直接开发范围，开发面积10平方公里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“按照这样的面积和人口，当时经开区也确实不需要太多编制。”朱敏说，但在发展过程中，萍乡经开区的面积逐渐扩大，而且伴随产业聚集、萍乡市老城区人口纾解等因素，导致经开区人口剧增。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按萍乡市官方发布的数据，经开区常住人口从2011年的11万人增长至2021年的25万人。同年，萍乡市下辖的芦溪县常住人口为26万人，莲花县常住人口为21万人。这意味着，经开区管理的人口与萍乡市的普通县城相当。在经济规模上，萍乡经开区2022年新年贺词显示，2021年前三季度经开区完成地区生产总值223.159亿元，总量列萍乡市第1位。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;管理25万人口的萍乡经开区有多少编制？朱敏介绍，2022年，上级编制部门对经开区管委会编制进行了重新核定，现有参公编102名，事业编138名，合计编制240名。而南方周末记者从权威渠道了解到，周边地市某区公务员编制有700多名，事业编有1000多名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为应对随着人口和区域面积不断增加而增加的社会管理职能，萍乡经开区开始自设机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，经开区自设机构基本分为两种情况：人口增长产生社会管理需求，必须自设机构提供公共服务；市级职能部门出于垂直管理需要，要求经开区设立相应机构以进行工作对接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，经开区自设5个社会工作管理局，每个局管理几个行政村，实际上履行的是乡镇政府或城市街道办职能；经开区的城管局、园林管理局的设立，则是因为萍乡市城管局、园林管理局要求经开区也设立管理机构，便于城管、园林工作在萍乡全市统一规划和开展工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一些自设机构是经开区为统筹条线工作而设置的。经开区公安机关是萍乡市公安局设立的开发区分局，检察职能由萍乡市检察院设立的驻开发区检察室履行，审判机构由安源区法院托管，设立了开发区法庭。为了统筹公检法和信访、巡访、综治工作，经开区又自设了政法委。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过31年开发建设，经开区已成为一个高度产城融合的功能区，经开区管委会的职能从单一转向综合，事实上在履行类似区县政府的职能。南方周末记者采访期间，经开区一位主要领导分析，以现有编制和人员数，经开区要履行好所有管理职能有点像“小马拉大车”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“锁死入口，畅通出口”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自设机构、自聘干部过多虽然有实际工作的需要，但也是机构人事管理不够规范造成的，机构、干部过多也产生了很多不良后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在干部队伍建设上，上级组织部门不认可经开区自聘干部，对干部成长造成了不利影响，这客观上是不利于干部的培养的。”喻志峰解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏调任经开区任党群工作部部长之前在萍乡市委组织部任职。 2019年，朱敏到萍乡市委组织部干部一科工作，负责联系经开区，“当时我就提过经开区组织工作不规范的问题，自设机构太多”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，萍乡市委、市政府大力推进萍乡经开区人事制度改革，市委组织部、市委编办、市发改委等部门牵头组织外出学习其他地区经开区人事改革的经验。到2022年，人事改革推进的力度明显加大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年第11期《中国机构改革与管理》杂志刊发了萍乡市委编办的署名文章《萍乡推动编外人员规范化管理》。文章总结萍乡市对于编外聘用人员进行清理的工作经验，总体原则是把编外聘用人员和在编人员统一纳入总量管理，机构编制部门根据部门的职能和编制情况核定编外聘用人员员额，对超出核定员额的编外聘用人员坚决清理，对员额内的编外聘用人员规范化管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文章还总结了使用编外人员的方向，对行政审批、行政执法、档案管理、政工人事、信访以及涉密等岗位禁止使用编外聘用人员；坚持“管事不聘人”的原则，用人单位的物业管理、安保、绿化养护、食堂服务、信息网络服务、公共建筑设施和设备维护等工作，除中小学、幼儿园食堂外，一律不得使用编外聘用人员，全部采取市场服务外包、政府购买服务的方式予以解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，经开区此次清理编外聘用人员也在上述原则框定的范围内进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月人事制度改革后，经开区根据萍乡市委、市政府批复的人事制度改革方案实行了员额总控。在这个基础上，经开区进一步规定，按照员额总控的要求，未来不再新增编外人员，只在编制限额内招录人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“锁死编外人员进入经开区的入口，同时强化对现有人员的考核管理，推行末位淘汰制，畅通出口。”朱敏说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;绝不是“扫地出门”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在解聘自聘干部时，经开区主要担心的是引起解聘对象的过度反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏就改革方案向萍乡市委主要领导进行过汇报，“领导强调了大方向：改革的目的不是把你们经开区改没了，经开区仍然是萍乡经济发展的引擎。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;撤并19个自设机构后，重新调整工作归口，将撤并掉的机构职能分别并入经开区党政办公室、经济发展局、社会发展局等8个内设机构和园区企业服务中心、社会治理中心等8个事业单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，经开区打破身份界限，对在编人员和编外人员统一实行“主办制管理”，不区分是否在编，只看岗位，主办共分为12级，每个级别对应不同的薪酬。主办有晋级机制也有降级机制，并且设置了每年5%的考核不合格率，明确连续两年考核不合格的直接予以淘汰，实现主办级别能上能下，薪酬绩效能升能降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在朱敏看来，经开区逐步消化编外人员绝不是简单的“扫地出门”，而是通过主办制让留下来的编内编外人员在同一个赛道竞争，“不管是体制内的还是体制外的，都要给这些年轻人留机会”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者采访期间，经开区正在进行一项调研，主题是探索干部队伍激励的新机制，通过竞岗、转岗、待岗、降岗、解聘等方式，构建具有竞争性的选拔机制。南方周末记者向经开区几位主办求证，他们表示在机构改革之后，工作节奏更快、工作强度更高、工作压力更大。 2023年国庆假期后，不少主办连续工作至今，周末基本也只能休息半天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而另一个原因是，机构撤并、清退人员后，原有机构的社会管理职能并未完全剥离，各项职能被划分至新成立的事业单位中，因此工作总量并未减少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，随着下一轮改革的到来，全国的经济技术开发区或许将迎来一次职能上的“瘦身”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年3月发布的《安徽省“十四五”开发区高质量发展规划》，有专门章节论述开发区体制机制改革，重点提到&amp;nbsp;合理划分开发区管理机构、属地政府、开发运营公司实权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，《河南省开发区高质量发展促进条例（草案）》提请河南省人大常委会第一次审议，草案明确管委会主要承担政策制定、发展规划、行政审批、招商引资、企业服务等行政管理职能，未提及社会管理职能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两地的表述都释放出一个信号：省级层面对开发区的职能定位也许仍然是经济发展。那么，在各地开发区发展过程中逐渐增加的社会管理职能如何处理？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，国家层面针对全国开发区下一轮体制机制改革的总体规划中，理顺开发区与行政区的关系，逐渐剥离社会事务管理职能是趋势之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际足联：沙特是2034年足球世界杯唯一申办方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:55:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;FIFA announced on October 31 that the Saudi Arabian Football Association was the only one to submit a proposal to host the 2034 Football World Cup before the deadline. Apply to the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FIFA confirmed that it has received Saudi Arabia’s application to host the 2034 World Cup, and Saudi Arabia is currently the only country that has expressed interest in hosting the 2034 World Cup to FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256476&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, FIFA announced that the only application for hosting the 2030 World Cup was jointly submitted by the football federations of Morocco, Portugal and Spain. Currently, these three countries have confirmed their intention to bid. Since the centenary celebration of the World Cup will be held in 2030, FIFA plans to hold a World Cup match in Uruguay, Argentina and Paraguay. These three countries have also confirmed their intention to host FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saudi Arabia, like Morocco, Portugal and Spain, still needs to pass the review of FIFA. If these bidding countries can meet the requirements put forward by FIFA, complete the entire bidding process and pass, then FIFA will determine its hosting rights at the FIFA Congress at the end of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总部人去楼空，国美无力回天？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT9aftX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YJ65b9i4FJZtzcQuCadEI1vKbyN8XFksZIT 9aftX. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, the Gome headquarters was empty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pengrun Building, located at No. 26 Xiaoyun Road, East Third Ring Road, Beijing, was once a The top-level office building with the largest single area in Asia is close to the Embassy District and Chaoyang Park. This is also where the headquarters of Gome Electric Appliances is located. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its opening in 2000, this 36-story light blue building with an apron on the top floor has witnessed the founder of Gome Huang Guangyu become the richest man in China three times, and now it has witnessed the rise of Gome The embarrassing situation of electrical appliances due to losses, payment arrears, and wage arrears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, on the lottery page of the Gome APP, a pop-up window targeting Gome founder Huang Guangyu and current Gome Chairman Huang Xiuhong appeared, including &quot;arrears of wages and arrears of payment.&quot; In fact, issues such as wage arrears at Gome have already emerged as early as 2022, and angry employees clashed with Huang Guangyu in Pengrun Building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;To what extent have employees been forced to do pop-up windows? Now Gome is in a state of no one&#39;s supervision, and employees can only find windows by themselves.&quot; Leaving Gome in Beijing in March 2023 Zhao Qiang, an employee at the headquarters, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Headquarters&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Empty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Gome Retail (0493.HK) Financial report data shows that Gome Group has a total of approximately 32,000 employees in 2021. As of the first half of 2023, the number of Gome Group employees is 3,609. This means that in one and a half years, Gome has lost 90% of its employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pengrun Building used to be full of American people. There was no place to park in the morning, and the cafeteria was full of people at mealtime.&quot; Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters, but when he left , most floors of the building were deserted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of Monday, October 30, Southern Weekend reporters came to Pengrun Building. It is divided into two buildings, A and B. The 3rd to 36th floors of Building B are the offices of Gome Electric Co., Ltd., and the only building in Building AB is The difference is that only Building B has strict access control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I walked into the Gome headquarters, the corridor lights were still on. The biggest feeling was that it was &quot;empty&quot;. Conference rooms, office areas, and reception rooms of all sizes were locked, and there were only a few staff members. Walking around with the cleaning staff, I saw strangers visiting me, but no one came up to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 18th floor of Pengrun Building, banners hanging on both sides of the elevator read &quot;Become a trusted world-class retail enterprise&quot; and &quot;Lead the survival and development of enterprises with &#39;faith&#39;&quot;. The black background wall in the middle is printed with &quot;Gome&quot; is two big words. On the right side of the background wall is the publicity room of Gome Group, which is densely packed with various certificates and trophies from Huang Guangyu, Du Juan and Gome Group in the past. But the time is mostly concentrated before 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conflicting with these past honors, there are now A4 papers posted everywhere here saying &quot;No entry to non-staff members of this floor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The 18th floor is the place where Gome receives merchants and suppliers. There are several large VIP conference rooms, and there used to be many people every day.” Zhao Qiang said. Southern Weekend reporters observed this floor for nearly half an hour, but no one came except one or two cleaning staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gome supply chain companies responsible for providing support to merchants and suppliers are concentrated on the 16th floor. They used to include Gome Customization Company, Ningbo Gome Zhenxuan Technology Co., Ltd., etc. The original office areas of these companies have been locked. And was removed from the floor guide board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. He made a high-profile statement that he would strive to restore the company to its original market position in the next 18 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His biggest move after his return was the launch of the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP, which represents Gome&#39;s retail strategy. The financial report shows that in 2021, Gome spent 962 million yuan on advertising on this APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Traces of &quot;True Happiness&quot; appear intensively on the 17th floor of Gome&#39;s headquarters. The red banner of &quot;Let&#39;s fight for a better career together and create a better life together&quot; is still hung in the office area, and the words &quot;12.24 9 :00-12:00 The room for the scheduled meeting of &quot;Home Appliances Division, Life Electrical Appliances&quot; has been locked. Zhao Qiang lamented, &quot;&#39;True happiness&#39; is earned by how many Gome employees work hard, work overtime and stay up late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth floor of the headquarters includes the national third-party logistics company established by Gome Group in 2012.&quot; The office area of ​​&quot;Anxun Logistics&quot;, a logistics company that had previously been rumored to be planning an IPO. It&#39;s pitch dark here now. At the end of 2022, news has emerged that Anxun Logistics and its subsidiaries owed more than 3 million in freight to multiple carriers in Henan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be said that after 2023, the entire country and the United States will fall into a state of deathly silence.” Zhao Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bt8FPUdo6Mqi7q4arE3fifbQywWAnz0zpzEUxeUm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The traces of &quot;really happy&quot; are still there. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where did the money go&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The top 36 floors of Pengrun Building were Huang Guangyu’s office in previous reports. However, a former employee of Gome who had successfully &quot;climbed&quot; told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Boss Huang also lives here, and there is a villa on the 36th floor that he renovated in a Chinese and Western style.&quot; If you want to climb to the 36th floor, You need to take the exclusive elevator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past, many employees came to ask for their wages and climbed up one level at a time, causing trouble twice. Later, in order to prevent people from going there again, we couldn’t enter that level.” Zhao Qiang remembered that there had been The supplier came to ask for payment, and squatted at the door of Pengrun Building until Huang Guangyu, and &quot;followed Boss Huang to the 36th floor, but I don&#39;t know how to deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, many media reported the news that Daqing Gome suddenly closed down and nearly 20 home appliance dealers begged for payment but &quot;didn&#39;t know who to ask for it from.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Judgment Documents Online, Gome was involved in 268 lawsuits in 2022, and this number reached 1,219 in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year’s lawsuits include an electrical equipment company in Foshan City, Guangdong Province requiring Foshan Gome Electric to pay a payment of 1.26 million yuan, a company in Zhejiang requiring Zhejiang Gome Electric to return rent and liquidated damages totaling 2.2 million yuan, and a construction company in Ningbo The decoration company requires Gome Electrical Appliances and Gome Retail to pay 2.4 million yuan for the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was March and April 2022 when employees who resigned began to discover problems in the company. &quot;The biggest problem is the funding problem, which means we can&#39;t settle the account,&quot; Zhao Qiang told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former employee who was directly involved in Gome’s sales and purchase still remembers that in the past, his work did not require consideration of billing issues, but starting in 2022, he was in a “pay here, then that” situation. I just can’t pay” situation. &quot;It&#39;s very intuitive to feel that cash flow is very tight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, he checked Gome&#39;s daily sales. &quot;I remember that the daily sales at that time could still reach tens of millions to 100 million or even higher, so I personally felt that it would not be overwhelming, but I don&#39;t know where the money went when it came back.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2022, &quot;employees&#39; basic salary is still there, but the performance part is rarely paid&quot;, and the situation gradually becomes more and more serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, at an all-staff meeting held in Pengrun Building, Huang Xiuhong, chairman of Gome Electric Appliances, publicly stated, “The company will only provide social security to employees and will not pay wages until the end of December. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome also requires employees to sign a commitment letter, which mentions that “starting from October 2022, we understand that the company may delay the payment of employee wages in the next six months to one year... Commitment adjustment Have a positive attitude and believe in the company... As employees, we promise to work hard, deliver business results on time, with high quality and quantity, and achieve performance goals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I also read this commitment letter at the time. If I don&#39;t sign it, does it make sense that I still owe back wages?&quot; Zhao Qiang said that some employees have already had zero income for a year. After his salary appeal failed, Zhao Qiang also filed for arbitration. According to the judgment, Gome owed him more than 200,000 yuan in salary plus provident fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another manager of a relevant Gome department told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;I am not owed wages, but all the children under me are owed wages. 200,000 yuan is a lot.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more unacceptable to Zhao Qiang is that starting from May 2022, Gome will no longer pay social security provident funds for its employees. &quot;But our personal contribution was deducted, and the company did not hand it over to the Provident Fund Management Center. This is the case for all employees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is equivalent to using our money, but we don’t know where it was used. .&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee of the Lianyungang branch of Gome Electric Co., Ltd. told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Since October 2022, we have realized that Gome has begun to have financial problems because wages have not been paid on time. , it was postponed until the store closed in March this year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employees all filed for arbitration, but they did not have much confidence. &quot;There is no money in Gome&#39;s account, so it will end in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome Electric Appliances has 3,895 chain stores across the country and more than 200 million members. However, starting in 2023, news of Gome store closings appeared one after another. In October, some media reported that all Gome stores in Guangdong were closed. Later, the company responded that not all Gome stores were closed. However, published data showed that Gome reduced its self-operated stores in Guangdong Province by 12 in the third quarter. There are 74 franchise stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome employees and consumers in Beijing, Shanghai, Lianyungang and other places also told Southern Weekend reporters that Gome stores in their cities are also gradually closing. Many interviewees said, “Gome stores across the country are basically closed.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the process of store closures, situations that were unacceptable to consumers emerged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A consumer in Shanghai purchased a 7,200 yuan washing machine at the Shanghai Gome Changning Head Office in December 2022. Gome did not deliver the goods and did not refund the money. The consumer sued Gome and then mediated. Gome promised Refunds will be issued before August 2023, but there has been no news so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although I know that Huang Guangyu has been in and out of prison, it does not affect my shopping at Gome. I have never thought about not shipping the goods after paying,&quot; the above-mentioned consumer told the Southern Weekend reporter. Among the thousands of lawsuits involving Gome in 2023, there are a large number of similar sales disputes, employee wage arrears lawsuits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the funding problem, in Zhao Qiang’s impression, the second change in the company is the frequent changes of direct leaders, which means that there is a problem in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, dozens of core executives including the former Gome Online CEO, Gome Electrical Appliances CEO, and Gome Retail President have resigned since 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How did you get to where you are today&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Huang Guangyu was born in Chaoshan, Guangdong, and is 54 years old. According to official information from Gome Group, Huang Guangyu established the first &quot;Gome Electrical Appliances Store&quot; with an area of ​​less than 100 square meters on Zhushikou Street, Qianmen, Beijing, in 1987. Gome&#39;s retail road officially started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Gome tried a new supply and marketing model, breaking away from middlemen and directly underwriting customization with manufacturers, launching a &quot;direct sales&quot; home appliance model. In 1993, Gome unified its store names, product display methods, store after-sales services, and publicity, becoming the prototype of China&#39;s retail chain model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Gome Electric Appliances was successfully listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange through a backdoor approach. Huang Guangyu used this to reach the top of the Hurun Report as the richest man in mainland China with a net worth of tens of billions, and he aspired to the top spot again in 2005 and 2008. , personal wealth once reached 45 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2008, Huang Guangyu, who was at his peak, was detained by the police on suspicion of economic crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, Huang Guangyu was sentenced to 14 years in prison for illegal business crimes, insider trading and unit bribery. In June 2020, the Beijing No. 1 Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled that Huang Guangyu should be paroled in accordance with the law. In February 2021, Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qHZYecYdZ7CXsA6rbq10BtLrX0iwfuC3R4DNFtfG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huang Guangyu’s past honors are still on display at the Gome headquarters. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Mei Ling/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang joined Gome the second month after Huang Guangyu was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have some understanding of Gome’s glory days, and I think its foundation is pretty good and its market share is huge. At that time, I thought that after Boss Huang came out, he would definitely have some new measures and methods that would bring Gome to the forefront. After vigorously developing it again and combining it with my resume, I joined.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Huang Guangyu returned in 2021, he first renamed Gome APP &quot;True Happiness&quot; as the &quot;total platform&quot; of Gome&#39;s retail ecosystem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to past media reports, when Huang Guangyu was in prison, he still communicated with company executives by writing letters. Gome executives even used drawings in their letters to try to make Huang Guangyu understand intelligence. The principles of mobile phones and APPs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhao Qiang said frankly, &quot;Until the day I resigned, I didn&#39;t know what the positioning of this APP was.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the &quot;True Happiness&quot; platform, there are three major scenes: competition venues, shows, and entertainment venues, as well as multiple sections such as content sharing communities, short video live broadcasts, event lists, and e-commerce shopping platforms. gather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang doesn’t know how to position this APP. Is it a community e-commerce, a hobby e-commerce, or a traditional e-commerce? In his opinion, this APP, which the boss has put all his efforts into, has no core and focus from design, product production to experience, which has a negative impact on communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a problem for decision-makers.” However, Zhao Qiang also mentioned that by the beginning of 2022, the basic functions of the “True Happiness” platform will already be in place, and consumers can buy things and return goods normally. . As long as there is a burst point in one plate, this route can still be followed after the overall tilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The serious internal friction within Gome made him begin to doubt the company&#39;s prospects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gave an example. Generally, the supply chain of e-commerce platforms is relatively concentrated, but within Gome, there are several companies that are engaged in supply chain at the same time. The same product of a brand may cooperate with many supply chain companies in Gome.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These supply chain companies have only one output port, which is the &quot;True Happiness&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This brings a huge waste of manpower. Each supply chain company has dozens or even hundreds of people, but multiple teams do repetitive work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Every team must survive. Everyone is constantly asking for money from the group and dividing it up. The boss may want to compete, but this kind of competition is not external, it is scattered and internal.&quot; Zhao Qiang Speaking to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gome has also built a shared and co-construction platform internally that is not open to the outside world. Small businesses and suppliers can access this system after paying a certain usage fee. &quot;The biggest problem with this platform is that no one uses it. If merchants want to open a store, they can just open a store on another platform.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;True Happy&quot; APP, Huang Guangyu has also continued to It has launched a number of apps such as &quot;Decorate Home&quot; and &quot;Zheshangzhe&quot;, which puzzled the market. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A mid-level person from Gome Group told Southern Weekend reporters, “In addition to the decision-making issues of company leaders and lack of understanding of the market environment, they are also affected by the epidemic.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Chinese Enterprises Home&quot; reported that in late October 2021, on the 36th floor of the Pengrun Building, Gome held high-level meetings for five consecutive days. Huang Guangyu was sitting in the main seat, but staring at the iPad lying flat on the table, playing the game &quot; angry Birds&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang said, &quot;Sometimes Boss Huang sleeps during the day, and meetings are held late at night, and the executives go crazy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Can it still be &quot;resurrected&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted a retired vice president-level executive about Gome’s current situation, but the other party refused to discuss the matter. In addition, all members of the public relations department of Gome Group have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the domestic official website of Gome Group cannot be opened, and the “Dressing Home” and “Zheshangzhe” apps have been removed from the Apple App Store. After spending a huge amount of promotion fees, in January 2023, “True Happiness” changed its name back to “Gome” APP. At present, some brands of Gome APP have been withdrawn, and some categories such as TVs and refrigerators have been removed from the shelves. In addition, the live broadcast sales list is blank, the cleaning, repair and other services that could have been provided have been deactivated, and no one has responded to customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the financial report, in the first half of 2023, Gome’s retail revenue was 415 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 95.74%; it achieved a net loss attributable to the parent company of 3.539 billion yuan. During the same period, Gome Retail&#39;s current assets were only 5.326 billion yuan, and cash and cash equivalents were 146 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Gome Retail’s total liability balance is as high as 37.313 billion yuan, with an asset-liability ratio of 106.55%, making the company insolvent. Among them, current liabilities were 36.106 billion yuan, accounting for 96.78%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, starting from the second half of 2021, Huang Guangyu and Du Juan have frequently reduced their holdings of Gome retail stocks, from 60.98% of their holdings at the end of 2021 to the current 10.79%. Cashed out nearly HK$2 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2021, when Huang Guangyu was officially released from prison after serving his sentence, Gome’s stock price experienced a surge. It was once nicknamed the “release concept stock” by the market. As of press time, Gome’s retail stock price was only The remaining price is 0.037 yuan per share, which is 97% lower than when he was released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the past ten years, Gome&#39;s development strategy has been mainly reflected in two words - conservative, and try not to spend as much money as possible. This is Du Juan&#39;s point of view.&quot; Liu Buchen believes that in e-commerce, In an era of dominance, the decline of traditional home appliance chains is inevitable. It is just a matter of speed or slowness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of former employees, the decline and end may be more dignified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qiang sighed, &quot;Looking back, I feel regretful. We joined Gome in the hope of helping the former myth to reshape another myth. You gave me the opportunity and I contributed my ability, but now it is difficult to come back to life. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gs8kFYyE5HhpP4GeCU4CIBL2FXr70QkUaQp1jN3g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gome&#39;s headquarters office remains in the Christmas atmosphere of 2022. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者梅岭/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中赵强为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海上危机专家谈：“我们需要的不是排外战略，而是包容的战略”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259713]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the ocean has become an emerging development space that countries are paying attention to, and a new ocean order is taking shape. At the same time, new issues such as maritime military crises and marine ecological security have also emerged. Are we ready for the new order? How should maritime disputes be managed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now that we are entering a new maritime order, we should do our best to maintain maritime security and avoid entering a state of disorder.” Jayanath Colombaj, former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy, said. He believes that many countries rely on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2023, at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control&quot; group meeting, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on issues such as maritime crises, maritime risks, maritime order and rules, etc. Discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, 2023, a number of Chinese and foreign scholars held discussions at the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing around &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Conflict-prone Period&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is facing tremendous changes, and maritime security issues have been affected A variety of factors influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Ding Yiping, former deputy commander of the People’s Liberation Army Navy, judged: “Various risk factors are superimposed, linked, and amplified, and the maritime situation is affected by them and enters a period of conflict-prone situations.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the one hand, there are traditional maritime security issues, sovereignty disputes, usage disputes, resource development, fishery and other issues.” Ding Yiping mentioned, “On the one hand, there are at least 60 countries involved in maritime usage disputes alone. More than 200 maritime disputes have arisen.” On the other hand, “criminal activities such as piracy, robbery, and terrorist attacks occur frequently.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are living in a maritime crisis.” Jayanath Colombaj is a retired lieutenant general and former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy. He is particularly concerned about maritime security issues in the Indian Ocean and its littoral countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean is the third largest ocean in the world, rich in fish and seaweed resources, and maritime trade is very developed. However, Colombaj noted that countries surrounding the Indian Ocean are still troubled by security issues, &quot;human trafficking, illegal immigration at sea They all occurred in the Indian Ocean, posing a great threat to the maritime order. In addition, there are a large number of military operations in the Indian Ocean,&quot; Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the increasing security crisis, the deterioration of the marine ecological environment has increasingly become a problem for marine governance. In recent years, climate change has led to frequent marine disasters. Melting glaciers, rising sea levels, and rising ocean surface temperatures have caused serious harm to marine and coastal ecosystems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, &quot;Some countries discharge industrial sewage and dump garbage into the ocean, resulting in seawater pollution and serious damage to marine ecology, while disorderly and uncontrolled development has caused the rapid decline of marine resources.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean that Colombaj is concerned about is also facing ecological damage. &quot;There is a 60,000 square kilometers area in the southern Indian Ocean, and there is a large area of ​​garbage.&quot; Colombaj is worried that if it is not dealt with in time, the environmental problems in the Indian Ocean will become more and more serious. serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the frequent maritime security issues, there are also more complex national games, which are not easy to solve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, “Because maritime disputes involve historical roots, national sentiments, economic and security interests, the countries involved are unwilling to compromise, and some major foreign countries intervene in other countries’ disputes for their own interests, resulting in disputes and confrontations. It has seriously affected the security and stability of some regions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Colombaj said that whether it is marine security management or marine environmental governance, countries are facing cooperation difficulties. &quot;There are several major obstacles to ocean governance, including a lack of trust, a lack of financial resources, a lack of political vision among leaders, a lack of public awareness, and a lack of broad policies,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;New Maritime Order&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are many &quot;strategies&quot; regarding the Indian Ocean. Colombaj believes that these strategies have led to strategic competition, strategic tightening, strategic dilemmas and strategic differences among a large number of countries surrounding the Indian Ocean, making the Indian Ocean unsafe. Similar to these strategies, there are a large number of joint initiatives in the Indian Ocean region, many of which remain on paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do we, a small country, need so many strategies? What goals are these strategies going to achieve? Can they bring great development to the Indian Ocean region?&quot; Colombaj believes that these strategies are about &quot;order and rules.&quot; The definition is controversial; what the Indian Ocean needs is not an exclusive strategy, but an inclusive strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When things go in the wrong direction, we can look back to the starting point. For example, with the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea adopted in 1982, we need to return to the original consensus.&quot; Colombaj believes that many The country relies on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. For example, &quot;sustainable and integrated ocean governance and enforcement are needed&quot; and &quot;military means cannot be used once a dispute arises on the ocean.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called on governments, non-governmental organizations, business and the private sector to unite together, because &quot;we can go fast alone, but we can go far together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We often hear that we live in an unpredictable world. Yet it is our (researchers’) job to anticipate the ‘unpredictable’. Now, we are entering a new ocean order. To prevent There is disorder, and we need to find order in disorder,” Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Shekhar Sinha, former Chief of the Joint Defense Staff of India, believes that after the end of the Cold War, more and more countries have improved their economies and strengthened their military strength, and the center of gravity of the balance of world power has shifted from the West to the East. , which in turn brings more great power competition. &quot;The intensity of military conflicts at sea will increase and will continue,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar is worried that violations in the military field will inevitably draw out the military, especially at sea, such as warship collisions. At the same time, the operation of military or military assets overseas involves disputes over maritime jurisdiction. The parties involved’s different understandings of history, regulations, conventions, etc. will also intensify the disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar proposed that global commerce is very important and conflicts should not affect the navigation of commercial ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that only 10%-15% of the world&#39;s ships are warships, and the rest are commercial ships. Whenever the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea is violated or violated, there must be a global warning and a law enforcement mechanism to stop such violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Warships account for a very small proportion of global ships. We must abide by relevant rules and protect commerce and trade. Conflicts between major powers are more reflected in maritime conflicts than trade conflicts.&quot; He said . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;China Plan&quot; for Crisis Management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said that the focus of the maritime security concept advocated by China can be summarized into three aspects - jointly safeguarding maritime and territorial security, and jointly responding to Maritime security threats, respect the maritime rights and interests of all countries, and oppose maritime hegemony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the ocean is public domain, and its security needs to be safeguarded by all countries in the world.” Ding Yiping proposed that we must maintain the maritime order based on international law, respect the peaceful maritime interests of all parties, and oppose the use of The oceans contain, contain, and suppress other countries, and use conflicts in other countries’ maritime interests to stir up trouble. Practice has proven that only by trusting each other, strengthening communication, active cooperation, positive interaction, and joint maintenance can we effectively ensure maritime security and maximize common interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to prevent and control maritime military crises? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping proposed that the first suggestion is to announce a strategy to prevent maritime disputes from escalating out of control and to stop inappropriate behavior by maritime military forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The current extraterritorial maritime military forces, dominated by the United States, conduct high-frequency reconnaissance, surveillance, and measurement activities in the waters surrounding China, especially the provocative acts against sovereignty in the South China Sea and the East China Sea, to control the intensity of the crisis. The increase has posed a serious obstacle to the prevention and control of maritime crises,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, U.S. warships have frequently transited the Taiwan Strait, stimulating tensions in the Taiwan Strait and constantly provoking China. Zhang Yazhong, the president of Sun Wen School in Taiwan, spoke at the meeting and said that the most fundamental and necessary way to establish a cross-strait military mutual trust mechanism, or to prevent and manage cross-strait maritime military crises, is that both sides of the strait must have a &quot;political consensus.&quot; Taiwan should return to the position of the &#39;1992 Consensus&#39;.&quot; He expressed the hope that both sides of the Taiwan Strait would have the wisdom to get rid of foreign influence, and that the two sides would resolve cross-Strait political and military problems on their own and work together to create peace across the Strait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Zhai Huan and Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[保障“外嫁女”合法权益，最高检、全国妇联联合发布6件典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 1, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the All-China Women’s Federation jointly issued a Typical cases of administrative prosecution of legal rights and interests in land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are a total of 6 typical cases in this batch, including Zhi Moulan v. the Natural Resources and Planning Bureau of a certain city in Shandong Province, collective land registration inspection and supervision case, Zhang Moujia v. Jiangsu Province A case of prosecution and supervision of the town people&#39;s government&#39;s decision not to accept the land ownership decision, a case of prosecution and supervision of the people&#39;s procuratorate of a certain district in a city in Hunan Province to protect the rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in land expropriation in accordance with the law, Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi sued a certain sub-district office in Zhejiang Province Cases of prosecution and supervision of failure to perform expropriation, resettlement and compensation responsibilities, cases of Yu suing the people&#39;s government of a town in Jiangsu Province for illegal demolition and administrative compensation, and cases of Zhou suing a village committee of a certain city in Hainan Province for the prosecution and supervision of membership confirmation of the collective economic organization of a villager group . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Procuratorial organs and women’s federations have been studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, proactively strengthening contacts, and establishing information sharing, case transfers, case notifications, and joint supervision. and other mechanisms to strengthen all-round judicial protection of women’s rights and interests. From January 2022 to September 2023, the procuratorial organs handled more than 4,000 administrative prosecution cases involving the protection of women’s rights and interests. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of my country’s urbanization process, rural women have experienced changes in marriage relationships, household registration, etc., which involve the identification of members of rural collective economic organizations, land contract management, land acquisition compensation, or Disputes over expropriation compensation and homestead use are more complex and have become issues of widespread social concern. This batch of typical cases focuses on the protection of the legitimate rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in collective economic organizations related to land, adheres to the basic national policy of gender equality, increases supervision of administrative litigation and administrative non-litigation enforcement cases involving the legitimate rights and interests of rural women, and strengthens investigations Verification, through integrated case handling, case management by hospital leaders, government inspection linkage, procuratorate and law linkage, etc., we can properly resolve disputes and promote the resolution of women&#39;s urgent, difficult and anxious issues with high-quality and efficient legal supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; pointed out that the basic national policy of equality between men and women should be adhered to and the legitimate rights and interests of women and children should be protected. The person in charge of the Seventh Procuratorate of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate said that this year is the first year to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and is also the first year of the implementation of the newly revised Law on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests. The administrative procuratorial departments of the procuratorial organs at all levels will adhere to Xi Jinping&#39;s Guided by the thought of the rule of law, we will thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on women and children, implement the Law on the Protection of Women’s Rights and Interests, continue to deepen cooperation with relevant departments such as the Women’s Federation, and work with sincerity and sincerity. Make greater efforts to handle every case with high quality and efficiency, further strengthen the equal protection of rural women&#39;s property rights, promote source governance, effectively enhance rural women&#39;s sense of gain, happiness, and security, and promote the high-quality development of women&#39;s and children&#39;s undertakings make new contributions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;关于印发维护农村妇女&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;的通知&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;各省、自治区、直辖市人民检察院、妇女联合会，新疆生产建设兵团人民检察院、妇女联合会：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近年来，随着我国城镇化进程的加快，涉土地征收征用纠纷呈现增长态势。农村妇女因婚姻关系、户籍等发生变动，涉及农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、土地征地补偿或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面的争议更为复杂。为全面贯彻党的二十大精神，深入学习贯彻习近平法治思想，贯彻执行新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》，加大对涉及农村妇女合法权益的行政诉讼、行政非诉执行案件的监督力度，更好维护妇女合法权益，最高人民检察院、中华全国妇女联合会共同选编了6件维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益行政检察典型案例，现印发你们，供参考借鉴。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;最高人民检察院&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;中华全国妇女联合会&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2023年9月7日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;维护农村妇女涉土地合法权益&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;行政检察典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例一&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;支某兰诉山东省某市自然资源和规划局集体土地登记检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女宅基地使用权登记抗诉&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;支某兰与支某瑞系姐弟关系，其父支某（2011年去世）在山东省某市某村有宅基地一处。 2015年，支某瑞向某市国土资源局（现更名为某市自然资源和规划局）申请案涉宅基地使用权的变更登记，市国土资源局同意并向支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证。 2018年10月12日，支某兰以某市国土资源局为被告、支某瑞为第三人向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求依法撤销该局为支某瑞颁发的集体土地使用证。某区人民法院于2019年4月25日作出行政裁定，认为支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，不能获得案涉土地使用权，该土地颁证行为不影响支某兰权益，裁定驳回支某兰的起诉。支某兰不服一审生效裁定，向某市中级人民法院申请再审。市中级人民法院于2020年6月4日裁定驳回支某兰的再审申请。支某兰向某区人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法受理。经听取当事人意见、调取法院卷宗和案涉土地登记原始档案、听取原审法官意见，查明：某市国土资源局主要基于案涉宅基地上房屋的《房屋继承协议》，认定支某瑞因继承房屋获得土地使用权，从而为支某瑞颁发集体土地使用证，但该继承协议列明了宅基地上房屋的5名继承人，并未写明仅由支某瑞一人继承。另查明，支某兰原系该村集体经济组织成员，婚后因孩子上学原因将户口迁出，目前生活较为贫困。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院经审查认为，根据国土资源部、中央农村工作领导小组办公室、财政部、农业部《关于农村集体土地确权登记发证的若干意见》，非集体经济组织成员因继承房屋占用农村宅基地的，可按规定登记发证。本案中，虽然诉讼时支某兰并非该村集体经济组织成员，但其系支某的合法继承人，与案涉宅基地登记行为存在利害关系，法院以支某兰现非案涉土地所在集体经济组织成员，以土地颁证行为不影响其权益为由，裁定驳回起诉，适用法律确有错误。某区人民检察院提请市人民检察院抗诉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;市人民检察院经审查，依法提出抗诉。市中级人民法院采纳抗诉意见，于2021年11月17日裁定撤销原审裁定，指令某区人民法院继续审理本案。某区人民法院于2022年9月26日作出行政判决，撤销案涉集体土地使用证。某市自然资源和规划局、支某瑞不服一审判决，提出上诉。市中级人民法院于2023年3月6日判决驳回上诉，维持原判。同时，某市人民检察院审查认为支某兰符合司法救助条件，协助其申请司法救助。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;集体经济组织中的“外嫁女”权益保护问题成为社会普遍关注的问题。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，妇女享有与男子平等的继承权，妇女依法行使继承权，不受歧视。申请农村土地承包经营权、宅基地使用权等不动产登记，应当在不动产登记簿和权属证书上将享有权利的妇女等家庭成员全部列明。户口迁出的“外嫁女”虽然不再是原集体经济组织成员，但其通过取得宅基地上房屋的继承份额，可以登记为宅基地的使用权人。针对法院以“外嫁女”与被诉土地使用权登记行为无利害关系为由裁定驳回起诉的案件，检察机关围绕争议焦点，强化调查核实，厘清事实、准确适用法律，以高质效法律监督促进司法公正，维护妇女的合法权益。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例二&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;张某甲诉江苏省某镇人民政府土地权属不予受理决定检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女土地权属行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;张某甲原系江苏省某镇某社区居民，其父母曾建有瓦房四间，并育有四女，后四女因婚嫁户口均从某社区迁出。张某甲父母先后去世。 2005年，某社区将张某甲父母的宅基地、承包地收回，重新发包给张某甲堂兄张某乙经营并签订土地承包经营合同，某市人民政府向张某乙户颁发了农村集体土地承包经营权证书。 2007年3月，张某甲离异后，户口迁回某社区。 2013年5月，张某乙夫妇将张某甲父母所建房屋拆除。张某甲等四姐妹将张某乙夫妇诉至法院，要求恢复房屋原状，未获法院支持。后张某甲的其他姐妹均出具书面申明，自愿放弃继承权。 2015年12月，张某甲向某镇政府递交宅基地使用权确权申请书，请求确认其父母原宅基地、承包地的土地使用权归其享有，确认张某乙与某社区签订的土地承包经营合同无效。 2017年3月，某镇政府对张某甲的确权申请作出不予受理决定。张某甲不服该决定，提起行政诉讼。一审法院认为，案涉土地已被某社区收回并发包给张某乙承包经营，根据《土地权属争议调查处理办法》第十四条规定，农村土地承包经营权争议案件不属于土地权属争议受案范围，某镇政府作出不予受理决定，符合法律规定，张某甲可依法另行寻求权利救济，遂判决驳回张某甲诉讼请求。张某甲提出上诉、申请再审，均未获支持。张某甲不服，向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员实地调查取证&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经审查原审卷宗，检索关联案件，实地走访调查，查明：自2013年以来，张某甲因案涉房屋及土地争议提起财产损害赔偿、不当得利返还、土地登记行为违法等13件民事、行政诉讼，其诉求均未获支持。相关生效判决虽已确认张某甲因继承取得案涉房屋所有权及宅基地使用权，亦指出某镇人民政府应当针对张某甲多年反映的宅基地被侵占问题妥善做好协调工作，但均未对该问题作出具体明确的裁决，导致案涉争议始终“诉而不决”。目前案涉社区已整体搬迁，张某甲回其父母原宅基地处重新申请建房不具有现实可能。张某甲常年在外务工，居无定所，多次诉讼实质是为求得其今后回原籍生活的“容身之所”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，本案为土地承包经营权争议，不属于人民政府土地权属争议受案范围，终审判决并无不当。但某社区未经张某甲等法定继承人同意，以自然闭户处理收回案涉土地，侵犯了张某甲等人的继承权，且张某甲户口迁回某社区后，作为村民亦应享有相应宅基地使用权。案涉争议持续近十年，历经多轮诉讼，张某甲的合法权益一直未能得到有效维护，且有引发新诉讼的可能，两级检察机关遂决定一体开展化解工作，彻底解决其多年“程序空转”难题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院致函某镇人民政府，指出张某甲权益受到侵害客观存在，镇政府应重视张某甲合理诉求，处理好当事人房屋土地问题，避免争议激化上行，保障妇女合法权益。同时，向当地妇联通报该案情况，共同至某镇政府开展化解工作。镇政府充分听取检察机关和妇联意见后，召集政法综治中心、某社区等部门商讨解决方案，最终确定张某甲可凭村民资格，以拆迁安置价格购买一套安置房用于解决居住问题。同时，检察机关向张某甲说明重新建房已不现实，应尽早从诉累中解脱，开始新生活。张某甲感受到人民政府的诚意，同意某镇政府方案。 2022年10月11日，张某甲与某镇政府签订和解协议，张某甲向检察机关撤回监督申请。该案的行政争议与民事纠纷得到实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在土地承包经营、宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。涉及村民利益事项的决定，不得以妇女未婚、结婚、离婚、丧偶、户无男性等为由，侵害妇女在农村集体经济组织中的各项权益。在办理争议历时长、关联诉讼多、民行交叉的涉损害“外嫁女”权益案件时，检察机关针对“案结事不了、程序空转”等问题，坚持人民至上、检察为民，聚焦群众急难愁盼问题，准确把握法律关系实质，统筹考虑法理情，综合运用实地走访、工作函告、协同属地妇联共同化解争议等方式“一揽子”化解行政争议与民事纠纷，切实维护农村妇女的合法权益，促进社会公平正义。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例三&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;湖南省某市某区人民检察院依法保障“外嫁女”土地征收权益检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政类案监督外嫁女征收补偿安置标准诉源治理&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2016年以来，湖南省某市自然资源和规划局某区分局（下称某自然资源和规划分局）在履行土地征收管理职能过程中，对在公安户籍管理系统单独登记立户的“外嫁女”张某及其子、王某及其女、易某及其子，分别纳入张某、王某、易某的近亲属户进行补偿安置。张某、王某、易某均不服，提起行政诉讼。 2017年6月，在张某行政诉讼案中，某区人民法院判决某自然资源和规划分局应按单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，某自然资源和规划分局依法履行了判决确定的义务；2018年12月，在易某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局主动按单独一户标准计算了安置补偿费；2019年4月，在王某行政诉讼案中，某自然资源和规划分局当庭发表“外嫁女”不按单独一户进行补偿安置的答辩意见。上述三起案件，某自然资源和规划分局对“外嫁女”是否按照单独一户核算征收补偿安置款，认定标准不统一。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院在开展“全面深化行政检察监督依法护航民生民利”专项活动中，以张某、王某、易某等三起具有典型性的案件为切口，通过数据检索，发现全区涉“外嫁女”土地征收补偿行政诉讼多达上百件。某区人民检察院经研判，决定开展类案监督。通过走访行政机关、人民法院及村民委员会，调取案卷、查看资料，发现行政机关对“外嫁女”征地补偿安置标准不统一的问题较为突出，还存在行政诉讼答辩“同案不同辩”应诉不规范等问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察人员就检察建议整改内容与行政机关进行沟通&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年3月29日，某区人民检察院向某自然资源和规划分局发出检察建议书，建议该局：1. 对“外嫁女”进行补偿安置时，要充分保障妇女合法权益，以是否依法登记所在地常住户口作为形式要件，以是否实际在本集体经济组织生产生活为实质要件，综合判断其是否具有集体经济组织成员资格。 2. 对“外嫁女”是否按单独一户进行补偿安置，制定统一的补偿认定标准。 3. 完善行政应诉机制，提升依法行政水平，维护政府公信力。检察建议发出后，某区人民检察院与某自然资源和规划分局、某区妇联多次召开联席会，交流意见，共商整改重点。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年4月27日，某自然资源和规划分局书面回复，表示进一步完善征地拆迁安置政策和补偿认定标准；严格落实“三轮会审”机制，及时梳理总结涉拆案件情况；提升自身应诉能力水平。 2022年5月，某自然资源和规划分局制定新的《征拆安置政策和补偿认定标准》手册，对“外嫁女”制定了统一的身份认定、户型认定的补偿标准，按单独一户标准对符合规定的王某等“外嫁女”及其子女计算安置补偿费。聘请4名专职律师负责行政应诉工作，从源头堵塞行政应诉不规范问题。某区人民检察院与某区妇联会签《检察监督保障妇女权益协作配合机制意见》，在线索移送、支持起诉、行政争议化解、司法救助等多方面达成合作意见，建立长效机制。 2022年6月以来，该区未再发生因“外嫁女”补偿安置标准不统一而引发的行政诉讼。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;征地拆迁补偿，事关民生民利。 “外嫁女”应否予以补偿安置，以及补偿安置标准是否一致，事关妇女群众切身利益。在土地征收补偿安置中，农村集体组织单独登记立户的“外嫁女”，应当平等享有安置补偿权利，以单独一户按照统一标准进行补偿安置。检察机关在履行法律监督职责中，对于侵害“外嫁女”补偿安置权益，已被人民法院判决纠正后仍得不到有效落实的多起同类不当行政行为，注重类案监督，找准深层次问题，推动完善制度构建，确保同类案件在同等条件下得到同等处理，促进诉源治理，充分彰显了检察机关敢于监督、善于监督的责任担当。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例四&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;钱某娟、季某熙诉浙江省某街道办事处不履行征收安置补偿职责检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格安置补偿社会治理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;钱某娟系浙江省某镇（现某街道办事处）某村村民，婚后仍落户在其父钱某户内，育有一女季某熙，亦落户在钱某户内。 2015年9月，钱某娟与其夫季某离婚，季某熙随母共同生活。 2017年，钱某娟、季某熙所在的某镇某村列入拆改范围，钱某的房屋在征收范围内。 2017年9月11日，钱某与某镇人民政府签订《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，钱某娟、季某熙未被计入安置人口。钱某娟、季某熙提起行政诉讼，请求撤销《房屋征收安置补偿协议》，并重新签订；附带审查并确认某区政府安置补偿实施方案中“虽户口在册，但已嫁于外村且无独立合法产权房屋，不计入安置人口”的规定违法。某区人民法院判决驳回诉讼请求。钱某娟、季某熙不服，提出上诉、申请再审，未获支持。钱某娟、季某熙向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理，并根据一体化办案规定，成立两级院办案组，由某区人民检察院检察长包案办理。经调阅法院卷宗材料，调取钱某的户籍信息及某村集体经济组织成员情况，咨询区集体土地征收安置人口认定政策的制定背景及实践情况，查明：钱某娟、季某熙的户籍自始在某村，未变动，二人一直与钱某夫妇在该村生活。钱某娟系某村集体经济组织成员，享受股权6.21股，有股权证。钱某签订房屋征收安置补偿协议后，房屋被拆除，钱某娟、季某熙面临住房困难。安置补偿实施方案中的“已嫁于外村”，在实践中解释为“与外村人结婚”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;经过检察人员的努力调解，钱某娟撤回监督申请&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，钱某娟、季某熙自始系某村集体经济组织成员，二人也未在其他农村集体经济组织中享受宅基地分配使用、安置补偿。安置补偿实施方案损害妇女、儿童权益，不应作为否认“外嫁女”及其子女获得安置补偿待遇的依据。考虑到提抗、审判、执行周期长，且可能引发新一轮诉讼，增加当事人的诉累，为从根本上保障当事人的权益，某市人民检察院牵头召开府检、法检联席会议，研判“外嫁女”安置补偿案件的司法裁判规则，某区人民检察院与区房征办、信访局、街道办事处等共同研究解决方案。经多方协调联动，最终达成对钱某娟、季某熙补偿50万元的方案。 2022年11月14日，钱某娟、季某熙领取补偿款后，向检察机关申请撤回监督申请。该案行政争议得到实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关由该案进一步推动行政机关制定科学、合法、可行的土地征收安置补偿政策。目前，某区政府已修订土地征收安置补偿方案，涉“外嫁女”安置政策得以调整。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;男女平等是我国的基本国策。党的二十大报告强调“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”，充分彰显党中央对妇女儿童事业发展的高度重视。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》也要求检察机关在履职中加强对妇女权益的保护。检察机关在履职过程中，坚持问题导向，针对将“外嫁女”土地征收安置补偿权益排除在外，违反男女平等基本国策及相关法律规定的现象，通过一体化办案、成立联合办案组、院领导包案、府检联动、法检联动等方式，依法开展监督，妥善化解争议，有效维护妇女合法权益。同时，通过案件办理，推动地方政府在行政管理中重视妇女权益保障，完善土地征收安置补偿政策，有力提升社会治理法治化水平。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例五&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;俞某诉江苏省某镇人民政府违法拆除及行政赔偿检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女拆迁补偿独立基本户行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;俞某系某镇村民，婚前与其父、兄共同居住。 2007年俞某结婚，户口未迁出，并一直居住在本村。因俞某属于与村集体经济组织以外人员结婚但户口未迁出的“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不符合单独分户条件，俞某同其丈夫（外地人）在俞某父亲宅基地翻建房屋240平方米，并多次申请宅基地及建房手续，但一直未能办理。 2017年，当地政府作出房屋征收决定公告，对俞某所在“城中村”改造项目内的居民房屋实施征地拆迁。房屋被镇政府拆除后，俞某向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求判令按照拆迁安置补偿的标准，以房屋产权置换方式对房屋灭失损失进行赔偿。某区人民法院审理认为，俞某与其父亲并未分户，其翻建房屋使用的是其父亲宅基地，未办理房屋建房手续。根据有关规定，案涉房屋不能按照拆迁补偿的标准予以赔偿，鉴于房屋确系俞某所建，可按照房屋重置价予以赔偿（每平方米500元）。审理中，某镇政府表示可以赔偿90万元，法院予以准许。俞某不服一审判决，提出上诉、申请再审，均未获法院支持。俞某向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经调查核实查明：俞某房屋被拆除后，一直没有经济能力购买商品房，长期在外租房居住；俞某丈夫在原籍集体经济组织无住房、无宅基地；拆迁部门认为俞某是“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不同意按照“独立基本户”进行拆迁安置补偿；俞某认为其一直在该集体经济组织享有权利和承担义务，系当地村民，在父辈宅基地上分户建房并一直居住，应以“独立基本户”对其进行拆迁补偿安置。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，并进行释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，因俞某未分户且所建房屋未能办理审批手续，终审判决并无明显不当，但俞某的权益并未得到充分保障。本案系历史遗留问题，涉及村民自治规则的正当性、传统观念根深蒂固等问题，争议化解难度大。为此，检察机关联合当地妇联，多次组织当事人协商，赴政府商谈，引导当地政府切实增强男女平等意识，依法保障妇女在农村土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面享有与男子平等的权利。同时，多次赴俞某家实地开展联合走访慰问，为俞某提供心理疏导和关爱帮扶，减少其对立情绪。为进一步厘清外嫁女的相关法律、政策问题，2022年6月23日，检察机关就该案召开听证会，并邀请具有市区两级妇联代表身份的听证员参与。会上，双方围绕争议焦点充分表达意见、听证员现场提问，明晰案件事实，就和解方案进行全面评估与多次磋商。最终镇政府一次性补偿数十万元，合计先前赔偿的90万元，俞某得到的补偿与拆迁补偿的标准基本接近，双方达成和解协议，俞某撤回监督申请。长达五年的行政争议得以实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，国家采取必要措施，促进男女平等，消除对妇女的一切形式的歧视，禁止排斥、限制妇女依法享有和行使各项权益。妇女在土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等权利。针对历史遗留问题，检察机关在办案过程中，坚持系统思维，统筹考虑拆迁安置争议形成的法律问题、社会成因和历史因素，为避免给当事人增加诉累，纾解其面临的现实困难，通过公开听证、联合商谈、入户走访等方式，推动当地政府研究制定合理的补偿方案，促成当事人达成和解协议，实质性化解行政争议，实现政治效果、社会效果、法律效果有机统一。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例六&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;周某诉海南省某市某村委会某村民小组集体经济组织成员资格确认检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格确认行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周某于1979年10月6日出生，户籍登记在某市某区某村其父亲周某驹为户主的家庭户口中。周某的父母以家庭承包的方式，承包该村土地11.31亩，承包期限至2027年12月31日。 2018年6月13日，周某与外地的冯某登记结婚，但户口未迁出，未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款。 2020年10月，某村决定给户口在本村的每个农业人员发放征地补偿款共计人民币80246元，村民小组以周某属于在本集体没有承包地的“外嫁女”，不具有集体经济组织成员资格为由，拒绝向其支付上述征地补偿款。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2021年1月6日，周某以村委会某村村民小组侵害其集体经济组织成员权益为由向某市某区人民法院起诉，法院判决确认周某未丧失村集体经济组织成员资格，仍系某村集体经济组织成员。某村村民小组应向周某支付土地补偿费80246元。该村村民小组不服，提出上诉、再审申请均未获支持。期间，周某两次请求某镇人民政府、某镇农业服务中心帮助解决确认集体经济组织成员资格问题，镇政府一直未处理，某村村民小组一直未支付土地补偿款。周某向某市某区人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关监督情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，现场释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法审查认为，某区人民法院判决认定事实清楚、适用法律正确；某镇政府应当依法履行对某村委会某村村民小组不予确认周某集体经济成员资格、侵害其合法权益行为的监督管理职责。 2022年8月22日，某区人民检察院向某镇政府发出《检察建议书》，要求及时协调、监督某村委会某村村民小组确认周某的集体经济组织成员资格，并加强对辖区农村集体成员身份确认工作的指导，避免出现类似侵害“外嫁女”合法权益的情形。同时，某区人民检察院组织公开听证，商请某市某区某镇政府代表、村民小组代表出席听证，邀请人大代表、人民监督员、律师担任听证员，摆事实讲道理，促进实质性化解本案争议。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年9月7日，某镇人民政府作出书面回复，已采纳检察建议，协调村小组人员确认周某集体经济组织成员资格，并已将周某录入集体经济组织成员身份系统，向其出具了集体经济组织成员股权证，并按程序分期向周某支付土地补偿款。 2022年11月1日，周某签署了息诉承诺书。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、集体经济组织收益分配、土地征收补偿安置或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。认定“外嫁女”是否具有集体经济组织成员资格，应当结合户籍、土地承包经营权、权利义务关系等综合认定，确保“外嫁女”应当享有的利益不落空。与他村村民结婚，但户口未迁出，在本村承包土地、履行村民义务，且未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款的“外嫁女”，依法具有集体经济组织成员资格，享有相关合法权益。检察机关履行法律监督职责中，对行政机关不依法履职导致“外嫁女”合法权益长期得不到解决的行政检察监督案件，综合运用检察建议、公开听证等方式，解决实质诉求，促进争议化解，有效维护妇女合法权益。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>