<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[大凉山11网红锒铛入狱：虚假助农的流量骗局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fCrq1aEqoZtFKFQvO3eQ2mgPihFz8XyVEf8mlo7M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/fCrq1aEqoZtFKFQvO3eQ2mgPihFz 8XyVEf8mlo7M. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liangshan, Sichuan, Atuleer Village, Zhiermo Township, Zhaojue County, a local Villagers live broadcast on their way down the mountain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time fans learned about the fate of these Daliangshan Internet celebrities who suddenly disappeared was in 2023 At the press conference of Liangshan’s “Series of Internet Celebrities Live Broadcasting Cases” on September 20, 2019, they were no longer able to update their daily life videos as usual. Recently, many Internet celebrities in Liangshan Prefecture, Sichuan Province have been jailed for false advertising and selling fake goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the days after the shock, the aftermath still affected the live broadcast rooms of some Liangshan anchors. People question, who are the locals? What are the local products? Which are the true stories? What is script arrangement? Since the rise of short video platforms, users have curiously turned their perspectives to the countryside and no longer have to imagine life in a different place in their minds. Through the lens of local people, people saw the scenery and culture, and also ate fruits and vegetables sent from the local area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, the relevant departments of Liangshan Prefecture launched a special campaign to &quot;clarify and strictly rectify the &#39;self-media&#39; chaos&quot; and disclosed &quot;miserable auctions&quot;, &quot;false aid to farmers&quot;, &quot;fake charity&quot;, etc. Violations of laws and regulations; 54 suspects were arrested, including 11 Internet celebrity anchors involved, 5 MCN institutions were destroyed, and 14 companies involved were seized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the most attention-grabbing ones are that accounts with more than 2 million followers including &quot;Xiao Yu&quot;, &quot;Zhao Ling&#39;er&quot;, &quot;Liangshan Qubu&quot; and &quot;Liangshan Mengyang&quot; have been permanently suspended. These anchors have The huge fan base once harvested a lot of sympathy, tears and wallets. So far, in the comment areas of related news, some fans still believe that they are innocent.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven departments including the State Cyberspace Administration of China announced in 2021 The &quot;Online Live Marketing Management Measures (Trial)&quot; was promulgated on April 16, and the State Administration for Market Regulation promulgated the &quot;Internet Advertising Management Measures&quot; on February 25, 2023. Lawyer Feng Shengfan explained to Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;This shows that the state Already aware of the chaos in the live streaming industry and the harm it brings, I believe that higher-level laws and related policies will be introduced in the near future. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Liangshan Grand Stage, come if you have talent&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Zhaojue County Public Security Bureau opened a case and found out that in July 2022, Chengdu Xiaoyu Zhang, the person in charge of Zhu Nong Media Co., Ltd. (MCN organization), came to Liangshan and found individual industrial and commercial households Zhao (female, Han nationality, 27 years old), Ari (male, Yi, 23 years old) and other &quot;Internet celebrity seedlings&quot; &quot; and began to incubate carefully. In less than a year, the number of followers of the two accounts &quot;Zhao Ling&#39;er&quot; and &quot;Liangshan Qubu&quot; has exceeded 2 million, and they have brought goods to cash.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of some fans, Qu Bu was deceived. A Sannong video blogger named &quot;Wang Ershuai&quot; who is familiar with these Daliangshan Internet celebrities explained in a live broadcast on the evening of September 22, &quot;I just said that I was bribed with money.&quot; &quot;Everything they did was negotiated.&quot; He gave an example. After selling for 10 million, the company received 3 million, but the boss took away the majority, and Qu Bu got 500,000 to 600,000. Zhao Ling&#39;er was a little higher than Qu Bu. , &quot;You are an amateur. You are nothing. You used to tighten screws in a factory. Will you do anything if I am given such a platform?&quot; You can’t make so much money by tightening screws for a lifetime.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nong Ge, a agriculture video blogger who has been in the industry for many years, told Southern Weekend reporters that some agriculture bloggers around him would hire local actors to perform. This is A semi-public secret in the industry, &quot;It costs a few hundred yuan to hire an actor. Some actors are quite expensive and you can&#39;t even hire them for a few hundred yuan.&quot; (Because) If you call any farmer or ordinary person, it will be obvious in front of the camera. Many people have camera phobia. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nong Ge said that some professional actors cost about one or two thousand yuan to shoot one or two jokes, but there are more “temporary hires”. These jokes are similar: meeting local farmers and having kind conversations, expressing He acted like he was helping others, and paired it with tragic music. &quot;As soon as the music started, everyone thought this anchor was awesome, really good. &quot;Using the same routine, bloggers started to tour the country, going to Hainan Island to sell pineapples, to Fujian to sell grapefruits, etc. Such live broadcast rooms have good data and high sales.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Internet celebrities from Daliang Mountain We were not satisfied with this, and implemented &quot;iterative upgrades&quot; based on the above-mentioned conventional routines.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2022, Zhao Ling&#39;er appeared for the first time as a young man who returned to his hometown to help farmers and start businesses. &quot;Qubu, a simple young man from the Yi ethnic group in Liangshan, began the story of Daliang Mountain. Zhao Ling&#39;er emphasized that he and Qubu met by chance. &quot;There is no team, let alone the capital and packaging of a big company as everyone talks about.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Just three months ago, Xiao Yu, a &quot;philanthropic blogger&quot; who claimed to be shooting in Daliang Mountain, also &quot;stumbled into the depths of lotus flowers&quot; and met the simple and hard-working &quot;Four Girls of Liangshan&quot;. Compare several Internet celebrities There are many similarities in the scenes, filming and scripts. Both are about encountering a single ethnic minority young man by chance, going to a stranger&#39;s house for dinner, killing a chicken to entertain him, taking out the bacon, and talking about the poor family situation during the meal. Established a deep friendship and created a relationship of assistance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, &quot;Little Zhongxing China&quot; also posted a video in October 2022, meeting &quot;Shiyi&quot;, a Yi girl from Daliang Mountain . It is reported that, like Zhao Ling&#39;er and Qu Bu, Eleven also signed a contract with this MCN organization in Chengdu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2022, Xiaoyu published an oral story in the self-media &quot;Interview with Real People&quot; . He claimed to be from Shangqiu, Henan Province. He started engaging in e-commerce in 2018 and earned 1 million yuan in one year. He was initially inspired by the story of the &quot;Cliff Village&quot; in Daliang Mountain. After going there, he found that the rattan ladders had turned into steel bars. Ladder.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in a series of videos he later planned, the local uninhabited production houses and dilapidated buildings in Gumo Village, Tebulo Township, Zhaojue County became theirs. Filming and live broadcast site. Local villager Hai Laihaqu said in an interview, &quot;One day the lights suddenly came on in the old house that no one could live in, and I later found out that they were filming videos and live broadcasts there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;When Xiaoyu was delivering supplies in Daliang Mountain, a local photographer asked to take pictures. &quot;What surprised me was that I only spent seven or eight thousand yuan on the last batch of supplies, but netizens gave rewards or gifts for the total amount About ten to twenty thousand. &quot;Xiaoyu has since tasted the sweetness and plunged into Daliang Mountain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 22, 2022, Chengdu Xiaoyu Zhunong Media Co., Ltd. was established. A month later, Zhao Ling&#39;er&#39;s account released an encounter with Qubu video. Qubu is similar to Ding Zhen, who became popular in 2020. They are both from remote villages, with dark skin, handsome face and innocent smile. He is considered to have the potential of an internet celebrity.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Ershuai remembered that when he first came to Daliang Mountain, Xiao Yu told him that if he wanted to truly understand the people in the mountains, he had to eat and live here. Make friends with them for a little money.&quot; According to media reports, Xiaoyu&#39;s team did not communicate much with local villagers in Daliang Mountain, but when they needed villagers to appear on camera, they would give them some money. They rented several local houses and They grow corn on the land and cook on the mountain.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter asked Wang Ershuai in the live broadcast room how to tell the authenticity of Internet celebrities. Wang Ershuai replied: &quot;You can tell the difference clearly after watching it too much.&quot; Come on... you can analyze it yourself. I can tell you about the things that have been revealed now. I will not talk about the things that have not been revealed. After all, people still rely on this thing to make a living and make money. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QgOxEPgrynEebvrA1wH3Ncg4n5GaWwYF4MRzSaUQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/QgOxEPgrynEebvrA1wH3Ncg4n5GaWwYF4MRzSaUQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;With the support of short video platforms for content that helps farmers, Daliang Mountain has become a traffic hotspot.&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The track selected by traffic&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xiaoyu is not the earliest Daliangshan Internet celebrity. The Liangshan Public Security Bureau discovered that since 2020 , Tang Mou, the head of Chengdu Aowei Culture Media Co., Ltd. (MCN Organization), used scripts, staged shots, etc. to incubate &quot;Liangshan Mengyang&quot; (Axi Moumou, female) with more than three million fans on the short video platform. Yi nationality, 21 years old), and &quot;Liangshan Aze&quot; (A&#39;s certain, male, Yi nationality, 21 years old).&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a previous report by &quot;China News Weekly&quot;, some fans went there out of sympathy in 2019 Jiqu Village, Bier Town, Zhaojue County, where &quot;Liangshan Mengyang&quot; is located, discovered that the place where Mengyang often shoots videos is actually a place where local farmers raise cattle and sheep, and Mengyang&#39;s family background is not bad, and he is considered wealthy in the village . Meng Yang dropped out of school early and worked in Guangdong. Villagers believe that Meng Yang’s fortune is inseparable from “meeting a good boss.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liangshan Prefecture Police stated that the above-mentioned illegal and criminal acts are well-organized and confusing. The case is strong and involves a wide range of areas, forming a gray industrial chain of counterfeiting and selling in recent years, including front-end creation of characters, incubation of Internet celebrities, mid-end script shooting, e-commerce operations, end-end supply of agricultural products, and traffic realization.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Why are these MCN institutions so keen on &quot;mining gold&quot; in Daliang Mountain?&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Huilin, a senior practitioner of agricultural products e-commerce, analyzed that Daliang Mountain is a natural reservoir of products and traffic. First of all, Daliang Mountain&#39;s The products have become popular among Internet celebrities; secondly, the topic of Daliang Mountain caters to traffic, “Daliang Mountain has ethnic minorities, beautiful scenery, and rich cultural heritage. People are rare for these few things, which solves the biggest traffic problem. &quot; Wang Huilin told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The economic development of Daliang Mountain is relatively slower than that of coastal areas, and with the attribute of helping farmers, this matter will develop more logically. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Daliang Mountain, but also Xinjiang and Inner Mongolia, places with “products, scenery, people, and culture” are sought after.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nong Ge believes: &quot;It&#39;s more credible to shoot there. There must be a choice. Why doesn&#39;t anyone choose to go to Zhejiang to help farmers? &quot;According to his many years of experience in carrying goods in the countryside, many short video bloggers like Meng Yang are suspected of exaggerating the misery of the countryside.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A farmer practitioner from a mountainous area in the north told Southern Weekend reporter, people always have a prejudice against mountainous areas. In fact, including the business environment, some local things may be better than those in developed cities, but these have no attention and traffic. &quot;There is no electricity in mountainous areas in xx&quot;, this topic is With traffic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Supporting farmers has become the focus of short video platforms. On September 12, the first &quot;Kuaishou Light Chasing Conference&quot; announced the launch of Kuaishou Village Broadcasting &quot;Stars Project&quot;, which will be launched in the next three years. Invest 10 billion traffic and 50 million cash to cultivate 1 million village broadcasters and 1,000 rural entrepreneurs, and provide talents to 160 key national assistance counties. On September 21, Douyin E-commerce released the &quot;2023 Harvest Festival Douyin E-commerce&quot; &quot;Agricultural Assistance Data Report&quot;, the number of short videos of trailers selling agricultural products on Douyin e-commerce is 21.86 million, and the total time of explaining agricultural products in the live broadcast room is 37.78 million hours. Fujian, Henan, Yunnan, Anhui and Sichuan have become the agricultural products on the platform. Businesses originate from the top five provinces.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liangshan Prefecture Police released the script of the MCN agency’s agriculture and rural areas video, which includes “collecting mountain goods”. For example, Shiyi and her cousin went to local villagers with scales, bags, backpacks, etc. Collect mountain goods at home.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The script of rural areas and farmers caters to the traffic algorithm of short video platforms in disguise. Nie Wenchang, chairman of an e-commerce group in Shandong, established one of the first live broadcast bases in Linyi. He told Southern Weekend reporters Analysis, &quot;The popularity will be high after the script is written. It is done according to some rules of the platform to boost the popularity. &quot; He said that the theme of rural life has broad resonance.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Huilin believes that the reason why these videos are popular is that they trigger the platform&#39;s mechanism, &quot;data feedback, not human feedback.&quot; Data indicators determine this If it is a &quot;good&quot; video, more traffic will be injected. Judging from the logic of the platform, the speed of fans accumulation of Daliangshan Internet celebrities is normal.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Huilin told Southern Weekend reporters that these scripts There is a lack of normal life logic, and the routines are not new, but short videos are often driven by emotions and do not need to think about logic.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the Daliangshan internet celebrity incident, Southern Weekend reporters called several farmers-helping culture The phone calls of media companies may not be connected, or they may remain silent.&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It looks like helping farmers, but it is actually selling goods&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Using false personas to attract people After becoming fans, the above-mentioned companies will open online stores and live broadcast to sell goods. Under the banners of &quot;helping farmers&quot; and &quot;high-quality original ecology&quot;, they purchase honey, walnuts and other agricultural and sideline products at low prices from foreign food companies, and pass them off as &quot;Daliangshan specialty agricultural products&quot; Trademarks were passed off as inferior and fake as genuine and sold across the country. According to the police, the company where &quot;Liangshan Mengyang&quot; works also hired Internet trolls to create the illusion of popular products and orders in the live broadcast room, inducing consumers to buy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Yang once shouted excitedly in the live broadcast room, &quot;You gave me the money for gifts, and you bought walnuts, which is equivalent to supporting many uncles, aunts and ordinary people here, you know? &quot;In fact, only a very small amount of the agricultural products brought by the above-mentioned companies come from the local area, and most of them are purchased from other places at low prices.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nong Ge does not agree with this way of helping farmers. He has been selling it for several years Agricultural products, he has always called himself a &quot;dealer&quot;. &quot;Most people easily believe it when they tell us how pitiful we are in front of the camera and use other people&#39;s kindness to make money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Shengfan&#39;s analysis, false personas, fictitious origins, etc. The situation has constituted the category of false advertising, and once false advertising is involved, the anchor and the MCN organization where he works may be required to bear three different legal liabilities: criminal, civil, and administrative if there is any conscious intention.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Even if the products are indeed from the place of origin, selling them by fabricating stories and creating personas may be illegal. Feng Shengfan told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Although the origin of the products is real, consumers are based on the stories and characters made up by the anchors. Assuming that only those who are willing to place an order have sympathy for helping farmers. Therefore, the anchor’s fabrication of stories and creation of characters also constitutes a misleading way of fabricating, fabricating, and distorting facts in false propaganda. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Odikebu, the village secretary of Gumo Village, said, “Our Gumo Village is such a small place and we don’t get so much honey. He is a liar and has not helped. Don&#39;t recognize him! ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant people from Xinxuan Group, a live broadcast e-commerce company, told Southern Weekend reporters that some places have problems with unsalable agricultural products and have fewer distribution channels. The public welfare agricultural assistance project aims to help local areas open up sales and drive employment, Help revitalize. Compared with other categories, agricultural products are more prone to problems, have low profit margins, and require a large investment of manpower and resources.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared with leading companies, the quality of local supply chains is uneven. Wang Huilin introduced that a common model in the industry is that the Internet celebrity company finds a suitable local supply chain, negotiates cooperation, and establishes links through short video platforms.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, Internet celebrities live broadcast to draw goods The commission for agricultural products is generally about 20%, and the commission for higher products can be as high as 30%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the products carried by Daliangshan Internet celebrities come from the supply chain of Pujiang County, Chengdu. Wang Huilin reminded that this It does not mean that the goods of these supply chain companies do not come from Daliang Mountain. Perhaps to save logistics costs, &quot;Hami melons in Xinjiang may be shipped from Xi&#39;an.&quot; According to Liangshan Prefecture Police, the Liangshan Internet celebrity who was imprisoned chose The supply chain does not actually get goods from Daliangshan.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another common model is for supply chain companies to cultivate and discover Internet celebrities. &quot;China News Weekly&quot; revealed that many Liangshan Internet celebrities He once cooperated with supply chain supplier Ren Yanbing to sell his products. Southern Weekend reporters contacted Ren Yanbing as a collaborator. He said, &quot;This business is not easy to do, and I am ready to change my career.&quot; This supplier was not affected by the Liangshan Internet celebrity. The impact of the incident.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nie Wenchang said that compared with other categories, agricultural products are special. The quality of agricultural products in the hands of farmers varies, and even if consumers get agricultural products from other places, it is difficult to distinguish the authenticity from the fake.&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the illegal behavior of some Internet celebrities has had a negative impact on Daliangshan specialties. Faced with doubts, some sellers have to make special explanations. A store that specializes in selling pure oatmeal flour from Daliangshan farmers has its business qualifications But it was shown in Panlong District, Kunming City, Yunnan Province. The anchor explained that the store was opened by fans, but the shipping address was his home. Another store claiming to sell ugly apples from Daliang Mountain in Sichuan has its business address in Haikou City, Hainan Province. The merchant explained in the live broadcast room that this was the address registered when selling pineapples in Hainan. He took out his mobile phone and asked &quot;Hi, Siri, what is the current altitude?&quot; Siri gave an answer of 2515 meters.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Nong Ge remains anonymous)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家医保局：半年追回“救命钱”63.4亿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/oJQaF1ux6W8TBXvy8GF7pGHv9ricnuyACau5xl3g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/oJQaF1ux6W8TBXvy8GF7pGHv9ricnuyACau5xl3 g. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252110&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 2023 National Medical Insurance Fund unannounced inspection has officially started in late August, focusing on medical imaging Examination, clinical examination, and rehabilitation are three areas where problems reported by the public are relatively concentrated. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Medical insurance funds are the &quot;life-saving money&quot; for citizens to seek medical treatment. How to regulate them has attracted much attention from all walks of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the first half of 2023, the national medical insurance department inspected a total of 390,000 designated medical institutions, dealt with 160,000 illegal institutions, and recovered 6.34 billion yuan in medical insurance-related funds. Since 2018, a total of 83.5 billion has been recovered Yuan.&quot; On September 22, 2023, Gu Rong, deputy director of the Fund Supervision Department of the National Medical Insurance Administration, said at a regular press conference in the second half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the 2023 National Medical Insurance Fund unannounced inspection has officially started in late August. In 2023, the national unannounced inspections will cover 31 provinces across the country and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, focusing on medical imaging examinations, clinical examinations, and rehabilitation, three areas where problems reported by the public are concentrated. At the same time, designated retail pharmacies were included in the inspection targets for the first time. So far, it has carried out unannounced inspections in 15 provinces including Guizhou, Shaanxi, Sichuan, Xinjiang, and Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Rong revealed that many provinces have also carried out provincial unannounced inspections based on the national model. In the first half of this year, provincial unannounced inspections have covered 488 designated medical institutions and 30 medical insurance agencies in 84 prefectures and cities. Institutions, 298 illegal institutions were dealt with, and 210 million yuan in medical insurance-related funds were recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Monitoring&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Using&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Big Data and Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The National Medical Insurance Administration has been used for 5 consecutive years Cooperate with the public security and health departments to carry out special rectification to crack down on fraud and insurance fraud. In 2023, the procuratorial organs and financial departments will also join in, making the advantages of joint punishment more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Rong introduced that the special rectification in 2023 will focus on key areas such as &quot;orthopedics, hemodialysis, intracardiac, examination, testing, rehabilitation and physical therapy&quot;, focusing on key pharmaceutical consumables that rank high in medical insurance settlement costs, focusing on Regarding key behaviors such as false medical treatment and reselling of medical insurance drugs, we strive to investigate and deal with a number of key cases, crack down on a number of illegal activities, and standardize a number of special areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Medical insurance data is huge and complex, and the role of big data and social supervision cannot be ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the National Medical Insurance Administration will select 11 provinces and 53 coordinating districts across the country to carry out pilot projects for the application and supervision of big data in anti-fraud in medical insurance, and encourage medical insurance departments at all levels to use new technologies such as big data and artificial intelligence. Strive to achieve full coverage of the intelligent supervision subsystem in all coordinated areas as soon as possible to form a national intelligent monitoring &quot;one network&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the country intelligently reviewed and monitored non-payments and recovered 980 million yuan of medical insurance funds. Through handling mass reports, 42.33 million yuan of medical insurance funds were recovered and administrative penalties of 7.65 million yuan were imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/F36lzS8lXFKnQqOk4HvBKv1gN3lkCinLbyl5yVQf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/F36lzS8lXFKnQqOk4HvBKv1gN3lkCinLbyl5yVQf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252109&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the morning of September 22, 2023, the National Medical Insurance Administration held a regular press conference for the second half of 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(National Medical Insurance Bureau official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;March to August&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Negotiated drugs have reduced the burden on patients by 109.7 billion yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the same time, every adjustment to the national medical insurance catalog also affects the minds of thousands of families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2022 version of the National Medical Insurance Directory was officially implemented on March 1, 2023, and has been in operation for nearly seven months. This version of the catalog adds 111 new drugs, covering multiple treatment fields such as oncology, immunity, rare diseases, and anti-infections. Among them, 91 drugs such as orebatinib, sarvotinib, and rispalan have been admitted through negotiation. By adding new drugs to the catalog, the total number of drugs negotiated for medical insurance during the agreement period reached 346. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;From March to August 2023, a total of 123 million people were reimbursed for negotiated drugs during 346 agreement periods, with medical insurance fund expenditures of 49.17 billion yuan, and the average actual reimbursement ratio was 69.7%. The dual factors of superimposed price reduction and medical insurance reimbursement , in the six months from March to August, 346 types of negotiated drugs have reduced the burden on patients by 109.7 billion yuan.&quot; Huang Xinyu, director of the Pharmaceutical Management Department of the National Medical Insurance Administration, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of the end of August 2023, 234,000 designated medical institutions across the country have been equipped with negotiated drugs during the agreement period, including 65,000 designated medical institutions, 169,000 designated retail pharmacies, and 91 in 2022. The newly added negotiated drugs have been deployed in 55,000 designated pharmaceutical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The adjustment of the 2023 version of the National Medical Insurance Catalog is also in progress. The application was launched on July 1, and the list of applied drugs that passed the formal review was announced in early September. Including 224 drugs outside the catalog and 164 drugs in the catalog, a total of 388 drugs passed the formal review. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We will carry out review, calculation and negotiation work as planned, and expect to announce the results of this year’s catalog adjustment in early December, and implement the new version of the catalog from January 1 next year.” Huang Xinyu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《关于依法惩治网络暴力违法犯罪的指导意见》出台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Although the Internet is a virtual space, it is by no means an illegal place. Those who wantonly publish abuses and insults against individuals on the Internet Cyber ​​violence that spreads rumors, defamation, invades privacy and other information must be subject to due legal sanctions. On September 25, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, and the Ministry of Public Security jointly held a press conference to officially release the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Internet Violence and Crime According to the Law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions&quot; have a total of 20 articles, mainly covering ten aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, clarify the applicable rules for the crime of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; provide guidance on the nature of online violence in accordance with the criminal law and relevant judicial interpretations. Specifically, those who openly insult others or fabricate facts to slander others on the information network, if the circumstances are serious, will be convicted and punished for the crimes of insult and slander; organize &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and the circumstances are In serious cases, they will be convicted and punished for the crime of infringing on citizens&#39; personal information. In addition, the crime of illegal use of information network can be applied to malicious marketing and hype behaviors carried out through cyber violence incidents; the crime of refusing to perform information network security management obligations can be applied to the behavior of failing to perform information network security management obligations in accordance with the law for discovered cyber violence information . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to clarify the rules for handling illegal online violence. For online violence, we should adhere to multi-dimensional and joint governance and improve the connection mechanism between administrative law enforcement and criminal justice. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that the implementation of online insults, slander and other online violence does not constitute a crime. If it complies with the provisions of the Public Security Management Punishment Law and other provisions, administrative penalties will be imposed in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to clarify the policy principles for punishing cyber violence crimes. The &quot;Opinions&quot; require that the spirit of severe punishment for cyber violence crimes should be reflected so that the people can fully feel fairness and justice. Adhere to strict law enforcement and justice, strictly investigate cyber violence crimes in accordance with the law, and effectively correct the erroneous tendency of &quot;the law does not punish the public&quot;. We must focus on cracking down on malicious initiators, organizers, malicious promoters, and those who persist in reforming despite repeated abuses. The &quot;Opinions&quot; also stipulate that there are those who commit cyber violence against minors and disabled people, organize &quot;trolls&quot; and &quot;thugs&quot; to commit cyber violence, fabricate &quot;sexually related&quot; topics to infringe on the human dignity of others, and use &quot;deep synthesis&quot; and other generative methods If artificial intelligence technology releases illegal information, or if network service providers initiate or organize cyber violence, they will be severely punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to clarify the boundaries between illegal crimes and legal behaviors of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that reporting or exposing other people&#39;s crimes or violations of laws and disciplines through information networks should not be considered a defamation crime as long as they do not intentionally fabricate facts or knowingly spread the facts to be fabricated. Commenting and criticizing other people&#39;s words and deeds, even if the views are biased or the speech is extreme, as long as it is not wanton abuse or malicious slander, it should not be considered an insult or crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth is to clarify the work requirements for public security organs to assist in evidence collection. According to the provisions of the Criminal Law, in cases where the victim files a private prosecution for online insult or defamation, if the people&#39;s court determines after review that it is indeed difficult for the victim to provide evidence, it may request the public security organs to provide assistance. The &quot;Opinions&quot; reiterate the provisions of the Criminal Law, and also clarify that the public security organs should promptly identify the perpetrators of online insults and slander according to the requirements of the People&#39;s Court and the specific circumstances of the case, and collect evidence and materials such as the spread and spread of relevant information and the impact caused. Network service providers shall provide necessary technical support and assistance for public security organs to obtain evidence in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth is to clarify the public prosecution standards for criminal cases of online insult and defamation. According to the provisions of the Criminal Law, those who commit crimes of insult or slander and seriously endanger social order and national interests shall be prosecuted in accordance with the law. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that in cases of online insult and defamation, public prosecution procedures will apply if one of the following circumstances occurs: (1) causing serious consequences such as mental disorder or suicide of the victim or his close relatives, and causing a bad impact on society; (2) arbitrarily using The general public is the target of infringement, and relevant information is widely disseminated on the Internet, triggering a large number of vulgar and malicious comments, seriously disrupting the order of the Internet, and having a bad impact on society; (3) Insulting and slandering multiple people or spreading insulting and slanderous information multiple times, causing social harm Those with a bad impact; (4) Organizing and instigating people to spread a large amount of insulting and slanderous information on multiple online platforms, with a bad impact on society; (5) Other situations that seriously endanger social order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seventh is to clarify the transition process from private prosecution to public prosecution in criminal cases of online insult and defamation. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that for online insults and slander that seriously endanger social order, the public security organs have filed a case as a public prosecution case, and the victim simultaneously files a private prosecution in the People&#39;s Court, the People&#39;s Court may request the private prosecutor to withdraw the private prosecution or rule not to accept it; it has been accepted If the case is found, a ruling should be made to terminate the trial and the relevant materials should be transferred to the public security organs. The original private prosecutor can participate in the lawsuit as a victim. The victim files a private prosecution before the public security organ files a case. If, upon review, the people&#39;s court determines that the relevant online insults and defamation seriously endanger social order, the case shall be transferred to the public security organ. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eighth, support civil rights protection against online violence in accordance with the law. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that if cyber violence is committed against others and infringes on others&#39; reputation rights, privacy rights and other personality rights, and the victim requests the perpetrator to bear civil liability, the people&#39;s court will support it in accordance with the law. If the right holder has evidence to prove that the perpetrator is committing or is about to commit an illegal act that infringes upon his or her personality rights, and failure to stop it in time will cause irreparable damage to his or her legitimate rights and interests, the People&#39;s Court may, upon the right holder&#39;s application, issue an injunction against infringement of personality rights in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ninth is to clarify the rules for public interest litigation in cases of online violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; stipulate that if online violence harms public interests, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may file a public interest litigation with the People&#39;s Court in accordance with the law. If a network service provider fails to perform its information network security management obligations in accordance with the law for discovered cyber violence information, resulting in the large-scale dissemination of illegal information or other serious circumstances that harm the public interest, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may file a public interest litigation with the People&#39;s Court in accordance with the law. When handling public interest litigation cases in the field of cyber violence control, the People&#39;s Procuratorate may require network service providers to provide necessary technical support and assistance in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tenth is to proactively perform duties and promote comprehensive management of cyber violence. The &quot;Opinions&quot; require that when handling cases of cyber violence, information on the progress of the case should be released to the public in a timely manner in accordance with the law, clarify the truth, and eliminate the adverse effects of cyber violence, so as to reduce the harm to the victims and help the victims get out of their predicaments; carry out legal publicity and give full play to law enforcement The role of rule guidance, value orientation and behavioral norms in handling cases is to educate and guide netizens to consciously abide by the law and lead social civilization; to conduct in-depth analysis of the root causes that promote the occurrence of online violence, promote multi-dimensional co-governance of online violence, and fundamentally reduce online violence occurrence, creating a clear cyberspace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙一文止步八强，新旧交替的女子重剑队亟待历练]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257567]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEzLcs4MrEYLK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/qLY0NaAvQ3TEA5d5kye3jm2Vd1xtEz Lcs4MrEYLK. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, women&#39;s individual epee four in the fencing event of the Hangzhou Asian Games In the quarter-finals, Chinese player Sun Yiwen (right) lost to South Korean player Song Shiluo 12-14 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;12 to 14, on September 24, the first official competition day of the Hangzhou Asian Games, in the quarter-finals of the women’s individual epee fencing event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Sun Yiwen lost to South Korean player Song Se-ra and stopped in the quarterfinals. So far, all Chinese players in this project have been eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Sun Yiwen’s third Asian Games trip. She and her teammates won the women&#39;s epee team championship twice before. At the last Asian Games in Jakarta, Sun Yiwen also reached the finals of individual events, but ultimately lost to South Korean star Kang Young-mi and won a silver medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This sport pays great attention to variety, balance, game and precision.” A game lasts up to 9 minutes. If you hit at the same time, you must be 1/25 second earlier than the opponent to score. A blink of an eye is 0.75 seconds, which is enough to turn the tide or give up victory. To do this, fencers need to &quot;count one step at a time.&quot; Excellent fencers are often in a state of &quot;integration of man and sword&quot;, that is, under various circumstances, they can hit the opponent&#39;s exposed effective parts (including the torso, legs, feet, hands, arms, and helmets) at the fastest speed and the shortest route. . Behind the &quot;subconscious&quot; sword thrusts again and again is the muscle memory cultivated over many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tokyo Olympic champion Sun Yiwen is the number one Chinese women&#39;s epee player. He has always been good at &quot;stopping with stillness and attacking later.&quot; &quot;Determined, calm, and explosive&quot; is how she sums up her playing style. However, after winning the Tokyo Olympics and Xi&#39;an Olympics, Sun Yiwen has been trapped by injuries and will not resume training until October 2022 and systematically participate in events. To &quot;find the feeling of starting over&quot;, the road is rough. Sun Yiwen once lamented that he &quot;can&#39;t even play games anymore&quot; and was &quot;very unfamiliar.&quot; It was not until the International Fencing Federation World Cup Barcelona in February 2023 that he gradually regained his form and won two bronze medals in a row, both individual and team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/Y1LICojmKJNk0KhWE9ZrblJq0W0assdjikvr0Ab1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 24, 2021, Sun Yiwen (right) celebrated with his coach after winning the women&#39;s individual epee final in fencing at the Tokyo Olympics&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous interviews with the media, Sun Yiwen once said that winning a gold medal is not necessary for this comeback. After reviewing the schedule performance of the last Olympic Games, she and the coaching staff found that although they won the gold medal, many problems and deficiencies were still exposed in the process. If they can be improved, the state will be better than before. &quot;A new coach has joined the team and taught me many new ideas and moves. Now I dare to try new moves in the game and explore new areas. This is what makes me most interesting and what makes me happy.&quot;我决定再坚持一个奥运周期的原因，我还在一直学习。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东京奥运会后，中国击剑队正面临队员新老交替、教练团队调整的过渡期。本次参加亚运会的选手当中，有四分之三都未曾在东京奥运会出战，杭州亚运会被视作这支年轻的队伍备战巴黎奥运会的一次重要的练兵机会。按照比赛计划，杭州亚运会击剑比赛将在9月24日至29日进行，共产生12枚金牌。 9月27日，孙一文还将率领年轻的队友在女子重剑团体赛上继续向奖牌发起冲击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如杭州亚运会中国体育代表团秘书长、国家体育总局竞技体育司司长张新所称，杭州亚运会是巴黎奥运会前的“中考”。不足一年后，32岁的孙一文将在巴黎迎来自己的第三次奥运之旅，而在此之前，她和年轻的中国击剑队还需刺破重重阻碍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/zSTuMc9YvjlkUYhKNhKW9jT7caOSYptFWqNxmbnw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月20日，在江苏无锡举行的2023年亚洲击剑锦标赛女子重剑团体赛季军争夺赛中，中国队战胜日本队，夺得铜牌。中国队选手唐君瑶（左一）、林声（左二）、朱明叶（左三）与孙一文在赛后合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“决一剑”背后&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;孙一文从不认为自己属于“天赋型选手”。她将自己在职业生涯中的收获归功于认真和倔强。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1992年，孙一文出生在山东烟台栖霞市王格庄村。年幼时，她体质很差，每逢冬日便会感冒缠身。孙一文的父亲孙洪明是当地村医，在父亲的督促和陪伴下，她从小就养成了跑步锻炼的习惯。长期的坚持收效颇丰。小学时，孙一文已经成了学校的体育尖子生。 11岁那年，孙一文被栖霞市体育竞技学校选中，主攻中长跑。两年后，她已经长到1米66，立定跳远的最好成绩超过两米五。因为个子高、臂展长、瞬间爆发力强，又是左撇子，她被时任烟台市击剑队总教练许昭伟相中，正式踏上击剑的道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;击剑是一项对能力要求非常综合的项目，“力量、速度、爆发力、耐力、协调、柔韧，还有思维”，一个都不能少。最初的训练是艰苦而枯燥的。晨训始于凌晨5点半，基础的步伐和移动，一练就是几个小时。为了培养耐力短板，小队员们还需要接受额外的跑步训练。周一到周五，早晚各跑3000米，周末还会进行6公里越野赛。若规定时间内完不成，就要加罚，用时越多，罚得越多。白天高强度的训练结束后，晚上还要学习文化课。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一周过后，孙一文就想放弃。为了宽慰和鼓励女儿，孙洪明特地从老家赶到烟台，陪了女儿两天。度过了最初的适应期，身体素质过硬、善于思考的孙一文开始逐渐崭露头角。 “每练习一个动作，做不到时，我会仔细去复盘和思考为什么。每赢一次比赛或输一次比赛，我也会去深挖底层逻辑。”2010年山东省运动会上，18岁的孙一文代表烟台击剑队和队友一同收获了8枚金牌。赛后，她成功入选省击剑队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可日子并未就此平顺。很长一段时间，因为在省队没有编制，孙一文需要自行支付外出比赛的费用。有时候一场比赛就要花掉父亲小半年的工资。当时，家中还有弟弟在读书，孙洪明夫妇在老家的生活十分拮据。由于技战术突破面临瓶颈，孙一文曾两度被省队退了回来。忧心于练习击剑无法出头，孙一文一度跟父亲提出要放弃击剑，外出打工，尽快补贴家用。父亲深知女儿的心思。和小时候一样，孙洪明一方面在心理上疏解，一方面积极和教练沟通，最终大家都没有放弃。幸运的是，在教练的建议下，孙一文开始尝试将枪柄剑改为直柄剑，此后她的苦练终于守得云开。一时间，在省内已经没有女队员能与之匹敌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，孙一文入选国家击剑队。同年，21岁的她完成了个人国际赛事首秀，收获了女子重剑世界杯大奖赛团体冠军。两年后，她在意大利击剑世界杯上斩获首个个人冠军。不过，真正让孙一文走上职业巅峰的还是2021年的东京奥运会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年的里约奥运会，作为“黑马”的孙一文就曾获得女子重剑个人铜牌、团体银牌。但随着里约奥运会落幕，国家女子击剑队也发生了天翻地覆的变化。彼时，对孙一文在思想和技术上影响颇深的“伯乐”勒瓦瓦瑟主教练离任，许安琪和孙玉洁等主力队员退役。新团队领军的担子一下子落到了孙一文身上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/O0mKyXd6lHmdwegDkVKOPAasw1yJDwy0BEGRnrOb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;孙一文&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，孙一文习惯于“二次意图”的打法，即先用假动作迷惑对手，再出其不意地进攻。然而，继任的主教练雨歌·欧伯利擅长直接进攻的战术，这恰恰是孙一文的短板。在长达一年左右的磨合期，孙一文的赛事成绩一直平平。她觉得自己仿佛回到了15岁刚刚进入击剑队的状态，一切都要从零开始，“当时的思路和思绪是完全混乱的，就像一团打结的麻绳。”经历过太多坎坷的孙一文只能默默鼓励自己，“这种状态一定是暂时的，人生总会有低潮，就要看你怎么跨过它。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幸运的是，由于东京奥运会推迟了一年举办，孙一文及时地在奥运会积分赛期间调整回了状态。通过融会两套技术思路的长处，她形成了新的作战风格。 2021年的夏天，她在东京奥运会女子重剑个人决赛上“一剑光寒定九州”，击败了当时世界排名第一的罗马尼亚选手波佩斯库，绝杀夺金。唯一遗憾的是，在随后的团体赛上，孙一文受伤被换下，中国女子重剑队最终止步团体四强。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东京奥运会结束后，孙一文因伤病接连缺席了2022年的数次大型赛事。在2022年初接受媒体采访时，她这样描述自己的伤病，“我现在是左腿后交叉韧带撕裂和积水、膝盖囊肿、半月板磨损，右腿后群到膝盖有一条很长的拉伤。平时哪怕简单动几下，或者天气不好的时候，我的膝盖还是会一直疼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和许多其他的运动项目不同，很少有人能在击剑领域保持绝对统治力。最近一年，由于腰骶始终压迫着腿部神经，孙一文一直处于带病参赛的状态，她一直在摸索着如何在技术和心理上与伤病共处。在7月举行的米兰世界击剑锦标赛中，孙一文夺得了女子重剑个人赛铜牌，这是她首次摘得世锦赛个人项目奖牌。在接受赛后采访时，孙一文表示，这枚铜牌对她而言是一剂“强心剂”，让她明白自己在有伤病的状态下“也是可以的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我对输赢无所谓，但我有一个劲儿，别人能做到的事情，我觉得我也可以。伤病、困难和问题摆在面前，我从不会逃避，也不会畏惧，我一定去解决它。越往上走的时候，遇到的问题就会越多。”在孙一文看来，18年击剑生涯教给她最重要的一课就是“不服软，不服输”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：《博客天下》《GQ报道》、潮新闻、大众网烟台频道、福布斯中国、《精彩OK》《齐鲁晚报》、中国新闻网、《北京日报》、上观新闻等。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从北京、广州到杭州：33年3届亚运会见证中国经济社会发展与国民精神进化丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月23日，第19届亚运会在杭州开幕。点火仪式上，一个巨大的“数字人”从场外飞奔而至，与现场的真人一同点亮主火炬，让这场充满科技感的开幕式达到了高潮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅仅是数字人点火，这场开幕式，可以说是迄今为止科技感最强的一场运动会开幕式。空中悬垂下来一张总长185米、高20米的“网幕”，地上一块6000平方米的地屏，让杭州奥体中心体育场“大莲花”成为一个巨大的立体显示屏幕。另有裸眼3D、AR等数字技术的加持，数字烟花灿烂夺目，开幕演出虚拟与实景融合，未来感十足。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是中国三十多年来第三次举办亚运会。而这三次亚运会的举办，也正体现了中国经济社会与国民精神心态的发展历程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1990年，第11届亚运会在北京举行。这是中国第一次承办大型国际综合性体育赛事，那时也正是中国改革开放初期。 1983年中国提出承办亚运会的申请，希望展现对外开放的形象。经济上，当时中国的发展刚刚起步，到亚运会举办的1990年，全国GDP总量只有1.89万亿元人民币，不到3609亿美元，人均GDP在全球排名更在130位之外，在亚洲也并不靠前。当时，甚至连筹办亚运会也缺少资金，不得不面向全国开展了募捐活动，全国数千万人参与，共捐款2.7亿元，超过北京亚运会全部投入的十分之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国第二次举办亚运会是2010年的广州亚运会。 20年间，尤其是新世纪初加入WTO、融入全球市场让中国成为世界工厂，经济获得了突飞猛进的发展。尽管2008年受到金融危机一定影响，但中国经济迅速恢复了发展速度。 2010年，中国GDP总量超过40万亿元人民币，折合美元超过6万亿，首次超过日本，跃居亚洲第一，世界第二。这次亚运会的举办地选在广州。广州是千年商都、改革开放的前沿，珠三角也是中国外向型经济最活跃的地区，是中国最重要的制造业与外贸基地之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而这次杭州亚运会，距离广州亚运会又过去了十多年。这十多年间，中国经济又增长了近2倍。更重要的是，中国经济的科技含量也得到了很大的提升，尤其是在数字经济领域引领全球。而杭州正是中国电商巨头阿里巴巴大本营所在地。杭州亚运开幕式上那些华丽的数字人、数字烟花，正是中国高端数字技术的集中展现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，这三次亚运会引起的关注度也有所不同，相信稍年长的朋友会更有体会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京亚运会从申办成功到筹备和成功举办，都引起了举国空前的关注。记得当时电视机在中国还没有普及，尤其是在农村，黑白电视机也不多见，彩电更稀罕，有些村只有村委会有一台彩电供村民们观看。农民白天要忙农活，没时间看亚运直播，到了晚上，村委会的彩电前就挤满了看比赛的农民。当然，更多的比赛消息，是从第二天早上村里大喇叭的广播里听到的，每一次有中国队获胜的消息，都会引起一阵狂欢。长城图案组成的会徽、吉祥物熊猫盼盼、宣传曲《亚洲雄风》都成为一代人的记忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州亚运会的开幕式匠心独运，非常出彩，“白云之帆”，显示出开放、开拓的宏大气象，不过，论关注度恐怕比不了北京亚运会那种全民参与的炽热状态。我2010年10月份从北京来到广州工作，正是广州亚运会举办前夕。就在前两年，中国刚刚举办了2008年奥运会。全球参与的顶级赛事都举办过了，国人的心理阈值自然上升了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而现在，移动网络已经成为传播的主渠道。每个人的手机上都装着各式各样的短视频、新闻App，就连支付宝这样的支付工具上也有亚运视频报道，随时随地都可以接收到亚运会的信息。在这样便捷的传播环境下，亚运会数字火炬传递活动得到了1亿多人的参与。不过随着生活方式的不断进化，我们也再没法见到全民端坐电视机前的那种状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚运会关注度的变化，也是中国经济社会与国民心态精神发展的必然结果。北京亚运时，中国经济仍然比较落后，亚运会是一次凝聚国人力量、展现民族自豪感的机会，官方媒体的大力宣传，让北京亚运人人皆知。而到广州亚运和这次的杭州亚运，随着中国经济水平的提高，在中国举办的世界级体育赛事已经多得数不过来。普通人也有更多渠道接触更多的信息，他们的注意力被分散了，当然，这也是好事，那些爱好体育的人，会初心不改地关注亚运会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十年三届亚运会，正是中国发展与国民精神进化的见证。在这个意义上，亚运会开幕式科技含量上升，关注度不比当年，恰是丰富多彩和发展进步的体现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“常·识”背后的南方报业融合转型密码]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，南方报业传媒集团党委书记、社长黄常开撰写的专著《常·识——南方报业媒体融合漫论》一书由南方日报出版社正式出版。这是作者继《传播力——南方报业媒体融合实践》之后，深入总结南方报业融合转型实践和经验、深刻阐释对省级党报集团融合转型规律性认识和感悟的又一部专业力作。书名虽曰“常·识”，但紧密结合南方报业近年来成功探索符合中央精神、行业趋势又具有南方特色的融合发展之路的非常历程，展现的是南方报人对媒体融合转型的深刻认识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/5b8d0c05c65e1a924c997e724b8104c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/5b8d0c05c65e1a924c997e724b8104c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252058&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;《常·识——南方报业媒体融合漫论》书影。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;从八组辩证关系看融合转型&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;没有传播力就没有一切&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;移动互联网时代，如何推进媒体融合发展，是时代之问，也是当代媒体人&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;的必答之题。媒体融合是一项系统工程，涉及理念、内容、形式、方法、手段的&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;创新，涉及资源整合、流程优化、平台再造等诸多任务，涉及技术、经营、管理等方方面面难题。从何处破题、如何破题，如何抓好“牵一发动全身”的重点改革，创新举措实现“一子落满盘活”的牵引效果，如何摆正各个方面、不同环节的复杂关系？对此，仅从《常·识》一书的内容结构上，就可以找到部分答案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从内容结构上看，全书共分为八个主题，即“旧业与新业”“饭碗与舞台”“事业与人才”“主业与产业”“内容与技术”“除弊与革新”“管理与建设”“大生态与小生态”。进一步，八个主题实际上阐释的就是破解媒体融合需要准确把握的八组重大辩证关系。例如，“旧业与新业”，关注的就是辩证看待传统媒体与新兴媒体关系，以及在融合转型迭代过程中，如何实现优势互补、此长彼长、此优彼优。“饭碗与舞台”，关注的就是面对传统媒体日渐式微的不可逆转趋势，如何通过做大做强自控可控传播平台，端好安身立命的饭碗、打造干事创业的舞台。以此类推，“事业与人才”关切的是融合转型的人才队伍建设；“主业与产业”探讨的是如何实现采编与经营的良性互促；“内容与技术”关注的是筑牢融合转型的技术底盘；“除弊与革新”指向的是融合转型的体制机制变革；“管理与建设”聚焦的是守好意识形态主阵地，如何既要管住又要管得出新出彩；“大生态与小生态”，展现的是对南方报业这样拥有多个子媒、多端口、多阵地的省级党报集团来说，如何构建错位发展、协同融洽的全媒体传播体系，放大融合发展的传播力和影响力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3bc02f7af596f0fabf0199532b415f1d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;530&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/3bc02f7af596f0fabf0199532b415f1d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;南方报业体制机制创新举措。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;详读《常·识》不难看出，八组辩证关系不是“凭空之论”，而是源于南方报业成功的融合转型实践，是融合转型“南方打法”的深刻总结。近年来，南方报业以提升现代传播力为首要任务，深入实施“三个一体化”和“四化”战略战术（详见《传播力——南方报业媒体融合实践》一书），构建起覆盖用户超4.57亿的报刊网端微屏全媒体传播体系，旗下南方日报、南方杂志、南方网、南方农村报、南方周末、南方都市报、南方+客户端等7家媒体机构全部跻身“亿元媒体”俱乐部，南方+、GDToday 新闻网（客户端）、南周App、南都App、N视频、粤学习等自主可控、传播力强的新型传播平台发展势头良好，南方+以超1.7亿下载量和日活超600万的出色表现，牢牢占据广东省委省政府第一权威移动发布平台地位，位列全国省级党报自有客户端传播力第一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的融合转型不俗表现，正是源于对书中所探讨的八组辩证关系的正确把握。作者所谓“漫论”，绝非泛泛而论，关注的恰恰是媒体融合转型的一系列重点难题、重要主题、重大课题。作者对八组辩证关系的深入阐释，是对有效破解媒体融合转型那些“既要、又要”两难问题的回答，从中亦可窥见南方报业融合转型的成功密码。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;从“常·识”感受规律性认识：&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;转型不是转行&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作者在自序中称，“书名曰《常·识》，既有平常观点之意，也是正常见识之谓”。综观全书对“没有传播力就没有一切”“南方+要出什么圈”“名记要成为怎样的人”“我们要做什么样的产业” “让管住管好从&#39;两难&#39;变成&#39;两全&#39;”等一系列行业关切话题的深入论述，可谓“金句频出”，给人留下了深刻印象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常识不同寻常。一直以来，面对互联网新媒体持续猛烈的冲击，媒体转型向何处去，是&lt;span>;最突出&lt;/span>;的难题。实践证明，对这个问题能否正确作答，往往决定了一个媒体的路径选择和前途未来。对此，作者明确指出“转型不是转行”，强调“作为主流媒体，不管报刊、广电还是网站、客户端，我们都要扪心自问：我们到底是做什么的”“南方报业要清楚自己的定位，不管怎么转、怎么融，媒体属性的基石地位不容动摇”。在行业激烈变革的当下，坚守“乱云飞渡仍从容”的战略定力，虽是常识，却仍需要不同寻常的“人间清醒”。类似还有书中的“轻忽媒体业务无异于舍本逐末”“自主可控不等于从零开始”，等等，看似并不深奥玄妙的道理，却往往需要人们在融合转型的现实中作出清醒正确的抉择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1ddee1f0902287b520469a2b18222ed6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1ddee1f0902287b520469a2b18222ed6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;南方报业营业结构四年变化（2019—2022）。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常识也是共识。正如作者所言，《常·识》“呈现的绝不是我一个人的实践思考，而是集体智慧的结晶”，既源自南方报业融合转型实践，也凝练了南方报业全体员工的共识。透过书中的论述不难看出，诸如“将内容生产传播作为安身立命之本”“建设新型主流媒体要抱持&#39;长期主义&#39;”“南方报业最珍贵的资产有两项：第一项是人才，第二项是传播力”“名记不是评出来的，是打出来的”“只有&#39;下沉&#39;才能基业长青”，不仅仅是南方报业融合转型坚持的重要理念原则，也早已融入集团发展的日常，成为南方报业上下践行的共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常识更是规律性认识。书中很多“金句”，既是洞见，也体现着对媒体融合发展规律的深刻认识。比如，谈到转型的实质，指出“转型，就是媒体从&#39;纸&#39;的形态转成&#39;网&#39;的形态；融合，就是新旧两种媒体形态的融合共生”；谈到主业和产业的关系，指出“通过做强主业，让传播力、影响力产生溢出效益，从而搞好主业经营，撬动产业、带来多元收入”；谈到技术与内容的关系，指出“内容传播到哪里，技术支撑就跟到哪里”……类似这样的论述，无疑对整个业界都有极强的启发意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;媒体融合发展是一篇大文章。今年是习近平总书记作出“加快传统媒体和新兴媒体融合发展”重要指示10&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;周年。在这样一个重要的时间节点，《常·识》的出版，无疑为我们总结整个行业的媒体融合转型实践，加快推进媒体融合向纵深发展提供了可供研究的生动样本和借鉴参考。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1f89d7f6202dd2ba9ff83a96f15f47a8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;5678&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/1f89d7f6202dd2ba9ff83a96f15f47a8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;《常·识——南方报业媒体融合漫论》目录。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/07bb486f461ce7c1189ca9b7220c0010.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;851&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/07bb486f461ce7c1189ca9b7220c0010.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;作者简介。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运新项目电子竞技开赛，中国香港队小组赛战胜中国台北队]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257563]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ef0b241597.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ef0b241597.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，浙江杭州，杭州亚运会电子竞技项目在中国杭州电竞中心开赛。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，杭州亚运会电子竞技项目比赛在中国杭州电竞中心开赛。这是“电子竞技”首次在亚运会上被列为正式比赛项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2d24a1f7bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2d24a1f7bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，中国香港队电竞选手正在比赛中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在9月24日上午举行的王者荣耀亚运版本小组循环赛B组第二场中，中国香港队以1-0战胜中国台北队。比赛场地中国杭州电竞中心是国内首座亚运会赛事标准的专业电子竞技场馆，馆内最吸引眼球的是拥有4面大屏和4面角屏、总面积202平方米的斗屏。这个大屏幕可升可降，最高可以升至离地面22米，能满足场馆内不同坐席位置的观众观看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/277ff3db5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/277ff3db5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，总面积202平方米的斗屏。这个大屏幕可升可降，能满足场馆内不同坐席位置的观众观看。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7ae897d930.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7ae897d930.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，在看台上观赛的群众手里舞动着荧光棒。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4b9cc5a147.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4b9cc5a147.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，王者荣耀亚运版本小组循环赛B组第二场中，中国香港队以1-0战胜中国台北队。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据了解，杭州亚运会电竞比赛时间为9月24日至10月2日，比赛共确定7个项目，分别为英雄联盟、王者荣耀亚运版本、和平精英亚运版本、刀塔、梦三国2、街霸5、足球在线4，其中包含5个PC端项目与2个手游端项目，将共产生7枚金牌。根据官方售票方案，电竞项目票价从200元起分为多档，其中决赛最高档票价高达1000元，成为最贵的亚运观赛门票之一，也是唯一需要抽签才能购买的项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9b0a05f6af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9b0a05f6af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，观赛群众中清一色年轻面孔。电子竞技观赛门票是最贵的亚运门票之一，也是唯一需要抽签才能购买的项目。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;回顾“电竞入亚”的历程，在亚洲范围内，电子竞技最早盛行于韩国，后逐步向中国、日本、越南、泰国等国家发展。2003年11月18日，国家体育总局正式批准，将电子竞技列为第99个正式体育竞赛项目；2008年，国家体育总局将电子竞技改批为第78个正式体育竞赛项目；2013年，国家体育总局设立中国电子竞技国家队，广泛展开赛事；在2018年雅加达亚运会上，电竞作为表演而非正式项目首次亮相亚运会，中国电竞代表团夺得2金1银；2020年12月16日，在第39届亚奥理事会全体代表大会上，电子竞技获准列为杭州亚运会正式比赛项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5b099e5d1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5b099e5d1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，比赛结束后，中国香港队电竞选手（右）与中国台北队选手握手致意。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从风暴到常态：审计结果公开二十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/wZQfLtQoOm2O6lcVO2LGZLhZEhsqWbg3H242Yr6H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height=&quot;844&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/wZQfLtQoOm2O6lcVO2LGZLhZEhsqWbg3H242Yr6H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京，国家审计署。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2023年4月，对2021年度审计发现的问题，已整改问题金额8501.11亿元，完善制度2900多项，追责问责1.4万多人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是2023年6月26日，审计署审计长侯凯在作《国务院关于2022年度中央预算执行和其他财政收支的审计工作报告》时公布的数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到2022年度审计工作报告时，中国审计学会副会长、西南财经大学会计学院教授蔡春认为，随着审计水平的提高和制度建设的完善，审计已是常态化服务国家治理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公众对审计工作产生印象至少是20年前的事。2003年6月25日，时任审计署审计长李金华向全国人大常委会作2002年度审计工作报告，财政部、教育部、原国家计委等一批部委被公开批评。那时，互联网刚刚兴起不久，报告在审计署官网全文公开，引发全民关注，并称其为“审计风暴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南京审计大学政府审计学院教授郑小荣认为，20年前，公众曾习惯政府对财政收支情况保密，在当时，“公开本身就是一个热点”，而现在，即使舆论不关注，审计也照常发挥作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而回顾过往20年不难发现，随着社会的发展，审计的重点也在发生改变。不同时期有不同重点，有些内容已成为历史。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;和盘托出&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2022年度审计工作报告有不少亮点。不同于以往的科技成果转化审计，这次首次聚焦基础研究和关键核心技术攻坚任务，指出部分任务部署和要求偏离预定目标，部分科研成果涉嫌造假等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;审计发现，45项重点任务从制定实施方案到签订任务合同，层层降低指标要求，有的技术国内已量产，无需攻关。649个已验收项目通过率为96.5%，但抽查其中135个发现实际有34个未完成全部任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑小荣观察到，“年年审，年年发现问题”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年度审计工作报告指出，41个地区向亏损企业征收国有资本收益、征收过头税费或直接乱罚款乱摊派等，违规组织财政收入77.5亿元；49个地区通过承诺兜底回购、国有企业垫资建设等方式，违规新增隐性债务415.16亿元；12个地区不得不从上级超预算额度调拨库款、由银行垫款或对外借款280.72亿元维持基本运转。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央各部委所属单位疏于管理和监督的问题仍然存在。例如，3个部门和29家所属单位铺张浪费，有的多花费2700多万元租用办公场所，人均办公面积达137平方米，有的超合同进度年底突击花钱8458.07万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20年前,类似的问题就被点名，2002年度审计工作报告曾指出，一部委编造虚假项目预算，并与某工程处签订虚假施工合同，将135万元预算资金拨付该工程处，然后分批收回，主要用于发放职工补贴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名审计干部回忆，正是在2003年，审计署才被公众认识。距离审计署成立的1983年，已过去20年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2003年6月25日，2002年度审计工作报告在审计署官网全文公开后，被媒体广泛转载。兰州大学经济学院教授杨肃昌仍对这份报告带来的震惊记忆犹新，“（原来）问题这么严重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一年披露的问题包括：县市财政收入“水分”较大，人为隐瞒赤字普遍，债务负担沉重；企业漏缴基本养老保险基金问题比较普遍，有关管理部门挤占挪用4.2亿元；教育部全国大学英语四六级考试委员会违规集中各地考试费2.24亿元，从中坐支相关考试费用等1.9亿元。等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于公布的问题触目惊心，公众将其称为“审计风暴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，“审计风暴”或可再往前追溯到1999年。按照当时的审计工作程序，每年5月份，审计署要就上一年审计工作情况向国务院出具审计结果报告，根据这份报告，再起草向全国人大常委会提交的审计工作报告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;向全国人大常委会的报告和盘托出了审计发现的问题。1999年6月26日，李金华向全国人大常委会作《1998年度审计工作报告》，指出国务院43个部门和直属单位挤占挪用财政资金31.24亿元等问题，《中国经济时报》曾援引部分委员的话，表示是“多年来最好的一个审计工作报告”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;十八大后扶贫审计成为重点&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2003年以来，审计工作都聚焦了哪些领域？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者梳理发现，从2002年到2022年的21份《审计工作报告》中，除每年固定的财政审计外，资源环境保护、社保基金、农业农村是最为关注的领域，分别出现17次、13次、13次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同时期，审计工作也有不同重点。以“三公”经费为例，2007年度审计工作报告用了103个字，首次指出税务部门存在无编制和超编制购置小汽车，以及招待费、会议费、培训费和出国费控制不够严格的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中共十八大后，随着中央八项规定的制定、执行，“三公”经费开始成为审计监督的重点。2013年度审计工作报告史无前例地用1244字的篇幅，直指“三公”经费和会议费管理使用问题，点名22个中央部门和所属单位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，中央部门“三公”经费和会议费支出比上年下降27%，部门本级公务用车改革基本完成。但审计仍然发现，科技部、原文化部等33个部门和单位长期占用其他单位车辆，或以租赁方式变相配备公务用车122辆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后连续九年，“三公”经费一直都被提及。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扶贫也一度是报告关注的焦点。2013年11月提出“精准扶贫”战略后，次年，审计报告在时隔十年之后，再次出现关于扶贫审计的内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告指出，审计19个国家扶贫开发工作重点县后发现，1595.71万元扶贫资金被个人侵占，1.73亿元扶贫资金被虚报冒领或挤占挪用，有5个县的扶贫工作主管部门在扶贫管理费等经费中违规列支吃喝、旅游费用53.36万元，还有2.27亿元扶贫资金闲置1年以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/evLOaYcG1oPhzGE1tX8YmI86cZI29BnAy3yyGxM4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1271&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/evLOaYcG1oPhzGE1tX8YmI86cZI29BnAy3yyGxM4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年度审计工作报告指出，高标准农田建设资金，地方统筹整合使用时存在难度。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年11月29日，中共中央、国务院发布《关于打赢脱贫攻坚战的决定》，提出确保到2020年农村贫困人口实现脱贫，要求抓好精准识别、建档立卡关键环节，使建档立卡贫困人口中有5000万人左右通过产业扶持等措施实现脱贫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这在第二年的报告中就有所体现，《2015年度审计工作报告》提到，抽查云南省寻甸县2015年发放的1339笔扶贫到户贴息贷款6560万元中，仅有711笔3433万元（占52%）发放给建档立卡贫困户。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年至今，报告则连续两年对就业补助和促进就业资金进行审计。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;有板块7次更名&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;20年来，审计工作报告的形式也在发生改变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个变化是报告名称。2013年作的2012年度审计报告名称为《关于2012年度中央预算执行和其他财政收支的审计工作报告》，次年改为《国务院关于2013年度中央预算执行和其他财政收支的审计工作报告》，这一格式固定至今。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是简单地多了3个字。郑小荣认为，根据审计法规定，审计工作报告由国务院向全国人大常委会提出，在实践中由审计署代表国务院作报告。标题中增加“国务院”更符合审计法精神，也更能体现审计工作报告的权威性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，审计工作报告开篇的称呼，则由此前的“全国人民代表大会常务委员会”，调整为“委员长、各位副委员长、秘书长，各位委员”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在郑小荣看来，全国人大常委会是一个机构，后者更为具体，“类似于点名”,称呼的变化是“希望在审议、决议工作报告时，每位参会者都高度重视，强化人大监督的作用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公众对哪些单位被点名格外关注。20年来，“点名”经历了从模糊到逐步清晰的过程，被点名单位的数量也有变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2002年度审计工作报告模糊处理了部分地区和单位信息，用“某省”“某区政府”“部分航空公司”等替代。而审计发现的违法违纪人员，直到2006年度审计工作报告才开始出现当事人姓名，此前只点出其单位和职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑小荣认为，这是审计机关谨慎的表现，信息公开在当时仍然敏感，“信息公开以后，会有意想不到的结果”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;另一个变化是，2017年以后，报告中点名的单位数量减少。南方周末记者不完全统计，2017年报告点名24家单位，这一数字在2018年下降到3家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西南财经大学审计系主任李越冬看来，这与审计功能的变化有一定关系，“现在更多的是帮助被审计单位解决问题。”审计取证的时间有限，也更加强调发现重大问题，“一些小问题不一定出现在报告中，告知整改就可以了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑小荣补充说，过去一些被审计单位在工作过程中不太配合，在报告中点名一度是促进其整改的方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;审计工作报告中的固定章节，也经历了多次更名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者梳理发现，2008年度审计工作报告首次出现“重大违法违规问题揭露和查处情况”这一章节，除了公布移送的重大违法违规问题和经济犯罪案件线索数量、涉案人数外，还对犯罪形式、手段和方法进行总结。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，该章节历经7次更名，如2012年的“审计查出的重大违法违规问题和经济犯罪案件”，2013年改为“审计发现的重大违法违规案件情况”，2014年是“审计查出的涉嫌重大违法违规案件情况”。2021年更名为“重大违纪违法问题线索”并保留至今，提及的问题包括“小官贪腐”、基层微腐败和“靠山吃山”等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在21份审计工作报告中，章节的内容、位置和名称，整体并不固定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑小荣也注意到这个现象，他认为，在制度逐渐规范的过程中，审计机关对审计工作报告的形式具有裁量权，也会影响报告的文本形式和框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;打破壁垒&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“不同层级的政府，都承担着公共受托经济责任，在履行责任的同时，政府也被赋予了特定的权力。”蔡春认为，审计的作用，就是保障政府责任的履行，促进公共权力的运用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者梳理发现，2009年度审计工作报告，就已经指出地方政府债务总体规模较大、部分地方政府偿债压力较大、财政资金偿债能力不足的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，按照国务院要求，2011年审计署组织全国审计机关4万多人，以“见账、见人、见物，逐笔、逐项审核”为原则，对全国所有涉及地方政府性债务的25590个政府部门和机构、6576家融资平台公司、54061个其他单位、373805个项目和1873683笔债务进行审计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;审计整改一度是“老大难”问题。在2021年审计法修订前，对于审计对象不按要求整改的，该采取什么样的措施，并没有作出具体规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到新修订的审计法作出回应：“审计结果以及整改情况应当作为考核、任免、奖惩领导干部和制定政策、完善制度的重要参考；拒不整改或者整改时弄虚作假的，依法追究法律责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据审计法规定，审计机关受本级政府和上一级审计机关双重领导。而在现实中，本级政府对本级审计机关的影响更大。湖南省怀化市审计局工作人员刘空军曾在2009年发表文章称，当地13个县(市、区)基层审计机关，62%的班子成员调整没有事先征求上一级审计机关的意见，双重管理流于形式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而据郑小荣介绍，在审计结果上报本级人大前，政府有机会拦截、筛选反映的问题，“有些问题不能查深查透，监督权没办法往下延伸”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年前后，关于审计体制改革的问题有多种观点，根据一篇2013年发布于审计署官网的文章中，审计署长沙办黄凯把各方观点归纳为升格论、垂直论、独立论和立法论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而最被业内人士推崇的是立法论，审计机关隶属于人民代表大会，对政府部门独立行使审计监督权力。早在2002年，杨肃昌对62位审计署官员、地方审计机关官员、政府官员、人大干部、审计学者开展问卷调查，其中77%的受访者赞同或基本赞同立法型审计体制改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对审计体制改革的讨论没有停止。2017年12月，中共十九大召开后，杨肃昌受审计署邀请，讨论审计体制改革的走向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;答案很快揭晓。2018年3月，中共中央印发《深化党和国家机构改革方案》，宣布组建中央审计委员会。“没想到会成立。”杨肃昌说，从现实角度看，“在中央审计委员会的领导下，审计工作与党的领导和监督体制融为一体。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;审计发现的问题“必须向中央审计委员会报告，而且是直达”。郑小荣认为，虽然目前审计机关仍然受本级政府和上一级审计机关双重领导，但中央审计委员会打破了政府管理下形成的壁垒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[印度裔CEO正在“统治”世界，凭的是什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257541]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期，职场人力资源（HR）领域流传着一种半开玩笑的说法：印度人正在用一种奇怪的方式“统治”世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其意思是：印度裔的职业经理人和职场精英，正在世界上取得越来越大的成功。在美国的硅谷大企业30%以上CEO都是印裔。在美国企业中，由印裔担任董事长、CEO、总裁、首席运营官的，排名前十有：Google &amp;amp; Alphabet、微软、联邦快递、IBM、诺华制药、NetApp、巴克莱集团、星巴克、Adobe、美光科技等全球知名企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这类担任顶层职位的印裔职业经理人牵带下，这些企业招聘了大量更年轻、层级稍低的印裔精英，各级高、中层管理职位，技术要职、财务、人力资源等关键岗位，越来越多被印裔职场精英所占据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印裔在西方世界的影响力越来越大，成为目前美、英社会里势力最大的少数群体，很多西方人都知道印裔族群不好惹，其获得的社会地位、取得的社会成就远远超过当地的华裔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾访谈过一些HR机构，了解其为何乐于推介印裔职业经理人，以及雇主对印裔管理人员的观感如何，印裔为何能取得如此成就，得到的反馈表明，印裔职场精英的优势大致如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;价值观认同：印度曾长期是英殖民地，印度人曾被嘲笑为英国的“长工、苦力”，而印人认同与想要融入英、美社会与生活方式的动机很足，他们好好学习的目的，常常是为了去英、美社会，从“长工”逐渐做到“领班、管家、掌柜的”。印人去了英、美，就没有再回去的打算，而是竭尽所能在那里扎根，从“印人”变成“印裔”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沟通优势：作为前英国殖民地，印度本土高端学校注重英语教育。因此其教育精英们，尽管口音浓重，但语言沟通无障碍，这在英、美职场是很大优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于印地语属“亚欧语系”，其与西方语言之间有较多相似性，在印式英语基础上，印人学法语、德语、西班牙语的障碍也较少。因此，目前印裔职场精英呈现从英语社会向整个西方世界扩散的趋势。印人的沟通优势之二，是其生活习俗崇尚聊天、闲谈、辩论，因此，他们与西方人能谈得来，即便观点不同，也能聊、敢谈，更容易混得熟，对升迁有利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文化多样性：印度本土有6大宗教、22种官方地区语言、212个民族、414个部族。各地区和不同族群的宗教、文化、生活习俗差异很大。这样复杂的社会，使印人更适应文化多样性的生活模式。印度历史上从未有过“大一统”，其统一都是英国人帮助建立的。因此，印人来到西方世界，不但不觉得那里光怪陆离，反而认为西方人过于严肃、刻板、简单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;团队合作力：印裔注重团队合作和人际关系，其个体通常具备良好的人际交往和沟通能力，这对高级管理职位而言非常重要。印裔很抱团，企业的印裔高管尽可能招聘印裔员工，甚至发生过弊案：美国医院招聘医生，印裔主任将所有非印裔应聘者的简历全部扔掉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而印人的民间规矩是：被招聘成功者，要将自己1-3个月的薪水（职位越高，回扣越高）全部送给招聘人，以感谢知遇之恩。而印裔群体几乎无人违反这种约定俗成，形成了其悠久的风俗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;服从与忠诚：与上述“招聘回扣”的印裔职场风俗相对应的是，印裔员工对自己上级的高度服从。其下级很善于与领导沟通，他们会经常主动问领导：你还需要我做什么？我有什么做得不好？怎样做才能使你更满意？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雇佣过印度人，会感到他们普遍比较顺从、可靠、安心，领导慢慢就会放心任用与提拔他们。一种说法是，印人经常轻轻晃着头（表示赞同、服从）说：I see、I see（我明白了）。被国人听成“阿三、阿三”。另一种说法是阿三是“阿sir”，当时英国人常招聘印度人去殖民地或租界当警察。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自己招聘进来的人比较拎得清、惹祸较少、少“坑爹”，也是印裔高管敢于招聘同族下属的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韧性：美国人喜欢嘲弄其政府无用、总统无能。而在印人看来，自己的国家和政府更糟糕，印人在本国为了生存，学会坚韧不拔，在无穷无尽的恶劣条件下，充分利用有限资源生活下去。这种能力，使印裔员工更加吃苦耐劳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谦逊：作为从落后、贫穷社会来的新移民，印人明白并承认自己在许多方面的局限与不足。因此在学习过程中更加谦逊，心态更加开放，因此他们更容易融入当地，也更容易被当地社会所接纳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;技术和工程领域方面的教育优势：作为后发国家，印度的教育与东亚类似，更偏重于科学技术、工程等理工科课程。尤其在计算机、工程、科技创新等领域颇具特色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“印度理工”甚至自我吹嘘“考不上印度理工的，去上麻省理工”。这当然是自吹自擂，但是其培养的大批理工科人才，正好弥补了英语世界富足太盛、承平日久后，越来越多的富有年轻人不愿再辛苦读理工科，而就读“文史哲艺”等所谓“富人学科”的弱点。欧美的“富N代”学习守成之术、驭人之法，而来自印度的理工科人才，担任CEO、总监、经理、科技精英……实现自身阶层跃升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;敢于冒险和创业：印裔个体更加敢于冒险和创业，他们更多敢于成立自己的公司，在发展壮大后担任CEO，这种创业倾向使得其在商业界取得了巨大成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，印裔正在从商界向政界发展，“统治”世界的笑谈，正在逐渐变得严肃起来：英国首相Sunak，新加坡总统Shanmugaratnam，爱尔兰总理Varadkar，葡萄牙总理Costa，毛里求斯总统Roopun、总理Jugnauth，圭亚那总统Irfaan Ali，苏里南总统Santokhi等都是印裔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而目前美国政府印裔阁员太多了：总统助理兼国内政策顾问、美国卫生部与公共服务部部长、国家经济委员会副主任、国务卿高级顾问、白宫芯片顾问和美国商务部首席经济学家、白宫总统人事办公室副主任、白宫高级幕僚和总统讲稿撰写人等都是印裔，而印裔仅占美国人口1.4%，以如此小的人口权重，撬动如此巨大的政治杠杆，影响到美国的国家政策，甚至对世界政治走向都产生了影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印裔精英“统治”世界的说法，在很多人看来是笑谈，但趋势确不可小觑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[有奖征集 | 鲁迅的哪些话，让你印象深刻？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257549]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;人生五十五年，留下文字万千。锋利有时，苍凉有时，振奋有时，柔情亦有时。《从百草园到三味书屋》《狂人日记》《少年闰土》《阿Q正传》《纪念刘和珍君》……他的笔触，关乎家国社会，跃然于几代人的语文课本，也激荡在每个国人的心头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天是鲁迅诞辰142周年，时代早已更迭，生活一日千里，再读那些铿锵有力的文字，仍然会感到醍醐灌顶、豁然开朗，更以体恤式的温柔，去消解五味杂陈的日子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鲁迅的哪些话，让你印象深刻？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎在下方评论区参与互动，&lt;strong>;我们将抽取1位最走心留言，赠送一件“鲁迅阅读系列T恤”&lt;/strong>;。把文字穿在身上，化作前行的力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;留言截至时间：2023年10月9日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0qsVbxH8GFKakbFx0pDTUFhMU8erUTB81TzWtMHJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0qsVbxH8GFKakbFx0pDTUFhMU8erUTB81TzWtMHJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国泳队包揽亚运开赛首日全部7枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257565]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-25 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，由杨浚瑄、程玉洁、吴卿风、张雨霏组队的中国队在女子4x100米自由泳接力项目中，以3分33秒96夺冠，这一成绩打破了赛会纪录。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2432a564ca.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2432a564ca.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，由杨浚瑄、程玉洁、吴卿风、张雨霏组队的中国队在女子4x100米自由泳接力项目中，以3分33秒96夺冠，这一成绩打破了赛会纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月24日晚，杭州亚运会游泳项目决出7块金牌。张雨霏、汪顺、李冰洁、潘展乐、唐钱婷、徐嘉余、程玉洁、杨浚瑄、吴卿风为中国队包揽7块金牌，打破多个赛会纪录、亚洲纪录！中国游泳队还有多名运动员获得了银牌、铜牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，男子200米混合泳，汪顺力压覃海洋夺冠。他以1分54秒62刷新了个人最好成绩，同时还打破了亚洲纪录。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/a925420da0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/a925420da0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，男子200米混合泳，汪顺力压覃海洋夺冠。他以1分54秒62刷新了个人最好成绩，同时还打破了亚洲纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女子200米蝶泳决赛中，中国名将、东京奥运会该项目冠军张雨霏，以2分05秒57的成绩成功卫冕，并打破了赛会纪录。这是中国游泳队本届亚运首金。俞李妍获得该项目银牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，张雨霏获得200米蝶泳金牌，完成了七枚金牌目标的第一枚。同时，她以2分5秒57刷新赛会纪录。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/54989279d5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/54989279d5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，张雨霏获得200米蝶泳金牌，完成了七枚金牌目标的第一枚。同时，她以2分5秒57刷新赛会纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，张雨霏在比赛当中。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/8e032ffdaf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/8e032ffdaf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，张雨霏在比赛当中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;男子200米个人混合泳决赛中，东京奥运会该项目冠军汪顺以1分54秒62打破了亚洲纪录，夺得冠军。覃海洋获得该项目亚军。赛后，汪顺表示：“破亚洲纪录非常满意，是家乡父老给了我力量！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，汪顺在比赛后挥手致意。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/193302a019.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/193302a019.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，汪顺在比赛后挥手致意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，覃海洋在赛前进行热身。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/17ec106ec8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/17ec106ec8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，覃海洋在赛前进行热身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女子1500米自由泳决赛，中国名将李冰洁以15分51秒18的成绩夺得冠军，并大幅度改写了赛会纪录。中国队另一名选手、15岁的小将高唯中获得银牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，女子1500米自由泳决赛，李冰洁以15分51秒18的成绩夺冠。15岁的小将高唯中获得银牌。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/ffd4af8357.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/ffd4af8357.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，女子1500米自由泳决赛，李冰洁以15分51秒18的成绩夺冠。 15岁的小将高唯中获得银牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，戴着熊猫泳帽的李冰洁在女子1500米自由泳项目中无悬念夺冠，她以15分51秒18成绩打破赛会纪录。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afef9efb15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afef9efb15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，戴着熊猫泳帽的李冰洁在女子1500米自由泳项目中无悬念夺冠，她以15分51秒18成绩打破赛会纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;男子100米自由泳决赛中，中国名将、亚洲纪录保持者潘展乐，以46秒97的成绩打破自己保持的亚洲纪录夺得冠军。他也成为第一位在该项目上游进47秒的亚洲选手。中国选手王浩宇获得该项目银牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，裁判员在泳池边摇铃提醒进入最后一圈的游泳选手。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/acaea8bce5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/acaea8bce5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月24日，裁判员在泳池边摇铃提醒进入最后一圈的游泳选手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，女子50米蛙泳，唐钱婷以29秒96夺冠。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/70572f9fb3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/70572f9fb3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，女子50米蛙泳，唐钱婷以29秒96夺冠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女子50米蛙泳决赛中，中国队选手唐钱婷以29秒96的成绩摘得冠军，在上午的预赛中她就打破了自己保持的亚洲纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，唐钱婷在比赛中保持领先。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afd8995c28.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/afd8995c28.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，唐钱婷在比赛中保持领先。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;男子100米仰泳决赛中，中国名将徐嘉余以52秒23的成绩打破赛会纪录夺冠。中国选手王谷开来获得该项目第四名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，女子4x100米自由泳接力项目中国队选手在比赛后摆出比心造型。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/01f1d92924.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/01f1d92924.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，女子4x100米自由泳接力项目中国队选手在比赛后摆出比心造型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，中国香港选手获女子4×100自由泳接力铜牌。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/40fff8a813.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/40fff8a813.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，中国香港选手获女子4×100自由泳接力铜牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女子4x100米自由泳接力决赛，由程玉洁、杨浚瑄、吴卿风和张雨霏组成的中国队以3分33秒96的成绩夺冠，打破赛会纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，为中国泳队助威呐喊的观众。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/10cdff31f3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/10cdff31f3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，为中国泳队助威呐喊的观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于中国泳队取得的丰硕成果，有网友戏称：这是来杭州批发金牌吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>