<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[新能源汽车充电费用为何上涨？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261338]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As one of the advantages of purchasing new energy vehicles, the cost of using new energy vehicles has always attracted the attention of car owners. . Recently, some new energy vehicle owners have reported that charging fees at public charging piles have increased since the second half of the year. Does this situation exist? With this question in mind, reporters conducted investigations in many places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Drivers of operating vehicles are more sensitive to changes in charging fees for new energy vehicles. Master Wei is an online ride-hailing driver in Zhengzhou, Henan, because he goes to public charging stations to charge once or twice a day. His mobile phone clearly records the cost of each charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/8707fe1a673b3f7a07d093f566fc40ca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/8707fe1a673b3f7a07d093f566fc40ca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan Zhengzhou Net Ride-hailing driver Wei Zhenhua: My charging fee has obviously increased. It used to be 1,200 yuan a month, but now it is as high as 1,500 yuan. It has indeed increased a lot. Especially after August, it rose by about 20 to 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charging fee at public charging piles consists of two parts: electricity price and service fee. Electricity prices have been mainly formed by the market, with &quot;level in and level out&quot; and charging pile operators are not allowed to increase prices. Prices vary in different seasons and during peak, wave, and flat periods every day. The service fee is determined by each charging pile operating company based on market conditions. During the interview, the reporter found that charging fees at public piles have increased not only in Zhengzhou but also in many cities in Henan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/06b4189b0c487b25cc2eed44e60cad19.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;662&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/06b4189b0c487b25cc2eed44e60cad19.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259661&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new energy Co., Ltd. Henan regional director Yu Haitao: We charging companies have raised the service fee for primary charging. It has been raised by about 1 jiao to 1 jiao and 2 cents compared to the beginning of the year. So overall, everyone feels the increase in charging prices. The amplitude is relatively large. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surveys show that the service fees of some charging companies have even increased by around 50%. So, why do they want to adjust the price? Some charging pile operating companies told reporters that the high cost of early investment in charging pile construction and the long-term strategy of &quot;grabbing the market&quot; for low-price operations have put them under greater operating pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97ea8d2c1b65c4cf380c9c6814e67c0b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97ea8d2c1b65c4cf380c9c6814e67c0b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An electronics company in Henan Wei Hongyu, Operations Director of Technology Co., Ltd.: The main reason for this increase is that as our operations deepen, we find that there is even a risk of inversion in the service fee income of charging stations compared to our station construction costs and our operating costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Financial reports of some charging operation companies show that although the company&#39;s operating income is rising every year, it is negative profits every year. At the same time, in order to attract more users, operators tend to build high-power charging piles. However, the basic cost of high-power charging piles is relatively high. Some also need to build additional corresponding distribution boxes, and maintenance costs will naturally increase. . Therefore, raising service fees has become the current solution to recover costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The cost of using new energy vehicles still has a greater advantage than that of gasoline vehicles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Through interviews and surveys, the reporter found that in some cities, the rising charging costs of electric vehicles do exist. So this situation Does it happen in all cities across the country? Are the cost advantages of buying an electric car still there? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During interviews and surveys in many places, reporters found that the rise in charging costs for new energy vehicles only occurred in some cities, and charging costs in most cities across the country fell into a stable range. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/51786d4413d5411912229c0755b9dc9e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/51786d4413d5411912229c0755b9dc9e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing New Energy Car owner: There is not much increase. I have charged at several nearby charging stations. There is not much change. It is basically the same as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen new energy vehicle owners: The electricity price at this time is 1.27 yuan per unit. The overall cost is not particularly high and it is quite affordable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the China Electric Vehicle Charging Infrastructure Promotion Alliance show that from January to October this year, the number of public charging piles in my country was 728,000, and the number in October was 63,000, a year-on-year increase of 50.3%. The increase in the number of charging piles not only meets the rapid development of new energy vehicles, but also makes competition among charging pile operating companies more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/b7fa96dfbaeb011d9617520d6d2e690a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/b7fa96dfbaeb011d9617520d6d2e690a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259662&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A smart phone in Beijing Chen Dong, the person in charge of Technology Co., Ltd.: The overall charging price is still relatively low now, because the competition in the industry is fierce. We have more than 40 charging stations in Beijing. Winter is the peak charging season, and the overall cost has not been adjusted upwards. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that fluctuations in charging fees in most cities are the result of market supply and demand adjustments, and the quality of increases or decreases cannot be judged absolutely. Most cities have now abolished the maximum price limit on service fees, and each operator can determine the level of charging service fees based on market competition. At the same time, in the face of the issue raised by some netizens that the cost of using new energy vehicles is almost equal to that of gasoline vehicles, experts also gave reporters a calculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/4bc772773657773a07d7dfe0eb594a4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/4bc772773657773a07d7dfe0eb594a4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259660&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Electric Power Corporation Liu Yongdong, deputy secretary-general of the federation: For example, for every 100 kilometers of our oil truck, the industry requires about 10 liters of oil. We estimate that it will be calculated at about 8 yuan, which is 80 yuan. Let&#39;s look at the tram again. On average, it requires about 15 kilowatt hours of electricity per 100 kilometers. The overall consumption of each kilowatt hour of electricity plus service fees is about 1.5 yuan. So the entire 15 kilowatt hours of electricity is about 22.5 yuan. Even if it is 25 yuan, we Comparing 25 yuan with 80 yuan, it should be said that there is still a huge gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Various regions have launched new measures to shape the healthy development of new energy vehicles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In order to ensure a good charging experience for new energy vehicle owners, various regions have successively introduced new policies such as time-of-use electricity prices for charging facilities. The implementation of relevant measures will not only guide car owners to use electricity rationally, but will also be more conducive to the healthy and sustainable development of the new energy vehicle industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September this year, Shandong began to implement a new time-of-use electricity price policy for residents&#39; charging, which subdivided the peak and valley periods and added deep valley and peak periods. During the deep valley period, the electricity price was 0.222 yuan per kilowatt hour, which is the same as The price difference during peak hours is 0.666 yuan per kilowatt hour. By widening the price difference, users are guided to avoid charging during peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97416b76a8b4710da6eed33e4ef12df7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97416b76a8b4710da6eed33e4ef12df7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259663&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jimo District, Qingdao New energy vehicle owners: Now the electricity price in Shengu for charging at noon is only more than 2 cents per degree. If you go home and have a meal, the electricity will be fully charged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Shandong, but also Guangdong, Jiangxi, Hunan, Shaanxi and other places have successively introduced time-of-use electricity price policies for residents’ electric vehicle charging facilities. During peak and peak hours, charging car owners need to bear more costs, and During off-peak periods, car owners can enjoy lower prices than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/ac2c310d54f1abcd7b404c830cf87215.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/ac2c310d54f1abcd7b404c830cf87215.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen New Energy Car owner: It is the peak period for charging now. The current price is 1.49 degrees. We usually choose to charge at noon or at night, and the price will be more favorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the continued efforts of government policies, some charging operating companies are also actively exploring new trends in future development. On the one hand, it is necessary to add new momentum to corporate operations, and on the other hand, the charging experience of car owners must also be considered. In order to &quot;stand out&quot; in the market competition, they choose to provide more comprehensive services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97bd9ffcf65eb191c4e283ced6f959ab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/97bd9ffcf65eb191c4e283ced6f959ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259665&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new person in Shenzhen Chen Huanyu, operations director of the energy company: Our service fee is only about a little more than a triangle, which is 5% higher than the service fee of surrounding operators. Our advantage is that the supporting facilities are relatively complete, which solves the driver&#39;s dining problem. To solve the problem of rest, we also have a comprehensive service area with quick car repairs, quick washes, and a comprehensive online car-hailing service platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, charging operation companies have also strengthened the level of interconnection and interoperability. In Hainan, the reporter saw that the supervision and operation service platform linked different operators together. There are 165 charging and swapping operators, 63 public battery swapping stations, and 3,358 charging stations connected here. The access rate of the province&#39;s public charging pile platform reaches 100%. The construction of the platform not only unifies the payment methods, making it more convenient for car owners to &quot;find charging stations&quot;, but also facilitates the monitoring of charging fee fluctuations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/d3189767590c844c999708027249926b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/d3189767590c844c999708027249926b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259664&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hainan Province Charge Wang Jin, Operations Director of Battery Exchange Network Service Co., Ltd.: Realize the interconnection of pile networks and power grids, promptly report charging stations with irregular charging pricing to pile companies for rectification, and report to the local government management department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that both the time-of-use electricity price policy and the active attempts and interconnection measures of charging companies are releasing positive signals and exploring new opportunities for the development of the entire new energy vehicle charging industry. path of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/be2c6bc8f9950f6ebf24436e7242ca9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1176&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/be2c6bc8f9950f6ebf24436e7242ca9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Electric Power Corporation Liu Yongdong, deputy secretary-general of the Federation: Our country is unswervingly committed to developing new energy vehicles. In this process, including the charging facilities industry, the power industry and the automobile industry, we must promote and eliminate new energy vehicles around a healthy ecology. construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[唐立梅：科普就是在传递生命的意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/gAabDh6gZPqP2K2yFXRskv3qf9uFPcOsBa4SrRAG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/gAabDh6gZPqP2K2yFXRskv3qf9uFPc OsBa4SrRAG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Limei finally lived the fulfilling life she had dreamed of. Waking up early and staying late has become the norm. Getting up at 4 a.m. to go to the airport and returning home at 1:30 a.m. after finishing the day&#39;s activities is not an exception. Not staying out overnight is partly to take care of my young daughter’s emotions, but also to satisfy her pursuit of efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She rarely used it to catch up on sleep when flying, but still raced against time to read and think. Since 2013, she has continued to travel to campuses of all ages, TV studios, events, lectures, forums, and dining tables used for live broadcasts and writing, sharing her deep dives in the Western Pacific with the &quot;Jiaolong&quot; Scientific expedition and the experience of participating in the 34th Antarctic Scientific Expedition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, she only gave lectures as a scientist as a researcher at the Second Institute of Oceanography of the Ministry of Natural Resources. Over the past ten years, she has gradually been dubbed a science popularization expert because of her tireless science popularization and vivid and humorous narration. title. In the past two years, she has won important honors such as Top Ten Science Communication Figures in China, Chief Science Communication Expert, and Female Science Popularization Expert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, she spared a few hours, ate a sandwich at noon, and rushed home to prepare for the live broadcast at 4 p.m. Not long ago, she went to attend classes at universities and party schools. The topic she taught was the core of leadership from the perspective of biological evolution, from natural science to humanities and then to philosophy (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;This is her usual style&lt;/span>;), recalling her hearty smile and said, &quot;There was no urine in the whole process&quot;; then she was also invited to participate in a TED speech, the theme was &quot;If your major is a transfer, you What will happen in the future?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experienced the transition from engineering to science (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Undergraduate survey technology and engineering, postgraduate geological engineering, doctoral geology&lt;/p>; span>;), Tang Limei decided to switch his research field to marine geology after listening to a lecture by chance while studying for his PhD. He realized early on that life has no limits and is full of unexpected and unplanned nodes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With ten years of accumulation in science popularization, she will bring a new book &quot;Exploring the Deep Sea with the &quot;Dragon&quot;&quot; at the end of 2023 to show people a new face of a science popularization writer. The book will introduce the basic knowledge of the ocean (&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, what is the sea, what is the ocean, how to form&lt;/span>;), the five major oceans of the world (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Newly included in the Southern Ocean in 2021&lt;/span>;)&#39;s cutting-edge knowledge, personal experience in deep-sea exploration, and the development history of the country&#39;s manned deep submersibles, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took less than half a year to write the book. She was busier than before. She didn&#39;t even have time to wash her face after getting up every morning. She said that her days now consist of only three things: work, exercise, and reading and thinking. She has been able to maintain her body shape for nearly 20 years after getting up early for a run. During the interview, she was wearing the team uniform she wore during the Antarctic scientific expedition in 2017, and it still fit her perfectly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other than that, there are very few pastimes, and I hardly watch movies. Everything I do must &quot;generate value and meaning.&quot; She would refuse without hesitation if asked to travel to the beach. Only when it became a matter of spending time with her children and family would she be willing to do so. &quot;I can&#39;t go out to play by myself, but I&#39;m willing to do it with others. It&#39;s valuable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She recalled more than ten years ago when life was not so full. , I still have plenty of time to watch &quot;The Legend of Zhen Huan&quot;, and during the period when I went to the Pacific to &quot;isolate&quot;, I watched it intermittently nearly 20 times in total. &quot;It wouldn&#39;t be so busy then. I would definitely choose to read a book now.&quot; It wasn&#39;t until 2022 that she turned the content of the TV series into a class, and then she finally let go of the time wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/GDFKKq1U2uGe4wXxCkfhZo5gEfOBJvo01JL7UOFU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/GDFKKq1U2uGe4wXxCkfhZo5gEfOBJvo01JL7UOFU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ocean Open Class&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(video screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lecture content revolves around &quot;Zhen Huan&quot; &quot;Scientific trivia in the Biography&quot;, &quot;For example, there is an episode where the emperor went to An Lingrong&#39;s place to celebrate her birthday. He was very tired of eating, so he happened to get him some light pastries. Why do we eat dessert after a meal? It&#39;s because we The perception of sweetness is at the tip of the tongue, and the perception of bitterness is at the back of the tongue, and then there are other areas in the middle, such as spicy food. Therefore, we can still eat something sweet after a meal because we can feel sweetness at the tip of the tongue at the earliest. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is also braised pork, which is the Maillard reaction. Isn&#39;t the Maillard color popular this year? Maillard is actually caramel color, which is what it turns into after the sugar is burned. Color, what happens between it and braised pork is the Maillard reaction. Why do we need to add sugar? When you make braised pork, you can educate your children about science. These knowledge points are closely related to life; and why do we have oleander powder? Poisonous? I explained its formula, and then what is the most poisonous part of it? Tree trunks, leaves and flowers are all poisonous. Finally, why are these women fighting in the play? These are the backward ideas of feudal society. Let’s talk about it finally. The awakening of women in our new era includes humanistic methods.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She believes that subject segmentation is actually unscientific because &quot;all knowledge is interlinked&quot; and is often lacking in the dissemination of knowledge. Not even one. She likes the title of &quot;Science Communication Figure&quot;, &quot;It&#39;s quite appropriate. Just like preaching, science is also a cognitive system.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She looks at everything around her with a comprehensive view of the universe and cherishes it. Curious, &quot;Actually, everything is learning. You may have thought it was entertainment before, but with a learning mentality, if you really understand the background, culture or meaning of TV series, movies and other cultural works, it is actually learning.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In her spare time during the Antarctic scientific expedition, Tang Limei also watched a few sporadic movies, including the literary film &quot;Sunset Trilogy&quot; series, which she also watched repeatedly. What attracts her is not the romantic encounter between the male and female protagonists, but the social topics that the two communicate and discuss from sunset to sunrise. &quot;In fact, the most attractive thing about it is its topic. It is not that two people are in love, they discuss They are all the destruction of society by developed countries, the infringement of weak countries, the garbage we produce now, the underlying logic of society, etc.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has also watched some of &quot;Celebrating More Than Years&quot; and she likes it. With time-travel elements, I am also planning to write some science fiction novels next, &quot;For example, two fishes (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;because we humans evolved from fish (&lt;/span>;), a story of pure love that has gone through five mass extinctions, nine evolutions, and then traveled through several lives. In this long evolution, &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; is set in the universe. It may be based on the hundreds of millions of years of biological evolution.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that she is in the conceptual stage, she is already very excited. &quot;It should be particularly enjoyable if I write it later. In fact, this is a process of creation. The meaning of life lies in creation. Only when you create something you love, will you feel happy and in a flow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2019, she participated in a training session at the Youth League School of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, and later became a member of the Youth Lecturers Group of the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League. Since then, she has frequently given lectures in colleges and universities. She noticed that the new generation of young people are increasingly concerned about spiritual values. &quot;Public welfare must be the trend in the future. There will definitely be more and more people engaged in charity and volunteer services among the post-2000 generation, because it may be difficult for them to make a rapid economic leap from their work, so they will look for other ways. To realize your own value, engage more in charity and manual work, that is, to help others and feel happiness from the process of serving others.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There will be more and more of these industries, like my daughter, What can you say to make her feel happy? It’s not that her mother went to her school and gave a speech. Everyone regarded me as an idol and worshiped me. This was a pressure for her; her happiness was similar to that once I took her to a friend&#39;s birthday party, and after she gave the butterfly she made with a twist stick to someone else, she felt sincerely happy because of the other person&#39;s gratitude.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first book has not yet been released, and it is non-stop. Tang Limei has already begun to imagine her future &quot;writing ambitions&quot;. &quot;If I publish one book every year, I can probably write 20 more in my life. I hope one or two of them will be popular science classics for teenagers.&quot; Through these words again and again. and written words. What she is committed to disseminating is not only scientific knowledge, but also &quot;the meaning of life.&quot; She hopes that her slightly tortuous but persevering experience can inspire young people and make those young faces in the audience understand, &quot;Everyone should have their own way out and live well.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吴慷仁，给自己拍拍手吧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261336]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/25/ZJCNUHvqqsswjIpk4Tq6AEUJT96BP6xETrXHQmgA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/ZJCNUHvqqsswjIpk4Tq6AEUJT96BP 6xETrXHQmgA. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Kangren (Visual China) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Newcomer Wu Kangren&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren is standing in the middle of the lobby of a hotel in Xiamen, dancing and talking with people. The companion said: &quot;Please be gentle and don&#39;t attract too much attention.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No one will pay attention to us. Everyone is living their own lives.&quot; He waved his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most watched Taiwanese actor at the moment, the favorite to win the Golden Horse Award this year, has long been able to get along with his fame calmly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first few years when he became famous, he avoided the public and social media, wore a mask when going out, and hated being stared at. By 2015, he left his agent to work independently. Just before he was about to win his first Golden Bell Award, Wu Kangren suddenly took off his mask. &quot;Wearing a mask is uncomfortable,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When someone looked at him, he looked back with a smile; when someone patted him, he waved his hand from a distance; when someone stared at him, he slowly changed his position to avoid it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I didn’t care much about what other people thought of me, I felt a lot less burdened.” Wu Kangren said, “I began to realize that the identity I originally cared about was just my career and an external label. . I want to get back my identity and my life. What I have to do at the moment is the most important, such as going out to buy things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Wu Kangren has starred in many word-of-mouth movies. Taiwanese dramas, from the early years of &quot;A Handful of Youth&quot; (2015), &quot;Narcotic Storm&quot; (2015), and &quot;The Distance Between Us and Evil&quot; (2019), to this year&#39;s &quot;Copycat&quot; and &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/lsUeNjPOXDad6Xuhj9oOrsYkYWA3xi4XUpRhHhER.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/lsUeNjPOXDad6Xuhj9oOrsYkYWA3xi4XUpRhHhER.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Anesthesia Storm (2015) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/JMp34TCWepLXusVDnaeFp4VgEQVA5mTkRV7GI3Xc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1546&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/25/JMp34TCWepLXusVDnaeFp4VgEQVA5mTkRV7GI3Xc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The distance between us and evil (2019) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /25/BPg5JnRngcNlpaDsl2IZ1i5Cg3Lvtzm9Rmamjvjq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2160&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/BPg5JnRngcNlpaDsl2IZ1i5Cg3Lvtz m9Rmamjvjq.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;259643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Copycat (2023) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Wu Kangren always says that no one knows him every time he comes to the mainland, and he mostly observes from the sidelines; even though the mainland media always give him this title repeatedly - &quot;The most powerful Chinese TV star!&quot; He should have been popular! &quot;But every time he came to the mainland in the past five years, he had a busy schedule, and everywhere he went there were crowds and cheers. In Xiamen, young people shouted to him: &quot;Gao Jiayue, praise, praise, praise!&quot; &quot;Gao Jiayue is his character in the new drama &quot;Lifetime&quot;, and his catchphrase is &quot;Zan Zan Zan&quot;. At the post-screening event of the movie &quot;Fudu Youth&quot;, many viewers expressed happily: Wu Kangren, I have liked you for many years, I hope you can win this year&#39;s Golden Horse Best Actor!&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fudu Youth&quot; is directed by Malaysian director Ong Lilian and stars Wu Kangren and Chen Chak Yao. It has won awards at many international film festivals. Wu Kangren won this year&#39;s First Youth Award Best Actor at the Film Festival.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He received the First trophy in Xiamen, took a group photo, and then held it halfway. He was also the Best Actor in this year&#39;s First Film Festival media selection. When he heard that there were also trophies for the venue selection, he shook with joy.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He cherishes every recognition he gets, whether it is an award or the favor of his seniors. This is why he often plays guest roles. : To repay a favor. He made a cameo appearance as a pervert who sexually harassed a female subordinate in the TV series &quot;Her and Her Her&quot;, but he couldn&#39;t find an actor for this disgusting role. Out of gratitude for the producer of the show who had taken care of him in the past, Wu Kangren took over the role. The original male lead of &quot;Copycat&quot; missed the appointment due to schedule, and the crew was at a standstill. They were in urgent need of a replacement who could be accepted by Netflix. It was Wu Kangren again. In order not to affect the follow-up film appointments, he rushed to work for 16 days in a row. He only sleeps two or three hours a day.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He thanked Chen Huiling, the director of &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; many times. &quot;(To the director) jokingly said that there was no opportunity to perform in &quot;Next Stop&quot; at that time, maybe now I was still serving plates in restaurants and stuff like that, but I actually meant it. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Wu Kangren starred in the idol drama &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; as Hua Takuya, the second male lead who silently protected the heroine for many years and finally let go. He created a chapter in the history of Taiwanese idol dramas Classic: With tears in his eyes, he suppressed the sadness rushing out of his chest, and said to the heroine with a smile: &quot;Why, I was the one who met you first, but you still chose to lead him six years ago and six years later. hand. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/UfGy4Qfh5w7K2VHjG4Qa5ctSc3ksZ3zcvRcMN3h6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;680&quot; height =&quot;1024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/UfGy4Qfh5w7K2VHjG4Qa5ctSc3ksZ3zcvRcMN3h6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Next Stop, Happiness (2009) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I watched it for the first time He was surprised when he was acting, how could someone crying be so touching. I asked director Chen Huiling, and the director said it was because he was acting with his life. &quot;said screenwriter Lu Shiyuan. Wu Kangren later became the leading actor in her works &quot;The Exit Office&quot; and &quot;The Distance Between Us and Evil&quot;. Both of these dramas brought Wu Kangren nominations for Best Actor at the Golden Bell Awards.&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In this way, Wu Kangren, who had just quit his job as a bartender, emerged with &quot;Hua Tuoye&quot;. At the age of 27, he encountered his favorite job: acting. &quot;After acting reaches a certain stage, it is no longer for me. A way to make money for a living. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; was the last peak of Taiwanese idol dramas. Since then, Taiwanese dramas, which have been popular in Asia for ten years, have been declining. What is mutually responsible for the decline of Taiwanese dramas is that mainland TV dramas and Korean dramas gradually occupied Taiwanese TV stations, and Taiwanese dramas that lost their audience also lost the funds of the TV stations. It was also at that time that the backbone of Taiwanese dramas and future stars, such as Ethan Ruan, Zhao Youting, Chen Bolin, Ariel Ariel, Chen Qiaoen, etc., all turned to the mainland Development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Newcomer Wu Kangren stayed in Taiwan and worked hard to act in his own way.&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Like a foreign worker&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starring &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; was won by Wu Kangren.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What he saw was the synopsis of the venture capital period. He liked it very much after reading it, so he met with Wang Lilin. The atmosphere of the meeting was harmonious, but there was no further discussion after that. Contact us.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next eight months, Wu Kangren finished filming two movies and was resting at home. One day he was staring at his cat and suddenly felt that filming in Taiwan was out of his comfort zone, and he wanted to change places. He thought of &quot;Fudu Youth&quot;, so he called the director and asked if you were still filming and if you didn&#39;t plan to find me.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The director also told me honestly: they do have other candidates. . But I feel that I am very sincere and can go to Malaysia a month earlier and the (remuneration) can be cheaper. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Wu Kangren, &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; is a rare opportunity. Nowadays, professional dramas are popular in Taiwan. He has portrayed etiquette masters, lawyers, prosecutors, etc. He has also tried many unconventional characters, For example, mamasang, habitual thieves who steal women&#39;s underwear, etc. This is how he trains himself.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/25/oFjvo5nnR54pP2w1ScDw66JDokygZzTeBkAo528W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/oFjvo5nnR54pP2w1ScDw66JDokygZzTe BkAo528W. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fudu Youth (2023) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fudu Youth&quot; is different. The people in the film have no career difficulties. They seem unconventional and marginal, but they actually exist in Malaysia. It tells the story of a pair of undocumented foreign workers. The brothers are living an ignoble existence in an old community in Fudu where foreign workers gather. The elder brother Abang (played by Wu Kangren) was born mute, and he works hard and accepts his fate. The younger brother Adi (played by Chen Zeyao) is unwilling to bow to fate. He only wants to make money and takes his brother with him. Leave this disgusting place.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Lilin is the producer of the movies &quot;Decibel Life&quot; and &quot;Lost Andy&quot;. When he was filming for &quot;Decibel Life&quot;, he observed that there were many problems in the Pudu community of Kuala Lumpur. Foreign workers, lonely elderly people, transgender people, etc. Three years later, he decided to shoot his first film with some unidentified people as the protagonists in the market of Fudu.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; Since &quot;Decibel Life&quot;, I have wanted to be close to these people, and I feel very strongly about them. &quot;Wang Lilin said.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie, from the director to the leading actors, followed the principle of &quot;really listening, seeing, and feeling.&quot; After Wu Kangren and Chen Zeyao worked in the market and learned sign language for about a month, the movie was released in Filming in Fudu has officially started.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fudu has a smell. The market where you work has the smell of fish, chicken and sweet fruits, and the enclosed building where you live has the smell of food, soap, sweat and Urine.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the film, there is a close-up scene of washing hands. Wu Kangren carefully rubs each fingernail. &quot;This is indeed an action I do every day at the end of the day, because the smell on my hands is so rich. &quot;Wu Kangren said, &quot;When I smoked, I smelled the smell of offal on my fingertips, so I thought, hey, I should wash it again. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The script gives branches, but the flesh and blood of the film depends on the actors themselves.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abang makes a living by killing chickens and moving goods, so Wu Kangren killed chickens that were 20 days old— —Although the director initially did not plan to shoot a scene of killing a chicken. Eggs can be found by poking the butt of a chicken, and foreign workers often eat the eggs raw. They wanted to give them to Wu Kangren several times, and Wu Kangren repeatedly said, &quot;Thank you, thank you, thank you.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Although the raw eggs were not eaten, Wu Kangren brought this detail into the movie: Abang, who came home from work, carried a bag of eggs and shared them with his neighbor and his daughter.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He wanted to let I am truly like a foreign worker in a rich city. Not only can I work, but I have also become black, thin and slovenly. &quot;When I first went there, I was like this now. I weighed more than 70 kilograms in vain. Don&#39;t spill the soup on me. appearance. &quot; He recalled, &quot;But when you really step into that market, you will find that everyone looks at you very differently, and you are out of place. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He imitated the state of foreign workers, unkempt, with sweat and animal blood on his body, and the look in his eyes was tired after repeating the action of killing chickens two hundred times a day. They collected money and handed over He had no energy to have more interactions with people.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was killing chickens while approaching Fudu. He smoked, ate, and chatted with the foreign workers, looking at the expired passports they carried with them, and listening to their He talked about having a girlfriend or quarreling with his wife. He observed rats and said that he had never seen rats that looked like they had been trained. They ran past in groups, clanking and clanking, and dispersed like Moses parting the sea when they saw people. Together again.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he felt that there were no more eyes sizing him up, he knew that he could play Abang.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From May to August 2022, Wu Kangren completed filming continuously In &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; and the Hong Kong movie &quot;May I Live Forever&quot;, after four months of starvation, a 1.78 meter man lost weight to 53 kilograms. He did not want to say how much weight he had lost, after all, &quot;if the film was not filmed well , Everyone thinks that you are just thin, what&#39;s not a big deal. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/hr6yc0q5ty8zpqtmsFemejmyfhtcgmvbb XT .jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 640 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/hr6yc0q55ty8zpqtmsfemejmyf Htcgmvbxt.jpg &quot;data-key = &quot;259640&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; I hope that people will last long (2023) &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the film enters the end, Abang does not eat or drink in prison, and begged to die. Wu Kangren also fasts to make himself slumped. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; He said it was easy to fast, just to say that the skin was broken, white and smooth. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In the past few years, Wu Kangren&#39;s weight change curve of the weight and thinness of the show is a series of &quot;W&quot;, in 30 kg When the gap between the gap. When the original &quot;termites&quot; (2016) were lowered, he was a bit optimistic. Thinking of the physical change first, he could observe the change of psychology. The unexpected effect. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Before being an actor, he bleed and sweat on the construction site and got paid, so he firmly believed that he would return to the cup on the back kitchen. The same is clean, and then it even turned into his belief: I, Wu Kangren, I saw it for you on the face, as in private. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is also the same. No one knows what this acting can be obtained, but he wants to know; he tried, so he knew the power of appearance changes. &quot;I am quite glad to do this and have a lot of help to me.&quot; He said, &quot;This is irreplaceable, it is self -practice.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; dumb &lt;/strong>; &lt;/ H4>; &lt;p>; When &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; killed the youth, the crew sent Wu Kangren a cake, and he started crying when he saw the cake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I can finally eat!&quot; He said that he was crying with tears, &quot;I went to eat chicken the next day!&quot; Once again, Wu Kuangren couldn&#39;t easily solve it with a joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Abang&#39;s death penalty, the prison arranged him to meet with the mage to make a final talk. In this play, the director completely played &quot;True Listening and True True&quot;: there are only the word &quot;complaints&quot; in Wu Kuangren&#39;s script, without lines; the mage is a real monk, who has opened a photo of the Mage for more than 30 years for the death prisoner. There is no script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wu Kangren and the director have dedicated more than thirty times to try to clarify why Abang has such a strong reaction to release himself in such a situation. &quot;We can imagine that he finally has a forceful display, but I didn&#39;t understand where this power base was before.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/25/pnousbga6pnrlpqfuxmeoj692wqpfd4yaarsu6is.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height =&quot; 640 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/ Medias/Image/23/11/ 25/PNOUSBGA6PNRLPQFUXMEOJ692WQPFD4YAARSU6IS.JPG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 259641 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Fudu Youth (2023) &lt;span s s Tyle = &quot;color: # AAA; &quot;>; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Due to the long preparation cycle and shooting in the order of time, the actor has enough time to integrate into the role, so when Wu Kuangren heard Master Kaishi said&quot; live well &quot; Suddenly, Abon was sorrowful. &quot;It&#39;s the hardest for him to live well. We seemingly simple things are extravagant for them. So we must start from this sentence.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Abang and Adi cannot rent The house often wakes up from the dream late at night and evades the inspection; you cannot open an account in the bank, and work money in a rusty biscuit box; you can&#39;t buy a motorcycle if you can&#39;t get a driver&#39;s license, you can only take a bus or walk everywhere. Without their identities, they can only do workers in Fudu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Abang once touched love, but that was fleeting; he thought that he could be overturned by fate with his brother in Fudu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But they also have a happy moment. Abon, Adi and the transgender sister Money depended on each other -in Malaysia, the transgender people are another sense without identity -they eat together and dance together. The three people knocked on their heads on the dining table, and they were so painful and laughing. This is Wu Kangren&#39;s favorite play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我觉得最珍贵的就是生活中的笑容。整个戏，他们笑容很少，那些生活的理所当然对他们来说太过严苛。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终， In the face of Kai Shi Master, Abang complained: I am always thinking, why I was born, I had no home, and I didn&#39;t even have a parent. I could only look at it from a distance. I am jealous of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I want to be the same. But I can&#39;t! Why do this? I want to speak, I want to be loved, but I have nothing. You call me not to give up, continue to live. I can&#39;t. I must always be careful, alert, hide, and escape. This is unfair, what I did wrong. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; My life is terrible, I want to change my life, but Impossible. I have no future. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; These complaints are completed in sign language and expression. Those echoes that were carefully observed around, the echo of the wrist iron chain on the table, and the tears that had been turned in the eye socket for a long time, all of them made this silent complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Don&#39;t preach to me, I have no identity.&quot; Abang pointed to the code on his prison uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Master Kaishi suddenly held Abang&#39;s hand. Abang calmed down, tears fell, and he sobbing a difficult syllable: &quot;I want to die, I want to die, I think ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He looked around and found that no one could understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Abang is dumb, which is a coupling of fate. &quot;A group of people without identity, like dumb, will not change even if they speak.&quot; Wu Kangren said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Zeyao, who played his brother, later saw this silent complaint on the screen, and was shocked and hurt. &quot;It turned out that Abang thought so, it turned out that he had always felt like a shadow. I couldn&#39;t help you with you Say too much inner feelings, because my heart is really painful. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Brother&#39;s farewell to that scene, Chen Zeyao instinctively expressed his emotions to his brother in sign language. &quot;I&#39;m crying, and forgot to mystery. Later, I found that everyone can feel it without talking about the lines.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;Abang, next time, I said next time, I would like to protect you.&quot; Adi said. Twenty years ago, the stray Abon and Adi met on the street and became brothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Wang Lilin, the &quot;Fugu Youth&quot; presenting today has achieved his expectations. &quot;I want to talk about people&#39;s emotions in the context of Fudu foreign workers. In such a cruel and oppressed society, the precious warmth and goodwill between people.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; What are the expectations of &quot;Fudu Youth&quot;? &quot;We asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Don&#39;t lose money, they are so hard to shoot a film.&quot; He answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The next day, Wu Kangren sent a social media: &quot;We did a great thing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/ CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/25/1MJ220voe9o4Tyiqivik3kr0r0ye1alckh7wtsqflg.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 686 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/25/1mj220voe9o4tyqivik3kr0ye1alckh7wtsqflg.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259642 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Wu Kuangren&#39;s personal social media account/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Clap &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In 2016, Wu Kuangren relied on&quot; A Blue &quot; The corner of &quot;Guo Yan&quot; won the Golden Bell Award for Best Actor. This is one of his most successful characters. He is mixed with the cynical sense of youth and vicissitudes of the life and death of war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His award -winning speech seems to be pleading: pleading for actors more resources, and begging for TV stations to develop more different types of dramas. &quot;They (actors) are waiting, as before, waiting for me to choose me like Cao Ruiyuan&#39;s eyes, we need a little more resources to help us. Maybe we are not the most talented, but we can always be the most. The one who works hard. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/6cdqyotwzk1gvljxjl3igl84qzobu9i37.jpg &quot;border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;673&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/6cdqyotwzsx1gvljxjl3igl84QZOBU9I37.JPG&quot; Data-key = &quot;259645&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt; p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; A young (2015) &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;p>; Relying on government subsidies and government subsidies and Later, the capitalization of the streaming media platform, Taiwanese dramas have been new in the past few years. &quot;A Blue&quot; and the type drama &quot;Outbound Office&quot; and &quot;Anesthesia Storm&quot; around 2015 were regarded as the first new trend. After 2019, the episodes represented by &quot;The distance between us to evil&quot; and concerned about social issues marked that the Taiwanese drama basically spent the low valley period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the above -mentioned Taiwanese dramas, Wu Kuangren all picked up the beam. From idol dramas to realism, his acting career has overlap with the ups and downs and changes in the 15 years of platform dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In terms of honesty, I would become famous because Taiwan was very lacking (filming) at that time. Taiwanese actors were not much at my age.&quot; He said in an interview with &quot;Taiwan Scales&quot; at the end of 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When entering the industry, he believes that he is not good in appearance and qualifications, but &quot;effort is more important than talent.&quot; When he was doing wine insurance, he would not speak English. After finishing work in the early morning, he went to the Eslite Bookstore, which was opened overnight. Many years later, the media went to interview the owner of the bar, and the other party used &quot;life to hang life&quot; to describe Wu Kangren: to work hard for one thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has experienced a negative stage. He knew what he was doing, he paid 200 %, and he was strict with himself, and asked the people around him to work as hard as him. &quot;I used to be quite aggressive at work, so there will be rumors that Wu Kangren is difficult to engage. I only slowly realized in the past two years. This is a team work.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; But because Wu Kuangren always emphasizes efforts, It is often said that they are not talented, and few people talk about his talent as an actor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has beautiful eyes, and his eyebrows are affectionate, so he is good at performing the explosive moment of complex emotions; he is long than observation, and he describes many details of the old districts of Fudu. Although he is daily and serious, standing on the stage and in front of the camera, he has a lot of words and humor, and his expression and physical movements are rich. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He is confident that he can persist in acting, yearn for a good actor like Li Xuejian, but not optimistic about the actor&#39;s career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I don&#39;t think I have always had a play, I want to contact a lot of possibilities earlier and faster. It may not be possible to perform a film in the future, and strive to strive for fate.&quot; He thought for a while, &quot;You won&#39;t see&quot; Fugu Youth &quot;in five years. I have entered the industry for 15 years, and I saw&quot; Fudu Youth &quot;.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; This is then It was why he tried a variety of unconventional characters after 2015. He wanted to know how much possibilities he had, and how to improve the performance. He went to the training class to practice vocal skills; he filmed 5 plays in 2022, and he was very solid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Perhaps because there is no agent, the film resources that Wu Kangren can come into contact with is limited. He has expressed his love for mainland art films several times, and admits that he has respected to the mainland to act in the mainland. &quot;Before you go, you have to prepare for it, not to make money.&quot; Without the agent, Wu Kangren&#39;s work decision was made by himself. After gone through a panic, he is now used to this way of working: he knows what is important, and he only needs to play a good show. He can take care of himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He yearn for Hong Kong actors in the golden age of Hong Kong films, such as Liang Jiahui, Liang Chaowei, and Andy Lau. &quot;Each actor has accumulated hundreds of dramas and leaves his own position.&quot; >; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/3ps1fpdk7zj6bsxs9jb3qbmfyu7ayjgorhx.jpg&quot; width = &quot;960&quot; width = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;960 &quot;Height =&quot; 1440 &quot;data-SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/3ps1fpdk7zj6bsxs9jb3qbmfyu7ayjgorhx.jpg =&quot; 259647 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; Co &quot;Co Lor: #999; Text- Align: center; &quot;>; The year of life (2023) &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The title of&quot; Life &quot;is Gao Jiayue&#39;s life summary. Gao Jiayue&#39;s coating was changed and wrote on the back of the &quot;testament&quot;: in the lifetime, it is good to grow so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the age of 14, Wu Kangren started working. The first part was to welded the box naked eyes. After the work, it was white, thinking that he was going to be blind. Since then, he has worked more than 50 workers, shuttled between the 20 -story scaffolding without a helmet and a safe net, and washed dishes in a variety of restaurants to entertain guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Twenty years later, Wu Kangren was asked what he wanted to say to himself, and he replied: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;15 -year -old Wu Kuangren, what you were afraid of at that time, Nothing happened, because you didn&#39;t learn bad, and now you take good care of your mother. Your decision at that time is right. P>; He raised his hand over his head and patted himself for himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨林超民：研究历史才能看到未来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261332]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-26 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;November 2, 2023, Lin Chaomin at the Wu Ma Yao Humanology Museum at Yunnan University. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/8a5bb3db.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height = &quot;811&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/8A5BB3E3DB.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;259633&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;colorRor : #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On November 2, 2023, Lin Chaomin was at Wu Ma Yao Humanology Museum at Yunnan University. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h5>; Doctor file &lt;/h5>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai Stkaiti; &quot;>; Lin Chaomin, the first doctor of Chinese national history. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1944 in Dali, Yunnan, and grew up in Tengchong, Yunnan. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1962, admitted to the history of Yunnan University. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1981, a master&#39;s degree in history. Stay as a assistant to Professor Fang Guoyu. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1985, obtained a doctorate in history. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Director of the Institute of Film and Television Anthropology, Vice President and Inspector of Yunnan University. Director of the Chinese History Society, the chairman of the Yunnan History Society, the chairman of the Yunnan State Society, the vice chairman of the Chinese National Society, the vice chairman of the Chinese National History Society, and the vice chairman of the Chinese Han National Research Society. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lin Chaomin after retirement, living in a family member near Yunnan University, here is close to Cuhu Lake. Siberia flies the red mouth of winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1962, Lin Chaomin was admitted to Yunnan University History. At that time, the history of the history department gathered a lot of scholars such as Fang Guoyu, Jiang Yingliang, Yang Yan, Li Yan, and founded the first major in Chinese national history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For the first time, it is in a systematic contact with the major of national history. Collection of &quot;sin&quot; in the works. There are only 6 borrowing cards in Yunda&#39;s students, but Lin Chaomin, who shoulders the &quot;task&quot;, took 20 borrowing cards, and picked up Fang Guoyu&#39;s theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Results, &quot;After watching it for a long time, I didn&#39;t find that Mr. Fang reactionary, but I am interested in the research of national history.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After various reasons, this session has been sent to the farm to receive re-education after 6 years of undergraduate students who are full of expectations in the future. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In May 1970, Lin Chaomin was assigned to the West Shuangbanna Province Erhai Tea Factory as a worker, and then taught at Erhai No.1 Middle School. In the meantime, he was appreciated by Ren Jiyu, a professor of the Department of Philosophy of Peking University for a discussion of the articles of Confucius thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1978, Lin Chaomin was 33 years old. He heard that he could take the postgraduate entrance examination. He thought of the Chinese national history of Yunnan University. But compared to the exam, the more difficult is to let the middle school be released. &quot;I went to the then county party secretary Yan Xiangkan. He was the Brown ethnic group. Said, &quot;I hope you want to study the history of our Brown people &#39;.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Some people have evaluated Lin Chaomin&#39;s &quot;opening of the atmosphere&quot;, in 1985, he passed the defense by answering the defense Become the first doctorate in the history of Chinese nation. One of the instructor Jiang Yingliang&#39;s plan for him is &quot;it is expected to make creative results in the study of national history. He hopes that he will not let him act as an administrative work and affect his research and teaching.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, after the doctoral graduation, he was immediately appointed as the deputy director of the Department of History of Yunnan University, and later served as Deputy President Yunda. As a manager, he faced the question of where the liberal arts micro -historical department went from. At that time, in the context of difficult enrollment, distribution, and creation, many teachers called the history department &quot;shit pits&quot; and shouted to jump out of &quot;shit shit. pit&quot;. In terms of office, Lin Chaomin organized the application of historical base classes, and set up a major of anthropology, social work, etc., and established the first Asian Institute of Film and Television Anthropology to allow this university located in the southwest side to seize the opportunity in the disciplinary system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lin Chaomin after retirement can also spend time on research. In recent years, he has paid particular attention to the overallness of Chinese history. On October 28, 2023, he organized a seminar on Fang Guoyu&#39;s historical ideas to commemorate the 60th anniversary of the theory of &quot;On the History of Chinese History&quot; and commemorate the 120th anniversary of Fang Guoyu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 2, 2023, in the campus of Yunnan University, Lin Chaomin accepted an exclusive interview with the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Dr. Lin Chaomin&#39;s thesis defense scene, taken in 1985. (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/25/7092cf4a07.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 571 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/ms/medias/23/11/25/ 7092cf4a07.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259634 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Dr. Lin Chaomin&#39;s thesis defense scene was taken in 1985. (Interviewee/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;No problem&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style Gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; What kind of environment do you grow up? Is history a major you longed for from an early age? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I was born in Dali and grew up in Tengchong. In 1942, the Japanese occupied Tengchong. My parents fled to Dali. I was born there. After the Chinese Expeditionary Force recovered Tengchong in September 1944, we came back from Dali again. At that time, due to the Anti -Japanese War, Teng Chong had a rubble in the city, and there was almost no standing house in the city. The central elementary school we read is the temple. Previously, the Japanese used it as the headquarters. Because of the strong architecture, it was stored. There were still many bullet holes on the wall pillars inside. I studied in the sixth grade school to repair the sports field, and I also dug a lot of bullet shells and bayonets for three -eighth rifle. I didn&#39;t leave Tengchong until I graduated from the third year of high school in 1962. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; When I don&#39;t know what to do, I just know to read a good book. At that time, my mother subscribed to different magazines for our brothers and sisters every age. For example, when I was very young, I watched &quot;Children&quot;, &quot;Red Scarf&quot;, &quot;Middle School Students&quot; and &quot;Juvenile Literature&quot;. There is a library. At that time, I read Lin Hansda&#39;s &quot;New Zhou Story of the Eastern Zhou Dynasty&quot;, &quot;New Editor of the Han Story&quot;, &quot;The Story of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;The Tai Shi who is not afraid of death&quot;, etc., and has a strong interest in history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; History of Yunnan University? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; My father is a technician engaged in water conservancy projects, participating in the construction Road, ditch, and reservoirs often tell me that New China has been established. The motherland needs to be industrialized. You have to go to the study of engineering and work for modernization. My mother is a middle school teacher. In 1957, many liberal arts teachers were wronged by Tengchong No. 1 Middle School. My mother said that she could not learn arts and it was easy to make mistakes. Therefore, I always wanted to study science and engineering. Later, my mother also advocated that I was studying medicine because it was useful at any time. In high school, we were good in all subjects, but it was more prominent in liberal arts. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1962, I was in high school. After graduating from the last semester, the school divided us into three groups according to our subjects. The other group is medical and agricultural department, and the other is liberal arts. My family decided to choose a science and engineering department, but in the specific division, I was assigned to the liberal arts group under the arrangement of the class teacher, Chinese teacher, and historical teacher. At that time, I went to Baoshan, Yunnan to take the college entrance examination, and issued a volunteer book before the exam. Everyone can fill in five volunteers, and I have filled the historical departments of Peking University, Renmin University of China, Nanjing University, Fudan and Yunda, and was later accepted to Yunda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Is the history department &quot;five years&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Our historical department has only one major in history, recruiting 32 people. Only one -half of the previous session, one third of the previous session. The curriculum arrangements are basic courses in the first, second, and third grades, such as ancient literature, politics, foreign languages, Chinese and foreign history, etc. The fourth grade is divided into &quot;specialization (group)&quot;. When I was studying, there were three specialized groups: Chinese national history, ancient Chinese economy history, and modern Chinese economic history. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, he did not study well at the time. Since 1958, there have been more labor education in universities. The central government has formulated sixty articles in Gao Education, emphasizing teaching. At that time, the Ministry of Education stipulated that the student had to take a labor class in a school year, which was five weeks, and it could not exceed five weeks. But in fact, the labor of each school year is more than five weeks. At that time, there were three farms in Yunnan University, breeding rice, buds, wheat, vegetables, and Apple Parks, pig farms. In addition, there are many public welfare labor, such as planting trees on the mountain. When farmers are busy, they support the spring plowing and autumn harvest. Later, Kunming repairing the train station and calling us to help. By 1961, after investigating the Ministry of Higher Education, I felt that students had to do labor and go to school. In less than 4 years, they were less than much to learn. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Mr.? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When I was in college, Mr. Fang undertook the compilation of the southwest part of the national task of China. He only brought graduate students. The national history is a high -grade professional course. The fourth grade is only taught by Mr. You Zhong and Mr. Mu Qin. On April 20, 1963, Mr. Fang gave a speech at the school &quot;On the overallness of the development of Chinese history&quot;. I first met him for the first time, but because he was a Lijiang, the Naxi people, the accent was very heavy, and he didn&#39;t understand much. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But I was impressed after reading the article. In September 1966, I was studying in the senior year because the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; stopped class. The school began to criticize a large criticism and criticize reactionary academic authority. At that time, Yunda established a large critical team. There was a Chinese group and a historical group below. The historical group mainly criticized the &quot;three big mountains&quot; of the historical department. Jiang Yingliang, who represents &quot;bureaucratic capitalism, once served as the county head in the car, is now Jinghong), and the third is Yang Yan, the&quot; representative &quot;imperialist (representative of Lyon University in France). I have five or six classmates in the historical group. We have 20 borrowing cards in the critical team, and we can enter the library to check the books and read books. At this time, I found all Mr. Fang&#39;s discussion and read it again. His &quot;Inspection of Western Yunnan&quot; told him to go to Aya Mountain in Lincang to do field inspections. Very good, I didn&#39;t find any problems. I didn&#39;t write an article that criticized Mr. Fang. Instead, he has learned the social history of the frontier, the ethnic minority customs and customs, and feel that his &quot;On the Plateralness of the Development of Chinese History&quot; is a good article to maintain the unity of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Fang Guoyu (first from the left) in guiding Lin Chaoyong (second from left), in the study of Professor Fang Guoyu in March 1973. (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http:/ /Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/e4fc9790F7.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 837 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/25/e4fc9790f7.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259635 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; 1) Instructing Lin Chaoyang (second from left) to take the study of Professor Fang Guoyu in March 1973. (Interviewee/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;There are too few national history of the country&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strongGG >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Students of the History of Yunda before, where do you work after graduation? Why did you go to the tea factory at the end? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Many of my seniors go to college as teachers. The course has a large demand for employment. All students from modern history have been distributed to the General Political Department of the PLA. In addition, there are many people who go to the Ministry of Philosophy and Social Sciences of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (now the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences). At that time, Yunda&#39;s national history was the first in the country. The Ministry of Philosophy and Social Sciences studied the history of the Dai people, the history of Yi, the history of the Bai, and the history of the Naxi ethnic group. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It should be aore to graduate in July 1967, but until October 1968, our group of college students except agriculture and medicine. Outside of majors, all were arranged to go to the farm for re -education and labor exercise. The distribution did not begin in April 1970. At that time, it was stipulated that college students should achieve &quot;four faces&quot;, facing grassroots, rural areas, industrial and mining, and facing the frontiers. During the distribution, no one was willing to go to Xishuangbanna. I have read Mr. Fang&#39;s &quot;Inspection of the West of Yunnan&quot;, Mr. Jiang Yingliang&#39;s &quot;Economic Life of Economic Life&quot; and &quot;Culture of Life Culture&quot;. Actively sign up to Xishuangbanna. In May 1970, when I arrived at Erhai County, Xishuangbanna, I was assigned to the Erhai Tea Factory as a worker. In 1972, Erhai No.1 Middle School founded a high school and needed high school teachers, but the factory did not let it go. It was not until 1973 that I tune me as a history and Chinese teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; I heard you are During the Erhai Tea Factory, he was appreciated by Professor Ren Jiyue of Peking University? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I work for 8 hours a day in the tea factory, and other times are their own. When I was in college, I was very interested in the history of Chinese thought. I read Houwai&#39;s &quot;The History of Chinese Thought&quot;, Zhao Jibin&#39;s &quot;New Exploration of the Analects of Confucius&quot;, Guo Moruo&#39;s &quot;Ten Critical Books&quot;, etc. I took notes. When I went to Erhai, I brought a &quot;Four Books&quot;. I wrote an article about Confucius&#39; thoughts in my spare time. Professor Li Yan in the department asked him to enlighten him. He handed the article to an expert in ancient Chinese thought, Professor Zhang Deguang, and Mr. Zhang recommended it to Ren Jiyu. Mr. Ren gave me a letter saying that in the remote place in Xishuangbanna, I could insist on studying Confucius, and it was not easy to write such an article, but he also proposed that my article was not enough to criticize Confucius. Mr. Ren also sent me a copy of his editor -in -chief of the History of Chinese Philosophy. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1972, Mr. Ren wrote to me and told me to recruit 10 graduate students in the history of Chinese philosophy. I hope I can prepare, I was admitted to his graduate student. So I learned foreign languages ​​every day, systematically studied the history of Chinese philosophy, and often wrote to him to ask him. However, Zhang Tiesheng had a white volume incident. Mr. Ren wrote to tell me that the postgraduate enrollment work stopped. In the future, the recruitment and research students must also implement the method of recommending workers, peasants and soldiers. I have no chance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kaiti_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; until 1978 resumed recovery When graduate enrollment, you can finally take the graduate student, but why didn&#39;t you contact Professor Ren Jiyue anymore? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I also want to write to Mr. Ren and do a philosophical history research with him, but at the time in Xishuangbanna, my thoughts happened. A lot of changes, I live in the Dai, Ladu, Brown, and Hani people. I found that I did not know their history. Later, I became a middle school teacher. Some students asked me about the question of ethnic minorities. At this time, I remembered the research of Mr. Fang Guoyu and Mr. Jiang Yingliang&#39;s ethnic minorities. I think that there are more philosophical history in the country and too few national history. They are unpopular. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In the 1960s, Lin Chaomin planted vegetables on the PLA farm. (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/cms /medias/image/23/11/25/4cfe138de1.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 802 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/medias/image/23 /11/25/4cfe138de1.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259636 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; In the 1960s, Lin Chaoming planted vegetables in the PLA farm. . (Interviewee/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Learn from the height of the unity of multi-nation&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are you impressed when you do research? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The first lesson of the graduate student, Fang brought me to the library The classical library of classical library, let me read, report a week later, I did not understand at that time. When the report was reported, he asked me how much you read. I said that I read a few books. He said that you can read a book like this. I read this book, but read a bookshelf and a bookshelf. He asked me to start with the directory, read &quot;The Siku All the Summary of the Summary&quot;, Yu Jiaxi&#39;s &quot;Siku Sub -Syllarsia&quot;, and Zhang Zhidong&#39;s &quot;Book Answers&quot; and other books. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Mr. Fang never criticized me directly. When I read the master&#39;s degree, I wrote some small articles in Yunnan Daily. You have not read enough now, and you are a small carving technique on the Yunnan Daily. Your task is to build a high -rise building. You must lay the foundation well, read more books, read well, and make creative results in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Is Mr. Fang asked you to publish papers? What are the requirements for reading and the number of words of graduation? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Read a good book. He said that any article cannot be fried in cold rice. Don&#39;t write articles without new ideas. He said that some people are not studying carefully, and are busy writing articles and anxious to publish articles. Many articles are fry back the pot. This is not possible! Doctoral students do not use the pigs raised by others to make steamed meat, thousands of meats, and braised pork. Instead, they have to cultivate new pig species themselves, create and invent. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Later, I summarized the doctor of reading into five &quot;independence&quot;. It is independent personality, independent thoughts, unique insights, unique paths, and uniqueness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; I noticed in recent years Come on you to mention the unified history on many occasions. Is this from Mr. Fang&#39;s inheritance? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Lin Chaomin: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; All the research of Mr. Fang is related to national unity and national unity. In 1939, Mr. Fang wrote &quot;Ren and Bai Zi&quot; and published in the &quot;Yishi News&quot;, criticizing the fallacy of the British and the French people as an independent country established by the Dai people. In order to verify historical issues, but to maintain national unity and national unity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1963年，方先生发表《论中国历史发展的整体性》，开始讲中国历史发展的整体性。文章针对国内外一些学者将中国历史当作单一的汉族历史，将非汉族的中国少数民族的历史排除在中国历史之外的荒谬言论，指出中国历史发展始终是一个整体，历史和现实、中原和边疆、汉族和少数民族、中华民族等都是一个整体。中国历史，指的是生活在这块土地上各族人民的历史，就应该包括他们的全部历史，不能“变更伸缩”。中国历史是有其整体性的，在整体之内，不管出现几个政权，不管政治如何不统一，并没有破裂了整体，应当以中国整体为历史的范围，不能以历代王朝疆域为历史的范围. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来我协助方先生讲授云南地方史，他在《云南地方史讲义》的导论里重申这个观点。到了1983年云南大学70周年校庆的时候，他又指导我写了一篇文章，叫《大理三十七部盟誓碑有关的几个问题》，也通过这块碑，讲中国历史的统一问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从国际上看，一些历史学者或许对大一统的历史观还持有一些其他观点，该怎么理解边疆问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;林超民：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;边疆问题比较复杂。中国以前没有边疆问题，只有华夏和四夷之间的关系，就是华夏与四夷“五方共和”“天下一统，华夷无间”，从中央到地方都是一个整体。即便是分裂期，无论汉族还是少数民族，都追求“天下统一”，都把自己建立的王朝视为中华正统；其所建立的王朝制度，也均以继承秦汉制度为基础，并未改变整体的经济、政治、文化结构。因为各民族长期共同生活，早已形成互补又合一的生产生活方式，孕育极具包容性和吸纳性的中华文明，使得中华民族形成以“共同性”为基础的强大内聚力。即便是在分裂时期，这种生产生活方式没有变，政治制度没有变，整体意识也没有变，文化一直在延续。这在国家观和民族观上就表现为“大一统”的国家观和中华民族整体意识。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近代边疆研究开始兴起是因为西方殖民主义的东来。首先是政治上的“边疆”。历史上很多地方分分合合，是一个发展的过程，比如云南在唐朝是南诏，贞元十年（794）建立云南安抚司，由剑南节度使担任云南安抚使统领。是一个自治的地方政权。大理国也是自治的地方政权，1253年蒙古平定大理，1274年元朝在云南建立行省。元朝还建立过缅甸行省，后来又划归云南行省管理。是云南行省统属的土司地。新中国成立后，1961年，中缅边界正式划定。中国在腾冲的边界上竖立中华人民共和国第一号界碑。表示我们正式尊重国际法上的边界划定，也就是国际法上的边疆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;还有文化的边疆，比如说中国的佤族和缅北佤邦的文化有很多相近的地方，这时虽然有政治上的边界，但其实大家文化同脉，历史同根，是命运共同体。所以说从国内来讲是中华民族的整体性，从国外来讲应该视作共同体。在国内我们维护中国的整体性、维护国家统一。在国际上我们构建人类命运共同体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;林超民的博士论文题为《安西北庭都护府与唐代西部边疆》，摄于1985年。（受访者/图)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/a4b5f7b5d0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1472&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/a4b5f7b5d0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259637&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林超民的博士论文题为《安西北庭都护府与唐代西部边疆》，摄于1985年。 （受访者/图)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“向前发展，必须问道过去”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985年5月底通过博士答辩后，你就成为云大历史系副主任，在当时文科式微的背景下，你面临着哪些难题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;林超民：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时文理科的基础学科普遍存在招生难、分配难、经费难等问题，历史学也不例外，当时各个系要创收，像经济系、外语系的老师可以去讲课、辅导，挣外快，虽然工资一样，但他们的外快是我们的好几倍，那时就有历史专业的老师说，要跳出“屎pit&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;学生思想也不太稳定，于是我提出了一个观点，历史看似无用，但是无用之用就是大用。我跟学生说，教室的桌椅、板凳、门窗、电灯都是有用的，但是看不见、没有用的是这个空间，但是如果没有这个空间，桌椅、板凳、电灯都无处安放。历史就是人类的时间和空间。看不到，摸不着，但时时刻刻离不开，随时随地有大用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来教育部提出要在文、史、哲三大门类各建设10个“基地”，文件下达学校的时候，距离申报截止日期不到5天，我夜以继日填写申报表，在评审会上陈述，云南大学是一个边疆大学，很多方面比不上北大、复旦等，但是云大研究边疆问题、民族问题是全国独一无二的，关系到国家统一、民族团结，是其他学校不可替代的。云大历史系的特点就是边疆、民族，任何一个学校都无法替代。就这样，1987年，云大成为了10个基地之一。基地班给云大带来了新的机遇，国家每年给基地班投入30万建设经费，并且有一半以上的学生可以保送读研，毕业后的就业也不再是问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;后来你还先后成立民族学和社会工作专业，中间有遇到困难吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;林超民：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1986年，我提出云大要成立民族学专业，校领导很支持，报到云南省教委，教委说民族学由民族学院办，一个省不宜有两个民族学专业，最后没有办成。后来我又重新写报告，申请创办人类学专业，1987年国家教委批准云大开办人类学专业。我们是全国大学的第二个人类学专业，第一个的是厦门大学，第一个有人类学系的是中山大学。 1988年我们招收第一批本科生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1988年人类学专业办成后，我就开始筹划申报社会学专业。 1939年7月吴文藻就在云大创办社会学系，到1954年，社会学系被撤销了，当时的系主任是杨堃先生。 1984年、1986年，我两次到中国社科院拜访杨先生，杨先生反复对我说，撤销社会学系是不对的，应该尽快恢复重建。我把他的意见带回学校，向领导汇报，虽然被置之不理，但他的话我时时记在心里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1990年10月，我到美国访学，知道社会工作专业是社会十分需要的专业，社会发展会带来许多问题，需要专门的社会工作者来应对解决。无论穷人富人都有社会问题。回国时经过香港，我到一些大学了解社会工作专业，他们社会工作的一个特色是帮助弱势群体，帮助穷人、失业者、残障人士等，回来后我就跟学校说，社会学专业不能办我们就办社会工作专业。当时学校教务处的大多数人不知道什么是社会工作，我就一遍遍解释，学校同意后报到省教委、国家教委，很快就被批准了，我们是继南开大学、中国青年政治学院后的第三家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你有没有给当下大学生，特别是历史系学生的一些建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;林超民：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在的学术氛围太功利，我常常跟学生讲，如果想发财，就去经商，求名就去当官，做学问就要乐于清贫，淡泊名利，甘居边缘，埋头问学、独立思考、独自创新。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;人类在创造历史，所以必须书写历史、记录历史。研究历史我们才能看到未来。历史是人类的记忆，人、社会和国家都不能没有记忆，一个民族没有记忆就没有灵魂，也就看不到方向。历史是无用之用，但它的用是大用。就像空气，我们看不见摸不到，但一刻也离不开。我们研究历史，目的是为了开创未来。向前发展，只有问道历史；借鉴历史，才能创造未来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生黄晓颖对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[徐卓媛：因为喜爱去攀登]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261243]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-26 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/jlh4uLkDEV5I0wjzaQur3Al4838vctWvTfIIMEXL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/jlh4uLkDEV5I0wjzaQur3Al4838vctWvTfIIMEXL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（图片由荣耀100系列拍摄/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月中旬，经过近10个小时的艰难攀登，长沙女孩徐卓媛成功登顶珠穆朗玛峰。 Four years ago, she shouted &quot;I want to board Mount Everest&quot; in a variety show. Four years later, at the age of 16, she fulfilled her promise with practical actions and became the youngest in China who reached the top of Mount Everest from the southern slope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受父亲的影响，徐卓媛很小的时候就开始接触攀登。 When she was 4 years old, her parents took her to climb the Simuashan, and unexpectedly found that she had a good adaptation to Gao. At the age of 12, she traveled to Tibet with her father Xu Jianglei. At that time, she regretted that she did not see Everest&#39;s sunrise due to the weather. On the way back, she climbed the Dafeng of Simuashan with her father. &quot;It was the first time that I really climbed a snowy mountain.&quot; Since then, the desire to climb the peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;登山是项仰赖运气的极限运动，接触攀登以来，她的情绪更稳定了，“攀登途中常常有人遇难，现在对我来说生死面前无大事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六个月前的这次攀登是徐卓媛首次挑战珠穆朗玛峰。启程之前，她往背包里装了父亲徐江雷当年登顶珠峰的手套，希冀作为“一种传承”。 2007年，徐江雷登顶珠峰，成为湖南省登顶珠峰第一人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐卓媛记得自己快接近峰顶的时候，身旁的夏尔巴向导提醒她快到顶了，天还没有亮，“我脑海里唯一的念头是一定要看到珠峰顶上的日出，父亲的登顶照一直让我印象深刻，照片里的他意气风发，迎着太阳笑得很灿烂，我可以感受到他对雪山的热爱。那张照片至今还在我家里摆着。”幸运的是，几乎在她登顶的那一刻，太阳出来了。现在，父亲的照片旁并排放着她登顶的照片，身后是初升的太阳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我要登珠峰”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;12岁时，你在一档节目中说“我要登珠峰”，当时是怎么想的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从小到大，珠峰对我来说一直有着不一样的意义。 12岁小学毕业的那个夏天，我爸爸带着我进藏，但当时由于天气原因没看到日照金山。后来我和爸爸就一起去爬了四姑娘山的大峰，这是我第一次真正意义上攀登一座雪山。当时山上下雪了，作为南方人的我觉得很新奇，从那之后我就非常希望有机会攀登珠峰看日出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;12岁立下那个目标后，爸爸How to say? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时他比较震惊，没想到我会有这个想法，而且可能觉得我不会真的去行动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你当时有给自己设定期限吗? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时想的是尽快完成。既然是我十几岁想做的事，等到二十几岁或是三十几岁再去做的话，心境可能就不一样了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;自那之后，你就开始为四年后的登顶珠峰做准备？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我从那时候起开始做一些训练，但前几年因为学业，训练排得没那么满。直到去年我完成慕士塔格峰的攀登后拿到了通往珠峰的门票，才开始系统性的集训。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了每天绑22公斤沙袋训练，你还为攀登珠峰做了哪些准备？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;比如说保加利亚深蹲啊，攀岩啊。我的训练比较强调腿部肌肉和核心力量的锻炼，以及耐力、体能和心肺的训练。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;密集的训练会影响你的学业吗? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多人喜欢问我怎么平衡学业和攀登，它们确实很难平衡，但如果真的热爱，你会想尽一切办法去平衡。我现在的高中课业任务很重，登山的训练任务也很重，所以我会把自己所有空闲的时间排满，在原有进度上提前学习。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;登顶不是成功，回家才是&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你登顶珠峰的那一刻是什么心情？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我以为自己会很激动，登顶也算是完成这四年来的梦想，但也不知道是因为当时天气太冷，还是高海拔会压缩人的一些情绪，我其实还挺平静的。我记得当时我把包里的旗帜一一拿出来拍照，然后给我妈打电话报平安。因为天气太恶劣了，暴风雪很大，夏尔巴向导催我赶紧下撤，我就想着快点撤回去。当时爸妈建议我在二号营地再待一天，第二天坐直升机撤回珠峰大本营。但我在山上待了8天，8天里一直没有洗澡，也没有网络，这对我来说其实已经到达极限，我就把睡袋和防潮垫直接丢到了四号营地，决定当天一定要返回大本营，所以那天我撤回去用了22个小时。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了不能洗澡，作为女生，你在攀登过程中还遇到了哪些困难？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实女性相比男性而言在登山的时候有更多不便，比如洗漱和上厕所。但不管是男性还是女性，在山峰面前都是平等的，只是女性要付出更多的努力才能完成这个目标。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;没有网络的8天里，你除了训练都在做什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;主要是训练，我们在二号营地适应了3天，然后一直在等三号营地的消息看修路队能不能修到顶。我们运气挺好的，如果当时修路队没修上去，我们可能要撤回珠峰大本营，等下一个周期。其余的时间，我会和登山队的队友聊天、打扑克牌，还要抗高反。我刚到珠峰大本营的当晚吐得厉害，不知道是不是因为在尼泊尔水土不服，休整了大概两天才恢复。后来就我一个人和队友在大本营训练，我妈妈给我打电话劝我撤回去。所以这次也是我第一次在没有爸爸妈妈的陪伴下去攀登一座山峰。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那个时候没想过撤回？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;可能就是有点犟，想着自己已经吃了那么多苦，登珠峰前要登那么多座雪山，一天到晚地训练，好不容易到了这里，为什么不坚持一下呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在山顶打给妈妈的那通电话里说了什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我说我登顶了，让她不要担心，我会尽快下撤。妈妈之前一直不太同意我登山，因为这是一项很危险的极限运动。她一直很担忧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;妈妈回了什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;她跟我说登顶不是成功，回家才是，让我注意安全。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这么危险，为什么还坚持攀登？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;登山学家乔治·马洛里常常被人问到攀登珠峰的原因，他总是回答“因为山就over there&quot;.我们很幸运地可以出于喜爱而攀登，但登顶对我来说不仅是为了让世界看到我，我希望大家还能看到我们这一代中国新青年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人不可能永远停留在登顶的那刻&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;登顶珠峰后重返学校，身边的朋友和同学会好奇你的这段经历吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他们会问我在山上看到的风景怎么样。但我没有感受到太大的变化。大家如常上课，我也按部就班地上课和训练。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;登顶对你现在的生活有什么Influence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实也没有什么。人不可能永远停留在登顶的那一刻，我也觉得自己不应该太沉溺于登上一山之巅的喜悦当中，后面的人生还有无数的山峰，无论是物理意义上还是其他层面的。我接下来的目标就是乞力马扎罗山，最近要重新开始训练了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但你会因为已经有了一个不错的成绩而压力更大吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实还好。每座山都有每座山的特点，运气也有好坏。对我来说，重要的是去勇敢地尝试。为了完成它，我会做很多准备，如果这次不行，那就下一次。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;登顶后，你收到尼泊尔国家旅游局的贺电，被央视认证为“中国年龄最小的从南坡登顶的女运动员”。很多人认为这是一种满分人生，你觉得呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;徐卓媛：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;确定自己的梦想并为之奋斗就是一件很满分的事情。对我而言，登上珠峰只是我现阶段比较满意的一份答卷，我才十六七岁，接下来的路很长，还有很多份卷子要交。珠峰只是一个途经点，下一阶段我的目标是完成7+2计划（七大洲的最高峰加上南北两极的徒步）。今年底，我将和妈妈一起完成非洲乞力马扎罗山的攀登。这是我7+2计划的第一步。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 26 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[魏书钧：描述理性漏洞与失控]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261268]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/ObzGU1xbMHbyjhzQ4InEp1BTKxpqC0FgdSbNhsQZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ObzGU1xbMHbyjhzQ4InEp1BTKxpqC0 FgdSbNhsQZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Out of curiosity about the three bizarre murders and the murderer’s motives, Wei Shujun read the novel “The Mistake by the River” several times, but still didn’t understand. Feeling humiliated and excited at the same time, he opened the first page of the computer document and read &quot;Mistake by the River&quot; in enlarged font size. Below it were two lines of small characters, original work: Yu Hua, director: Wei Shujun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He wants to adapt this novella published in 1988. The perpetrators of the three murders all pointed to madmen, but they could not build a complete chain of evidence to bring him to justice, which made both the town and the criminal police captain Ma Zhe uneasy. Writer Yu Hua&#39;s parody of detective novels in the avant-garde literature period used violent absurdity as the surface and subversion of tradition as the core. I have sold the copyright several times but have never changed it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficult thing is to find a word that points to the philosophy behind all suspenseful stories. In 2021, Wei Shujun and screenwriter Kang Chunlei entered the second year of their adaptation. After overturning the general direction twice, they were determined to find the word. They searched for two days and two nights, wandering around the house until they got something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Bug.&quot; He was quite satisfied with this new development. &quot;It is a word born from the progress of information technology. It is a vulnerability problem based on code and the best rational logic. We think it is too accurate. , isn&#39;t our &quot;Yong&#39;an Town Story Collection&quot; called &#39;Ripples of Life&#39;, this one is called &#39;Bugs of Life&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was August 2021, and Wei Shujun was preparing to shoot a new film in Northeast China &quot;White Crane Spreads Wings&quot;. After work, the crew plays badminton together. However, indoor venues have been closed due to the new crown epidemic, and they are planning to play basketball outdoors instead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A month ago, his second feature film &quot;The Story of Yong&#39;an Town&quot; was selected for the Directors&#39; Fortnight section of the Cannes Film Festival; a year ago, his first feature film &quot;Wild Horse Parting Mane&quot; was nominated for the Cannes Newcomer Award. As a feature film director, his graduate work &quot;Yanbian Boy&quot; won the Cannes Short Film Special Mention Award. He received critical acclaim when he first appeared on the scene. Industry seniors and critics praised his talents and talents, and were curious about the possibilities he brought to the table. sex. Wei Shujun received attention as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the adaptation of &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; quickly fell into another strange circle. Bugs do not exist alone. To describe rational loopholes and loss of control, the premise is to explain what rationality is. The argument about rationality is a wide-ranging, academic discussion that is energy-consuming and unnecessary. &quot;We looked in the wrong direction again,&quot; we had to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By chance, while scouting locations in Hangzhou, Wei Shujun felt that there should be a dream at the end of the story. &quot;The causes of their deaths are not completely connected on a rational level and cannot serve to solve the case. But in the dream, they interlock with each other, as if they are all established, revealing a certain inevitability in a series of accidents, giving people a creepy feeling.&quot; In the final version of the script, dreams became the core sequence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This seems to be his consistent creative approach, which values ​​the true feelings of the creative subject and expresses them effectively in the film. Photography director Cheng Ma, who has worked with him three times, provided evidence: &quot;We basically create based on our feelings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Ma and Wei Shujun met for the first time in Shanghai three years ago, and they chatted quite well. . They have many consensuses on the nature and creative concepts of movies, two of which are simple but very important: movies were created to create &quot;realistic illusions&quot; at the beginning, and they should still be so today, and movies may not be the best way to tell stories. It is a medium, but it is a channel for storing and transmitting the creator’s feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, regarding &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot;, Wei Shujun told Cheng Ma that it was restrained, quiet, and elegant, and that many things happened on a humid and rainy day. This was how he felt when reading the novel. Accordingly, Cheng Ma felt that the images should be consistent with the 1990s, when the characters were wandering and out of place, and geographical features such as counties or towns were far away, not close. Cheng Ma suggested shooting on 16mm film, and they hit it off immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2022, with 45 days left before filming, the crew arrived in Nanfeng, Jiangxi Province, where the filming took place, to make preparations. The actors were busy with their own work. Tong Linkai had to practice splits and back fists. Zhu Yilong wore a leather jacket to visit the local police and gained 30 pounds to achieve an overworked figure. Zeng Meihuizi was also making herself gain weight in order to look like a pregnant woman. The crew cooked together, watched movies, and played badminton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I think the best state of creation is when all the main creators are relaxed. I don’t like that kind of tense, night-and-night (state) like a repair project, which is very tiring. That is to say, although it is You are working, but you still have your own life order, and you still retain your pursuit of beauty and passion for life.&quot; Wei Shujun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He often carries a film camera with him - the crew has a total of more than 20 film cameras, and even a darkroom for developing black and white photos - to capture the daily life of the crew. There are more saved in the photo album on his mobile phone. When he opens it and looks through it, he sees friends meeting, travel scenes, rivers, trees, and the sea. “It seems to have some kind of ability to leave time behind, making you think of it as a pleasant time.” In the afternoon, a happy state.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relaxation is rare. What is also rare is that, in Cheng Ma&#39;s words, Wei Shujun places a particularly high importance on creation. &quot;As a director of his age, he can actually withstand a lot of pressure. We have to shoot smoothly, but many people ask us what to do with the scenes and what to do with the actors&#39; time. For example, a certain role has many scenes, but the actors can only come for 10 days in total. , the usual approach of the crew is to focus on filming all his scenes in these 10 days. But Wei Shujun feels that smooth filming is of great value to his creation, so he will give up scenes that cannot be matched by actors or at inappropriate times.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Chunlei also said: &quot;I think he has an almost intuitive ability to control the scene. I always told him, you shine on the scene.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also Once, Wei Shujun changed his character&#39;s name on the spot. In the novel, Ma Zhe&#39;s subordinate is Xiao Li, a young man who takes the initiative to report case analysis from time to time. So of course Tong Linkai’s name is Xiao Li. After a few days of filming, Wei Shujun suddenly said, thank you so much &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (&quot;Thanks&quot; means shit)&lt;/span>;, don&#39;t call me Xiao Li. Just call me Xiao Xie. Wei Shujun greeted other actors and revised his lines. The printed police officer ID card of Xiao Li was re-attached. Tong Linkai&#39;s role became Xiao Xie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But to be honest, the feeling at the scene was not that wonderful. Wei Shujun&#39;s own version is: &quot;Imagine that when you were in school, you had to sit in the classroom at 7 a.m. every morning to study early. On the way from home after breakfast, you felt that you were still waking up. When you got to class, you thought about writing yesterday&#39;s homework. No, I didn’t write it, so I wrote it quickly. After I wrote it, I felt very at ease. I started to think about going to the canteen to buy something to eat during recess, and then I went to the actual class to listen to the teacher. It was the same on the set, everyone was here, Shui After brewing it, we started drinking water. We walked around the scene and the actors were almost done. Then we discussed the scene and confirmed our schedule with the photographer. Everyone prepared individually and then started to prepare for shooting. If something didn’t feel right in the first two days, Adjust it, and it feels good. If you take a few more shots, it will be time for lunch. It really feels like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is a slope every day, and you have to climb up a slope. You have to crawl over to get to that position.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; was completed accurately and efficiently, and was shortlisted for the &quot;Un Certain Regard&quot; section of the Cannes Film Festival. Five months later, it won two honors: Best Film and Cinephile Choice at the Pingyao International Film Festival. After another four days, it was released nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the film, there was often chatter in the theater. Wei Shujun used a long dream to allow Ma Zhe to reveal himself in order to resolve his own uneasiness and chaos. The dream was clear, coherent but illogical. After witnessing everyone&#39;s death by the river, Ma Zhe sat on an old cinema seat and saw the director on the big screen holding a ping pong ball with the number 3 printed on it, shouting at him. ——Ma Zhe! Third class merit! In this shot where conjecture and prophecy overlap, thousands of ping pong balls roll down from the bottom of the screen and swarm towards Ma Zhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone was very excited during the shooting. After taking one shot, everyone picked up the thousands of ping pong balls while shouting &quot;One more, another one&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the show, the audience was full of doubts and endless interpretations and comments about the film, forming multiple dreams outside the screen, a kind of &quot;rationality and irrationality, the combination of the viewer and the viewer.&quot; effect&quot;. From this perspective, Wei Shujun&#39;s initial uneasiness when reading the novel, his exploration of the creator&#39;s intentions, and his several elusive moments during the adaptation were all conveyed to the audience. We think we have the answer, but in fact we have the illusion of an answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I am not too obsessed with pursuing the truth in life, because I feel that it is difficult to find it.&quot; Cheng Ma said that this is another consensus between him and Wei Shujun that the truth is difficult to find, &quot;the so-called The fate of your life is a random existence. You can only see its existence and don’t know the truth behind it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The slight existentialist tendency of &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is just that Back to &quot;existence precedes essence&quot;, or in other words, &quot;back to the thing itself&quot;. Just reiterate one point, &quot;I believe that I &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(creator)&lt;/span>; has determined the sole right of interpretation, and the audience must accept this interpretation Right, this is the biggest paradox.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the movie was released, Wei Shujun sent a message to Yu Hua, saying that it seems that we did not use a movie to write annotations for the novel, but used the movie to write an annotation for the novel. Thoughts after reading. For a while, the two of them were keen to share with each other the audience&#39;s various interpretations of the movie, including a test paper on &quot;Who understands the movie &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; better, Yu Hua or me?&quot; After Yu Hua finished, he showed Wei Shujun his score, which totaled 40 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢张宇欣的帮助。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[不恋爱，搞事业，迪士尼又来了新公主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261316]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;In 1923, young Walt ·Disney came to Los Angeles and joined his brother Roy Disney. The two brothers jointly founded &quot;Disney Brothers Studio&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Five years later, an animated character named Mickey&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (Mickey)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; was born, with round ears, a pointed mouth, and a body Wear white shorts and be adventurous. No one expected that this Mickey Mouse would quickly become a hit and become a classic of the times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/5e03d3effe045cdbe79ca86fb8e48406.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/5e03d3effe045cdbe79ca86fb8e48406.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259599 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be said that everything Disney owned later was started by this Mickey Mouse. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;After that, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Donald Duck, Snow White&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, The Lion King, Pinocchio&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Cao and others came out of here. series of IPs, and has expanded from animation to movies, streaming media, theme parks, games and many other fields, growing into a veritable global media giant. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This year is Disney&lt;/span>;’s 100th anniversary. To commemorate this moment, it has launched a new animated feature film &quot;Star Wish&quot; 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/353e94e2bec94f8dde0a2d4c5ab0a0d9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/353e94e2bec94f8dde0a2d4c5ab0a0d9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259598&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Disney is a dream maker&lt;/span>; factory, and most of its animated stories encourage people to bravely pursue their dreams. As a tribute to the centenary, &quot;Star Wish&quot; certainly closely follows this theme. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The background of the movie is set in a kingdom of wishes called Rosas. People come from all directions to offer their dreams to the magical King Manifico, and the king will choose the right person from them. Help them achieve it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine Yasha’s biggest wish is that her grandfather’s dream comes true. However, when she came into contact with King Manifico, she realized that &lt;span>; the king was not as kind and generous as he appeared on the surface. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/13d838d9212ca2dcc2eb87255e9f04b0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/13d838d9212ca2dcc2eb87255e9f04b0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259601 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Manifico is an extreme conservative. He will only select dreams that he considers harmless to realize, while shelving creative dreams. He regarded such dreams as a scourge that would shake Rosas&#39;s foundations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course Asha disagrees with the king&#39;s point of view, so she joins forces with the wishing star and Valentino the goat to try to get her grandfather&#39;s dream back. The king, under the temptation of lust for power, further darkened. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/74d2011fa8ecac1b3913c1015dd621ca.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/74d2011fa8ecac1b3913c1015dd621ca.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259600 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The assists in the movie, the wishing star and the goat, are easily reminiscent of the combination of Olaf and the reindeer in &quot;Frozen&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In fact, &quot;Wish&quot; did use the production team of &quot;Frozen&quot;, directed by Chris Buck&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (&quot;Frozen&quot;)&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Co-directed with Fawn Villasensohn&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&quot;Dragon&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;; Jennifer Lee&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&quot;Crazy&quot;) Zootopia&quot;, &quot;Wreck-It Ralph&quot;, &quot;Frozen&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Allison Moore, Chris Buck&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(&quot;Frozen&quot;)&lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Co-screenwriter; Liu Yifei and &quot;Feng Shen&quot; star Yu Shi voice the heroine Asha and the goat Valentino respectively. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/b84fb45c94d73c7e1f362563182558b4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;423&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/b84fb45c94d73c7e1f362563182558b4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259596 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/88d8e113486ed2c5ea475b6ca9393435.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/88d8e113486ed2c5ea475b6ca9393435.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259597&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the past, Disney always promoted the truth, goodness and beauty in the world, but &quot;Star Wish&quot; used a lot of space to depict the process of the king&#39;s ambition expanding and eventually being backlashed. And &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;No matter what the situation, Asha was always loyal to her heart, &lt;/span>; and won more allies, and finally overthrew Manifico&#39;s rule. The dystopian nature of the movie is very un-Disney. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I don&#39;t agree with your point of view, but I will defend to the death your right to speak.&quot; Putting it here is an excellent comment. Everyone has the right to pursue their dreams, and the king cannot deny it easily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being good at creating dreams, Disney is also good at creating princesses. Since the release of Snow White (Disney&#39;s first animated feature film &quot;Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs&quot;) in 1937, Disney has followed the development of the times for more than 80 years and successively launched more than a dozen characters. Princess. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/484faf306e6df3f6adc26b4a7344eea8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;342&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/484faf306e6df3f6adc26b4a7344eea8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259602 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early&lt;/span>; Disney princesses, beautiful and innocent, with supreme love: Snow White who ate the poison apple waited for the prince to kiss them awake; Cinderella who dropped her crystal slipper ( &quot;Cinderella,&quot; 1950) relies on the prince to rescue her; the cursed Princess Aurora (&quot;Sleeping Beauty,&quot; 1959) also wants a kiss from the prince&#39;s true love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that the princesses of this period satisfied people&#39;s beautiful imagination of love, but they were too dependent on men, had beauty but no brains, and were always in a passive &lt;span>; situation waiting for the prince to save them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/09b2f11f3d59a649db4c87c8f166cd63.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;685&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/09b2f11f3d59a649db4c87c8f166cd63.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259604 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Especially the box office failure of &quot;Sleeping Beauty&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; made Disney&lt;/span>; start to reflect. Later princesses have improved their initiative and self-awareness. For example, Ariel in &quot;The Little Mermaid&quot; (1989) sacrifices singing to walk on land in order to meet the man she loves; Ariel in &quot;Beauty and the Beast&quot; (1991) Belle and the ugly beast have been in love for a long time; Jasmine in &quot;Aladdin&quot; (1992) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; refuses the king&#39;s offer Referring to marriage, falling in love with Aladdin. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The princesses of this period&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; will take the initiative to fight for what they want, but&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Their goal in life is still to find true love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/631f8f80da83892c3fea154bbfc85969.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;669&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/631f8f80da83892c3fea154bbfc85969.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259603 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such &quot;progress&quot; was obviously not enough. Later, Disney&lt;/span>; began to give princesses a brave and rebellious spirit. They were no longer powerless cowards. Miss &lt;span>;, and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is both wisdom and strength. For example&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;For example, in &quot;Mulan&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(1998)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Hua Mulan disguises herself as a man&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and goes into battle to kill the enemy;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;&quot;Tangled&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2010)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Rapunzel&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; dares to knock over a stranger with a pan; &quot;Brave&quot; Merida in &quot;Legend&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2012) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is like a naughty baby who ruined her own blind date with her own hands. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/a6f1403f8998cb784f724c5fba8a5070.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/a6f1403f8998cb784f724c5fba8a5070.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259605 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The emergence of &quot;Frozen&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2013)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; directly broke the &quot;prince and princess living happily together&quot; &quot;The purpose of this. The family relationship between the two sisters became the main thread, and the handsome prince became the villain of the entire film. The princess no longer passively waits for the prince to save her, the princess herself is very powerful; true love no longer involves the prince kissing the princess, and the sisterhood is also very touching. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/c1da20b56f8dbd4531cb0b088ba7c214.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;418&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/c1da20b56f8dbd4531cb0b088ba7c214.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259606 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be said that Disney subverted Disney. Starting from this&lt;/span>;movie, Disney princesses completely got rid of the male gaze. They took off their costumes and became their own heroes. Like the &lt;span>; princesses in &quot;Moana&quot; (2016) and &quot;Legend of the Dragon&quot; (2021), they all gave up on romance. One lived her life how she wanted, and the other led her people to protect their home and country. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/0c8e54ba1a97dd0ceb9f0f15dd4a0e8d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;224&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/0c8e54ba1a97dd0ceb9f0f15dd4a0e8d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259607 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;And this &quot;Star Wish&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is also of the same origin&lt;/span>;. Asha dares to question and is not afraid of power. In order to protect all the residents of Rosas He did not hesitate to stand on the opposite side of King Manifico. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But compared with the previous princesses, Asha&#39;s combat effectiveness is obviously weakened. She no longer has the ability to go to heaven and earth. She is more like an ordinary person, a civilian hero who resists the aloof king. Just like the theme song of the movie sings, &quot;Maybe you are afraid but you still reach out your hand, and you will not run away because of a weak tremor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This may also be the century-old road that Disney has walked for itself. Write down &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s sincere notes&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;: &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;If you don’t forget your original intention and hold your dreams in mind, you can always get through the twists and turns of the river&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/9dc306addaa0bd973987160fd8f00c69.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;423&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/25/9dc306addaa0bd973987160fd8f00c69.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259608 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[易梦玲：尽力做好每件事，把结果交给时间和命运]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261235]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/r7wWOGybhtzL7svIzZDSLQTzo4ZpYfZCh6PToEVj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/r7wWOGybhtzL7svIzZDSLQTzo4ZpYfZ Ch6PToEVj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“No matter what the result is, it is all experience”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the field of Internet celebrities, there are too many legends about ordinary people and the arrival of geniuses and all kinds of falls. Each one has a story that is compelling and extraordinary. But Yi Mengling’s story clearly does not fall into this category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to define Yi Mengling seems to be an issue that the public is more interested in now. She is a model, a blogger, an Internet celebrity, and a newcomer to the film and television industry. And Yi Mengling is still making a lot of attempts and challenges. Maybe there will be more labels and identities added to her name in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is widely known because of Yi Mengling’s unique style of photos and short videos. With good aesthetics, makeup and outfits, coupled with sunshine, smile and always bright attitude, Yi Mengling has gained tens of millions of fans on social platforms. She didn&#39;t take the initiative to define anything, but various labels followed, such as &quot;a sense of atmosphere&quot; and &quot;a sense of pure desire&quot;...these labels were either envy, love, or ill-intentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, this thin girl who attracted too much attention walked up to the filming site on the second floor and greeted everyone who came her way. During the shooting break, she skillfully communicated with the photographer about technical issues, &quot;You have to trust me.&quot; When discussing a certain lighting technique, she sincerely gave her suggestions, which made the photographer laugh out loud. laugh. Yi Mengling had not eaten anything from morning to noon. When the accompanying staff hurriedly delivered the takeaway during the break, she said, &quot;Just a few bites&quot; and &quot;call me when you are ready.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This may be a more realistic look of Yi Mengling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, some people imitated her, some people disdained her, and there were more and more discussions about her. However, Yi Mengling rarely fought with netizens, and she still only exported life related to herself. fragment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also occasionally responds to some controversial discussions. For example, &quot;Big Mouth&quot; brings a signature smile, but also brings ridicule. Yi Mengling&#39;s response is more of self-acceptance and gratitude, which makes her unique in the field of modeling. For example, after recording her first experience in acting and variety shows, netizens compared her with female celebrities because of her acting skills and appearance. More comments about &quot;Internet celebrities should not enter the entertainment industry&quot; followed. But in Yi Mengling&#39;s view, she treats the world as a big playground and is an experiential player. It takes courage to try different things and challenge different things, but she thinks the process of taking the challenge is cool, and she is also cool if she chooses to challenge herself. &quot;No matter what the result is, it is all experience. I think it is worth it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone likes Yi Mengling. In addition to her beauty, they also like her calm personality. Many times, she is trying her best to relieve some anxiety and output some positive energy. For example, she appeared without makeup, shared her tips behind taking photos, and posted photos of her belly with meat after meals, making everyone feel that beauty is not a statue, but a living person. Similarly, such behavior will still cause dissatisfaction. Some people feel that this is deliberate or a &quot;concave and down-to-earth persona&quot;. No matter what she said, Yi Mengling accepted it all. In her opinion, she actually has nothing to be taboo about. As a public figure, it is essential to face criticism. Many of the things others said were exaggerated, so just laugh after reading them. Yi Mengling said: &quot;Try not to fall into the vicious circle of self-evidence. After all, explanations are never-ending.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is an amateur and has a place on the Internet with her own advantages. It seems that all internet celebrities can be found in her, but she cannot be classified into the same category as anyone. Yi Mengling&#39;s story may not be complicated, but no matter what, she fought her way out of the siege in a place where the fighting was more intense. To a certain extent, whether the public recognizes it or not, she has courage, tenacity and strength beyond her age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About an ordinary girl becoming the focus of the spotlight, how does she face all this? The following is Yi Mengling’s answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Rather than being self-consistent, it is better to say that I am trying to find growth here&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you still remember the turning points that you think are important? Are you adapting to this (whether it’s attention or controversy) smoothly? Was there a process of psychological construction? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Maybe this is my first time to participate in the recording of a variety show. Facing various evaluations, I think it is both encouragement and motivation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We have been following you for a long time, you are very Face the problems you encounter positively and always seem optimistic and tolerant. So how do you deal with these emotions in private? You&#39;ve had some tough moments too, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There will definitely be, but I am a forgetful person. I will only take the initiative to remember happy things. Don’t let internal friction take up too much time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today’s Internet environment is actually very harsh. You How do you achieve self-consistency? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because everyone on the Internet wants to express their thoughts more, I will distinguish some comments, accept them or laugh. Let it go. Rather than being self-consistent, it is better to say that I am trying to find growth in this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think you have many brave actions, For example, challenge yourself in areas you have never tried before, and generously share your tips for taking photos. How do you walk the line between getting closer to everyone and remaining mysterious? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You don’t have to choose between being close to everyone and staying mysterious. Share as much as you want to share, and do it in your own time. Will return to his own nest. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What qualities do you most admire in yourself? What do you think are the particularly good things about yourself that you have always insisted on? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My mentality is relatively good. In current terms, I may be emotionally stable. A good mood is the cornerstone of doing everything well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have seen all kinds of things about you Comments, one point worth discussing is that people think you are young and promising, and have everything. Does having such achievements at such an age make you feel confused or confused at certain moments? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think I am still far away from having everything. But I know that I am a relatively lucky girl, and based on good luck, I will also work harder. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What will you do in private to maintain Self-input? After all, your job and identity require a lot of output. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In addition to traveling to different places and meeting people from all walks of life, a new hobby I have this year is listening to podcasts . Listening to podcasts is a good choice when doing housework at home or taking a bath. The content of many programs is very current, and the angles and viewpoints are also very novel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our theme this time is &quot;New Faces&quot; &quot;, what &quot;new things&quot; do you think you bring to everyone? New also means not repeating yourself, which means a lot. What is the state or appearance that you hope to always maintain? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Trying different challenges, breaking conventions and comfort zones are all things I want to show everyone the new me. I want my status to be undefined. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You feel that you have gained Which ones are worth losing, and which ones are lost that you really don’t want to lose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the biggest gain is my growth. From a child who didn’t understand anything, to now I have become a person worth going to. The &quot;adults&quot; I rely on have made a lot of progress in both my abilities and my mentality. What I regret to lose may still be some &quot;willful rights&quot;. In the past, I could post whatever I wanted, and there would not be so many interpretations. Now, as a public figure, I really need to restrain myself with words and deeds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think it is very important to prove yourself? Difficult things? At what point did you have a strong desire to prove yourself? Or say no? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am more of a &quot;Buddha&quot;. Nothing must be proven to someone. Everything in the process must be proven. Do your best and leave the result to time and fate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What will you do to eliminate your own bad habits? mood? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yi Mengling: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Go travel, nature will give you the most primitive healing and peace. When you are far away from the city, you will feel that the starry sky is infinite, and we are just a small dot on one of the planets. In a long time, the things we encounter are actually so insignificant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西安泽县永鑫通海铁路物流公司施工事故导致7人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 19:41:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Propaganda Department of Linfen Municipal Party Committee, Shanxi Province that the construction of Shanxi Yongxin Tonghai Railway Logistics Co., Ltd. in Anze County Seven people buried in the accident have been confirmed dead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter saw at the scene that there were eight nearly 30-meter-high column buildings arranged in a &quot;one&quot; shape in the north-south direction. The roof of the first building on the south side collapsed. Search and rescue personnel were working on the building. Wooden boards were built at the bottom to prevent secondary collapse of the overhead scaffolding. There was a large amount of concrete accumulation in the search and rescue area at the bottom, and on-site search and rescue personnel were carrying out demolition construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 22:00 on the 24th, a concrete support model for pouring a corridor fell off at the construction site of Shanxi Yongxin Tonghai Railway Logistics Co., Ltd. At around 20:30 that day, 30 cubic meters of concrete was poured into the beams and slabs at the 28.5-meter section of the 8th section of the raw coal shed constructed by Chinalco International (Tianjin) Construction Co., Ltd. The scaffolding suddenly collapsed at about 22:00, and six workers were involved. and a concrete pump truck commander fell to the bottom and were buried in reinforced concrete. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一“码”就医，人均省43分钟：医保码如何更好用更智能？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261330]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/25/f5352e97c9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 25/f5352e97c9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259632&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On June 2, 2020, residents’ mobile phones in Shangshui Lakeside Community, Luyang District, Hefei City, Anhui Province Scan the QR code to activate the &quot;Medical Insurance Electronic Voucher&quot;. Visual China | Picture &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qiu Yunqing, Executive Deputy Dean of the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, also understands that queuing is the most headache in the process of medical treatment -registered number pick -up, payment appointment to queue a lot of time. As soon as he entered the hospital&#39;s outpatient hall, the crowds of the black and hot air were inevitably more depressed in the mood of patients who had a good body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thanks to the medical insurance code (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; &quot;Medical Insurance Electronic Volume&quot; &lt;/span>;) The first hospital has more than 7 million outpatient volume a year, and the outpatient hall &quot;will not seem so crowded.&quot; &quot;Patients have a registration fee for settlement of small program medical insurance in advance and reported online. After the clinic, the consultation fee for medical insurance settlement directly through the small program.&quot; Qiu Yunqing told Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The data provided by Qiu Yunqing shows that the patient&#39;s hand -held medical code can go to the entire process of medical treatment, which significantly improves the patient&#39;s diagnosis efficiency and the hospital operation efficiency. %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, 31 provinces across the country (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti;&quot;>; municipality, autonomous region &lt;/span>;) The Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps have supported medical insurance codes for medical and purchase medicines, and more than 800,000 medical institutions were connected to fixed -point pharmaceutical institutions, and medical insurance code users exceeded 1 billion. At the press conference of the State Medical Insurance Bureau on November 24, 2023, Fu Chaoqi, deputy director of the Office of the State Medical Insurance Bureau, provided the above data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fu Chaoqi pointed out that from the activation of the provinces of the medical insurance code, Zhejiang and Qinghai provinces have taken the lead in achieving coverage of insured in the province, and the activation rate of more than half of the provinces of more than half of the provinces exceeds 75%. According to the data calculated by Tencent, for an ordinary insured, the appointment registration can be achieved through the WeChat public account before the clinic. During the settlement, the medical insurance code can be used to complete the online medical insurance payment, which saves 43 minutes for each clinic. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Breaking the barriers, use the entire process of medical purchase of medicines &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Purchase medicines at hospitals and pharmacies, and the mobile phone &quot;bright code&quot; can be traced back to four years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 24, 2019, the first medical insurance code (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Medical Insurance Electronic Volume &lt;/span>;) Provincial Jinan City activation. At that time, the National Medical Insurance Bureau hoped that the medical insurance code was not only simple electronic, but the vision of &quot;seeing a doctor without cards, only using medical insurance codes&quot;. Standard nationwide unified, cross -regional mutual recognition, and an electronic voucher can be processed. All medical insurance business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Four years later, these visions not only gradually landed, but also made new attempts. Take Zhejiang Province as an example. In the past, there were 54 medical insurance systems in Zhejiang, which divided each other and did not share each other. Until March 2022, Zhejiang&#39;s &quot;Smart Medical Insurance&quot; system accepted the national medical security platform across the region to achieve the same medical insurance settlement in Zhejiang Province The set system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cao Cen, deputy director of the Zhejiang Medical Insurance Bureau, introduced that all designated medical institutions in Zhejiang have transformed the HIS (hospital information management system) to support the use of medical insurance code throughout the process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, in Zhejiang Provincial Hospital, from registered, medical, payment, inspection tests, printing reports, to obtaining drugs, hospitalization and medical insurance settlement, it can be completed as long as the code scan the code; , Medical Insurance Code support prescription circulation, purchase of drugs and medicine, medical insurance settlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The medical insurance code also opened up the barriers outside the hospital. Zhejiang Jinhua City Central Hospital mentioned in a paper that the electronic prescription circulation through the application of medical insurance codes can choose &quot;dual channels&quot; by themselves (through the two channels of fixed -point medical institutions and fixed retail pharmacies, to meet the conditions for synchronization of conditions and include medical insurance payment ) Purchase prescription drugs for fixed -point retail pharmacies to enjoy the same reimbursement treatment as the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The service scenario changes from the&quot; single point &#39;to&#39;. &quot;Xie Zhangyi, deputy director of the State Medical Insurance Bureau&#39;s Financial Regulations Department, said that the entire process of medical insurance codes is the key work of the medical insurance department in 2023 One is to promote the use of medical insurance codes from the entire process of reservation registration, sign -in, diagnosis and treatment, report inquiry, pharmacies and drugs in reservation registration, sign -in, diagnosis and treatment examination, report inquiry, and pharmacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Family favors, so that the elderly and children are convenient. &lt;/H4>; &lt;p>; The hospital is mostly the elderly. It is particularly important how fashionable technology takes into account the needs of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A paper from Zhejiang Cancer Hospital mentioned that the average age of medical insurance patients in Hangzhou in 2021 is 55 years, of which about 40%of them are 60 and over. &quot;On the one hand, elderly patients are intelligent. The use of mobile phones is low; on the other hand, compared with young people, the proficiency and fluency of elderly patients using smartphones are poor. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In terms of aginging transformation, the WeChat medical insurance code has been launched on the barrier -free version, supporting the visually impaired people to use the medical code through voice, and at the same time launch a family account service in many provinces, apply face recognition and other technologies to support relatives to support relatives Agent business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qiu Yunqing told the southern weekend reporter that most of the elderly have family members to accompany them. Through the function of medical insurance family account function, the family members who accompany the companion can bind the medical insurance code of the elderly to their accounts to facilitate the appointment and payment for the elderly for the elderly cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, according to the medical insurance policy in Zhejiang and other places, the personal account of insurance participants has passed the &quot;family support filing&quot; in the years, which can be used to directly pay the spouse of the same medical insurance to participate in the basic medical insurance. The medical insurance cost of children and parents. For example, young people&#39;s personal accounts cannot be used, they can be used for parents, &quot;(&lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; Parent &lt;/span>; The medical insurance sent a text message. What medicine and how much money was prescribed, it was also very convenient after binding. You can pay with your own account money. &quot;Qiu Yunqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We also pay attention to the needs of medical insurance services that are more difficult to use in intelligent technologies such as the elderly, minors, etc., effectively integrate traditional services with intelligent methods, and launch family accounts, medical treatment on different places, etc. Function, and adding offline activities of the medical insurance code in the medical insurance agency, helping special groups to obtain and enjoying the medical insurance services, and improving the accessibility of medical insurance convenience services. &quot;Xie Zhangyi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Be wary of the use of medical insurance codes to ensure the safety of medical insurance funds &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; However, while the medical insurance code is convenient, how to ensure the safety of the medical insurance fund also brings challenges to all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Guangzhou Medical Insurance Service Center pointed out in a paper that there is no related photo information for medical insurance electronic vouchers. Regulatory work brings difficulty and challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September 2023, the Putian police detected a case that used medical insurance codes. After the villagers died, their relatives used medical insurance codes to seek medical reimbursement and cheated 1232.73 yuan for medical insurance funds. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Junjie, general manager of Alipay Medical and Health Division, said that the system will analyze multi -factor security technical analysis of information such as the use habits of the insured, account change and other information. Once abnormalities are found, immediately report the medical insurance bureau and start the risk control system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In June 2023, the State Medical Insurance Bureau issued the &quot;Two -Combination of Three Supplements&quot; Work Plan &quot;of the National Medical Insurance Bureau, requiring medical insurance data to be connected vertically and horizontally to achieve comprehensive supervision of the medical insurance fund. The National Medical Insurance Bureau also requested that before the end of 2023, all the intelligent regulatory subsystems were launched in all regions. At the end of 2025, the intelligent audit and electronic monitoring system was basically established. The data is closely connected to form a normalized regulatory system of daily review and on -site inspection, big data analysis, and intelligent monitoring of the whole scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the medical insurance code users broke 1 billion, the National Medical Insurance Bureau was also promoting the service function of the medical insurance code from &quot;available&quot; to &quot;easy to use&quot;. &quot;At present, the masses&#39; demand for medical insurance services presents a multi -level, diversified and personalized characteristics. Combined with the actual needs of the masses, the medical insurance department has launched a batch of fun and use of the masses&#39;&quot; Internet+medical insurance services&#39;. The diagnosis, one -button recipe, re -examination of drugs, online settlement, medicine delivery, etc., can better meet the needs of the masses to see a doctor and buy medicine, &quot;said Xie Zhangyi, deputy director of the Department of Finance and Regulations of the State Medical Insurance Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend Intern Xi Lijie also contributed) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[父亲带脑梗儿子跑网约车感动万千网友：灵活就业让赚钱与陪伴得以两全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261194]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-25 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; This is a news that all middle-aged fathers will see it. In Chongqing, a 53 -year -old online car driver Yi Heping runs the car with a cerebral infarction son every day. Every time he receives orders, he will apologize to the passengers first: &quot;Sorry, the co -driver is my son, he is sick ...&quot; In September this year, he mentioned that he had apologized more than 1,800 times. Visually, this data will increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His son is unfortunate. In 2021, Yi Heping&#39;s son was admitted to the hospital for cerebral infarction; in early 2023, Xiaoyi was sent to the emergency room again due to cerebral hemorrhage. After treatment, Xiaoyi&#39;s physical condition gradually recovered, but he lost his ability to take care of himself. In order to better take care of his son, Yi Heping took Xiaoyi to &quot;on the road&quot; together. He has encountered the cancellation of orders and is also understood and considerate by more passengers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As far as the destiny and the set of people are concerned, he has two &quot;cuts&quot;. One is the loser of Shanghai. Yi Heping used to be &quot;Boss Yi&quot;. In 1996, he went to Shenzhen to start a business and became an earlier group of people who operated communication equipment. Since then He decided to return Yijin to his hometown and return to Chongqing to start a business. At that time, there were more than 20 million yuan on his personal account. There were all villas and luxury cars, as well as his own full -time driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2015, Yihe&#39;s investment failed, resulting in bankruptcy, and many years of hard work. This trajectory is desolate and sad, full of frustration of middle -aged men; the other is the father who is struggling between making money to support his family and take care of his son. His wife could not take care of her son due to diabetes, coronary heart disease, etc. This burden could only be carried by this tired father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, such a story is &quot;lonely&quot;, but those who bring their children or their loved ones &quot;on the road&quot; to ask for life is not just Yihe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2019, Anhui Takeaway Brother Li Yuanyuan put the only six months old, and put the takeaway in the takeaway box, which attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In January 2022, the media reported that Guizhou guy Xiao Xin took his 3 -year -old son to takeaway. Life is not good for him, divorced, second child, baby, and work hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2022, a video of a playback and review volume of 100,000 + attracted attention. Children, and take her takeaway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2023, the Hyundai Express reported that &quot;Uncle Bald&quot; Fu Zhenyang from Liu&#39;an, Anhui, began to sports in Suzhou with his sick wife in Suzhou since 2017. It was 6 years of running. Fu Zhenyang wants to pay more than 200,000 yuan in debt, and also take care of the half -paralyzed wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; No need to do it one by one. The common point of these stories is that most of the heroes came from the countryside to the city to work hard, and they all encountered a huge twists and turns. They chose not to abandon or give up. They sparen the heavy pressure and endless test of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The direct reason they are difficult to add is to stay away from the family zone and bloodline bond. The strong and optimistic post -00 mother -in -law was ruthlessly launched by her mother -in -law, and more situations had to come to a big city to make a living in order to change the situation. Obviously, in the rural and family context, a person has difficulties, and everyone can set up a handle. You go to work, some people can help you see the child, you are ill, and someone will send you a hot meal to your family. This echoes your power to a large extent. But after coming to the city alone, all the &quot;reinforcements&quot; disappeared. In the scene of the neighbors &quot;do not know each other&quot;, you can only rely on yourself. The first thing you wake up every day is to rely on your loved ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What they encountered is a substantial &quot;atomicization&quot;. As the experts say, social atomicization mainly refers to the process of changes in social connection status during the change of the unit system. It is mainly manifested by the weakening of personal connection and the alienation of individuals and the public world. And these daily busy situations are the actual portrayal of &quot;post -units&quot; and lonely individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are actually in a lonely island, is isolated and helpless, and they are not even qualified to fall down -Yihe is the most worried that once they are gone, what should their sons do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earning money and companionship are important and cannot be given up, but how to do both is a problem. Obviously, it is difficult for them to enter a &quot;regular unit&quot; in the secular sense and check in nine to five places. Even if they have such ability, they need to take care of themselves and cannot take care of their loved ones. Moreover, almost no unit allows employees to bring dolls or wives to work. Whether it is an enterprise&#39;s system or order, they will say &quot;no&quot; to this situation. After all, the employer does not have this obligation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fortunately, they found places to live in the flexible employment field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the realistic situation of the bone, the &quot;dilemma&quot; hanging on their heads forced them to find another law. The rise of platform employment and freelance has given them great hope. This is a way of working that can be freely controlled without punching in. It can be said that the Internet economy, including the takeaway economy, provides the final guarantee for such people. Behind this is actually a new idea that society opens to help solve the practical difficulties of a crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For this group, this is the only way they break the state of &quot;atomicization&quot; and get out of the predicament. Only those who are desperate to fight doom and hardship can find this difficult but quite solid path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the other hand, those wandering people with the children &quot;on the road&quot; also set an example for the children to persist in and glow in adversity. Children who have this process of life can also read the true meaning of life, and they will also be sensible earlier than their peers. A recent video video shows that a mother with a paralyzed lower limb in Yan&#39;an in Shaanxi accidentally fell when she was paralyzed on the wheelchair, and her 4 -year -old son tried his best to raise his mother again and again. On November 14, Li Yuanyuan released a video of the three -year -old daughter, Yu Er to help brush the bowl, and once again triggered discussion among netizens. Netizens directly called the little girl &quot;the smile was too cured.&quot; Hardness is also the best tutor. I am convinced that those who flew to the streets with their children have also had the psychological construction that cultivated children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When we explore the social assistance mechanism to protect the group, we should also see that mortals grit their teeth and carry the burden of a family, and support the extraordinary significance of a beloved loved ones. This narrative seems to be sporadic, loose, atypical, but also converges a lively sample that confronts uncertainty and unsatisfactory, becomes a society that is &quot;atomicized &quot;The indispensable force in the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>