<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任殷美根被“双开”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258198]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reviewed the former deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress , Deputy Director Yin Meigan conducted a case review and investigation on serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Yin Meigan lost her ideals and beliefs, deviated from party principles, had no sense of discipline and law, resisted organizational review, and engaged in superstitious activities; ignored the spirit of the eight central regulations, accepted gifts and money in violation of regulations, and entered and exited Private clubs; failing to report personal matters as required, failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing interviews and correspondence; borrowing money and housing from management and service recipients, being morally corrupt, and engaging in power, sex, and money transactions; violating regulations and intervening in market economic activities. and disciplinary and law enforcement activities; neglecting the education of spouses and children; forming a community of interests with unscrupulous businessmen, collaborating with relatives to engage in power and money transactions, taking advantage of the convenience of one&#39;s position to seek benefits for others in job promotions, project contracting, etc., and illegally accepting Huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Meigan seriously violated the party’s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and suspected of bribery crime, and did not restrain or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. , is serious in nature and has a bad impact, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to give Yin Meigan the sanction of expulsion from the party; by The National Supervisory Commission dismissed him from public office; terminated his qualifications as a representative of the 15th Jiangxi Provincial Party Congress; confiscated his illegal income; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[自由的健康的创作，很好丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257988]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;176&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/RobfInKocHxEIOn9ssnq6HH5c1iM3ScZWgn2EAlE . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www. infzm.com/content/257431&quot; title=&quot;Director Wang Mu and his &quot;gentle shell&quot;&quot;>;Director Wang Mu and his &quot;gentle shell&quot;&lt;/a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed young directors Wang Mushi repeatedly mentioned that he was not a professional screenwriter before - from the time he quit the drama circle in 2010 until he wanted to make his own movie in 2018, he was a film and TV screenwriter. He doesn&#39;t like revising drafts or attending meetings, and he doesn&#39;t endorse or talk about the discourse system that may be a mixture of film screenwriting reference book theory and Internet platform &quot;playing methods.&quot; He didn’t even meet the actors, go to the set, or compare the differences between his script and the final product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a writer, I really empathize with his approach: he only does what he wants to do, and doesn’t do anything he doesn’t want to do; at the same time, I feel that he can live in a small world with his own rules. , how difficult it is to make money, and how lucky it is at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While doing an interview with Director Li Xiaofeng for this topic (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;he has collaborated with Wang Mu several times&lt;/span>; ), I envy that kind of atmosphere even more. Everyone has a consensus on the concept of creation and trusts each other&#39;s personality and talents. This is the basis. On top of this, Li Xiaofeng gave a popular description, &quot;Whoever holds the knife eats the meat.&quot; Whoever writes this draft Write with your own characteristics. We don&#39;t need to be screwed together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng said that creative freedom is particularly important. It may be unstable, but it can ensure physical and mental health. I can understand what Li Xiaofeng means by &quot;unstable&quot;. &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; and &quot;Rebirth from the Ashes&quot;, which he directed and Wang Mu co-wrote, did not receive particularly high Douban ratings, but I liked them very much. Fully respect everyone&#39;s opinions and creative temperament. The effect may not be good enough, but the participants will definitely feel comfortable and some viewers will also enjoy watching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu and Li Xiaofeng collaborated once more. The script &quot;Hypnotized by Water&quot; written by Wang Mu won a screenplay award at the Busan International Film Festival, but was not filmed due to lack of funds. But of course, success is not the most important, at least not the only valid criterion. At this point, I think their creations have returned to the essence of creation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interview with Wang Mu did not go as smoothly as I expected. He is not a cinephile director, and I am a layman in theater. When interviewing him himself, after several back and forths, I still couldn’t fully understand what it meant that drama held far more weight in his heart than movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peripheral interviews helped me. Li Xiaofeng said that Wang Mu is a serious creator. He likes Chekhov. His novel writing style is very static. There is a bust of Lu Xun in his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng also talked about their first collaboration on the script for &quot;Rebirth from the Ashes&quot;. In this play, people in the 2010s have to look back to the 1990s, when ethical relationships changed dramatically and shocks occurred in people&#39;s hearts. The script was previously called &quot;Chasing&quot;, and there were already seven drafts when Wang Mu joined. Xu Feng and Li Xiaofeng, one of the protagonists, have imagined several identities, including repair shop workers, postmen, etc. Wang Mu changed Xu Feng&#39;s occupation to worker. Li Xiaofeng immediately felt that it was accurate, &quot;That movie actually contains a lot of thinking about social forms. Wang Mu wrote Xu Feng as a young man who was greatly affected by family and social changes, and he was also very innocent. He made Xu Feng&#39;s purity and ours The emotions for the working class are unified.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think of &quot;The Tender Shell&quot; again. Wang Mu looked for image references for the young male and female protagonists who were traumatized and redeemed each other. Dai Chun was Peter Sheff. Allen in &quot;Ikus&quot;, Juexiao is Antigone in the Greek myth written by Sophocles. Li Xiaofeng said that when he watched &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot;, he felt that &quot;there is a little bit of stagnation. The characters in Wang Mu&#39;s works have a relatively high quality and density of souls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think about it, as the first work of a young director, it has no popular stars and does not have endless road shows like the movies in the past few months. It can get more than 12 million at the box office, which is pretty good. I hope that good works can be seen by more people, good directors can go further, and free creation can demonstrate its value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国银行原党委书记、董事长刘连舸严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:21:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;830&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/4ac458be98201dc0f6e86725df18dac4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission investigated the former Party Secretary and Chairman of Bank of China Co., Ltd. Liu Liange&#39;s serious violations of discipline and law were investigated and investigated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideals and convictions, abandoned his original mission, was not firm or compromised in implementing the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, abandoned his financial risk prevention and control responsibilities, and interfered in credit projects in violation of regulations. Illegal granting of loans, resulting in major financial risks, failure to fulfill the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, seriously damaging the political ecology of the unit, illegally bringing prohibited books and periodicals into the country, and deliberately trying to resist organizational censorship; ignoring the spirit of the eight central regulations, illegally accepting gifts, entering and exiting Private clubs, accepting skiing and travel arrangements, long-term borrowing of vehicles subject to management; failing to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing inquiries, hiring, adjusting and promoting cadres for personal gain; running businesses in violation of regulations; intervening in fund lending and illegally Keep confidential information; have bad morals, have bad family traditions, and neglect their relatives; have no bottom line in discipline and law, act arbitrarily, &quot;rely on finance to eat finance&quot;, and use their position to benefit others in terms of loan financing, project cooperation, etc. , and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu Liange seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of accepting bribes and illegally granting loans. They did not restrain themselves or hold back after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. They are serious in nature and have bad influence, and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Disciplinary Punishments of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and submitted to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Liu Liange from the party; according to It stipulates that the benefits he enjoys will be cancelled; his qualifications as a representative of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China will be terminated; his illegal gains that violate disciplines and laws will be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues will be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved will be transferred together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[救援队分析上海4岁女童走失情况：事发地系泥沙滩，沙质不好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 4, a 4-year-old girl disappeared on the beach of Nanhui New Town in Pudong, Shanghai. She has been missing for more than 10 years. 60 hours. The local police, firefighting and private rescue teams have been searching for days. On the 7th, Li Chenguang, the captain of the Shanghai Dandelion Rescue Team who participated in the search and rescue, told Nandu reporters that after the water receded on the evening of the 6th, the rescue team searched along the breakwater along the low-tide coastline. The girl was found but has not yet been found. According to the introduction, the beach where the girl was lost is a mud beach impacted by rip currents, and is not a scenic spot. &quot;We have always discouraged everyone from entering, but when the weather is good, people do play here every day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About Regarding the controversy over how far the girl was from the coast when she was lost, Li Chenguang analyzed it to Nandu reporters. If the girl was lost around 17:30, the girl’s father was not as far away from the shore as he said when he left. According to recent hydrology It is estimated that the location of the incident is about 100 meters from the shore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Pudong police report, the girl’s father said that when the incident occurred, he returned to the shore to get his mobile phone and left the girl alone on the beach. He returned more than ten minutes later but did not find his daughter. Surveillance footage showed that the girl waited in place for about 10 minutes, then walked towards the water, fell down at the water&#39;s edge and disappeared into the waves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fdedb3e1be01a5c599cb91d2793c8e42.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253229&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The lost girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4-year-old girl disappeared in the waves&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 5, the girl’s parents posted a message for help on social platforms, saying that their daughter died in October. Lost on Nanhui New Town Beach at around 17:20 on the 4th, 4 and a half years old, 108cm tall, wearing a blue Elsa princess dress, no shoes or socks, with a bow on each side of her head and two small braids at the end of her hair. , wearing a yellow butterfly headband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the police information report issued by the Pudong Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau on the 6th, at about 18:40 on October 4, the girl’s parents went to the Lingang New City Police Station of the Pudong Public Security Bureau for help, saying that their 4-year-old daughter Lost while playing at the beach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl’s father said that he took his family to the beach that day, and he took his daughter Huang Moumou to the beach about 20 meters away from the sea to play. During the process, he went back to get his cell phone and left the girl alone on the beach. More than ten minutes later, he returned to the beach but could not find his daughter. Because it was dark and the search failed, he asked the police for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the report, the Pudong police immediately organized a large number of police forces to conduct a dragnet search along the coast. The fire department dispatched infrared sensor drones. Relevant personnel searched throughout the night, but no trace of the girl was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, the Pudong police, together with the Fire Rescue Corps, organized nearly 200 people from 6 rescue teams including Lantian and Houtian to carry out a comprehensive search. At the same time, the organization personnel checked more than 20 surveillance probes around the beach one by one, and initially ruled out the possibility that the girl was taken away from the beach by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the on-site probe is far away, people can only appear as blurry white dots in the image. It was not until evening that his father finally pointed out the exact location of the girl when he and the girl were separated on the surveillance. Based on this, the police found the suspected girl&#39;s figure among the nearly 100 people in the image. After waiting in place for about 10 minutes, she walked towards the water. Go, fall down by the water and disappear into the waves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report stated that at present, Pudong police have coordinated with hydrology experts from Shanghai Ocean University and Maritime University to analyze the flow direction to further carry out search work. If the general public has relevant clues, please contact the police in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The search and rescue team members said that the girl was about 100 meters away from the shore at the time of the incident&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 7, Li Chenguang, captain of the Shanghai Dandelion Rescue Team, told Nandu reporters, They received help from the morning of the 5th, and on two consecutive nights on the 5th and 6th, about 6 rescue teams with a total of more than 200 people participated in the search. &quot;Yesterday afternoon, the police confirmed that the child was swept away by the sea water, and our search outside the area stopped. The subsequent search work focused on searching in the breakwater along the low-tide coastline after the tide ebbed at around 6 p.m., because the girl might have been swept away. He rushed back and got stuck in the breakwater.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chenguang told Nandu reporters that local police and fire fighters had searched the girl on the night of the 4th, but the search on the nights of the 5th and 6th still did not find the girl. &quot;The Coast Guard also arrived at the scene yesterday. Maybe the government will have more power in the next step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Chenguang, the beach where the incident occurred is a mud beach impacted by rip currents, and the sand quality is not good. It&#39;s not a scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This tidal flat is not allowed to enter now. In fact, everyone has been discouraged from entering, including the victim. They also climbed over it. The coastline here is relatively long. When the weather is good, there are indeed people there every day. We play here, including ourselves sometimes, but the sea water is still quite dangerous. This time I also remind everyone to pay attention to safety, especially to watch the children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About the distance when the girl was lost Regarding the controversy over how far the coast is, Li Chenguang analyzed to Nandu reporters that if the girl went missing around 17:30, the girl&#39;s father was not as far away from the shore as he said when he left. &quot;Because according to the recent hydrological conditions, the exposed beach surface during this period is only one or two hundred meters in total. (Where they are) is about 20 meters from the water and about 100 meters from the shore.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家体育总局原党组成员、副局长杜兆才严重违纪违法被开除党籍和公职]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 15:08:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Du Zhaocai, a former member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the State Sports General Administration, for serious disciplinary violations Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Du Zhaocai lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original intention and mission, failed to perform the main responsibility of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, seriously damaged the political ecology of the football field, resisted organizational censorship, and engaged in superstitious activities; ignored the spirit of the eight central regulations , accepting gifts and money in violation of regulations, accepting banquets from others in violation of regulations; not reporting personal matters in accordance with regulations, and failing to explain problems truthfully when organizing correspondence; using public tools for personal use, &quot;relying on sports to eat sports&quot; and &quot;relying on football to eat football&quot;, and not only want to be an official He also wanted to get rich, engaged in power-for-money transactions, took advantage of his position to benefit others in business operations, employee recruitment, etc., and illegally received huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Zhaocai seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline and life discipline, which constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, which was of a serious nature. , the impact is bad and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Du Zhaocai from the party; by The National Supervisory Commission dismissed him from public office; confiscated his illegal gains that violated disciplines; and transferred his suspected criminal issues to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved was also transferred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[世风日下或许只是错觉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258162]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/BayJvmt4lz9Q9EKVZLrfFKYFOwxjBwld21fViZHQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/BayJvmt4lz9Q9EKVZLrfFKYFOwxj Bwld21fViZHQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253098&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From &quot;the world is declining and people&#39;s hearts are not as old as they used to be&quot; to the endless emergence of &quot;the worst generation&quot; and the &quot;beat generation&quot;, research has found that people are increasingly concerned about moral decay and moral trends. The feeling of being worse spans time and geography and is a common social phenomenon that can even be traced back to more than 2,000 years ago. If such a feeling is real and accurate, it may mean that human moral standards have been steadily declining and reaching new lows for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But there is also another possibility, that is, the general moral decay and declining social order are just people&#39;s illusions. There is a certain pattern behind it that causes people in different eras and different regions to always have such similar feelings. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, researchers from Columbia University and Harvard University used more than 12 million related scientific data to verify people&#39;s views on moral development trends. The results found that the subjective feeling of &quot;the world is declining&quot; is indeed not an individual time. , a phenomenon that occurs in individual places, but is extremely universal. However, through more objective comparisons of survey data over decades, researchers are also convinced that these subjective feelings of &quot;the present is not as good as it used to be&quot; are actually an illusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Universal and lasting feeling&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This study was published in the magazine &quot;Nature&quot; in June 2023 and relied on data from recent times around the world. Sixty countries and a time span of more than 70 years. Through these horizontal and vertical comparisons, the elders have a more scientific explanation for the criticism of young people that &quot;one generation is inferior to the other&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For most people, morality mainly refers to the way people treat other people in daily life, such as whether they are honest, polite or even willing to help others, etc. The researchers used a series of survey data dating back to the 1940s to understand people&#39;s attitudes toward moral changes. The surveys included direct questions about trends, such as “Do you feel our society’s integrity and ethical behavior have changed more, less, or the same over the past few decades?” “Now do you feel the moral values ​​of the country as a whole have changed?” Better or worse?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that in more than 80% of the survey items, most people believe that the moral level of the entire society is declining. Specifically, people are more likely to experience moral decline when the comparison period is longer. For example, when comparing the longer period of the past ten years to the past year, people are more likely to feel that the level of social morality is declining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some recent surveys, researchers have also found that age is also an important factor in how people feel. People will feel that people today are less friendly and less sincere than the people they saw when they were 20 years old. Similarly, they will also feel that the people they saw at 20 years old are not as moral as the people they were born in. And overall, older people feel more morally bankrupt than younger people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But has social morality really been declining? Some more concrete and objective investigation shows that this is not the case. In addition to asking people generally about their feelings about moral changes, decades of survey data include direct questions about a wide range of people&#39;s specific moral behaviors. For example, &quot;Were you respected by the people around you yesterday?&quot; &quot;In the past 12 months, how often did you give up your seat to strangers, give directions, look after things, or lend money to others?&quot; The results of a number of surveys on specific moral behaviors are clear. By comparing people&#39;s records of their own and their peers&#39; moral behaviors in different eras, the moral level is actually relatively stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even when evaluating some specific social and moral issues, people may feel moral improvement. For example, when the survey asked about how to treat people with disabilities and sexual minorities, many people believed that society was making progress. These data all show that although when people generally evaluate social moral changes, they will feel from the bottom of their hearts that morality has been declining or even getting worse. However, by comparing relatively more objective specific moral behaviors, the subjective judgment of moral decline cannot be held up. foot. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Happier and more ethical&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I do often hear people say that people are becoming more and more selfish and less generous. Etc. I hear this statement both from the public and other academics. However, I always point out that the data shows this is not true. This latest study is very convincing and I agree with the author, though Many people feel that this is the case, but there is no objective evidence that moral standards are actually declining.&quot; Abigail Marsh, a professor in the Department of Psychology at Georgetown University, told Southern Weekend reporters that some of her own research shows that , some forms of altruistic behavior are actually on the rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, she collaborated with researchers from the Department of Psychology at Harvard University and other institutions to conduct a summary analysis of survey data on altruistic behavior in a large number of countries. The results found that a country’s altruistic behavior is related to the subjective happiness of local people. There is a positive correlation. When the material resources and cultural value of a place support people from both objective and subjective conditions, and people feel happier, altruistic behavior will also increase. Moreover, the more individualistic values ​​prevail in places, the greater this effect will be. obvious. Relevant research was published in Psychological Science, and similar conclusions were also included in the latest edition of the 2023 World Happiness Report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some data suggest that altruistic behavior, especially toward distant strangers, generally increases over time. This may be because happiness increases, and as happiness increases Altruistic behavior appears to be increasing as well. These studies also show that around the world, where subjective well-being is higher, there are also higher levels of various altruistic and generous behaviors, such as being more likely to donate to charity and volunteer. Serve, help strangers, donate blood, donate organs and bone marrow, and treat animals humanely.&quot; Of course, ethics is more than selflessness and generosity, but these are important components of ethics, Abigail Marsh explains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The findings of the latest research highlight this paradox about morality. On the one hand, human society has been developing in terms of material and spiritual culture, and there is no reasonable explanation for the continued decline in morality. On the other hand, there are differences in the level of development, cultural traditions, and people&#39;s happiness in various places. Under such circumstances, the widespread moral decay is even more unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analysis, Columbia University psychologist Adam M. Mastroianni and Harvard University psychology professor Daniel T. Gilbert, who participated in the latest study, believe , two common psychological laws may explain this strange social phenomenon. One is an attention bias and the other is a memory bias. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Psychological biases that are prone to occur&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A large number of psychological studies have found that humans are fascinated by negative information about others and always tend to search for and pay attention to negative information. It&#39;s such a good thing that negative information in the mass media has received more attention. This creates an attention bias. When recalling past events, people tend to forget those bad experiences and are more likely to remember some good memories, showing a memory bias. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, when people look at the current society, they may pay more attention to the dark side of society, including immoral people and things. When comparing the past, it is easier to remember the good people and good deeds and forget the immoral behavior, thus feeling that the world is deteriorating and people&#39;s hearts are not as old as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to verify the influence of these two psychological effects, the researchers also changed the participants&#39; attention through experiments, asking them to focus on familiar people such as family and friends in their social circle. The results were obvious. Double answer. People believe that the moral level of people in society as a whole is declining, but the moral level of their acquaintances and relatives has not only not declined, but has improved. Similarly, when people put aside the influence of memory bias and compared two eras that they had never experienced, the phenomenon of moral decline also disappeared. Generally speaking, people believe that the moral decay of society begins when they are born. These different answers are indeed intriguing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that there are still some limitations to the latest research, including inaccuracies in historical data measurements. The combined effect of attention and memory biases is only an explanation that the latest research attempts to give, and it is not enough to scientifically prove the reason behind the phenomenon of moral turpitude illusion. People all over the world, both ancient and modern, lament the deterioration of society. There may be other reasons behind this social phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, some scientists have indeed given slightly different explanations before. Researchers from the Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences at the University of California, Santa Barbara believe that personal characteristics play an important role in this phenomenon. In real life, a considerable part of the scenes of lamenting the deterioration of society and moral decline are caused by the elders blaming the younger ones. In the eyes of these elders, today&#39;s children are incomparable to them in the past and have lost many beautiful moral qualities. Research has found that in such accusations, elders can easily form a series of biased opinions based on personal characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, if you are good at something, you will be more likely to focus on other people&#39;s shortcomings in this aspect; if you have advantages or preferences in a certain aspect, you will assume that everyone was like this when you were a child. This self-centered attention bias and memory bias may have given rise to the impression that &quot;one generation is inferior to the other&quot;. In this impression, the shortcomings of young people are so glaring, and the qualities that everyone in the older generation has now been lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Difficulties in changing moral behavior&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;These discussions on moral changes also reflect the complexity of moral issues themselves. In 2019, Jenae M. Neiderhiser, a professor in the Department of Psychology at Pennsylvania State University, and others analyzed the moral development of children in a large number of families and found that moral quality is not entirely determined by the upbringing environment, but rather There are also genetic influences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study, which lasted for nearly ten years, focused on two moral indicators: social responsibility in adolescents and responsibility in early adulthood. Because it also included twins of all types and brothers and sisters in recombined families, it was possible to compare genetics and The role of environmental factors in moral development. Research shows that genetic factors and the upbringing environment provided by parents jointly shape children&#39;s moral character in the early stages of adolescent growth, but after adulthood, the role of parental upbringing weakens. Relevant research was published in Behavior Genetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Professor Abigail Marsh, who has long studied altruistic behavior, moral behavior also has a physiological basis. Compared with the law of survival of the fittest driven by selfishness, altruists are willing to help others even if their own interests are harmed. This is a unique problem from the perspective of evolutionary theory. Abigail Marsh and others have used magnetic resonance imaging to study the brains of a group of extraordinary altruists and found that these people who are willing to donate kidneys to strangers can be identified by characteristics such as an increase in the size of the right amygdala. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People often refer to these extraordinary altruists who are willing to risk themselves to help others as &#39;patron saints&#39; or &#39;saints.&#39; But our research suggests that biological phenomena may help explain why some People engage in extraordinary altruistic behavior. This may be because they have specific neurological and cognitive characteristics that make them more concerned about the well-being of others than the average person.&quot; Abigail, who is also a professor in the Interdisciplinary Program in Neuroscience at Georgetown University Marsh told Southern Weekend reporters that morality is fundamentally about weighing the consequences of oneself and others in behavior, and a series of studies have shown that there are biological differences behind some people choosing to value the happiness of others more. &quot;The brain is designed to learn and adapt. In general, I believe that people help others based on their true values ​​and that they genuinely care about the well-being of others. If people generally become more selfless over time, then It must be because we have learned to value the happiness of others more. What we don’t quite understand, however, is how to increase the importance one attaches to the happiness of others in some targeted way.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It also means that understanding and changing moral behavior itself may be more difficult than the common delusion of moral decay. More importantly, for the real society, if people in a society have formed a consensus of moral decay and believe that the social moral level is declining, then both the direction of public policy and the development of interpersonal behavior will have a negative impact. produce a negative impact. After all, a society with a declining moral level contains the motivation to restore tradition and return to the past in the public arena, which may trigger a series of socially regressive behaviors. And once people believe that the world is in decline, the way of interpersonal communication may also develop in the direction of mutual distrust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many psychological surveys have found that because they underestimate the kindness of strangers, people are more hesitant to ask strangers for help, and they are less afraid to take the initiative to say hello to strangers. This interpersonal environment of mutual distrust has greatly affected people&#39;s happiness and sense of belonging to society. The illusion of a declining social moral level may be one of the reasons for this phenomenon. What’s even more frightening is that people are often very sensitive to changes in social norms and behavioral norms. Once they make a mistake in judgment, it may lead to truly unethical behavior in the subtle process. These highlight the significance of a correct understanding of this illusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[魏明毅：“像个男人”的要求如何伤害男人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/OPKkXxVazmd4ofE5r7XLw1SjL9BW1KszkfaehUff.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/OPKkXxVazmd4ofE5r7XLw1SjL9BW1 KszkfaehUff. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wei Mingyi, writer and psychological counselor, has been engaged in psychological counseling and supervision for decades. Author of &quot;Silent Worker: Days and Nights at the Dock&quot; and &quot;Reflections of Suffering: Field Notes of a Suffering Worker&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 At 11:20 in the morning at the end of August, 53-year-old Taiwanese psychological counselor Wei Mingyi appeared in the video, an hour later than the agreed time. She quickly apologized and explained that when she was helping colleagues at the placement agency in class in the morning, a child with visual limitations suddenly picked up a fruit knife, and she delayed the interview while dealing with this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I told the child that you must have encountered something. Please tell the teacher and we will discuss it together. Put down the knife first, and then we can talk about it.&quot; The crisis was quickly resolved. Every once in a while, Wei Mingyi will go to the resettlement agency to teach colleagues to help children who have been improperly disciplined by their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her new book &quot;Reflections of Suffering: Field Memos of a Suffering Worker&quot; published in March 2023 &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot;)&lt;/span>;Some chapters are also about this kind of children, &quot;They may not be very smart and have great difficulty solving problems. I don&#39;t look at them from the perspective of illness. Usually, People will interact with the outside world in a worse way after being treated inappropriately by the people around them. As long as they are treated in an appropriate way, they can return to their original appearance.&quot; Wei Mingyi sat in front of the screen and talked about this again Eyes red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was probably the inertial outlet behind years of emotional labor. She was not surprised that she shed tears. In 2016, she completed her field record at the Keelung Pier, &quot;Silent Workers: Days and Nights at the Pier&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (the simplified Chinese version will be published in 2022) &lt;/span>;, she would cry when participating in new book sharing and interviews, &quot;I vaguely feel that I am suffering. I still like to work, but why is the heavy feeling still very big.&quot; When she repeatedly talks about the suffering of others, suffering also becomes Her own. The publishing house later simply prepared the paper for her in advance, &quot;because she knew Mingyi would cry in the next scene.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a last resort, she turned down all job offers and flew to a strange country to walk every day. &quot;At that time Only walking makes me comfortable.&quot; Day after day, she found that the suffering she witnessed in the anthropological field gradually became her flesh and blood, which happened to be an opportunity for her to write her second book &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot; is a collection of her more than 20 years of work experience in psychological counseling and social supervision. In it, she writes about her brother who killed his sister due to a dispute over a game, and how she gave birth to a son who had incest with his father and was killed by his family. She happily accepts underage girls, violent women, and men who kill their wives... It has been seven years since her last book was published. During this period, she was still working as a psychological counselor and was used to the continuous daily consultation. I hope that my busy work can alleviate some of the suffering in society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Wei Mingyi’s account:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Even though a large group of people want to do things well, the suffering has not been alleviated&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The so-called appropriate way to treat a child is to go back to the child himself and understand who he is, how he sees the world, and how he thinks. But in a place with high competition and little regard for children&#39;s human rights, this can easily be overlooked. Many inappropriate interactions and parenting stem from parents who do not view their children as human beings with free will, and such children are unlikely to be healthy. We need to know: Children are not extensions of adults. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because there are so many things worth reminding, I often say when I teach parents in Taiwan: If you remember Don&#39;t live too much, just remember not to do anything you regret. Don&#39;t use your words to say hurtful things. We look forward to changing others, but when our eyes look at others, it is easy to forget how we face others. If you want your children to respect you, you must first practice respecting your children. I often wonder, is what I am doing now the same as what I teach others? I remind myself in this way: I have to be a consistent person, otherwise I will be very conflicted internally. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Part of my current job is to provide regular training to parents and institutional colleagues. Reservations usually begin in October of the previous year and are then booked throughout the year. I work 25 days a month and go to two different places every day. When I encounter some special suicide cases, I will be added temporarily. The work is intensive, but I don&#39;t think it&#39;s self-exploitation. If I can do something, I will try to do it as much as possible. It was only in the past two or three years that I discovered that even though a large group of people seriously wanted to do things well, the suffering was not alleviated. The work of a psychological counselor is like doing back-end first aid. No matter how much time I give, the consultation can&#39;t be completed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What&#39;s the problem? If the social structure is relatively healthy and cares about life, suffering will not arise so quickly. In the past few years, I wonder if I can go to the frontier and do some primary prevention work, such as writing a book - to organize the things I have seen over the years into words, so that more people can start to have the opportunity before they get worse. Reflecting on the important role that individuals play in the social structure, the entire social structure and cultural situation may have the potential to change. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These ideas are certainly related to my anthropological training. &quot;The Silent Worker&quot; was a big turning point in my life. Like most people, I used to be quite individualistic and believed that destiny was in the hands of individuals. Facing the general environment, psychology emphasizes adapting through awareness and adjustment. However, from the perspective of anthropology and my field experience in Keelung, I discovered that many things cannot be conquered by man. People are not that great. The role played by the entire social structure and cultural situation is like air that appears around us and affects our lives, but we may not be aware of it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the value of &quot;like a man&quot;, men are also victims&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Silent Worker&quot; was originally a very marginal piece of writing, but the response it aroused was beyond my expectation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2009, as a graduate student in anthropology, I went to Keelung Pier to do fieldwork. During my eight months in the field, I experienced culture shock. After working as a psychological counselor for more than ten years, I thought I knew a lot about Taiwanese workers and their situation. However, when I went to the field, I found that my knowledge was limited. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past, whether it was my work or living environment, &quot;like a man&quot; required men to behave tough. , showing their masculinity. In comparison, women seem to be devalued and in a relatively weak position. But in the field I discovered that this gender label has two sides. &quot;Like a Man&quot; frames a daily ideal, allowing men to act in it, think about how to shape themselves to become a &quot;valuable&quot; man, and constantly evaluate whether they are like an (ideal) man. They have to tread a line and if they fall outside of that line they are not recognized and respected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On the contrary, women seem not to be expected, but they also grow resilience from the trampling of life, This resilience is more evident in older women. For men who were recognized in their young adulthood, their lives almost plummeted when they failed to meet the mainstream value expectations of society. This is also the reason why the suicide rate of men in Keelung is much higher than that of women. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Keelung&#39;s suicide-seeking data ranks among the top two in Taiwan all year round. Suicide is a word that workers often mention in private, but they are reluctant to talk about it in the field. In addition to feeling shameful, the more common reason is: they have no way of understanding. I usually don’t ask my group of dock friends directly if they have any experience of cheating, but if they have heard of or encountered it. Almost everyone will tell me that they have experienced such a thing at some distance or near. Regarding the men around them who have experienced and heard about men who have died suddenly, the most common expression they express is &quot;I&#39;m just fine as usual, I don&#39;t see anything wrong with it.&quot; These responses reminded me of reporter Wang Jialong’s desire to “speak” and “be heard.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​afternoon in the field, Wang Jialong, as usual, said in a local voice that he would take me to try it Authentic snacks that only Keelung people know. But based on previous experiences, I knew he wanted to say something, and he always used food as the excuse. He first talked about how he was careful not to blurt out in front of his current girlfriend that his specialty was actually taught by his ex-girlfriend, and then said that he had some things that he never knew who he could tell:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s from outside. At first, I just call and listen to your voice. Then I want to meet your person, and then I ask you to stay overnight. ;Later, I don’t want your money, I want your people. At that time, my wife and girlfriend were committing suicide, cutting their wrists, and taking sleeping pills. I also took sleeping pills. At that time, I felt that things were all mixed together, such as the privatization of the dock. I didn’t know what the future would be like, and I had a headache every day. As a result, one day the crime team called me and told me that my girlfriend had jumped from the building where we lived together. If a good person becomes like this in our family, others may think that I am good, but I know that it will end in tragedy. (Original words of Wang Jialong)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So you see, if others don’t know that Wang Jialong has committed a crime, they all I think it’s great that he has many girlfriends. He had no one to talk to about these things, because he couldn&#39;t show his weak side and he had to maintain his dignity. When the entire society emphasizes that men are superior to women and that men should &quot;be like men&quot;, men&#39;s suffering is also rooted in this value system. These are things I didn&#39;t realize before. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IzZQAXNo5QvBSgbB0M1rfpEv44vXH3YGKZqwUaJw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 677&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IzZQAXNo5QvBSgbB0M1rfpEv44vXH3YGKZqwUaJw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;In Tea Shop, they are seen as human beings&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The roles of psychological counselors and researchers are actually very different. When running in the fields, whenever I have something to say to the other person, I will ask myself who I am now and from what perspective I am speaking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​of my teachers said that it is okay to do something for the field, but you must After having a clear idea of ​​what exactly happened in the field. Sometimes we want to help others, but we may not understand them well enough and intervene too crudely. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So when the dock workers complain that I don’t understand, I won’t feel uncomfortable. After staying at the dock for more than two months, a reporter said, Miss Wei, you talk to us in the waiting room every day, without basking in the sun or waiting for work in the middle of the night. You don&#39;t know our hard work. Ask us. Will it be close to our reality? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I agreed and would follow him to the dock at midnight the next day and persist until the end of the field. This is &quot;a gate&quot; in the field. The day I showed up at the dock in the early morning, I knew that I was recognized by him. Although I still didn&#39;t understand, I wanted to understand their world, rather than standing in a distant and comfortable position. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After running with this group of dock workers for several months, I found that the information I collected was missing. The female part. At that time, there were not many opportunities for dock workers to go to the &quot;tea shop&quot;, but it was still a topic they often talked about. Although 2009 was well past the busiest period in Keelung as dock workers said, when walking along the port city streets, leisure and entertainment venues such as teahouses, tea shops, and karaoke bars are scattered everywhere. They were connected with the red lights (sex industry area) next to the railway tracks and became the most popular area in Keelung Port City before the late 1990s. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is less than one kilometer away from the dock, and dock workers gather here every day. Take the tea shop as an example. Men not only chat and kill time there, but also wait for the boat. Every small shielded space in the house is also a place where they connect with each other and coordinate their work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Most of the workers in Tea Shop are foreign women with financial difficulties - mostly their spouses or their own Gambling debts, or financial hardship accumulated from previous generations. They moved into this strange port city alone or with their young children in hand, and became &quot;aunties&quot; (female waiters) who could not be called young in the teahouse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first time I stepped into Tea Shop was with Li Zhengde (one of the reporters). After entering the door, I saw a table lamp on inside, and the light illuminated a lady with her head lowered at the counter. Li Zhengde&#39;s accompanying friend called her &quot;Auntie&quot; as soon as he entered the door. The latter raised his head from the counter, was stunned for a second or two, and then responded with a smile: &quot;Oh, A Liang, you are here.&quot; Ms. Chen, whom A Liang calls &quot;Auntie,&quot; has long wavy hair, Lightly applied makeup, about 60 years old. After a brief exchange of greetings, Ms. Chen took us up the stairs, helped us order food, and chatted briefly with the three of us. In just ten minutes, she seemed to pay attention to everyone inadvertently, and no one was left out or forgotten in the conversation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some people confide some unhappiness, and some people get comfort when toasting and clinking glasses. What I experienced in it was not the ambiguous flow of emotions and hormones, but the extremely high concentration of emotional exchanges catalyzed by the men on the dock, and the care Auntie showed for everyone in the house in such a small room. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This feeling of being cared for and seen is something that dock workers cannot get from their families. When they come home from a busy day, they are expected to be like a husband: bringing home the household items and taking care of the children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/V3qL8sq2s98Jfb7nY1pP0mpnkOOxcPYK0OOZVUmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/V3qL8sq2s98Jfb7nY1pP0mpnkOOxcPYK0OOZVUmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Keelung, a fisherman rides a bicycle past the fishing boats moored at the pier&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Let&#39;s imagine a scenario: My wife is tired after doing a lot of housework at home one day, and receives a call from the teacher saying that the child is at school Naughty and mischievous, her child came home from school with a list of fees to be paid, but she found that there was not enough money. At this time, when her husband came home from get off work, her first thought must be that there was not enough money. Is there any way to give me money? She may also hope that her husband can discipline the children, and she has no time to take care of the tired look on her husband&#39;s face. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The relationship between husband and wife inherently implies some responsibilities and obligations, and the relationship between the dock worker and his aunt Tsai&#39;s social relationship is completely different. They have no responsibilities to bear when going to the tea shop, as long as they enjoy being taken care of. This is also the reason why companion culture is prevalent among dock workers. Once men get married, their roles as husbands and fathers are very thinly regarded. Their roles as human beings can only be restored in spaces like Tea Shop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;All endings are to be continued&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Talking about Tea Shop Boy Dock workers will also mention red light shops, but they will emphasize that they go to tea shops more often. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When dock workers go to tea shops to chat with aunties, they will think that they are equal and there is no sexual involvement. . Even though the relationship later develops into a romantic and sexual relationship, in their hearts, Auntie is completely different from the women in prostitution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This distinction is actually influenced by Confucian culture, that is to say, a person distinguishes himself through his own The body (which is extremely devalued in Confucian culture) or labor in exchange for money are divided into high and low. They are two distinct classes. As consumers, going to tea shops will be regarded as having sufficient economic capital, but if they use money to go to prostitutes, they will be &quot;reduced&quot; to relatively powerless people - they need to pay directly to obtain sexual relations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This distinction is not only for women, but also for themselves. For example, as a female graduate student, the way they talk to me is different from the way I talk to my aunties. I was bookish to them, and my gender as a woman was downplayed. When they chat with me, they match my word choices, switch from dialect to Mandarin, and never smoke. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the late 1990s, with the rapid shift of international routes, international cargo ships left Keelung Port one after another. Amid price-cutting competition from private companies, port stevedores and container truck drivers have become direct bearers of the era of &quot;small profits&quot; claimed by cross-border companies. Most of the workers were forced to leave the docks, and the wages of those who remained on the docks were cut by more than half. This not only means a change in their economic conditions, but also reshapes their original cluster-style work space. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6mG5MbmwjFb10YpfsU1dKX8xixRgScScZdRAHAxc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6mG5MbmwjFb10YpfsU1dKX8xixRgScScZdRAHAxc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Keelung Port&#39;s container yard&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;With the wave of layoffs, dock workers were driven back to their families. But over a long period of time, the accompanying culture has long pulled the dock workers away from their families. When they returned in the lower class era, they found that there was only an atmosphere of family dinners with nothing to say, the children&#39;s accusations of their father&#39;s early absence, and the fact that their father could no longer provide enough Quarrel and conflict over money. Their former event space was also developed into an ocean plaza by the local government to attract more tourists. They were expelled from the visible public space because their image did not conform to the international tourist image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The sad thing is that they often blame themselves for their decline. When a person&#39;s suffering stems from social structures but is seen as a personal problem, he may become immobilized and have a lot of self-blame. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After &quot;Silent Worker&quot; was published in Taiwan in 2016, many readers said it looked very good and felt that the dock The workers’ stories are harrowing. After hearing these comments, I also reflected. What readers are reading is the story. How to connect us with what happened to the dock workers? Therefore, when I wrote &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot;, I changed my style and became very analytical. I didn&#39;t want to be a person who sells stories. After &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot; was published this year, readers said it was painful to read. I said that was right, because pain is the truth of life. Many readers have also asked me that our suffering seems to be related to the overall environment. What should we do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Don’t forget that no matter how large the social structure is, it is still composed of many individuals. If I didn&#39;t believe in personal power, I wouldn&#39;t quit working to write a book. Even if what we do now is in line with social and cultural expectations, as long as our awareness is clear, given time, you can go in the opposite direction. As long as people&#39;s free will is still there, they will not be co-opted or become something they don&#39;t like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you have the opportunity to come to Keelung recently, you will find that Ocean Plaza, which is often visited by tourists, has Street performers with local characteristics sing songs that dockworkers would listen to. In the evening, everyone sat in the square watching the sea and listening to songs. Ocean Plaza was originally planned as a very middle-class place, but local people changed its purpose. So, as I wrote in &quot;Reflection of Suffering&quot;, all endings are unfinished. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Part of the content is quoted from &quot;Silent Workers&quot; and &quot;Reflections of Suffering&quot;. Thanks to Chen Meiyi for her help with this article. Reference: &quot;Mirror Weekly&quot;.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳一安居房被指总造价1亿，未完工已提取10亿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Aoyi News noticed from the &quot;Leadership Message Board&quot; of People&#39;s Daily Online that in mid-September, many netizens reported that , the construction progress of the Tianhe Beiyuan project located in Longhua District is slow, and the building has not been fully topped out according to the construction plan. At the same time, there is a problem of over-withdrawal of construction funds. The total main construction fund is 104.1 million yuan, but 1 billion yuan has actually been withdrawn before completion. We sincerely request the relevant departments to intervene in the investigation and bring the funds into supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, the Longhua District Housing and Construction Bureau and the Shenzhen Municipal Housing and Construction Bureau responded through the above platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the Tianhe Beiyuan project is located at the intersection of Longguan Avenue and Shiqing Avenue, Fucheng Street, Longhua District, Shenzhen City. All the residences in the project are affordable commercial housing, with a total of 3 towers. The estimated delivery time is before June 30, 2025. The average placement price is 27,250 yuan/㎡. The developer is Shenzhen Baiheng Trading Co., Ltd., a subsidiary of Sino-Ocean Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/b863e53bd47586c3b7f6a8b9613d52ae.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/b863e53bd47586c3b7f6a8b9613d52ae.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253179&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Public information&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Problem 1:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The building was not fully capped according to the construction plan &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 14, some netizens said that the construction progress of the Tianhe Beiyuan project was slow, and as of that day, the three towers had not been capped. &quot;According to the construction plan, all three units in Beiyuan can be capped by the end of July, but the construction progress has been delayed. After communication and feedback from the Security Administration, the capping can be completed on August 31, but once again the capping has not been completed. The developer has been working hard. The latest The feedback is that all services will be capped on September 20th,” the netizen added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the &quot;Tianhe Beiyuan Construction and Acceptance Plan&quot; provided by other netizens, it can be seen that the construction of the main structure will start on June 14, 2023, and the completion time will be August 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f8027eefc4c09c6b8e5213a9a52890f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;547&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f8027eefc4c09c6b8e5213a9a52890f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253175&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, the Shenzhen Municipal Housing and Construction Bureau responded to the issues reported by netizens, saying, &quot;The Municipal Housing and Construction Bureau has interviewed the project leader and enterprise leader of the construction unit, and issued a letter of supervision, requesting the construction unit Increase investment in manpower, material resources, and financial resources, carefully organize construction, speed up construction progress, and ensure that the building is delivered on time. Tianhe Beiyuan was capped on September 19.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d31cc51ff48fe0f45eab59ed59b9e5a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;435&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/d31cc51ff48fe0f45eab59ed59b9e5a4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Question 2:&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Excessive Withdrawal of Construction Funds&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 14th and 15th, many netizens reported that the Tianhe Beiyuan Project’s construction funds were overdrawn. The total capital for the main construction is 104.1 million yuan, but 1 billion yuan has actually been withdrawn before completion. We sincerely request the relevant departments to intervene in the investigation and bring the funds under supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0a9589e082888d0fe44d261b2319625e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0a9589e082888d0fe44d261b2319625e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253177&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The project overview map attached by netizens shows that the total cost of the project is 104.1 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fcb9152d01206ad3f516ceb8900b188c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/fcb9152d01206ad3f516ceb8900b188c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253176&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, on September 22, the Longhua District Housing and Construction Bureau stated, “It is understood that the Tianhe Beiyuan project fund supervision agreement was signed by the construction unit, the bank, and the supervision unit. According to the agreement signed by the three parties and Relevant regulations stipulate that banks and supervisory units shall supervise the use of pre-sale funds. In order to respond to the owners&#39; demands and do a good job in supervising project funds, our bureau has ordered the development enterprise to include the pre-sale fund account within the scope of administrative supervision. The development enterprise has agreed and Cooperate. Due to the low level of bank cooperation, our bureau has issued a letter requesting the regulatory banks to cooperate in bringing the project pre-sale capital account into the scope of administrative supervision. At the same time, it notified the Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau of the relevant situation to assist in promoting the inclusion of pre-sale capital accounts in administrative supervision. .&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Longhua District Housing and Construction Bureau said, “In the next step, our bureau will strengthen communication and coordination with the Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau and banks to bring the Tianhe Beiyuan project pre-sale fund account into the scope of administrative supervision as soon as possible. , Strictly supervise the use of special funds by development enterprises. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/566e782610518e8fb7de969a4e843741.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/566e782610518e8fb7de969a4e843741.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253178&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, the Shenzhen Municipal Housing and Construction Bureau responded, “Regarding the issue of supervision of the use of pre-sale funds, the Municipal Housing and Construction Bureau has requested the Longhua District Housing and Construction Bureau to verify the status of the used funds, and Strengthen the supervision of pre-sale funds to ensure the normal use of funds. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0d163bf84be799d03fac6abebe1c9b64.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/0d163bf84be799d03fac6abebe1c9b64.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253180&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aoyi News is synthesized from People&#39;s Daily Online &quot;Leadership Message Board&quot; and Shenzhen Housing and Construction Bureau&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘玉栋痛批男篮“软骨头”“没血性”：赛场是社会的映像]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258174]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, basketball star Liu Yudong made sharp criticism of the men’s basketball performance in an exclusive interview: “They Reluctant to work hard, even though the conditions are so good. He&#39;s all soft and weak, with no spirit at all. &quot;He can&#39;t show his bloody side, it&#39;s just because he has developed a habit.&quot; &quot;This man should do it, you have to do it.&quot; Go fight, you are too timid to act like a man, but you are not fighting like a man.&quot; This caused a lot of resonance and discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Have athletes lost their fighting spirit and vigor as their incomes have increased and their training conditions have improved? Obviously, the two are not necessarily related. There are also top athletes who have higher incomes, better training conditions, and still have high morale. This situation is even more common. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation is incentives. If the athlete&#39;s level is not outstanding and there is a significant gap compared with the international level, but due to the popularity of domestic fans and commercial endorsements, he can get high income, then for the athlete, the marginal benefit of continuing to work hard will be very small. Well, as long as we can compete on the field, why bother fighting to the death? On the contrary, if an athlete can only get a high salary if he performs well on the field, then he will have a strong incentive to work hard and maximize his potential. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to motivation, as an athlete, internal drive is also important, if not more important. To do something well, it is not enough to rely on incentives such as fame and fortune. You must feel that doing it well has intrinsic meaning and you have a strong motivation to do it. What supports all of this is your own personality. Inner endowment: You must have strong vitality, blood, courage, fighting spirit, a sense of honor, a field from the inside out, a strong and radiant soul, in a word, you must have a strong spirit Kernel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, to accomplish something, the methodology or technical approach comes second, and the motivation or internal driving force to accomplish it comes first. If you have internal drive, you won&#39;t feel it&#39;s hard to work hard, and you will devote yourself to it and get closer to your goal step by step. On the other hand, if you need a strong push from the outside world or outsiders to do this, your internal motivation is insufficient. You will neither set high goals for yourself nor strive for excellence, and will just muddle along. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This strong vitality, drive, or courage is often called &quot;masculinity.&quot; Society as a whole expects men to possess these qualities, so-called &quot;like a man.&quot; But this does not mean that courage or &quot;masculinity&quot; are only possessed by men. Margaret Thatcher and Dong Mingzhu are examples of such women. In fact, regardless of whether you are a man or a woman, no matter what era or country you are in, if a person wants to achieve success, the most important personal trait is to have courage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When watching sports, people hope to feel the beauty of speed and strength, to feel the courage and bloodiness from the athletes&#39; sweaty struggles in the arena, and to witness challenges and breakthroughs to human beings&#39; own limits. This is what people who spend money and time to watch events hope to get. Athletes who fail to provide this are doing their consumers/supporters a debt. Liu Yudong&#39;s criticism of the men&#39;s basketball team should be viewed in this sense. After all, Liu Yudong knew what he wanted to do and has always understood what the public expects from athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, the playing field is a reflection of society. There is a longstanding public discussion about courage or &quot;masculinity.&quot; The discussion focused on the phenomenon that today&#39;s children seem to be becoming more and more fragile, and boys are increasingly lacking &quot;masculinity&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being mentally fragile is not a good thing. How can a child grow into a qualified adult if he cannot bear a little setback? This has resulted in many children becoming &quot;neotenish&quot; when they grow up, without the mental state that adults should have. A lack of “masculinity” in boys is also not a good thing. We cannot think that it is no big deal for men to be more feminine and at the same time hope that men will stand up to injustice when they see it. We cannot think that children must be &quot;obedient&quot; and &quot;good&quot; at the same time, and at the same time hope that they will have a strong spiritual core when they grow up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone has seen the &quot;disappeared ten minutes between classes&quot;. This is indeed caused by many factors, and many parties are responsible. It is not difficult to find that the main consideration of this move is to eliminate various risks that children face in school. This approach and its educational outlook are very problematic. Children cannot go downstairs or go to the playground during class, and are stuck in the classroom most of the time. This is contrary to children&#39;s nature of loving freedom and playing. How can it be possible to let children Are children mentally robust, robust and antifragile? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, it is common to count class points, which leads to children supervising and grading children. If a child commits a minor offense, the class points will be deducted, and group sitting and companionship will be carried out, creating confusion between teachers and students. Confrontation with children. Children with a little bit of personality will be subject to various disciplines, pressure and &quot;polishing&quot;. Education is to maximize children&#39;s talents and inspire good spiritual qualities and values, rather than blindly disciplining and cultivating obedience, leaving children mentally fragile and depressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Read Gong Zizhen&#39;s &quot;Records of the Sick Plum Pavilion&quot;: &quot;Plums are beautiful when they are curved, but they are shapeless when they are straight; they are beautiful when they are straight, but they have no scenery; they are beautiful when they are sparse, but they are shapeless when they are dense.&quot; , this is a sick aesthetic. &quot;Put them straight and nourish their side branches; cut them dense and kill their young branches; hoe them straight and suppress their vitality.&quot; This is a morbid practice based on morbid aesthetics. Don&#39;t make our children sick. &quot;Allow them to obey, destroy their basins, bury them all in the ground, and untie their brown bonds; within five years, they will be restored and all will be restored.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, there are problems in the arena, but I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s not just a problem. Problems on the playing field; athletes have problems, but I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s not just an athlete&#39;s problem, the social problems it reflects are even more worthy of concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[相似的人为什么会产生吸引力？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258164]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/LptLfvffb5ltkCpCuQ9EKoy47JeD9aGBVQcu2P5I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/LptLfvffb5ltkCpCuQ9EKoy47JeD9aGB VQcu2P5I. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Birds of a feather flock together, and people flock together. A large amount of research shows that similarity attracts a powerful rule in interpersonal communication. R. Matthew Montoya, a psychologist at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, has analyzed more than 300 related experiments and surveys, and the results show that the relationship between interpersonal attraction and similarity is very significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this association is not only reflected in the actual similarity, but also in the perceived similarity. That is to say, in social interaction, not only the objective degree of similarity will generate attraction between people, but also the subjective feeling of similarity will enhance interpersonal attraction. Therefore, even if two people have only a short relationship or even no interaction at all, as long as they feel that they are similar to each other, they may be attracted to each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, why does similarity attract? For a long time, psychologists did not agree on the mechanism behind this. Recently, researchers from institutions such as Boston University and Stanford University tried to explore the mechanism behind the similarity attraction effect through a series of experiments. Their findings suggest that the psychological laws of self-essentialist reasoning may lead to people being attracted to similar people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Imagination of essential fit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Essentialist reasoning is actually very common in daily life. In addition to using &quot;nature is hard to change&quot; to predict a person&#39;s In addition to human development trends, people are also accustomed to making moral judgments by tracing the good and bad of their &quot;essence&quot; to comprehensively evaluate people&#39;s behaviors and motivations. In the process of essentializing everything around them, people will try to find the inherent unchangeable characteristics of a thing to define it, and at the same time, get rid of the illusion attached to it to recognize the essence of a thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, although wolves and dogs look very similar, a wolf is a wolf and a dog is a dog. There are essential differences. The behavior of a group of people may be very different and elusive, but through their occupation, community, region and other social attributes, the essentialist reasoning method will allow people to naturally deduce some essential attributes they share. In the process of essentializing the self, people will also unconsciously ask what kind of nature the true self has deep inside. When carrying out various social activities and facing complicated interpersonal relationships, this nature of the self will be revealed. Doctrine reasoning has become an important reference for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through four sets of experiments involving more than 2,000 people, researchers believe that the reason why people are attracted to similar people can be roughly divided into two processes. First, people gain insight into some of their own essential characteristics based on the belief in self-essentialism, and then refer to these to define people with common attributes as people who are very similar to themselves. Secondly, use essentialist reasoning to project their other essential characteristics onto similar people, and form an overall impression of similar people through speculation, thereby strengthening their own understanding of the world. Relevant research was published in the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology in April 2023, providing a new explanation for revealing the laws of interpersonal communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first set of experiments, nearly a thousand participants were randomly assigned to some controversial social issue situations to learn their views on the death penalty, euthanasia, gun ownership and other issues. Subsequently, the researchers also introduced participants to a virtual character named Jamie through reading materials. To some, Jamie has similar views on social issues, while to others, Jamie has very different views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers then measured people&#39;s essentialist beliefs about themselves, as well as indicators of Jamie&#39;s attraction to them. As expected, the more participants endorsed self-essentialism, the belief that there are constant qualities within themselves, the more likely they were to be attracted to Jamie, who shared similar views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In subsequent experiments, the researchers continued to verify some of the key nodes and found that even small similarities are enough to generate attraction. However, if the essentialist concept and broader similarities are severed, The correlation between people makes people believe that the similarity of opinions has nothing to do with the essential fit, and the effect of similarity attraction is weakened. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Complex Attraction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the reasoning of attraction through similarity, the process of inferring commonalities against the essential characteristics of individuals is extremely critical. . People usually start from the similarities they find between the two parties and imagine in their minds that they have more things in common with each other, thereby feeling stronger attraction to the other party. But when the researchers told participants that this cognitive style was inaccurate and could not form reliable perceptions of others, the effect of similar attraction also weakened. These controlled experiments further suggest that some of the thought processes associated with self-essentialist reasoning may be causally related to the similarity attraction effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of attraction through similarity has been discovered for a long time, but previously, psychologists mainly explained this phenomenon from the aspects of motivation and cognition. For example, one view is that there are people with similar ideas to oneself, which actually validates one&#39;s own ideas and satisfies people&#39;s pursuit of a consistent worldview, which will obviously generate positive emotions and attraction. There is also the idea that shared characteristics and perspectives mean greater support, which is positive information for a social goal. The findings of the latest research mean that the unconscious cognitive mode of self-essentialist reasoning may be a major mechanism behind similar attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human social relationships are complex. Some people attract much attention and are attractive to many people, while most people have limited attraction. Psychologist Matthew Montoya once proposed a two-dimensional model for understanding interpersonal attraction, which focuses on assessing a person&#39;s abilities and willingness. Interpersonal attraction to another person is strong if one person has both the ability to promote the needs and goals of another and the underlying willingness to do so. And these attractions are usually expressed through some behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, some researchers summarized some attraction-related behaviors through survey analysis, such as eye contact, smiling, imitation, etc. These behaviors caused by interpersonal attraction also contribute to trust. of construction. Compared with indirect behaviors such as eye contact, smiling, and imitation, more direct behaviors such as physical contact and conversation have a stronger relationship with perceived attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, once a threat is anticipated and the possibility of rejection is high, people&#39;s behavior will be affected even if they feel emotionally attracted. The research, published in the Psychological Bulletin, provides some insights into concrete understanding of attraction. Compared with these external manifestations, the latest research focuses on the source of attraction, providing a mechanistic explanation for the phenomenon of similar attraction. It should be noted that the latest research also has some obvious limitations that may affect the understanding of related phenomena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the attraction measured in the study belongs to the first impression. Although the first impression is also very important when meeting by chance, going on a blind date, or communicating with strangers on social software, it is not important in daily life. In subsequent interactions, there are actually a large number of different social situations, and attraction may not only depend on the first impression. Furthermore, the social and cultural background of the psychological experiment participants in the study lacks sufficient representation, and the differences in the idea of ​​self-essentialism in different cultural environments may affect relevant conclusions. These need to be confirmed by more research in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is not easy to understand others&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In modern society, contact with strangers is a normal part of life. In some interactions, a few words of conversation can give you the feeling of feeling like old friends and cherishing each other at first sight. According to the latest research, this warm experience of finding similar people is likely based on self-essentialist beliefs and related reasoning processes. For society as a whole, this discovery may help people understand some of the bad phenomena related to human nature in modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, people can infer or even assert the nature of others based on only a small amount of observations, and divide people around them into different camps based on similarities and differences in only some of their views, creating group antagonisms. In these cases, whether it is the attraction caused by similarity or the distance caused by dissimilarity, it affects people&#39;s ability to obtain the real situation and is not conducive to making accurate judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of researchers, understanding others is an extremely difficult thing compared to understanding oneself, and new research findings mean that people are always accustomed to using their own feelings to understand others through speculation and other methods. People, and this way of reasoning obviously has certain problems. Although the similarity attraction effect allows people to see themselves in other similar people, get to know themselves better, and build their own social circle, this way of thinking of labeling people based on initial impressions can also easily exclude some people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In public life, this may lead to people fighting against dissimilar people because of less important differences such as interests and hobbies, and in business decisions, an overly self-centered approach to decision-making can also lead to The efficiency becomes lower. Using self as a reference to judge who is more like you and who is not like you. This model of attraction generation may seem simple, but it may not be an effective way. &amp;nbsp;Nevertheless, the attraction generated by similarity as a guide for relationships appears to be an important rule in the development of romantic relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Youyou Wu, a researcher at the Department of Psychology at the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom, and others pointed out in a study in Psychological Science that relationships between partners and friends Not only will they be more similar in terms of region, age, education level, concepts and IQ, but they will also be more similar in personality. However, Wu Youyou also explained to Southern Weekend reporters that it is not yet certain whether people are together because they are similar, or whether they become similar because they are together. There is also insufficient evidence whether attracting people together by similarity is more conducive to the development of relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A rational view of the attraction effect&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, even so, some other phenomena found in romantic relationship research still support the similar attraction effect to a certain extent. Influence. For example, it is common for friends to develop into lovers. A survey by psychologists at the University of Victoria showed that nearly two-thirds of people said they had or currently had the experience of developing a relationship with a friend. In the friend stage, they not only spend a lot of time together to understand and communicate with each other, but also have many similarities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, psychological research based on German society also found that people tend to find another person with similar personality traits to their ex even after breaking up. Relevant research was published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoobin Park, a scientist at the Department of Psychology at the University of Toronto who participated in this study, told Southern Weekend reporters that repeatedly looking for similar people as romantic partners has both advantages and disadvantages. The place. The good thing is that people already have relatively familiar strategies for getting along with similar people, and can make better use of their past social experiences to deal with future challenges. But the bad thing is that once you encounter similar obstacles that you can&#39;t get over, the ending of the relationship may be similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These phenomena that may be related to the similar attraction effect remind people that they should treat the attraction caused by similar partial characteristics rationally. From age, height to income and job, many people are accustomed to using quantitative comparison as a reference for finding a partner or even a marriage partner, in order to find someone with very similar material conditions. However, large-scale studies on partnerships have shown that indicators such as a partner’s personal characteristics are generally less effective in predicting the quality of a partnership. Whether it is a high degree of education or a high income, it does not mean that you will definitely have a high-quality partner in the future. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most predictive indicator is the relationship itself, which is the dynamic feelings partners have toward each other during their long-term relationship, such as trust, mutual appreciation, perceived commitment of the other party, etc. Combined with the findings of the latest research, these dynamic relationship situations are not achieved by similar attraction like love at first sight, but rely on the continuous maintenance of the relationship during the long-term relationship between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, it is worth noting that the similarity attraction effect is not only reflected in romantic relationships, acquaintance relationships or even real relationships. As a more common psychological phenomenon, between strangers who pass by each other, Even between people who interact only virtually, attraction can arise because of similarity. The relationships between these strangers, and the corresponding risks, also deserve attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[议长麦卡锡被本党议员罢免，共和党发生了什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258176]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/8JIm3FXtzEvK6ZLvOiGThdO8pWzxcRrYA4R56xdj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/8JIm3FXtzEvK6ZLvOiGThdO8pW zxcRrYA4R56xdj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, the U.S. Capitol in Washington, Florida Republican Congressman Martin Gates talks with reporters after the House Republican meeting &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 3, 2023, United States A shocking scene unfolded in the House of Representatives. Proposed by Republican Congressman Matt Gaetz, a majority of 216 votes to 210 voted to remove House Speaker McCarthy, who will only take office in January 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since taking office on January 7, 2023, McCarthy has only been in office for 269 days, making him the speaker of the House of Representatives with the third shortest term in U.S. history. This is also the first time in the history of American politics that a speaker has been removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, the reason for McCarthy&#39;s removal was that he cooperated with the Democratic Party to pass a temporary federal funding bill before the October 1st deadline, which prevented the Biden government from shutting down and angered those in the party. Far right. The current hijacking of the entire party by far-right groups within the Republican Party has made it difficult to bridge the gap between the traditional right-wing represented by McCarthy and the far-right represented by Matt Gaetz. This may be the deeper reason for McCarthy&#39;s removal. reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/fSmZnF5IF2nbIUzWskCfOK3Ocmsj83OZ0yP5eAmv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/fSmZnF5IF2nbIUzWskCfOK3Ocmsj83OZ0yP5eAmv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023, in Washington, the United States, former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi (front right) and Representative Maxine Waters (front left) Conversation outside the Capitol &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The budget is the trigger&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;November 2022 In the mid-term elections, the Republican Party won 222 seats in the 435-member House of Representatives, becoming the majority party, but with only a slim 9-vote advantage. This made the far-right &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; (Freedom Caucus) with only a dozen people a &quot; The key few forces are those who fail to succeed but fail to succeed. In January 2023, Rep. Kevin McCarthy, a Republican from California, was elected speaker after a record 15 rounds of voting. The reason was the constant vetoes from members of the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot;, of which Matt Gaetz was the leader. member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, McCarthy gave them major concessions, including allowing anyone in the party to bring a motion to remove the speaker—a new rule that McCarthy later backed down to, which he himself had nodded to months earlier. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of the matter is the budget. The U.S. government&#39;s new fiscal year begins on October 1 of each year. Presumably to allow time for protracted bargaining in Congress, the Biden administration had already proposed a budget for the next year as early as March 2023, but the two parties have been unable to reach a consensus in the next six months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The far-right Republican Party hopes to significantly reduce government spending to alleviate the serious fiscal deficit and ease the debt crisis. At the same time, it will spend more money on domestic issues such as the border refugee crisis and reduce aid to Ukraine; the Democratic Party believes that Assisting vulnerable groups is the government&#39;s obligation. Supporting specific industries through tax cuts and subsidies is to maintain the competitiveness of the United States. Aiding Ukraine is an international obligation of the United States as a global leader, so it opposes spending cuts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The matter was delayed until the end of September. If there is no budget, according to the law, after October 1, except for a few essential public services, all other government workers must take unpaid leave. This is commonly known as a &quot;government shutdown.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1976, there have been 21 government shutdowns in the U.S. government, most of which occurred during Clinton’s term as president. The then Speaker of the House of Representatives, Gingrich, caused many artificial shutdowns because of his disagreement with Clinton. The &quot;Government Shutdown&quot; incident; the longest government shutdown occurred from 2018 to 2019, when then-President Trump and congressional Democrats were in a stalemate over the construction of a border wall, resulting in the failure of the government budget to pass. That government shutdown lasted 35 days, running through the Christmas and New Year holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the government shutdown was about to happen again, House Speaker McCarthy pushed the House to propose an interim budget a few hours before the deadline. It was finally passed by a vote of 335 to 91, and then the bill was passed in the Senate It also passed by a vote of 88 to 9 to extend federal funding until November 17. The crisis of government shutdown is temporarily lifted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although McCarthy deliberately excluded the content of aid to Ukraine in the interim budget to appease the extreme right wing of the party, the latter did not appreciate it. They found it difficult to accept McCarthy&#39;s betrayal of cooperating with the Democratic Party, so they left it to the Democratic Party. Gates took the lead in proposing a motion to remove McCarthy from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although McCarthy was dismissed by the Republican Party because he cooperated with the Democratic Party to pass the interim budget, politics is realistic. The Democratic Party does not intend to help McCarthy retain the speakership, and they also have a high degree of distrust in McCarthy, including McCarthy. Not long ago, he also led the launch of the impeachment investigation against President Biden, and tried his best to please former President Trump after the Capitol riots on January 6, 2021, etc. The 2024 election is only a year and a month away, and Democrats are probably happy to see their competitors in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the centrists of the Democratic Party had communicated with McCarthy in private before, but McCarthy did not show goodwill and put forward clear exchange conditions, so the Democratic Party had no incentive to come to the rescue. Jeffries, the Democratic leader of the House of Representatives, said in a letter to all his fellow Democratic members: &quot;It is the responsibility of Republican members to end the Republican civil war in the House of Representatives.&quot; As a result, all Democrats voted in support of the recall bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, of the 216 votes supporting the recall, Gates and his Republican comrades only contributed 8 votes, while the Democrats contributed 208 votes; the Republicans voted 210 against; among the 7 who did not vote, 4 Democrats and 3 Republicans. Gates&#39; political revenge, combined with the Democratic Party&#39;s political calculations, ended McCarthy&#39;s career as speaker just 72 hours after the interim budget was passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;McCarthy finally accepted the vote results with a smile and said he did not regret cooperating with the Democratic Party. It should be said that he demonstrated the sense of responsibility and responsibility of a veteran politician. This kind of cross-party cooperation based on national interests was originally very common and considered a fine tradition of American politics. However, in recent years, due to the deepening of partisan differences, it has become It&#39;s becoming increasingly rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XFX5oFvfLliIzWgZhhS2xlPhyLL09UnsUHmUNjrL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XFX5oFvfLliIzWgZhhS2xlPhyLL09UnsUHmUNjrL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, live footage of the House of Representatives voting to remove Republican House Speaker McCarthy in Washington, D.C.&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who is Matt Gates? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Matt Gaetz, who took the lead in calling for McCarthy’s removal, was born in May 1982. He has been a federal representative representing Florida’s first district since 2016 and has been re-elected three times. His father, Don Gates, was also a politician and served as president of the Florida Senate. Matt Gates had previously been implicated in a scandal of paying for sex with underage girls, but the Justice Department finally decided not to prosecute in February 2023 after a two-year investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matt Gaetz represents a congressional district with conservative values. Since running for the House of Representatives for the first time in 2016, he has led by more than 30% in a total of 4 elections. , there is no need to worry that his idiosyncratic behavior will have a negative impact on his political career. Voters obviously like his ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of philosophy, Gates actually has a lot in common with the left wing of the Democratic Party, such as opposing foreign military intervention, supporting the decriminalization of certain recreational drugs such as marijuana, and calling for stronger supervision of large technology companies. ,etc. But Gates is often classified as far-right, more because of his combative style than ideology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ostensible reason why Gates is so obsessed with removing McCarthy is that McCarthy worked with Democrats to pass an interim budget, allowing the government to avoid a shutdown, which is beneficial to the Biden administration. However, the underlying reason is still personal political interests: Gates is a fan of Trump, and his political methods are similar to Trump&#39;s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Trump, Gates is good at turning politics into entertainment and using social media and Fox News to build momentum for himself and attract voters to maintain his personal attention. For example, in October 2019, during the impeachment investigation of Trump by House Democrats, he led more than a dozen Republican congressmen into the sensitive information isolation room of Congress and live broadcast the confidential impeachment hearing content to social media; the new coronavirus epidemic During this period, he once wore a gas mask to work; then in early 2023, he repeatedly vetoed McCarthy as speaker and removed McCarthy this time. US media speculated that the congressman is considering running for Florida governor in 2026: due to term limits, current Governor Ron DeSantis will not be able to seek re-election by then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of Matt Gates, like the rise of Trump, has a profound social background: the development of globalization has caused a large number of blue-collar jobs in the United States to be transferred overseas, and the knowledge economy has made educational attainment and success Directly linked, and less than 30% of American adults have college diplomas. As a result, the biggest losers in this process are the white middle class who have graduated from high school but do not have college diplomas. Most of these people have gathered under the Republican Party. They are opposed to globalization. dissatisfaction, and the conservative attitude of never giving in on moral issues such as anti-abortion, anti-same-sex marriage, and gun rights, are all reflected in the Republican Party&#39;s platform and style of conduct. Whether it is Trump’s vulgarity or the sex trafficking scandals in which he and Matt Gaetz have been accused, their supporters regard it as a manifestation of “masculinity” and are harmless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Gates alone cannot remove McCarthy. Seven other Republican congressmen agreed to remove him, most of them from the far-right &quot;Liberty Caucus&quot; in the party. This caucus originated from the &quot;Tea Party&quot; wave in 2010. Its members were very dissatisfied with the inability of the mainstream Republican Party to check the strict fiscal discipline adopted by the Obama administration. They believed that it was necessary to establish a new organization to exert the collective influence of right-wing members and appeal to the Republican leadership. Put pressure on them to restore the tradition of &quot;financial prudence&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; is an alternative within the Republican Party, which is dedicated to having trouble with the top leaders of the party. In 2015, the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; believed that then-House Speaker John Boehner was not tough enough on Obama and forced the former to resign; in 2017, the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; tried to launch a challenge to then-Speaker Paul Ryan through its internal members, and the latter Forced to resign early to avoid humiliation. From this point of view, McCarthy&#39;s recall motion by members of the &quot;Freedom Caucus&quot; is just another flashback of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/jTeN4HMXqVTUgmkklGWfCpYGB0UlzieGHvaBdrTB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/jTeN4HMXqVTUgmkklGWfCpYGB0UlzieGHvaBdrTB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, in Washington, the United States, McCarthy spoke to media reporters. The U.S. House of Representatives voted on the same day to pass a resolution to remove Republican House Speaker McCarthy &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pelosi was Impact&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After McCarthy steps down, according to the rules of procedure of the House of Representatives, the position of acting speaker will be filled by a person recommended by the former speaker himself. At the top of McCarthy&#39;s recommendation list is North Carolina Rep. Patrick McHenry, a close McCarthy ally who has begun serving as acting speaker, responsible for convening next week to re-elect the speaker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;McHenry was furious at McCarthy&#39;s ouster. In retaliation, he emailed former Speaker Pelosi to vacate her office in the Capitol, and also expelled former House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer, a Democrat. According to tradition, these two people have previously retained their offices in Congress. It is rumored that the vacated office of Pelosi will be allocated to McCarthy. Staff had already started cleaning the office on the evening of the 3rd. After McCarthy was dismissed, she criticized Pelosi for &quot;treachery&quot; and accused her of failing to stand up for him at critical moments as promised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Republican side, some congressmen held up their mobile phones at the voting site to show fundraising text messages sent by Matt Gaetz’s camp, criticizing him for attracting attention just to attract more donations and sponsorships. Some pro-Republican parties The media also criticized Gates as a liar and a reputation seeker. The other seven Republican congressmen who voted after Matt Gaetz were either wildly criticized on TV shows or threatened to cut off financial support from the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9p8cYVY2tWBoprZUp6JWOxCvqeDGTVR91WztDJWZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9p8cYVY2tWBoprZUp6JWOxCvqeDGTVR91WztDJWZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 1, 2023, pedestrians walked past the &quot;Treasury Debt Clock&quot; in New York, USA. The National Debt Clock updates the total U.S. public debt in real time and shows how much each American household has to shoulder. On the same day, the U.S. Senate voted and approved the bill related to the agreement reached by Democratic President Biden and Republican Speaker of the House of Representatives McCarthy on raising the federal government’s debt ceiling, thereby avoiding a U.S. debt default&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua Social/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The canvassing for votes for the new speaker has already begun. McCarthy has stated that he will not participate in the competition again. Currently, Scalise, the majority leader of the House of Representatives and the second-ranking figure in the Republican Party, , House Republican Whip Emmer and House Judiciary Committee Chairman Jordan are already eager to try. Former President Trump was not directly involved in this infighting, but there are still Republican congressmen who have expressed support for him to become the speaker. Legally, there is no requirement to be a member to serve as speaker, but according to the House Republican rules of procedure, anyone accused of a felony cannot hold a leadership position, and Trump has been sued four times, regardless of whether he admits it or not, and the charges are Basically all are felonies. Moreover, Trump’s goal is to be re-elected as president, so it is impossible for him to really go into this muddy water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But no matter who ultimately takes office, it will not change the political reality that the Republican Party is kidnapped by a small number of far-right parties. His future situation will not be much better than McCarthy&#39;s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>