<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[礼盒混装、糕点伪装……月饼何时“包装有度”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8 tDTuhfG52. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The implementation of the new national standard can encourage manufacturers to focus on the innovation of mooncakes themselves and ban overly elaborate and complicated ones. packaging, but there are still some businesses that take advantage of loopholes, and relevant departments need to strengthen supervision. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people have mooncakes for breakfast during this Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday? How many people have noticed changes in the piles of mooncake gift boxes at home? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you happen to have a mooncake gift box on hand, you might as well take a little quiz: Open the gift box. In addition to the mooncakes, does it also come with knives, forks, plates or other products? Counting outward from the packaging bag where the mooncakes are placed, can you count the four layers? If the answer is yes, then the mooncakes in front of you are very likely to violate relevant national standards due to &quot;excessive packaging&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This standard is the &quot;Restrictions on Excessive Packaging of Goods Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021) revised and issued by the State Administration for Market Regulation (National Standards Administration), and will be officially implemented on September 1, 2023. The No. 1 revision of the standard further proposes regulations to restrict excessive packaging of moon cakes from four aspects: packaging void ratio, number of packaging layers, packaging cost, and mixed packaging requirements. It has been implemented on August 15, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Modification Order No. 1, mooncakes should not be mixed with other products, and the packaging should not exceed three layers. For mooncakes with a sales price of more than 100 yuan, the proportion of packaging cost in the sales price shall not exceed 15%. At the same time, precious metals, mahogany and other precious materials must not be used in packaging materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a one-year transition period, are mooncakes still over-packaged? Southern Weekend reporters randomly surveyed the mooncake gift box products on e-commerce platforms and found that the phenomenon of mixed packaging was the most prominent. Some merchants also played tricks on product descriptions to avoid relatively strict mooncake management standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Mengjiao, an engineer at the Beijing Haidian District Metrology and Inspection Institute, told Southern Weekend reporters that mooncakes, as a traditional Mid-Autumn Festival food, evoke images of family reunions rather than exquisite packaging. Although mooncakes have certain social attributes, Gift recipients also hope that mooncakes will be worth their money. The implementation of the new national standard can encourage manufacturers to focus on the innovation of mooncakes themselves and ban overly exquisite and complicated packaging. However, there are still some businesses that &quot;take advantage of loopholes&quot; and the relevant departments need to strengthen supervision. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The hardest hit area of ​​mixed mooncakes: cultural and creative and co-branded gift boxes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mooncake gift boxes contain plastic knives and forks, which was once a &quot;routine practice&quot; for Cantonese-style mooncakes , after the introduction of new regulations prohibiting mixing, except for food deoxidizers and ice packs used to protect mooncakes, all products including knives and forks are not allowed to appear in mooncake gift boxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investigation by Southern Weekend reporters found that there are still many mixed products in the mooncake market in 2023, with the mixed packaging of cultural and creative products and co-branded gift boxes being the most prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the well-known food brand Daoxiangcun launched a mooncake gift box co-branded with Xiaotu Shuner IP. The gift box contains Daoxiangcun mooncake filling package and DIY mold, and provides tutorials on making mooncakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;774&quot; height= &quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 5, 2023, Daoxiang Village and Chen Xiaotao launched mooncake gift boxes with mixed DIY molds. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Tmall Daoxiangcun flagship store/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some catering brands have also launched mixed gift boxes, and have repeatedly explored the upper limit of 500 yuan. In June 2022, the National Development and Reform Commission, the State Administration for Market Regulation and other four departments jointly issued the &quot;Announcement on Curbing &quot;Sky-High Price&quot; Mooncakes and Promoting the Healthy Development of the Industry&quot;, proposing to implement key supervision on boxed mooncakes with a unit price of more than 500 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-end chain brand Dadong and Liu Qingyang, a scholar of fine-brush painting in the Song Dynasty, jointly launched the &quot;Dong Zhiyue·Lixiang Collection&quot; mooncake gift box. The gift box contains seven mooncakes and a hanging painting, with a marked price. 468 yuan (398 yuan after discount). There are two options under the product category. Although it is called &quot;Mooncake Filling Type&quot;, Dadong e-commerce customer service told Southern Weekend reporters that the mooncake types in the two gift boxes are the same. The difference lies in whether the painting received is &quot;Hundred Species of Peonies&quot; or &quot;Hundred Species of Peonies&quot;. &quot;Wu Tong Double Moon Rabbit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to food brands, some cultural and creative customization businesses are also testing the bottom line of excessive mooncake packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a store on the Taobao platform that specializes in customized holiday souvenirs has launched a Mid-Autumn gift box that is divided into different combinations of packages. The package comes with 2 herb-flavored mooncakes as standard, and consumers can also choose aromatherapy. Various contents such as tablets, oolong tea, perfume, greeting cards, etc. are mixed and packed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height= &quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A cultural and creative custom shop sells Mid-Autumn Festival souvenirs that are a combination of &quot;mooncakes + cultural and creative&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Taobao store/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Cultural and creative products managed in accordance with mooncake standards, as long as they contain products other than mooncakes, they are Mixed packaging. If a gift box uses creative packaging, and the packaging itself can be used for other purposes (such as a storage box with a mirror, a board game board with toys), you also need to confirm whether the gift box is managed according to mooncake standards.&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Confusing pastries and mooncakes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;A new way to avoid punishment&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Restricting Excessive Packaging of Goods Requirements for Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021) National Standard Modification No. 1 sets out requirements for mooncake packaging, but not all mooncake gift boxes are &quot; Real mooncakes”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters discovered that the &quot;Moonlight City&quot; chocolate mooncake gift box launched by the local chocolate brand Novan contains a mix of knives, forks and plates, and the monthly sales volume on the e-commerce platform exceeds 4,000 pieces. However, the product packaging provided by the brand&#39;s customer service to Southern Weekend reporters showed that the product&#39;s food name is &quot;mooncake-type chocolate products&quot; and is managed with reference to chocolate and chocolate products standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;787&quot; height= &quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 2, 2023, Novan e-commerce customer service told Southern Weekend reporters that except for two styles, other chocolate mooncake gift boxes contain mixed knives, forks and plates. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Tmall Novin flagship store consultation page/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters randomly selected 10 different brands on the e-commerce platform There is a problem with the mixed packaging of mooncake gift boxes. Although three of the gift boxes are marked with the word &quot;mooncake&quot; during marketing and the food is in the shape of a traditional mooncake, in fact the products are in compliance with pastry standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Yandan, Standardization Section of Beijing Haidian District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, told Southern Weekend reporters that the sales packaging of all food (including bulk food) and cosmetics produced, sold and imported in my country is subject to the &quot;Restrictions&quot; Requirements for Excessive Packaging of Goods Food and Cosmetics” (GB 23350-2021). Southern Weekend reporters found out that according to the No. 1 amendment, the packaging requirements for moon cakes and rice dumplings are more stringent. Except for moon cakes and rice dumplings, there are no restrictions on the mixing of other foods and cosmetics. This means that although foods such as pastries and chocolates are subject to the new national standard’s restrictions on excessive packaging, they can still be mixed with other products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current recommended national standard for mooncakes (GB/T 19855-2015), mooncakes are defined as using wheat flour and other cereal flour or plant flour, oil, sugar (or no added sugar) as the main raw materials It is processed into a pie crust and wrapped with various fillings. It is a traditional festival food mainly eaten during the Mid-Autumn Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In this case, if it is actually judged to be other pastries but sold as mooncakes, then the actual product may not match the description. It is necessary to further confirm whether the food sold is consistent with its labeling.&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said , usually, the product name, implementation standards, food production license number, etc. on the label of pre-packaged food can be used as the basis for judgment, or the competent department can make a comprehensive judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that there is also a type of merchants who deliberately blur the concepts of mooncakes and pastries in their product descriptions, disguising &quot;real mooncakes&quot; as pastries in an attempt to circumvent the new national standard&#39;s requirements for mixed packaging of mooncakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Yandan, Standardization Section of Beijing Haidian District Market Supervision and Administration Bureau, told Southern Weekend reporters that according to the provisions of Article 27 of the &quot;Standardization Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, &quot;Enterprises should organize production and operation activities in accordance with standards. The products produced and services provided should comply with the technical requirements of the company&#39;s public standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to judge whether mooncakes are over-packaged? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Inspired by &quot;The Jade Rabbit in the Toad Palace&quot;, the gift box uses hollow patterns on the front and back, and is decorated with lighting, like holding the bright moon into your arms.&quot; This introduction comes from a new Chinese-style packaging. The highlight is the mooncake gift box containing keywords such as &quot;high-end&quot; and &quot;gift-giving&quot;. The product is priced at 358 yuan and has attracted hundreds of people to buy it on the e-commerce platform. There are many buyers recommending &quot;the outer packaging is beautiful&quot; in the comment area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an ordinary consumer, how should we judge whether the mooncakes we buy are over-packaged? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Standard Modification No. 1 of the &quot;Restricting Excessive Packaging of Goods Requirements for Food and Cosmetics&quot; (GB 23350-2021), four indicators can be used to determine whether moon cakes are over-packaged: number of packaging layers, packaging Cost, mix, and packaging voids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height= &quot;1503&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of packaging layers refers to the number of layers that completely wrap the contents The number of layers of packaging that can be physically separated, where complete wrapping refers to a packaging method that prevents the package from falling apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If it is an open handbag, a half-pallet that fixes the contents or packaging, or a girdle outside the packaging box, it does not meet the definition of a complete package and cannot be counted as a layer. And the drawer type Packaging, even if there are two layers of drawers, is only counted as one layer of packaging. For creative mooncake packaging with exquisite and complex packaging but the number of layers meets the requirements, you can further determine whether the packaging cost is in violation,&quot; Zhang Mengjiao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The packaging void rate is calculated based on the net content of the mooncake. The greater the net content of a single piece of mooncake, the smaller the void rate specified by the standard. For mooncakes with a single piece of net content greater than 50g, the void rate must be ≤30%. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mengjiao said that due to the complicated calculation method, packaging void ratio is generally tested by technical institutions in the laboratory on random samples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Municipal Administration for Market Regulation told a reporter from Southern Weekend that since August 2023, the Shanghai Municipal Administration for Market Regulation has carried out excessive packaging supervision and spot checks on mooncakes sold in the city’s market, involving supermarkets and bakery chains. A total of 80 batches of mooncakes were randomly inspected at 52 production and business units, including hotels and restaurants. The main reason for mooncake packaging violations was that the packaging void rate was unqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPG China Chief Economist Bai Wenxi told Southern Weekend reporters that cracking down on excessive packaging will help reduce consumers’ purchase costs and improve shopping experience. It can also reduce consumers’ behavior of buying high-priced mooncakes, thus reducing the price of mooncakes. Social waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from the Shanghai Municipal Bureau of Market Regulation that consumers can use the WeChat applet &quot;Packaging Youdu&quot; developed by the Shanghai Municipal Bureau of Market Regulation to enter simple information about product packaging in just 1 minute. That is, it can be preliminarily determined whether the product is suspected of excessive packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“异域星球”墨石公园丨指尖华夏⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257593]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Moshi Park is located at the junction of Kama Village and Zhonggu Village, Daofu Bamei Town, Garze Prefecture, Sichuan Province. &lt;span>;5&lt;/span>; square kilometers, with an altitude of about &lt;span>;3500&lt;/span>; meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With its unique mylonite forest landscape, Moshi Park is like an &quot;exotic planet&quot;, attracting many tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/j9EJoHWumm5ymv9A06VC9mCWdQNTo1FuBTo78OuD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/cJUGfObe7VWbkpfujF9hyuOR8FXipxCganY5TXGG.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/nGONj8Tnu5h2VXIRUg1JX6jfcI1ubWr6ilg7KmYA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/KiRYiKvh52GtS91MyV44zj01Iq3kGn8gTGbz8io1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/NcrNEpe4aGZnJcyPch8bpQ1YahVM5AgQj15vbqgj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Moshi Park. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhao Junchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[绝杀日本队，中国女篮亚运会夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 5, in the women’s basketball final of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, the Chinese team finished with &lt;span>;74- 72 defeated the Japanese team and won the gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/b348c693a8df39e6e8e165cb8dea26c7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253066&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/1f2cb7a45ba9676004ace980b51f6b89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253067&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/49d7848a9886de74ef950dbdf16341ad.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雨林中的玛雅遗址：“巴黎”与霸主丨古国多少事⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257360]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As one of the three ancient civilizations in the Americas, the Mayan civilization once had many city-states in the tropical jungle, but it was restricted Due to the development of the natural environment and technology, just like a string of small oasis countries in the deserts of the Western Regions in ancient China, they were unable to unify and grow. In the end, they were vulnerable to an ecological crisis and withered at the same time. They were covered in dust by the returning tropical rainforest for thousands of years... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been fortunate enough to travel to Central America to visit nine Mayan city-state ruins located in three countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for Mexico and El Salvador, the other Central American countries where the Mayan ruins are located - Guatemala, Honduras and Belize - have not yet established diplomatic relations with our country, and relatively few Chinese have been there, but this area is precisely The hinterland of the Mayan civilization in its heyday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copán&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Copán)&lt;/span>; was my first stop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/11VdBB6fTLcQbxkv2y5YxcsGwH1EQwGA1KiJF36q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The ancient town of Flores, Guatemala, the last religious center of the Mayan civilization. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Paris of the Mayan World - Copan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Copan ruins are located in western Honduras The border is about five kilometers from Guatemala and no more than fifty kilometers from El Salvador. Not far to the west of the ruins is a border town called Copán Ruinas &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Copán Ruinas)&lt;/span>;, which is Spanish and means &quot;Ruins of Copan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan was the heyday of the Mayan civilization &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (250-900 AD, also known as the Classical Period)&lt;/span>; The most important city-state in the southeast. During the Classic Period, the Maya experienced Tikal&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Script_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Tikal)&lt;/span>; and Calakmul&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体,楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Calakmul)&lt;/span>;A long-standing confrontation between two powerful city-states, both located in the Yucatan Peninsula&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体,楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Yucatan)&lt;/span>;In the central part, one south and one north, separated by dense jungles, there have been continuous battles. Perhaps in order to expand its territory and resources, Tikal expanded to its rear in the early fifth century and established the city-state of Copan in a river valley in the middle of the Mesoamerican isthmus. The two sides formed a solid alliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan was placed in the twelfth place in the mid-seventh century &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (roughly corresponding to the period of Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty in China)&lt;/span>; It entered its heyday under King Chan Imix K&#39;awiil (r. 628-695)&lt;/span>;. Yanbao ascended the throne at the age of 15 and reigned for 67 years, the longest among the seventeen kings of Copán. His successor Uaxaclajuun Ub&#39;aah K&#39;awiil (reigned 695-738)&lt;/span>; in that era He is also considered a birthday boy, and he reigned for 43 years &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (same as Tang Xuanzong Li Longji)&lt;/span>;. The two kings ruled for a total of 110 years. During this period, Copán was transformed from a river valley city-state into an emerging empire, controlling a number of vassals and opening up trade routes to the Caribbean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the good times did not last long. Due to the large-scale construction and militarization of the Eighteen Rabbits, Copan, which had limited strength but overexpansion, quickly fell into crisis. In the middle of the eighth century, a rebellion similar to the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot; broke out: Batu was attacked by his cronies who had been placed in the small vassal state of Quirigua&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Quirigua)&lt;/span>;. -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(K&#39;ak&#39; Tiliw Chan Yopaat)&lt;/span>; Switched sides and rebelled. He was caught off guard and lost the battle. He was captured alive and taken to Quirigua, where he was captured in the main square. Beheading as a sacrifice - modern historians have noticed that two years ago, the monarch of the city-state of Calakmul made a special visit to Rainy Day, thus speculating that Calakmul may have planned and funded the rebellion behind the scenes. , the purpose is to cut off the right-hand man of the feuding Tikal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of Eighteen Rabbits, Copán, which was countered by Quirigua, has since gone downhill, although it once had a close relationship with Palenque, a large city-state in the west&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Palenque)&lt;/span>;The marriage tried to make a comeback, but the decline of the national destiny was irreversible. At the beginning of the ninth century, the history books of Copán stopped updating, and the river valley city-state suddenly declined and quickly disappeared into the resurgent rainforest vegetation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thousand years later, the American archaeologist Stephens &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(John Stephens)&lt;/span>; and the British painter In 1839, Frederick Catherwood &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Frederick Catherwood)&lt;/span>; found the Copan ruins in 1839 based on the legends of the Mayan indigenous people. He made this comment on the ruins in the jungle:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is laid out in front of us, like a broken ship in the ocean. The ship, its mast is gone, its crew is gone, no one knows when it came or what destroyed it, everything is a mystery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/YHloVyPZjVDhCq4f3GOL25dsDqeRBKHVTnRp4jCW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Grand Plaza of Copan, with the &quot;Stairs of History&quot; covered by a canopy on the right. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Copan ruins we see today are only a small part of the core area of ​​the city-state of Copan. It is around the large square that served as the political, religious and cultural center of the Mayan city-state. There is a small pyramid in the center of the square. On the north side are eight stone statues more than two meters high, six of which are carved with eighteen rabbits. These stone carvings are reminiscent of the architectural decoration style of South Asian temples: the details are extremely complex and gorgeous, but overall they lack highlights and personality. Perhaps it can be called Mayan Rococo style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the southeast side of the pyramid is a kickball court. Cuqiu is a unique sports competition of the Mayans and a noble sacrificial activity. Due to the lack of literature, it is not yet fully understood how it is played. It is generally believed to be a bit like today&#39;s volleyball. Players from both sides take turns hitting a solid rubber ball that symbolizes the sun. They are not allowed to touch the ball with their heads, hands and feet. Instead, you can only hit the ball with your elbow, hip or knee, hitting the ball behind the opponent, or causing the opponent to be unable to save the ball and lose points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the annual Quidditch game at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry in the &quot;Harry Potter&quot; novels has a sure-fire setting for capturing the Golden Snitch, the kickball game also has a sure-fire rule. The kickball court is rectangular, with a high wall on each side of the long side. There is a stone ring at the top of the center of the high wall, which is similar to the &quot;basket&quot; in the basketball court, except that the basket is not horizontal, but vertical. , and the position is quite high, it is absolutely impossible for players to take off and dunk; the holes in the ring are also very small, only slightly larger than the diameter of a rubber ball. In the kickball game, if the player successfully passes the ball through the stone ring, he wins and the game ends immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the outcome of the kickball players, historians are still debating. Some people think that the loser will have his heart disemboweled and sacrificed to the gods. The other side has the opposite opinion and believes that only the winner can obtain this supreme thing. of glory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cu stadium we see today is the third-generation stadium in the history of the city-state of Copan. It was built under the edict of the Eighteen Rabbits. Its two predecessors have been buried under its feet. This golf course is also the second largest golf course excavated in the Mayan world so far, second only to the Chichen Itza Stadium in Mexico. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/GDDRFyXAphjGoYhSo02bo4mBPUVUF4pQ1qsPtl7G.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The court is played, and the high platform in the background is the royal temple of the King of Copan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the southeast side of the Cui Stadium is a spectacular &quot;Historic Staircase&quot;, which consists of 2,500 half-meter square There are 63 stone steps, about 30 meters high and 10 meters wide, with a slope of nearly 60 degrees, very steep. Each stone is engraved with Mayan hieroglyphics - the entire stone step records the history of the city-state of Copan from its establishment until Eighth century history. In order to protect the cultural relics from the sun and rain, a plastic canopy was erected above the &quot;Historic Stairs&quot;, which affected its appearance and internal lighting. Visitors are also unable to climb and can only look up from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Directly south of the main square is a hill. The top of the mountain was once a temple. When kickball games and sacrificial ceremonies were held, the royal family of Copan looked down on the people from here. In its heyday, Copan had 27,000 people. Thousands of residents are indeed worthy of the title of “ten thousand peoples”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entire Copan ruins are not very big and can be browsed in two hours. Any place that is fenced with ropes or covered with plastic sheets is worth a closer look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copan is known as the &quot;Paris of the Mayan World&quot; and is famous for its exquisite carvings and developed culture. So why did it suddenly fall during its heyday? Was it just because it suffered a rebellion? According to the results of archaeological excavations, the decline of Copan is actually the inevitable result of ecological deterioration, and the wasted national power of the Eighteen Rabbits only accelerated this process. The city-state is located in a fertile and narrow river valley, surrounded by steep mountains and low soil fertility. With the rise of city-states and rapid population growth, the limited farmland in river valleys could not sustain their food needs, so people went to the mountains in droves to clear up wasteland. The royal family also cut down a large number of mountain trees for fuel and made plaster to smear on palace buildings for waterproofing. As a result, local Vegetation has dropped sharply, the ecology has deteriorated, and mountain landslides have occurred repeatedly, submerging fertile farmland in river valleys and further reducing crop yields. Eventually agricultural production collapsed, and the city-states were abandoned and turned into large rainforests again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/jM4b2wvmJyMOn4acWV6Ixmd5kkoHLa9JCLxDWJjr.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The stone macaw sculpture above the court&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is dusk , the few tourists dispersed one after another, and I sat on a high platform beside the golf course, with a stone sculpture of a macaw head above my head. Quietly watch as the large square gradually becomes a paradise for macaws. They either glide in groups and chirp freely, or perch in pairs on branches, preening each other&#39;s feathers lovingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen hundred years ago, the Mayans used macaws as their totems and held fiery and bloody kickball games under their curious gaze. Nowadays, the Mayan civilization has disappeared, but the macaw is still the master here, and it has never changed for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The overlord of the Mayan world - Tikal&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Tikal ruins are located in the Mayan rainforest in northern Guatemala. To the north and west is Mexico, a large country in Central America, and to the east is Central America. The only English speaking country is Belize. Due to the deep grass and forests, the borders between the three countries were drawn using latitude and longitude lines, and a square rectangle was drawn on the map of the Yucatan Peninsula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far south from Tikal is Lake Petén Itzá, which is shaped like a hammerhead shark. )&lt;/span>; and its south coast island Flores &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Flores)&lt;/span>; - the last religious center of the Mayan civilization , it was not destroyed by the cultural genocide atrocities of Spanish colonists until the end of the seventeenth century. The closest airport to Tikal is built on the land southeast of Flores Island: Mayan World International Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I took a Saab 340 twin-turboprop plane from Guatemala City—probably the smallest commercial airliner I have ever flown in, with only thirty seats—under the intoxicating sunset over the lake and sky. We landed here and drove 70 kilometers to the Tikal ruins early the next morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1OW5BqQAwjMkn1CCLOm8twqn0b902T1RjhLBnWK3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tikal Temple No. 1&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tikal is a Mayan temple One of the two unparalleled heroes who stood side by side with Calakmul during the classical period of civilization. The surrounding terrain is low-lying and densely covered with swamps, and Tikal is a low hill with neither drought nor flooding. It has become a rare livable place in the Yucatan Peninsula, which is generally short of water. It has been there since at least the seventh century BC. Inhabited by the Mayans. About a thousand years later, the Maya world entered the Classical Period. With the rich local obsidian resources, Tikal could not only build sharp weapons to improve its own combat power during times of war, but also sell them to other city-states for profit in times of peace, so its national power grew rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through international trade, Tikal originated from Teotihuacan, a large country located in central Mexico There, I learned how to fight with spears. I no longer need to fight with the enemy face to face. Instead, I surround the enemy and kill them by throwing spears. This achieves a &quot;long-range strike&quot; to a certain extent, thus significantly reducing our own casualties and more effectively reducing our own casualties. Become the overlord of the Mayan world with advanced military ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Teotihuacan sent an expeditionary force to raid its students at the end of the fourth century - the straight-line distance between the two places is more than a thousand kilometers, which is equivalent to the Tang army relying entirely on boats and walking&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Teotihuacan and Mayan civilizations failed to invent wheels and vehicles)&lt;/span>;, carrying all weapons and equipment and food and grass supplies on their shoulders, starting from Chang&#39;an Expedition to Tuyuhun on the Qinghai Lake - and once fully controlled the political and military power of Tikal. But the two places were too far apart after all. Teotihuacan, which started out on the Mexican plateau, could not establish itself in the humid monsoon rainforest of the Yucatan Peninsula for a long time, so Tikal eventually regained power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of the Copan ruins is the beautifully carved stone statues, while the highlight of Tikal is its tall pyramid. Although limited by ancient construction technology, the pyramid of Tikal cannot reach the sky, but at least it can tower through the forest. Standing on the top of the pyramid, you feel as if you are standing on the tip of a sharp sword, piercing through the endless mountains. Rainforest canopy. If you imagine the lush forest canopy as clouds, then these pyramids are like Shushan Mountain breaking through the clouds and coming out through the clouds, giving people a very majestic feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/1W1L8Yf8zisdbLt0F3bJlnf8CL3OtZwlLDJKGtnO.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tikal Temple 1-3&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;mentioned Are there any differences between pyramids, Mayan pyramids and Egyptian pyramids? The Egyptian pyramid, as its name suggests, is similar to the Chinese character for &quot;gold&quot;. It is a square pyramid composed of a square base and four isosceles triangles. The Mayan pyramid looks similar to the Egyptian pyramid at first glance, but if you look closely, you will find that it is not the same. A pointed cone without a top, its cross-section is an isosceles trapezoid, as if a small pyramid was cut off from the top of a large pyramid. The base is not always square. For example, several large pyramids at the Tikal site have rectangular bases, and the Uxmal site in Mexico also has the Warlock Pyramid with an oval base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are there no pointed cones on the top of the Mayan pyramids? This is related to the different functions of the two types of pyramids. The Egyptian pyramid is a pharaoh&#39;s tomb, with a hollow interior, and a tomb chamber is built to store the pharaoh&#39;s mummy; the Mayan pyramid is the base of the temple, and the purpose of building it is to highlight the sublimity of the temple. Therefore, the Mayan pyramid is generally solid, in order to leave To build a temple in space, a platform must be left at the top, so there is no top cone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the different functions, the shapes and sizes of the two types of pyramids are also quite different. There is a temple on the top of the Mayan pyramid, and the priests need to go to the altar to perform rituals or observe the stars at night. Therefore, there are stone steps on both sides of the Mayan pyramid or on the central axis of the front, rear, left, and right sides; while the Egyptian pyramid is a pharaoh&#39;s tomb and does not require climbing to the top. , so there is only the entrance to the mausoleum at the bottom, and there are no stone steps leading to the top cone. Also due to sacrificial needs, Mayan pyramids are generally not high. The tallest Tikal Temple IV is only 64.6 meters, which can be said to be dwarfed by the Egyptian pyramids: Egypt&#39;s tallest Pyramid of Khufu was 146.6 meters high when it was built. After 4,500 years, Due to the erosion of wind and sand, it is still 138.8 meters high, more than twice the height of Tikal IV Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the amount of construction earthwork is proportional to the cube of the size, the Mayan pyramid is an order of magnitude smaller than the Egyptian pyramid, so the amount of building materials and engineering required is much smaller than the latter, and the number of constructions is much higher. the latter. According to incomplete statistics, there are more than 100,000 Mayan pyramids in Mexico alone, while there are only more than 100 pyramids in Egypt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are four most important pyramids in Tikal, including one on the east and west sides of the main square, which means a couple looking at each other. Temple No. 1 on the east side was built in the mid-eighth century and is 44 meters high. It is a rare mausoleum-shaped pyramid in the Mayan world. It is the burial place of the famous Zhongxing master of Tikal, the Double Moon King _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil I, reigned 682-734)&lt;/span>;, he led the city-state through the jungle to defeat the old enemy Calakmul in 695, leaving the latter unable to recover, and could only rely on Small tricks such as secretly fomenting rebellion and weakening Copán were used to relieve military pressure from Tikal, and Tikal entered its second heyday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/30/tk9W7RDl4NjfWRt8qcIQ3gheQ3KgyxqIFyFhE9UM.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;210475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shuangyuewang Stone Stele Relief&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No. 1 The stone steps of the temple are narrow and steep, causing at least two tourists to slip and fall to their deaths. Tourists are now prohibited from climbing. Temple No. 2 on the west side is also a mausoleum, where the queen of the Twin Moon King, Lady Twelve Macaw, is buried. >;. Her mausoleum is six meters shorter than her husband&#39;s pyramid, and the stone steps are wider. However, direct climbing is prohibited. Instead, wooden steps are built behind it for visitors to walk up to the top of the tower and overlook the elegant and quiet grand square. There are more than twenty stone pillars erected in the square. They have the same function as the stone statues in the main square of the Copan ruins. They are used to commemorate the achievements of the previous kings. However, the stone carving art of Tikal is far inferior to that of Copan, so there are no stone statues here but only stone pillars. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tikal&#39;s Temple No. 3 is located on the west side of Temple No. 2. The front of its base has been covered by vegetation, and it is like a slope, buried in the dense jungle, but it is 55 meters high. The top of the tower stands majestically, far higher than the surrounding trees, giving viewers a strong shock with the tenacious struggle between nature and manpower across the vicissitudes of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the Tikal temple we see today is the product of archaeological excavations, stripping away its trees, cleaning up its soil, and repairing its stone steps. When the European archaeological expedition first came here in the early 19th century, all the pyramids looked like Temple No. 3 now. At first glance, they were nothing more than steep mountains that suddenly rose up from the flat ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Temple No. 4 is located at the western end of the core area of ​​the site. It was built in 741 by the son of the Twin Moon King. It is the tallest temple in Tikal and the tallest building in the Mayan world. Looking eastward from its top platform to Temple No. 1, No. 2, and No. 3, it is easy to get the illusion that the continuous tropical rainforest trees under your feet are just a patch of low bushes, while the three temples are like three stone monuments, rising from the bushes. The bushes stretched out tenaciously - the scale of everything suddenly shrunk here, and I seemed to have entered a miniature world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/11/pyk0T8NZrX2ucXSOFELI9SpZDxrvzaxlVxGy7ek3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;211203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A temple in &quot;The Lost World&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Starting from Temple No. 4, I continued south deep into the rainforest, looking for the ancient pyramid &quot;The Lost World&quot; which was built in 700 BC &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;( El Mundo Perdido)&lt;/span>;. The number of tourists gradually decreased, and only me, a group of white-nosed coatis walking happily with their long tails wagging high, and the low roars echoing in the forest were the only ones left in the dense forest. At first I thought it was just the background sound played by the park through the loudspeaker - because if any carnivorous beast really made such a loud noise, it meant that it had arrived around me and could start hunting at any time - and I was surprised by the unique interest of the player, and later I realized that the breathtaking roar came from the branches above my head: two medium-sized howler monkeys were crawling back and forth anxiously, announcing the territory of their group with continuous roars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prosperous age created by the Twin Moon King lasted for nearly a hundred years. After entering the ninth century, the entire Mayan world entered a drought period that had not been seen in seven thousand years. Starvation was everywhere and the city-states were in ruins. As the largest city-state at the time, with a population of nearly 200,000 at its peak, Tikal declined rapidly after facing famine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last king of Tikal who went down in history reused the name of the Twin Moon King and called himself Jasaw Chan K&#39;awiil II, but this did not allow him to defeat nature and revive the country&#39;s destiny. By the end of the 10th century, Tikal was reclaimed by nature, the cornfields no longer existed, and the majestic temples and tombs of the ancestors were covered by dense forests. From that time on, the howler monkeys established their homes in the center of the former city-state, making powerful sounds that could be heard several kilometers away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么全国大部分打印店都“姓”湘？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257190]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Walking into the university campus, if you find the print shop owner saying Don’t be too surprised when you hear the rich modulations of “Shapu”, because if you continue to pay attention, you will find that this accent can even be found in print shops in the streets and alleys across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hunanese are not only the leaders in the spicy food industry, but also have great confidence in the literary and printing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Xinhua County, located in central Hunan, has shouldered the heavy responsibility of the &quot;Wenyinxiang Army&quot;. According to statistics, Xinhua&#39;s printing and printing industry has captured more than 95% and 70% of the market share in the national universities and the national printing and printing industry respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks have opened stores across the country, but also Xinhuaren’s Wenyin Shop. Today, Xinhua Printing Industry has opened more than 150,000 picture and text express printing shops, more than 3,000 copier remanufacturing and distribution companies, and more than 2,000 consumable production and sales companies in more than 660 cities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason why Xinhua Wenyin has swept the country has to start with the small town of Yangxi. Many years ago, a Peking University doctoral thesis &quot;The Life History of Xinhua Copying Industry&quot; became popular on the Internet, which revealed the secret of how Xinhua people turned a piece of graphics into a 100-billion-dollar industry through &quot;teaching and mentoring&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This small town located in a corner has a tradition of &quot;supplementing agriculture with technology&quot; since ancient times. Yangxi people accidentally learned mechanical typewriter repair technology, then united a group of repair technicians to go nationwide, and then relied on repair technology to develop the second-hand copier business, gradually realizing iterative upgrades in the text and printing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the complete industrial chain of typing, copying, drawing, printing, printing equipment and remanufacturing, and consumable manufacturing and operation, more than 300,000 people Xinhua printing technicians have traveled all over the country. Under the impact of &quot;paperless office&quot;, Xinhua printing industry is still booming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From &quot;introduced manufacturing&quot; to &quot;independent intelligent manufacturing&quot;, Xinhua Wenyin is getting rid of the shackles and building the world&#39;s business card of &quot;Xinhua Wenyin&quot;. Today, independent intellectual property products such as high-speed inkjet blueprint machines are accelerating industry changes; Xinhua Printing has gone abroad and has settled its printing products in more than 80 countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mobile phone cases, stationery, mouse pads, background walls... These DIY personalized printings that are popular among young people have also become the &quot;get rich&quot; for Xinhua Wenyin people &quot;High-gloss&quot;, new printing products represented by Meow Meow Machine, 3D printing products, etc. have created more possibilities for Xinhua Printing. Today, Xinhua, known as the &quot;Chinese Capital of Printing and Printing&quot;, is still domineeringly declaring its own &quot;printing&quot; strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will take you to learn about the &quot;Hunan&quot; font size business that &quot;dominates&quot; print shops across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/de5bb231c0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/9a25dd92da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e7e6a11306.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/bcee885338.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/54098d0c52.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 20/fa591a1c31.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 21:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九华山：气象万千的水墨丹青丨眼睛在旅游⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257609]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在土耳其， 探访亚美尼亚的古都丨古国多少事⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257362]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 10/23/q1dtyKAs2YKSFdfv9IKNw2fhrYaiFkUwOMWBNhNQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/q1dtyKAs2YKSFdfv9IKNw2fhrYaiFkUwOM WBNhNQ. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Looking at the ancient city of Ani from a distance, there are three obvious buildings from front to back: a mosque, Cathedral, Church of the Savior. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;A European-style town in the Islamic world&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Kars is the Silk Road A quite alternative city in the western section. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After traveling in Pakistan and Iran for more than a month, I have already become accustomed to the mountains and the Gobi, the minaret and the Grand Bazaar, the call of dawn and dusk with black gauze and white hats, the lively markets and winding alleys... Enter Although the landscape in eastern Turkey changed to gentle slopes and the language changed to Turkic and Kurdish, the strong imprint of Islamic civilization has not weakened at all. But when you come to the northeastern border town of Karls, the cool and elegant cityscape, the streets with a checkerboard structure, the neat and straight stone roads, and even the bank branches shining warmly in the bleak autumn wind make people suddenly feel like they have traveled to a Nordic town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The unusual origin of Kars comes from: it was occupied by Tsarist Russia for 40 years from 1878, and was planned, built and managed in a European style. of Soviet Russia was ceded to Turkey. Before that, Kars was the capital of the middle Bagratid dynasty. It was successively occupied by the Byzantines, Seljuks, Mongols and Turks in the more than 800 years after the fall of the dynasty. The Bagratid Dynasty was a mini-version established by the only remaining nobles who took advantage of the gap between the Byzantine Empire and the Arab Empire after the once vast Kingdom of Armenia, which controlled hundreds of thousands of people, was divided by the Roman Empire and the Parthian Empire. The Armenian country has been a country for 160 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no Armenians in Kars today, but just a hundred years ago, 84.1% of the population here was Armenian. Because the Tsarist Russian government was relatively friendly to Armenians, people from Western Armenia (generally referring to the former Armenian territory in Turkey, corresponding to Eastern Armenia, which is now the Republic of Armenia and part of Azerbaijan) who suffered discrimination and abuse from the Ottoman Turkish Empire at that time migrated to Kars , especially during World War I, the Ottoman Turkish Empire implemented a genocidal policy against the Armenians in its territory, resulting in the deaths of 1 million to 1.5 million Armenians. This is known as the Armenian Genocide in history, and even prompted Western Armenians to flee to Kars for refuge. Unfortunately, the good times did not last long. After Soviet Russia ceded Kars to Turkey, the Armenians here had to embark on a journey of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My companions and I found a small hotel to stay in - the hotel sign on Turkey Street is easy to recognize, written as otel, which comes from the French word hotel with a silent h - we were preparing to take advantage of the sun yet. Go down the mountain to see the landmark here, the Seljuk Castle built in the 12th century AD, and Celil, the famous old fox of Kars, comes to visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Turkey is a big tourist country, but tourists mainly go to the Aegean coast in the west, the Mediterranean coast in the south and Cappadocia in the center. Even the quiet and elegant Black Sea coast in the north is rarely visited. Not to mention eastern Turkey, which is adjacent to &quot;high-risk areas&quot; such as Syria, Iraq, Iran and the Caucasus. The rare few who make the long journey to Kars are undoubtedly to have a look at the ruins of Ani, and Celil, who has a keen sense of smell, specializes in these people&#39;s business. He can track every first-time tourist, and even the backpackers who spend a lot of money can be killed by him before they know the east, west, north, and south. Having said that, the number of tourists here is limited and it cannot support more tourism operators. The tourism transportation in Ani is not developed, so Celil has become an unavoidable broker for tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Celil speaks fluent English, and this skill alone is a talent that can only be encountered within a few hundred miles. He was going to personally take a group to Ani the next day, and he had no control over the two of us. He just wanted to find a car for us and a young man from Melbourne we met on the road to go to Ani, and charged 20 lire per person - I asked about the price for chartered cars, which was 40 lire. The Turkish lira has experienced a 50% plunge in 2018 and a 20% depreciation since the COVID-19 epidemic this year. Now it is only 85 cents in exchange for RMB, but at that time, 1 lira could be exchanged for more than five yuan. This chartered trip was equivalent to three hundred yuan. For the first time, Celil took a third of it - only after we were on the road did we learn that Celil actually asked the simple Melbourne boy for 5 liras more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, another Chinese tourist came to Karls, and he also got three people to charter Celil’s car to Ani. Celil has entered middle age from a young man, and has worked hard to innovate. He originally negotiated a charter price of 100 lire, but after the journey, he charged 50 lire per person. He actually wanted to ask the simple German guy for another 50 lire tip. He was evaluated as &quot;Malicious greed&quot; - I accidentally read this on the Internet and couldn&#39;t help laughing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/22/b2DP79UXKCZMTxHbuShKPAOxXNV7e2wIj5lSlXk8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/22/b2DP79UXKCZMTxHbuShKPAOxXNV7e2wIj5lSlXk8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;115783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Turkish breakfast in the European-style small town of Karls. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;A dynasty growing in the cracks&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Early the next morning, sitting In a small restaurant full of locals, I ate a basket of bread with a large bowl of soup made from mutton hamstrings - this is the Turkish version of Runan mutton soup breakfast, and then drove to the ancient capital Ani, 45 kilometers away. This place is located on the Armenian Plateau that connects the Iranian Plateau and the Anatolian Plateau. Along the way is still the typical temperate grassland in Central Asia. The herdsmen are stacking hay into pyramids five or six people high to prepare for the winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani, the destination of this trip, is the fourth and last capital of the Bagratid dynasty. It was the capital for the longest time, lasting 84 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking of the revival of the Bagratid dynasty in Armenia, Robert I, who led Scotland to regain its independence, is comparable to Robert I, who was capricious and devoted to family interests in the movie &quot;Brave Heart&quot;. The English invaders betrayed the leader of the rebellion, William Wallace, and then rebelled against the independent Scottish nobleman Robert the Bruce. This man was truly a generational hero known as &quot;Braveheart&quot; in history. Ashote I, the founding monarch of the Bagratid dynasty, was also such a figure. After the fall of the Kingdom of Armenia, the Romans and Persians fought on its territory for many years and were severely weakened. As a result, the newly rising Arabs came from behind and became the conquerors of the Armenian Plateau. In 705 AD, the Arab governor sent by the White-coated Food (Umayyad Dynasty) almost killed all the remaining Armenian nobles, and the Bagratid family survived; more than 40 years later, the White-Coated Food changed dynasties and became the Black-Coated Food (Abbasid Dynasty), sent troops to bloody suppress the uprising launched by the Armenians who took advantage of the chaos, eradicated the local civil resistance forces, and the Bagratid family, who had long been friends with the black-clad Caliphate, once again survived, and they have been together ever since. With its strong support, it became the most powerful political and military force on the Armenian Plateau, and also became a local force that foreign Arab rulers must rely on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was at this time that Ashuote I succeeded him as the family governor. On the one hand, the Arab Caliph supported him to neutralize the surrounding separatist forces and became the King of Armenia, hoping to use him to calm down the instability in the Caucasus Mountains so that he could concentrate on dealing with the Byzantine Empire to the west; on the other hand, the Byzantine Emperor Basil I hoped to win over the Armenian nation. They shared the belief in the Kingdom of God, thus forming a siege on the Black Era from the northern flank; on the other hand, Ashot I not only wanted to use the Byzantines to drive away the Arabs, but was also worried that the Byzantine Empire, which believed in Orthodox Christianity, would force the Armenian Apostolic Church to convert. , thereby threatening the legitimacy of his regime. Therefore, Asot I strictly adhered to the principle of keeping a low profile and double-dealing throughout his life. At the same time, he formed alliances with Byzantium and Arabia and watched the two empires fight in front of the Caucasus Mountains. He devoted himself to making Armenia bigger and stronger, and did not let the Arabs He had time to intervene in his own country&#39;s affairs and prevented the Byzantines from obtaining practical benefits from the Caucasus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first capital of Ashote I after the founding of the country was Bagaran, the base of the Bagratid family. After his son ascended the throne, he moved the capital to Shirakavan. Both places are on the east bank of the Aras River. Today, due to geopolitical changes, the Aras River is the boundary river between Armenia, Turkey, and Iran. More than a thousand years ago, it was the mother river of Armenia. The Bagratid dynasty located its first two capitals on the east bank of the Arras River in order to use the defensive function of the river to keep foreign enemies west of the river. When Abbas, the grandson of Asjot I, came to the throne and the Bagratid dynasty became more powerful, it moved its capital to Kars west of the Aras River to better protect the trade route from the Caucasus to the Black Sea and resist Byzantine aggression. Encroaching eastward. After Abbas&#39;s son Ashot III came to the throne, he moved the capital to Ani on the west bank of the Arras River. It never moved the capital again until the demise of the dynasty in 1045 AD. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/bPBS8zxe6WU5Oh5XfTtuJ7wW3oemOJsmjEPCCkip.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/bPBS8zxe6WU5Oh5XfTtuJ7wW3oemOJsmjEPCCkip.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Haystacks in Armenia&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian./Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Civilized Transfer Station&lt; /h3>; &lt;p>;The Kingdom of Armenia was the first Christian country in the world. After the resurgence, the Bagratid Dynasty continued the status of the Armenian Apostolic Church as the state religion and consolidated the legitimacy of its regime by sending large amounts of donations to the church. As a result of this approach, the ancient capital Ani was once dotted with churches and was known as the &quot;City of One Thousand and One Churches&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another title of Ani is the &quot;City of Forty Gates&quot;, which refers to its vast area and abundant business travel. But today there is only one north gate left in Ani. The later conquerors, the Seljuqs, built an outer wall around the north gate to form a corridor-like urn city, which improved the defensive function of the city gate. This only remaining city gate was named after the Seljuk Sultan Arslan who captured Ani in 1064, and was called the Gate of Arslan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to defend the city of Ani with only one gate left? Out of the way. The terrain of Ani is very similar to the Jiaohe Ancient City in Turpan. It is located on a platform formed by three deep rivers. There are almost dry deep valleys to the east and west, and the steep Alas Valley to the south, forming a natural moat. Only the north has a road leading to the outside world. In the era of cold weapons, it was really a great pass that was easy to defend but difficult to attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani is located at the crossroads of the Caucasus Mountains to the south, Persia to the west, Mesopotamia to the north and Asia Minor to the east. Its location is very important. In addition, it is adjacent to the Arras Valley and has abundant water resources. The trade routes in the Volga River Basin that crossed the Caucasus Mountains merged into the junction of the Silk Road, thus witnessing the rise and fall of ancient civilizations one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Armenians, the Byzantines attacked Ani three times in history until they captured the city in 1045. Afterwards, Ani became an important eastern town in the Byzantine Empire equivalent to the capital Constantinople. , there were 100,000 residents living on this platform in its heyday, marking the Caucasus entered its commercial heyday under Byzantine rule. Unfortunately, the good times did not last long. With the decline of Arab power in Central Asia, the Seljuqs rose rapidly and occupied the ecological niche of the Arabs. They then defeated the bloated Byzantine army in the west and captured Ani in 1064, starting from there. Asia Minor turned the Caucasus into its own backyard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Seljuks left, Ani was successively occupied by the Georgians and Kurds. It was not until 1239 that the short-lived Mongols conquered Ani. This was the last time the city was captured—— A major earthquake 80 years later destroyed most of the buildings in the city, forming the ruins we see today. In addition, the Ottoman Turkish Empire straddled the east coast of the Mediterranean and the Balkan Peninsula, cutting off the Silk Road between Western Europe and East Asia. As a result, Ani&#39;s status as a trade center no longer existed and it declined rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Ottoman Turkish Empire gradually declined in the 19th century, Ani and Kars fell into the hands of Tsarist Russia for a time, and only returned to Turkish hands after World War I. During the Cold War era, this was the border between the Warsaw Pact and NATO in Asia. Once the Soviet armored forces broke out of the Caucasus mountains, they would flood into the Anatolian Plateau. This has become Turkey&#39;s nightmare for many years. Both Turkey and the Soviet Union stationed heavy troops along the Arras Valley, and Ani was under military control for 40 years as an important border defense area. It was not until the collapse of the Soviet Union, Armenia&#39;s independence, and the disappearance of the military threat faced by Turkey that control policies were relaxed. But at first, tourists still needed to apply in advance before entering the ancient city of Ani, just like my country&#39;s border permit system, which was canceled after Erdogan came to power in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/M7uFh32a7tGHPnbFFt1BeaF1sF8obd5ei15Qulmt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/M7uFh32a7tGHPnbFFt1BeaF1sF8obd5ei15Qulmt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The ruins of the ancient city of Ani can overlook the rocky village on the opposite cliff, giving you a sense of Cappadocia. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The city of one thousand and one churches&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The ancient city of Ani has been abandoned for several years For centuries, the landform has basically returned to its original appearance in ancient times. Only a dozen of the most magnificent and solid ancient buildings remain, which have withstood the test of time and natural disasters and stand quietly in the grass, silently displaying the civilizations left by different eras. imprint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;St. Gregory was the founder of the Armenian Apostolic Church. He was imprisoned in a dungeon for 13 years by King Tiridates III of Armenia. Finally, he used miracles to convert the king and established the world&#39;s first Christian country. , so he is regarded as the patron saint by the Armenians. There are three churches named after St. Gregory in Ani. Among them, the one near the north gate is also called Abughamrents. It was built in 994 AD and has a conical roof and 12 walls on the facade. The niche is a typical Armenian architectural style and is very eye-catching on the withered yellow grassland. From here, you can overlook the rocky villages on the opposite cliff to the west, giving you a sense of Cappadocia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another Armenian-style church is the Church of Redeemer. Although it is small in size, it is the most fascinating place in the city of Ani. This church was built between 1034 and 1036 AD to store the &quot;True Cross&quot; gifted by the Byzantine Empire, which is the legendary fragment of the cross that crucified Jesus Christ. The &quot;True Cross&quot; is like the Buddha&#39;s relic in Buddhism. It is not uncommon in the Christian world, and its authenticity is doubtful. The Church of Our Savior is fascinating because it has stood for more than 900 years and has survived wars and earthquakes. It is the only well-preserved ancient building in the entire ancient city of Ani. However, it was accidentally struck by lightning in 1957, leaving only half of the outer wall. Standing among the rubble with the vault, it looks like a warrior whose skin has been eroded but whose skeleton is erect, showing a unique desolate beauty in this thousand-year-old ruins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/AnOBp9f1cSPaiSZ0p20VdlU05RZgqZof8D9x9qNt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/AnOBp9f1cSPaiSZ0p20VdlU05RZgqZof8D9x9qNt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Church of the Saviour&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most magnificent church in Ani is The Byzantine-style Ani Cathedral was designed by Trdat Mendet, the master architect who presided over the reconstruction of Hagia Sophia in Constantinople. Construction started in 987 AD and took 24 years to complete. This cathedral looks inconspicuous from a distance, like a magnificent mansion. When you walk into the church and take a closer look, you will find that it combines grandeur and exquisiteness: the grandeur is reflected in the tall red and black basalt columns inside - Byzantine style architecture. The main purpose of the architect is to use height to create a gap in a limited space, so that believers will feel awe; the exquisiteness is reflected in the meticulous carvings everywhere in the church, making believers sigh for the perfection of heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hagia Sophia, Ani Cathedral was converted into a mosque by the Seljuq conquerors who believed in Islam, named &quot;Victory&quot;. After the Seljuks left, the Georgians and Armenians turned it back into a church, and after the Turks came, they turned it into a mosque again... After several rounds of sawing, the vault, which was the soul of the Byzantine church building, collapsed, and so No one cares about this cathedral anymore, and it stands alone overlooking the rushing Aras river below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/lfbdpmz14PYzPWK93qkeod9h4xfYb7bYbF7rJJBv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/lfbdpmz14PYzPWK93qkeod9h4xfYb7bYbF7rJJBv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cathedral&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another St. Gregory the Great in the west of the city The church was also built by Trdat Mendet, which makes me suspect that this is a character similar to the water conservancy engineer Zheng Guo at the end of the Warring States Period, who was sent by the Byzantine Empire to consume the national power of the Bagratid Dynasty. Its vault design is exactly the same as that of Hagia Sophia. Unfortunately, it collapsed not long after it was built, and now only a huge circular base and a pile of rubble remain. On its northeast side is a Georgian church, and on its east side is the Zoroastrian temple left by the Persians, which is the oldest architectural remains in the entire city of Ani. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third St. Gregory the Great Church in Ani was built in 1215 and was funded by a wealthy Armenian businessman. It witnessed the final glory of Ani. Just over twenty years later, the Mongols came over, slaughtered all the civilians, and turned the castle into a camp. Later Turks called this church Resimli Kilise, which means mural church. It is hidden halfway up the valley and is not easily visible from the mesa. There are long Armenian inscriptions on the outer wall of the church, and a large number of early Christian murals are preserved inside. The lines are elegant and smooth, and there is no dullness in such religious propaganda paintings of the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/E4yrX2ktkjLLaMKgpJm3Usst2dieC7leGjLqgIt2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/E4yrX2ktkjLLaMKgpJm3Usst2dieC7leGjLqgIt2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116066&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fresco church&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/4LIZWpuDi030WkfHTln9fYPMfPNCJBPE0YEv4FpA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/20/10/23/4LIZWpuDi030WkfHTln9fYPMfPNCJBPE0YEv4FpA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116067&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mural church preservation The murals &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, let’s talk about the marks left by the Seljuks. The first is the Church of Holy Apostles built by the Armenians. The Seljuks actually opened a new arch in it, which is transparent from north to south, and turned into a large car shop for resting caravans. But because of this, the church escaped the war and fire, and its internal structure and decoration are well preserved. Its rib arches, carvings and mosaics can still be clearly seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a red-brown building on the cliff south of the ancient city. From a distance, it looks like a rectangular factory building with a large chimney. The architectural style is very different from the surrounding Armenian or Byzantine churches, but the color scheme is similar. This is actually the first mosque in Turkish history. It was built by the Seljuqs in 1072. It adopts the Armenian red and black color scheme. The &quot;big chimney&quot; is a minaret, but the top of the tower has collapsed. . The mosque overlooks the Arras Valley. There is the Monastery of Our Lady and the Broken Bridge at the bottom of the valley. Armenia is on the other side of the river. Since Turkey and Armenia are feuding countries, they have not yet established diplomatic relations, and the borders between the two countries are naturally closed to each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/B8ZQc7lMGZjtNY5ZNJBgRpcHaIH7tvYTzzZCJw8j.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/23/B8ZQc7lMGZjtNY5ZNJBgRpcHaIH7tvYTzzZCJw8j.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;116068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mosque&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ancient city of Ani was listed as a A world cultural heritage, it is not only a witness to Armenia’s long civilization, but also a shining pearl on the Silk Road. Austrian art historian Josef Strzygowski once commented on Ani: Only the genius who built Hagia Sophia (Byzantium) and St. Peter&#39;s Basilica (Rome) can truly understand the importance of the Armenian pioneers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, blocked by ethnic hatred and geopolitics, Armenians are only separated from this thousand-year-old capital by a river, but they cannot visit it. Coincidentally, Mount Ararat, the spiritual totem of Armenian civilization, has also been assigned to Turkey. Armenians can only look up from outside the border at the foot of this perfect cone-shaped volcano. Although they are close at hand, they cannot take a step closer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ani and Ararat are the cultural roots of the Armenian nation that are elusive! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[关注 | 2023诺贝尔奖揭晓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258135]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 18:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>; Starting from October 2, the list of 2023 Nobel Prize winners will be announced one after another. This year’s prize will be increased to 11 million Swedish kronor, approximately A total of RMB 7.23 million. The scientific highlight of the year, when human stars shine, from mRNA vaccines to attosecond pulsed light to the discovery and development of quantum dots... Behind some esoteric terms, the next future of the world may be hidden. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公务员招录：“35周岁以下”的门槛可否放开？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258050]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, a hot topic regarding the civil service examination is: relaxing the age limit and replacing the current &quot;35-year-old&quot; The threshold for &quot;under the age of 40 or 45&quot; has been relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of discussion is a reflection of the mid-life crisis in the workplace. Many people have worked for more than ten years and are in the prime of life, facing workplace pressure and even unemployment crises. There are many job opportunities in the market for fresh graduates, and civil service positions are also fully open to them, with preferential admissions. Even in the civil service examination itself, fresh graduates have an advantage. A large number of young people are pouring into the public service system, and middle-aged people are under pressure from the workplace, which they think is unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Middle-aged people are just a little older, but when it comes to being energetic and hard-working, they are not inferior to young people in any of them. When it comes to work experience and communication and coordination, the abilities of middle-aged people in their thirties are far beyond that of fresh graduates who have just left school. It has to be said that this complaint is justified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The civil service system has always favored fresh graduates, roughly because college students are highly educated, learn new things quickly, and have strong plasticity. This is true in an era when college students are scarce. But nowadays, most middle-aged people are college students, and their education level and work ability are fully qualified. The reason in the past is no longer tenable. In fact, the most important reason is: to relieve employment pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the college graduation season, college students rush into the market and the short-term employment pressure is very high. Recruit civil servants and &quot;leave&quot; jobs to them. In years of economic downturn, we even hesitate to expand recruitment to relieve employment pressure. This seems to be an impeccable arrangement that kills two birds with one stone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, recruiting college students for civil servants does not really solve the employment problem, because civil servants rely on taxes to support them. To create wealth and tax revenue, we have to rely on enterprise production and operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of actual needs, it seems more reasonable to select people with certain social experience as civil servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Civil service positions in China are generally divided into general management, professional and technical, and administrative law enforcement categories. Professional and technical positions have a small number of people and high requirements, and young people usually have no opportunity; administrative law enforcement positions perform punishment, supervision, inspection and other responsibilities, involve major matters, and have tense interpersonal interactions, making it often difficult for newcomers to the job to be competent. There is a tradition of “mentoring and apprenticeship” in frontline law enforcement work, and here’s why. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comprehensive management position, which has the largest number of people and handles the widest range of affairs, it is necessary to interact with people and involve the basic rights of citizens. Even a simple window clerk&#39;s ability, efficiency and sense of responsibility will have a significant impact. More comprehensive management positions will inherit the leadership&#39;s will and come down to merchants and individuals. While they work within the legal framework, they have a lot of room for personal judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young man who has just stepped out of school and entered the public sector, lacking social experience and no work experience, can be said to be ignorant of the sufferings of the world to a certain extent. Its services and management are closely related to the interests of citizens. Especially in administrative law enforcement positions, the overturned palms of law enforcement officers often affect the joys and sorrows of other people&#39;s families. Is this appropriate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, middle-aged people who have long-term work experience and have dealt with complex relationships may be more suitable for civil servants. It’s not that they are more compassionate than young people, but they are better able to understand complex things, appreciate the hardships of the world, and make appropriate decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, we have seen from the media that individual civil servants are rigid in enforcing the law. To give a few examples, for example, in March this year, a snack bar in Fuzhou newly opened and placed several opening flower baskets at the door. It was deemed to be &quot;operating on the road&quot; and was fined a sum of money before it opened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July this year, a man who sells vegetables on a tricycle in Henan received a &quot;sky-high price ticket&quot; for selling substandard vegetables. He made a profit of 21.05 yuan from selling vegetables and was fined 110,000 yuan. Outsiders find it unbelievable, but law enforcers have plausible arguments and can find evidence for them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being fined for selling vegetables, there is a very controversial fine item in rural areas. If farmers kill their own pigs, it is not a big problem if they only eat the meat. If you sell a few kilograms of meat to your neighbors, you will face a fine of tens of thousands of yuan. This kind of thing was unimaginable in the past, but now it has become a common fine item in rural society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision-makers of these policies and penalties are all middle-aged cadres and above, and they seem to have nothing to do with young people - in fact, they were also young civil servants in the past. As soon as I graduated from university, I entered officialdom. Interpersonal interactions are simple, mainly about obeying or giving instructions; I have little financial experience, mainly spending money, and I never have to look for money when I am short of money. Professional civil servants are good at paperwork and conference affairs and have limited contact with people. There is a gap with real society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, I agree with the call of contemporary middle-aged people to open the age limit for civil service examinations. Not only should the upper limit be relaxed, it would be better to set a lower limit. For example, we can discuss banning fresh graduates from taking civil service exams - they need to enter society and gain experience before they can manage and serve the public. Except for a small number of simple technical and internal civil servants, most civil servant positions should set age requirements and examine work ability to ensure that they are competent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Given that work history and abilities are relatively subjective, age is particularly important. Recruitment companies in the market will set requirements for job seekers&#39; working years and experience. The more important the position, the higher the requirements. Once incompetence is found, the job will be quickly demoted or even fired. In comparison, the recruitment criteria for civil servants are much simpler - almost only based on test scores, and there is no risk of unemployment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a lot of room for reform in the current civil servant recruitment and assessment model. The goal of the reform is to make civil servants more down-to-earth and less bureaucratic. Increasing the age requirement, examining professional resumes, and increasing the proportion of the contract appointment system are all directions that can be tried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访《少年的你》导演曾国祥：“我不希望把责任推到谁的身上”丨影视大咖谈⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257485]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/19/ 11/08/BHybgYSlr2zOIrNdKdL0mDhAAo7VfIRzcBt5eWhU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/19/11/08/BHybgYSlr2zOIrNdKdL0mDh AAo7VfIRzcBt5eWhU. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;38825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Zeng Guoxiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some eyes are only for teenagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie &quot;Young You&quot;, Chen Nian and Xiao Bei, two low-income teenagers whose parents have neglected their duties, are like two helpless little animals who need to hug each other for warmth and lick each other&#39;s wounds. When one party accidentally did something wrong and faced jail time, the other party decided to stand up and &quot;take the blame&quot;, completing an agreement that could change their fate almost instantly. There is no verbal communication, the eyes are enough to show the firm trust, and he will not hesitate to be broken into pieces. Director Tsang Kwok-hsiang is well aware of the value of a young man&#39;s eyes, so he shot a large number of close-ups, hoping to show the fire in the young man&#39;s eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eyes were exchanged again, and the location shifted to the visiting room of the detention center. A glass wall separates them from two worlds. The young man&#39;s face overlaps on the glass. You are in me, and I am in you. There should have been a thousand words, but once again, there were no words, just looking at each other, tears streaming down their faces. Soon, their fate will be reversed again. This is also a scene that makes Zeng Guoxiang proud. He insisted on not having any dialogue and what he wanted to say was expressed clearly in his eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 6, 2019, the 13th day of release, this movie focusing on college entrance examinations, tutoring and campus bullying has grossed more than 1.2 billion yuan at the box office and has a Douban score of 8.4. Yi Yang Qianxi, who plays Xiaobei, gave an impressive performance, which made him far away from the label of &quot;traffic star&quot;. The discussion also went beyond the movie itself, with many viewers recalling the joys and sorrows of their own growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Young You&quot; tells an alternative story about the college entrance examination. In the college entrance examination re-reading class, Chen Nian, a good student played by Zhou Dongyu, witnessed his friends being bullied on campus and chose to shut up. Unfortunately, he himself became a victim of bullying. She is focused on completing more important things, that is, relying on the college entrance examination to change the fate of herself and her mother who ran away to avoid debts. Xiaobei is a &quot;little gangster&quot; who was abandoned by his parents since he was a child and grew up on the streets. They came together by an accident, and Xiaobei soon appeared silently like a shadow on Chen Nian&#39;s way to and from school, protecting her from bullying. How could life be normal? One &quot;derailment&quot; and the dominoes fell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Dongyu has always been quirky and casual, which is often the case in movies. In her first film &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;, which she collaborated with Zeng Guoxiang, she just acted according to her personality, and the director just captured the moments that felt useful. But in &quot;Young You&quot;, Zeng Guoxiang repeatedly told her: &quot;I don&#39;t want Zhou Dongyu.&quot; Many times, Zhou Dongyu almost collapsed. She especially couldn&#39;t understand that if Chen Nian was beaten, he could just beat him back. Why endure it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I kept explaining to her, because you are not only carrying your own destiny, but also your mother&#39;s future.&quot; Zeng Guoxiang recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Guoxiang also needs to know more things. At first, he could not appreciate the great significance of the college entrance examination to the individual. His father is the famous actor Eric Tsang. He completed his studies in Canada, and his background is very different from that of mainland candidates. He watched a lot of documentaries about the college entrance examination and read related books. During the two days of the college entrance examination, he and his team stayed outside a middle school in Chongqing to capture photos. They stayed there from six or seven in the morning until the students left the examination room, and then they stopped working. Those two days meant a lot to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film was shot in Chongqing, and there are many scenes worth pondering. There is a spiral bridge next to the school, which looks like the Colosseum in ancient Rome, reminiscent of the atmosphere of the college entrance examination; at the same time, it spirals upward, like a metaphor for youth growth, and a turning point in the story is also placed here. In real life, this is just a pedestrian bridge at Tongyuanju Subway Station on Chongqing Metro Line 3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s like a maze. These young children can’t seem to get out of this world. We chose Chongqing because the city has many ups and downs, highs and lows, and many winding alleys. It feels like it takes forever to walk. You can&#39;t leave this place. There are viaducts and buildings everywhere you go, which gives you a feeling of pressure. We hope to present this sense of oppression and the feeling of being trapped in a place in the movie.&quot; Zeng Guoxiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2019, Zeng Guoxiang accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;To make a good movie, you must consider things from each character&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Young You&quot; has aroused a very enthusiastic response. What do you think triggered the audience&#39;s enthusiasm? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;At least in Chinese-language movies, the pain of growing up and school bullying are rarely discussed in this way. I didn&#39;t expect the response to be so big. Of course, when I wanted to make this movie, I also hoped to have such an effect. Let everyone reflect and show a little care and love to the people around them, which can have a positive impact. I have always felt that adolescence is a period that particularly needs protection and protection. Teenagers feel that the world is not good enough. The idea that they can change the world is particularly valuable and requires the protection and protection of adults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But in &quot;Young You&quot;, parents are collectively missing of. Chen Nian kept asking where the adults were when she was bullied. What are your thoughts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;I don’t want to put the responsibility on anyone. Everyone has the responsibility. This matter is extremely complicated and is not just a problem for parents. Of course, the biggest influence on a child is the parents, but we explained the state of her family in the movie. Everyone is a little powerless, and they don’t treat others like this on purpose. Sometimes the environment is like this, and people like this are formed, and things like this happen. The same goes for schools, teachers, and other students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before filming the movie, did you have any interviews with mainland campuses and senior high school students? Do some homework? Have you combined your own experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;We knew at the script stage that the college entrance examination would be a very important element. In fact, it is the timeline and backbone of the entire story. As the coming-of-age ceremony for this group of teenagers, the college entrance examination is a very, very important step. We did a lot of homework before filming. As a Hong Kong director who &quot;went north&quot;, I felt a lot of pressure to shoot such realistic subjects. I want to make sure that the things I shoot are down to earth. After watching it, everyone will feel that this is how they came here. This is the atmosphere during the college entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I read a lot of documentaries and books about the college entrance examination, talked to some teachers and students about their state during the college entrance examination, and talked to the staff or friends around me about how they passed the college entrance examination. The filming of this film started in Chongqing in mid-July 2018. During the two days of the college entrance examination in June, we went to the examination room to capture photos. We stayed there from 6 or 7 in the morning until the students left the examination room after taking the exam before calling it a day and returning. Those two days were particularly meaningful to me. We observed many details and restored them in the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the details? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;We took pictures of the entire college entrance examination, what clothes parents wore, what they brought students to the examination room, the students’ state and eyes before entering the examination room, What to talk about. We tried our best to faithfully restore what we saw in the movie. Apart from the school uniforms, it does take into account the art of the movie, so it will be made a little neater and more beautiful, but not excessive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I didn’t put too much of my own experience into the movie. After all, my growing up experience was so different from that of the students in the movie. I just tried to refer to a lot of information and materials and tried to restore what I found interesting. It&#39;s hard for me to say how I feel about it. I can only say that I sympathize with them very much and understand their pressure. Before making this movie, I had been paying attention to the news about the college entrance examination. There were many characters and stories in it, which were very interesting. Every student is burdened with heavy pressure, which is unfamiliar to me and particularly touches me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I also experienced the college entrance examination, in Canada at that time, we were quite relaxed. Although it is also a very important exam, I don’t take it that seriously. I think it is an exam that will change our future destiny. When I started working in the Mainland, I came across news reports about the college entrance examination one after another. I was particularly distressed by how much sweat some students put into preparing for the college entrance examination and how much pressure they had to bear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You majored in sociology at university. Did your professional background help? There are richer sociological issues implicit in &quot;Young You&quot;, such as class and upward mobility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;Sociology taught me how to have empathy; after leaving school, sociology taught me how to approach the perspective of different classes, countries, and races. , see things from their perspective. During this filming on campus or before, I worked as a screenwriter and wrote the script. What is the background of each character, what will happen, how to make him have his current values, and his attitude towards things. This is a very big help. . As a director, to make a good movie, you must consider things from each character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;Use close-up to show the fire in their eyes&quot;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You and Zhou Dongyu collaborated in &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;. At that time, you asked her to &quot;spare her acting&quot; and capture her suitable moments. Did you take the same approach this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;No. After &quot;July and Ansheng&quot;, there will actually be pressure for us to work together again, because no one wants to repeat what we have done. When I photographed her before, I tried to capture her normal feeling, always going with her more naughty and casual feeling. But this time I suppressed all her past and told her very clearly that I don’t want the Zhou Dongyu of the past, and I hope that everyone can see a very different Zhou Dongyu. She understands very well and wants to find a breakthrough. During this collaboration, what I told her the most was &quot;I don&#39;t want Zhou Dongyu.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In &quot;Young You&quot;, the audience saw the big Zhou Dongyu Sometimes she is extremely tolerant. For example, she was always bullied by a group of girls in school. It is said that she was very dissatisfied during the filming. According to her character, it would be fine if she was bullied and beaten back. Why should she endure it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;She was very entangled when she first started filming. She couldn&#39;t believe it: Why do you have to endure it like this? I kept explaining to her that because you are not only burdened with your own destiny, but also your mother&#39;s future, if you resist and speak out, the result will be that you will not be able to study, review, and take the college entrance examination properly. The latter is more important to you than anything else. important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I choose to close my eyes. I feel dissatisfied when others are bullied and cannot bear to see them, but don’t speak out. Later, she became the target of bullying, but she still chose to endure it, because she felt that everything would be fine after this year, and she would be able to leave this place and get into a good university. Her fate was different from that of her mother. So she has been under so much pressure and struggling. I kept explaining to Zhou Dongyu, and after the scene with her mother was finished, she gradually understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a scene in the movie that is very impressive. Two teenagers are visiting a prison. faces overlapped on the glass. You also used many close-ups of characters&#39; faces in the film. Is this an aesthetic consideration? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;The method of overlapping faces is not my innovation. It has been done in many movies, but I think it is very suitable here. I have been analyzing this with the actors, and later on in the interrogation scene, the two people have become one. In the close-up of each person, there is a reflection of another person, that is, I am in you, and you are in me. I like to use a lot of close-ups in my previous films, but this time there are a lot more. Not only the close-ups of the main actors, but also the close-ups of many students, I wanted to capture the eyes and expressions of these teenagers. The young you and the young me have to show the innocence and straightforwardness of their youth. I hope to use close-ups to show the fire in their eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to Zhou Dongyu, Yi Yang Qianxi’s performance in the movie is also good That’s interesting. What specific “training” did you do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;It’s not that I changed him. Maybe people were biased against him before, labeling him an “idol” and a top traffic person. &quot;Little fresh meat&quot;, I immediately felt that he couldn&#39;t act. Everyone has not seen him act fairly, but he is actually a very serious boy. From the first day we chatted, to the time he joined the cast, he was really attentive and determined to be a good actor and play the role of Xiaobei well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the scene where Xiaobei and Chen Nian were chatting about Xiaobei’s mother on the bed, I actually didn’t tell him that I wanted to cry at all. I just talked to him and explained his relationship with his mother. He brewed it by himself and acted it out. When the emotion arrived, tears naturally flowed down his face. This shows that Qian Xi himself is a very sensitive boy, and the mother-son relationship allows him to find the fulcrum to enter the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“I hope to give the actors a sense of security on the set”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yi Yang Qianxi and Zhou Dongyu had a rivalry scene. When the two first came into contact, he pushed Zhou Dongyu into the corner. This scene was very tense and the scale was right. How did you explain the scene to him at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;This is a very good point. He was a little nervous at first. He had never had the experience of pressing a girl against the wall, so he was very embarrassed and shy and didn&#39;t know how to act. I also took a lot of shots during that scene, and I kept guiding and demonstrating to him how to do it. He also needed some time to adjust slowly. Patting and patting, he slowly let go, and we were able to reach the degree we needed. He is a very good actor, but he doesn’t have that much experience. We need to talk to him more and give him more time to meet our requirements for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wei Lai, the perpetrator of campus bullying in the movie, happens to be a A very good-looking girl with a good family background. What are your considerations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang: &lt;/strong>;We met the actors and wrote the script at the same time. I have always been confused about what kind of person to choose to play the role. I don’t want her to become so superficial. In many movies, one look at the person&#39;s appearance and you know that they are definitely the head of the bully, which we want to avoid as much as possible. I met many actors and kept an open attitude to see what kind of people I could meet that would inspire me. Later we met Zhou Ye, and it was actually she who inspired us to think this way. The day she came, we had a strong feeling that she was very confident, and then she was so beautiful and cute. At that time, we felt that if we cast such a person, with such a high starting point, and bullying others, the cruelty would be even stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, the people who have the least empathy do not necessarily have poor families or bad backgrounds. Instead, those with good family backgrounds but distorted family views are the most terrifying. They think that others can do whatever they want. I&#39;m at my mercy. So we set it from the beginning that Wei Lai has a good family environment and is good at studying, but her family view is very distorted and she has no empathy. She doesn&#39;t feel that she is doing anything wrong to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;To sum up, do you have any unique experience in &quot;training&quot; actors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Guoxiang:&lt;/strong>;I have no secret, I am still very honest with actors. I hope to give the actors a sense of security on set, which is very important. Actors often bare their hearts to the audience. If they don&#39;t trust the director and the team, they will often protect themselves and their performance will not be that good. What the director can do is to invest more, shoot this point well, and consider their feelings more. Small things like this allow the actors to slowly build trust in you as the director, and then they will trust your opinions and tips. I often let the actors play the version they think is most correct, and I make adjustments based on that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 17:55:10 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的家乡重庆丨月是故乡明⑤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257350]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-05 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 12/02/nszAcS51cXSdJFRcz6yYfmyY5xfdkskn6p7vDzSc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/nszAcS51cXSdJFRcz6yYfmyY5xfdkskn6p7v DzSc. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 1, 2012, in Ciqikou, Chongqing, citizens raised the Drinking tea and chatting on the rocks &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown, Chongqing, is located in the southwest of China&#39;s inland area and the upper reaches of the Yangtze River. It is a municipality directly under the Central Government of China, an important strategic fulcrum for the development of the western region, an important connection point between the “One Belt and One Road” and the Yangtze River Economic Belt, and an inland open highland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chongqing is a mountain city, because it is mainly a mountain road with many uphill and downhill slopes. There are beautiful night views of the mountain city, majestic cross-river bridges, unique urban traffic, and magical overpasses that even experienced drivers can get lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the special geographical environment and climate, Chongqing has many nicknames, such as &quot;Stove&quot; named for the extremely hot summer; &quot;Mountain City&quot; named for the city&#39;s buildings on the mountains; The clouds are light and the fog is heavy, so it is also known as the &quot;fog city&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a city with unique terrain, mountains, rivers and culture. As a &quot;Chongqing kid&quot; who grew up in Jiefangbei and climbed hills and mountains eating spicy hot pot, I have a deep affection for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/dESuJydDdo45qO7g4ofhWqGEq2QxuGez6UDIdkK4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/dESuJydDdo45qO7g4ofhWqGEq2QxuGez6UDIdkK4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 16, 2018, Chongqing Jiefangbei. As a city landmark, the Liberation Monument has witnessed the changes in Chongqing over the past 40 years of reform and opening up &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/P8dxXnb3vmLdSWqZKDXIYfWKsJOUq8saK4JKKEka.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/P8dxXnb3vmLdSWqZKDXIYfWKsJOUq8saK4JKKEka.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On June 9, 2018, citizens chatted leisurely in a teahouse on Huangjueping Main Street in Jiulongpo. This teahouse is the only teahouse in Chongqing that maintains the style of the 1980s &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/zdEN79mBMW2cYkXFAXQzbylpflysTYLvr0HYmb3m.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/zdEN79mBMW2cYkXFAXQzbylpflysTYLvr0HYmb3m.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017 On June 22, 2019, people danced the baba dance in the riverside square at night &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qBVYUk6OxoBO1tmuRhZsENZmGeYicPw75zRT2Q7e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qBVYUk6OxoBO1tmuRhZsENZmGeYicPw75zRT2Q7e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On July 15, 2018, people watched the night view of the city at Yikeshu Scenic Area in Nanshan &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/wrmOfmfwdIgoArJpoH6JJyGCS3fTcwCAioYNgHmY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/wrmOfmfwdIgoArJpoH6JJyGCS3fTcwCAioYNgHmY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On June 26, 2020, citizens jumped from the high platform into the Jialing River at Shimen Bridge. The high platform is a remnant of the former pier and is now a diving platform for diving enthusiasts &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/lNOJdGlHG95lcfUwhqqNdCOLXzHsjn9OJwhVBy1l.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/lNOJdGlHG95lcfUwhqqNdCOLXzHsjn9OJwhVBy1l.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On August 23, 2010, people watched the floods passing by the Chaotianmen River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/H5RlxtlMUYPa4P5L6flO94Udr3pU7k9IH7T4TgQl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;488&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/H5RlxtlMUYPa4P5L6flO94Udr3pU7k9IH7T4TgQl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On July 7, 2013, in Shizhuhuangshui Town, an old couple from Yubei District sat huddled on a hanging chair, looking peaceful. The uncle said that they come to Huangshui to escape the heat every summer, and go to Hainan to spend the winter &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/SjKdI7WsFq5GCaZYX5nWhrw0UKvhURtgWAX2ZbNw.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/SjKdI7WsFq5GCaZYX5nWhrw0UKvhURtgWAX2ZbNw.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2017 On May 16, 2019, citizens returning home walked on the pedestrian bridge on Zuoying Street in Yuzhong District. This overpass is about 40 meters above the ground, with a deck width of about 2 meters and a length of about 30 meters &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/kpnRG6oQWBDTGzt2Tjvxa9cOjTAHH2SPEvLNYRBt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/kpnRG6oQWBDTGzt2Tjvxa9cOjTAHH2SPEvLNYRBt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 16:00 on August 30, 2012, the old landmarks of the Chaotianmen area, the Chongqing Port Passenger Terminal and the Three Gorges Hotel came to a close - successfully blasted. The future Chaotianmen will be an urban complex integrating residences, hotels, shopping malls, office buildings, service apartments, and restaurants and clubs &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/Bi38Ogp9m6PGFM2B054KuiWymePnrlrTAz7haMx6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;490 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/Bi38Ogp9m6PGFM2B054KuiWymePnrlrTAz7haMx6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 19, 2020, people were relaxing on the rocks by the Jialing River, and the city lights were reflected in the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/1ntLJ5pISRrv9dMm5i4Z6CYHPO6UHO80nWPjl4zT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 734&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/1ntLJ5pISRrv9dMm5i4Z6CYHPO6UHO80nWPjl4zT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2018, the Yangtze River Cableway is a large-scale cross-river passenger cableway designed and manufactured by China. It has a total length of 1,166 meters and connects Yuzhong District and Nan&#39;an District. 6 meters, running time is about 4 minutes &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/gmahmon9COvTteK99FKkXNswKi50YsoXV1RrmJsG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/21/12/02/gmahmon9COvTteK99FKkXNswKi50YsoXV1RrmJsG.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;March 2, 2012, Beibei Tutuo Chedu Wharf, with more and more cross-river bridges put into use, fewer and fewer people cross the river by boat. This pier has only one ferry, and very few cars cross the river every day. This is the last car ferry in the main city of Chongqing&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/E3hHK9vwZEXClYALI2xNvjUYJQIAqv2xhXBOMXKD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;489 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/E3hHK9vwZEXClYALI2xNvjUYJQIAqv2xhXBOMXKD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;174014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;August 7, 2018. Air-raid shelters were used to avoid enemy air raids during the Anti-Japanese War. Since 2003, Chongqing began to try to open up civil air-raid projects as a cooling spot for residents in summer&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Song/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>