<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从“局外人”到“第一个人”：加缪110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRmVSmK7F8E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRm VSmK7F8E. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Albert Camus (November 7, 1913 - 1960 January 4), French writer and philosopher, born in Algeria. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature at the age of 44 and died unexpectedly at the age of 47. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, 1913, Albert Camus was born. On January 4, 1960, he died in an accidental car accident at the age of 46. Today, it has been 110 years since Camus was born and more than sixty years since his death, but people do not feel that Camus belongs to a distant era. He used his short writing career to create a series of distinctive contemporary images. , is still closely related to our living situation today. The embarrassment, discord, and sense of powerlessness of &quot;outsiders&quot;, the repeated hard labor in &quot;Sisyphus&quot;, and the struggle and dignity of people facing disaster in &quot;The Plague&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus is both a writer and a thinker. He does not capture readers with the splendor of his words, but shocks them with his postmodern understanding of life. He is the youngest winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature. one. Camus&#39;s enduring popularity is symptomatic. Just like Kafka, he wrote a &quot;clinical diagnosis&quot; of contemporary people&#39;s mental dilemma; just like Lu Xun, he does not provide bright answers, or even It&#39;s a bit dark and cold, but at the end of the coldness is a philosophy of resistance and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus once worked as a journalist. On January 1, 1940, he wrote an editorial for the last issue of the &quot;Republican Evening News&quot;. You can get a glimpse of his restraint, coolness, and calmness with a sense of power. Words: &quot;This year, hoping for happiness will be in vain, building it through work is the key. Don&#39;t hope for anything, but do something. Don&#39;t wait for others to build your destiny from beginning to end, especially when destiny It is still in our hands. The Evening Republican will not wish you happiness this year, knowing that you are going through a severe physical and mental trauma. But it will ask you to maintain the necessary strength and sobriety to strive to maintain your own tranquility and dignity. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the darkest moment of World War II. Shortly after Camus wrote this dedication, while fleeing on the border of France and Spain, Benjamin failed to get a pass and came to the end of his life. At the end, although Zweig fled to Brazil, he still committed suicide in despair. Camus belongs to a new generation of young people. He once joined the French Communist Party, fought and resisted, and condensed the power of his resistance into continuous writing. If the deaths of Benjamin and Zweig marked the spiritual boundaries of yesterday&#39;s world, Camus established the starting point of his writing on the wasteland of war and post-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The postwar world is neither a wasteland nor a new heaven and a new earth. His arguments with his friend Sartre and his ambivalent attitude toward the Algerian War made Camus increasingly lonely while receiving literary honors. When he returned to autobiographical writing and the &quot;first person&quot;, an accident caused this sharp soul to bid farewell in advance. For a writer like Camus, commemorating him at any time is both our condolences and an invitation for him to return. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;France’s “outsider”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 2 a.m. on November 7, 1913, her mother Catalina gave birth to Camus, who was the first child in the family. second son. The next day, at the Mondovi Municipal Government in Algeria, the father registered the birth of his child. He was 28 years old and worked as a wine cellar manager. The mother was 31 years old and filled in the occupation column as a housewife. The birthplace of Saint-Paul Farm is located 8 kilometers south of the city of Mondovi. The nearby city of Bonny is the most important port in French Algeria, not far from the Tunisian border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Algeria became a French colony in the 19th century, most of the immigrants who immigrated here were poor people from all over France, as well as Spain, Italy and other European countries. New immigrants were granted residence rights under French protection and lived among the overwhelming majority of locals. “The French in Algeria are of mixed race. Spaniards, Alsatians, Italians, Maltese, Jews, Greeks gather there,” Camus later wrote. Camus is a mixed-race child, his mother is Spanish, and he believes that his father comes from Alsace, the battlefield where France and Germany have fought for generations. The reason for &quot;thinking&quot; is that my father&#39;s exact ancestral home has been lost and difficult to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus had never met his father before he could remember. My father is 1.8 meters tall, with brown hair and blue eyes. He works in a wine company, supervising the grape pressing, winemaking, storage, and shipment to the Port of Pawnee for shipment. Not long after Camus was born, World War I broke out, and his father was conscripted into the French army. Almost as soon as he entered the battlefield, he was injured in the Battle of the Marne to prevent the German army from advancing towards Paris. He was hit by shell fragments and was sent to a rear hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 1914, my mother received the bad news by telegram, as well as a small piece of shrapnel removed from her husband&#39;s head that the widow had asked to keep. His father was mysterious to Camus. He often asked his mother: &quot;Am I really like my father?&quot; &quot;Oh, you look exactly like your father.&quot; During the four years of World War I, his mother received no After passing a penny in France, it was only a few months before the end of the war that I received official notification of her husband&#39;s death and a pension check. An accountant next door helped her fill out the pension application form because no one in her family knew how to fill it out. In order to make a living, my mother sorted warheads in an ammunition manufacturing factory until she suffered from rheumatism and was unable to continue this work, so she began to work as a domestic helper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 8 months to 17 years old, Camus lived with his mother and grandmother under the same roof in Algiers, the capital of Algeria. It was Belku, the workers&#39; district of the city, home to people who worked hard in small workshops and port equipment factories, craftsmen, small traders, grassroots civil servants and clerks. As an adult, Camus returned to the house frequently, sometimes to visit the elderly and sometimes as a temporary haven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in middle school, football fascinated Camus. He was very brave and liked to tackle from the feet of his opponents, so he was often injured. Camus described a fierce football match, on a pitch adjacent to a cemetery, in which the opposing players pressed forward mercilessly. They “were all on top of me, spikes on my shins, knees on my crotch, squeezing me against the goal post…” “I quickly learned that the ball doesn’t come from where you expect it to. This was very helpful in my life, especially in France, where not everyone is honest,&quot; Camus later wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Camus came to settle in Paris in early 1940, he felt that &quot;I am not from here, nor from anywhere else. The world is just a strange scenery, and my spirit is helpless here. Everything It has nothing to do with yourself.&quot; He was stuck between France and Algeria, between Paris and impoverished Bercoux across the Mediterranean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;969&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Camus (first from right) is backstage with two actors during the performance of his drama &quot;Martial Law&quot; in Paris in 1948. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sisyphus&quot;: The victorious loser&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While Sartre, who came from a middle-class background, was dreaming of a literary hero, and Beauvoir was enjoying her books and the gifts in the candy shop window, Camus was in a home without electricity, running water, newspapers and books, and no Growing up in the world of radio, he once wrote in his diary: &quot;Living in poverty for a few years is enough to create all the sensitivity.&quot; Tuberculosis plagued Camus throughout his life, but it also exempted him from military service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1942, &quot;The Outsider&quot; and &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; were published one after another. The former tells the story of a French-Algerian named Meursault who experienced two deaths. The first was his mother&#39;s death. He couldn&#39;t even remember the date and didn&#39;t shed tears. The second was when he had an affair with a holdover on the beach. There was a conflict with the Arab about the knife. Meursault happened to be holding a friend&#39;s gun. When his eyes were dazzled by the reflection of the sea and the blade, he almost subconsciously shot the man. After being arrested, Meursault told the judge in confusion that the reason he shot was the sun. Meursault did not defend himself, and the court also lacked interest in the murder case and focused on investigating his personal life. Indifference became the biggest evidence of crime and was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of the essay collection &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; is taken from a story in &quot;Homer&#39;s Epic&quot;. King Sisyphus disobeyed God and was sentenced to push a huge boulder up a mountain for eternity, each time the boulder approached the top of the mountain. When the time comes, it will slip from his hand and roll down again, and he can only go back again, starting over and over again. Camus used the myth of Sisyphus, just like Freud through the Oedipus complex, to make the mythical figure deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts again. The most famous sentence in &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; may be: &quot;There is only one philosophical question that is truly serious, and that is suicide. To judge whether life is worth living or not...&quot; Camus said in the preface of an English translation many years later , wrote this book because &quot;even within the borders of nihilism, it is possible to find ways to move beyond nihilism.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play Caligula, published in 1944, discusses freedom and meaninglessness pushed to the extreme by recreating the story of the assassinated Roman Emperor Suetonius. These three books are collectively called Camus&#39; &quot;Trilogy of the Absurd.&quot; They were written and published in the critical state of war and occupied Paris, where everything was compromised and everything was lost. From Kierkegaard&#39;s existential philosophy, Camus saw Abraham, who sacrificed his son, as &quot;infinitely He gave up everything, and then took it all back with the help of absurd power.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus took the initiative to get to know him during the rehearsal of Sartre&#39;s play &quot;The Fly&quot;, and the two hit it off. Previously, Sartre had written an article for Camus&#39;s novel &quot;The Stranger&quot;, and Camus had commented on it. The special &quot;Disgusting&quot;. Beauvoir and Sartre found that Camus was a simple, happy man who was always funny and vulgar in his conversations, very emotional, and would even sit on a snowy street at two in the morning and talk about his love troubles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don Juan went from one woman to another not because of a lack of love, but because he loved them with equal passion and devoted himself to them every time. He must repeat this talent and harmony. Explore... Why do you have to love less to love well?&quot; &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; reads. Camus had two marriages. His first wife, Simone, was unable to quit morphine, which caused him great psychological trauma. After remarrying Francine, Camus maintained semi-public intimate relationships with many women. , including theater actress Maria Casares, who exchanged more than 800 love letters. It is as if Don Juan became an incarnation of Sisyphus pushing the boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Plague&quot;: End and Resistance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II and the liberation of Paris, the reputations of Sartre, Beauvoir and Camus were at their peak, and the Left Bank The Flower Goddess and the Double Sole Cafe in Shanghai have shrouded the halo of existentialist writers, and the radius of the halo extends to the United States on the other side of the ocean. All three of them received invitations to visit from New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From March to May 1946, Camus traveled around the United States. He was more nervous than Sartre and felt that he was always affected by endless little troubles. He&#39;s also a careful observer, noting that Americans drink juice in the morning, drink scotch and soda across the country, and are passionate about animals, from gorillas at the Bronx Zoo to taxidermy at the Museum of Natural History. , death and the dead can be dressed up as quickly as possible, &quot;die and leave the rest to us.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only place that made Camus feel familiar and at ease was the Bowery Street in New York. At that time, it was still an abandoned area, full of cheap bars and run-down hotels, with the elevated railway running from the height of the second floor. Passing by, shadows covered everything below. Camus was disgusted by the United States and felt that there was a lack of pain and tragedy, but in the eyes of many critics, &quot;The Stranger&quot; is a parody of American noir novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, the novel &quot;The Plague&quot; was published and was so popular among readers that it was reprinted eight times in two years. After that, &quot;The Plague&quot; and &quot;The Stranger&quot; were at the top of the French literary bestseller list for a long time. From 1941 to 1942, the plague was prevalent in Algeria, which was the starting point for Camus to prepare &quot;The Plague&quot;. The reason why this novel is so thrilling is because the plague is described as both real and terrifying, and it is also symbolic. It alludes to World War II. During this period, the harsh reality of the Nazis in Germany was wreaking havoc. Nazism and fascism are also a political and spiritual plague. Its military power, spy system, autocracy and racism sweep across everything like the god of death. After being manipulated by it, they either succumb to it, cooperate with it, or know that it is impossible. Those who resist for the land are like all living beings in the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Camus highlighted three symbolic situations of life. One is the situation of separation, including the separation of relatives, separation of husband and wife, and separation of lovers, which means isolation, blockade, imprisonment, and exile. , concentration camp... The second is that there is no condition of any woman in the novel, which means imbalance, deformity, bitterness, and lifelessness... The most terrifying atmosphere and situation is death...&quot; Liu Mingjiu, the translator of the Chinese version of &quot;The Plague&quot; Said, &quot;&#39;The plague is lurking in everyone, because no one, yes, no one in the world is immune to it&#39;... In this way, Camus also put his philosophy about the absurd world in &quot;The Plague&quot; It greatly broadens and deepens the story, and points the absurd roots to human faults and human society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the desperate situation of World War II, Camus was not the only one who chose to write about a critical state through the background of the plague. , the German playwright Brecht also created &quot;The Life of Galileo&quot;, in which Galileo also experienced a narrow escape from the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I tried to use the plague to express the suffocation we suffer and the environment we endure that threatens and drives people into exile.” Camus said. In the apocalyptic city of Ahlan, the protagonist of the novel, Dr. Bernard Rieux, became an ordinary hero because of his dedication to his duties. Camus reshapes heroes in the form of anti-heroes. When disaster strikes, what we can expect is not a hero falling from the sky, but every ordinary person resisting evil through the smallest efforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Resistor, a collection of essays published in 1951, is where Camus clearly proposed the philosophy of resistance after the philosophy of the absurd, &quot;What is a rebel? A person who says &#39;no&#39;. However, although he He refuses but does not give up: he is also the person who says &#39;yes&#39; from the very beginning.&quot; However, this book with a huge amount of information put him in a situation where he was surrounded by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Back to &quot;First Man&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Rebel&quot; involves a commentary on Surrealism and was immediately criticized literary by the group. Refute. More intense criticism came from leftist thinkers. Because he disagreed with Camus&#39;s many views on the revolution and Soviet history, the magazine &quot;Modern&quot; edited by Sartre published a fiercely criticized article by its editor, Francis Chanson. Camus had to respond and wrote an open letter to Sartre to defend himself. This led to Sartre&#39;s &quot;Reply to Camus&quot;, which was extremely harsh and mean, calling Camus &quot;a bourgeois&quot; and &quot;abandoned history&quot;, and the publication of &quot;The Resistance&quot; was a counter-revolutionary &quot;Thermidor Coup&quot;. . Their long-standing friendship was ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike many writers who only define their writing by &quot;pure literature&quot;, Camus has always been an organic intellectual. It was the strong &quot;political nature&quot; of &quot;The Resistance&quot; that stirred up the hornet&#39;s nest. The break between Sartre and Camus, the pair of existential writers, and the subsequent breakup between Godard and Truffaut, the twin stars of the French New Wave of cinema, became sensational and intriguing events in the postwar cultural history. Sartre stood in a more radical position. Even when it came to the Nobel Prize, he was more radical and rejected it outright. What is depressing is that Camus, a writer who has always been in the progressive camp, was denounced as conservative because he was more moderate on certain issues, or did not follow a certain principle or dogma and put forward his personal understanding and judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1949, Camus created a play &quot;The Just&quot;, in which a group of &quot;terrorists&quot; debate whether innocent people can be harmed when carrying out political assassinations. Camus made it clear that this was wrong. When Algeria&#39;s independence struggle broke out in 1954, he also believed that the rebels&#39; planting bombs and killing innocent people were equally unfair as the French government&#39;s violence and execution. This view made him controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a speech celebrating Camus&#39;s winning of the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1957, Camus was asked to explain why he did not support the Algerian uprising against colonialism. He said: &quot;Now people are going to Algeria. put bombs on the tram tracks. My mother might have been on one of the tracks. If that was justice, I would have chosen my mother.&quot; Camus called for the creation of an Arab, Berber, Blackfoot nation in Algeria A coalition government in which Frenchmen (European immigrants) governed as equals made everyone hate him. French nationalists feel that he sympathizes with Algerians, and Algerians feel that he represents white French people. However, his father died needlessly at the age of 29, and his mother was an extremely poor and illiterate woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 4, 1960, the car driven by publisher Michel Gallimard with Albert Camus in the back seat crashed into a tree, rolled and struck another. In the tree, Camus was thrown out of the back window. In the mud not far away, people found a briefcase containing Camus&#39;s diary and an unfinished novel &quot;First Man&quot;. This book is based on his childhood life in Algeria and imagines him. &#39;s father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Camus passed away, although Sartre did not forgive him, he wrote an obituary full of praise in the &quot;Osservatore Française&quot;: &quot;He was the heir to the ethical school of anti-historical trends in the 20th century. , his works are perhaps the most original of all French literati. His stubborn, narrow-minded, simple and simple humanitarian feelings launched an unreasonable challenge to the widespread and ugly orders of our time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the news of Camus’ death over the phone, Beauvoir took sleeping pills that had been discontinued for a long time, but still couldn’t fall asleep, so she got out of bed and braved the biting January drizzle in Paris. Wandering the streets. The next morning, she was still in a daze: &quot;He can&#39;t see this morning.&quot; But in fact, Camus not only did not pass away, but because of the strong impact of the car accident, he became the center of the world&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last few pages of &quot;Camus&#39; Notes&quot;, there are these words: &quot;In the short daylight given to you, keep warm, illuminate, and don&#39;t deviate from your track. ... Millions of other suns come to accompany you to rest. ... Under the happy slate, sleep for the first time. ... The wind sows, the wind harvests, but the creator is human, passing through the times, with a moment of life Proud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(References: Herbert Lotman&#39;s &quot;The Biography of Camus&quot;, Sarah Bakewell&#39;s &quot;The Existential Café&quot;, &quot;The Complete Works of Camus&quot; edited by Liu Mingjiu and &quot;Camus&#39; Notes: 1935-1959 (Selected Collection)&quot; translated by Guo Hongan)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[再访“山地之王”：高仙芝的西域足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260116]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hijri 133 (&lt;em>;Ten years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty, AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;751 &lt;/em>;), the month of pilgrimage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hajj month is the 12th month of Muharram. This year&#39;s pilgrimage month is in midsummer. On the edge of the Central Asian steppes, a black flag army knelt down and prayed in the direction of the Holy Land on the right bank of the Talas River, completed the morning ritual, and then set up its formation facing the rising sun. : At the front are light cavalry equipped with large horses. They hold Damascus scimitars and stand on foot to harness their power; then there is an infantry group mainly composed of Khorasan and Tocharian people, and behind them are archers and long-range soldiers. Spearmen; on both wings are Sogdian cavalry from the river countries. Although they are high-spirited, they have not been naturalized for a long time, and they are pagans. Their combat effectiveness is still questionable, so they are used to protect the flanks of the Islamic army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opposite the black flag army are the enemy forces from the mysterious silk country in the east. They were much smaller in number, so they placed their infantry in front in a defensive formation. These infantrymen are uniformly holding Eastern-style long-handled swords, which are bladed on both sides, reflecting dazzling light in the morning sun. The huge stainless steel blade is extremely sharp, no less than the cannibal&#39;s scimitar. With its weight Able to split a galloping horse in half, and as strong as a spearman to withstand the impact of cavalry. These infantrymen are also equipped with horses for marching, but these pack horses are now scattered along the Talas River behind the enemy&#39;s side. Behind the infantry were crossbowmen equipped with powerful crossbows, and on both sides were Qarluks Turkic cavalry from the northern steppes. Behind the main force of these infantry and cavalry are their commanders, divided into main generals, deputy generals and special generals, as well as vassal troops from Bakhna as reserves - I heard that those guys started this war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commander-in-chief of the Black Flag Army, Abu Muslim, is The great food in black &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(currently translated as the Abbasid Dynasty)&lt;/span>; is the leading founding father and a military genius who became a monk on the way. He was born as a slave of Persian descent and had been preaching at the bottom of the Great Food Empire for a long time. He returned to his homeland of Persia six years ago and raised an army to resist the white-clothed Food Empire&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(now Translated by Umayyad Dynasty)&lt;/span>;. Last winter, he led his army into Mesopotamia. In the Battle of the Zab River, he won with a small number and a large number. He first used an array of spearmen to withstand multiple rounds of attacks by the opponent&#39;s cavalry, and then launched a cavalry charge to defeat the enemy who had lost their fighting spirit. The infantry forced into the river with floating ice floes, defeated the enemy that was at least three times their size, hammered the last nail in the coffin of the white-clothed food that had enjoyed the country for ninety years, and established a more than 500-year-old army in Baghdad. Years of black food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year he once again set out from Persia on an expedition to Central Asia to face the Chinese army who also came from afar. The commander of the other side heard that he was a handsome man named Gao Xianzhi. However, the origin of this battle has to start in Persia a full hundred years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Talas Valley in Kyrgyzstan. The location where the Battle of Talas took place is no longer known, but the battle took place at the mouth of the valley, and the terrain will be relatively flat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Barbarians of the West&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大In the second year of Yonghui of the Tang Dynasty (&lt;em>;AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;651&lt;/em>;), the young &quot;Tian Khan&quot; Li Zhi met in Chang&#39;an with an envoy sent for help by the last emperor of the Persian Sassanid Empire Yi Siqi. . The envoy said that a group of barbarians from the west were attacking Persia: they asked us to choose one of three situations: either accept their faith, pay a poll tax, or go to war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The envoy did not know that when he begged Tang Gaozong to send troops to rescue Persia, Yi Siqi had already died on the way to escape. The surviving prince Belus &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Persian means &quot;Victor&quot;)&lt;/span>; suffered repeated defeats and finally fled to China. , and died here, buried in Luoyang, the eastern capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;barbarians&quot; who destroyed the Sasanian Dynasty were called &quot;Tachik&quot; by the Persians, but they were actually Arabs. The name &quot;Dashi&quot; comes from the Tayyi tribe in eastern Arabia. It was regarded by the Persians as a collective name for Arab Muslims. After it was spread to the Tang Dynasty, because they used white flags, Chinese history books called it &quot;Dashi in White&quot;. . After the Persians converted to Islam, they were called Tachik by the Turks. This is probably the origin of the name of the Tajik people who also speak Persian today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhi, who had been on the throne for less than three years, had no interest in rescuing Persia, which was far away. At that time, the Tang Dynasty had not yet completely pacified southern Xinjiang, and its limited military resources had to be used to control the four towns of Anxi to the east of Congling, and were beyond its reach to the west of Congling. After Dashi conquered Persia, the expansion momentum in the east was suspended due to domestic battles for throne. It was not until the 60th year that the rear sent the famous general Qutaybah ibn Muslim to the east to attack the Transoxiana region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hezhong&quot; area, as the name suggests, is the Amu Darya River, the two largest rivers in Central Asia&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (called Wuhu River in ancient times)&lt; /span>;The plain area between the Syr Darya River (ancient name Yaoshashui), it borders the Central Asian grasslands to the north, the Tianshan Mountains and the Hindu Kush Mountains to the southeast, two long and high majestic mountain ranges, and Persia to the southwest plateau. Business travelers who walked out of Congling along the two rivers gathered here, and the goods changed hands here and continued to the Mesopotamia and Asia Minor through the Persian Plateau. Therefore, the Transoxiang area has been an important hub of the Silk Road since ancient times. During the Han Dynasty, the Yuezhi people migrated here from the Mongolian Plateau under the attacks of the Xiongnu and Wusun. After merging with the locals, they formed the Sogdians. They established many oasis countries such as Kang, Shi, An, and Shi in the arid river area. Chinese history books call them the Nine Surnames of Zhaowu. Because the Sogdians lived on the trade route, they became an outstanding commercial nation that integrated trade between the East and the West in the Middle Ages. A large number of merchants moved to the Central Plains to work as businessmen. The image of the Hu people on the camels and horses in the Tang Sancai is the Sogdians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; >;In the first year of Xiantian of the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(712 AD)&lt;/span>;, Qu Dibo marched into the river from Khorasan in northeastern Persia, and successively Capture Samadan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now translated as Samarkand)&lt;/span>;, and the Kingdom of Shi , STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Tashkent)&lt;/span>;, Bakhna&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s translation of Fergana)&lt;/span>; and other countries. At that time, Li Longji, Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, had just ascended the throne and was plotting to overthrow his aunt Princess Taiping, who was involved in politics. They were as indifferent to the killings west of Congling as his grandfather Li Zhi was. Two years later, Qu Dibo, who was militarily unstoppable, was accidentally killed during civil strife. The white-clad army retreated as quickly as it came. Tubo, which had coveted this place for a long time, took advantage of the opportunity and established the new king Ada in Bukhanna. This move immediately aroused great vigilance in the Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samarkand, Uzbekistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中Sub-geopolitics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bahanna&quot; is an ancient name, now it is called &quot;Ferg&#39;ona&quot;, and its consonant &quot;g&quot; was still given by Russian colonists In addition, I heard that the local people actually pronounce it as Fer&#39;ana, and the pronunciation is close to &quot;Fuana&quot;. It is a basin at the end of the West Tianshan Mountains. It was called Dawan in the Han Dynasty and the famous sweat-blooded horse was produced here. During the Soviet era, in order to divide the Turkic tribes so that they could divide and rule, the Russians forcibly subdivided five ethnic groups in Central Asia and built five intertwined &quot;Stans&quot;. Especially in the small Fergana Basin, they actually divided them It was divided among the three union republics of Uzbekistan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan, and a large number of enclaves and even enclaves within enclaves were carved out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fergana Basin map, enclaves within enclaves, can be seen intertwined. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna in the Tang Dynasty did not have these disputes. It was a single-ethnic Sogdian country. It was located in Between Suiye, an important town in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty, and the Hezhong countries, it was the key point from the Anxi Protectorate to the Hezhong area via Congling. What&#39;s more important is that the Tang Dynasty could accept the food control of Bukhana, but it could not sit back and watch Tibet enter the Central Asian grasslands - this involved the geopolitics among the four major countries in Central Asia at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna is surrounded by great powers, with Turks in the north, Tubo in the south, Dashi in the west, and Tang in the east. The Turks were traditional conquerors of the grasslands, and used their strong fighting power to collect protection fees from the riverine countries; the White Food was an emerging empire that combined politics and religion, but in the early stages of its expansion, it was neither for war nor for wealth, but for &quot;Find an outlet for the warlike spirit of each tribe&quot; - Turks and Dashi are a zero-sum game between the old and new conquerors, which cannot be reconciled; Tubo arose in the bitter cold land of Qinghai-Tibet, and always aimed at the rich Central Plains, but suffered from Unable to open the tightly-knitted fences of the Tang Dynasty, they detoured to Congling, hoping to join forces with the Turks in the north to carve up the western regions of the Tang Dynasty, and then enter the hinterland of the Central Plains along the Hexi Corridor; and the Tang Dynasty was the only one of the four great powers to be dominated by farming. The political power established by the nation, the primary goal of opening up the Western Region is to use offense as defense to defend its own territory: from Guanzhong via Longxi and Hexi to Anxi, and finally reach Congling, the western border of the Tarim Basin. Just defend the towering Congling. Block external forces from entering the Central Plains. Therefore, the Tang Dynasty’s pursuit was not to plunder land and colonize&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(大食)&lt;/span>; or to exploit the natives&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Turkic)&lt;/span>;, opening up channels&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Tubo)&lt;/span>; or protecting trade routes ——The trade routes were just a by-product of the expansion of the Tang Dynasty, not the purpose. Instead, they simply defended themselves and blocked the north-south passages to prevent powerful enemies from forming alliances to deal with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, Tubo and Turks from the south and north seek to join forces to attack the common enemy Tang Dynasty, while Datang Dynasty and Dashi Dynasty occupy both sides of Congling, one from the east and the other from the west. Once Tibet crossed this east-west equilibrium line and was expected to enter the northern grasslands and join the Turks, Datang&#39;s &quot;red alert&quot; was triggered. In the third year of Kaiyuan of the Tang Dynasty (715 AD), Qu Dibo was killed, the food army withdrew, and the Tubo army In the year when they conquered Ba Khanna, Zhang Xiaosong, the supervisory censor who was inspecting the Anxi Protectorate, made a decisive decision. He marched across the Daidai territory and commanded the vassal army of the slave country to march thousands of miles straight, crossed the Congling Mountains and arrived at the Ba Khanna Basin, where he defeated the heavy Tibetan army. Eight hundred years after Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty conquered Dawan, he occupied this place again and blocked the Tibetan entrance to the Central Asian grassland through the Congling West Road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Tubo tried to open up the Congling East Road through Taobolu, but was also frustrated by Zhang Xiaosong, who was the governor of Beiting at the time: in the tenth year of Kaiyuan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(722 AD)&lt;/span>; Zhang Xiaosong sent 4,000 cavalry to rescue Xiao Bolu and defeated the Tibetan army. This matter has been mentioned in the previous article &quot;Visiting the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot;: Gao Xianzhi&#39;s Plateau Footprints&quot; and, so I won’t go into details. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Expedition to Congling West Road&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Eight Years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (749 AD)&lt;/span>;, two years after Gao Xianzhi regained Xiaobolu, he returned to Boxian &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Qiemo, Xinjiang)&lt;/span>; span>;Destroy Tubo. The Tibetan army, which suffered a bloody blow on the eastern front, had to turn around and head to the Congling West Road on the western front to find the weaknesses of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s Western Region defense system. After receiving the information, Gao Xianzhi could have gone to Bahanna, where he would have been waiting for the Tibetan troops who had been on an expedition to come and give them a head-on attack. However, Gao Xianzhi, who had been pursuing the initiative on the battlefield all his life, did not do that: since the Congling West Road was still passable. , then I will cut it off completely! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Chitral, Pakistan, the seat of the ancient Shishi Kingdom. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianbao Nine Years&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (A.D. 750)&lt;/span>; Gao Xianzhi sent troops to Congling for the second time and came to Xiaobolu again. From there, he followed the Suyi River (Today&#39;s Gilgit River)&lt;/span>;Go upstream, cross the Shanduer Pass, and head to the Kingdom of Shishi at the eastern foot of the central Hindu Kush Mountains ;&quot;>;(now Chitral, Pakistan)&lt;/span>;. Some historians have verified that the Kingdom of Shishi was the end point of Alexander the Great&#39;s Eastern Expedition. The ancient tribes that thrive in the nearby Kalasha Valley are said to be the descendants of the Greek expeditionary force. The distance from Xiaobolu to Yushi is more than 700 miles. Now it takes two full days to travel by road. The road conditions are very good on the first day, and there are long-distance buses available. On the second day, we can only take the local four-wheel drive with the villagers. It is possible to travel west along the Mastuj Valley, with the continuous snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Kush to the north and the 6,542-meter-high snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Raj to the south. Peak Buni Zom. The Mastuje River cuts deeply into the dense loess at your feet, forming a T-shaped towering platform, which is reminiscent of the Tuolai River Valley outside Jiayuguan. The soldiers under Gao Xianzhi must have drank by the Tuolai River on their way from the Central Plains to the Western Regions via Hexi. Let&#39;s cross the horse, I believe they also discovered the similarities between the two places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Toolai Valley outside Jiayuguan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two Tang Books&quot; &quot;&quot; does not record how long Gao Xianzhi went on the expedition against the Xu division, and &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot; only mentions the winter march of the Tang army. According to my estimate of the terrain along the route of our division, it would have taken an ancient army at least half a month to carry its baggage. It was even more difficult for the Tubo army: since the Tang army had controlled Xiaobolu and the Suyi River Valley three years ago, the Tubo army had to detour through the high mountains in the south. Whether they could reach Yushi in a month was a problem. The Kingdom of Yushi is an ally of Tubo. It is located at the midpoint of the West Congling Road. After passing Yushi, you can cross the Hindu Kush Mountains, then follow the Panchi River through the Alai Mountains in the west of Congling and the West Tianshan Mountains, and finally arrive at Bakhna Basin - that was another more than a month&#39;s journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Gao Xianzhi made a surprise attack on the Chu army and cut off the west road of Congling, the extremely tired Tibetan soldiers who had come from afar no longer had to cross the four great mountains of Hindu Lage, Hindu Kush, Congling and Xitian Mountain. Mountains, not to mention struggling to attack the fortress jointly guarded by the Tang army and the Sogdians in the scorching Bukhan, you can return to the cool Qinghai-Tibet Plateau all in one piece - isn&#39;t this the peace dividend brought by General Gao of the Tang Dynasty? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, after losing the important relay point of Xushi Division, Tubo completely gave up the idea of ​​opening up the east and west roads of Congling. Zai and Thirteen were defeated by Gao Xianzhi&#39;s successor Feng Changqing on the two eastern fronts, so that the Tibetan army was unable to pose a major threat to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty for the next ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi successively put down the Tibetan offensive on the east and west fronts, and pushed the Tang Dynasty&#39;s military control line from the east of Congling to the west of Congling, achieving the strategic goal of stabilizing the Western Region and defending the Central Plains. It can be said that it has achieved reached the pinnacle of personal military achievement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at this moment, he received a letter of request for help from Ba Khanna, asking him to stop by the army to attack the Shi Kingdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Traditional teahouse in the Fergana Basin&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;&quot;All the Hus are angry&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna was first destroyed by the White-coated Eaters, and then was supported by Tubo as a puppet regime. Finally, the country was restored with the aid of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s reinforcements, so it was China&#39;s The most loyal vassal state in Asia to the Tang Dynasty can be compared to Goryeo to the Ming Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So why did Bahan call on the Tang army to attack Shiguo? There is a lack of clear historical records on this matter. It is generally believed that there may be three reasons. First, there is a gap between Bukhanna and Shiguo. Bukhanna is located in the basin upstream of Yaoxishui, while Shiguo is located downstream of the basin where Yaoxashui flows out. , its capital city, Toshkent, is today&#39;s capital of Uzbekistan, Tashkent. &quot;Toshkent&quot; means &quot;Tosh&quot;, which means &quot;stone&quot; in Turkic language. The two countries are both Sogdian countries. The Shi State blocked the exit of Bukhanna to the Central Asian grasslands, while the Bukhanna blocked the water source of the Shiguo. There may be grudges between the two countries; secondly, Bukhanna showed his loyalty to the Tang Dynasty. Take advantage of the power vacuum in the Hezhong area to control it; thirdly, the Shi Kingdom is located at the frontier of the Hezhong area and the Central Asian grasslands, and has good relations with Tuqishi, the successor of the main Turkic tribe Tuqishi, surnamed Huang, and Tuqishi It has long been a threat to Datang and has stepped on Datang&#39;s red line. In short, Gao Xianzhi adopted Ba Khanna&#39;s suggestion, led the army northward into the Fergana Basin, and then followed Yaoshashui to the Stone Kingdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shi Kingdom belongs to the nine surnamed states of Zhaowu in the Hezhong area. It is the land controlled by the Tang Dynasty. They regard the Tang Dynasty as their suzerain state and pay regular tribute to the Tang Dynasty, but they have no practical administrative, financial and military capabilities. Manage and control relationships. The name of Gao Xianzhi&#39;s crusade against Shiguo was &quot;no vassal courtesy&quot;, but the specific crimes were not listed in the history books. The weak Shi Kingdom proposed peace, but Gao Xianzhi pretended to agree, but imprisoned Naju Chebishi, the king of Shi Kingdom who came to negotiate in person - he had used a similar strategy in the Battle of Xiaobolu to trap his relatives with property. After the Tubo nobles came out of the city, they arrested and beheaded them - and then captured Tuozhe City without any bloodshed. After the city was broken, Gao Xianzhi sent his troops to massacre and plunder a large number of treasures from the Shi Kingdom. He himself received &quot;more than ten dendrobiums, five or six golden camels, many good horses and precious jade, and his family was rich in millions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Sese&quot; mentioned here is one of the most expensive minerals in the Middle Ages: lapis lazuli. It originates from the Badakhshan region in the upper reaches of the Wuhu River &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now northeastern Afghanistan)&lt;/span>;, and is re-exported and trafficked through the river area to All over the world, it is not only a precious gemstone, a &quot;magic medicine&quot; for treating diseases, but also a rare blue and purple pigment. The turquoise tone that became popular in the 2022 New Year&#39;s Eve dance &quot;Only This Green&quot; originated from the handed down treasure &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; painted by Song Huizong with precious lapis lazuli from the palace collection for the young painter Wang Ximeng, and Bai Juyi&#39;s famous saying &quot; &quot;Half the river is rustling and half the river is red&quot;, what is chanted is also the color of lapis lazuli that the river emits under the setting sun. Gao Xianzhi plundered a large amount of lapis lazuli from the Stone Kingdom, which must have been treasures accumulated in his treasury over the years, especially before gold, so its value can be imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi captured the King of Shiguo, the King of Yushi, the Tubo chief and the Tuqi Shi Khan surnamed Huang who was probably captured in Shiguo during this expedition&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(This may explain why Gao Xianzhi massacred Tuozhe City to punish Shi Guo&#39;s collaboration with the enemy)&lt;/span>; All of them were sent back to Chang&#39;an to offer prisoners, and their military exploits can be described as outstanding. But he His betrayal of trust and cruel massacre aroused the public indignation of all the countries in the river except Ba Khanna. According to the &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot; record, &quot;The prince of Shiguo fled to the barbarians and accused Xianzhi of deception, corruption and violence.&quot; . All the barbarians were angry, and they lured Da Shi to attack the four towns.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the historical records of Da Shi, the cause of the war was that Ba Khanna was hostile to the Shi Kingdom and asked for help from the Tang Dynasty; the Tang army surrounded Shi Kingdom, the king of Shi Kingdom surrendered and was not persecuted; after Dashi learned about this, he sent troops to fight against Tang Dynasty - this narrative lacks logic and it is difficult to explain the reason why Dashi sent troops. In my opinion, Dashi sent troops that year The change of dynasty has just been completed, and the black-clothed food has replaced the white-clothed food. A victory in the external war is needed to heal the internal divisions. The commander-in-chief Bingbo Xilin has just suppressed Anguo&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style, italic style _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Bukhara, Uzbekistan)&lt;/span>;&#39;s rebellion freed up his hands to use Anguo as a base to send troops to invade the Hezhong area that his predecessor Qudibo had conquered. Now the Hezhong countries take the initiative He came to submit and fell into his trap. Bo Xilin then took over and annexed all the land in the river, and then led the high-spirited army of Dashi and the vassal armies of the river countries to march eastward along the Central Asian grasslands, with a straight front. Refers to Suiye City, the outpost of the Tang Dynasty in the Western Regions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Gao Xianzhi learned of the great changes in the river, he led the main forces of the four towns of Anxi and the vassal armies of Geluolu and Bahanna to cross Congling for the third time. Heading to the river to quell the rebellion, the two armies met at Talos between Tuozhe City and Suiye City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the map of the Battle of Talas, Ningyuan is Bakhna. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Battle of Sekigahara in Central Asia&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&quot;Taluosi&quot; is the name of the city in the eastern part of the Stone Kingdom. It is named after the Talas River, which is an intermountain river in the remnants of the Western Tianshan Mountains. Although the water volume is not large, it has a long history and is more than a thousand miles long. The lower reaches of the Talas River flow northwest along the valley and finally enter the grassland area. Today, the mountains within the valley belong to Kyrgyzstan, and the plains outside the valley belong to Kazakhstan. There is a Kyrgyz town called Talas in the valley, and a large Kazakh city called Taraz on the grassland outside the valley. During the Soviet era, the Kirov Reservoir was built at the pass of the Talas Valley in 1975, which blocked the small amount of river water. The reservoir was only 7 meters deep and was used for agricultural irrigation in the valley. Therefore, the Talas River entered Kazakhstan. After the border of Stan, only a trickle remained, forming a thirsty oasis, and finally stopped in the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Kirov Reservoir built in the Soviet era&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of It has been so long that it is now impossible to confirm whether Talos City in the Tang Dynasty is today&#39;s Talas Town or Talaz City, or somewhere in between. Because we are located on the border between Kyrgyzstan and Kazakhstan, as a foreigner, I cannot go to the exit of the Talas Valley—the place where the Talas War is most likely to take place—to conduct inspections, nor can I fly a drone from the air. Overlooking this river valley. But what is certain is that the Datang Allied Forces with fewer troops occupied the inner side of the valley with a slightly higher terrain, using mountains and rivers to protect their flanks; the Dashi Allied Forces with superior strength attacked the valley from the grassland side. The battlefield was opened on the north bank of the Rath River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taras River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About the comparison of the military strength of the two sides , historians have different opinions. Currently, it is generally believed that the strength of the Allied Forces of the Tang Dynasty is 20,000 to 30,000. Considering that the strength of the entire Anxi Protectorate does not exceed 30,000, and they have to guard the huge southern border, it is impossible to transfer all of them to the front line. I am inclined to According to the records of &quot;Zi Zhi Tong Jian&quot;, Gao Xianzhi&#39;s total troops for this expedition were about 30,000. It is estimated that half of them were Tang troops, mainly infantry, and the rest were vassal armies of Geluolu and Bahanna. Among them, Geluolu army As cavalry, Bakhna&#39;s army was also dominated by infantry. There is another theory that the Tang army had as many as 60,000 to 70,000 troops, which means that most of them were vassal troops. This is not consistent with the actual situation in the Tang Dynasty when all the people in the Hezhong area rebelled against their relatives and only Bukhanna followed, while Geluo As a newly emerging Turkic tribe, Lu could not provide so many troops. There is even less historical data on the Great Eclipse. It is generally believed that there were 70,000 to 100,000 people, and some believe that it was as high as 200,000 to 300,000 people. I think that the logistics support conditions at that time could not support such a huge force on the grassland expedition, so I tentatively think that this The first battle was a field battle between 70,000 Dashi Allied Forces and 30,000 Datang Allied Forces on the banks of the Talas River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;History records that this battle lasted for five days. In the first four days, the Dashi army attacked, but failed to break through the tight defensive formation formed by the Tang army. But on the fifth day, the battlefield situation changed dramatically. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some Japanese scholars likened this battle to the &quot;Battle of Sekigahara in Central Asia&quot; - the Battle of Sekigahara was the largest battle in Japan&#39;s Azuchi Momoyama era. The main force of the Western Army was outnumbered. When the enemy was about to take the initiative on the battlefield, the friendly Kobayakawa Hideaki tribe who had been stationary at the top of the flank suddenly switched sides and cut into the rear of the main force of the Western Army, which was fighting fiercely with the Eastern Army, forming a pincer attack on it. The Western Army collapsed. Although this analogy is not exact, it is quite similar to the reversal of the Battle of Talos: The Tang Army&#39;s elite Mo Dao team blocked multiple rounds of attacks from the Food Army. It was expected to replicate the opponent&#39;s coach and Bo Xilin&#39;s victory last year. A successful example in the Battle of Zab River, using cavalry countercharge to crush the enemy&#39;s fighting spirit. It&#39;s a pity that the cavalry troops of the Tang coalition were vassal troops of Geluolu. At this critical moment when the Tang army was about to take the initiative on the battlefield, the Geluolu people, who had a tacit understanding with Dashi, counterattacked and instead cut into the fierce battle with Dashi&#39;s army. The Tang Army&#39;s rear area formed a pincer attack on it, and the main force of the Tang Army fell into a tight encirclement and bitter fighting, suffering all casualties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commander-in-chief Gao Xianzhi was unwilling to fail. He also hoped to use the reserve force to stabilize the position, collect the defeated troops on the front line, and then fight the enemy for a showdown. His lieutenant, Li Siye, a fierce general who had made extraordinary achievements in the battle of Lianyunbao, persuaded him to retreat at the critical moment: The general went deep alone without reinforcements, and the surrounding Hu people and other countries were just followers of the victor, and they would definitely be against us. A group formed a siege. Once our entire army is wiped out, who will go back to defend southern Xinjiang? Although I am a reckless man, I can clearly see that the situation is critical, and the general can no longer be rigid and stubborn! &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Old Book of Tang Dynasty·Li Siye Biography&quot;: A fool may have a chance to gain, but the situation is so dangerous that he cannot glue the pillar)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Li Siye dragged Gao Xianzhi to abandon the main force of the surrounded Tang army and retreat eastward along the Talas Valley. The terrain became higher and the mountain roads became narrower. The vassal army of Bukhan, who was the first reserve force to turn around and retreat, blocked the road tightly. The Tang army behind them could not pass through and was about to be overtaken by the Dashi pursuers. At this time, Li Siye put down his sword, picked up his big stick and fired at the friendly troops of Tuhan. &quot;Both men and horses were killed with one hand.&quot; Tuhan&#39;s troops gave way to the left and right, and Gao Xianzhi was able to escape; but the third in command of the Tang army, Biel General Duan Xiushi stepped forward and blamed his superior Li Siye for killing friendly troops in order to escape for his own life. &quot;It is not brave to run in fear of the enemy; it is not benevolent to avoid being trapped by others.&quot; Li Siye stopped the killing in shame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the tragic situation of the Tang army after its defeat in Talos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Entrance arch in Talas Province, Kyrgyzstan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;Epilogue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the Battle of Talos, the two armies returned home respectively. Datang and Dashi were still bounded by Congling, and the strategic balance did not fundamentally change. In the next five years, the Black-clad Dashi sent eight groups of envoys to Datang, indicating that the two sides still maintained close diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geluolu: A Turkic tribe that defected before the battle, formed an alliance with Tubo after the Battle of Talas, inherited the role of Tuqishi, and became a new generation of Turkic conquerors on the grassland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna, a vassal state in the Western Region in a corner of the green mountains, remained loyal to the Tang Dynasty after the tragic defeat and massacre of Talos, and was &quot;the most cautious in dealing with the Tang Dynasty&quot;. After the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot; broke out, Ba Khanna responded to Tang Suzong&#39;s invitation and sent troops thousands of miles away to assist the Central Plains. To this day, Fergana is still an important silk town in the world, and its raw silk production ranks third in the world. This is the thousand-year legacy of the Silk Road in the Tang Dynasty to this hot basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The countries in the river, the Sogdian city-states under the great power game, the Tang Dynasty withdrew from the Western Regions after the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot;, these Persian countries have successively undergone Islamicization and Turkicization under the influence of Dashi and Turks historic transformation. According to the research of historians, papermaking technology had spread here long before the outbreak of the Talas War. It helped Anguo, one of the nine surnames of Zhaowu, to gradually become an important cultural center in the Muslim world and was known as the &quot;pillar of Islam.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The symbol of the Islamic Cultural Center of Bukhara in Uzbekistan: Mir-i-Arab Madrasa&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bingbo Xilin, the war god commander who was born as a slave, was involved in the battle for the throne three years later. He supported the second generation Caliph and defeated his opponent, but was tortured and killed by this Caliph three months later - as the saying goes, &quot;when the birds are gone, the good bow is hidden.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Xiushi was an outspoken Confucian general who was promoted to judge by Li Siye, whom he had reprimanded after he withdrew to Anxi. Two years later, he assisted Feng Changqing in conquering Dabolu. He also made great achievements on the front line many times. At the age of 64, he died for his country for opposing the traitor Zhu Si. The &quot;Maybe to attack the thief&quot; in Wen Tianxiang&#39;s &quot;Song of Righteousness&quot; is an allusion to his vow to fight the thief to the death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Siye, a two-meter-tall fierce general, returned to the Central Plains during the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot; and joined forces with the famous ZTE general Guo Ziyi to win consecutive battles against a weak enemy and regain the Guanzhong Plain and the eastern capital Luoyang. Become a &quot;firefighter&quot; in the weak Tang army. In the second year of Emperor Qianyuan of the Tang Dynasty &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (759 AD)&lt;/span>;, he was hit by an arrow while fighting, &quot;he bled for several liters, and died after being injected into the ground.&quot; ——Whenever I talk about Li Siye, I first think of the heroic scene of &quot;when Siye wields the sword, both men and horses will be shattered&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Otemok Pass in Talas Province, Kyrgyzstan. The &quot;King of the Mountains&quot; may have passed through this place more than 1,200 years ago. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi, a famous general with extraordinary courage but greed for merit and wealth, four years after the Battle of Talos, the &quot;Anshi Rebellion&quot; &quot; broke out, Gao Xianzhi and Feng Changqing were ordered to lead a temporarily assembled mob to resist the main force of the elite rebels. They had to defend Tongguan based on the strong city, but they were both killed by Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty. Another famous general who succeeded them, Ge Shuhan, was forced to send troops to fight the rebels in the field. As a result, the entire army was wiped out, Tongguan was lost, and Chang&#39;an fell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi had a chance to make a comeback before his death: Bian Lingcheng, the eunuch who had slandered Xuanzong and was ordered to go to Tongguan to execute Gao Xianzhi, led more than a hundred Mo swordsmen to embolden him, but he never thought that these elite soldiers would all They shouted: General Gao is wronged! &quot;Its voice is enthusiastic&quot;. Gao Xianzhi could have used these loyal soldiers to capture Bian Lingcheng, or force Xuanzong to take back his life. But he did not do so in the end. Instead, he sighed with emotion as he looked at the corpse of his old comrade Feng Changqing and went to die without hesitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This famous general in the prosperous Tang Dynasty eventually came to nothing along with the prosperous Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:26:40 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一家经营不善的公司，承建了佳木斯5年就垮的体育馆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:36:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOo Bpgrqzc. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huannan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 19:20 on November 6, 2023, an incident occurred in the National Fitness Gymnasium of Yuecheng Square, Huanan County, Jiamusi City, Heilongjiang Province Collapse accident. At that time, seven junior high school students were playing basketball inside. One student noticed an abnormality in the roof and ran to the door. Then the roof collapsed, with a total collapse area of ​​675 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 7 students, 3 escaped on their own, 1 was rescued and sent to hospital, and 3 died. A friend of the victim told the media that he was a young man who loved playing basketball since he was a child and was called the &quot;Ball King&quot; by his classmates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 24, 2023, the Magistrate of Huanan County went to the gymnasium to inspect the safety work, and emphasized that cultural market operators must fulfill their main responsibilities for safety production and always tighten the string of safety production. The day before, the roof collapsed in the gymnasium of No. 34 Middle School in Qiqihar, Heilongjiang Province - that accident killed 11 teachers and students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, the discipline inspection and supervision agencies at the Jiamusi City and Huanan County levels immediately intervened and set up an investigation team to investigate. The Huanan County Government Information Office said that the operator of the collapsed venue was Huanan County New Sunshine Fitness Club. The person in charge, Men Yanan, has been controlled by the police, and the cause of the accident is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The building owner of the gymnasium once leased the venue to others for operation, but starting from December 2022, it will be transferred to the management of the New Sunshine Fitness Club run by Men Yanan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Men Yanan is Yuecheng&#39;s &quot;old friend&quot;. She established Yuecheng Sports and Fitness Club in April 2021, canceled the company eight months later, and established New Sunshine Fitness Club in July 2022. She also serves as a supervisor at Hunan County Yuecheng Cinema City Co., Ltd. The actual controller of the company is Yang Jinli, who is the actual controller and beneficial owner of Hunan County Yuecheng Commercial Building Co., Ltd. established in August 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuecheng Plaza is a project that the Huanan County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Department vigorously attracts investment. Beijing Deyiyintong Technology Co., Ltd. invested 380 million yuan to register Heilongjiang Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. to build an urban commercial complex and a high-end residential community in the original shantytown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2015 to 2022, three companies, Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd., Yuecheng Commercial Building Co., Ltd., and Yuecheng Sports Culture Development Co., Ltd. were established in Hunan County. Many of the shareholders and executives overlapped, but this Three companies have been deregistered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Huanan County Government Information Office, Building 7 of the Yuecheng Plaza complex where the accident occurred was built by Heilongjiang Haifeng Weiye Construction and Installation Engineering Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Haifeng Weiye&quot;) in July 2017. Construction started and was completed in July 2018. The supervision unit is Jiamusi Sanjiang Construction Supervision Company. It passed the acceptance inspection in July 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, Haifeng Weiye was established in Hegang City with investment from Zhu Hai and Zhu Bo (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Er Zhu&quot;). In May 2016, Er Zhu quit the company and 26-year-old Yue Chengqi took over. One year later, the construction of the Yuecheng Plaza complex began, and Haifeng Weiye&#39;s market entity type was changed from &quot;natural person investment or holding&quot; to &quot;natural person sole proprietorship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A civil judgment with the case number &quot;(2018) Black 0822 Minchu No. 272&quot; shows that before 2016, Haifeng Weiye, who mainly worked on projects in Hegang, was heavily in debt, so he paid annual interest rates Borrow money from Yue Chengqi at 6% interest. In 2016, Erzhu completely gave up Haifeng Weiye and transferred it to Yuecheng Qi. At this time, Zhu Hai and Zhu Bo still owed the Hegang Gongnong District Local Taxation Bureau and the National Taxation Bureau a total of 2,059,920.94 yuan in taxes plus late payment fees. They borrowed money from Yue Chengqi and paid the taxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2018, Yue Chengqi sued Erzhu for repaying the loan and interest, and received support from the court. However, Erzhu said that he had no money and could not repay it for the time being. This loan totaling 2.42 million yuan was not enforced until 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first took over Haifeng Weiye, Yue Chengqi tried many ways to make money, such as purchasing resettlement housing that had been delivered but was resold several times. Later, the court believed that he was purchasing a house. He failed to verify the situation of the actual residents at the time, which constituted a gross negligence. Therefore, his claim for physical ownership of the relocated house is not supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also participated in gambling and ended up with 7,500 yuan in gambling capital. After losing all, he borrowed 10,000 yuan on the spot, with interest of 300 yuan per day. Later, he was caught on the spot by the public security organs on December 2, 2016, his gambling funds were confiscated, and he was subject to administrative penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Chengqi&#39;s social software avatar is a picture that says &quot;Life depends on oneself&quot;, and the signature is &quot;What parents give is called background, what one works hard for is called country, there is a kind of hard work called relying on oneself&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking over Haifeng Weiye, Yue Chengqi had no experience in managing construction companies or large-scale construction projects. But through hard work, he used a Hegang construction company that was being enforced for debt arrears to take over the Yuecheng Plaza, a star project in Hunan County with an investment of 170 million yuan. After that, Haifeng Weiye became a major tenderer of Huanan County Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the public bidding information, &quot;Southern Weekend&quot; concluded: &quot;(Haifeng Weiye) has participated in a wide variety of projects. In terms of municipal engineering, it has undertaken the construction of public parking lots, roads, high-speed rail parking lots, etc., as well as medical projects There are the county CDC, the infectious disease area of ​​the county hospital, and the 120 emergency center, as well as the beautiful rural infrastructure construction in Huanan County, the material reserve warehouse of the county power supply bureau, and the black soil transfer earthwork in the pig slaughtering plant area of ​​​​Huanan Economic Development Zone. In addition, we also won the bid for the county&#39;s affordable housing project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the night of the accident, Yue Chengqi gave a brief interview to Southern Weekend. He said that he was already aware of the stadium collapse incident, but was not sure if it was his own project. &quot;I need to go back and check the information.&quot; The next day, Yue Chengqi&#39;s mobile phone continued to go unanswered. In the afternoon of the same day, Jiamusi issued a notice confirming that Haifeng Weiye was responsible for the stadium collapse. Construction side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heilongjiang Huayou Construction Engineering Co., Ltd., another developer that once undertook the Yuecheng Plaza complex, is actually the second shareholder of Yuecheng Real Estate and is also a major tenderer for local government projects. It once undertook the renovation of the Jiamusi Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital. Yongfang, the cultural facilities construction project of Huachuan County Culture, Radio, Television, Press and Publication Bureau and the dilapidated house renovation project of Huannan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the incident, a staff member of the Propaganda Department of Huanan County Party Committee responded in an interview with the media that the roof collapse was related to snowfall. Huanan County issued a red snow warning signal at 16:47 that day, prompting the suspension of classes and businesses (except for special industries) if necessary. According to meteorological monitoring, the snowfall in Hunan County, where the incident occurred, reached 44 mm in 24 hours on the 6th, breaking the November snowfall record. Just two days ago, the county held a working meeting on preventing and responding to the current extreme weather, requiring various industries and fields to do their own safety precautions according to the division of responsibilities and minimize the occurrence of secondary disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访港交所前行政总裁李小加：互联互通是香港资本市场成功的基石]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Li Xiaojia is known as &quot;one of the earliest practitioners of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial securities industry.&quot; While working at the famous Wall Street law firm Davis Polk &amp;amp; Wardwell and Brown &amp;amp; Wood, he was invited by &lt;span>;China&#39;s Ministry of Finance&lt;/span>; to participate in China&#39;s first global sovereign debt transaction. Issuance work; when he served as Chairman of Merrill Lynch China and Chairman of JP Morgan China, Li Xiaojia took the lead in the cross-border listing of the first batch of central state-owned enterprises such as CNOOC and China Mobile; he participated in the planning and initiation of the China National Offshore Oil Bid for Unique, and was He believes that &quot;created a new era for Chinese enterprises&quot;; after more than ten years in charge of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, he successfully promoted a number of strategic initiatives that were crucial in the history of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, including &quot;Shanghai-Hong Kong Stock Connect&quot; and &quot;Shenzhen-Hong Kong Stock Connect&quot;. What impressed the market even more was the implementation of the reform of the different rights listing system for the same shares in 2018 and the acquisition of the London Metal Exchange in 2012. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, he started a business called &quot;Drip Irrigation Connect&quot; and established and operated the &quot;Drip Irrigation Connect&quot; ASX in accordance with the relevant administrative orders of the Macau government, hoping to &quot;connect international capital with China&#39;s small and micro enterprises.&quot; This is a revolutionary financial experiment on a global scale. After 7 months, on October 26, 2023, Drip Tong ASX was certified by the Sharia Regulatory Commission and complied with Islamic teachings such as the prohibition of interest collection. &lt;span>;This certification includes&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Islamic Finance&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s confirmation that the income sharing product created by Diguantong is not a loan interest collection model, and recognizes that Diguantong’s investment is based on sharing of risks. Way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did China issue its first global sovereign debt more than thirty years ago? Why did China&#39;s first batch of state-owned enterprises land in the U.S. capital market more than 20 years ago? Twenty years ago, how was the first overseas bidding done by a central enterprise? Over the past ten years, how has the Hong Kong Stock Exchange broken the ice and achieved interconnection with A-shares? In an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, Li Xiaojia reviewed these major events closely related to China&#39;s financial reform and opening up. He said that internationalization, embracing the new economy, and realizing interconnection are still the cornerstones of the success of Hong Kong&#39;s capital market today, and are also the reform and innovation for China&#39;s capital market to go global. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height= &quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Xiaojia: former CEO of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange and current founder and chairman of Drip Tong Group&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The overall benefits of promoting reform through overseas listing are multilateral&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾牵头参与我国第一次发行全球主权债，这次发行全球主权债的主要难点是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;发债首先需要一家大评级机构给中国主权进行信用评级。我参与评级工作的两个多月时间，非常紧张。如果评级不合适，中国根本不会发行主权债。其中发生了很多故事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过艰苦努力，1993年，中国拿到A级主权评级，次年年初发债成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你也牵头主持了首批央国企跨境上市，当时主要为了解决什么问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时的诉求非常简单，就是为国企解困。当时大量国企非常困难，三角债严重。最主要的动因是国企改革，需要融资，依靠资金进行改革。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国企改革就要真正进入市场，按市场经济规律运行。在这个过程中，大家很快感觉到，通过上市本身融资，很容易把大家的思想统一起来。然后把境外上市作为一种催化剂，要想去境外融资，央国企就要做各种改革，政府功能、社会功能和企业功能要分开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些改革在央国企海外上市的过程中慢慢变得重要。它是靠融资把大家的认知统一起来，为了达到这个目的，让大家慢慢接受改革必须承受的一些成本、一些影响和冲击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以海外上市促改革，是否达到了预期目标？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那当然了。首先，这个目的或者说整体益处是多边的。企业本身在最关键的时候融到大笔资金。 1993 年，首批9 家企业，很快有22 家企业。这些企业用海外融资做了大量资本开支，解决了大量发展中需要的资金问题。它非常及时地解决了当时资金的迫切需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央国企跨境上市真的吹响了国企改革的号角，带动和催发了原来启动相当困难的各个方面体制和机制改革。海外上市之后，国企改革慢慢进入到主赛道。大家开始全面接受国企改革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅如此，央国企跨境上市很快催生了中国资本市场的发展。我们这么多企业不可能全部到国外上市，而且中国这么多资本，老百姓也有钱。为什么我们的资本不能投入到我们自己的企业里呢？从发行人的角度及投资者希望参与改革开放的发展红利来看，它促进了中国资本市场的诞生和发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一点也很重要，央国企第一次走向世界。外界开始认识中国企业，认识中国经济。然后外资由于投资，深度关心、参与和体验中国经济现代化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得我国央国企内部治理效率方面的提升空间有多大？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国企也好，央企也好，只是所有权的一种形式。新加坡也有主权基金，但它的运作方式完全市场化，除了出资人身份以外，其他与私营企业一样的运作模式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的央企也非常高效。要说效率提升，管理者激励机制和其它企业一样吗？我们不能以企业所有权形式简单地说哪个更有效，哪个更好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;世界已经基本上不可能脱钩了&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在，一批央国企可能要从纽交所退市。你怎么看目前这种形势？是否有可能走向“资本脱钩”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;即便退市，和资本脱钩这个事，依然是相差得太远的事情。它们是如今国际资本参与中国市场发展中极小的少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，全世界投资到中国的外资体量如此之大，包含范围是主要民企和在香港上市的央国企。除了科技领域比较明显的脱钩外，其他方面的脱钩会有一些。但完全还没有到老死不相往来的程度。我们已经习惯了与一个高度发达的资本市场之间的相互渗入和连接。现在这个连接比它鼎盛期间已弱了很多。如果从二三十年前看如今，今天这个世界的相连已经基本上不可能脱钩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全世界像一驾飞机一样，世界经济最大的两个引擎怎么可能脱钩？在极其深度密切合作的20 年后，目前有一些回撤。即便在回撤之后，两国的经济联系远不能用脱钩这样的字形容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“港交所改革的两大核心考量&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;对内地的历史价值和现实意义”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;执掌港交所10年，你主导了多项影响深远的改革。你对哪些改革更满意？ Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我平常不这么想问题。在历史大潮中，一个人刚好很幸运地在一个很重要很合适的位置上，然后天时地利人和的条件下做了一些事情。这些不能说成一个人的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;任职港交所期间，哪项改革对内地更有历史价值和现实意义？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是港交所所有改革最主要的两个核心考量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个大主题就是香港在很长时间作为一种国际市场，应该是帮助内地资本市场国际化，帮助国际市场更多融入内地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这个角度讲，每一件事情都要系统性地解决。毕竟这两个市场是两个完全不同的体系，既有极大动力互相融入和互联互通，也有它很强大的内在机制和力量。这使互联互通非常困难。换言之，这两个市场各有自己的管理体制、市场体制和运作方式，愿意融合，但又不愿意为了融合而大量改变自己的制度和系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么利用香港极其独特的地位呢？我们充分认识到两边市场哪些可以为了互联互通进行一些改变，哪些是不可能改变的，哪些改变是必须的。找到一个最大公约数和最小公倍数，找到在最小成本里边达到最大幅度的互联互通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在所有改革中，我们要考虑很多问题。也许某种形式的互联互通最有效最好，但它的成本可能太高。大家不愿意承受；一些事情可能很容易改革，但没什么特别大意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如，我们开始想选择很小的事情，比如说两边交易所的交易时间段不一样，开市和收盘都不一样。看上去似乎很小的事情，但改革并不容易。它涉及两地不同的生活习惯和工作习惯。看起来大家应该没有什么争议的改革，实际上却是当时最困难的改革之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回过头看，以下几件改革对港交所有重大历史价值和现实意义。首先，港交所不能只是在香港的内地市场，港交所不仅只在亚洲，应该往欧美突破，因为内地希望通过香港市场走向国际；不能只在股票市场，要向内地最需要的大宗商品市场突破。因此，港交所兼并收购了伦敦金属交易所，也尝试过收购伦敦交易所，但没有成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二是港交所股票市场本身。因为监管规则，中国科技企业一直无法上市。它们代表先进的生产力，却只能到美国上市。并不是之前的监管逻辑错误，但在全世界都在竞争的时候，我们为什么死死抱住原有的东西不改变呢？美国的监管逻辑原来也和港交所一致，但它可以找到非常现实的原因并允许改变。我们最后进行改革，小米、京东、阿里等等都可以回归到港交所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A股市值已高居全球第二。这么庞大的市场与香港市场及国际市场怎么能够实现互联互通，但又不改变双方各自的规则和制度？因此，沪港通、深港通、债券通、债券互换通等等一系列改革创新陆续出笼。两个市场之间达到基本互联互通功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际化、拥抱新经济、实现互联互通，直到今天都还是香港市场成功的基石，也是中国资本市场走向世界的改革创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对任职港交所期间的工作还留有遗憾吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在互联互通是二级市场，即沪港通和深港通可以南下或北上买卖已在港交所或深交所与沪交所的股票。但互联互通没有向一级市场延伸到“新股通”。这是我的遗憾。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个产品的名字，我以前用“新股通”。新股通让中国市场最终和世界资源对接。在香港实现互联互通，能实现巨大的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;让国际&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;资本&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;和中国小微&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;企业充分&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;联通&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;告别港交所，你以一种全球最新的投资模式和交易模式开始创业——2023年8月正式运营滴灌通澳交所。滴灌通澳交所要解决世界性难题——小微企业融资难。为何滴灌通澳交所可以解决这个难题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;滴灌通澳交所是全球首个持牌的收入分成产品（DRO）交易所。滴灌通的愿景与使命是将国际资本与中国小微经济充分联通起来，要让国际传统金融和中国小微经济这两个非常难以兼容的运营体系实现互联互通。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这件事情能突破的基础和前提是中国数字化革命全面普及。无现金社会为一种崭新的、革命性的融资形式提供了可能。有了这个革命性的前提后，加上我们自己创建的滴灌通澳交所，就把这事做成了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万一我们没做，或者万一我们没把它搞好，一定很快就会有其他人把它搞好做起来。就像没有互联网的时候，马云跳到天上去，他啥也干不了。有了互联网以后，他就做了淘宝，但是很快也有了京东、美团等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并不是我们带来了灵丹妙药，一下子破解了大家的难题。只能说我们是第一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么你们会成为第一个？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大部分从事金融的人，看不上小微生意，认为这是不可能的；从事互联网或数字化的大部分人不了解金融的本质。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么能做呢？我们知道，全世界的资本市场主要解决两个问题，一是投资的信息准确和真实，一是投资的钱和货进出的安全有保证。具体而言，全世界投资者只会投资股票或债券，而且是大公司的股票和债券，因为投资者关心的上述两个核心问题是投资的前提。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传统交易所为解决这两个问题，依靠大量的专业人士做研究报告、做年报等等；交收安全则依靠银行、券商和交易所一系列机构背书，保证资金进出安全保障。但这两件事件都极其昂贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种情况下，小微企业不会通过上市和发债融资。但在中国数字化革命的当下，这两个核心问题可以低成本解决了。一个小店的收入，在支付体系里完全体现出来，即信息的准确。我们就在收入上做文章，我投资你，买你的收入行不行？从收入中分一笔行不行？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于投资进出保障的问题，我们在支付体系里直接扣款，直接在银行分账体系扣款。交收安全问题就解决了。华尔街金融体系里面解决的两个核心大功能，我们通过小芯片就解决了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决这个问题不是做慈善，是实实在在把回报拿回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最近有个别人质疑这个商业模式。几乎与此同时，澳交所获得伊斯兰教律监管委员会认证。澳门金管局行政委员会委员刘杏娟也表示，将秉持“风险为本”的监管原则对澳交所进行日常监控。这种创新模式的法律监管是什么样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;投资链条非常清晰：滴灌通通过海外机构进行募资，通过外商直接投资在内地联合经营开店。目前涉及的监管包括有四个国家和地区相关法律：中国内地作为一种民事法律关系有相关法律法规、中国香港证监会监管、中国澳门金融监管条例的相关条款，认购产品的国际投资人这块，受英国法律监管。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师被扣手机己归还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:42:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxRVLml.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxRVLml.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;迟夙生在法庭昏迷后，法院叫来了救护车。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“头痛原因待查”。 2023年11月7日上午，迟夙生拿到医院的病情证明后，仍需继续住院治疗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;67岁的迟夙生是黑龙江夙生律师事务所律师，曾连任第九届至第十一届全国人大代表。 11月6日，她代理的一起涉黑案件在云南宣威市人民法院公开审理。开庭前，迟夙生因在法庭拍摄了两张照片被认为违反法庭纪律，手机被扣留。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天下午6时许，审判长宣布休庭。迟夙生要求返还手机，与法院工作人员沟通无果后在法庭内昏迷。一个小时后，她被送至宣威市第一人民医院急诊科就诊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月7日下午4点多，迟夙生告诉南方周末记者，宣威法院院长陈永福在当天下午1点左右到医院看望她，并在3点多归还了她的手机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;两张照片&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年11月6日上午8点40分左右，距开庭还有20分钟，迟夙生抵达法庭。她向南方周末记者回忆，现场只有一名书记员，合议庭成员、检察官和其余律师都还没到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一起涉黑案重审一审开庭的第二十一天。此前，该案已经历一审、二审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月10日，宣威法院一审判决，认定涉案的刘顺平等10人不构成黑社会性质犯罪，但存在以刘顺平为首要分子、组织成员经常纠集在一起，共同实施寻衅滋事、敲诈勒索、非法拘禁行为，被认定为恶势力犯罪集团。刘顺平按照集团所犯的全部罪行数罪并罚，其余人员按照其所参与的犯罪行为被处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一审判决后，刘顺平等人不服，提出上诉。检察机关未抗诉。 2022年12月9日，曲靖中院二审以“部分事实不清”为由裁定撤销原判，发回重审。案件重审期间，宣威市检察院追加了3项罪名补充起诉，并仍指控刘顺平等人涉嫌黑社会性质犯罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入法庭后，迟夙生注意到被告人席位上并排摆放的10张黑色铁制审讯椅，带有固定手脚的装置。在这天前，此案庭审时被告人坐的一直是常规带靠背的木制椅，手脚可以自由活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她的经验中，这种状况并不常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;依据《中华人民共和国人民法院法庭规则》（以下简称”法庭规则”），除认为被告人人身危险性大，可能危害法庭安全外，法院在庭审活动中不得对被告人使用戒具。迟夙生下意识地举起手机，拍了两张审讯椅的照片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，她走出法庭，将手机存放到法庭外的铁皮柜内，为开庭做准备。这时，代理此案的其余律师陆续进场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生和另两名代理此案的律师均表示，从此案开庭的第一天开始，法院就口头要求他们不能带手机进入法庭。曾有律师对此提出异议，认为法庭规则只规定了不得拨打或接听电话等，并没有禁止携带手机，法院未对此作出回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4次沟通&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;迟夙生没想到，因为庭前拍摄的照片，此后她的手机被法院扣留。整个过程中，她同法院工作人员有4次沟通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开庭前，迟夙生把手机存入铁皮柜不久，就被法警叫至法庭外。据她回忆，一名法院工作人员要求她删除照片。她拒绝了这个要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法庭规则规定，全体人员在庭审活动中不得对庭审活动进行录音、录像、拍照或使用移动通信工具等传播庭审活动，违反这项规定的，法院可以暂扣其使用的设备及存储介质，删除内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生认为，自己拍照时庭审还没开始，没有违反法庭纪律。随后，她回到法庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上午10时20分左右，庭审中场休息20分钟。迟夙生被要求留在法庭内，其余律师均不被允许进入法庭。她记得，审判长提出要暂扣她的手机，书记员在现场做了记录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三次沟通发生在开庭期间。下午庭审时，轮到迟夙生发言，她继续申请返还她的手机。她强调，自己是在法庭尚未宣布开庭前拍摄照片，扣押她手机的行为毫无道理。她还表示，如果法院要扣押她的手机，需提供书面材料。审判长则表示，如果合议庭有违法违规的行为，迟夙生可以向上反映情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下午6点15分左右，法庭休庭。迟夙生来到法庭外的铁皮柜处取手机时，发现手机已经不在柜内。此时她已经一天没有使用手机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上周，迟夙生接到通知，这起本计划于11月8日结束庭审的涉黑案开庭将延长一个月。她急着和其他法院协调开庭时间，“我就特别着急，喊审判长&amp;nbsp;&#39;把手机还给我呀&#39;。审判长说&#39;丢了你就报警吧&#39;。”两名在场律师均向南方周末记者证实听到了这一对话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生返回法庭，希望再找人交涉此事。随后，她感到“全身发软，站不住了”，躺在了律师席的椅子上。当天晚上7点半，迟夙生被送至宣威市第一人民医院急诊科就诊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月7日，刘顺平等人涉黑案继续开庭审理。迟夙生未能到庭。她已在当天下午出院，打算休息一段时间，检查身体状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小金眼中的大金丨人来人往]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260080]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDTusi9UKvZB3J0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDTusi9UKvZB3J0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;金圣华与金耀基在翻译研讨会上。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港中文大学前校长金耀基教授，已届望九之年，退休至今也将近二十载了，仍老当益壮，精神抖擞，钦佩之余，乃想起了当年的往事。 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2004年某一天，在中文大学行政楼与图书馆之间、校内人一致称为“中央梯级”（Central Steps）的台阶上，遇上了一位即将退休的同事。她在校服务多年了，自中大创校校长李卓敏开始，共事过五位校长，可说是一位历朝元老。跟她闲聊，提到退休的事，谈起金耀基校长也离任在即，深感不舍，她突然说了一句：“金校长人太好了，我不怕他！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不怕他？有谁会怕金校长呢？可是，再想深一层，为什么下属会不怕主管？按常理来说，难道下属怕主管不是司空见惯的事吗？这就使我在脑海里浮现了这位“本家”的形象──和蔼可亲，笑容可掬，幽默机智，才情横溢；对任何人，上自校董，下至工友，都一视同仁；治校时，纳谏博采，从善如流；闲来抽一支烟斗，陶然自乐。这样一位温柔敦厚的主管，当然只会令人“敬爱有加”，而不会“敬而远之”了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;认识金耀基教授已经有几十年了。当初，校内姓金的教员不多，我们两人既然都隶属新亚，同事多以“大金”“小金”来区分，而我们彼此之间，也以“本家”互称，加以金教授的大名与我大哥的名字只有一字之差，在我心目中也就自然而然视之为兄长了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初认识金教授时，还在上世纪七十年代。犹记当年，这位“本家”刚从美国返港不久，英姿勃发，年轻有为，未几，就屡任要职，后来还获选为新亚院长。当时，金耀基才四十出头，加以并非新亚出身，这两个因素，使他初掌重任时，可能也曾遭遇过一些阻碍，可是凭借超卓的才智与惊人的魄力，一切困难，在他手中，都可迎刃而解。此后，金教授在中大数十年，层楼更上，他的事务越来越多，责任越来越重，可是有谁见过他愁眉苦脸、不胜负荷的模样？在大家的心目中，金公永远是谈笑用兵、举重若轻的。也因为如此，校方凡有“疑难杂症”，就自然会交托给他，希望他能“对症下药”，妙手回春。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2003年12月，中大教职员工联谊会举行圣诞舞会，把金校长也请来了。晚会上，主持人要我讲几句话向他致意，我说道：“世上有两种领导：第一种，别人对他又敬又畏；第二种，令人对他又敬又爱，金教授当然是属于第二种。”这段话，获得了大家的认同。当晚，平日不擅跳舞的金校长，在大家簇拥下，居然也跳得十分尽兴，他就是这样一个体贴随和的人。多年来，凡同仁有事求教，他不管多忙，必然会放下一切，专心聆听，令人感到在金教授的心目中，你是最重要的人，你的事是最重要的事。他在听，他在想，他在为你分担，为你解忧。日理万机的他，让时间停下来，陪着你，护着你，前路不管多么崎岖，他会为你筹措，为你排难解纷。这样的一位主管，又怎不叫人心悦诚服？同事为学校尽心尽力、竭诚服务时，他不但听到看到，也会以行动表示感激。每年颁授学位典礼前夕，公关小组的同事往往忙得不可开交，彻夜不休。有一次，时近午夜，金校长竟然亲临探班，还带来了慰劳的巧克力！这样一位真诚待人的领导，才能使全校上下一心，不分彼此，为共同的目标而奋力求进。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金教授最为人称道的是他那出众的口才与出色的文章，他是出口成章、下笔成文的人物。每逢国际会议、纪念庆典、揭幕仪式等等重要场合，只要有金公在，只要他开金口，则必然会宾主皆欢，举座动容。金耀基的口才，不仅仅是舌灿莲花、咳珠唾玉而已，使人望尘莫及的是他的幽默，他的机智，他那挥洒自如、谈笑风生的本领，仿佛天地之间，万事万物都随时待命，只要他一招手，一点头，就会布阵遣将，列队而出。记得有一次，金教授要到市区去主持一个晚宴，在车上，他随意问了我几个问题，把列席宾客的资料略一掌握，结果在宴会上致辞时就发挥得淋漓尽致。我国第一位宇航员杨利伟顺利升空后，金校长在不同场合都引用了“感觉良好”的话语，但次次都用得恰到好处，效果奇佳。又有一次，翻译系举办国际研讨会，邀了金公来主持开幕礼，他请我事前代拟讲稿。开幕当天，金公如约前来，按稿发言，念了一半，他忽然说：“这文情并茂的演稿可不是我写的，是金圣华代拟的。”他的风趣幽默，从容自在，可见一斑。最近一次，是2022年9月24日在我新书（《谈心——与林青霞一起走过的十八年》）发表会上的演讲，那天，中文大学的善衡书院举办我和青霞的对谈，特地请来了金公作对谈后的评述。他一上台，就一本正经地问观众是否可以除下口罩，那时香港仍执行防疫措施，当然不行，于是，他接着说：“我不脱口罩没关系，林青霞戴了口罩，大家的损失可大了。”此语一出，马上惹得哄堂大笑，把整个会场的气氛烘托得热腾腾了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也记得在2003年第二届全球华文青年文学奖的晚宴上，金校长曾经说过，当晚星光闪耀，大大小小文曲星降临中大，既有大文曲星如各位评判王蒙、白先勇、余光中、林文月等名家，也有许多小文曲星如各组得奖的青年同学。其实，金校长本人才是不折不扣的文曲星，他一方面在社会学的领域中著书立言，垂教后世；另一方面又在文学的园地里，叙事言怀，寄想托情。 1975年访问剑大期间，金教授受感于剑桥的灵韵秀色，于撰写鸿文巨著之余，也开始散文小品的创作。在剑大一年，历经晴雨雾雪、春夏秋冬，金教授的灵思妙语，泉涌而出，完成《剑桥语丝》一书。十年后，在海德堡大学担任访问教授时，又将所思所感，诉诸笔端，撰写&amp;nbsp;《海德堡语丝》一书，前后二册，互相辉映，成为受人称道的“金体文”。 2007年，金公在退休之后，又有了故土之行，其一是前往沙漠艺都敦煌朝圣，回来后，出版了《敦煌语丝》一书，与前两册“语丝”呼应连接，是为脍炙人口的“语丝”三姐妹之作。综观金教授一生，既可运如椽巨笔，以山的凝重，撰写经世治国、针砭时弊的大块文章，读之掷地有声；又可执如丝细笔，以水的轻盈，描绘直抒胸臆、出自肺腑的世间真情，读之感人至深。不论巨著或小品，皆理中带情，情中含理，两者交融，不着痕迹。作者俯仰于天地之中，遨游于中西之间，溯古论今、寻幽探胜，既能在浩如烟海的学问中擘肌分理，找出头绪；也能在百花齐放的文坛上另辟蹊径，开出奇葩。究其因由，实在与其个人的素养禀赋与性情品格息息相关。金教授除本行专业外，对文学、历史、哲学、教育皆涵泳深沉，此外，为人处世，通情达理，所谓“世事洞明皆学问，人情练达即文章”，故不但能在谈诗论艺时，出类拔萃，在千丝万缕的人事丛结中，亦善于折冲樽俎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金耀基教授在中大服务共三十四年，在他出任校长的两年之间，经历了许多困难艰辛的时刻，形势非比寻常，包括SARS的暴发，及因政府削资而促使减薪等事故，所幸金校长任劳任怨，沉着应付，终于把难关一一克服。金校长在任内更完成多项任务，不但创设了法律学院，为大学筹募巨额捐款，并引进新机制以改进大学管治架构等。金校长上任时，曾经幽默地自称：“我是任重而道不远！”的确，两年的时间不算长，但金校长治校的成就却有目共睹，备受称道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2004年6月底，金耀基校长荣休前夕，中大设宴惜别。当晩高朋满座，盛况空前。所有应该来的宾客都来了，想不到的朋友也来了，包括校内各阶层各部门平时不喜饮宴的同事。晚宴举办得十分成功，没有冗长的演讲，没有煽情做作的场面，一切都来得纯朴自然，就像金校长历来的作风。校长致辞时说：“我是中大历来最年轻的院长，也是最年老的校长。大家问我退休后可以干什么？我想，朗奴‧列根（罗纳德·里根）七十一岁才出任总统，我大概还够资格去选总统！”风趣如故，幽默如故，这就是金校长的本色！晚宴举行到半场时，突然出现了众人趋前邀请金校长合影留念的场面：一桌又一桌，秩序井然，自动自发地走上前来，目光中尽显依依不舍的神色，这是从未见过的景象。从校董到秘书，从教授到文员，难分彼此，不论高低，此时此刻，大家心目中只有这位即将离任的金校长，这位温文儒雅、待人宽厚的金校长！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚宴最后一个节目，是中大校友临时召集成队的歌咏团，为金校长献唱&amp;nbsp;《祝福》一曲。这首由叶倩文原唱的名曲，经才子何文汇教授改编歌词，唱出了众人的心声：“凌云才华人共见，校长金公一谪仙。风趣俊朗待人甚友善，量阔腹中可撑船。行仁能奉献，献出真心感远天。真挚博爱育才没厌倦，万缕春风轻吹温暖。啊！春风春风，他朝再吹我面。轻轻挥手，离别愁深未断。听我细诉，日后要开心不变。有爱妻相伴，又有烟斗，烟圈千串……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金校长退休之后，比起过往繁忙的岁月，日子虽过得云淡风轻，却充实依旧，飘逸胜昔。除了著述不断，金公亦勤写书法。金耀基自幼在父亲督导之下，努力练字，然从不言苦。根据他的自述，“我对翰墨之道的探索追求，在我自中文大学退休、七十岁后之事”，因此，雍容自在、迈入古稀之年的金公，不但从心所欲，安享含饴弄孙之乐，也再续童年开始的翰墨之缘，并将之发扬光大，成为传颂一时、脍炙人口的“金字体”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好友林青霞不断由我口中听闻金公的大名与种种逸闻，再从《明报月刊》不时拜读他的大作和欣赏他的书法，一天，这位求贤若渴的才女，主动提出想跟金校长碰碰面，并向他讨教写作和书法的妙诀。 2021年9月24日，我在上海总会设宴，于是，学术界泰斗和演艺界翘楚终于在彼此互赏的状态下结识了。当天晚上，两人虽然第一次会晤，却有一见如故的感觉，席间青霞谈起了刚学习京剧不久，众友提出要求请她清唱一曲，话犹未了，她却已经爽朗豪迈地站起身来，毫不忸怩地唱起了《苏三起解》（花旦）和《三家店》（老生），金公一听，喝彩之余，以洪亮之声喊出了一句“胆大包天”！全场闻之，不由得嘻哈绝倒，鼓掌大乐！这以后，朋友之间，常以“胆大包天”来形容如今凡事都挥洒自如全力以赴的“拼命三娘”林青霞，而青霞自己，也认为金公的赠言可圈可点，甚至到金公提出要送赠墨宝时，还特地请他提了这几个字，高高悬挂在客厅里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久，金校长又赠送长幅墨宝《将进酒》给青霞，这幅字，写得逸兴遄飞，潇洒灵动，把诗仙李白的名作，衬托得天衣无缝。青霞请美术大师张叔平帮她裱好挂在墙上，日日观赏，谁知道2022年7月，大屋发生“火旺”事件，青霞远在海外，当时系念的不是珠宝衣物等身外之物，而是担心在熊熊烈火滚滚浓烟之下，墙上悬挂的《将进酒》是否安然无恙？说也奇怪，&amp;nbsp;那场三级烈火，烧毁了名画，烧毁了家具，然而一到《将进酒》之前，却戛然而止，一墙之隔，&amp;nbsp;偏偏没有烧到墙后青霞房中的书画和衣服。事后，金耀基叹息道：“我就知道林青霞水火不侵，林青霞就是林青霞！”林青霞则认为金公的墨宝是镇宅之宝，有防火御灾的神功。看到他们两人彼此赞赏，互相夸耀，不由得感到这两人之间惺惺相惜的情谊，多么雅致而有趣！如今，《将进酒》已经移居至青霞的半山书房，凡有文人雅士到访，女主人必会邀之在金公的这幅墨宝前留影纪念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林青霞与金耀基在《将进酒》前合影。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠肆虐，三年来疫情严峻，金校长却泰然自若，处变不惊，夫人元祯更是气定神闲，说道：“生死有命，怕也无益！”金校长则继续追求生活美学，自谓：“美食、美酒也从不肯刻意避让。在危危乎疫情中，若得良朋知己共醉，一举杯，便是人生！”如此胸襟，如此境界，与洒脱的东坡居士，亦不遑多让矣！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本家金耀基，人如其名，在众友心目中，恰似一道金晖，暖暖照耀着周围的一切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[业委会成员向开发商索要好处费：监督业委会还需业主亲力亲为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260056]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，四川广安一居民小区业主委员会两名成员向开发商索要好处费13万元，涉嫌非国家工作人员受贿罪，被公安部门立案侦查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据悉，陈某炳高票当上了广安某小区第一届业主委员会主任，陈某任安保协调委员、绿化卫生委员。 2020年5月底，政府考察小区的商业楼，筹备修建幼儿园，而小区开发商已将4楼部分房屋设置为物业办公室及业委会办公室；陈某炳找到小区开发商索要13万元好处费，声称自己可以让物业、业委会、业主等同意办公室搬迁，2020年6月，开发商与陈某炳商议好办公室搬迁事宜后，支付8万元给陈某炳，支付5万元给陈某。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈某炳、陈某的行为已触犯了《中华人民共和国刑法》第一百六十三条之规定，涉嫌非国家工作人员受贿罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了13万“好处费”，陈某炳、陈某就能让小区商业楼变幼儿园，可见其作为业委会成员，“能量”不小。这起案件还有几个关键点待厘清。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，四川省颁布的《四川省物业管理条例》第三十条规定，业主委员会应当定期在物业管理区域内向业主公布下列情况和资料：物业共有部分的使用和经营收益的收支情况。该业主委员会是否就居委会和业主办公室搬迁、原有房屋改幼儿园等事项，第一时间向业主大会公布相关信息，业主对此有无审核？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，如陈某炳、陈某蓄意拖延甚至瞒报，该小区业主对于这一重要事项的知情权就难以保证。这又涉及第二个问题，按照住建部颁布的《业主大会和业主委员会指导规则》，业主委员会由业主大会会议选举产生，由5至11人单数组成。为何占大多数的其他业委会成员对此决定没有提出异议，任由陈某炳、陈某拍板？如此也反映出其他业委会成员同样存在不作为情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这又指向更深层次的问题：谁来监督业委会？业委会是小区自治的体现，在物业管理区域内，全体业主组成业主大会，选举产生业委会作为业主大会的执行机构。然而，有关业委会成立过程被干扰乃至操纵、业委会成立之后就沦为少数成员谋私利的自留地，此类事件屡屡发生，让某些业委会的独立性、公正性几近于无。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就业委会选举而言，某些开发商或物业公司，为了保证自身利益，干扰、阻拦乃至操纵业委会选举。我所在小区今年就进行了业委会换届选举，但遗憾的是，由于约占小区产权总面积近10%的周边商铺业主，在通知到位、多次邀请的情况下未投一票，导致此次换届选举未能达到“专有部分面积占比三分之二以上的业主参与表决”这一规定，新业委会因此难产。有参与新业委会筹备的业主反映，物业向商铺业主许诺减免租金，交换条件是对方不参与投票，其目的就是阻扰业委会换届。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哪怕通过重重阻挠，最终成立业委会，小区业主也将面临更多的考验。由于业委会代行部分业主大会权力，一旦其缺乏职业道德和责任心，只关注自己的利益，不顾及其他业主的权益，必然走向公器私用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观业委会成员监守自盗的方式，大致有三种。第一，将公共维修基金变成自家“钱袋子”。据《北京晚报》2018年报道，北京珠江骏景小区业主反映，自己的公共维修基金账户早在2013年就支出四千多元而毫不知情，一些业主还发现，他们的公共维修基金被挪到了业委会账户上。业委会称，此举是为大家谋福利，进行投资，不公开是怕有人过来“挑茬儿”。但这一说法难以令人信服。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;手法二是“广开财源”，将小区各类公共设施全面开发商业化，让本应由全体业主共享的收益，由业委会成员与物业分润。 《重庆晚报》2010年曾报道，九龙坡区石坪桥地博春天小区物业公司与业委会签订合同，公共收益“三七分成”（业委会三成、物管方七成），但很多业主并不知情。此外，业委会主任还在物业领取3000元/月的报酬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;手法三则是将手伸向物业公司更替。业委会成员以更换物业为由，让现有物业公司向其缴纳“保护费”，或者换上与自己有利害关系的新物业公司，从而获利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观众多案例，我们可得出结论：业委会成员的道德自律不可靠，第三方监督不可少。按照《四川省物业管理条例》第三十九条规定，业主大会、业主委员会作出的决定违反法律、法规的，物业所在地的街道办事处（乡镇人民政府）或者县（市、区）人民政府住房城乡建设主管部门自收到投诉或者发现之日起三十日内，应当依法作出处理决定，并通告全体业主。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除此之外，广大业主作为小区的主人，也须意识到，自治权不仅仅是一项权利，更是一种责任和能力的体现。业主应花更多时间和精力，积极参与社区治理，通过业委会选举、参与业主大会、制定管理规约等途径，加强对业委会的监督和管理。同时，对于业委会公布的小区重大事项如公共收益等，还可聘请专业审计机构审计，以更强的公共意识和法治观念，切实维护自身权益，提升小区品质。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[入职两个多月，00后班主任留遗书自杀，班级管理该不该单独设岗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260099]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独居者老死在家中怎么办？用智能水表监测是一大创新]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260072]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;What to do when people living alone get old is a long-standing topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens said that some streets in Shanghai do this: collect information on elderly people living alone in the jurisdiction, and if the household has no water within a few days, they will come to check. This innovation is gradually spreading in aging communities. Other netizens added that Shanghai began to install smart water meters after a series of elderly people died alone in their homes and were found to be smelly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Their words caused a burst of sighs. Some netizens said bluntly that they were hurt in their hearts after reading the relevant content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement is not based on imagination, but is supported by news reports. Regarding the death of an old man without anyone knowing, here is an example: In December 2021, a news piece about &quot;an old man living alone in Shanghai died for many days and was discovered by firefighters&quot; attracted attention. According to neighbors, the old man is a native of Shanghai and is in his seventies. When the neighbor comes back from get off work every day, the old man will greet him, but he has not seen the old man for 5 days. I smelled a bad smell recently and called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of thing is not unique to Shanghai, it has happened in many places. For example, in November 2015, an old man surnamed Pei in Huangshi, Hubei Province, who had never been married and lived alone for many years, was found dead in the bathroom of his home. His body had turned into a pile of bones. According to media reports, the elderly man disappeared six years ago. Community workers and police worked with the deceased’s relatives to search for him but failed. The local Dongchu Evening News reported that “a 70-year-old man has disappeared from the world for more than a year.” Conducted special news reports on the topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This type of innovation is not unique to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the installation of smart water meters, CCTV&#39;s &quot;News 1+1&quot; reported in December 2020 that Jiangsu Road Street, Changning District, Shanghai, installed smart water meters for 6 elderly households living alone in the area. If the reading is less than 0.01 cubic meters within 12 hours, the neighborhood committee will immediately receive the signal and send someone to check it in time. It was on a pilot basis at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, such practices have appeared frequently in various places. For example, in May 2021, the Beijing Daily client reported that 25 elderly households living alone in the Red House Community in Nanyuan Street, Fengtai District used smart water meters with automatic alarms for free. If the water meter reading is less than 1 liter within 12 hours, the information will be fed back to the neighborhood committee, and someone will come to visit. In addition, smart mattresses, smart light sensors and smart one-button alarms can capture information about the daily activities of elderly people living alone. Once an abnormality is discovered, the back-end staff will promptly contact the community and the elderly&#39;s family members to provide safety protection for the elderly living alone and the disabled elderly. In July 2022, the website of the People&#39;s Government of Haishu District, Ningbo, Zhejiang published this news: &quot;Water Meter Butler&quot; to protect elderly people living alone is online. Abnormal water consumption will automatically alarm 24 hours a day to protect safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 16, 2023, Foshan Sanshui Foshui Water Supply Co., Ltd. launched the Sanshui District’s “Political and Public Conduct Hotline-Dialogue on People’s Livelihood” program. The company said: We have monitored that elderly people living alone use water When the data volume is abnormal, the grid staff of the village or neighborhood committee will be contacted. For example, if an elderly person used 0.5 cubic meters of water one day and no water the next day, we will recognize this change and notify the grid operator at the residence of the elderly person living alone to contact the civil affairs department and go to the scene to contact the elderly person. Make connections to see if there are any abnormalities in water use or other aspects. We hope that by monitoring water usage, the lives of elderly people living alone can be helped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s cryptic, but you know the meaning. News reports use suggestive and evocative language to describe objective facts. Relatively speaking, netizens’ vernacular is more shocking. But no matter how you express it, the core of the truth is indeed so bleak. For an elderly person living alone, it is not surprising that once his health has problems and no one is around to take care of him, his later life will be miserable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author has talked about the importance of having children in many articles. Whether you have children or not, the outcome is very different. That kind of blood and spiritual connection cannot be replaced by any instrument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, even if you have children, there may still be problems with the elderly living alone and the children not visiting the elderly often. The children of the aforementioned elderly people living alone in Shanghai live in the outer suburbs. The old man passed away, and the children didn&#39;t know about it. It can be seen that they haven&#39;t visited him for many days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many reasons why children and the elderly are separated and lack of care for the elderly. For example, some children are extremely busy at work or start a business in other places. As for the elderly who do not want their children to disturb their lives due to differences in interests, temperaments, and cognitions, there are many examples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But more importantly, the Chinese family structure of three generations and four generations living under one roof has long been impacted by many trendy concepts, such as &quot;separating children and the elderly is more conducive to harmonious relationships&quot; and &quot;children and children living together harmoniously.&quot; The elderly live separately but keep a bowl of hot soup away.&quot; In this context, it is an indisputable fact that more and more elderly people live alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what factors cause the elderly to live alone, it is indeed a worrying social problem for the elderly to live alone and be temporarily or permanently &quot;forgotten&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to solve it? It is a proposition worth examining that the elderly and their children should live together as much as possible. Of course, taking into account various practical problems, &quot;living together&quot; should include the option of &quot;living nearby&quot; for children and the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singapore attaches great importance to promoting this &quot;project&quot;. For a long time, in order to encourage children to live with the elderly, the government has provided conveniences and discounts to families living with the elderly in HDB flats, such as when allocating government flats. Price discounts and priority arrangements will be given to families with three generations living under one roof. In addition, a series of subsidy programs have been launched to provide elderly care and medical subsidies to low-income families supporting the elderly to reduce their family burden. This move increases the enthusiasm of young people and the elderly to live together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order for family care to become the main way to provide for the elderly, policy promotion is essential. In November 2021, the &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening the Work on Aging in the New Era&quot; was released, emphasizing the need to improve the elderly care service system, innovate the home and community elderly care service model, and based on home care, through new construction, renovation, leasing, etc. Community elderly care service capabilities. Adult children are encouraged to live nearby or together with their elderly parents to fulfill their support obligations and assume care responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that relevant surveys show that 58.51% of adult children are willing to live with the elderly. This ratio gives people confidence. It is not difficult to realize the vision of &quot;living together&quot; for children and the elderly on a larger scale when they are trying their best to shoulder the responsibilities and obligations of providing for the elderly, and with the help of good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中产三宝拉夫劳伦不香了，年轻人开始走“没钱风”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/0d38a337b2acadb1e7320d558b846b73.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;952&quot; height=&quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/06/0d38a337b2acadb1e7320d558b846b73.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257148&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / picture）&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is said that the middle class has three treasures: Ralph Lauren, lululemon and Archaeopteryx. But recently, Ralph Lauren, one of the three treasures of the middle class, has begun to lose its sales. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The financial report for the first quarter of fiscal year 2024 shows that as of July 2023, Ralph Lauren’s sales increased by only 0.4% compared with the same period last year. North America performed poorly, with revenue down 10%, and growth in the European market also slowed. Overall, the performance in the past two years has been slightly weak. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Then the question is, as a classic representative of &quot;rich style&quot;, Ralph Lauren was once considered a must-have for the middle class. How did the miracle of Ralph Lauren&#39;s rise be explained? Created? How did it gradually come down from the altar? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Ralph Lauren and Old Money Style&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1967, Ralph Lauren was founded by Ralph Lauren was founded in the United States and is positioned as a designer brand full of American classics and British style. In the early days, by sponsoring popular films such as &quot;The Great Gatsby&quot; and &quot;Annie Hall,&quot; Ralph Lauren successfully bound itself to the &quot;American Dream.&quot; In countless American literature, &quot;models dressed like Ralph Lauren&quot; ” is another expression of becoming a superior person. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The classic polo logo and stand-up collar Polo shirt have conquered many middle-aged men, unified the aesthetics of elite men around the world, and established a firm foothold in their cloakrooms. Ralph Lauren&#39;s Polo shirt is as classic as jeans are to Reeves, and down jackets are to Bosideng. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, long-lasting Ralph Lauren classic items such as cable-knit sweaters and Oxford cloth shirts are popular all year round, which can be said to be an effortless way to look old money. A styling tool that sells well all over the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Speaking of the &quot;old money style&quot; that made Ralph Lauren out of the industry, why are the new middle class so attracted to it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Old money&quot; is a concept opposite to the &quot;new middle class&quot;. They are often people who were born in Rome and have been rich for several generations. They are known as the royal family. Most of them are nobles or wealthy businessmen, and they are in a class that is beyond the reach of ordinary people. And their dressing sense shows distinctive characteristics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The overall style is mostly basic, with silhouette-based clothing styles, classic and timeless designs, brand logos that are not deliberately displayed, and fabrics that look expensive. What matters is high-end and quality. The happiness of rich people is so unpretentious and boring. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The beauty of &quot;old money style&quot; is not piled up, nor is it created by luxury goods, but is enduring after time, calm retro and A solemn elegance, noble and unassuming, low-key but deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As Paul Fussell said as early as the 1980s in his sociological work &quot;Style: Social Class and Lifestyle&quot;: In appearance, housing , consumption, leisure, furnishings, spiritual life, language and other aspects of realization will reflect different social levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because machine-made consumer products are so perfect that their high-profile and cheapness can be recognized at a glance, and colors with grayscale components that deviate from the machine have become the center of attention. The favor of the upper class. “The softer and darker the color, the more classy it is.” “Low-key is a common tendency.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The behavior of being covered in luxury goods with logos, wanting to wear the most valuable possessions on your body, and showing off your money and power to others is what the old money do. Disdainful, with the aura of rich people and nouveau riche, too exaggerated and flashy, and appearing to be using too much force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The unified and harmonious color system, clean and simple clothes, on the contrary, look noble and elegant, with a natural sense of relaxation, and show off effortlessly. sense of fashion. This is the essence of old money style, which is simple and low-key, but has texture and looks full of nobility without any effort. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ralph Lauren is at the forefront of this old money trend. At first glance, it looks ordinary among the crowd, but at a closer look, the brand&#39;s logo reveals its identity and status. It is conveyed in a low-key yet high-profile way, perfectly capturing the middle-aged people&#39;s preference for high-end brands. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Relying on its close ties with the &quot;old money style&quot;, Ralph Lauren successfully captured the American elite, and then embarked on a journey of global expansion, without exception. Let China&#39;s middle class compete for it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/510edbfc3b41bdcca5acf9dfc0526a7d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1349&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/510edbfc3b41bdcca5acf9dfc0526a7d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257145 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; The three treasures of the middle class cannot be loved by young people? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the 2007 domestic drama &quot;Struggle&quot;, Tong Dawei wore a Ralph Lauren Polo shirt, which brought this American elite brand into the eyes of a wider range of Chinese people. Since then, Ralph Lauren has begun its own golden age. Through the offline agency model, it has spread all over the country and achieved rapid expansion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, success is also a failure. A large number of stores introduced low-end lines in order to reduce sales, which lowered the brand level. Frequent discounts destroyed consumer trust, and counterfeit goods The proliferation of it on the streets has also caused the brand image to plummet. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ralph Lauren’s financial reports have changed from the previous highs to continuous declines, and ushered in the darkest moment in 2021. Compared with the peak, revenue fell by 40%. Only 4.4 billion yuan. And due to the impact of the epidemic, half of China’s offline stores have been closed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After this, Ralph Lauren began drastic reforms, completely transforming the Chinese market into direct sales, and began high-end and digital transformation. Marketing focuses on KOL and social media, and also launches younger sub-brands. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nowadays, the trend of &quot;how to dress like a rich girl&quot; is popular among Generation Z. The makeup and clothing of rich girls are flooding the social media at home and abroad, attracting attention. There are many imitators. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After being immune to the dopamine style, sweet-cool-girl style, and Y2K style, the reincarnation of fashion has returned to the &quot;old money style&quot; style, and young people have begun to get involved. The nostalgic complex of &quot;old money style&quot; has the ultimate pursuit of making oneself dress more luxurious, hoping that one can create a low-key, refined and elegant image to the outside world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a result, Ralph Lauren has gradually begun to win over young people from harvesting the middle-aged three treasures of the middle class. It is worth thinking about that the short-term preference of young people does not make Ralph Lauren confident. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Essentially, &quot;old money style&quot; is also a fresh trend. Young people are yearning for another kind of life even though they can&#39;t get it. They can feel it through their outfits. The world of &quot;old money&quot; is a feasible strategy. However, after trying it, they often lose long-term interest, stop trying it and fall in love with it, and the late wavers rush to the next fashion trend non-stop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Once a representative of the old money style, Ralph Lauren was sought after as a must-have item. However, when the &quot;old money style&quot; lost its popularity, the price increased by 80% in five years. Young people just can’t fall in love with Ralph Lauren. After all, in today&#39;s risk society, young people pursue stability more and are less arbitrary and more rational in spending money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Basic Polo shirts, which can easily cost three to four thousand a piece, are really hard to get rid of. At this time, I look back and see that the UNIQLO co-branded models and MUJI are really good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When the current trend of &quot;no money&quot; begins, and consumption downgrades are accompanied by clothing downgrades, we don&#39;t know how long Ralph Lauren will remain popular in China. What is certain is that &quot;the North Face team was all members last year, the Birdman team was last year, and the Ralph Lauren team is this year.&quot; In the dictionary of fashion, nothing is immortal. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Outfitting is not only a style, but also an expression of personality, so Ralph Lauren is just a symbol. Young people don’t care which brand this symbol is embodied by. , the point is, a way of thinking and attitude towards life that is not influenced by trends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[毕业生就业难，企业用工荒，创新国际化办学可破就业“悖论”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260104]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;January 29, 2023, Haining, Zhejiang, on the production line of a company. (Visual China /Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/a8ac71dd93.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/a8ac71dd93.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;January 29, 2023, Haining, Zhejiang, on the production line of a company. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Obviously companies are in short supply of people, why can&#39;t college graduates find jobs?&quot; October 30, 2023, in Zhejiang At the third &quot;Zhejiang University Oriental Forum Haining Sub-Forum&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Forum&quot;) held in Haining City, Zhejiang Province, Chen Lijun, a professor at the School of Public Administration of Zhejiang University, raised a &quot;paradox&quot; about employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After analyzing millions of employment data of global college graduates on LinkedIn China (LinkedIn), Chen Lijun found that the employment data of the top 100 college graduates in the world&#39;s QS rankings The first-time employment rate (the number of people who choose to work after their first graduation) is close to 80%. In China&#39;s leading universities, this figure is close to 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Lijun believes that an important reason for the emergence of the &quot;paradox&quot; is the disconnect between the talent chain and the education chain. &quot;The talents cultivated by schools are not the talents that enterprises need.&quot; , the industrial chain is disconnected from the talent chain, causing employment difficulties and labor shortages to coexist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the county economy, the problem of connecting high-end talents and enterprises may be more serious. Significantly. In Haining, where the forum was held, one local solution was to introduce educational resources. As early as 2013, the Haining Municipal Government reached a cooperation with Zhejiang University and introduced Zhejiang University International College. The goal of the cooperation between the two parties is to establish an international cooperative education model area with the Haining campus of Zhejiang University International College as the main body and linking the entire Haining area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, Zhejiang Haining International Campus has been recruiting students for seven years. Wang Yiming, executive deputy mayor of Haining City, proposed at the forum that the cooperation between Zhejiang University and Haining is &quot;gradually getting better.&quot; &quot;The integration of schools and places, the integration of science and technology, and the integration of industries are getting deeper and deeper, and supporting talent and employment services are also keeping up,&quot; but he also admitted that &quot;it is still difficult to introduce and retain talents.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;Innovative international education&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Haining is a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Zhejiang Province, adjacent to the provincial capital Hangzhou and only more than 100 kilometers away from Shanghai. It was once known as the &quot;Leather Capital&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The problem of human resources is a prominent issue in county development.&quot; Professor Wu Jiebing of the School of Public Administration of Zhejiang University introduced at the seminar that before 2010, he had After conducting research on the leather industry in Haining, companies reported that “it is difficult to attract undergraduate graduates from a prestigious university.” More graduates chose to stay in Shanghai or Hangzhou, where companies have R&amp;D centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The problem facing Haining is how to gather talents and innovate and develop high-tech industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was also around 2010 that Chinese universities launched a wave of innovative international education. Duke Kunshan University, New York University Shanghai, Wenzhou-Kean University and other Sino-foreign cooperative universities have been approved for establishment. Interestingly, combined with the previous University of Nottingham Ningbo and Xi&#39;an Jiaotong-Liverpool University, the economically developed Yangtze River Delta region has concentrated half of the Sino-foreign joint universities with independent legal personality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2013, Zhejiang University reached a cooperation with the Haining Municipal Government, and the school’s International Union College settled in Haining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;International education is closely related to local economic development needs. After analyzing provincial panel data from 1997 to 2019, Li Fengliang, a professor at the Graduate School of Education at Tsinghua University, found that whether it was the number of Sino-foreign cooperative education institutions or the number of projects, there was a significant positive correlation between the scale of Sino-foreign cooperative education and the level of economic development. This shows that the expansion of education opening to the outside world can promote the improvement of economic development levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2016, Zhejiang University Haining International Campus officially opened. At the end of the same year, Haining decided to build a new science and technology city based on Zhejiang Haining International Campus, focusing on the three industries of pan-semiconductor, life and health, and modern service industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some scholars once pointed out that international education is a double-edged sword. Hong Chengwen, executive deputy director of the Institute of Higher Education of Beijing Normal University, once compared decorating a house to China. He believes that the internationalization of education is to decorate his own home with the best materials, but the ultimate goal of internationalization of education should be &quot;how to serve other people&#39;s houses and be a house designer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qu Lijuan, deputy dean of Zhejiang Haining International Campus, said, &quot;The main task of Zhejiang Haining International Campus is to introduce advanced school running concepts, education models and investment mechanisms. The International Union College has established extensive links with world-class academics, and then empowers local economic development through education, technology, and talents, and the corresponding transformation of scientific and technological achievements must be completed locally.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, 2023, Haining, Zhejiang, the third &quot;Zhejiang University Oriental Forum Haining Sub-forum&quot; roundtable meeting, Chen Lijun, professor of School of Public Administration, Zhejiang University. (Interviewee/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/315958bd61.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/07/315958bd61.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30, 2023 , Haining, Zhejiang, the third &quot;Zhejiang University Oriental Forum Haining Sub-forum&quot; roundtable meeting, Chen Lijun, professor of School of Public Administration, Zhejiang University. (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to retain graduates&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the forum, Chen Lijun threw out the question about employment to the participants &quot;Paradox&quot;: On the one hand, college graduates cannot find jobs, and millions of people are going to &quot;take public exams&quot;; on the other hand, companies in the transformation and upgrading period cannot recruit urgently needed talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She believes that the simultaneous emergence of &quot;employment difficulties&quot; and &quot;labor shortages&quot; reflects the disconnect between the talent chain and the industrial chain. &quot;Companies are too short of people.&quot; , I participated in a talent symposium in Hangzhou before, and a company said that there is no shortage of designers, but senior technicians, and they are ready to go to South Africa to introduce them. High-skilled talents (cannot be recruited) should be said between education and the industrial chain The disconnect between them is already serious.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, there is also a disconnect between the education chain and the innovation chain. &quot;The conversion rate of scientific and technological achievements in our domestic universities is only about 6%,&quot; Chen Lijun pointed out, &quot;There are &#39;two skins&#39; between many university campuses and industrial parks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In our country, the agglomeration between various innovation elements is still There are certain problems.&quot; Chen Lijun mentioned that a very important feature of global science and technology innovation centers is the high concentration and integration of various innovation elements, including universities, scientific research institutes, enterprises, and various intermediary agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How to solve the integration problem among the talent chain, industry chain, education chain, and innovation chain (referred to as the &quot;four chains&quot;)? Chen Lijun pointed out that one way is to deploy innovation and industrial chains around the talent chain, such as the cooperation model between Zhejiang University and Haining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Wang Yiming&#39;s view, talents are the media between the education chain, the industrial chain, and the innovation chain. He introduced that the campus-site cooperation between Haining and Zhejiang University has begun to bear fruit. “In terms of campus-site integration, we have established a campus-site construction committee and an international education cooperation office, and established a science and technology innovation fund for talents to provide institutional and design guarantees. ; In terms of scientific and technological innovation integration, the Hangzhou Bay North Wing Science and Technology Innovation Hub is under construction and is expected to be initially formed in 2025; in terms of industrial integration, we have built 8 industry-education centers with Zhejiang University; in terms of employment support for talents, we have newly built a new hub around the campus international schools and international hotels.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Can innovative international education retain talents and solve the employment paradox? According to data released by the International Union College of Zhejiang University, the further study rate of the college’s first three graduates reached 89.7%, and the overseas further study rate reached 66.2%. Wang Yiming mentioned that it is still difficult to introduce and retain talents. &quot;When will so many of our students for further studies come back? If they can come back to China, it will be the result of successful technological transformation, but what we have seen so far is not very good.&quot; &quot;More.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The related background is that after a wave of terminations of Sino-foreign cooperative education institutions and projects around 2018, international education has picked up. According to data released by the Sino-foreign cooperative education supervision information platform, as of the end of May 2022, there are more than 1,300 Sino-foreign cooperative education institutions and projects operating at undergraduate and above levels in ordinary colleges and universities across the country, with more than 700,000 students enrolled. Judging from the scale distribution of provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) within the country, except for Tibet, the other 30 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) have opened different types of Sino-foreign cooperative schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;(Retaining) international talents is not only a shortcoming of Zhejiang Province, but also a shortcoming of the entire China.&quot; Chen Lijun said that studying abroad is a global talent flow The most important way, judging from the existing data, is that 50% of people in China&#39;s advantaged universities want to further their studies, and 70% of them choose to go abroad. In terms of return-to-return ratio, China only ranks 100th in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Yiming admitted frankly that the breadth and depth of cooperation between the two parties need to be further deepened in the future. He revealed, &quot;The new round of cooperation will invest 10 billion to provide elements for talents. Guarantee, how to actively cultivate innovation (talents) in the future is a test of the capabilities and level of Haining Municipal Government.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>