<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[连酵母都要种了？面包怎么变成你吃不起的样子？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, &quot;a monthly salary of 10,000 yuan cannot afford bread&quot; Hot searches have stung the hearts of many working people, and the lingering heat has not dissipated. Recently, a RT-Mart &quot;Potato Bread&quot; originally priced at 18.9 yuan for 4 pieces was once raised to 100 yuan on behalf of the purchaser. People can&#39;t help but complain, how can the bread be more expensive? Is it getting more expensive? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the public&#39;s pursuit of a healthy eating lifestyle, the Chinese people&#39;s dietary structure is becoming diversified, whether it is old-fashioned, new Chinese, or European. And Japanese style, bread, as a major branch of baked goods, is undergoing a transformation from snack to staple food or meal replacement food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, the competition in China&#39;s baking market, which is becoming saturated, is fierce, the market size is still expanding, and the requirements for updating the baking track will increase in the future. For example, the consumption of zero-sugar products has become popular, and the demand for sugar substitutes has caused huge changes in the baking industry chain. Upgrading technology, updating equipment, innovative products and sales channels will become new challenges facing the baking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, consumers have formed regular purchasing habits for baked goods. Coastal areas and first- and second-tier cities have strong spending power. Among them, female users and middle-aged Young people have become the main force driving the consumption of baked goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Baked food not only meets the daily needs of consumers, but also occupies the public&#39;s attention as a cultural symbol, identity mark and social currency, such as &quot;citywalk+coffee+Beijing&quot; The combination of &quot;fruit&quot; has become one of the trendy lifestyles of contemporary young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Behind the iteration of consumer trends is a kind of self-reinforcement of collective action - which has led to rounds of reshuffles in the baking industry. The predecessors have left the scene and the successors have taken the stage. The bakery market is showing a trend of ice and fire: &quot;store closing wave&quot; and &quot;financing boom&quot; coexist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The industry is undergoing a major reshuffle. What remains unchanged is that the &quot;Baking Assassin&quot; is still standing, and the Sword of Damocles hanging over consumers&#39; heads has not disappeared. . According to industry insiders, for certain high-priced baking keywords, 5 yuan will be added every time one appears. So, do young people buy into this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As mentioned by Japanese scholar Miura Exhibition in &quot;The 4th Era of Consumption: Sharing Economy, a Major Trend that Makes People Happier&quot;, the &quot;4th Era of Consumption&quot; The trend is towards simplicity, reality, low prices and low consumption desire, and consumption values ​​tend to be social, local and shared. This consumption characteristic seems to be emerging among China&#39;s young consumer groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Faced with &quot;baking assassins&quot;, they refused to be &quot;cut off leeks&quot; and chose simpler pre-made baking products. They refused to be charged by scalpers and set their sights on Community bakeries, hold group meetings online to grab bread; refuse long queues and enjoy the fun and deliciousness of baking at home. Some advanced baking players have even started to grow yeast to create the spiritual interest of baking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Know&quot; talks to you about how young people will cope when bread becomes more and more unaffordable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/12945c742d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/12945c742d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258909&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9aa6f41590.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9aa6f41590.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258910&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/85f66a37db.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/85f66a37db.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258911&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/2fcb670f45.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/2fcb670f45.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258912&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/0afba86876.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/0afba86876.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/04558a91ad.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/04558a91ad.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/9f1d9e5be5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/9f1d9e5be5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/d754baba8e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/d754baba8e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258917 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你好，两眼炯炯有神的外星生物丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VHmTK17O6xJf358f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VH mTK17O6xJf358f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, the main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention-Chengdu People walk in the &quot;Space-Time Tunnel&quot; at the Science Fiction Museum &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260297&quot; title=&quot;Humans please answer: Can science fiction keep up with the magic of reality&quot;>;Humans please answer : Can science fiction keep up with the magic of reality?&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw UFOs when I was a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was a few days before the 2008 Beijing Olympics. There is always a ten-year gap between the time in the county and the big cities. UFO exploration and the mystery of aliens that are popular in big cities did not reach me until the year I graduated from junior high school. That summer I was particularly fascinated by UFOs and aliens. I read a lot of books about aliens in Wenhui Bookstore, and watched programs about searching for ghosts and aliens on local TV. When I was walking, I often stopped suddenly and looked up into the sky. I feel like there must be something in the sky looking at me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One evening, I finally saw a UFO when I looked up. They were two fireballs stuck together, orange in color, flying at a constant speed in high altitude, and the tail of the aircraft seemed to be spitting fire. &quot;You finally came to pick me up.&quot; I happily followed the aircraft in the sky, completely forgetting that I was in a strange city until it completely disappeared. Later, when my parents found me who was lost, I didn&#39;t say anything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, I attended the 81st World Science Fiction Conference in Pidu, Chengdu. The UFO often came to my mind. I don’t think any science fiction fan present would laugh at me. The sci-fi conference was really lively for a few days. The most popular elements in the Chengdu Science Museum were pandas and Liu Cixin. I read less science fiction, but during the interview I became more and more curious: why is it science fiction, why is it in Chengdu, and why is the rise of science fiction happening? In China in the past ten years? At the same time, I felt like I was awakened to the vague emotions about the universe that I had as a child. Yes, we have been guessing about the truth of the world and the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People’s expectations for science fiction writers also come from the history created by science fiction writers in the past, and their imaginations about the future are constantly being fulfilled in their works. After the on-site interview at the science fiction conference, I went to a friend&#39;s new bookstore before leaving Chengdu. New bookstores have emerged in Chengdu in the past few years. This bookstore that is still in trial operation is called &quot;Baidu&quot;. 3 of the 6 founders Bit is for web3. The first row of large book walls in the store is quite special and very smooth. It covers technology first, then machines, then the Internet and artificial intelligence. At the end of the whole row of books is a series of science fiction literary works - the imagination about the future network society. There are only Two books by Chinese science fiction writers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I heard that my business trip was to cover a science fiction conference, the girl who worked on web3 held me in question for half an hour until I had to rush to the airport to catch my flight. This year, she and her partners attended a conference in the Bay Area. Cutting-edge network technicians from all over the world expressed their fear that AI will change the destiny of mankind. She kept asking me almost eagerly: Artificial intelligence is already unstoppable. Why haven’t China’s top science fiction writers pointed out the profound changes that are about to occur in human society? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But why would such a requirement be placed on a literary genre? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No other literary genre should be given such expectations. It seems that these network practitioners know what technology will create next, but they do not know where technology will ultimately lead mankind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More and more literary forums discuss writing under new technologies and the meaning of human existence. The panic caused by ChatGPT is something I didn’t expect. “The previous industrial revolutions created all material things. , what is being created this time is the spirit.&quot; Han Song, a science fiction writer who works for Xinhua News Agency, said in an interview, &quot;Earlier when big machines appeared, people felt that they would lose their jobs, and nuclear weapons appeared, and they felt that human beings would be exterminated, but this time It&#39;s different.&quot; This is more like a species crisis for humans, which may be replaced by more intelligent creatures. What if this is part of evolution? It really cannot be considered pessimistic to point out the laws of evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is all really curious. At the science fiction conference in Pidu, I would still suddenly stop and look up while walking, feeling overjoyed. For extraterrestrial creatures, it would be a shock to see these guys holding a science fiction convention on Earth, looking at their big round heads one by one. &quot;These alien creatures with bright eyes are going to... How to write about us.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们需要怎样的图书馆？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the one hand, there is news about the decline of paper books. Many people even made it clear that they will no longer buy paper books. Don’t read paper books, only e-books. On the one hand, many people still suffer from the lack of convenient ways to borrow books, and there is an urgent need for community libraries and other borrowing places that are close to life. What should the future library look like?</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清华博士当占星师：算命作为职业，合法吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261198]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to media reports, in the face of the increasingly fierce competition for graduate employment, Mary, a PhD graduate in history from Tsinghua University Ann chose an unexpected career path and became a full-time astrologer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Ph.D. graduate from a prestigious university and a senior intellectual, with these unattainable titles, gave up jobs that were relevant in the traditional sense. Many people felt that she was not worth it and criticized her for wasting her quota at Tsinghua University. Marianne also admitted that she did not expect to transform from a historian to a full-time astrologer today. However, she believes that career choices should be based on one&#39;s own interests and abilities, and should not be restricted by traditional career boundaries. You should be brave enough to try and find your own professional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She spent 5 years studying astrology and worked as an astrologer for 2 years. Her customer base is mainly young people, who found her through friends&#39; introductions or Internet searches. In the past two years, she has done very well, receiving nearly a thousand customers, and her monthly income has just exceeded 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To judge her choice, the first question to be faced is: Is it illegal to use fortune telling, astrology, tarot cards, or other methods that claim to be predictive to predict people&#39;s fortune and destiny? This question is simple, but the answer is more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what form of fortune telling, whether it is illegal or not depends on whether the specific behavior is illegal. Courts generally give a certain degree of respect to traditional Chinese Feng Shui, Zhouyi and other cultures and customs, and do not make scientific or superstitious judgments. Instead, they regard them as legitimate consulting services. As long as the fees are within the normal range, they are regarded as normal labor expenses. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foundation of Chinese fortune-telling is the &quot;Book of Changes&quot;. Telling people&#39;s fortunes based on the Four Pillars, Five Elements and Eight Diagrams seems to be regarded as the research, discussion and practice of traditional culture. According to a kind of saying, some money must be paid for these leaks, otherwise it will be more detrimental to the fortune teller. So, if you receive dozens, hundreds, or even hundreds of yuan, the person receiving the money will be happy, but the person giving the money will not matter. , both parties are consensual, and there is no fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Five Elements and Eight Trigrams are allowed, birth dates are allowed, and divination and burning turtle shells are allowed, then even though horoscopes, crystal balls, and Tarot cards are passed down from foreign countries, they are still not illegal and can be regarded as An advisory or entertainment. Take this astrologer who graduated from Tsinghua University as an example. His current monthly income is just over 30,000 yuan. It may not have been that much before. His two-year income is estimated to be only 200,000-400,000 yuan. With a thousand customers, the average income per person is two to three hundred yuan. . This amount is obviously not illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if a fortune teller pretends to be a god or a mage, commits fraud, fraud, extortion and other illegal acts, or defrauds money by exaggerating or falsely advertising, or charges a large amount, it is considered a crime. Illegal conduct. The court will determine that this kind of &quot;fortune-telling&quot; is unjust enrichment and is not a legitimate reason for obtaining benefits under the law. At the least, it will apply the civil law&#39;s unjust enrichment to return the property and return the unjust enrichment to the injured person. At worst, it will involve a criminal offense. . For example, using tarot cards, crystal balls, astrology and other methods to introduce physical, mental and spiritual fraud courses is an out-and-out crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the legal issues are complex, they are well-founded. A more difficult question to answer is, how should we view the rise of this type of profession? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern society is developing at a fast pace, interpersonal relationships are tense, and it is full of opportunities and challenges, but it is also accompanied by great uncertainties, such as the rise and fall of stocks, profit and loss of business, rising or unfinished real estate prices, and so on. There is the eternal topic of good health. Faced with these complex uncertainties, there is always an indescribable uneasiness permeating the hearts of contemporary people. Many people believe that their own destiny is not completely within their control. There is a supernatural power that affects the direction of their destiny. People do not accept this as their fate with peace of mind. They desire to control their lives and seek certainty. There are also some people who have achieved great success. Looking back at the past, their fate is full of coincidences. They feel that many things are beyond human control. While thanking God for his blessing, they will naturally worship this power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, religion and fortune telling became the way for them to seek spiritual comfort. Various fortune-telling and predictions are how they seek comfort and certainty from this unknowable power. For modern people, fortune telling is relatively familiar, but tarot cards and crystal balls are more advanced because they are rarely seen and come from foreign countries with exotic customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are degrees of distinction in seeking various fortune tellings. Some people don&#39;t necessarily believe in the results of fortune telling, but just treat it as entertainment and seek psychological comfort. For example, if you want to share something tomorrow, or conduct a live broadcast, or take an exam, you can find someone online and spend dozens or hundreds of dollars to tell your fortune, or look at a crystal ball or tarot cards, and get a As a result, Quan is happy. If the result is good, take it as a positive psychological hint to yourself, and don&#39;t take it personally if it&#39;s not good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of this astrologer who graduated from Tsinghua University, astrology is not just prediction, but a tool to help people better understand themselves and life. She said: &quot;Astrology has allowed me to see the bigger world and give me a deeper understanding of human nature. Every time I see a client feel relieved or inspired by my help, I feel very satisfied.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There is some truth in what she said. Astrologers are actually providing psychological massage to a certain extent. An excellent astrologer understands the ancient astronomy and mythology related to astrology itself, but also involves philosophy and psychology. Only in this way can he provide comprehensive psychological support to his clients. This is obviously the advantage of a historian as an astrologer. This is similar to traditional Chinese fortune telling. Three scholars asked the fortune teller about the results of the imperial examination. The fortune teller raised a finger: one of them passed the exam; only one failed; and none of the three passed. One finger corresponds to three results. This is a kind of deception, but it is also a psychological suggestion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, can these methods really bring long-term comfort to people? In fact, fortune telling is more of an escape. True courage is to maintain courage and determination after going through hardships, to find solutions and face uncertainty based on reason and courage. Turning to psychological counseling, psychotherapy and other methods to adjust your mentality and face reality is more reliable than fortune telling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周依然：偶然的，不确定的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261270]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/cykfx0ZM4x1a0rqZ3LwAEN3ubgEWFqEANGjPwSm8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cykfx0ZM4x1a0rqZ3LwAEN3ubgEWFq EANGjPwSm8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Yiran was discovered on the day after attending the dance teacher’s birthday party. When she was less than 20 years old, she was walking home wearing an exquisite short skirt. A stranger who claimed to be the casting director of the film crew appeared in front of her, handed her a business card, and took a photo of her on the spot. &quot;Front, side, 45 degrees, back. That was my first group photo, and I was wearing steel teeth.&quot; Zhou Yiran laughed, &quot;It&#39;s very dramatic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said in confusion. After taking the business card home, the whole family studied it, and the next day they took her to Chongqing for an interview and entered the crew&#39;s training camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of chance is like having the opportunity to learn dance when I was 11 years old. During recess, a teacher from outside the school came and walked around, named a few students, and said he would wait nearby after the exercise. &quot;We are still doing radio gymnastics down there.&quot; Zhou Yiran danced and gestured, &quot;I was selected. Then they said seriously, we are from the dance academy, you have great advantages and innate conditions, we all think it is very good , I hope you will come.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She took the dance school&#39;s flyer home to her parents, and her mother went to discuss it with her aunt. After a round of discussion, she decided to let Zhou Yiran learn to dance. After that, she really studied classical dance for nine years without stopping. Daily practice is boring and unbearable. “I can only grit my teeth and persevere, and then over time, I will really get used to it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Zhou Yiran didn’t worry about decisions and results, even though he was training with the same batch She was never able to star in that drama after she was born. She just felt it was very fresh, a life different from practicing hard in the dance studio all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I am a late bloomer when it comes to such a big life decision. I have never considered the proposition of life. Even if I don’t find a job after graduation, I am not in a hurry. I will follow myself more. On the day of the graduation performance, Zhou Yiran finished dancing &quot;Red Lips&quot; and ushered in the highlight of his life. She knew this wasn&#39;t the end for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She knew that she didn’t want to be a dance teacher or dancer, but she just didn’t know what to do. There was a scene in the TV series &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot; in which she later starred: Zhao Sanyue was idle at home for a year. After an argument with her mother, she left home and moved to rent a bed in a B&amp;B. She was lying on the bed, filled with resentment and doubts. &quot;Why can&#39;t we let people who like to work work, let people who like to lie down lie down, roll as hard as they want, and practice as much as they want to become Buddhas.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only Zhao Sanyue&#39;s confusion, but also Zhou Yiran&#39;s of confusion. &quot;Before graduation, I had an idea, play, really.&quot; But as she grew up, she vaguely felt another thing, &quot;Don&#39;t lie down, the meaning of life still has to move.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 , the online drama &quot;The Sky of the Wind Dog&quot; was broadcast, in which Zhou Yiran played a girl named &quot;Dali Jiao&quot;. &quot;Dali Jiao&quot; is the only girl in Daxing Village. She is born with supernatural powers, speaks loudly, is straightforward and has a quick mind. This character is so deeply rooted in the hearts of the people that Zhou Yiran is often asked by people he has just met, why are you different from what you imagined? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Yiran&#39;s natural aura is just like what director Li Mo, who she worked with, later said about her: &quot;I have always felt that she is a very spiritual actor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Not long after finishing the filming of &quot;The Sky of the Wind Dog&quot;, Zhou still received the script of the movie &quot;Crossing the Angry Sea&quot; directed by Cao Baoping, playing the role of Jin Lina, an international student who was killed in a foreign country, the ultimate crazy girl. She started taking language classes and going to bookstores every day, &quot;just like going to KFC or McDonald&#39;s to do homework when she was a kid.&quot; She went to sushi restaurants, drugstores, or to the homes of international students to chat, so that she could feel the characters, understand, empathize, and express them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2019, the filming of the movie started. Zhou still sometimes had to put on special effects makeup for five or six hours, lie in the morgue of the funeral home, or be forced to the edge of the balcony with his body hanging in the air. &quot;I felt like I was being squeezed dry at the scene.&quot; But before the filming is completed, Zhou Yiran&#39;s only worry is still whether he will be replaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, it seems that all the big turning points were decided by my mother for me, but in fact, everything I did later was my own idea.&quot; Zhou Yiran said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since entering the industry, Zhou Yiran has participated in many movies and TV series. In March 2023, she won the 36th Huading Award for Best Actress in a Chinese Drama Series for &quot;Sanyue Has a New Job&quot;. &quot;When the award was announced, I couldn&#39;t believe those words were true.&quot; So far. , Zhou still felt, &quot;This is definitely a milestone for me. I like the sense of solidity of taking one step at a time. This is also a huge force that pushes me to continue the next step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Growing up is farewell&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhao Sanyue in &quot;Sanyue has a new job&quot; You resisted working, which overlaps with what you said about your mentality when you graduated, but you also felt that you couldn&#39;t lie down. Why did you feel that you couldn&#39;t lie down? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The word &quot;lying down&quot; was not popular at that time. At that time, people would think that lying down was an inactive behavior. You still have to turn around, only then will there be new opportunities or surprises, only then will there be hope and some new discoveries. And at that age, you basically can’t lie down, you are very energetic, and you have to move. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was the environment like when you were growing up? Woolen cloth? What imprint has dance practice left on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was a child, my environment was relatively primitive. I would often get in touch with nature. I would always finish my homework quickly. Then I went downstairs to play with friends of the same age, growing up relatively freely. Dance is very challenging, and you can find the meaning of perseverance in dance. For example, pulling a ligament is a step-by-step process that cannot be accomplished overnight. If you don&#39;t do it for a long time, it will become stiff. Some of the characters I honed in dance still help me a lot in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are your fun stories growing up? Can you share? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The things I played when I was a child are different from the things kids play now. For example, pretending to be a household, now all the pots and pans are It was mini and very delicate, but at that time I went outside with my friends to build a stove with stones, using wild grasses and the like as vegetables, and leaves as tableware. It was very original. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I grow up, I will travel after graduation. Going to each city to experience the local cultural characteristics is also a way for me to relax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think about the outside world describing you as having &quot;aura&quot;? thing? Where do you think &quot;reiki&quot; comes from? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If I want to talk about my impression of Reiki, it is that everything has animism. When integrated into nature and into this world, different lives will actually have their own behaviors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether for personal growth or as an actor, self Cognition plays a very important role in this. I’m curious, has your self-perception changed or been updated in the past two years? Why did such a change occur? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am a slow-tempered person and a late bloomer. All major decisions in life are made with my family, even teething. They were two months later than other children of the same age. Until they graduated from college, they were quite heartless and immersed in their own world. I just focus on what I want to do, and rarely step out to look at my life or even my plans from God’s perspective. But in the past two years, my understanding will be more objective, and I will not be as immersed in my own world as before, although in fact it is happier! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I am very satisfied now, because growing up is saying goodbye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any plans or expectations for the future? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhou Yiran: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I hope to live a good life while taking care of my work. You can continue to challenge different types of roles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“很多男生一个引体向上都做不了”——部分高校大学生身体素质下降现象调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261292]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I was dangling on the horizontal bar and couldn’t pull up even a pull-up. I ran 800 meters in more than 5 minutes. Mi went upstairs and her legs were trembling...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from &quot;Xinhua Viewpoint&quot; recently visited some colleges and universities and found that the physical fitness of some students is worrying. Many boys find it difficult to do pull-ups and cannot do long jumps while standing. Many students lack explosive power in sprinting and have a &quot;fear of long-distance running.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Basic Standards for Physical Education in Colleges and Universities&quot; issued by the Ministry of Education in 2014 requires strengthening the management of physical education in schools, innovating education and teaching methods, guiding students to exercise scientifically, conducting physical health tests on all students every year, and guiding students Carry out targeted physical exercise. How to implement relevant requirements and continuously improve the physical fitness of college students? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;No energy&quot; &quot;Can&#39;t run&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;40% of the boys in our school failed to score in the pull-up event in the physical test, and many boys could not do any of them. The excellent rate of physical tests is declining every year.&quot; The person in charge of the physical education department of a university in Shandong said that more than ten years ago, most of the boys You can get 10 or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter once went to Yunnan University to conduct on-site research on the physical examination class. Most of the boys&#39; 1000-meter scores were below the passing mark; a girl in a certain class ran 800 meters, and in the last 50 meters, it was obviously very difficult. After crossing the finish line, she bent her back with a painful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259555&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In November 2021, girls from Yunnan University ran 800 meters. (Imposed photo) Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin, director of the Key Laboratory of Sports and Physical Health of the Ministry of Education at Beijing Sport University, once participated in the revision of the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and has long been concerned about the physical fitness of college students. Health status. &quot;Even though the passing standards for some projects have been lowered based on the students&#39; physical condition, the physical test results are still unsatisfactory,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin said that taking the university men&#39;s 1,000 meters as an example, the 60-minute pass in 1989 was 3 minutes and 55 seconds, and in 2014 it was 4 minutes and 32 seconds, a decrease of 37 seconds. This is equivalent to the fact that students who just passed the long-distance race in 1989 have reached the finish line, while students in 2014 are still running hundreds of meters away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the results of the Eighth National Student Physical Fitness and Health Survey released by the Ministry of Education showed that college students’ physical fitness is seriously declining, and problems such as obesity and lack of endurance are prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A physical education teacher in Beijing said that in order to avoid physical examinations, some students will buy &quot;medical records&quot; and pretend to be sick to take leave, claiming that they have hydrops in the knee joints and meniscus damage. &quot;We cannot distinguish the authenticity of the &#39;medical records&#39; one by one, and we are also afraid that students will have accidents, so the number of students exempted from the test remains high.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some students even find &quot;shooters&quot; to pass the physical test. The reporter saw on social media that some college students posted &quot;asking for a substitute test&quot; or &quot;take the test&quot;, mainly focusing on middle and long-distance running and other events. Some college students said that on the one hand, they are looking for a &quot;substitute&quot; because of their poor physical fitness, and on the other hand, because the physical test scores are linked to the evaluation of excellence and awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Why has physical fitness declined? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s investigation found that the decline in physical fitness of college students is not only due to students’ unwillingness to exercise, but also related to the fact that some colleges and universities do not pay attention to physical tests and have unreasonable physical education classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities do not strictly implement the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and do not pay attention to physical tests. According to the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot;, when students from ordinary high schools, secondary vocational schools and ordinary colleges and universities graduate, those whose test scores do not reach 50 points will be treated as completed or dropped out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the sports department of many colleges and universities said that due to various considerations, this regulation is not strictly implemented in many colleges and universities, and some even directly ignore it, causing students to have psychological problems with physical exercise and testing. slack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin revealed that in response to random inspections and reviews of college students&#39; physical health tests, some colleges and universities learned that when the expert team came, they would specifically look for students with good sports scores to cooperate, resulting in distortion of the physical test data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities have unreasonable physical education courses. To improve the physical quality of college students, college physical education classes play an indispensable role. The reporter&#39;s investigation found that the current physical education courses in many colleges and universities are similar, out of touch with the sports needs of college students, and affect their enthusiasm for class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nowadays, physical education classes basically still take track, field, football, basketball, etc. on the playground, which is similar to more than ten years ago.” Some college students reported that young people now like yoga, exercise for fat loss, and outdoor development. There are almost no such &quot;new physical education classes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhang Yimin, compared with the physical education and health curriculum standards for primary and secondary school students, there is no unified curriculum standard for physical education classes in colleges and universities. Many undergraduate colleges usually only offer physical education classes in the first and second grades, and students have obviously insufficient time for physical exercise and poor results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Education’s student physical health sampling review data shows that as of 2020, the failure rate of college students is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some college students are not willing to exercise. The interviewed physical education teacher said that some students were playing mobile phones on the side of the playground during physical education class. “In the past, students were often seen fighting for space on the football field, but now there are only a few people here and there.” “During morning exercise time, there are very few students doing exercise”…&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Li Jinglei, a graduate student at a university in Shandong, said that there are no physical education classes at the graduate level of the school, and sports are all dependent on individuals. Only one-tenth of the students in the class do regular physical exercise, and even if they want to play basketball, there are not enough people. Either it’s too hot in the summer and too cold in the winter, or there are other entertainment activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some college students interviewed even said: &quot;If you are too lazy to walk to the cafeteria to eat, why do you exercise?&quot; &quot;How can you go for a morning jog when you can&#39;t even get up to attend professional classes at 8 o&#39;clock in the morning?&quot; Is it fun or is surfing the Internet boring?&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Take multiple measures to improve the physical fitness of college students&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewee said, Improving the physical fitness of college students not only requires &quot;self-pressure&quot; of college students, but also requires joint promotion by relevant departments and schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that relevant standards should be strictly implemented to increase students&#39; attention. In 2021, the &quot;strictest physical education regulations&quot; issued by Yunnan University have triggered heated discussions on the Internet: starting from freshmen enrolling in the fall of 2021, if they fail the physical test in any academic year, they will not receive a diploma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not the first initiative of Yunnan University, but a regulation of the Ministry of Education.” Wang Zongping, dean of the School of Physical Education of Yunnan University, said that after the school strictly implemented relevant regulations, the passing rate of students’ physical examinations has increased significantly, from 2018 to 2018. 68.6% increased to 90.3% in 2022. &quot;Now students pay more and more attention to physical exercise. Every night at eight or nine o&#39;clock, they can be seen exercising on the school playground.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259556&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On November 21, 2023, the male 1000-meter physical test site of Yunnan University. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Bo, director of the Physical Education Department of Tsinghua University, suggested that schools can offer more special courses based on their own conditions to help students increase their interest in sports. At present, Tsinghua University insists on offering physical education courses for four-year undergraduate students, involving more than 50 courses such as competitive sports, leisure sports, traditional ethnic sports and physical therapy courses, and offers sports elective courses for graduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the composition and evaluation methods of physical education classes should be optimized to prevent falsification of physical tests. Cheng Shouyun, a physical education teacher at Hefei University of Technology, said that the school has carried out an integrated reform of physical education inside and outside the classroom, and has included &quot;physical fitness&quot; as one of the required modules in the &quot;Second Classroom Transcript&quot; as a hard indicator for student graduation. Physical education class scores are linked to students&#39; extracurricular exercise. In-class tests and final assessments in physical education classes account for 60 points, theoretical study accounts for 10 points, and extracurricular fitness accounts for 30 points. In extracurricular fitness, running exercises account for no less than 60%. Other appointments can be made through the smart system. Sports should not exceed 40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prevent fraud such as taking exams on behalf of others, Hefei University of Technology adopts the method of verifying student ID cards, and the test can only be carried out when the person and ID are combined; Anhui University uses dual authentication of ID card and facial recognition detection. Once a substitute exam is found, The phenomenon will be investigated seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is particularly important to integrate physical education with education to develop good exercise habits. At Tsinghua University, undergraduate freshmen will gather together to experience the sports tradition and spirit of &quot;without sports, there is no Tsinghua University&quot; through the &quot;First Physical Education Lesson&quot;. There are also many students who have found their favorite sports and gained their own sense of accomplishment and belonging by participating in the Freshman Barefoot Games and Campus Marathon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Colleges and universities can help students master 1 to 2 sports skills and develop lifelong exercise habits through measures that suit their own characteristics, and create a campus that is open to all students, runs through the entire process, and educates people in all aspects Sports culture.&quot; Liu Bo said: &quot;The inherent educational value of physical exercise can be transformed into excellent qualities promoted in social life, which will benefit students throughout their lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 12:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国全额缴清联合国会费，缴费比例33年增长19倍丨漫热点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261308]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;776&quot; height=&quot;10000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259589&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[凯雷出售“麦当劳中国”：新基金募集压力“倒逼”项目退出？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261290]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Carlyle, a large global PE institution, once again &quot;takes action&quot;, but this time he is selling assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, McDonald&#39;s Global agreed to acquire Carlyle&#39;s 28% stake in McDonald&#39;s China Mainland, Hong Kong and Macau Strategic Cooperation Company (hereinafter referred to as &quot;McDonald&#39;s China&quot;). After the transaction is completed, McDonald&#39;s Global, as a minority shareholder, will increase its shareholding ratio from 20% to 48%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the acquisition requires regulatory approval and is expected to be completed in the first quarter of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, the acquisition price is US$1.8 billion, and Carlyle will receive a return of approximately 6.7 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If it weren’t for the current VC/PE market project withdrawal slump, Carlyle might have been able to sell it at a higher price.” A partner from a domestic PE institution lamented to reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters have learned from various sources that the industry generally believes that Carlyle’s sale of McDonald’s China shares at a relatively low price is likely to be closely related to the current difficulty in exiting VC/PE market projects and its sluggish performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of November, Carlyle announced its third quarter financial report of this year, which showed that the total revenue for the quarter was only US$562 million, a simultaneous decrease of about 50%, and the net profit was only US$81.3 million, a year-on-year decrease of 71.05%. The main reason for Carlyle&#39;s revenue decline in the quarter was that it was difficult to exit projects, which resulted in a 76% drop in performance income from exited investment projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Carlyle’s fundraising scale this year has basically been the same as in 2022, but far lower than the same period in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“To change this situation, Carlyle urgently needs more project exit cases, but given the current sluggish IPO market and the increased risk of a U.S. economic recession, Carlyle may have to sell at a lower price More high-quality projects and create more project exit cases to win LPs’ commitment to Carlyle’s new fund.” Analyzed the partner of a domestic PE institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, project mergers and acquisitions between industrial capital and PE are quite common during periods of increased macroeconomic fluctuations. However, this time industrial capital had the upper hand in M&amp;A negotiations because during the previous period when the Federal Reserve implemented extremely loose monetary policies, industrial capital raised a large amount of funds by issuing bonds or borrowing from banks at extremely low interest rates; in comparison, PE However, due to the sluggish IPO market and the sharp interest rate hikes by the Federal Reserve in recent years, institutions have encountered difficulties in project exit and new fund raising. As a result, PE institutions have to sell high-quality assets to industrial capital at low prices to create more project exit cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nowadays, industrial capital with abundant funds has become the taker for PE institutions eager to exit the project, but the former will also force the PE institutions to make more concessions in order to obtain more generous bargain hunting profits. &quot;A M&amp;A fund manager pointed out to reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;behind&quot; Carlyle&#39;s sale of McDonald&#39;s China shares&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Reporters have learned that in April, the market began to hear rumors that Carlyle was planning to sell its shares in McDonald&#39;s China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, people familiar with the matter revealed that Carlyle and Trustar Capital, a private equity subsidiary of CITIC Capital Holdings Co., Ltd., are offering to sell part of McDonald’s China Company for US$4 billion. Among them, Carlyle Lei will sell 28% of McDonald&#39;s China Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person familiar with the matter also said that Carlyle and Xinchen Capital were in discussions with the Government of Singapore Investment Corporation (GIC) and Abu Dhabi’s sovereign wealth fund Mubadala Investment Co, hoping that they could Participated in the acquisition, and their overall valuation of McDonald&#39;s China Company was US$10 billion, that is, the 28% stake held by Carlyle was valued at US$2.8 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it was McDonald’s Global that finally made the move. And Carlyle is the only one selling equity in McDonald&#39;s China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of many PE industry insiders, McDonald’s China is actually an important high-quality asset in Carlyle’s PE investment portfolio. In 2017, CITIC and Carlyle acquired McDonald&#39;s businesses in mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau for US$2.08 billion and obtained 20-year franchise rights in the two places. CITIC and Carlyle formulated a plan for McDonald&#39;s China The &quot;Five-Year Plan&quot; strives to expand the number of McDonald&#39;s restaurants to 4,500 by 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, McDonald&#39;s has more than 5,500 stores in mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau. In recent years, McDonald&#39;s China sales have maintained a growth of more than 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They believe that an important factor that forced Carlyle to decide to sell this &quot;high-quality asset&quot; was weak performance. The recent third-quarter financial report released by Carlyle showed that both total revenue and net profit experienced significant year-on-year declines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This will definitely affect Carlyle’s new fund-raising.” The aforementioned domestic PE institutional partner believes. Normally, when a PE institution plans to issue a new fund to raise funds, it will first return most of the investment principal and income of the previous fund to investors (LPs) to boost their interest in continuing to invest in the new fund. confidence. On the other hand, if the previous fund project exits slowly and cannot return sufficient principal income to LPs, it will affect the rise of LPs to continue investing. In this case, PE institutions can only sell high-quality projects to industrial capital at low prices to create more project exit cases and return principal and interest, in order to win the &quot;commitment&quot; of LPs to continue investing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sharp contrast, in July this year, large European PE institutions completed the fundraising of their ninth M&amp;A fund, with a scale of 26 billion euros, setting a record for the largest fundraising of a M&amp;A fund. This is mainly due to the fact that CVC has achieved the exit of a number of large-scale investment projects in the past year, including the sale of Messer Industries shares to Messer and the sale of energy exploration company Neptune Energy Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rob Lucas, managing partner of CVC, said that the exit of these projects will help promote the fundraising of new funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Obviously, Carlyle’s management team also realizes that without enough project exit cases and return of principal interests, the new phase of fund raising will face many challenges, especially it will be difficult to convince LPs Continue to inject capital.&quot; The domestic PE institution partner said frankly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;Industrial capital is waiting for PE to make more &quot;concessions&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to selling equity in McDonald&#39;s China, Carlyle has recently been operating multiple sales projects to further increase its Number of project exits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, there were market rumors that Carlyle was seeking to sell German software company SER and Japanese cosmetics supplier Tokiwa Corp. At the same time, Carlyle also plans to sell off its shares in AmbioPharm, a peptide active pharmaceutical ingredient CDMO (contract development and manufacturing organization) company, valuing the company at approximately US$1 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of industry insiders, this means that Carlyle is selling more projects to quickly reverse the decline in financial performance and return more investment principal profits to LPs. Earn their “commitment” to continue investing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the current economic environment, it will not be easy to sell the above projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the first six months of this year, global PE funds received less than US$37.7 billion through exit channels such as portfolio listings and acquisitions, falling to the lowest level in the past 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Even though the market recently expects the Federal Reserve to cut interest rates soon and the U.S. economy remains resilient, industrial capital is not enthusiastic about acquisitions.&quot; The person in charge of the above-mentioned M&amp;A fund told reporters. The reasons are: First, more and more industrial capitals are not optimistic about the future global economic development prospects, and would rather retain more funds to &quot;overwinter&quot; than to rush into mergers and acquisitions and encounter the risk of M&amp;A failure; secondly, some industrial capitals also know that PE Institutions are eager to create project exit cases to return principal income to LP (for the purpose of raising funds for a new phase of funds), and are waiting for PE institutions to further lower the project sales price, thereby obtaining higher bargaining returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This forces more and more large PE institutions to make more concessions on price in order to complete project mergers and acquisitions and exit as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, Tiger Fund transferred its remaining shares in Flipkart, a large Indian e-commerce company, to Walmart for a total transaction value of US$1.4 billion. This corresponds to a valuation of Flipkart of US$35 billion, which is lower than Tiger Fund’s previous investment in Flipkart. Valuation of Flipkart at US$38 billion in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Currently, most industrial capital with abundant funds are not eager to make acquisitions. They are still evaluating whether acquisitions can have an immediate boost in improving corporate performance.&quot; The head of the M&amp;A fund said bluntly . This has made PE institutions even more anxious, because the global IPO market downturn in the past two years has prevented PE institutions from returning considerable principal returns to LPs, which is causing LPs to question the project exit capabilities of PE institutions. Once this situation continues, more and more LPs will eventually vote with their feet for PE institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is foreseeable that in order to achieve more project mergers and acquisitions and exits, many large global PE institutions can only continue to lower their status and lower project sales prices, and strive to create more project exit cases. This must not be allowed. LPs continue to question their ability to exit projects, because this will greatly weaken the industry reputation and image of these large PE institutions in the VC/PE market.&quot; He analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“23000塔卡薪资抗议”：国际大牌背后的孟加拉国“血汗工厂”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261306]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Working 8 hours a day during the day, there are usually 2 hours of paid overtime. I haven&#39;t asked for it in six years of work. Leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem, a machine operator at a garment factory in Gazipur, Bangladesh, told Southern Weekend reporters that although there is meager overtime pay, if workers forcefully ask for leave, they are likely to be laid off verbally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Bangladesh government adjusted the minimum wage standard in 2018, the monthly income of garment workers has remained at 8,300 taka (equivalent to RMB 530) for a long time. This money can hardly afford to live with inflation and high prices due to the new crown epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Bangladesh’s cheap labor has brought huge profits. According to statistics from the National Bureau of Statistics of Bangladesh, in 2022, the production value of the textile industry will account for more than 13% of Bangladesh&#39;s total GDP, and the country relies on clothing exports to make US$55 billion in profits every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the silent volcano erupted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/1706045b48.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/1706045b48.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259581&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;During this round of protests, Bangladeshi police are using sticks to drive away female garment workers. Picture provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October 24 to November 14, 2023, tens of thousands of ordinary Bangladeshi workers launched a &quot;Taka 23,000&quot; protest in Dhaka, the capital of Bangladesh, and its surrounding cities. Wage protest” (equivalent to RMB 1,472). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Six years ago, after passing a mechanical operation test and a simple interview, Fahem entered this garment factory. Because he is engaged in a more technical position, his salary is 10,500 taka (equivalent to RMB 672) per month, which is slightly higher than the 8,300 taka of an ordinary garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Most garment workers are women, and their situation is even more difficult.&quot; Fahem said. When Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact several female garment workers, they were unable to get a reply because they were unable to communicate in English. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem mentioned that some female workers don’t even know how to type on their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/73ff85113b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/73ff85113b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259582&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The income of female garment workers in Bangladesh is only half that of female workers in India and Cambodia. The latter two also have a large number of female garment workers in their countries. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem did not directly participate in this &quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest.&quot; The city of Gazipur where he is located is a textile industry city in Bangladesh, 25 kilometers north of the capital Dhaka. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early November, Bangladesh’s Minister of Labor and Employment Sufian announced that the minimum wage for workers would be raised to 12,500 taka starting from December 1. Bangladeshi textile workers hope that employers can triple the minimum wage to 23,000 taka - garment workers believe that 23,000 taka is the baseline for maintaining food and clothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gazipur, Asuriya and other industrial cities are the core areas of the &quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest&quot;. Police in Asuriya, Bangladesh, said that more than 10,000 local workers protested along the highway. During the protests, about 300 factories closed down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least four workers were killed and thousands injured in violent protests, according to the Bangladesh Garment Workers Federation. The police have launched 40 criminal cases so far, with more than 20,000 workers accused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/9ca9fdd311.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/9ca9fdd311.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259583&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Bangladesh is one of the very few Muslim countries that allows women to work outside the home. They can work in various places such as banks and universities. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;More than 100,000 workers across Bangladesh participated in the wage increase movement.&quot; Tohidur Rahman, chairman of the Bangladesh Garment Workers Federation, is one of the organizers of this protest one. He told Southern Weekend reporters that every year, he submits a salary increase plan to the Bangladesh Ministry of Labor and Employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Individual workers dare not make any demands to their employers for fear of being fired.” As one of the representatives of the local union, Fahem did not go directly to the streets. He was avoiding arrest by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When prices and rents rise, the salary cannot sustain my life, and I cannot lose this job.&quot; Fahem told Southern Weekend reporters that in order to support his family, he can only hold on to his &quot;job.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Female Workers in Bangladesh&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Being a garment worker is a common occupation in Bangladesh. &quot;Most people only need to receive very little training to stay and work.&quot; Jon Hossain, a Bangladeshi, told Southern Weekend reporters that his friends would also choose textile engineering when they went to college. major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Bangladesh, more than thirty private and public universities train textile industry graduates every year, further increasing the number of technical talents in the textile industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the factory where Fahem works, it is more common to see female garment workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a study by the Ethical Trade Initiative, more than 50% of the 4 million textile industry workers in Bangladesh in 2022 will be women. In the 1980s, female workers accounted for as high as 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/7d7b73aa51.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/7d7b73aa51.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259584&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Lunch for Bangladeshi female workers. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sewing edges, cutting threads, and packing boxes. For 10 hours a day, female workers will sit in the hot workshop and repeat these processes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Including overtime, Rima needs to work 62 hours a week. The weekly output of her production line must reach 1,000 pieces of clothing.&quot; American author Maxine Bedart&#39;s book &quot;Amplified Desire&quot; A book chronicles the work of Rima, a Bangladeshi garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book mentions that every working day, Rima can only go to the toilet after completing her production target. If she falls behind, her manager is nearby, loudly urging her to work faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Labor rights activists in Bangladesh and the United States believe that Bangladesh’s garment industry provides young women with opportunities to move from the margins of society to the center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hazy, a female worker, once worked in a garment factory, sewing shirt pockets, &quot;every day until she couldn&#39;t sew anymore.&quot; But she still &quot;loves it here.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can decide my own life, and I can also make money to support my family.&quot; Hartz believes. Some relatives and friends praised her as &quot;the only one in the family who earns a salary.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While being squeezed by their employers, Bangladeshi garment workers also face potential safety hazards at work. The collapse of the Rana Plaza garment factory in Savar, Bangladesh, in 2013 killed more than 1,130 people, making it one of the world&#39;s worst industrial disasters&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of salary, the monthly salary of 8,300 taka for female workers is far from enough to live on. In a study on &quot;Basic Rights to a Living Wage&quot; by the U.S. non-profit organization Microfinance Opportunities and the C&amp;amp;A Apparel Foundation, the income of female garment workers in Bangladesh is only half that of female workers in India and Cambodia. The latter two also have a large number of domestic workers. Garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f17f5bedbb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f17f5bedbb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259585&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;In addition to working, they also have to bear the burden of family. Since the Bangladesh government adjusted the minimum wage standard in 2018, the monthly income of garment workers has remained at 8,300 taka (equivalent to RMB 530) for a long time. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bangladesh is one of the very few Muslim countries that allows women to work outside the home. They can work in various places such as banks and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina is a woman, and she has provided more preferential policies for women in Bangladesh.&quot; Jon Hou, Ph.D. in International Investment Law, China University of Political Science and Law, Bangladeshi Sain told Southern Weekend reporters that there is no tuition fee for women in Bangladesh to go to college, while men have to pay. &quot;It&#39;s just that many women get married early and give up their studies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hussein smiled and said, if in the factory If there were more male workers, it would be easier for protests to break out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who will bear the cost of salary increase? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bangladesh, a South Asian country with a population of less than 200 million, is one of the largest clothing manufacturers in the world. According to statistics from the Bangladesh Manufacturers Association, nearly 3,500 garment factories in the country employ 4 million people, and they supply well-known European and American brands such as Levi&#39;s, Zara and H&amp;amp;M. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics, the inflation rate will rise to 9% between 2022 and 2023, the highest value in 12 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unequal wages have attracted the attention of international big names. In September 2023, 18 brands including Levi&#39;s, H&amp;amp;M, Gap, and Puma wrote to Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, calling on him to re-establish minimum wage standards to meet the basic needs of workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/d03de605c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;486&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/d03de605c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;A group of garment workers gathered on the outskirts of Bangladesh in an attempt to protest against unequal wages. Picture provided by respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We recommend that the Bangladesh government adopt an annual minimum wage review mechanism to keep pace with macroeconomic changes.&quot; The letter stated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Bangladesh government reviews the minimum wage every five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If you want to support workers’ demands for wage increases, clothing brands in European and American countries also need to increase order prices.” Farooq Hassan, chairman of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association, lamented that although these brands have publicly They shout support, but when costs rise, they threaten to &quot;buy goods from other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2023, a study of 1,000 garment factories in Bangladesh by the University of Aberdeen in Scotland and the initiative &quot;Transforming Trade&quot; found that more than half of the factories experienced at least one of the following situations: order cancellation, refusal of payment , price reduction or delayed payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also found that 37% of brand companies engaged in &quot;unfair behavior&quot;, including H&amp;amp;M, Gap, etc. After the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, some companies still want to order at the original price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large brands such as H&amp;amp;M do not directly open factories in Bangladesh. They sign contracts with local factory owners. Factory owners need to pay all upfront costs, including raw materials, factory equipment, and worker wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For many small garment factories, it is very difficult to raise wages for employees.” Bangladeshi Jon Hussain told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of Hussein&#39;s friends sold part of his property and opened a small clothing factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/33e9261a6c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/33e9261a6c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259587&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Bangladeshi police patrol near the factory. Picture provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The export price has been negotiated between the factory and the brand. If employees need a salary increase, many small factories will close.&quot; Hussein mentioned that due to insufficient production levels , most small factories are also unable to purchase automation equipment, and once workers take to the streets, the factories are forced to stop production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protests forced the closure of hundreds of factories. Kalpona Akter, president of the Bangladesh Garment and Industrial Workers Federation, mentioned that the suspended factories supply almost all well-known European and American brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The low cost of international FMCG brands is not unrelated to the low income of workers in exporting countries. When brands seek lower prices from OEMs, worker wages will only stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the COVID-19 epidemic, international brands canceled approximately US$40 billion in orders from factories around the world, and factories and workers paid the price. At that time, the workers&#39; rights alliance launched many labor movements on social media, some of which claimed to have caused major brands to repay nearly US$22 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起诉“停止大象表演”败诉，野生动物表演等于虐待吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261296]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新嫂燕球丨云间夜话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261246]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fish Balls. Visual China | Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/b6156a5182.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/24/b6156a5182.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fish balls. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Songjiang River in Shanghai was called &quot;Yunjian&quot; in ancient times. When I first moved to Songjiang, it felt a bit like &quot;between the clouds&quot; - empty and silent, misty and deserted. There are no acquaintances. Naturally, there were no familiar delicacies. I thought I would start a lonely life and start everything from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, I was suddenly called by my name on the quiet road that day. I couldn&#39;t help but be startled. I took a closer look at a fat lady, but I didn&#39;t recognize her, but she smiled and said, I often watch on TV. I see you here, why are you here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turned out to be Jin Mei, my childhood neighbor. Hearing that her mother was still alive, she couldn&#39;t help but be surprised: New sister-in-law, is she still there? ! It&#39;s about ninety, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ninety-seven!&quot; Jin Mei replied. I immediately asked to see her. Because when she was a child, she was a popular idol in the alley. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;New Sister-in-law&quot; is probably called famous by a group of old people. The reason must be that she was a bride in the alley back then. It is said that many people want to see a new wife who can&#39;t cook and make a fool of herself, but the new sister-in-law&#39;s skills make many older people feel inferior to her. What makes many women obey the most is that she actually raised eight boys and one girl in one go. Her youngest daughter Jinmei is my classmate. Behind her back, the old ladies call her &quot;Laikehang&quot; (a kind of foreign chicken that is very good at laying eggs). ). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although her ancestral home is Shaoxing, she is more proficient than ordinary people when it comes to &quot;being a good person&quot;. When people in Shanghai say that people &quot;can be a good person&quot;, they are praising a kind of &quot;intelligent frugality&quot;, which is left-brained and right-brained. Living a life by discussing things is not just living a stingy life. For example, using mature loofah tendons to wash dishes is far better than sponges, but the price is negligibly cheap; cutting discarded sweatshirts into strips of cloth to tie into mops is much better absorbent than yarn; buying meat at a &quot;small market&quot; You can be precise enough to buy only 2 taels, which is enough to fry shredded pork for a meal. This is in contrast to the honest and honest people in the north who often buy half a fan, forming a &quot;precision&quot;. When you go to a restaurant to eat, most of the leftovers have to be packed up and re-cooked at home, called &quot;zaluo soup&quot;. The most typical one is the invention of the &quot;fake leader&quot; in Shanghai, which uses the least amount of fabric to maintain the greatest dignity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But these &quot;life skills&quot; are just &quot;mere&quot; in the eyes of the new sister-in-law. She has her own unique skills, and they are beyond everyone&#39;s imagination, which makes the whole alley admire her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin’s sister-in-law’s hometown has a lot of bamboo shoots, and every year a lot of bamboo shoots are brought there by people. In order to preserve them, Xin’s sister-in-law always boils the bamboo shoots in a large pot of salted water, cuts the cooked bamboo shoots into pieces, and air-dries them. The old soup used to cook the bamboo shoots is not changed, and is cooked batch by batch. Finally, the old soup is slightly thick, and the large bottle and large wine bottle are poured in sequentially. The whole process does not touch the water, and the wine bottle is sealed with oil paper. This is the &quot;soy sauce&quot; for cooking in her family. &quot;. They call it &quot;bamboo shoot oil&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, good red soy sauce cost 27 cents per catty, white soy sauce (fresh soy sauce) cost 21 cents per catty, and MSG was even more expensive. But with the bamboo shoot oil, her family never buys soy sauce and MSG. My grandmother often orders me to go to her house and buy a bottle. The freshness is better than the soy sauce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new sister-in-law also pickles bacon every year, adds coarse salt and pepper, and pours some sorghum wine. The strange thing is that she is reluctant to throw away the reddish marinated meat water. She &quot;makes meat with meat&quot; and uses the marinated meat water to cook braised pork. Just add a little red soy sauce to make the meat very red and fragrant. Neighboring, the kind of fragrance between &quot;bad&quot; and &quot;wax&quot; is almost indescribable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what we miss the most is her &quot;Yanqiu&quot; - the new sister-in-law Yanqiu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Specially difficult period&quot;, considering that her family is a &quot;super-large family&quot; of 11 people, eight boys, and eight &quot;tiger&quot;, it is natural that there is a serious shortage of meat resources. Anyone who wants to touch big meat Their thoughts were not only &quot;immoral&quot;, but directly &quot;cheating&quot;, but the new sister-in-law&#39;s &quot;Shaoxing-style wisdom&quot; actually solved them as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time she stopped at the market, a storm would rush through her eyes - in the fish stall, there were dead white fish (silver carp), as cheap as mud, the most undesirable, and the new sister-in-law would kill them with a move. &quot;Here are two, big ones!&quot; The stall owner was so flattered that he offered them at the lowest price. In the meat stall, people walked around the milk fat pork, the loosest fat on the pork belly, and the stall owner often felt worried about it. At this time, the new sister-in-law waved her pink arm and said, &quot;Two pounds here!&quot; The stall owner was like Feng Lunyin. Not only did he cut the meat wide, but he also charged the floor price, and often even refused to charge for the meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Mei and I love watching our new sister-in-law make swallow balls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw her quickly removing the scales, gills and internal organs of the fish, and then rinsed it clean. Then cut it in half from head to tail, remove the bones and large spines, cut off the head and belly of the fish (reserve for fish soup), leaving two large pieces of fish meat, skin side down, place on the chopping board and nail them For the fish tail, hold the sharp knife upright and scrape the fish meat from the outside inward. When the skin and red meat under the skin are left, the new sister-in-law said proudly, many people don’t understand and are greedy for this piece of red meat! In fact, you must not ask for red meat. The fishy smell comes from the red meat! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My new sister-in-law chopped the scraped fish meat repeatedly and finely, saying that all the fish bones were gone. Then I put it in a container, stirred it clockwise for a few minutes with two pairs of chopsticks, added salt, and stirred it until it bubbles. , then picked up the milk and fat meat. Chop the cooked milk fat pork and lard residue together, add starch and chopped green onion and ginger, then mix in the fish paste and mix well until thickened, and shape into fish balls. Because of the abundant raw materials, she made the fish balls larger. It is as big as a ping pong ball or even a tennis ball. It is cooked in a pot of boiling water for a while. It is as white and crystal clear as snow. It is as tender and smooth as tofu in the mouth. It is not fishy and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why we treat it as a swallow ball every time is because every time we can taste one first and squeal with joy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night was a carnival where the eight boys and her husband had a &quot;meat feast&quot; - when the big pot of swallow balls was served, the new sister-in-law had to use the spoon solemnly with a straight face. They were strictly allocated one by one. If it were left to them, it might be a dinner table accident with blood splattering three feet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the story is not over yet. The &quot;Eight Tigers&quot; had eaten all the swallow balls, and there must be a by-product of the swallow balls, &quot;fish soup&quot;, waiting for them the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After my new sister-in-law cooked the tripe that was chopped off yesterday, she removed the fish, removed the spines, chopped the fat meat into pieces, mixed it with the fish and added it to the soup. Add vinegar and salt. Sprinkle in a lot of celery leaves or minced garlic, the aroma is fragrant, fresh and slightly sour, and the big pot of brown rice is gone in an instant. It can be described as more than just &quot;dinner&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While being jealous, a group of old women headed by my grandma often commented quietly: This dish actually comes from Hangzhou cuisine. The most outstanding thing is that it uses the most unwanted &quot;trash&quot;. And make it delicious. Who wants this dead white fish? If it cannot be sold, it will rot; who will buy this fat meat? If it can&#39;t be sold, it can only be boiled in oil residue. But with her help, the New Year&#39;s Eve dinner can be served. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gradually, everyone put down their arrogance and asked the new sister-in-law for advice; gradually, the fish stalls and meat stalls in the vegetable market, those &quot;abandoned items&quot; that no one usually touched, were noticed... &lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Gradually, it became the most popular, affordable and nourishing home-cooked dish in our alley. The official name given to it by the neighbors was &quot;Xinsao Yanqiu&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many years have passed, the time has almost changed, and the alleys have disappeared, but how many generations, especially the &quot;eight tigers&quot; have grown up eating the cheapest and most delicious &quot;big meat&quot; , joining a job, getting married - and even getting older, my new sister-in-law is actually still alive! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I stood in front of her bed. To be honest, at ninety-seven, she was too old to remember me, but when she talked about her swallow balls, her eyeballs flashed a few times. He pursed his lips and said nonchalantly: &quot;...It&#39;s a pity that there was no oil at that time. In fact, it tastes better if it is deep-fried!...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>