<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[交通运输部：中秋国庆假期小型客车免收通行费]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257286]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 10 o&#39;clock today (September 21), the State Council Information Office held a press conference. Introduction: During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holidays in 2023, from September 29 to October 6, a total of 8 days, toll roads across the country will continue to waive tolls for small passenger cars with less than 7 seats (including 7 seats). The free period is September 29 0:00 to 24:00 on October 6. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[肖像被恶搞：当尊重企业家的认定与感受丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257226]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 14, the Beijing Cyberspace Administration of China released the &quot;Guidelines for reporting enterprise-related online infringement information&quot; on its WeChat account , classifying &quot;rumor information&quot;, &quot;leak information&quot; and &quot;insulting information&quot; as &quot;enterprise-related network infringement information&quot;. Among them, &quot;rumor information&quot; and &quot;leak information&quot; are relatively easy to understand, and the corresponding penalties include &quot;defamation&quot; and &quot;infringement of commercial secrets&quot;. In comparison, the definition of &quot;insulting information&quot; is much shorter: &quot;information that attacks and insults companies or entrepreneurs, spoofs portraits of entrepreneurs, maliciously associates with pornographic and vulgar topics, etc.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of the &quot;Guidelines for Reporting Enterprise-related Internet Infringement Information&quot; is to protect the legitimate rights and interests of enterprises and entrepreneurs, improve the efficiency of reporting enterprise-related infringement information, and maintain a good business environment. Among them, the formulation of &quot;spoofing entrepreneur portraits&quot; is more attention-grabbing and deserves in-depth analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the basis for &quot;spoofing entrepreneur portraits&quot; is &quot;online infringement information&quot;, which originates from Article 1019 of the &quot;Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, &quot;No organization or individual may vilify or defame, Or use information technology means to forge and infringe on the portrait rights of others.&quot; According to this law, &quot;spoofs of entrepreneur portraits&quot; will constitute infringement if they are proven to be &quot;uglified&quot; or &quot;forged.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, spoofing portraits of entrepreneurs is not necessarily directly equivalent to &quot;vilification&quot; or &quot;forgery.&quot; For example, if an entrepreneur&#39;s portrait is turned into an emoticon or a cartoon character, it does not necessarily constitute &quot;uglification&quot; or &quot;forgery&quot;. Compared with &quot;attacking and abusing entrepreneurs&quot;, &quot;spoof portraits&quot; also have elements of ridicule and humor, and are often beautified and praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the actual situation, most of the entrepreneurs spoofed by netizens are famous and successful entrepreneurs. They have strong industry influence and social popularity, and they are already public figures themselves. As public figures, entrepreneurs&#39; lives and work have attracted widespread attention, and their words and deeds are closely related to public interests. As a special group in society, the portraits of well-known entrepreneurs have become a piece of &quot;public knowledge&quot; well known to the public. As public figures, they also bear certain obligations of tolerance and bear certain derogation of interests in their portrait rights. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary to refine the identification criteria to determine whether &quot;parody images of entrepreneurs&#39; portraits&quot; constitute &quot;insulting information&quot; and &quot;corporate-related infringement information.&quot; This leads to the second question: How will entrepreneurs protect their rights once faced with &quot;spoof portrait pictures&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, complaints from public figures against netizens for “portrait rights infringement” are often concentrated in the entertainment industry. More than one entertainment star has been very angry about &quot;spoof portrait pictures&quot;, which has triggered many legal lawsuits. According to statistics from the &quot;Southern Metropolis Daily&quot; on April 18, 2023, the China Judgment Document Network disclosed 356 civil cases related to celebrities&#39; portrait rights in 2022. Among them, the proportion of celebrities winning the lawsuit is very high, &quot;Ge You complained about &#39;Ge You lying down&#39; &quot;It has an almost complete winning rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparatively speaking, entrepreneurs encounter spoof portraits. Almost no well-known entrepreneur can escape the &quot;spoof&quot; of netizens, such as Lei Jun&#39;s &quot;are you OK&quot; and Wang Jianlin&#39;s &quot; &quot;Don&#39;t worry about the hundreds of millions&quot;, Robin Li &quot;what&#39;s your problem&quot;, etc. However, the leading entrepreneurs who were pranked did not feel that this was an insult or infringement on themselves, and they did not take legal action. Not only that, some entrepreneurs will actively join in the spoof and use it as a marketing tool to get closer to consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the alleged infringement liability of &quot;spoof portrait pictures&quot;, most of them belong to personality rights disputes, and the most serious cases point to the &quot;crime of insult&quot;. Article 246 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China stipulates that the crime of insult refers to &quot;the use of violence or other methods to openly tarnish the reputation of others and the circumstances are serious.&quot; The crime of insult is a crime of circumstance. The perpetrator&#39;s behavior of openly insulting others must reach the level of &quot;serious circumstances&quot; to constitute a crime and be investigated. This crime falls under the category of &quot;no complaint, no action&quot;, that is, no action will be taken until a complaint is made, except for cases that seriously endanger social order and national interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If entrepreneurs themselves are spreading their own spoof portraits, emoticons and even ghost videos, it is naturally even less likely that the outside world will consider this to be an infringement of the entrepreneur. Therefore, as long as the entrepreneur himself does not feel dissatisfied, similar behavior should be tolerated. If an entrepreneur really believes that &quot;spoof pictures&quot; are insulting or infringing, then he certainly has the right to initiate legal proceedings and use legal weapons to protect his legitimate rights and interests like ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we can see that well-known entrepreneurs generally have a tolerant and generous attitude towards life when faced with attacks, abuses, and pranks. After all, compared with the turbulent waves of the business world, &quot;portraits being pranked&quot; are sometimes an extra boost for entrepreneurs and a small comment on the &quot;entrepreneurial spirit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[苦等五年，第二批罕见病目录公布：新增86个病种]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257274]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 13:15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/Cig8PapifnL34jPiIf4CiVkuwLzvF8PVvESVrRTB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/Cig8PapifnL34jPiIf4CiVkuwLzvF8PVvESV rRTB. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 7, 2022, Xiamen Maternal and Child Health Hospital, medical staff sampled rare diseases Noxinaxen Sodium Injection, a specific drug for spinal muscular atrophy, is ready to be injected into children. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 20, 2023, the official website of the National Health Commission announced the second batch of rare disease catalogs. Add 86 rare diseases such as achondroplasia to the catalog, and the registration date is September 18. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“(This is) something that everyone has been calling for for a long time.” For Huang Rufang, founder of the Coude Rare Disease Center, as well as many rare disease patients and related medical professionals, this is a five-year battle. Much eager waiting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2018, five departments including the National Health Commission jointly formulated the &quot;First Batch Rare Disease Catalog&quot;, which for the first time disclosed 121 rare diseases to the public in the form of a catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This catalog provides an important basis for various departments to formulate policies related to rare diseases. The health department organizes efforts to clarify diagnosis and treatment guidelines for these diseases one by one, and relies on industry organizations to carry out training for medical personnel to improve the standardized diagnosis and treatment of rare diseases. ability. At the same time, a series of supporting systems have been introduced to strengthen the research and development of rare disease-related drugs, accelerate review and approval, and access to medical insurance, which have greatly improved the current situation of rare disease diagnosis and treatment in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, a total of 207 rare diseases have been included in the two batches of rare disease catalogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/E5gEIt4kPP1SGOGXeuadq6Dpjbou9c1Y4Hh1lnJl.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;914&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/E5gEIt4kPP1SGOGXeuadq6Dpjbou9c1Y4Hh1lnJl.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251496&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Many I have never heard of the disease.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;To be honest, I have never heard of many diseases, and I don’t know what to say.&quot; Xing Huanping of Meier SMA Care Center saw She told Southern Weekend reporters after the second batch of rare disease catalogues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 20 million rare disease patients in China, the SMA (spinal muscular atrophy) patients helped by Xing Huanping are lucky to have technological breakthroughs from pharmaceutical companies and good opportunities from government reforms. In 2018, SMA was also included in the first batch of rare disease catalogs, and two innovative drugs for symptomatic treatment were approved for marketing in China and entered the national medical insurance catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many rare disease patients and families who were not included in the first batch of catalogs are looking forward to the second batch of catalogs being released, hoping that their diseases will be included in the catalog, so that everyone can at least be seen and have access to the list. More hope.&quot; Xing Huanping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past five years, all sectors of society have paid close attention to the expansion of this &quot;niche&quot; directory, and the National Health Commission has also disclosed the progress. In February 2022, the &quot;Reply to Recommendation No. 9415 of the Fourth Session of the Thirteenth National People&#39;s Congress&quot; published on the official website of the National Health Commission mentioned that the selection process for the second batch of rare disease catalogs has been launched in due course in accordance with regulations and is in the process of material review. stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to that time, the National Health Commission had successively received applications for adding disease categories submitted by relevant departments, &quot;more than 200 copies of relevant materials.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why are these rare diseases included? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are more than 7,000 rare diseases in the world, and there are more than 1,000 rare diseases in China. Therefore, catalog selection requires considerable prudence and science. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Working Procedures for Formulating the Catalog of Rare Diseases&quot; issued by the National Health Commission in May 2018, the catalog should be formulated based on national conditions and fully combined with factors such as economic development, population situation, and social security levels. And refer to the management experience of countries or regions with similar social development levels to our country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The diseases included in the catalog should meet the following conditions at the same time: there is international and domestic evidence that the incidence or prevalence is low; it is harmful to patients and families; there are clear diagnostic methods; there are treatment or intervention methods , affordable, or there is no effective treatment or intervention but it has been included in the national scientific research project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in November 2019, the China Rare Disease Diagnosis and Treatment Service Information System established and developed by the National Health Commission was put into use, and 324 hospitals in the National Rare Disease Diagnosis and Treatment Collaboration Network began to use the system to register rare disease cases. Work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This system has collected information on about 500,000 rare disease patients. This information is of great significance for gradually understanding the number and distribution of rare disease patients in my country, diagnosis and treatment bottlenecks, disease burden and difficulties, etc. It has important guiding value for government departments to formulate a more scientific and reasonable national strategic plan for rare diseases.&quot; the National Health Commission mentioned in the aforementioned reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There will be more challenges in the future”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ma Tao, Executive Secretary of the Beijing Sickness Challenge Charity Foundation, learned that the second batch of catalogs was announced, and the first Immediately, I forwarded the news to the WeChat group where my colleagues and the person in charge of the patient organization belong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the whole, some of the diseases included in the second batch of catalogs have related patient organizations. These rare disease patient organizations have also done a lot of appeals in recent years, and everyone’s efforts have finally come to fruition. .&quot; Ma Tao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After calming down, Ma Tao, who has been paying attention to rare diseases for many years, thought that the release of the second batch of catalogs might be the beginning of another long journey. How to diagnose, treat, protect and return more diseases to society requires joint attention and investment of resources from all walks of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that in addition to rare disease organizations, some pharmaceutical companies with related rare disease drug research and development also successively forwarded news of the second batch of catalog announcements on the 20th, such as Zai Lab, Langyu group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There will be more challenges in the future. For the Pain Challenge Foundation team, our service scope and service capabilities also need to quickly adjust and improve, and continue to work hard.&quot; Ma Tao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/lrktG44jOOsvFv6MGB3BeOCFImNK4k0GmWYA4lAm.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height= &quot;1152&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/lrktG44jOOsvFv6MGB3BeOCFImNK4k0GmWYA4lAm.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/xTVCDAsUlGlKwYhATyMOTbndqtmWN86cFIIMJfxX.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;958&quot; height=&quot;1174&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/xTVCDAsUlGlKwYhATyMOTbndqtmWN86cFIIMJfxX.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/21/odwQpM9PwOk0QfEGV1yAfwXjkVUxWKGa5xxp2s6Q.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;966&quot; height=&quot;1172&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/odwQpM9PwOk0QfEGV1yAfwXjkVUxWKGa5xxp2s6Q.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/V0dpaBgEqDAfsmKEB5WCxy6jOvBiogAMhDqrBF0W. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1170&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/V0dpaBgEqDAfsmKEB5WCxy6jOvBiogAMhDqrBF0W.png&quot; data-key= &quot;251499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TsYEQMGbCvSpIMNw7927zlhOaQunMAzCsHpssWuj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1054&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TsYEQMGbCvSpIMNw7927zlhOaQunMAzCsHpssWuj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“特产互寄”走红，不出门体验当地特色，真的香吗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257222]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州多区取消限购，买房不再受户籍和社保限制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257250]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/F9TJYfwjWZ9iJm0jvRlDsk1tav3YuMXNvpnEy8EH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/F9TJYfwjWZ9iJm0jvRlDsk1t av3YuMXNvpnEy8EH. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangpu District in Guangzhou is one of the three districts where purchase restrictions have been relaxed this time. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can buy as many sets as you want, anyone can buy them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 20, 2023, Guangzhou released new real estate regulation policies. Li Yujia, chief researcher of the Guangdong Provincial Housing Policy Research Center, was invited by relevant departments to write relevant comments one day in advance. He learned that Guangzhou, except for core areas, has lifted purchase restrictions, and buying a house is no longer subject to household registration and social security restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that Guangzhou has become the first city among China’s first-tier cities to relax purchase restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot;, the purchase restriction areas only mention parts of Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Nansha and Baiyun Districts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these 6 districts, households registered in Guangzhou are limited to purchasing 2 units; households not registered in the city are limited to purchasing 1 unit after paying social security for 2 years, and the time to pay social security is shortened from 5 years to 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, only two of the 11 districts in Guangzhou, Conghua and Zengcheng, had no purchase restrictions. After the policy adjustment, Huangpu, Panyu and Huadu were added to the non-restricted areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Real estate prices are starting to increase&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou’s new property market policy was announced at around 6 p.m. Zheng Yang, a real estate consultant, was working at a sales office in Huangpu District. Not long ago Foreign customers who are in a hurry to buy a house come to inquire about the qualifications for buying a house. After seeing the news, Zheng Yang immediately contacted the other party and said that the house that was not available for purchase more than an hour ago can now be purchased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Yang said that the company has not had time to react and the price has not been adjusted for the time being. Due to sluggish sales, the price of this property was lowered some time ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huangpu District is about 30 kilometers away from the city center. It is one of the gathering places for home buyers in Guangzhou. Other areas where purchase restrictions have been lifted are similar to Huangpu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that Guangzhou currently maintains purchase restrictions mainly in the four central urban areas of Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan and Tianhe. These areas were developed earlier and are mainly housing stock, with low elasticity of supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Baiyun is close to the central area and has convenient transportation. It is located in the sub-periphery. There are many new Guangzhou residents buying homes but the supply is small, and the purchase restriction policy has also been maintained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nansha, which is far away from the central city, aims to create a platform for entrepreneurship, innovation, and livability in the Greater Bay Area. It is an important area for Hong Kong and Macao residents to start businesses and live in the mainland. Therefore, despite the long real estate inventory cycle in recent years, we still insist on purchasing restrictions to reduce dependence on real estate and create conditions for the concentration of industries and talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A real estate project in Nansha is raising prices. A real estate consultant told Southern Weekend reporters that after the new policy is introduced, price adjustments will be implemented faster. By next week at the latest, the average real estate price will increase by 5%-8%. He believes that maintaining purchase restrictions represents the value of Nansha District. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pay less value-added tax on second-hand houses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to relaxing purchase restrictions, the new policy also proposes to include Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun, Huangpu, Panyu, and Nansha , Zengcheng and other districts have adjusted the value-added tax exemption period for individual sales of housing from 5 years to 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as this policy for second-hand houses came out, seven or eight new houses were listed in several communities that Song Ming was responsible for within a few hours, and two owners contacted him to lower the sales price. Song Ming has been a second-hand housing agent in Yuexiu District for eight years and now maintains more than a dozen properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Ming told Southern Weekend reporters that life will not be easy in 2023. The company&#39;s gold medal brokers can only sell one house a month, and many peers cannot sell one in half a year. It is the peak sales season of &quot;Golden Nine and Silver Ten&quot;, and the market is still sluggish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia said that from July to August 2023, Guangzhou’s second-hand housing price index fell among the top 70 cities in the country. The purpose of changing the value-added tax exemption period from 5 years to 2 years is to reduce the cost of transaction links, promote the smoothness of selling and buying, not only satisfy the immediate needs but also ease the demand for house replacement, and ensure the entry of transactions of rigid needs and improvements, new houses and second-hand houses. A virtuous cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the introduction of the New Deal, Li Yujia predicts that in the remaining four months of the year, Guangzhou’s commercial housing market is expected to gradually shift from a continued excessive decline to a bottoming out and stabilizing trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the Guangzhou New Deal is the implementation of the spirit of the Political Bureau meeting of the Central Committee on July 24, 2023. This meeting proposed that we should adapt to the new situation of major changes in real estate supply and demand, implement city-specific policies and make good use of the policy toolbox, and meet residents&#39; rigid and improved housing needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a cyclical change, but a trend change.” Li Yujia said that during the long-term overheating period in the past, the regulatory policies characterized by tightening and demand-side suppression are no longer applicable. Gonna quit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Zheng Yang and Song Ming are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[商家标低了团购价格该反悔吗？得失不能只看短期，声誉关乎长期利益]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a customer surnamed Chen in Foshan, Guangdong reported that he bought 6 coins worth 788 yuan for 1 yuan on a certain platform. After buying the set meal, when I went to the store to consume it, I was told that I couldn&#39;t use it and was kicked out of the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have family members who are in business, and it is very common for businesspeople to get prices wrong. On the merchant&#39;s side, once the wrong price is marked, it means a loss of profits. 788 seconds will change to 1. The gap is too big. You can imagine the anxiety in your heart. The store involved stated that it had a live broadcast on the evening of September 9, and the promotional price of the package originally priced at 1,488 yuan was 788 yuan. However, due to a platform system problem, the price was mistakenly changed to &quot;1 yuan purchase&quot;, which triggered panic buying. When it was discovered that it had been It was too late, 500 copies were already sold out in 20 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platform responded that the 1-yuan package was caused by a mistake in the merchant&#39;s own settings. Regarding the merchant&#39;s own practice of setting the store to permanently close in the background, the platform stated that its account has not been canceled and the agreement between the two parties remains. Take effect. Considering the user experience, the platform did not forcefully cancel orders, actively handled customer complaints, and provided some compensation to consumers in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting the price wrong, there are roughly two ways to deal with it. One is to &quot;cancel&quot; the wrong price and recover the loss. The merchants involved actually did this later. In order to protect their interests, they even used non-hospitality methods to drive people away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the merchant&#39;s &quot;repentance&quot; is not without legal basis, because the customer in this incident was involved in &quot;unjust enrichment.&quot; The Civil Code clearly defines unjust enrichment: the fact that there is no legal basis and causes others to suffer losses while oneself gains benefits. Although there is still room for debate as to whether consumers&#39; &quot;1 for 788&quot; behavior is an act of unjust enrichment, because some merchants do engage in such preferential activities, but there is no doubt that merchants have used legal means to put &quot;bleeding bandages&quot; on themselves s right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, the phenomenon of &quot;snatching wool&quot; by taking advantage of merchants&#39; incorrect pricing occurs frequently, and it is not uncommon for businesses to be stopped according to law. On January 16, 2021, the staff of Chow Tai Fook&#39;s official flagship store entered an incorrect price into the system, and Wang and his wife spent 40,000 yuan to buy gold jewelry with an original price of 250,000 yuan. Chow Tai Fook asked him to cancel the order and was willing to pay the couple 500 yuan each as compensation. After being refused, Chow Tai Fook took Wang and his wife to court. The court ruled that the online shopping contract entered into between the two parties should be revoked. The reason is that Chow Tai Fook marked the price of the gold jewelry involved in the case as far lower than the purchase and actual sales price, which is obviously inconsistent with normal merchant sales behavior, and Wang and his wife failed to provide corresponding evidence to prove that the plaintiff engaged in low-price promotions. Behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But no matter what, the mistakes made by merchants are not caused by consumers. When consumers&#39; enthusiasm for &quot;squeezing out wool&quot; is extinguished by cold water, the reputation of the business may also be damaged. A bright double-edged sword is visible. The aforementioned “788 Set Meal Store” was deducted 3 business points by the platform, and caused a stir on the Internet. The heavy hidden price paid for this is clear evidence. The market economy is a credit economy. When merchants are unwilling to bear the consequences of mistakes, credit has been put into question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another way is to make mistakes and let consumers benefit. But such courageous merchants are rare. In fact, the &quot;one-yuan set meal&quot; is not unrealistic. Many merchants have launched &quot;one-yuan dishes&quot; and &quot;free tastings&quot; in the past, so it is understandable that consumers have expectations of a &quot;one-yuan set meal.&quot; If a merchant believes that instead of trying to &quot;repair&quot; the bad impression it has caused to consumers, it is better to accept the order generously and let consumers enjoy it, then the merchant is likely to obtain unprecedented benefits by becoming a party to a top-notch news event. self-exposure effect. In an era where traffic is king, this kind of focus effect caused by the explosion of public discussion spaces cannot be obtained by spending money on advertising. What&#39;s more, doing so itself is also a warning to one&#39;s own behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, on October 26, 2021, there was a price error in the Yuanqi Forest official store. The original price of 79 yuan for a box (12 bottles) of sparkling water was changed to 10 yuan for 3 boxes, causing users to place crazy orders. , apparently the Vitality Forest suffered heavy losses. However, some people pointed out afterwards that the exposure, popularity, traffic and discussion gained by Yuanqi Forest in this incident brought the brand publicity value to more than 40 million yuan, which far exceeded the losses caused by &quot;mistakes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no absolute &quot;standard&quot; for how to view and calculate the gains and losses involved, but there is no doubt that the public&#39;s feelings in such incidents cannot be underestimated. Consumers come to the store with the hope of enjoying the &quot;one-yuan set meal&quot; but return disappointed. This result is unfair and unfriendly to consumers. In similar incidents, merchants or platforms often use &quot;compensation&quot; to explain the problem, indicating that they are somewhat aware of this problem, but in many cases, merchants do not do enough. This is also the root cause of many consumer complaints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Think of this, what choice should a person make when he makes a mistake. Whether to admit your mistake or not is a choice of interests, but also a moral choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In interpersonal communication, we should not take advantage of other people&#39;s mistakes. This is a normal way of being a human being. But when we make a mistake ourselves, we must consider from a moral perspective whether we should have the courage to admit the mistake and bear all the &quot;costs&quot; it brings, or whether we should try our best to cover it up, deny it, and pass the blame to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, when the economic cost of making a mistake is too great for an individual to bear, it is not incomprehensible to try to gain forgiveness from others and thus get a chance to &quot;recover.&quot; But this is an extreme situation after all. Under normal circumstances, as long as admitting our mistakes will not cause us to be &quot;broken&quot; or unable to sink, we should still face right and wrong with a realistic and unavoidable attitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If merchants can still &quot;withdraw&quot; the wrong price, then people cannot &quot;withdraw&quot; what has happened in social media. In this case, whether you care about temporary gains and losses, or whether you care more about long-term reputation (meaning long-term gains and losses), is a very test of character. Facts have shown that we can never completely avoid making mistakes, but being good at &quot;paying for&quot; our mistakes after making them is a knowledge that urgently needs to be &quot;popularized&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长沙欢迎研发：一场以研发为名的“双转型”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fUixGi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fU ixGi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There is a surging crowd outside Cha Yan Yuese&#39;s shop. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2018, Hu Biliang, who had studied and worked in the United States for more than ten years, decided to return to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2007, Hu Biliang has studied at the University of Southern California and the University of Pennsylvania, studying under the &quot;father of CAR-T cell therapy&quot; Carl June. After receiving his PhD in the field of cellular immunotherapy, Hu Biliang is also paying close attention to the development of the domestic biopharmaceutical industry. In June 2018, having already started a family in the United States, he decided to return to Changsha with bare hands and start from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, another summer, four kilometers away from Hu Biliang&#39;s office, a new R&amp;D institution with the functions of talent gathering, cutting-edge research and achievement transformation - Peking University Changsha Computing and Digital Economy Research The institute (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Peking University Changsha Research Institute&quot;&lt;/span>;) was opened. Bai Zengding, who has been recognized as a high-level talent in a certain first-tier city, decided to give up a subsidy of nearly one million yuan and join the institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha, an Internet celebrity city, is extremely popular on social media, especially in summer. As a popular summer travel destination, there is even a joke circulating here that &quot;Yuelu Mountain was stepped down by 2cm due to tourists.&quot; However, somewhat unexpectedly, as tourists are coming in droves, top scientific and technological talents are also coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Changsha welcomes research and development.&quot; This unwritten city attitude has been regarded as a guideline by local politicians before, and finally made its highlight debut in the summer of 2023. On June 19, Shen Xiaoming, Secretary of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee, announced at the opening ceremony of the Yuelu Internet Summit that Changsha is planned to become a global R&amp;D center city. On July 30, the Changsha Municipal Government issued relevant policies and implementation opinions. On September 1, a group of scientific and technological R&amp;D institutions from universities, scientific research institutions, and leading enterprises unveiled their names on site or signed contracts to start construction at the first opening ceremony of Changsha&#39;s efforts to build a global R&amp;D center city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A research and development craze began to stir up this central city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the craze, there are more mysteries of urban development worth studying. After investigation, Southern Weekend found that Changsha’s plan to build a global R&amp;D center city and the micro-innovation practices of this long-established construction machinery capital reveal two transformation models currently taking place in Changsha: First, the integration of manufacturing centers into R&amp;D centers Transformation; second, the integration and transformation from production center to life center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by the &quot;dual transformation&quot;, Changsha&#39;s urban functions and innovation levels are quietly undergoing spiral advancement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The smart mobility chassis developed by Changsha Automobile Innovation Research Institute can realize functions such as four-wheel independent steering and four-wheel independent drive, and can easily complete U-turns and lateral driving on the spot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Changsha Evening News all-media reporter Yi Yi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Interactive network of developers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I personally have always I am doing research and development in the direction of biopharmaceuticals, hoping to develop a better innovative drug through my own technological innovation.&quot; Having been engaged in virus-related research and gene therapy for more than ten years, Hu Biliang has always regarded the research and development of innovative drugs as a professional pursuit and life goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people did not understand his decision to return to Changsha from the United States to continue this research career, but Hu Biliang had his own considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hunan’s biopharmaceutical industry does have a weak foundation compared to the United States. But if an innovative drug can be produced here, it will not only bring better treatment options to tumor patients in our hometown, but also I can also contribute to the development of the biopharmaceutical industry in my hometown, which is also the core value and significance I pursue in my technology research and development journey.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With such fighting spirit and expectations, in the summer of 2018 , Hu Biliang returned to Changsha alone with bare hands to make preliminary preparations for starting a business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, he was no longer alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here we have support from colleagues in terms of laboratories and equipment, preferential treatment for factories in industrial parks, and assistance from government talent and entrepreneurship policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Biliang detailed the help he received from many sources during his entrepreneurial journey and attributed it to &quot;luck.&quot; But in fact, behind this &quot;luck&quot; is the entire city&#39;s respect for the high-tech industry, its preference for high-tech talents, and its expectations for the achievements of high-tech wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such an environment, the implementation process of research and development is relatively smooth. In 2023, Hunan Siweikang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. founded by Hu Biliang received clinical trial approval for a national Class 1 new drug. This is the first biopharmaceutical IND approval in Hunan Province, which is of great significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hu Biliang’s plan, in the next three years, the first clinical trial of cell drugs will be completed, and the cell drugs developed by the team can be successfully launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only a technological milestone breakthrough, but also the starting point for the vigorous development of a regional industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are new research and development forces, and they also chose Changsha, but Peking University Changsha Research Institute is the starting point of a different story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an important platform for the transformation of Peking University’s scientific research results, the institute’s research centers fully considered Changsha’s local industrial characteristics when they were first established to “get closer to the market frontier and industrial needs.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Digital Transformation Promotion Center where Bai Zengding is located conducts applied research around data elements and is committed to serving the national strategy of enterprise digital transformation and traditional industry upgrading; the Industrial Intelligence Research Center next door is oriented towards intelligence. The digital transformation needs of manufacturing, logistics and transportation, supply chain and other fields enable the digital transformation and upgrading of enterprises through data, algorithms and models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha is a big manufacturing city. From hardware, software to cloud services, as well as the huge amount of data in the manufacturing production and processing links, it provides us with a very rich material library, which is why we chose to come here. The reason for being a platform for the transformation of scientific and technological achievements.&quot; Bai Zengding said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to overseas R&amp;D teams and new R&amp;D institutions, there is also a third type of &quot;foreign force&quot; worthy of attention—foreign-funded R&amp;D centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On one side are newcomers. In 2019, Schaeffler established the second R&amp;D center in Greater China in Xiangjiang New District, and closely interacted with local enterprises Xiangjiang Intelligent and Xidi Intelligent Driving. Through collaborative R&amp;D and information sharing, it accelerated the development of Changsha&#39;s intelligent connected automobile industry. Development process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is to increase investment. For example, Soenger China plans to invest a total of 3 billion yuan and continue to increase its R&amp;D investment in Changsha. The newly built Soenger Global New Energy Products and Technology R&amp;D Center has a construction area of ​​tens of thousands of square meters and is expected to be put into use within the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the influx of new foreign R&amp;D forces, R&amp;D paradigms of local companies are also sprouting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry is the source of innovation, and enterprises are the core subject of innovation. According to Du Debin, dean of the Institute of Global Innovation and Development at East China Normal University, Changsha, the capital of central China, needs to build a global R&amp;D center city based on its own advantageous industries, conduct differentiated competition, cultivate global R&amp;D centers in subdivided industries, and then spread through innovation. The effect gradually moves closer to the target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take construction machinery as an example. In 2007, when Hu Biliang went abroad for further study, Shi Wenbing graduated from Huazhong University of Science and Technology majoring in mechanics. Full of longing for the future, he got on the school recruitment bus of Sany Heavy Industry. Soon after, Lu Chuang, who came from Yichang, Hubei Province, decided to continue his studies in the mechanical major of Central South University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Here is the most active market and the most cutting-edge technology in the construction machinery industry.” With the same expectation, the two came to Changsha one after another. Since then, the paths of fate have secretly marked their intersection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen years later, Shi Wenbing became a senior engineer of Sany Heavy Industry, leading a number of major R&amp;D projects, constantly breaking through technical bottlenecks, and going global with the company, using global innovation resources to carry out technological research. It is understood that SANY Group’s overseas business now covers more than 160 countries and regions, and it has 13 overseas manufacturing centers in the United States, Germany, India, Brazil, and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working at the State-owned Enterprise Research Institute for 8 years, Lu Chuang joined an upstream company that provided products and services to Sany Heavy Industry and served as the general manager of Hunan Zhongji Shenyi Testing Technology Co., Ltd., establishing a testing center from scratch. The test base fills the gaps in some testing and pilot service projects for construction machinery and core components. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same industrial chain, in different positions, the chain owner enterprises and supporting enterprises each perform their own duties and jointly contribute to the industrial iteration of construction machinery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Top overseas R&amp;D teams have settled in Changsha, laying the foundation for building chains for emerging industries; new foreign R&amp;D institutions are highly consistent with local industrial clusters; foreign-funded R&amp;D centers continue to increase their presence and interact closely with local companies; at the same time, Changsha Leading companies go global, supporting companies collaborate with each other, and the chain has close relationships and collaborative research. The panorama of Changsha’s R&amp;D entities has basically emerged. Various types of R&amp;D entities show their talents and release the energy of innovation. This is a real and frequent innovation story happening in Changsha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Wang Fan, director of the Science and Technology and Standards Institute of CCID Research Institute, Changsha’s innovative practices coincide with his views. Wang Fan believes that in building Changsha into a global R&amp;D center city, chain owners should play a leading role, promote in-depth cooperation between large and small enterprises in the chain, continuously strengthen and optimize the chain, and form leading enterprises, supporting enterprises, colleges and universities, and scientific research institutions. An ecological development pattern of collaborative linkage, competition, cooperation and symbiosis among institutes, third-party platforms, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of their existence, the goal of becoming a global R&amp;D center city is not unrealistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the prosperous R&amp;D panorama, what is the driving force that nourishes its vigorous growth? In other words, why does Changsha need R&amp;D so much? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shenyi researchers are conducting simulation assembly experiments. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Two-way drive of R&amp;D and manufacturing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Want to answer the above questions , we must first understand Changsha’s industrial background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are seven major 100-billion-level manufacturing industry clusters here, including engineering machinery, automobiles and parts, new materials, electronic information, and energy storage materials. The total digital economy has exceeded 450 billion yuan, and high-tech industries have increased. The average annual growth rate is more than 10%, accounting for 29.6% of GDP. It is also home to the third largest construction machinery industry cluster in the world. The other two are Illinois in the United States and Tokyo in Japan. It is known as the &quot;Construction Machinery Capital of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCID Consulting&#39;s &quot;Research Report on the Top 100 Advanced Manufacturing Cities (2022)&quot;, Changsha ranks eighth in the development of advanced manufacturing, ranking first among cities in the central and western regions. This city, which is famous for its soft power of &quot;entertainment&quot;, is also closely related to the hard-core &quot;manufacturing&quot; industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at the same time, a background of the post-epidemic era that cannot be ignored is the dramatic changes in the international economic and trade pattern, the weakening of the domestic demographic dividend and the tight industrial space. The combined effects of multiple factors have led to the transformation and upgrading of China&#39;s manufacturing industry. Imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the views of many researchers, this boom in scientific and technological innovation in the name of research and development, which occurred in the manufacturing city of Changsha, has a certain inevitability: to strengthen technology research and development innovation, increase the localization substitution rate, It is not only a &quot;charge&quot; for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry, but also a &quot;battle&quot; for core technology dominance, and it is also a &quot;pursuit battle&quot; for the ranking of central cities in the new round of industrial revolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;R&amp;D means &quot;research and development&quot; and refers to the key links in the manufacturing industry from laboratory technology to new product development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha’s proposal to build a global R&amp;D center city is actually a signaling mechanism with a very clear goal, and has a clear intention of leading the way in industrial transformation and upgrading.” Chen Ling, director of the Industrial Development and Environmental Governance Research Center of Tsinghua University, said Now, Changsha is the first city to specifically focus on the &quot;R&amp;D link&quot; as a brand building. In a sense, it takes advantage of local manufacturing advantages to take the lead in the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry driven by R&amp;D breakthroughs or innovation. Judging from the local government&#39;s strategic planning, Changsha City does not intend to leave this transformation and upgrading completely to the market&#39;s own trial and error, but to carry out large-scale planning, layout and investment through the government&#39;s organized approach. This is a comparison Outstanding features. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The source of the government’s organized and planned leadership behavior still comes from enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 National People’s Congress and the National People’s Congress, Liang Wengen, then chairman of Sany Group, once proposed that in the face of the digitization of construction machinery and manufacturing, the group would “either turn over or capsize.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Sany Heavy Industry Changsha Factory No. 18 was rated as a &quot;Lighthouse Factory&quot;. This is the second one in Hunan Province and represents the highest level of intelligent manufacturing and digitalization in the global manufacturing field. All equipment in the factory is connected to the Internet, and the flow of production information, usage, and assembly line information is completely connected. All parts transfers in the factory are carried out by AGV (Automated Guided Transport Vehicle) automatic distribution robots. Industrial robots replace manual work, and &quot;cost reduction and efficiency increase&quot;, a synonym for high-quality development, is supported by vivid scenes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaudi, who has been deeply involved in the field of robotics for more than ten years, has long-term observations and thoughts on how technological research and development can change the traditional manufacturing industry. Changtai Robotics, where he works, takes it as its mission to explore manufacturing technology upgrade scenarios and meet application needs. In Gaudi’s view, if Changsha wants to achieve a global leadership position in the field of industrial robots, Changsha may be able to focus on the software and industrial Internet tracks to create differentiated advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Gaudi focuses on recruiting high-tech talents in the field of artificial intelligence. Guo Dongni, who is also from Northeast China, is one of the good candidates. This seemingly fair and well-behaved female engineer born in 1995 is actually the leader of the machine vision and artificial intelligence algorithm research and development project team. She once led a &quot;women&#39;s army&quot; with master&#39;s degrees with an average age of less than 30 years old to develop cloth defects with independent intellectual property rights. The inspection system - &quot;ZTVT tire base non-woven fabric self-learning vision system&quot; uses artificial intelligence to liberate workers&#39; eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhangtai Robot is not an exception. A number of specialized and new enterprises such as Super Robot and Dingli Technology are relying on Changsha&#39;s scientific and educational resources and industrial advantages to explode with vigorous innovation vitality in many fields such as robots, intelligent equipment, and new materials. Accelerate the industrial upgrading process through technological breakthroughs in subdivided fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Technological innovation actually includes two aspects. One is to spawn new products through technological innovation, which may eventually form a new industry; the other is to promote industrial upgrading through scientific and technological innovation. . The demand for the latter will always exist, and the volume is larger.&quot; Du Debin analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, Changsha’s construction of a global R&amp;D center city requires a series of measures to gather a large number of R&amp;D centers, including those of multinational companies, local R&amp;D centers, new R&amp;D centers, etc. Type, promote innovation in business models and technologies, thereby driving industrial upgrading and transformation of urban functions, transforming Changsha from a product production center to a knowledge production center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many international city cases for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry. Judging from the relationship between product production centers (manufacturing centers) and knowledge production centers (R&amp;D centers), they can be roughly divided into three types: &lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The first is the model represented by Hong Kong. Due to the rising cost of production factors, since the reform and opening up, Hong Kong has transferred manufacturing to the Pearl River Delta region through the &quot;three to one supplement&quot; model. However, it has not turned to the development of R&amp;D, but has transformed into a financial industry and modern service industry. International financial center - South Korea, Singapore and Taiwan, also the &quot;Four Asian Tigers&quot;, have established their own R&amp;D networks. However, Hong Kong has always paid attention to R&amp;D. In the 1990s, it explored government actions to promote R&amp;D such as the &quot;Cyberport&quot; plan. Now it is vigorously developing innovative technology and creating a &quot;Northern Region&quot; that integrates Shenzhen&#39;s scientific and technological resources. metropolitan area.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the &quot;unitary system&quot; model represented by Detroit. As the heartland of the U.S. automobile industry, Detroit once experienced rapid population loss and rapid industrial decline due to the pace of transformation and upgrading that was slower than market changes. After being stimulated and guided by a series of recovery plans, Detroit has now transformed into a research and development center for the automobile industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munich, which also has the automobile industry as its pillar industry, has taken a completely different industrial path from Detroit. There is BMW&#39;s oldest factory here, as well as the R&amp;D headquarters of automobile companies such as Audi and MAN Group. It is a &quot;dual integration&quot; model that combines production and R&amp;D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Du Debin’s view, faced with an industrial structure dominated by the real economy, many cities in China should refer to the development experience of Munich’s automobile industry and encourage companies to conduct technology research and development while retaining production centers and R&amp;D centers. &quot;Integration, transformation, and both are the goals for the healthy development of our city&#39;s industries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to Changsha from overseas cities, it is not difficult to find that with manufacturing as the priority, we are now building a global R&amp;D center Isn’t Changsha a latecomer to the “Munich Model”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A variety of R&amp;D entities come together and are closely linked with each other. Its essence comes from Changsha&#39;s good industrial foundation. New technologies have huge market demand and application scenarios here, thus urging rapid iteration of technology; and new R&amp;D results will empower the manufacturing industry to upgrade and promote its transformation from scale to R&amp;D and brand. Wait for the two ends of the smile curve to shift. The two-way drive between R&amp;D and manufacturing works together to improve urban competitiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, we have seen the full picture of Changsha&#39;s first &quot;transformation&quot;: from a manufacturing center to a R&amp;D hub, from a product production center to a knowledge production center, and it is not a one-way transformation from &quot;you &quot;To &quot;I&quot;, it is the fusion of two centers, the synergy of &quot;manufacturing&quot; and &quot;R&amp;D&quot;, and the symbiosis of &quot;product production&quot; and &quot;knowledge production&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more valuable is that in Changsha, this &quot;integrated transformation&quot; model not only occurs in the production of products and knowledge, but also occurs in the balance between the &quot;production center&quot; and the &quot;life center&quot; middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1181&quot; height= &quot;2067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The secret of &quot;attracting and retaining&quot; talents&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The balance and integration of production center and life center is Changsha’s unique urban advantage. The direct impact of this feature is to attract a large number of talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Changsha’s permanent population has grown by 32.3%, ranking among the top cities in China in both absolute value and rate of population growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ling introduced that according to the &quot;Global Innovation Hubs Index 2022&quot; released by Tsinghua University&#39;s Center for Industrial Development and Environmental Governance (CIDEG) and Springer Nature Group (Nature Research) Index, GIHI2022) report, Changsha performs well in talent-related indicators, such as the inflow of professional talents per million people, the number of active scientific researchers per million people, the number of highly cited scientists and other indicators, almost all of which are in the 50-70% range globally. Ranking of names. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is the core element of innovation, and those who get talents will win the future. Many data show that the city of Changsha has advantages over other cities in terms of talent attraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only the return of Hunan talents such as Hu Biliang and Bai Zengding, but also the promised land for Hubei talents such as Shi Wenbing and Lu Chuang. It is also the common choice of fellow Northeasterners from different generations such as Gao Di and Guo Dongni... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The pace of talent has already broken through the restrictions of geographical areas and shown new flow patterns. Many experts have pointed out that the secret of &quot;attracting and retaining&quot; talents lies not only in the existing law of &quot;people follow the industry&quot;, but also in the balanced integration of urban production centers and life centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to the latter is whether it can meet the material needs of talents for career growth and labor returns; whether it can meet the needs of talents for housing prices, education, medical care and other public services; Meet the spiritual needs of talents for public spaces such as culture, leisure, and consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Satisfying three needs at the same time is not an easy task. However, a new trend has emerged in Changsha, which is transforming from a single production center to a space integrating production and life centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Fan’s view, the integration of production centers and life centers is the trend of the times. It requires more emphasis on people’s subjective initiative and responds to people’s demands. It reflects the concept of comprehensive, coordinated and sustainable development. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Dongni, who was born in 1995, fell in love with Changsha&#39;s delicious food and friendly housing prices as early as when she was studying at Hunan University, and decided to stay in &quot;this happy city&quot; in the future. Nowadays, she is a professional and rigorous female engineer at work, but she is an energetic girl who loves hip-hop dancing in life. During her breaks, she drives to the Xiangjiang River to camp with her colleagues; The snack street is attractive, so you can enjoy a late-night snack. This is the energy given by fireworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Chuang, born in the 1980s, seems to be living a parallel life with Guo Dongni. Fifteen years ago, Lu Chuang chose to come to Changsha for its educational resources and employment opportunities. While studying, whenever he was confused and confused, he would climb Yuelu Mountain alone. Sit for a while, the mountain will not speak, and the people will understand. Nowadays, he is not interested in commercial malls, but he still takes his family to visit his hometown from time to time to experience the changes in his mentality at different stages. This is the nourishment given by nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, after Hu Biliang returned to Changsha, he received strong support from the local talent policy. In the exchange with relevant leaders, he deeply felt the government&#39;s cherishment and respect for talents, and the carefulness and thoughtfulness of policy service talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha City’s talent policy has really helped me solve some practical problems, especially the problem of children enrolling in school.” Hu Biliang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, 22 items of Changsha’s talent policy were released; five years later, the “45-item upgraded version” of Changsha’s talent policy was released, proposing 45 policy points from 7 major aspects; two months later, The 26 supporting implementation measures of the New Deal have been upgraded again based on the original policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 22 to 45 and then to 26, there is no optimal, only better; there is no constant success in the credit book, only greater confidence and stronger determination. Practical welfare policies such as housing subsidies and tax rebates protect the rights and interests of talents and make it worthwhile for them. What this “two-way rush” achieves is double surprises for people and the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People of different ages and personality traits have different definitions of ideal life, but they make the same choice. The only reasonable explanation is probably that this place meets most of the needs and imaginations of each individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trend of integration and transformation from production center to life center has built Changsha’s “life-friendly” urban characteristics, while “life-friendly” continues to empower “R&amp;D-friendly” and “manufacturing-friendly”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talent policy is rich and comprehensive, the cost of living is low, public services such as medical education are high-quality, the cultural creativity is deep and dynamic, and the combination of various characteristics jointly builds a research and development space, a production space, a cultural space, A balanced and appropriate comprehensive urban system such as consumption space and cultural tourism space promotes the gathering of R&amp;D and innovative talents, and then intellectual achievements are born and transformed here, further promoting industrial transformation and upgrading, and forming a virtuous cycle of spiral advancement of industry and population. It will serve as a basis for improving urban supporting facilities and improving the quality of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about how to view the topic of &quot;Changsha building a global R&amp;D center city&quot;, Chen Ling said that Changsha will elevate the &quot;global R&amp;D center city&quot; to the level of the city&#39;s business card and carry out systematic development through policy measures. Comprehensive operation and layout will inevitably produce a brand effect and attract the attention of enterprises and talents. This approach is very consistent with the city&#39;s traditional image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Changsha has always been a city that encourages cultural creativity and tolerates emerging things. The spirit of leisure and entertainment and the atmosphere of human life rooted in the hearts of every citizen have led to the birth of Mango Channel, which dominates the prime time slots of satellite TV, and the birth of a number of new consumer brands such as Cha Yan Yuese and Wen He You. Its unique urban temperament and diverse tourism resources continue to attract a large number of tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuese Tea, a must-visit for tourists, recently announced an investment of 520 million yuan to build a brand R&amp;D and production base, focusing on product technology R&amp;D and product flavor R&amp;D. Compared with the secondary industry, the research and development link of the tertiary industry has a broader meaning, including not only the exploration of front-end products and technologies, but also product and service innovation in the terminal link, starting from the details to improve the consumer experience. In addition, Cha Yan Yuese also deeply explores the local culture of the city and promotes the spread of traditional tea culture and regional culture through packaging, logo, store design and many other elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wanxing, who proposed to &quot;get a salary as high as Shenzhen, live in a livable house in Changsha, and work in the global software industry&quot; is another example of Changsha&#39;s increased research and development in the creative field. In 2022, Wondershare&#39;s global operations headquarters and creative software global R&amp;D center will officially settle in Changsha. Additional investment in the 3.0 project has been initiated, and it is planned to build a &quot;Wanxing Creative World Industrial Park&quot; of nearly 100,000 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the &quot;double-sided Changsha&quot; image of culture, entertainment and hard-core manufacturing is connected by the link of &quot;research and development&quot;, forming a superimposed effect in the field of public opinion. Changsha welcomes research and development, regardless of track. , come if you dare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two transformations&quot; are going on at the same time, and the &quot;three friendships&quot; are interrelated. The innovative practices carried out in central China and their next steps will not only drive the rise of a new innovation center, but also influence The transformation of manufacturing cities is of exemplary significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha, which welcomes research and development, will also be welcomed in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend researchers Tang Jiale and Li Jing also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[合作25年，一朝决裂：石榴集团“宫斗”祸起境外架构]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4JXWhsL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4 JXWhsL. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pomegranate Group’s Beijing headquarters is located in the Fengtai Branch Center of Zhongguancun Science and Technology Park, also known as the Pomegranate Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now both parties are retreating, guaranteeing the delivery of housing, protecting the interests of owners and investors, and not giving the government Cause trouble, so try not to occupy public issues anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter interviewed Cui Wei, chairman and major shareholder of Pomegranate Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Pomegranate Group) At that time, the company gave this reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a media communication meeting held 4 days ago, Cui Wei knelt down in public, hoping that financial institutions would not withdraw loans due to the company’s chaos. If financial institutions cause real losses, I will jump from the 22nd floor of the Pomegranate Center where we are.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, nearly three months have passed since internal strife broke out in this private real estate company, which ranks among the top 100 private real estate companies in China. During this period, incidents such as Cui Wei &quot;stealing the official seal&quot; and the dismissal of vice chairman and second shareholder Sang Chunhua frequently aroused public opinion. Sang Chunhua was also involved in a scandalous news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Cui Wei held a media communication meeting, Sang Chunhua also held a media communication meeting on September 14 and released a reconciliation signal at the meeting. He shouted to Cui Wei: &quot;I am still willing to give in and let you get more until we reach an agreement and stop the dispute.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two sides have been at odds for some time. In 2021, Pomegranate Group failed to go public in Hong Kong. The next year, Sang Chunhua proposed a separation, believing that Cui Wei had not made the right decision in more than ten years and did not want to be held hostage again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei proposed that his equity would require a 30% premium when the company was separated, but Sang Chunhua refused to accept it. Conflicts accumulated over the years are about to break out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exposing each other&#39;s shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2001, Cui Wei and Sang Chunhua cooperated to establish Beijing Agile Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Agile) in Beijing; in 2008 , the two parties also established Huamei K2 Real Estate Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Huamei K2), named after K2, the world’s second highest peak; in 2016, the company was renamed Pomegranate Group, aiming to be the “Apple in the real estate industry.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than 20 years since its establishment, Pomegranate Group has developed more than 90 projects in more than 30 cities across the country, focusing on mid-to-high-end residential products. At the press conference on September 11, Cui Wei once stated that the company has not had a single uncompleted building, a financial bad debt, or a bank overdue payment so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How difficult it is to achieve such results, so why do we have to come out like this on June 21st?&quot; Sang Chunhua once shouted to Cui Wei from a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, a drama of &quot;stealing for official seals&quot; was staged in the conference room on the 16th floor of the Pomegranate Group&#39;s office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the statement of a company employee signed by &quot;Zhang Yongkai&quot;, Cui Wei believed that &quot;Vice Chairman Sang Sir (Sang Chunhua hopes to be as capable and efficient as the Hong Kong police) has violated the company&#39;s system and affected the company&#39;s operations and other illegal acts &quot;, forcing members of the seal team, including Zhang Yongkai, to stamp documents that could not see the full text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Cui Wei put the official seal into his pocket and said, &quot;Not only does he have to stamp it, but he also needs to take the seal home. This is his own company, he is the chairman, and this is his right. No one else can control it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After struggling until 4 a.m., the members of the seal team were allowed to go home. From this day on, Pomegranate Group announced that Sang Chunhua would be terminated from his labor contract and all his duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei said that the company’s dismissal of Sang Chunhua was legal and “a serious, legal and regulatory adjustment and defense of corporate governance rights.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the dismissal of Sang Chunhua was that Sang arranged for relatives, classmates, fellow villagers, etc. to enter the company. The company was internally controlled by relevant interest groups. He was sidelined as the chairman, and the company&#39;s internal management and cost control were extremely chaotic. . Moreover, Sang had problems with his lifestyle, which caused damage to the company&#39;s goodwill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 6, Liu Xia, CEO of Yunhe Variable Group, an investment company, reported Sang Chunhua on Weibo with his real name, saying that he invited many people to participate in unhealthy activities in Beijing on the pretext of eating. I was abused on WeChat and over the phone for dozens of minutes.&quot; It was later revealed that Li Guangtian, president of Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai regions of Pomegranate Group, and Ding Qingwei, president of Jiangsu region, were also involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, Sang Chunhua issued a statement saying: &quot;The dissemination of my unverified and untrue remarks by online platforms and individuals has seriously violated my right to reputation. I demand that the slander be stopped immediately.&quot; stigma, and reserves the right to pursue the legal responsibilities of online platforms and individuals. I have entrusted a lawyer to initiate relevant legal procedures.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with Cui Wei&#39;s many accusations, Sang Chunhua also held multiple press conferences, Fight back against it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to disclosing the situation on June 21, Sang Chunhua claimed that the dismissal was without legal decision-making procedures of the company. He also accused Cui Wei to the media of improperly occupying company property and refusing to return it, and installing bugs in the vehicle he was riding in. device. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also attending the press conference with Sang Chunhua on September 14 was Lin Xinwu, the former general manager of the Risk Control Center and Chairman of the Board of Supervisors of Pomegranate Group. He said that Pomegranate Group launched an A-share listing plan in 2016, and 62 core members paid in 216.8 million yuan as partners to participate in the share reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the A-share listing was blocked, Pomegranate turned to Hong Kong stocks in 2021, but still failed, and the partners’ funds were not returned. It wasn&#39;t until the official seal incident broke out on June 21 that Cui Wei, the working partner, &quot;collectively forced the wife to marry&quot;, asked for part of the money back. But the five partners, including him, were not only fired, but also did not receive refunds, totaling 33.5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sang Chunhua also disclosed that Cui Wei had firmly refused to agree to dividends for 25 years, and the two borrowed money from the company when they needed it. In recent years, Cui Wei has borrowed hundreds of millions of yuan from companies in public names, and his whereabouts are unknown. Cui Wei also used company funds to speculate in Shougang stocks, resulting in a cumulative loss of 6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei also accused Sang Chunhua of having &quot;huge and sudden&quot; external personal debts, endangering the company&#39;s operational security. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Apprentice or shareholder? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the back-and-forth attacks are actually hidden equity differences between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until August 4, Sang Chunhua still couldn’t enter the office. Downstairs of the company, he held a report on national enterprise credit information disclosure and introduced himself to the camera, saying that he was the director and general manager of Pomegranate Group and held 42% of the shares. The company has only two shareholders, with Cui Wei holding the other 58%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the camera, Sang Chunhua has short buzzcut hair and wears a pair of black-rimmed glasses. He called Cui Weilian twice, but no one answered. Then he dialed 110 and claimed to the police, &quot;I am the boss of this company and he has no right to fire me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after the shareholding of Pomegranate Group was penetrated, it was two companies registered in Hong Kong, and the national enterprise credit system could not see the shareholding status of the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Pomegranate Group went public in Hong Kong in 2021. The prospectus obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that the company has established an overseas equity structure, with Cui Wei holding 57.42% of the shares, Sang Chunhua holding 41.58%, and investors Chen Jianyong holds 1% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yonggang has worked at Pomegranate Group for nearly ten years and is still working next to Sang Chunhua. He told Southern Weekend reporters that Chen Jianyong was a friend of Sang Chunhua. He withdrew his shares after the listing failed. Now Cui Wei and Sang Chunhua hold 58% and 42% of the company&#39;s shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the failure of listing, the prospectus of Pomegranate Group is currently invalid and cannot be viewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of the media, Cui Wei, a former geography teacher, always calls Sang Chunhua his &quot;best student&quot;, &quot;just like Cao Yunjin to Guo Degang.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that he went overseas as a state-owned enterprise in 1993 and founded CITIC Real Estate Brokerage Company in Nanjing the following year (Editor’s note: public information cannot be found) and engaged in second-hand housing real estate brokerage. In 1998, he recruited Sang Chunhua, who was 20 years and 4 months old. At that time, Sang had no real estate sales experience and his monthly salary was 300 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the World Cup in France that year. One night, Sang Chunhua was watching the game alone in the store when he met the owner Cui Wei who came to inspect the store. The two chatted for a long time while watching the game. Choi is 10 years older than Sang. After that, the two went to Qingdao and Beijing together to gradually expand the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei said that it was not until he transformed the sales agency business into a demutualized company and donated part of his shares to Sang Chunhua free of charge that Sang became a shareholder. Subsequently, the company entered the real estate development business, and he transferred the shares of the sales agency company held by Sang into the development company, and successively granted him the positions of general manager and vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the share split is regarded by Cui Wei as a huge mistake, laying the foundation for today&#39;s disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sang Chunhua did not accept Cui Wei&#39;s statement that he was a student and an employee. He claimed that in the past 25 years, &quot;two people started a business and started from scratch.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference on September 14, Sang Chunhua introduced that he started working in 1996. When he met Cui Wei in 1998, he was already the sales director of a real estate company in Nanjing, doing first-hand housing business. , and it was he who mobilized Cui Wei, who was still doing second-hand housing at the time, to enter first-hand housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sang Chunhua, when they went north to start a business in Qingdao, the two had already determined the equity ratio of 70:30. In 2001, the Shandong team was disbanded, and he and Cui Wei came to Beijing again and registered Agile in the same year. At that time, we negotiated shares in Henderson Center and finally reached a ratio of 58:42. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The so-called gift of shares is nonsense, and not paying for it is even more of a joke.&quot; Sang Chunhua said bluntly. Zhang Yonggang provided Agile&#39;s industrial and commercial information to Southern Weekend reporters, which showed that the company&#39;s registered capital was 10 million, with Cui Wei investing 5.8 million yuan in currency and Sang Chunhua investing 4.2 million yuan in currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yonggang told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2008, Cui Hesang established Huamei Qiaogoli and transferred the shares of Agile. The ratio of 58:42 was still maintained, which was the predecessor of Pomegranate Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference on September 14, Sang Chunhua said that on September 8, he took the initiative to interview Cui Wei and proposed to end the dispute, but the other party insisted on a 30% premium from the major shareholder. &quot;We still have to grab it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Trouble with overseas structures&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reason why Pomegranate Group has corporate governance chaos is because it involves overseas structures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sang Chunhua pointed out that Cui Wei did not agree to dismantle the overseas structure after the company failed to go public in 2021. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qichacha shows that Pomegranate Group is 100% owned by Beijing Minjiang Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Minjiang Technology). The latter’s legal representative is Cui Wei. After the equity penetration, it is owned by two Hong Kong companies. The Hong Kong company is in turn held by a company registered in the British Virgin Islands. Under this offshore structure, neither of the two major shareholders directly holds shares in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Equity lawyer Lu Qinghua once represented equity disputes similar to those of Pomegranate Group and authored the book &quot;Corporate Control&quot;. She analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that the domestic company Pomegranate Group is 100% owned by Minjiang Technology, and Cui Wei, the legal representative of Minjiang Technology, has the right to decide the candidates for the board of directors of Pomegranate Group. In the absence of special provisions in the company&#39;s articles of association, the legal representative also has the right to manage the official seal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since August 2023, the management of Pomegranate Group has undergone a major change. After dismissing Sang Chunhua and Lin Xinwu, the company added four directors and one supervisor within one day. According to Sang Chunhua, the new directors include Cui Wei’s wife, Zhu Yanhua, who was appointed without his consent as the second shareholder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lu Qinghua’s view, under the overseas equity structure, Sang Chunhua does not directly hold shares of Pomegranate Group. This means that even if Sang Chunhua sues Cui Wei to dismiss him without going through legal procedures, it will be more difficult to win the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Zhigang, a professor at the School of Finance at Renmin University of China who focuses on corporate governance research, holds a different view. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the ownership structure must ultimately restore the individuals who actually invested and reflect the true wishes of the investors. The appointment and removal of company directors require the approval of a majority of shareholders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, he also agreed that if litigation is involved under an overseas structure, the actual legal effect of overseas awards may face challenges, and the litigation process may be a difficult tug-of-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Zhigang introduced that the disputes at Pomegranate Group reflected some common issues in the governance of private enterprises. Many private enterprises focus on investment in the early stages of entrepreneurship. The founders are independent of each other and are maintained by family ties, friendships, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the company becomes bigger, some companies fail to handle the problem of profit distribution through institutional methods such as equity and compensation, or do not pay attention to the formation of a standardized corporate structure by introducing external investors. Problems caused by corporate governance often As a result, it is difficult for its business to last forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the dispute, Pomegranate Group began to face the risk of bank loan withdrawals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industrial Bank took the lead in sending a notification letter to Pomegranate Group, requiring it to deposit the remaining 74 million yuan of principal and interest repayable for this year on a 1.8 billion yuan loan into a supervisory account before August 12, 2023. Otherwise, Industrial Bank has the right to declare all loans to expire early and hold the borrower and guarantor responsible for breach of contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pomegranate Group’s 2022 corporate bond annual report shows that as of the end of 2022, Pomegranate Group’s total interest-bearing liabilities were 16.678 billion yuan. Among them, bank loans within one year were 375 million yuan, and trust borrowings within one year were 1.146 billion yuan. A total of three interest-bearing bonds are in existence, with a total amount of 2.916 billion yuan, all of which will mature in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as of the end of 2022, Pomegranate Group’s monetary funds were only 2.864 billion yuan, of which 536 million yuan was a restricted amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Zhang Yonggang is a pseudonym in the article. Southern Weekend reporter Shi Xuan also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[槟榔可抗疫？清代岭南槟榔是如何传入湖南的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8IXxCkuDt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8 IXxCkuDt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251274&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 26, 2017, at a betel nut processing factory in Wanning, Hainan, farmers were sorting out Just purchased betel nuts. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岭南地区嚼食槟榔的习俗，与其药用价值有极深关系。湖南湘潭人嗜食槟榔，最初也是出于治病抗疫需要，只是一旦形成习惯就不能停。湘潭为清代岭南槟榔北上的主要集散地。乾隆四十四年至同治二年的几次湘潭大疫，促成了嚼食槟榔的习俗。据业内传说，引进槟榔的关键人物是湘潭知县白璟，白璟之父白为玺曾任广东英德知县，这是岭南槟榔被引入湘潭的特殊机缘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;辟瘴即是防疫&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;槟榔的药用价值，古人早有认识，东汉南海人杨孚《异物志》已记载食槟榔可以“下气”助消化，此后有关槟榔可以下气、消胀、驱虫、辟瘴、治疫的文献记载，层出不穷。湘潭大学张恩迅、申玲玲《瘴气、瘟疫与成瘾：地方社会变迁中槟榔食俗的传播与重构》一文，全面梳理了历代有关槟榔药用价值的论述，并指出：“唐宋时期槟榔是伴随中央政权开发岭南的除瘴工具，清（代）民（国）时期槟榔是见证近代中国商贸网络发展与地方社会变迁的治瘟药材。”此处的“治瘟”“除瘴”，换言之就是防疫治疫。无论是闽粤还是湖南，嚼食槟榔，最初的正当理由是防疫治疫，这并不排斥一些人为寻求快感、出于礼仪需要而食用槟榔，三者可以同时并存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古人多用药用植物辟瘴防疫，明末清初有人传播吸烟可以辟瘴的说法。清代湘潭文人朱声亨写过一篇《蔫说》：“吕宋产蔫叶，剉而吸之，谓能辟瘴。”湘潭人把烟叶叫做“蔫叶”。该文认为，吕宋烟在清初传入福建，很快就风靡全国，但最初人们吸烟的理由是“辟瘴”。朱声亨对吸烟的危害有深刻认识，指出“蔫之害与鸦片埒”。 （何歌劲辑注《湘潭历代文赋选》下册第504-505页）值得注意的是，烟草与槟榔都能成瘾。正如清廷把鸦片称为“洋药”，烟商、槟榔商人强调药用价值，是要消除人们对成瘾性食品的心理障碍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;嚼食槟榔能成瘾，浪掷金钱，与明清时期儒家价值观相违背。湖南社会长期崇尚节俭，主流文人对此十分排斥。湘潭知名学者罗汝怀就觉得嚼食槟榔浪费钱：“盖潭人之于槟榔，虽孩童时用咀嚼。尝闻之人云，其壮盛时日需百钱，而一家终岁之费，常在二三十缗，不亦傎（颠diān）乎？”（《罗汝怀集》第262页）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经营槟榔的商家，必须有冠冕堂皇的理由，抵挡儒生阶层的批评，诱人消费，治病、防疫就是最正当的理由。现代医学普及以前，人们普遍认为南方各省存在“瘴气”，岭南、湖南、贵州等地都曾被认为是“瘴区”，感染“瘴气”经常可以致命。那么，吸烟、嚼食槟榔，如果能辟“瘴气”，正当性就无可置疑，毕竟保命还是第一位的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乾隆四十四年湘潭大疫，知县白璟用槟榔治疗居民的“鼓胀病”，由此形成嚼食槟榔习俗，此后历经几次大疫而全面普及，这个解释似最为合理。乾隆朝两部《湘潭县志》还没有提到槟榔，嘉庆《湘潭县志》则明确记载“槟榔、蔫叶，所在酷嗜”，可证明此俗形成于乾隆朝晚期与嘉庆朝前期之间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;833&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251273&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;曹雨《一嚼两千年：从药品到瘾品，槟榔在中国的流行史》书影。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;湘潭知县白璟的推动&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;青年学者曹雨《一嚼两千年：从药品到瘾品，槟榔在中国的流行史》一书，尝试对湖南湘潭嚼食槟榔习俗的由来做新的解释。他综合各方研究成果，揭示湘潭既是米市也是药材集散中心，同治年间槟榔存货充足、湘军回乡促使消费能力提升。岭南槟榔北上的陆路贸易，原本有东线（经江西）、西线（经湖南）两条线路，太平天国战争使东线受阻，湘潭的商业中心地位在太平天国战争期间得到强化。岭南槟榔越岭而北，都先聚集到湘潭，再分销各地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹雨将目光聚焦于1864年湘军遣散一事，在书中下了这么两个结论：“湘潭地区嚼食槟榔的习惯，很有可能就是这两股力量——积压了槟榔的商人和持币待购的退伍士兵——共同推动而形成的。”“湘潭嚼食槟榔习俗大兴于1864年至1880年间，在此期间湘潭并未发生过大范围的瘟疫，因此嚼食槟榔避疫的传说不是历史事实……”曹雨挑选了光绪《湘潭县志》记载的疫症空白时段作论证，但嘉庆《湘潭县志》记载嘉庆前期湘潭槟榔消费已十分盛行，这个记述被无视了。如果一定要考虑遣散湘军的作用，我认为这些退伍士兵只是将槟榔食俗传播到湖南各县。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;601&quot; height=&quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251272&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《湘潭县志》关于槟榔食俗的记载。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王闿运总纂、光绪十五年刊行的《湘潭县志》，是研究湘潭槟榔食俗的基本史料。该书卷九《货殖》称：“广商则银朱、葵扇、槟榔为大，家日剖数十口，店行倍蓰焉。……计每日得百钱之利，月当糜钱五六百万，如此岁费钱二百余万万……为费甚矣。”银朱、槟榔是以药材身份来到湘潭，只是槟榔的成瘾性使消费者一经接受即甚难停止。王闿运作为本地文人领袖，对槟榔消费十分厌恶，他在县志序文中抨击“槟榔之费，拟埒稻粱”，意谓湘潭人买槟榔的开销与粮食开支差不多相等。职是之故，王闿运在志书中，只谈槟榔生意规模，不乐意探讨湘潭槟榔消费的起源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;笔者认为，湘潭槟榔消费习俗，是清代几次大疫所推动，关键年份则是乾隆四十四年。光绪《湘潭县志》卷九《五行志·疫》记载“乾隆四十四年大疫”“道光十六年四月大疫” “（道光）二十二年大疫”“同治二年七月疫”。乾隆四十四年为1779年，这是槟榔食俗在湘潭形成的关键年份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湘潭槟榔业元老黄俊良记录了这样一个传说：乾隆四十四年大疫，许多居民患鼓胀病，吃药无效。县令广东人白璟，谙医理，明药性，将赴任带来的药用槟榔分给患者嚼之，嚼后均觉腹部舒服，再多次嚼之膨胀消失，病痛解除。尔后，原患者嚼之，未患者也随之而嚼，习惯逐渐形成，“不过那时把槟榔当作一种药物。”（黄俊良：《我所知道的湘潭槟榔业》，载《湘潭文史》第12辑）黄俊良自1926年入槟榔店当学徒，他所了解的白璟事迹，属于业内共同记忆，不可忽视。周大鸣、张恩迅、申玲玲等学者，因发现白璟籍贯奉天而怀疑业内传说的真实性，可以理解，但他们没有留意到白璟与广东的渊源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白璟字希宋，号璞斋，奉天镶白旗汉军旗人。他在湘潭知县任上，自撰《燕喜亭碑记》一文称：“予奉家慈就养于署，时勖予曰汝父宰英德，有善政……”（嘉庆《湘潭县志·艺文》）也即白璟的父亲当过广东英德县知县。查道光《英德县志》，乾隆十五年至十九年的知县白为玺，镶白旗人。据此可大体确定，白为玺就是白璟的父亲。官员眷属多随任居住，白璟应在广东居住过，由是被误会为“广东人”。笔者认为，正是他们父子在广东的经历，使白璟在湘潭大疫、“鼓胀病”流行时，用从广东带来的药用槟榔给居民治病。王闿运对白璟有成见，或者就是因他引入槟榔一事而起。在《湘潭县志》官师传里面，王闿运议论白璟施政“稍任己意，或有所偏颇，至今论者异同”，在《五行志·疫》“乾隆四十四年大疫”下面，王闿运写上“牧令主其休咎也”，表明他对白璟非常不满。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道光十六年（1836）、二十二年（1842）、同治二年（1863）湘潭又发生几次大疫，促成槟榔食俗在湘潭真正普及。湘潭人嚼食槟榔习俗的形成，供货充足只是充分条件，几次大疫的发生才是必要条件，而习俗形成的关键人物则是知县白璟。湘潭槟榔食俗，于乾隆四十四年得白璟的提倡开始形成，经过几次大疫进一步普及，而有关槟榔辟瘟防瘴的传统医学学说，则将二者成功串联起来。现代医学证明，嚼食槟榔有引发口腔癌的危险，至于其防疫作用则见仁见智，但古人是相信的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博主用无人机跟踪女性被抓，高科技产品何以沦为隐私“刺客”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:22:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[引资、清欠、对接客户，民营经济发展局的地方经验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHDna4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1123&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHDna4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月4日，国家发展改革委副主任丛亮介绍，中央编办正式批复在国家发改委内部设立民营经济发展局。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民营经济发展局，一经设立，便吸引了全社会的目光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月4日，国家发展改革委副主任丛亮介绍，中央编办正式批复在国家发改委内部设立民营经济发展局。它是促进民营经济发展壮大的专门机构，作用在于加强相关领域政策统筹协调，推动各项重大举措落地见效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丛亮介绍，该局的主要职责是制定促进民营经济发展政策，建立与民营企业的沟通交流机制。在百余字的职责表述中，未见“管理”相关字样，以“服务”为主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是国家部委层面首次设立民营经济发展局，但地方上，对它并不陌生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者搜寻企查查和各地政府官网发现，国内各地高峰时曾有民营经济发展局、民营经济发展促进局、民营经济发展服务局等相关机构200余个，现在仍有民营经济发展局180余个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它们分属于各地的不同部门。如地方的工信部门会设有中小企业发展机构、市场监管部门也有推动民营经济的内设机构，人社、税务、司法、金融监管部门也会根据需要设有相应服务处室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起点在2000年左右，那时部分省、市、区县开始设立民营经济发展相关部门，并加挂乡镇企业管理局或中小企业局的牌子，而后名称也会多次变更。2019年后，各地中小企业局在机构改革调整下撤销，现已成为地方工信局、经信局或市场监管局的下设处室。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大部分相关机构，是在已有的机构上加挂一块牌子，即一套班子、两块牌子，仅有少部分地区，单独设立了“民营经济发展局”作为市政府组成部门，比如青岛、雅安、济南、重庆北碚区、重庆九龙坡区等，它们普遍在2019年以后成立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些地方经验，能为国家级部门提供怎样的探索经验和启示？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;多地早有民营局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2000年前后，部分省政府一级就已设有负责民营经济的机构，名称为乡镇企业管理局、民营经济管理局、中小企业局等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在多次机构改革后，它们的身影已经模糊了，现在只能通过政府官网的干部履历、当年的预决算、单位简介、职能介绍等公示文件窥得其发展脉络。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，山东德州市禹城市工信局的一位干部履历写着，1997年至2013年供职于禹城市民营经济发展局，此后，供职单位变为禹城市经济和信息化局，2019年后再变为禹城市工业和信息化局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又如，山西吕梁离石区中小企业服务中心在官网简介中详述了自己的发展历程，其前身为1976年的离石县社队企业管理局，1984年改为离石县乡镇企业管理局，2002年机构改革后成立了离石市乡镇企业服务中心，挂牌离石市民营经济发展局。这一机构开始负责全区中小企业、乡镇企业和民营经济的监督、指导、协调和服务。2004年8月，再度更名为“离石区中小企业局”，保留“离石区民营经济发展局”的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《山西经济：改革开放四十年》一书中介绍，2003年，山西省调整组织结构，将省级的乡镇企业管理局过渡至民营经济发展局，次年，加挂了山西省中小企业局的牌子。自此，山西省11个地级市、119个县市区均成立了中小企业局，职能也由原来的乡镇企业扩大到县域经济、民营经济、中小企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东青岛市民营经济发展局办公室主任李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，2019年机构改革前后，全国各地中小企业局撤并转，原中小企业局职能并入当地工信局、经信局、市场监管局，在这些部门加挂中小企业局牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，山西省太原市、朔州市、吕梁市、阳泉市、运城市等地工信局都加挂了民营经济发展促进局的牌子，下辖的区县也在工信部门加挂民营经济发展促进局的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温州是在市经济和信息化局加挂了民营经济健康发展促进局的牌子。四川省的广安、自贡、资阳也在经信局挂了民营经济发展局的牌子，内江、阿坝州、凉山州则是在市场监管局挂牌民营经济发展局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十余年来，民营经济发展局在地方政府机构设置中的成批出现与中央推出鼓励民营经济发展的政策波峰大致吻合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，“非公经济36条”是新中国成立以来首部促进非公经济发展的中央文件。2019年，中共中央、国务院印发《关于营造更好发展环境支持民营企业改革发展的意见》，多方面支持民营经济。2023年，《中共中央&amp;nbsp;国务院关于促进民营经济发展壮大的意见》公开发布，提出31条政策措施，鼓励促进民营企业做优做大做强。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;需要综合协调部门&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2015年，李晓峰就职于青岛市工商局下属的企业注册局民营经济发展处，做民营企业综合协调的工作，包括制定全市民营经济工作要点和将原来散落在各个部门的关于民营市场主体的相关数据归拢。“还是做宏观梳理的工作，了解面上的情况。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工商局对民营经济的工作范围也仅限于此，其他部门虽也有跟民营经济相关的工作，但都是在各自范围内落实职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，青岛市政府进行机构改革，在限额38个工作部门的条件下，将民营经济发展局和海洋局加入改革方案，这两个局成为了市政府的组成部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时，李晓峰调任至民营经济发展局，先后任协调指导处处长、办公室主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他向南方周末记者解释，以往不同单位虽都有服务民营经济的部门，但由于职能限制，关注点各有侧重。比如，工信部门更关注工业企业及其产业，科技、商务等部门则关注高新技术、消费类企业及其行业发展，必须要成立一个专职部门才能涵盖民营经济发展各个方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比在原先的机构，李晓峰发现，民营经济发展局这一专设部门更能发挥协调作用，“我们现在就是做综合协调、平台搭建等服务工作，不是行业主管部门，更接近综合部门的角色”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一角色的优势在于方便协调各个部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“民营经济工作涉及面宽、政策性强，需要各个部门密切协作配合，形成工作合力。”国家发改委副秘书长兼人事司司长张世昕接受采访时也有类似表述，在国家发改委设立民营经济发展局，也为了能更好发挥统筹协调、综合施策、促进发展的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但李晓峰认为，在国家层面，民营经济发展局属于国家发展改革委的内设机构，对于地方上已经单设但没有放在发改委的相关部门，没有必要撤并。“服务民营企业本就涉及多部门协调配合，职能上也不会存在交叉、冲突的问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在青岛民营经济不是支撑半边天，而是主力军。”李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，2019年到2020年间，青岛的民间投资依旧能保持两位数增长。2023年1月-7月，青岛民间投资增长6.1%，高于出全国6.6个百分点。民间投资在建项目拉动投资3.6个百分点，对全市投资增长贡献率77.3%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市民营经济发展局办公室书面回复南方周末记者：该局于2019年3月设立，2019年上半年济南民营市场主体数量为99.33万户，目前为150.5万户，占全市市场主体数量的98.6%。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;服务符合产业需要的民营企业&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;做好服务的第一步是让民营企业和当地民营局相互了解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛民营局一方面通过街道区市掌握民营企业情况，设置了由政府人员和企业服务机构组成的300名企业政策服务专员，另一方面通过梯度培育管理为民营企业设置不同成长赛道，发掘有发展潜力的中小企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛云路股份（688190.SH）项目负责人耿润儿告诉南方周末记者，获评政府给予的荣誉称号是对企业的肯定，为投资机构、金融机构判断企业价值提供衡量标准，一定程度上有助于企业融资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;云路股份从事先进磁性金属材料设计研发及销售，是一家有央企持股的混合所有制企业。耿润儿主要负责项目申报等工作。她说，公司在当地政府支持下已成为独角兽企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在青岛市2023年创新型中小企业公示名单中，获评企业多为高新技术等新型制造业，偶有一两家食品、服饰行业相关企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家青岛制衣厂的负责人告诉南方周末记者，“我们可能接触过民营局，但了解不多”。目前企业面临的主要困境是用工成本高，行业内的服装工厂很多转移至人力成本更低的东南亚、印度等地。她的企业主要承接代工的外贸订单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多人宁愿到市区办公室里挣三千的工资，也不愿意在厂里工作，（工资）开到六千多都没人来。”她说。她现在也在为企业寻求转型，不再走代加工模式，尝试通过网络平台经营自主品牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰说，每个地方政府都有其着重发展的产业。青岛市有24条重点产业链，与青岛城市产业规划和发展需要相契合。纺织服装更是24条产业链中的优势产业链，如青岛酷特智能企业，就是在服装个性化智能定制上找到了转型路径。“还是要看企业的模式和核心竞争力是否适应社会形势的发展变化，以有效应对市场化的优胜劣汰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在济南，民营局的主要做法包括搭建民营经济监测分析服务系统，监测分析营业收入、利税、研发投入等综合指标，动态掌握民营企业发展情况。该局也提请市政府出台《关于开展攀登行动支持民营企业跨越发展的若干措施》，明确实施融资促进等5大行动21条培育措施，开展为期5年的精准培育。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家位于济南的密码企业的工作人员表示，济南市政府相关部门曾为他们解决过办公场地产权、对接融资需求等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家位于济南的生物医药企业的工作人员告诉南方周末记者，他们在当地是龙头企业，济南近些年营商环境发展力度大，市里成立专班服务龙头企业，“毕竟大企业体量大、贡献大”。他肯定了政府的工作，但也表示企业个性化的问题难以面面俱到、服务到位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，济南四大主导产业分别是大数据与新一代信息技术产业、智能制造与高端装备产业、生物医药与大健康产业、精品钢与先进材料产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;企业什么时候需要政府？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;由于工作缘故，李晓峰常能接触到各种规模的民营企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，过去企业与政府打交道，希望政府最好无事不扰，但在企业发展初期和瓶颈期等关键时期，也需要政府出手，提供资源上的支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耿润儿曾代表公司参与过民营经济发展局组织的创意会，企业以创意方案提出发展诉求。云路股份与下游企业共同提交的方案是非晶高效节能变压器，主要面向的客户是各地供电局和城市轨道交通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场创意会将邀请3-5家企业分享提案。到场的除了企业代表外，还有政府工作人员、项目评审人员和受邀前来的客户代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在政府的平台上向国企用户推介产品无疑是快速打开客源、建立双方信任的一条捷径。创意会结束两个月后，云路股份顺利参加了后续项目落地的沟通推进会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰告诉南方周末记者，参加创意会的企业各类规模都有，前期会遴选企业提出的创意，入选创意由民营局联系专家和政府有关部门做充分论证，符合青岛产业发展方向的项目则能进入后续的推进会，并协调各相关部门解决项目和产业发展所需的资源，如企业普遍关注的土地、人才、资金等。自2019年至今，已举办十多场，吸引到落地的投资金额约四百亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耿润儿说，由于他们处于关键材料技术这类“卡脖子”的行业，人才需求迫切，民营局曾连同人社局帮助企业引进一名日籍专家，并为专家解决了人才绿卡问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;资金方面，李晓峰介绍，除了部分企业上市后有一定奖补外，民营局融资合作处也会组织“政银企”等对接会活动，引导有需求的民营企业对接金融机构，企业提金融需求，金融机构推介产品。“相比企业自己挨家挨户找银行机构对接，他参加对接活动一次就能接触八到十家金融机构。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南民营经济发展局在书面答复中也提到，他们设立万家潜力企业培育库、千家重点企业培育库和百家投资机构库，对接本市民营企业获得280轮次基金投资。同时，也推动企业融资需求与银行对接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁盛是一家为政府部门提供服务型产品的企业负责人，他的企业曾在全国多地开展业务，主要通过竞标获得政府采购项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，大多数向政府提供服务类产品的民营企业，免不了遇到“要账难”的问题，账款迟迟难以到位时有发生，部分民营企业还会碰到“新官不理旧账”的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，国家发改委等多部门出台28条具体措施，推动破解民营经济发展中面临的突出问题，其中包括加大对拖欠民营企业账款的清理力度，重点清理机关、事业单位、国有企业拖欠中小微企业的账款等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晓峰介绍，青岛民营局从成立初期就关注到这一问题，2019年开始为中小企业清理欠款。只要企业提出来，对于经过排查后确认存在拖欠账款情况的政府部门，民营局牵头下发督办单，督促其分期分批清偿拖欠中小企业的账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中梁盛为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>