<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[出走半生，归来仍是《小时代》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; is undoubtedly A good start to the September season. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Yu Shu&lt;/span>; The main CP led by Xin and Zhang Linghe continued the popularity of &quot;Eternal Life Flower&quot; in &quot;Canglan Jue&quot;, and the supporting cast included Cheng Lei, Lu Yuxiao, Young actors such as Tian Jiarui also successfully &quot;served on the table.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But, what is the quality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After ten episodes, I just want to say: &quot;Guo Jingming has been away for half his life, and he is still &quot;Little Times&quot; when he comes back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ac0690abaedf15b3ce46f48519d38909.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ac0690abaedf15b3ce46f48519d38909.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although, after the series started airing, the chief director and The screenwriter&#39;s signature was changed to &quot;Gu Xiaosheng&quot;, but familiar viewers know that Gu Xiaosheng is the pseudonym of Guo Jingming (Guo Xiaosi). The actual controller of Zuishi Culture, the co-producer of the series, is also Guo Jingming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ca271e02d9ed357d3577c8f05408b86e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;524&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ca271e02d9ed357d3577c8f05408b86e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250378 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In May this year, in the 2023-2024 major drama list released by iQiyi, the director’s signature Still Guo Jingming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The story of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; takes place in an imaginary ancient background. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Gong family is a well-known and upright family in the world. They live in seclusion in deep mountains and valleys, living a nearly isolated life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Broken down, there are four families with their own specialties: Shang, Jiao, Zheng, and Yu. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The wise and brave Gong Huanyu&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Ji Lingchen)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and the frail Gong Ziyu&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;(played by Zhang Linghe)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Is the son of the current leader of Gongmen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e135141865e13db3fe55a92e71dbc31d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e135141865e13db3fe55a92e71dbc31d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250377 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gong Shangjiao of Jiao Palace&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Cheng Lei)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is ruthless and has extraordinary abilities. Gong Yuanzheng (played by Tian Jiarui) of Zhenggong is good at making drugs and is a senior brother-controller who follows Gong Shangjiao all day long. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/355ef4cbc340a4c0ddef87f7c946370d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/355ef4cbc340a4c0ddef87f7c946370d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250379 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5b752f8ebbdb2327527fcad6e00102fb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5b752f8ebbdb2327527fcad6e00102fb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250381&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to these four young masters, the Gong family also has a hilarious and nymphomaniac eldest lady Gong Zishang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Jin Jing)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/febbb14f36052b928d812157e439a979.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/febbb14f36052b928d812157e439a979.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250382 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is also a killer organization in the world called Wu Feng. It has been trying to dismantle the palace for many years and has sent out many undercover agents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the time when the palace is choosing a wife, the Wufeng female assassin Yun Weishan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Yu Shuxin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Shangguan Qian &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Lu Yuxiao) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sneaks into the Gong family with different tasks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/97aac732115cfd1e8226f4b8b2c7b821.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;459&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/97aac732115cfd1e8226f4b8b2c7b821.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250383 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This was a troubled year. The old leader and first heir Gong Huanyu died mysteriously. Gong Ziyu succeeded him at the critical moment and got the support of his sister Gong Zishang. However, the more powerful Gong Shangjiao is eyeing the leader, and Gong Yuanzheng has repeatedly provoked and secretly caused trouble for him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With their beauty and strength, Yun Weishan and Shangguan Qian stood out from the many brides and lurked next to Gong Ziyu and Gong Shangjiao respectively. Where should their fate go? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a48c9dcbecd2d69d86875b9011b9b6e1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a48c9dcbecd2d69d86875b9011b9b6e1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250386 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although there are many characters and complicated subplots&lt;/span>;, love is undoubtedly the main thread of this drama. In the final analysis, it is the story of a female undercover agent and a male target falling in love. &lt;span>; With a sincere heart, he is entangled, confused, and finally makes a choice between mission and emotion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/0e7be16731d2df118912b0a8c8df50da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/0e7be16731d2df118912b0a8c8df50da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250387 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/acd389bb4cc73e1cdfa5137543e3fdbe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/acd389bb4cc73e1cdfa5137543e3fdbe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250384&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the other side, Gong Shangjiao and Shangguan Qian will stage a fox-rabbit love story. The two high-end game players gradually developed feelings that they did not expect during their testing, mediation, and pulling. For two people whose reason is greater than their emotions, they may have to compete for &quot;who falls first&quot; until the last moment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/353403007bd0ad44965bfa471a0e7e63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/353403007bd0ad44965bfa471a0e7e63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250385 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/9a616aecee21fd328e8babc6aa98574d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/9a616aecee21fd328e8babc6aa98574d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250388&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;From this perspective, what Guo Jingming wanted to film &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; may be a variation of &quot;Lust, Caution&quot;: men and women trapped in identities. They are on guard against each other, but it is difficult to resist physical attraction and the desire to be loved. Love is hard to hold on to, love is hard to find, those who are sober will pull away, and those who are infatuated will leave their tears empty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This requires a detailed description of emotions. It must be written that every decision made by a man in reason is mixed with overwhelming pain and lasting love, and it must be written that a woman&#39;s heart is shattered after all the tricks have been exhausted. I suddenly realized that he was the only one who cared about me. I wanted to write about the weakness of human nature, the burning body of love, and the dark thoughts growing secretly in the coffin-like mansion...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &quot;Yun Zhi&quot; &quot;Yu&quot; is not the ancient puppet version of &quot;Lust, Caution&quot;, but &quot;Tiny Times 5&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like August’s high school days in Chang’an, Shuang Xuetao’s frozen Northeast, and Han Han’s small towns and racing cars, many writers’ creations repeatedly echo their most nostalgic elements. What Guo Jingming likes is just like the &quot;Tiny Times&quot; series of the year, which is noble and decent on the surface, but frivolous on the inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first rule of Guo&#39;s rule: noble people must have the surname Gong. Each play has its own Tang Wanru. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Little Times&quot;, CEO Gong Ming has severe mysophobia and collects expensive cups like crazy. &lt;span>; His face turns pale when he sees fish. He consumes protein powder every day to maintain his appearance from &quot;VOGUE&quot; 》The face torn off the fifth page of the magazine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cc62eb65db10f8e71b62144cbe0bcc65.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;666&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cc62eb65db10f8e71b62144cbe0bcc65.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250391 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; allows us to see Gong Ming&#39;s ancestors and grandfathers: Gong Ziyu, even eating ice cream in June will be cold enough to cry. Cold body is a delicate disease of wealth. ; Gong Shangjiao doesn’t eat chicken and fish because he doesn’t want to see dead fish eyes and dead corns. This must be the source of Gong Ming’s DNA. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The character of Tang Wanru, who loves gags and can’t move his legs when seeing handsome guys in &quot;Little Times&quot;, has also been transferred to Gong Zishang in &quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; . Just like Tang Wanru was out of place among the sisters of the era, Gong Zishang was also an outsider of the Gong family. He was a rich man but he stalked the handsome guards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/89b6c75ce3676cc3b75c65f56ae81e75.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/89b6c75ce3676cc3b75c65f56ae81e75.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250389 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo&#39;s Rules&lt;/span>; Rule 2: Visual impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, &quot;Tiny Times&quot; allowed everyone to re-understand Shanghai&#39;s life and death in a dazzling array of brand-name clothes and dazzling luxurious scenes. The fashionable outfits in it are still fashionable today. Timeless. Many viewers even believe that the most suitable career for Guo Jingming is costume stylist and art director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/bc18d2b2cd46560ea74003226305954e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/bc18d2b2cd46560ea74003226305954e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250392&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When it came to &quot;Cloud Feather&quot;, he became interested in symmetrical composition and wabi-sabi aesthetics. Audiences who like it admit his care in visual effects, while those who don&#39;t think it&#39;s just pretentious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3ae75478e83c90ed0af4ab469cfa6895.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3ae75478e83c90ed0af4ab469cfa6895.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250390 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/75d282ef87285c0bc505e500a0c8eb9c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/75d282ef87285c0bc505e500a0c8eb9c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250393&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/854be081d615cc29d62a30afae09cec7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/854be081d615cc29d62a30afae09cec7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250394&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo&#39;s Rule No. 3: Tear it up, be happy, there is plenty of time anyway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a famous tearing scene in &quot;The Feather of the Clouds&quot;, which is comparable to the scene in &quot;Little Times&quot; where &quot;Gu Li was poured red wine by Nan Xiang on his birthday, and the blessing turned rotten and smelly&quot;: The Successor Gong Ziyu was questioned about Germany&#39;s unmatchability and got into a fight with Gong Yuanzheng. Gong Shangjiao walked over and gave each of them a slap in the face, regardless of their respect and power. Gong Zishang was shouting at the side, Gong Ziyu was angry and tearful but did not fight back, opposite Gong Shangjiao had contempt written on his eyebrows, while Gong Yuanzheng had a mocking smile. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ed19b2bb0658976d98266ce188f3b196.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ed19b2bb0658976d98266ce188f3b196.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;250399 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, he is much more restrained than before. Most of the time in &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; is secretly tearing apart. If he can&#39;t bear it anymore, he will have a fight scene&lt;/span>; on the stage. , it can be seen that it is quite restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo’s Rule 4: Consumption of male sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Jingming always understands the psychology of the (female) audience and shows different types of handsome little fresh meat on the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Little Times&quot; there is Gu Yuan, Gong Ming and Zhou Chongguang, &lt;span>; in &quot;Qing Ya Ji&quot; there is Qing Ming Boya He Shou Yue, in &quot;The Feather of the Cloud&quot; there is the Gong family boy band, &quot;Marry Entering the palace and obeying the regulations&quot; also became a hot topic for a time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cdabb3a80df1a2a1bc2e326ed2de6075.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1431&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cdabb3a80df1a2a1bc2e326ed2de6075.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250397 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After watching ten episodes, the perception of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; is hovering between two extremes: the plot rhythm is fast and slow, and the audience&#39;s experience is sometimes good and sometimes bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first four episodes quickly introduced the portraits of the Gong family and the Wufeng assassin, and cut to the core plot line quickly. The death of Gong Ziyu’s father and brother pushed the rhythm to the top, and at the same time dropped a double layer of suspense: Who is the murderer? How can Yun Weishan and Shangguan Qian survive the crises? Even the first four episodes are full of plot points such as inappropriate memories of the heroine and slow discussion of plans by the heroine and co-star across the stairs, but overall there are no big problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But when Gong Ziyu was asked to pass the &quot;Trial of the Three Domains&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (a test that must be passed as a sword-wielding successor)&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;At the beginning, the rhythm of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; had a big problem, and each episode was one hour long and did not convey much effective information. The foreshadowing of the previous situation made the audience think that Yun Weishan, Shangguan Qian and Gong Shangjiao were all people who were doing great things. However, these powerful characters did not advance the development of the plot line, but had meaningless conversations day after day. The conflict between Wu Feng and Gong Men intensified, but Gong Men was still a pool of stagnant water. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What’s even worse is that the plot also repeatedly contains slaps in the face. For example, when the poison in the female assassin&#39;s body broke out in Ban Yue, they were supposed to contact Wu Feng&#39;s superiors on time. The audience tried one hundred and twenty ways for them to escape briefly, but the final solution was to carry on; another example is &quot;Three Domain Test&quot; The first level of &quot;Refining&quot; was highlighted as a dangerous level. Even the talented Gong Shangjiao took more than ten days, but Gong Ziyu actually passed it by grabbing a box with the help of Yun Weishan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/12eca1cda1359ac2fe6745f4fd755ffa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1020&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/12eca1cda1359ac2fe6745f4fd755ffa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250395 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; is also very good at throwing up suspense at the end of each episode and resolving conflicts at the beginning of the next episode: for example, at the end of the sixth episode, the guard saw from Yun Weishan&#39;s tricks The shadow of Wu Feng was once again blocked by her in a few words in the seventh episode; at the end of the ninth episode, Yun Weishan pointed out the undercover identity of his aunt Ming Wuji, and in the tenth episode she said that the other party had heard wrongly. These were supposed to be the boosting points of important plots, but what was waiting for them was the feeling of one big step forward and two big steps back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/537bea127b0d8ddd3bc8f71d441c09f8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1058&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/537bea127b0d8ddd3bc8f71d441c09f8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250396 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/4fcfeafe201c307844358a42c7fdeb11.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/4fcfeafe201c307844358a42c7fdeb11.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250398&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In general, the intertwined character relationships in &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; may attract &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the attention of some viewers. However, the excessive and indiscriminate plot advancement will consume everyone&#39;s patience. If this continues, the series is bound to start high and then go low. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s not that we didn’t give him a chance, it’s just that the answer sheet he handed over was still a reimagined version of “Tiny Times.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[旅客吐槽候机厅全是按摩椅？山西太原机场最新回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256892]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thanks very much to all walks of life and passengers for their attention to the issue of &quot;massage chairs&quot; at Taiyuan Airport. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 16, relevant media reports attracted our company’s great attention. In response to media reports and social concerns, Taiyuan Airport immediately formulated a massage chair adjustment plan. We also began to adjust some of the massage chairs in the terminal that night, and all seats were adjusted into place as soon as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Taiyuan Airport will continue to ensure aviation services, create a warm and comfortable waiting environment for passengers, and give you a better travel experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;We are deeply sorry for this incident. Thank you again to the media and travel friends for supervising our work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Taiyuan International Airport Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot; >;&lt;span>;September 17, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[初中两女生投毒全班：犯罪动机值得深究丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256884]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A shocking &quot;poisoning case of middle school students&quot; attracted attention. On September 14, 2023, it was reported on the Internet that a poisoning incident occurred at a junior high school in Shanghai. Many students became ill after drinking unknown liquids. Shanghai police issued a notice that day, confirming the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the police report, at 15:37 on the day of the incident on September 12, the Pudong Branch received a call that many students at the East School of Shangnan Middle School were feeling unwell. After preliminary investigation by the police, the case was committed by Yang Moumou (female, 13 years old), a student of the school, and Zheng Moumou (female, 13 years old), a classmate of the same class. The two returned to the classroom during physical education class that morning and poured a mixture of cleaning and bleaching liquid into the water cups of students in the same class, causing many students to feel uncomfortable. &quot;The students involved were sent to the hospital for treatment and were discharged that night, and have now returned to normal classes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After carefully examining the entire process of this case, there are some questions worthy of analysis and questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, this case still requires in-depth investigation, and the full story of the incident needs to be restored and released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenshots of the leaks posted on the WeChat group showed that 23 people in the class drank &quot;added water&quot;, more than a dozen of them had their stomachs washed, and several students suffered varying degrees of damage to their liver and kidney functions. . If this revelation is true, the number and extent of the victimized students need to be further confirmed by follow-up investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenshots of the revelations also showed that one of the poisoners was the monitor of the class. &quot;He was planning revenge on the class teacher during the summer vacation.&quot; He once formulated a policy of &quot;one poison to kill, two gasoline, alcohol, and hydrogen peroxide to burn to death.&quot; According to the two plans, the girl involved &quot;there were three bottles of unknown liquid in the table. When the teacher went to collect it, (the girl) picked up one bottle and wanted to drink it herself&quot; and &quot;the girl actually had three fruit knives on the table.&quot; In addition, the two girls usually have good grades and have received &quot;key training from the class teacher.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are still doubts about the revelations spread on the Internet, and the motive of &quot;planning to retaliate against the head teacher&quot; is also open to investigation. Let me ask, since the girl involved was targeting the class teacher, why did she poison the entire class? If the &quot;three bottles of unknown liquid&quot; and &quot;three fruit knives&quot; situations are true, I am afraid they are directed at more people than simply retaliating against the class teacher. In addition, the information of &quot;cultivation by the head teacher&quot; and the rhetoric of &quot;retaliation against the head teacher&quot; are contradictory and difficult to justify, and it is difficult to be trusted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the facts of the case, it seems a bit far-fetched for the girl involved to describe her motive as &quot;revenge against the class teacher.&quot; However, the revelations spread online have brought an increase in information after all, adding many details to the case, and many subsequent interpretations are based on these details. Faced with the divergent opinions on the Internet, the police should investigate these details in depth, complete the puzzle of information that has not yet been provided in the police report, and announce it to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the criminal motivation and nature of the crime of the girl involved, as well as the real cause of the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, if the girl involved does have good grades and has no obvious conflict with the teacher, then her motive for committing the crime is indeed a question that still needs to be resolved. Some netizens regard the girl&#39;s long-planned poisoning in this case as a &quot;psychological and mental problem&quot;, which is inconsistent with the basic principle of causality between harmful behavior and harmful results in the criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the girl involved made a criminal plan in advance and took the initiative to carry out the crime, intending to harm dozens of classmates in the class. There is a serious suspicion of deliberate murder or &quot;retaliation against society&quot;. Any &quot;Hidden secrets&quot; and &quot;causes&quot; cannot be the reasons for the two girls to commit poison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior of the two girls was not due to negligence, nor was there any &quot;irresistible or unforeseen reason&quot; behind it. Instead, they knew that poisoning would harm others, endanger society, and even There is a serious suspicion of attempted intentional homicide, which cannot be excused or mitigated for any reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a step back, even if the girl involved, Yang Moumou, has &quot;psychological problems&quot;, does her co-defendant Zheng Moumou also have &quot;psychological problems&quot;? Even if the girls involved were really seeking revenge, did the entire class offend them? Obviously, the criminal motives of the two girls involved deserve further investigation. The police should strictly investigate their social media and social relationships to find possible perpetrators who instigated the crime, or signs that the girls involved were influenced by specific extremist thoughts, and track down these truly reliable crimes. Cause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the aftermath of this case includes punishing those involved and relieving the victims, but there are still areas for discussion in these two aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Lizhi News&quot;, it is reported on the Internet that the parents of the girl involved have apologized in the class group, saying that they &quot;feel guilty for not being able to control their children well because of their dereliction of duty.&quot; According to the current law, the two students involved are under the age of 14 and do not need to bear criminal responsibility or administrative responsibility. They can only order the parents of the students to strictly discipline them. If the victim student has medical expenses and other expenses, the parents can sue the parents of the two students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two girls in this case have committed the crime of releasing dangerous substances, and they have successfully committed the crime. Article 114 of the Criminal Law stipulates that those who set fires, breach floods, explode, release toxic, radioactive, infectious disease pathogens and other substances, or use other dangerous methods to endanger public safety without causing serious consequences shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years but not more than ten years. If &quot;causing serious injury or death to others or causing heavy losses to public or private property&quot;, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of more than ten years, life imprisonment or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that if this case involves an adult deliberately poisoning a minor, then the person involved will definitely face severe legal sanctions and receive a sentence of between three years and less than ten years in prison. However, Article 17 of the Criminal Law stipulates, “A person who has reached the age of fourteen but under the age of eighteen commits a crime and shall be given a lighter or reduced punishment.” In this case, the two girls involved were both under the age of fourteen, which brings problems to their punishment. problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the circumstances of this case, the criminal behavior of the girl involved may not have been a spur of the moment, and a &quot;bug&quot; situation cannot even be ruled out. If this situation is true, this case is that a minor criminal committed a crime with an adult&#39;s mind, but he boldly escaped punishment by virtue of his status as a minor. Is it possible that society can only allow juvenile criminals under the age of fourteen to go unpunished? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current law on the protection of minors seems to only be able to deter and punish adults who harm minors, but it is powerless to deal with the situation of &quot;minors harming minors&quot;; at the same time, according to Article 1 of the Compulsory Education Law According to the provisions of Article 27, the school can only &quot;criticize and educate the students involved in this case who have been suspected of murder, and cannot expel them.&quot; This is obviously seriously inconsistent with the principle of proportionality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, according to the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention of Juvenile Delinquency&quot;, simply &quot;criticizing and educating&quot; or &quot;strictly disciplining&quot; the girl involved in this case is obviously not enough to punish criminal behavior , and cannot comfort the victimized classmates. Therefore, it is necessary to implement the &quot;corrective education measures&quot; in Article 41 or 45 of this law, or to &quot;maliciously increase the age of the offender&quot; so that he will receive the punishment he deserves and give justice to the victim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国庆出行没抢到票？这些方式可提高购票成功率]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256890]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from China State Railway Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;State Railway Group&quot;) that since September 13 Since the first day of transportation during the National Day Golden Week, which is September 27, train tickets have been on sale, and from September 16, tickets have been on sale for the second day of the holiday, which is September 30. Railway train ticket sales are booming. From September 13 to 16, the railway sold a total of 74.05 million train tickets, of which September 15 hit a record high of 22.877 million tickets sold in a single day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the Passenger Transport Department of the China Railway Group said that judging from the pre-sale of train tickets from September 13 to 16, the day before the holiday, September 28, and the two days before the holiday, that is, September 29 to On the 30th, tickets from Shanghai to Wuhan, Shanghai to Xi&#39;an, Shenzhen to Changsha, Shanghai to Changsha, Shanghai to Hefei, Shenzhen to Xiamen, Shanghai to Zhengzhou, Beijing to Zhengzhou, Beijing to Wuhan, Guangzhou to Guiyang and other directions are in short supply at some points. Popular trains with better and faster speeds are more tense, but Beijing to Shanghai, Shanghai to Nanjing, Shanghai to Beijing, Chengdu to Chongqing, Suzhou to Shanghai, Hangzhou to Shanghai, Wuhan to Shanghai, Guangzhou to Nanning, Shijiazhuang to Beijing, Xi&#39;an Some trains to Beijing and other directions still have tickets left, including trains from Shenyang to Beijing, Hong Kong to Guangzhou, Shenzhen to Hong Kong, Nanning to Guangzhou, Qingdao to Beijing, Taiyuan to Beijing, Wuhan to Shenzhen, Wuxi to Shanghai, Kunming to Chengdu and other directions. There are enough votes left. For tickets sold during the pre-sale period on and before September 27, there are sufficient remaining tickets in all directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that passengers travel during holidays are highly concentrated, and trains in some popular directions and hot periods will have ticket shortages. Passengers can choose to travel in off-peak hours according to the remaining tickets at different times and directions. You can choose to purchase tickets through waitlisting, transfer, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No handling fee is charged for railway 12306 waitlisted tickets. After the ticket purchaser submits the waitlisted ticket order, he or she will pay the fare advance simultaneously. The ticketing system will continue to try to honor the waitlisted demand. If there are tickets matching the demand, The system will automatically generate a paid order and notify the ticket purchaser. If the advance payment is greater than the actual ticket price, the system will automatically refund the difference; if the waitlist purchase is unsuccessful, the advance payment for the waitlist order will be automatically refunded in full. Passengers can submit waitlisted orders with multiple combinations of &quot;dates, train numbers, and seats&quot; to extend the waitlist redemption time and increase the success rate of waitlisted ticket purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you cannot buy a direct ticket, it is recommended that passengers can meet their travel needs by transferring or taking buses in sections. Railway 12306 will intelligently recommend transfer plans with remaining tickets based on passenger travel needs and remaining tickets for passengers to choose from. In order to facilitate passengers to transfer between trains, the railway department has set up convenient in-station transfer channels at 100 major stations, and arranged station staff to provide guidance services. Passengers can enter the waiting room to wait without leaving the station, effectively shortening the time for transfers. Multiply time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The railway department reminds passengers who use the Internet or mobile phone clients to purchase tickets, the railway 12306 website (including clients) is the only official online train ticket sales channel, and does not charge any additional fees. Dear passengers, please Purchase tickets through official channels to protect your legal rights and personal information security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔡磊：“抗冻”先行者向死而生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the fate of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 997&quot; height=&quot;1496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250528&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/251236&quot; title=&quot;Cai Lei: Hunting Medicine The shock caused by the patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&quot;>;Cai Lei: The shock caused by the drug-hunting patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After lumbar puncture , a bottle of liquid was quietly pushed into the spinal cavity of Nanjing (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;pseudonym&lt;/span>;) from outside the body through a needle. A few days later, her family discovered that her hands could support the armrests of her wheelchair and help her stand on her own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years ago, Nan Jing, who was in her early 20s, suddenly found it difficult to lift her left leg. Since then, her condition has deteriorated rapidly, and it has become increasingly difficult for her to walk. Several times while going up and down the steps of the work commuter bus, Nanjing fell to the ground and was almost run over by a vehicle speeding behind him. Soon, she was diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early June 2023, Nanjing was enrolled in the clinical trial of a new single-gene drug that Cai Lei and a team of scientists collaborated with Beijing Tiantan Hospital, and has used the drug four times so far. Although her leg muscle strength has not improved significantly, she has made great progress compared to the time before when she had to be helped by her family to stand up. For Cai Lei, who has led the team to develop drugs and fight ALS for more than four years, this is a historic breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nanjing is lucky, but there are still 500,000 ALS patients around the world who are in urgent need of the attention and assistance of the whole society.&quot; Cai Lei said. &quot;Furthermore, Nanjing belongs to the SOD1 subtype, which accounts for less than 2% of all patients. The other subtypes and the pathology of sporadic ALS are still a mystery, waiting to be explored and solved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because A disease of the motor nerve cells in the brain and spinal cord, patients with ALS gradually weaken their muscles and eventually become completely paralyzed and lose their body functions. For more than a hundred years since its discovery, the pathology of ALS is unknown and there is no cure. Most patients die within 2 to 5 years of the disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly four years ago, Cai Lei, the former vice president of JD.com, was also diagnosed with ALS. In the industry, Cai Lei, who is full of passion, keen insight and action, and good at organizing and cooperating, is like a &quot;hard-working man&quot;. When he got sick, he was in his early forties and had just married and had a son. Being thrown into a sudden desperate situation, he also experienced despair. But within a month after his diagnosis, he decided to mobilize all the resources he had accumulated over half his life to invest in scientific research and drug development for ALS. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s impossible, it can’t be done.” These opinions from inside and outside the industry have never shaken Cai Lei’s belief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was difficult to get through patient data between hospitals, so he used the most primitive methods to build the world&#39;s largest big data platform for ALS patients through phone calls and WeChat exchanges; he visited the house again and again, He impressed a number of top scientists who were not involved in ALS research, including Chen Gong, Dai Jianwu, Lu Yunfeng, Meng Songdong, and Chen Lingling, to cooperate with him and promote the launch of more than 100 R&amp;D pipelines; he took the lead in signing letters of intent, leading more than a thousand patients and family members to Voluntarily donating brain and spinal cord tissue samples after his death; he shortened the recruitment of patients for clinical trials from the previous one or two years to the &quot;extreme speed&quot; of two hours...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether it is financial or professional, In fact, I am not the strongest candidate in the world to overcome ALS. But I don’t want to just sit and wait for medical progress. I have to do things that others have not done or done.” Cai Lei put the funds, Laboratories, scientists, pharmaceutical companies, hospitals, and patients are connected one by one, becoming the lubricant and booster in many aspects of basic research and the medical industry. He believes that only by making the fight against ALS a cause that is valuable and beneficial to all parties involved can it become a sharp blade to tear through the darkness and let light continuously shine in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is far from a simple inspirational story of an individual fighting against fate, but arousing the goodwill and motivation deep in the heart.” Xu Wanjiao, a medical practitioner who has been engaged in drug research and development for 15 years, sighed with emotion. &quot;Everyone approaches Teacher Cai because Teacher Cai approaches each other. This connection itself is a kind of energy and energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, Cai Lei has been a long-term staff member of Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China. When he was teaching a postgraduate student majoring in accounting at a university, he spoke frankly when faced with the confusion of young students. &quot;They often ask me, how can we be successful and respected? Some students think that our generation has many opportunities and can make money in anything, and is not as competitive as them. I want to say, which era is not fierce? Which era is not fierce? Is success not difficult? Struggle and progress are the life young people should pursue. Helping others can also reduce confusion and emptiness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After falling ill, Nanjing, who works as a clerk in Nanjing, can only use a wheelchair. as a companion. The mother is suffering from terminal cancer and needs to come to Beijing for treatment. The grandmother accompanies her daughter and granddaughter to rent a house and see a doctor in this strange city. Nanjing experienced anxiety and worry, not knowing what she could do. After meeting Cai Lei, she changed. &quot;I have no reason to be decadent. I can sweep the floor, mop the floor, and wash clothes. Whatever I can do is a little bit. Find your own meaning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter what your fate is, strive to continue to create value and live out your own spirit.&quot; This is the wealth that Cai Lei believes he can leave to the world, and his footsteps have not stopped yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the destiny of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[偷遍上海所有无印良品店铺，小偷夫妻自称“品牌代理”，半年赚26万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256731]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼师针扎孩子、对孩子使用麻黄碱：当让持扭曲价值观的人远离孩子丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256856]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Parents with children are very worried after reading this. On September 12, a parent of a young child in Shanghai posted a message: On March 24 this year, parents found injuries on their child who was studying at the Dahua Tadpole Music Park in Baoshan District, Shanghai, and suspected that the kindergarten teacher had abused the child. On March 27, the parents called the police, and the police issued an injury examination form for the child to go to the hospital for examination. &quot;The police issued an injury examination form to check the child&#39;s injuries that day because there were many bruises on his body. In the next few days, the police issued an injury examination form again.&quot; , doctors at the Children’s Hospital found multiple pinpoint-like holes.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hospital injury examination sheet uploaded by the parent showed that there were many pinpoint-like holes on the toddler&#39;s body. &quot;The parents immediately asked for a hair test. The results showed that all five children contained ephedrine, two of them.&quot; Child contains lidocaine&quot;. &quot;It has been more than half a year since the case was reported. Parents have suffered a lot. They have suffered from insomnia and nightmares. We just want to know the truth! What have the children experienced? What have they endured? What will happen to their physical condition in the future?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 13, a reporter from Dawan News called Dahua Tadpole Music Park. The kindergarten replied: &quot;You can go to the police station and they can give you the most correct answer, or the answer you want most.&quot; &quot;All our processes They all follow the arrangements of the Education Bureau and the police station.&quot; Subsequently, the reporter called the local police, but there was no reply; when calling the Baoshan District Education Bureau, a staff member said: &quot;We as a whole attach great importance to this matter and have been following up and handling it. We have also seen the content posted by parents on the Internet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Half a year has passed for such an abominable and suspected criminal incident, and there is neither any explanation nor any explanation as to whether the perpetrators have been dealt with. Below, it’s no wonder that parents are reluctant to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the nature of this matter is vile, and the relevant circumstances are outrageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the injury examination notice from the Shanghai Public Security Bureau uploaded by the parents, the parents stated that the boy was only four years old. The day before he was admitted to the hospital, the parents found a suspicious pinpoint-like hole. After asking the child, they learned that &quot;maybe There is abuse or use in clinical trials.&quot; On that day, fever symptoms appeared, with the highest temperature being 39 degrees; the test results were: &quot;Stomach and energy have become worse than before, there is tenderness in the penis and scrotum, and repeated swelling and pain.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s all because you have a little more. It looks like a needle-like hole, and some of it has healed. &quot;There are also many needle-like holes in the penis and scrotum.&quot; The test conclusion is: &quot;The scrotum is red, swollen, and tender.&quot; &quot;There are many suspicious needle-like holes all over the body. The purpose is unknown. The police need to be called.&quot; Collaborative treatment.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The parent said: &quot;All five children contained ephedrine (in their hair), and two of them contained lidocaine.&quot; If what is said is true, it would be even more terrifying. Because ephedrine has central nervous system stimulant effects, it is a drug-making raw material strictly controlled by the government. Lidocaine is a local anesthetic. Think about it, everyone. Even when you go to a pharmacy to buy pseudoephedrine, a drug that relieves cold symptoms, you have to buy it in limited quantities and register your ID number. Where did the perpetrators get these drugs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more questions: Are these &quot;needle-like holes&quot; just a needle stick in the child, or are they the marks left by using a syringe to inject ephedrine and lidocaine? For such a long period of time, many children have been systematically injected with acupuncture, ephedrine and lidocaine. Is it a crime committed by one person, or is it a coordinated crime by many people? Where is the perpetrator now? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time a kindergarten teacher stabbed a child with a needle. Similar incidents have been exposed many times and occur all over the country. Therefore, we must consider the possibility of imitating crimes and abetting crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2019, the Tianjin Binhai New District Court held the first public hearing on the case of two middle five teachers of the Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten suspected of abusing their care recipients. The prosecutor alleged: From July to October 2018, the defendants Zhao and Dou, as kindergarten teachers in the fifth class of Tianjin Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten, resorted to needle sticks, pushing, and The children in care were abused by pulling and other violent behaviors, and the number of victims was as many as 24. Two kindergarten teachers were sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, a mother’s 3-year-old daughter was in the middle class at Chuntian Huahua Kindergarten in Dachang Kulun Village, Saihan District, Hohhot City. One day she overheard her daughter saying that Teacher Guo from the kindergarten pricked someone with a needle. Later, I discovered that there were scabs that looked like needle holes on my daughter’s body, head, ring finger, armpits, thighs, ankles, etc. Two other parents also found scabs on their children that looked like needle holes. The kindergarten was later closed down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these cases, the case in Baoshan District, Shanghai was even more egregious in nature, going beyond the scope of general abuse, with obvious intentions and consequences of personal injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the perpetrator’s motive is worth exploring. There is always a motive for abusing or physically harming a child: feeling that the child is disobedient and disobeying management is one kind; having conflicts with parents and being angry at the child is another kind; being driven by distorted values ​​​​and crazy hatred is also another kind. kind. The last one is probably the scariest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kindergarten should be a place where children live, play and play together. It should be a place of relaxation, freedom and safety, like a sweet dream. Kindergarten teachers should love children and care for each child as their own. Having normal values, loving children, and being patient are the minimum requirements for a kindergarten teacher. If a seemingly normal face hides disgust and hatred for children, then the kindergarten will not only not be a warm and loving paradise, but will become a chilling nightmare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, especially in first-tier cities, kindergartens generally charge a lot of money. From the perspective of professional ethics, how can we take money from parents and turn away, close the door, abuse, and harm children like angels? Such evil behavior not only breaks through the bottom line of professional ethics, but also represents the degradation and loss of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary to conduct a thorough investigation and examination of the perpetrator&#39;s life world and spiritual world to see who the perpetrator usually associates with, what content he follows on social platforms, celebrities and himself. Media, which groups and circles to join, and see if this person and the online and offline circles he interacts with have any extreme remarks, actions or even organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, it is necessary to install monitoring equipment in kindergartens across the country. In principle, all activities of children and all interactions between teachers and children should be recorded on video to deter those treacherous people who hold distorted values. ; At the same time, kindergarten teachers and early childhood staff who are entering and working should review their social media, speech and values, and keep those who hold distorted values ​​away from children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[若尔盖：黄河在这“美丽回眸”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256735]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京跳水大爷：只愿安静跳水，不想当网红]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256880]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team coach Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1, 2, 3, jump!&quot; Coach Meng Derui gave the order, and more than a dozen adults and aunts in swimsuits jumped into the water from left to right, splashing everywhere. splash. &quot;Someone jumped, let&#39;s do it again.&quot; Coach Meng was in second place, and he heard that the rhythm of entering the water behind him was wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Diving Team&quot;) rehearsing the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump in the South Moat on September 13. Every day at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, this group of 60 and 70-year-old people come here from all directions to participate in &quot;training&quot;. They perform tuck-knee pose, swallow pose, back swallow pose, front and back somersaults...all of them are as strong as swallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Training is over , Zhang Yuan rode an electric bike home &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting out of the water, water droplets lay on her wheat-colored skin, which was particularly bright under the sun. . Although the team has been established for less than three years, most of the team members have 20 to 30 years of winter swimming or diving experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the personal training session, Coach Meng completed a set of backward somersault half-circle pike jumps. &quot;201B, performance level, so exciting,&quot; teammates and passing spectators clapped and praised. Applause and laughter continued on the shore - some applauded, and some who failed the jump were heckled and joked, &quot;Isn&#39;t this shot painful enough?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, everyone is laughing so hard Damn it, everyone is here just to have fun.&quot; Mengdry said while looking at his teammates. This 67-year-old Beijinger grew up in the alleys of Di&#39;anmen. He remembered two very happy things when he was a child. One was flying a kite on the tiles of a bungalow, and the other was swimming in Shicha Sea. In the 1960s, Meng Derui, who was in primary school, studied diving at the Shichahai Sports School. His coach later went abroad to teach and also brought out world diving champions. Because of his professional background and his friendly nature, the team members affectionately called him &quot;Meng Jiao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For every new pose, Meng Jiao explained the movements to us from head to toe and gave us personal demonstrations. No matter how cold the weather was, he could do a standard demonstration when he climbed on the platform. In his Under the leadership of the diving team, we adults have moved from a group of diving bastards to a quasi-professional level,&quot; said 62-year-old team member Zhang Yu&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The team members rehearse the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Don’t want to take risks Risking your life to become an Internet celebrity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 3, 2023, Meng Jiao led the diving team to Tianjin to socialize with local diving friends. At that time, the diving master of Tianjin Lion Forest Bridge was popular all over the world. net. Some netizens posted a video of the team members arriving in Tianjin online with the title &quot;Beijing Diving Master Comes to Tianjin to Play Gym&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, it’s not a competition at all, but an exchange and learning between diving friends. We have known each other for many years and are very familiar with each other. We go there to dive there every year because there are more suitable venues for high school students in Tianjin. The environment for bridge diving - the water is deep, the bridge is high, and the water bottom is clean.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an introduced, &quot;Like the Beijing South Moat where we train daily, the water depth is about 3 meters, and the bridge deck is 5 meters away from the water. For safety reasons, law enforcement officers do not allow us to To jump from the bridge, you can only jump from the guardrail on the shore, the height is only 2 meters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop in Tianjin is the Chifeng Bridge, which is more than 9 meters high. Wang Tieshun, the &quot;Ironman of Winter Swimming&quot; in the team, was the first to take the stage. In his first jump, the &quot;Reverse Swallow&quot;, his buttocks touched the water first, and he was slapped hard, which was not ideal. He analyzed that it was due to the increase in height that there was a problem with the angle of entering the water. He immediately adjusted his posture when entering the water, and performed a wonderful dance afterwards, which won bursts of applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Brother Wang is 69 years old. Generally, when a person of this age stands at a height of 9 meters and looks down, his legs will tremble. Not only does he dare to jump, but he is also a &quot;anti-Yan&quot; who is cool and neat, so generous. People are impressed.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an said as he opened his arms in a &quot;swallow pose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second stop was the &quot;8A-level scenic spot&quot; Lion Forest Bridge. The deck of the Lion Grove Bridge is about 6 meters above the water surface, which is an ideal height for high bridge diving. The team members just skipped here three months ago and it was a great experience. But at this time, there were already a sea of ​​people on and off the bridge, and the scene was very chaotic. Those who could jump and those who couldn&#39;t jump plunged into the water. Meng Derui saw a man walking into the water with his child in his arms, and he still has lingering fears. For safety reasons, he decided to lead his team members to evacuate immediately without jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training , the brothers went to a nearby restaurant to have a drink&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Someone at the scene recognized that we were from Beijing and chased us all the way. We were following the filming, but we still withdrew. Everyone comes to dive for physical and mental pleasure and to improve their skills. They don’t want to risk their lives to become an Internet celebrity and be in the limelight.&quot; Zhang Yuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Changluo, director of the emergency department of Changsha Central Hospital, said in an interview with the media that high-bridge diving is very dangerous, and it is easy to get injured if you blindly try it without professional guidance. In addition to damage to the retina, head and cervical spine, if the diving posture is incorrect and the abdomen falls into the water first, the impact may damage the internal organs, or even cause fatal consequences such as spleen rupture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another risk comes from the complex and unpredictable underwater conditions of natural waters. Every time the diving team arrives at a new water area, they will send members to go into the water first to survey - how deep is the water and whether there are large rocks or sharp foreign objects. Wang Tieshun once found a shared bicycle and several broken beer bottles underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Safety is the most important thing for the diving team. In addition to their own safety, there is also the safety of others. Some young people passing by also want to dive with the old men on a whim. &quot;When encountering this situation, we will first dissuade them - if you haven&#39;t practiced before, don&#39;t jump blindly. If you jump, we will also remind you: the water depth here is not enough. If your head enters the water, you must raise your head in time, otherwise it will be easy to poke vertically to the bottom of the water.&quot; Meng Meng and his team members have encountered many such young people. Some of them couldn&#39;t wait to take off their clothes and shoes, and shouted to plunge into the water. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the training, Zhang Yuan rode his electric bike home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years, the team members We have rescued many people who accidentally drowned. &quot;Especially in the summer of 2023, which was extremely hot, more people came to swim than in previous years. Many delivery boys came here to take a shower. They parked their cars on the shore, took off their riding clothes, and plunged in. After a while, He was dangling in the water, and when we found out, we quickly swam over and pulled him ashore,&quot; Wang Tieshun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the 1990s, Meng Derui participated in the New Year diving event at Xinjiekou Gap&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fun and hidden dangers of natural waters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For adults and adults, on the premise of ensuring safety, the fun of swimming in natural waters is something that cannot be achieved in indoor swimming pools. Comparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the view is wide and there are few people. You can enjoy the natural scenery while swimming. Secondly, there is the water quality. Many adults said that they cannot stand the smell of disinfected water in indoor swimming pools, which &quot;makes their brains hurt.&quot; Natural waters like the South Moat are treated gray water, which is safe and odorless. Of course, there are also economic reasons. A swim in an indoor swimming pool costs at least dozens of yuan, and you only need to prepare a pair of swimming trunks in natural waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, as Beijing’s water ecological environment has gradually improved, the water affairs department has continued to increase the openness and sharing of river and lake spaces to meet citizens’ water-related needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About two years ago, a group of swimming enthusiasts that Zhang Yuan belongs to forwarded eight officially opened natural water swimming spots in Beijing, including Beijing Bay Sunken Square, Dongzhimen Triangle, and Yongyin Canal 8. A lake and the south moat where the diving team is currently located, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The warning sign here used to be &#39;No Swimming&#39;, but now it is &#39;Civilized Water Activities, Ensure Life Safety&#39;. Recently, the relevant departments have also equipped lockers on the shore. These are welcome new features. Weather.&quot; Mendry said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Regulations on the Protection and Management of Rivers and Lakes in Beijing&quot;, in non-water source protection areas and waters where there are no &quot;No swimming, skating and other water activities&quot; signs, event personnel or organizers should take safety protection measures. activities under the premise. However, due to safety concerns, relevant managers will dissuade you from doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every afternoon, the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team will train on the bank of the South Moat&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;The two movable jumping platforms currently used by the team members are made by Wang Tieshun, which is safe, easy to move without damaging the guardrails&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;Some managers are afraid of being held responsible for accidents, so they set up obstacles and prevent swimming in legal natural waters. We have our own ideas about this. Many of us have been swimming our whole lives, and we often travel in groups. How could something happen so easily? Among our team members, there are quite a few people who have rescued people who slipped and fell into the water, accidentally drowned, and committed suicide. Without daily outdoor exercise, how could we have the ability and physique to save people?&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an hopes to pay attention to nature. The management of water activities in water areas should not be “one size fits all”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As evening approached, Mr. Li, who lived nearby, took his children to the river to swim. The family had just moved to Dongcheng District for the purpose of studying for their children. One day I was riding by here and saw people swimming and diving in the river. The children also wanted to try it. Now they can&#39;t wait to come here to play in the water every day after school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For children, this kind of natural water area is definitely much better than the experience in an indoor swimming pool. You can have more fun here. Diving is not allowed in the indoor swimming pool, and you cannot change swimming lanes at will, because it will It affects other people.&quot; Mr. Li was a little concerned about the water quality at first, but the children swam for more than half a month and felt fine. &quot;The water quality here may have a higher microbial content, and the residual chlorine and urea in the swimming pool may be higher. . Chlorine is very harmful to the respiratory tract, especially children. If you keep swimming in it, there may be some potential harm. There is no such problem in natural waters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, a large area The water plants floated slowly, and the curious children wanted to catch them, but Mr. Li immediately stopped him, &quot;Don&#39;t touch the water plants, they will tangle you up and make you unable to move your hands and feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Beijing’s middle-aged and elderly diving team took a group photo with the Bayi Lake diving team who came to exchange and learn. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Diving is a spirit Relief&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking back on Meng Derui, the three years he spent learning diving in the sports school were unbearable. Other children were happily playing pinball and shooting cigarette cases after school, but he could only go to training hard. &quot;Although I was in the amateur team at the time, the training was very strict. A group of 10 jumps for each movement was counted, and five or six groups had to be danced in half a day. Basic skills such as leg presses and shoulder presses were interspersed in between. The coach was also very strict, and the movements were not up to standard. Just hit the bottom of the shoe.&quot; Meng Derui has a family with many children, and he is the sixth child. His family sent him to a sports school just to have a free place to take care of him and to exercise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Derui loves water by nature. He feels a sense of excitement when standing on the diving platform, and it is indescribable satisfaction when he jumps into the water. Later, when he went to the mountains and countryside, he took advantage of his lunch break to go to a nearby reservoir to continue practicing. After returning to Beijing for work, after dinner, I rode my bicycle to a bridge at Xinjiekou Gap to dive. On weekends or holidays, go dancing on the high platform of the outdoor swimming pool in Gongti or Taoranting Park. It costs 10 cents for two hours. At this time, there is no urging from the coach, but an inner need - when diving, you must concentrate on thinking about the movements and not have distracting thoughts, so that you can forget a lot of &quot;messy things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Mengdry helped take care of his grandson. Sometimes when he did not come to training in the afternoon, his teammates knew that he must have gone to pick up his grandson. &quot;At home, it&#39;s all about fulfilling obligations, being tired and worrying. Coming here to dive with everyone is the most relaxing and joyful thing of the day,&quot; Mengdry called it a &quot;spiritual relief.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the training, the team members shared their fruits, and the brothers occasionally met up to have a drink. If a team member has a birthday or someone’s grandchild is one month old, they have to find a place to celebrate together. Not long ago, Meng Jiao&#39;s wife broke her foot. Zhang Yu&#39;an immediately sent his unused wheelchair to his home and accompanied him to the hospital. Several teammates went to visit his home. &quot;The relationship between our teammates is closer than that of real brothers.&quot; Mengdry sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yuan had many hobbies when he was young and studied art and decoration in his spare time , photography and design. In terms of sports, he is involved in skating, skiing, swimming, diving, cycling, running, and mountain climbing. He knows that he is not good at everything but enjoys the process and joy of learning and mastering each sport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Zhang Yuan got acquainted with Meng Jiao and these like-minded teammates, and concentrated his energy on diving, almost without landing for three years. He felt physically stronger and more energetic than before. &quot;We seniors in our 60s have a very simple idea: move more, exercise more, get sick less, and put less burden on the country and our children.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an has many dancing friends around him, and many years of chronic diseases such as high blood pressure, hyperlipidemia, and arthritis have passed. Keep exercising and get effective control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training, Wang Tieshun rinsed his body with his own water. Almost every team member has such a homemade bucket&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One early morning two weeks ago, an 80-year-old man came for a morning tour of the moat alone. Died of sudden illness. After hearing this, the team members expressed their regrets. Zhang Yuan had his own thoughts: &quot;It is very sad that such an accident happened. But I think this old man died very happily and could immerse himself in his lifelong hobby at the last moment of his life. In this way Leaving silently is much better than struggling in the hospital bed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[和心智障碍者成为同事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nervous and scared, I pushed open the door of the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others, I don’t know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked forward cautiously, and no colleagues with mental disabilities showed up. Don’t ever encounter it, I thought silently in my heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pap tap tap~&quot; came the sound of footsteps going down the stairs, and around the corner I met the first colleague with a mental disability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl, with her high ponytails, smiling, with bright eyes, raised her hands and shook them at me, &quot;Sister...Hello, sister!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It was an opening that I had anticipated a lot in advance but didn’t expect. I didn&#39;t know how to respond to her enthusiasm, so I forced a smile on my tight face, said &quot;Hello&quot;, and turned around to go upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who knew that this girl was just here to lead the &quot;warm greeting army&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was catching up with my colleagues with mental disabilities in the factory who had changed into work clothes and went downstairs to do morning exercises. As they filed out, each one of them greeted me: some stopped and stood to say good morning to me. ; Some ran past me quickly, leaving echoes of hello drifting through my ears; others slowly walked downstairs, shyly saying good morning to me... The nervousness turned into surprise, and I suddenly Time just smiles and nods and says &quot;hello&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they finished walking, the stairwell became quiet again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I felt their outpouring of enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I walked up the stairs, there were pictures of them hanging on one side of the wall: profiles of employees working hard; employees participating in events; female employees dressed beautifully for Women’s Day... They seemed to be telling me: look! I&#39;m not dangerous, I can work, I can be beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing the entry procedures, the ordinary employees of the factory began to introduce me to the basic information of the entire factory and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked into the production workshop. Every colleague with mental disabilities was working seriously at his or her position. There was only the sound of the machine and the trainer&#39;s voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are engaged in some simple assembly and sorting work, which is boring, but they enjoy it very much. On my first day here, I heard that one of my colleagues with mental disabilities was called the &quot;Clamp King&quot; because of his excellent work on clamps. This resounding name was well known in the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The factory is very user-friendly and will arrange work according to their characteristics and provide them with some auxiliary tools to help them complete their work more efficiently. For example, when sorting two types of parts, one large and one small, because the difference is very small, the factory will use a 3D printer to make a slot into which one type of part can be placed, so that colleagues with mental disabilities can tell which type of part it is by placing it. As I got familiar with the factory, I secretly admired it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch, the employees lined up in an orderly manner when they heard the lunch bell and walked to the dining area carrying their plates. After I sat down, an employee sat next to me and started some conversation: Hello, sister, what is your name? My name is so-and-so, sister, are you here to work? Sister, you look so beautiful today. Sister, where are you from? … They spoke a little slowly and maybe a little unclear, but they were very polite. What surprised me most was that the girl with the twin tails said to me after finishing the meal: “Sister, I’ll eat and leave first, please take your time.” &quot;Then he picked up his dinner plate, wiped the table clean with paper, pushed the chair under the table, and left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They would sing their favorite songs in the lounge during lunch break, mostly catchy old songs. Some people sang seriously, some interrupted and made trouble, some sat quietly by the window and watched the scenery... The work bell rang, and they returned to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will not shout suddenly or rush to attack others. Observation is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was chatting with others that I was interning in a factory where people with mental disabilities were the main people. Others looked at me strangely: Can these people also work? Is it a welfare institution organized by the government? Before actually entering this workshop, I also had this &quot;strange vision&quot;. However, after truly understanding it, I realized that there is light and love here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be civilized and polite, they are the best practitioners of this slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a graduate student majoring in journalism and communication)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国三大车企工人首次同时举行罢工 前十天累计损失或超50亿美元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256852]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021183175256&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;The cumulative losses in the ten days before workers from the three major U.S. auto companies went on strike simultaneously for the first time may exceed US$5 billion.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2. myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12 51434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width= &quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the contract between the auto workers and the auto manufacturer expired on the 14th, and the two parties failed to reach an agreement, a large number of American auto workers began to strike in the early morning of the 15th local time. Analysts pointed out that the auto workers&#39; strike may plunge the operation of the auto industry into chaos, thereby affecting the US economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At midnight local time on the 14th, which is noon on the 15th Beijing time, the labor contracts of approximately 150,000 American auto workers with the three automakers General Motors, Ford and Stellantis expired, and both parties have not yet agreed. A new contract can be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250948&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, 12,700 workers of the United Auto Workers union went on strike at the three plants of the three major automakers in Michigan, Missouri and Ohio. This is also the first time in more than 80 years since the founding of the United Auto Workers that auto workers have staged a strike against the three automakers mentioned above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;United Auto Workers President Sean Fein said that a larger &quot;general strike&quot; has not yet been held, but said that if labor and management cannot reach a new contract, &quot;any option is possible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Auto industry analyst Garrett Nelson:&lt;/strong>;The most optimistic estimate we have seen so far is that in terms of strike costs, the cumulative losses in the first ten days may exceed $5 billion. The automobile industry is the largest manufacturing sector in the United States. If this situation continues into October and November, economic growth will definitely be affected in the third quarter and even more severely in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>