<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[走出村小的学生正在服务杭州亚运，让我看到教育的意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday will give you a few days to spare. While watching the replay video of the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games, I remembered that Xiao Yang, who I had been in contact with before and was now in Hangzhou, might be serving the Asian Games as a volunteer at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I immediately sent her a message, but it took a few hours for me to receive her reply: She was on rest during service, not in the library, but still busy... Finally, while she was resting During the break, I learned that she was working with several other volunteers this time to provide information consultation for athletes in the e-sports stadium, issue game passes, arrange for athletes to enter the lounge, and check-in matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at some of the live pictures and work photos of the e-sports stadium that she posted on her WeChat Moments, the more I looked at them carefully, the less I could recall too many scenes of her as a primary school student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was the first group of students I taught when I became a teacher ten years ago. At that time, compared with other students in the class, she was not necessarily very cheerful and lively, but she was serious, studious, and careful enough. She was selected as a &quot;study committee member&quot; very early. She lived right across from the school. Sometimes she would finish her homework in the classroom after school and then go home. She would also occasionally come to the school after dinner to chat with me and another young teacher who lived in the school. Although her grades in elementary school have always been among the best, even though she occasionally sent me holiday greetings after entering junior high school, and even though she heard my opinions when she filled in her application for the college entrance examination, I never imagined that the person who read the text aloud ten years ago A student who was not very loud and did not perform actively in public classes can now use fluent English to help e-sports players from different countries successfully enter the arena and complete the game and win their praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes me even more moved is that the starting point for her volunteer service for the Asian Games was an extremely ordinary rural primary school, a primary school with less than 300 people, a sports ground on dirt... A student can pass After ten years of study and continuous hard work, I entered the city, entered the university, and entered the Asian Games e-sports stadium with a sense of technology and modernity. I used my enthusiasm and professional ability to contribute to the Asian Games. I have always been in a township school. In my opinion, it is simply a miracle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not sure whether Xiao Yang could have imagined that he would have such a special situation when he was in elementary school ten years ago, high school five years ago, and college two years ago. But for me, a teacher who has taught her for two years, witnessed her growth, and followed her learning, there are too many surprises and too many gratifications. This surprise and relief was the result of seeing her continue to learn and receive education. It was so beautiful and good. Even the whole process and results were something that neither she nor I, who had experienced it, had ever imagined or expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my tenth year of teaching, many of my students have already entered the workplace early, some are still studying on university campuses, some are still preparing for the college entrance examination, and some have just entered junior high school. Whenever I wonder how much positive role I, as their teacher, have played in their growth and learning, Xiao Yang’s experience in serving the Asian Games should be the best answer I can give at the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a teacher in Suixian County, Suizhou City, Hubei Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010 ;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submit your contributions Email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[回故乡之路丨月是故乡明⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OHl0geXE8w.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OH l0geXE8w. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;203155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xiaochen 4x/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was born in Liling, Hunan. Since I left when I was very young, I have always regarded Pingxiang, Jiangxi, as my hometown. When I first heard that the capital of Anhui Province was called &quot;Hefei&quot;, I was as surprised as I was when I learned about the history of Pingxiang. Although this coal city in western Jiangxi is called &quot;Pingxiang&quot;, in fact, it has become a well-known industrial and mining city at home and abroad as early as the late Qing Dynasty with the rise of Anyuan Coal Mine; it is not only the birthplace of the Chinese workers&#39; movement, but also the autumn harvest. Why was the origin of the uprising named &quot;Pingxiang&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn’t it just Pingxiang? There are also many cities in China with interesting names. For example, the capital of Hebei Province is called &quot;Shijiazhuang&quot; and the famous porcelain capital of Jiangxi is called &quot;Jingdezhen&quot;. In the 1970s, a flood in the upper reaches of the Huaihe River washed out Henan Province. A prefecture-level city was named &quot;Zhumadian&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is either a town, a village, or a store. It is conceivable that most of these place names come from its history. But the combination of these two Chinese characters &quot;Hefei&quot; makes people feel strange. A cross talk once joked that it was &quot;two fat men sleeping&quot;. Later I learned that it got its name because it is located where the two Fei rivers in the north and south merge into Chaohu Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Anhui, or the first time to Hefei, was in May of 1993, when the flowers were blooming. At that time, I was still working in Pingxiang City. The two places were separated by more than a thousand kilometers. Because of the inconvenient transportation, Hefei felt like a distant existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent two full days on that trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set off early in the morning the day before. After taking the green train for most of the day, I first arrived in Nanchang and stayed at a small hotel near the long-distance bus station. The next day, I took a bus before dawn. Genius 1 bus bound for Hefei. Then, the car passed through countless villages and towns. The road was uneven and had potholes from time to time. After a day of bumps, the bones were falling apart. Lunch seemed to have been served at a roadside shop in Huangmei County, Hubei Province. It was probably the driver&#39;s personal designated restaurant. The food didn&#39;t look clean, and there was a strange taste in the mouth. This is nothing, the worst part is going to the &quot;bathroom&quot;. Although the car stopped twice during the journey, both times it stopped in the wilderness of Qianbuba Village and Hoububa Store; those two places were blocked. The sheds called &quot;public restrooms&quot; were only one person high and had no doors. The passengers were self-conscious at first and lined up at a distance, but the male compatriots who couldn&#39;t wait went to look for trees or grass that could provide shelter. To solve the problem, our female compatriots could only guard the toilet. The dirty floor in the toilet and the flying mosquitoes and flies made me retching uncontrollably. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order not to go to the toilet, I didn’t dare to drink a sip of water or take a sip of food along the way. By the time I arrived in Hefei, it was already dark and I was so hungry that my chest was touching my back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that terrible experience, I did not dare to return to my hometown. It was not until three years later that a railway was built between Hefei and Nanchang, and I began to return to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, this special line was not included in the national railway system and was only a local railway between Anhui and Jiangxi provinces. It starts from Hefei&#39;s West Railway Station, passes through Feixi, Lujiang, Shucheng, Tongcheng, Qianshan, Susong, and Wangjiang in Anhui Province, passes through Huangmei in Hubei Province, and then crosses the Yangtze River and enters Jiujiang and Yongxiu in Jiangxi Province. , and finally arrived in Nanchang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I do remember that the first time I boarded that southbound train was one morning at the end of 1996. At that time, our financial situation was still very difficult, and all we bought was a seat ticket. When my husband and I got into the car carrying large and small bags, we were surprised to find that there were very few passengers in the car. Although some people started to get on along the way, they were always sparse and there were so many empty spots that people could even lie down and sleep. Looking out the window at the rolling mountains, the sleeping fields under the winter sun, and the fleeting simple farmhouses, I felt mixed feelings. Fortunately, I no longer have to endure the pain of long-distance buses where I dare not even take a sip of water. Switching to a spacious and comfortable train, the time is shortened by nearly half. What is worrying is that there are too few passengers and the passenger flow is so small. Volume, let alone making money, whether the cost can be maintained is a question, and the economies of Anhui and Jiangxi provinces are still underdeveloped. If they are always losing money, can this train be saved? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This train arrived at the terminal, Nanchang, in the evening. Since there were no more trains to Pingxiang that day, we had to stay in Nanchang for one night. I remember we chose a hotel called &quot;Da Guangming&quot; on Zhanqian Road. &quot;Da Guangming&quot; is a small hotel. The rooms are poorly furnished and there is no separate bathroom. A very funny thing happened in &quot;Great Light&quot; that day, and even today, twenty-six years later, I still remember it fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While packing the luggage the next morning, my husband suddenly discovered that an envelope containing 3,000 yuan in cash was missing! The door was locked and the windows were bolted, so it was impossible for outsiders to come in and steal. But after searching every corner of the room, as well as the corridors and public toilets outside, nothing was found. My husband then went downstairs to find the waiter, and soon a hotel security guard came up. He said that only the two of us lived on the entire floor that day, and even if it fell on the corridor, it would not be picked up by anyone. What he meant was that the envelope could only be left in the room. So, in front of him, I took off the quilt cover, lifted the sheets, took out the items in the box one by one, and rummaged through them again, but there was still nothing. At this time, my husband made a request to him, &quot;Maybe I accidentally dropped it into the toilet when I was convenient and it was washed away. Can you take me to the sewer to have a look?&quot; The man did not refuse. He agreed, &quot;It is possible. Not long ago, a traveler dropped a watch and found it in the sewer. There were not many people staying in the hotel last night, and the water from the sewer should still be accumulated downstairs. I will take you Go down and look for it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a glimmer of hope, we followed him downstairs. He took out an iron rod with a hook from a corner, led us around to the small courtyard behind the hotel, and opened two The iron plate, underneath is the sewer. He bent over and rolled up his sleeves, completely ignoring the stench coming from the sewer. He held the iron rod and carefully raked it back and forth little by little. After raking it out three or four times, he still found nothing. He smiled at us apologetically: &quot;Nothing either!&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;If I really can’t find it, I can only admit that I am unlucky. We left &quot;Da Guangming&quot; sadly, took the train back to Pingxiang, and stayed at Dadi&#39;s house at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That year, my eldest brother was allocated a new apartment. This money was originally a gift to him, but unexpectedly something unexpected happened, so he had to owe it first. Unexpectedly, when my husband went to bed at night, he took off the black woolen jacket and something fell from his sleeve, and it was not the envelope containing the money! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for how the envelope slipped into the sleeves, there is no way to verify it; he didn’t even notice it when he was getting dressed, and he didn’t even notice when he put it all the way around, which shows that he doesn’t care about such trivial matters in life. He is a careless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While I was blaming his Madaha for giving me a false alarm, I was also full of guilt for the Da Guangming Hotel. Think about it, in the middle of winter, I had to dig out the gutter early in the morning, and I still looked unhappy when I left. I always thought that the money was lost in the hotel, and I even suspected that the waiter had picked it up! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the Daguangming Hotel and the tall security guard have been deeply engraved in my mind. Even after our economic conditions improved, I still chose to stay in &quot;Da Guangming&quot; every time I was in transit from Nanchang. Once, my son had a high fever in the middle of the night, but I did not panic and gave him medicine calmly because I believed that this hotel would definitely lend a helping hand if needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years later, this Anhui-Jiangxi line was integrated into the national railway network. The trains from Hefei to Nanchang were also extended from Nanchang to Guangzhou, and a pair of trains to Dongguan were also added. There are many trains to choose from, but both trains depart from Hefei at noon or evening, and arrive in Nanchang either in the evening or in the middle of the night; and the train from Nanchang to Hefei departs in the early morning, either in the middle of the night or in the early morning. When traveling between Hefei and my hometown, I still have to stay one night in Nanchang. I have been riding this kind of train for more than ten years, so I have stayed at the Daguangming Hotel no less than forty times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I don’t have a good impression of Nanchang Railway Station. Every time I leave the station, there will be a number of people holding signs to solicit guests to stay in the hotel, and they will keep pestering you; in front of the station When dining in a small restaurant, if you don&#39;t agree on the price in advance, sometimes you will be charged an exorbitant price, and you will have to consider yourself unlucky if you get ripped off, because those people are very rude and seem to be ready to use their fists at any time. Fortunately, this hotel prevented us from being too disappointed in this city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 2010, my journey back home changed again: Hefei opened two direct trains to the southwest, one to Kunming and one to Nanning; Both trains pass through my hometown. The former departs in the morning and arrives in the evening, while the latter departs in the morning and arrives in the evening. The time it takes to reach Pingxiang does not exceed twelve hours. From then on, my journey back to my hometown suddenly became very smooth. I no longer needed to change trains midway. I only had to buy a sleeper ticket, get on the train from Hefei after dinner, and sleep all the way to Pingxiang in time for breakfast the next day; or I was still in Hefei in the morning, and before the sun went down, I came to the streets of Pingxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the convenient transportation, the number of times I return to my hometown has naturally increased. It used to be once or twice a year, but now it has become several times. Something happened at home. I got a call the day before and I arrived early the next morning. It used to be difficult to meet my classmates and friends from my hometown, but now it is easy to meet once or twice a year. Whenever there is a school anniversary or class celebration event, as long as I can spare the time, I will rush back to join in the fun. , although I have been away from home for more than 20 years, my former classmates and friends have miraculously recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Spring Festival, my husband and I went back to our hometown to visit my mother. When we purchased tickets online, we unexpectedly discovered that the train from Hefei to Kunming suddenly disappeared; the train to Nanning was also absent. Pingxiang stopped. But at the same time, I was even more surprised to find that there is a high-speed rail connection between Hefei and Nanchang! Moreover, the high-speed rail departs six times a day, and the whole journey takes just over two hours! Then, I also discovered that the passenger train that used to operate between Anhui and Jiangxi had also returned, but it had also changed from the earlier green train to a motor train, and the time was greatly shortened to two hours and forty minutes! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 12 noon on the fifth day of the Lunar New Year, my husband and I boarded the train. Looking at the wilderness and farmhouses passing by outside the window, my mood suddenly returned to the unstoppable excitement I felt when I first took the train back to my hometown twenty-six years ago. In my impression, the speed of the green train at that time was only 60 kilometers per hour, and in order to prevent thermal expansion and contraction, there were gaps at the joints of each section of the rail. When the wheels passed by, a clear and audible &quot;thumping thump&quot; would be emitted from underneath the train. The sound of &quot;thump, thump, thump&quot; is especially loud when people are quiet at night; and now the speed of high-speed trains has reached more than 200 kilometers per hour. People sitting on the train can no longer hear the sound of wheels hitting the rails. It is so smooth that even the water in the cup can&#39;t be heard. It didn&#39;t move at all. As you can imagine, the rails today are obviously seamless. There are only twenty-six years before and after. Twenty-six years is not a long time, but it is enough to give birth to a generation. It is only a blink of an eye. In the past twenty-six years, China&#39;s railway transportation has indeed undergone earth-shaking changes. . In terms of speed alone, there used to be only local trains or express trains, but at the beginning of the 20th century, there were express trains and direct trains. By the 2008 Olympic Games, the first intercity high-speed rail line appeared between Beijing and Tianjin. The municipalities have implemented high-speed rail and public transportation, and it only takes half an hour to travel to and from each other. In terms of color, in the past, local trains were always green, while in the transition to express trains, there were red and blue. Later, high-speed trains and high-speed trains were all white. Now, high-speed trains have spread all over the country, and only Anhui Province has done so. Arrive at Shishitong High Speed ​​Rail. So, I discovered that the colors of the cars have been adjusted again: except for the high-speed trains, all ordinary passenger cars have returned to the previous green color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Green is the color of spring, which makes you feel refreshed and full of vitality. Of course, the bigger change is that today&#39;s rail transit has switched from burning coal to using electricity. This is a change of the times. It has not only become faster, but also cleaner and more environmentally friendly! So, I am guessing what kind of new energy will be used to drive high-speed rail and high-speed trains in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I searched on the Internet with great interest and found out that the high-speed railway between Nanchang and Hefei was officially opened to traffic this year, that is, in January 2022. I was earlier. One of the passengers who enjoys this benefit. There were not many passengers on the train that day. Just like the first time I took the local railway, most of the seats were empty. But I no longer have the worries I had back then, because the reason why there are so few passengers this time is not due to passenger volume, but due to the COVID-19 epidemic. Everyone is responding to the government’s call and trying not to travel if possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-speed rail not only greatly shortens the time compared to ordinary trains, but the convenience of transfer is also a major advantage. I have transferred at Tianjin West Railway Station in a municipality directly under the Central Government, and at Bengbu South Railway Station in a prefecture-level city. Both times I could transfer without leaving the station. This time, the train entered Nanchang West Station. We got off the train and followed the &quot;Convenient Transfer&quot; signs to get on the elevator of the station&#39;s overpass. We crossed the overpass and entered the waiting room directly. Because there are as many as 26 high-speed trains running from Nanchang West to Pingxiang North every day, we only stayed at the station for a short time and completed the transfer easily. An hour later, we ended our journey back to our hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about it, all this is incredible: from Hefei, between the Jianghuai River and the Huaihe River, to Pingxiang, the coal capital of western Jiangxi, the trip used to take two days and one night, but now it only takes four hours. Such speed was something I couldn&#39;t even dream of before. Many people have watched &quot;Water Margin&quot; and know that Dai Zong, the magical Taibo in it, can travel a thousand miles in a day and eight hundred miles at night. Everyone thinks that is just a myth. But with China&#39;s high-speed rail now, why does it take one day to travel a thousand miles? Two or three hours is enough! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the journey back to my hometown can be said to be a kind of enjoyment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次历届最火的迷笛音乐节，和乐迷遭遇的65起盗窃案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:50:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The classic scene widely circulated at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival: lifting a wheelchair man. The picture comes from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic image that has been widely circulated at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival: lifting a wheelchair man. The picture comes from the official Weibo of the Midi Music Festival&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After witnessing the two classic scenes of &quot;Mud Fight&quot; and &quot;Lifting a Wheelchair Brother&quot;, Liu Rui could have brought this exclusive experience of the Midi Music Festival with him Looking back, I ended my annual music pilgrimage with joy, but I didn&#39;t expect that an unexpected theft incident at the last moment destroyed almost all the &quot;beautiful things in this world&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This senior music fan, like many of his friends, has had a habit of going to music festivals during the National Day holiday for many years, but none of his previous experiences were as exciting as this one in Nanyang, Henan. Unforgettable: &quot;I have heard of things being thrown away at music festivals before, but it was not as serious as this time. This time it is too exaggerated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, &quot;Central Plains Midi&quot; in Nanyang, Henan &quot;Music Festival&quot; has been on the hot search topic list many times. Among them, according to reports from many music fans on social platforms, a large-scale property theft occurred in the Midi camping area on October 3. Videos and pictures provided by music fans showed that local villagers broke into the Midi camp and brazenly &quot;ransacked&quot; tents. , many computers, mobile phones, musical instruments and other valuables were confiscated. &quot;It&#39;s outrageous that my home has been moved away after I went to the bathroom. It was already an open robbery.&quot; A music fan told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, a reporter from Southern Weekend called the Nanyang Municipal Public Security Bureau. A police officer surnamed Lu responded: &quot;We are still registering the lost items of music fans. The specific situation needs to be contacted by the Municipal Public Security Bureau.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, the official Weibo of the Midi Music Festival announced that the local police received a total of 73 reports and implemented 65 theft cases. After investigation by the public security organs, some thieves have been captured and detained, and some property has been recovered. On the same day, the WeChat public account &quot;Nanyang Radio and Television Station&quot; issued a notice saying that based on the current registration situation of music fans, 79 ID cards and 3 computers have been returned , 17 mobile phones, and the remaining items are being verified and contacted. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Because of the rain, few people live in the camping area&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is the first time Nanyang has hosted the Midi Music Festival, which will be held for four days from September 29th to October 2nd. In order to hold this music festival, the local government opened a large open space in Huangshan Village on the outskirts of the country, planted a large lawn, and named it &quot;Green Field Monologue.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It rained for three days during the four-day music festival.” Liu Rui said that outdoor music festivals like Midi usually provide open spaces for music fans to bring tents for camping. At noon on September 29, the camping area was officially opened to music fans. However, during the past few days of the music festival, except for the sunny weather on September 30, it continued to rain for the other three days. After setting up their tents, many music fans only use them to rest during the day and choose to stay in hotels in the city and take a shower at night. For the sake of convenience, many people do not carry their luggage with them, but put it directly in the tent as usual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that the camping site is divided into three areas: A, B, and C. Among them, Area C where he is stationed is located inside. The theft was not serious. He only lost his power bank, The relatively low-value items such as power strips did not call the police. However, thefts in areas A and B near the exit, especially near the fence, are very serious. &quot;It seems that Shenzhen music fans put their things on the wall and suffered heavy losses.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to him, he had not heard of any &quot;lost things&quot; in the days before the festival. On the last morning, he returned to After setting up camp, many people found their belongings missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have a (music fan) organization, and we all camp together.” Wu Siqi is from Shenzhen, and this is her fourth MIDI tour. She recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that because of the rain, she only stayed in the tent for one night on the second night, and stayed in the hotel the rest of the time. She put her luggage in the tent and zipped it up. On the evening of October 2, I was in a very excited mood after watching the performance and found nothing unusual. When I returned to the camping area from the hotel on October 3, I found that the zipper of the tent had been opened, many belongings were missing, and some items were scattered beside the tent. It was obvious that There are signs of being picked up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After verification, she lost a mobile phone, several bank cards, some cash, and some souvenirs. &quot;They should have come in by climbing over the wall.&quot; Wu Siqi said that music fans can get a bracelet on site after purchasing tickets. There are staff on duty at the entrance, and they can enter and exit freely with the bracelet. &quot;There are people watching the entrance, and the security on the wall inside is poor.&quot; She said that the wall at the music festival venue is about two meters high and is not guarded by security guards, making it easier to climb over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wu Siqi communicated with friends from Shenzhen, they all suffered varying degrees of loss. She saw videos and pictures taken by music fans. Some people climbed over the wall and jumped into the camping area, while others were rummaging through tents in the camp. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Music fan Liu Ling lost her laptop, headphones, power bank, and goods used to set up a stall. When she went to the police station to call the police, she met a stall owner who claimed that more than 80,000 yuan worth of goods was missing. In order to find her lost items, she joined three music fan support groups. Each group has four to five hundred people, all of whom said they had lost their belongings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Liu Ling’s first time to participate in a large outdoor music festival. She had not graduated from college yet, so she took the green train from Guangzhou to Nanyang for more than ten hours. &quot;My family doesn&#39;t know about this yet. I&#39;m still in school now, and it costs a lot,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Another classic scene &quot;Mud Fight&quot;. Picture from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/06/8202470098.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ 8202470098.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Another classic scene &quot;Mud Fight&quot;. The picture comes from the official Weibo of Midi Music Festival&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;Multiple suspects have been arrested&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;After the incident, some netizens posted on social media that during the music festival, someone was broadcasting , once released the information that no one wanted the tents after the music festival, which played a misleading role. In response, the Organizing Committee of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival stated in an announcement on October 5 that on the morning of October 4, netizen Chen illegally posted false information that &quot;the event has ended and the scene must be cleaned up,&quot; causing nearby villagers to Taking advantage of the chaos, there were many cases of property being stolen in camping areas. The announcement also revealed that Chen, who published misleading and false information, has been arrested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t know what his mentality is, why would he send such a message?” Liu Rui said that on the second and third days of the music festival, he discovered that someone was “picking up” the moisture-proof mat. Within the acceptable range, &quot;I just want to pick up some small advantages.&quot; The turning point came on the penultimate night of the show, when items from the tent began to be stolen on a massive scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that he had participated in many music festivals before and had property stolen from time to time. He had even heard of gangs of thieves committing collective crimes, but nothing like this at the Nanyang Midi Music Festival. exaggerate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stealing is stealing. We do believe that a lot of things have been stolen from the entire camp.&quot; Wu Siqi said that she saw some netizens on the Internet excusing the villagers, thinking that what happened in Nanyang Midi The disgraceful incident was not considered theft, but the villagers &quot;took&quot; some items abandoned after the event. She believed that this argument completely ignored the facts, &quot;They are just denying the facts, and this is not acceptable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Siqi said that her trip to Nanyang Midi originally left her with very good memories, but the final encounter ruined these experiences. She said that due to the continuous rain, some music fans&#39; plans to camp outdoors were scrapped. The organizers provided free accommodation for some music fans who could not find a hotel temporarily. They caught a cold after being exposed to the rain. They could also receive free brown sugar at the music festival. Ginger tea. Details including transportation connections and other details are also in place, and the favorability level was once full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also had some contact with local residents. When she went to the city for a stroll during the music festival, the citizens she met were very enthusiastic, because it was difficult to take a taxi, and she also encountered well-meaning passengers and drivers who &quot;crash&quot; &quot;Give them a ride.&quot; &quot;I felt very warm and moved. As a result, when I returned to the camp on the last day, I found that my house had been robbed and stabbed.&quot; Wu Siqi said that the experience of these few days was magical, &quot;It immediately took me back from Utopia. It exposed the reality and made me see the dangers of society.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Kun is a music fan born in the 1970s. Due to the weather, he has been staying in the hotel, but he still witnessed the final &quot;fantasy&quot; scene. &quot;It feels like the mentality of fellow villagers who steal pumpkins, or overturn the fruit cart on the highway, and grab the fruit.&quot; He said that at first, it was just the mentality of taking advantage of it, &quot;picking up&quot; some worthless things, but later people saw that the advantage had been taken away. People picked them up and simply coveted the items in the tent. In the end, the situation intensified and turned into &quot;looting&quot; with open fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, a Southern Weekend reporter called the Midi Music Festival Organizing Committee. A person in charge said that the police have been called and detailed registration work has been done for fans who have lost their belongings. The public security organs have A special work team has also been set up for this collective theft case, and many suspects have been arrested so far. &quot;We compared the recovered items with our registration information at the scene, and have now returned some of the fans&#39; items. We also later learned that one of the netizens, Chen, spread false information on the Internet after the night of the 2nd. The message indicates that the event is over, and no one wants many things. Let everyone pick them up. At present, Chen has been arrested by the public security organs.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Encountering a &quot;Black Swan&quot; in investment promotion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Midi The music festival is an original music festival founded by Beijing Midi Music School. It is a music festival IP with a long history in China and has a deep foundation of music fans. In recent years, Midi Music Festival has frequently moved out of first-tier cities and been held in third- and fourth-tier cities in the mainland, which also has box office appeal. However, the arrival of the Midi Music Festival in Nanyang is an initiative of the Nanyang local government to attract investment and attract traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to local media reports, in May 2023, leaders of the Wolong District Committee of Nanyang City led a team to Beijing Midi Music School to discuss cooperation. The leaders of the Wolong District Committee said that Wolong District has sufficient development space and activity scenes. , hoping that both parties will promote cooperation, jointly ignite urban vitality, release industrial potential, highlight cultural charm, and inject more young forces into Wolong District&#39;s &quot;urban growth&quot;. The person in charge of Midi Music School said that Wolong District has a beautiful natural environment and broad prospects for the development of the cultural tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 2, the person in charge of Beijing Midi Music School said in an interview with Nanyang Daily that this music festival was very successful and set a box office record for the 47th Midi Music Festival in 30 years. , the number of live audiences also broke the previous record. There were more than 20,000 viewers on the eve of the music festival, and the number of viewers was close to 40,000 every day for the other three days. All tickets for the music festival were sold out in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, Southern Weekend reporters called the Wolong District Culture and Tourism Bureau of Nanyang City. The staff on duty at the bureau did not provide any more information about the music festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Rui said that because there are more restrictions in big cities, the trend of large-scale outdoor music festivals developing in third- and fourth-tier cities is very obvious. Local governments choose to cooperate because of the considerations of attracting investment and developing tourism; From the perspective of music fans, it is also a good choice to travel to different cities and experience the customs of different regions while attending music festivals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the music festival ended on October 3, but the National Day holiday has not yet ended. Previously, the usual practice was that many music fans would choose to continue visiting the city where the music festival was held for a few days, and then return Make return arrangements. &quot;So many people come here to eat, drink and play, which can boost the economy.&quot; Liu Rui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liu Rui’s view, before the theft incident, the entire event was actually very successful and basically met the organizer’s expectations. He said that because the lawn of the music festival had just been laid not long ago, after continuous rain, the entire venue was muddy, and it turned into a large-scale &quot;mud war&quot;, which became a scene that went viral on major social platforms and short video platforms; in addition, A young man in a wheelchair from Hebei was lifted up by many music fans to pay tribute at the music festival, and it became a classic scene that moved many netizens. These many factors have caused the 2023 Nanyang Midi Music Festival to frequently fail to appear, attracting attention from the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It turned out that everything went smoothly, but I didn&#39;t expect that something like this happened.&quot; Liu Rui felt sorry for Midi and Nanyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Liu Rui, Wu Siqi and Liu Ling are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特诺奇蒂特兰沦亡五百年祭丨古国多少事⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Flying from Atlanta to Mexico City, the scenery changes three times: first, from the flat and fertile southern plains of the United States to the sea and sky. over the Gulf of Mexico, and then crosses the Gulf of Mexico at a 45-degree angle, then enters the warm and tropical northern coast of Mexico, and finally reaches the rugged central Mexican plateau, which is the starting point of the northern end of the long volcanic belt that forms the Central American isthmus. The Pacific Ocean and the Atlantic Ocean connect the two continents of North and South America. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be clearly seen from the plane window that the moist air from the Gulf of Mexico is blocked at the northern foot of the Central Plateau, forming a continuous cloud belt, and finally turns into rainfall and moistens the northern coast again. The central plateau, with an average altitude of nearly 2,000 meters, is cloudless and the sun is scorching; there is little vegetation on the ground and it is very dry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The flight arrived over the Valley of Mexico, where the capital Mexico City is located, with an altitude of 2,240 meters, ranking eighth among the highest capitals in the world. Historically, this place was called Tenochtitlan. The precious precipitation from the central plateau gathered here and once formed continuous mountain lakes. It prospered as a result, and it perished five hundred years ago as a result. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;City of the Gods&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Although Mexico is the largest country in Central America, it has the Gobi Desert that stretches to North America in the west and the warm and comfortable Baja California Peninsula, and Yucatan in the east The peninsula has lowland jungles and savannahs, as well as alluvial plains and swamps on the north and south coasts. The topography is very rich, but its country name comes from the almost isolated Valley of Mexico (Valle de México) on the central plateau. This is because when the Spanish came to this area in the early sixteenth century, the most powerful city-state Tenochtitlan was located in this valley. Later it became the capital of the colonists: Mexico City, and &quot;Mexico&quot; became the entire The name of the colony - &quot;x&quot; in Spanish is pronounced as &quot;h&quot;, and the Chinese transliteration of &quot;Mexico&quot; comes from this. If it is pronounced in English, it becomes &quot;Mexico&quot;, which does not match the local place name. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Valley of Mexico is actually a basin. The basin with an altitude of 2,200 meters is surrounded by volcanoes with an altitude of 5,000 meters, which is insurmountable. Therefore, there are no outflow rivers here, and all the rainfall meltwater completely flows to the bottom of the valley, forming a rare large mountain lake in history - Lake Texcoco. Its water area reaches 5,400 square kilometers, and it is the largest freshwater lake in my country, Poyang Lake. about 1.7 times. Due to strong evaporation, the water depth of Lake Texcoco changes greatly throughout the year, forming a wetland around the lake that is repeatedly submerged and then exposed. This is very similar to the Tonle Sap Lake (&lt;span style) reported by this edition in October this year. =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Cambodia: The Trisolaran World of Tonle Sap Lake&quot;&lt;/span>;). This wetland around the lake is a rare livable place in the vast plateau. Primitive agriculture was developed here, making it one of the important birthplaces of ancient Mesoamerican civilizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mexico Valley Location Map&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to archaeologists Excavations have shown that humans lived here 12,000 years ago, and the city was formed around 1200 BC. The specific location was on the west bank of Lake Texcoco, on the western outskirts of today&#39;s Mexico City - China at that time was still in the late Shang Dynasty. The Wuding and Zhongxing periods. The city was later destroyed by a volcanic eruption on the west side of the lake. The people migrated to the east coast of the lake and settled in a mountain depression called Teotihuacan by later generations, creating an ancient city with a thousand-year civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ruins of Teotihuacan are Mexico&#39;s first World Cultural Heritage and a must-see for travelers. I went to visit it on the second day after arriving in Mexico City. The main landscape is a north-south central axis of the city called &quot;Yellow Springs Avenue&quot;, with dense Mesoamerican-style trapezoidal pyramid buildings on the east and west sides. The two largest pyramids are almost equally tall according to visual inspection, but the Moon Pyramid located at the north end of the avenue is higher, so the Sun Pyramid located on the east side of the middle of the avenue is actually taller. The base of the latter is square with a side length of about 225 meters. The top of the remaining tower is about 64 meters high. Originally, there was a magnificent temple built on the top platform, but since the entire ancient city was abandoned 1,200 years ago, the temple has been completely lost. Now it is impossible to know which god this temple was built for. , and it is not clear what the exact height of this pyramid was in its heyday. What we can determine is that it was built around 100 AD using 3 million tons of boulders without metal tools, livestock for transport, or vehicles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Imagination of Central American indigenous people building pyramids&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;I came here in mid-January, and chubby local tourists wearing short-sleeves and braving the scorching sun were waiting in a long line to climb the Pyramid of the Sun: the tower has four floors, and you have to queue up again on each floor before you can finally leave. It takes 2 hours to climb the 248 steps to the top of the tower. I sighed and gave up my plan to check in at the world&#39;s third largest pyramid. Instead, I climbed up the Pyramid of the Moon with steep steps, opened a can of Mountain Dew, and breathed calmly while looking down at the Huangquan Avenue in front of me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teotihuacan means &quot;City of the Gods&quot;. Like the &quot;Avenue of Yellow Springs&quot;, &quot;Pyramid of the Sun&quot; and &quot;Pyramid of the Moon&quot;, they are all speculations of later generations about this thousand-year-old city - - Since the Teotihuacan civilization left no written language and the stones themselves cannot speak, historians do not know its origins. They only know that it was a city-state civilization that originated in 200 BC. Its heyday was about 20 years ago. With a population of more than 10,000, it declined before the eighth century AD, leaving only the magnificent buildings and exquisite stone carvings that amazed future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1446&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The ruins of Teotihuacan are among the first batch of World Cultural Heritage sites in Mexico. The picture shows the Avenue of the Yellow Springs from the Pyramid of the Moon. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first wave of descendants of Teotihuacan were the Toltecs - the descendants were not Descendants, but those who come after. The Toltecs established a new city-state in Tula, not far to the northwest, and named this deserted but awe-inspiring ruins Teotihuacan, which means the place where the gods built: they obviously It’s hard to believe that this largest ancient city in Mesoamerica was built by humans themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second group of descendants of Teotihuacan were the Aztecs. They named the central axis of the ancient city &quot;Avenue of the Yellow Springs&quot; and named the two largest pyramids after the Sun. and the Pyramid of the Moon. They believe that the magnificent pyramids are mausoleums built by the gods for their ancestors, and these dead ancestors are the potential driving force supporting the movement of the sun - this is based on a method from Teotihuacan to Toltec to Aztec. Ke&#39;s consistent and unique world view is that the survival of the world depends on human sacrifice: nourishing the operation of the world with human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Aztecs are the protagonists of this story, the founders of Tenochtitlan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Lake Country&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Tenochtitlan is often called the &quot;Aztec Empire&quot; today, with the name ranging from &quot;Aztec&quot; to &quot;Empire&quot; In fact, it is not appropriate. Let’s start with the Aztecs (&lt;span>;Aztec&lt;/span>;). This is a legendary nomadic group from northwest Mexico. They migrated south along the desolate Mexican plateau and finally arrived in the Valley of Mexico, which is rich in water and grass. They settled here and became vassals of the Toltecs. After the demise of the Toltec civilization, they integrated with other local ethnic groups for a long time and formed an alliance among three major city-states. They used a common language and called themselves Mexica (&lt;span>;Mexica&lt;/span>;). That is, the people who lived in the Valley of Mexico formed a national identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we use China as an analogy, this is equivalent to the alliance between the two tribes of the Yellow Emperor and the Yan Emperor to build a national identity. Their descendants consider themselves descendants of Yan and Huang, and they call themselves China based on the middle land where they live. People - the &quot;descendants of Yan and Huang&quot; and &quot;Chinese&quot; here can roughly correspond to the two concepts of &quot;Aztec&quot; and &quot;Mexican&quot;. But it is obviously not appropriate to call China the &quot;Yanhuang Kingdom&quot;, because &quot;Yanhuang&quot; is an ancient myth passed down from ancient times; similarly, the &quot;Aztecs&quot; are also an ethnic group that exists in ancient myths, and they combine the real It is also inappropriate to call the country of the Mexica &quot;the Aztecs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;empire&quot;, as mentioned earlier, this is actually a loose alliance between three city-states, and there is no unified empire. Therefore, the so-called &quot;Aztec Empire&quot; was actually an alliance of city-states led by Tenochtitlan in the Valley of Mexico. These indigenous people called themselves Mexica and believed that they were descendants of the Aztecs. The civilization they established is now called the Aztec civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Restored map of Tenochtitlan, with east at the top. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what kind of city-state was Tenochtitlan? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that when the Aztecs moved south, they received a message from the oracle to find an eagle sitting on a cactus with a snake in its mouth. That was their new breeding ground. When they arrived at a sandbar on the west shore of Lake Texcoco after a long journey, they saw this scene and settled on the sandbar. They named the sandbar Tenochtitlan after Chief Tenoch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Aztecs built three long embankments to connect the sandbar and the lake shore from the north, west and south. They also built a long embankment between the sandbar and the center of the lake to isolate the waves. and attacks from across the Great Lake; they diverted mountain spring water from the west coast and supplied drinking water to the sandbar through the causeway; because the volcanic ash is rich in minerals, the soil around Tenochtitlan is very suitable for farming, and they rely on corn as their main food , also grow pumpkins, beans and amaranth; they also invented a type of floating island agriculture called chinampa (&lt;span>;chinampa&lt;/span>;), which is somewhat similar to the polders in the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River in China, using silt from the bottom of the lake to create fields. , fixed with wooden stakes and wickers, to form fertile artificial islands and expand the planting area; there are no domestic animals such as horses, cattle, and sheep in the American continent, and there are no fish in Lake Texcoco. They mainly raise dogs, rabbits, chickens and ducks to obtain For protein, the way to cook is to bake it on a stone slab &lt;span>;——&lt;/span>; Because the Aztec civilization was still in the Bronze Age and did not have iron pots; they laid a sewage system and put a large pot at the pipe joint. The garbage in the sewage settles in the large tank and sends people to clean it regularly; they implement Spartan-style military education for all people, while the nobles and rich can learn cultural knowledge; because there is no iron, their weapons are made of obsidian Spears, swords and arrowheads - obsidian is the &quot;national stone&quot; of Mexico. It is a natural glass formed after the cooling and condensation of volcanic lava. It is obviously not very durable. The obsidian dagger I brought back from Mexico returned to Shanghai on the first day It broke while my son was playing with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Obsidian arrow cluster&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Aztecs will witness The place where the oracle was spoken was designated as the center of the city-in their view, it was also the unquestionable center of the universe-and their temple was built here. This temple was later destroyed by the Spanish, and the first Catholic church in Mexico was built in front of it using the removed stones to suppress the &quot;evil spirits&quot; of the pagans. This is today&#39;s Catedral Metropolitana in Mexico City. ). 457 years later, municipal workers accidentally unearthed an important relic of the Aztec temple: the stone statue of the Moon Goddess. The Mexican government decided to demolish the building above the site and fully excavate the great temple so that the Aztecs could The gods are revealed again. So, today we can see two world cultural heritage buildings located side by side on the north side of Constitution Square in the center of Mexico City. On the west side is the Baroque Cathedral, and on the east side is the semi-open-air Tenochtitlan Cathedral. Temple ruins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Constitution Square has existed since ancient times. As early as the Aztec era, it was a large open-air market next to the Great Temple. The Spanish could raze the pagan capital to the ground, but they could not destroy a square into a primeval forest, so they left it as the central square in front of the cathedral. In &lt;span>;1821&lt;/span>;, in order to celebrate the promulgation of the Diaz Constitution after Mexico&#39;s independence, it was named Constitution Square. The government once planned to build an independence monument on the square, but due to financial reasons, it only laid a foundation. The Spanish word for &lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;foundation &lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>; is called &lt;span>;zócalo&lt;/span>;, so this place is half realistically and half mockingly called &lt;span>;Zócalo&lt; by people from all walks of life in the capital. /span>;square. Unexpectedly, the central squares in other Mexican cities would also be called this name after the capital. As a result, the word &lt;span>;Zócalo&lt;/span>; actually came to mean central square in Mexican Spanish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Great Temple Nested Model&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Great God The main building of the temple is a four-story trapezoidal platform similar to the Teotihuacan Sun Pyramid, but its size is greatly reduced - after all, the carrying capacity of the lakeside sandbank in Tenochtitlan is limited. There were originally two altars above the platform, respectively used to worship the Aztec sun god, war god and rain god, but they had long been destroyed by the Spanish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It doesn’t seem like much? No. The unique thing about this temple is that it has an outer layer covering an inner layer, with a total of six layers inside and outside - that is to say, there are seven temples in total from the inside to the outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s going on? It turns out that Tenochtitlan was a martial city-state that controlled other surrounding indigenous city-states and tribes. Whenever a monarch dies, the next ruler launches a coronation war to regain the loyalty of various territories. Once he takes control of the situation again and spreads military force across the country, he will ask all states and ministries to send people to Tenochtitlan to participate in the construction of the temple, and build a trapezoidal pyramid outer wall from the base to the temple built by the previous generation of monarchs. Wrap it up, cap the outer wall to form a new platform, and build a new double altar temple. The completion of this new temple marks the establishment of a new generation of monarchy, and can be regarded as the Mexican interpretation of &quot;the major events of the country are sacrifice and military service&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the big temples are nested layer by layer, becoming bigger and bigger as they are built. Using simple engineering principles, we can judge that the amount of earthwork in this &quot;matryoshka&quot; project increases in a cubic relationship, which consumes a huge amount of national power and is unsustainable. Tenochtitlan was founded nearly 200 years ago and built a seven-story temple, which cost as much manpower and material resources as the Pyramid of the Sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what are the series of large temples built over generations used for? Sacrificing human beings to offer sacrifices to the gods and pray for blessings - simply put, it is killing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chuck is a messenger between man and God, used to worship people&#39;s hearts. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Bloodthirsty Civilization&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The Aztecs believed themselves to be the descendants of the sun. It is believed that the sunrise is the result of the sun god&#39;s victory over darkness. They believe that the world has been destroyed four times and is now in the fifth contest between the Sun God and the Dark Gods. The Sun God needs his people to provide him with nourishment, which is human blood. Therefore, the Aztecs, regardless of gender, were accustomed to using sharp agave thorns to pierce their earlobes, tongues, chests and even genitals to collect blood as a sacrifice to the gods. The priests dipped blood from their temples to paint paintings and dedicated them to the sun god. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, blood collection is only a personal act, and a sacrificial ceremony more sacred than blood collection is a public human sacrifice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The late American archaeologist Patricia R. Anawalt once stated clearly in the opening chapter of her paper &quot;Understanding Aztec Human Sacrifice&quot;: &quot;The use of living humans as sacrifices has always been a common practice in the New World. It has appeared in the Old World. Such examples can be found not only in Central America, but also in Mesopotamia, Egypt and China. The difference is that Aztec human sacrifice has long been known. The understanding of the ancient culture of the Old World is a recent thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take our country as an example. The excavation of the Yin Ruins in Anyang started in the late 1920s allowed us to understand the large-scale development of the Yin and Shang Dynasties. Human sacrifices, 3,684 human sacrifice bones were found in Yinxu alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Aztecs’ human sacrifice behavior was even more shocking when exaggerated by the Spanish conquistadors. New discoveries from archaeological excavations prove that the Spanish records are not just a smear campaign against the losers. For example, Mexican archaeologists accidentally unearthed a large number of skulls near the Grand Temple. They were not like ordinary mass graves or mass graves, but were neatly arranged in a three-dimensional matrix in the same direction. After cleaning, archaeologists found strangely that there were holes on both sides of all the skulls, which were obviously dug through artificially. Finally, when the entire site was excavated, everyone understood what was going on: It turned out that there was once a five-row stone shelf more than 30 meters long and more than four meters high. There were many wooden beams inserted on the shelf, and the wooden beams were covered with clothing. Platoon&#39;s skull - as recorded by the Spanish. Later, it was buried with soil and the wooden beams decayed, forming an underground matrix of skulls. Archaeologists named this site &quot;Wall of Skulls&quot; in the Aztec language. They selected three skulls and strung them together with wooden beams for display in the museum behind the Grand Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combining written records and archaeological excavation results, it is now possible to roughly restore the human sacrifices of the Great Temple: under the watch of the vast number of citizens, the sacrificed human sacrifices formed a queue in front of the Great Temple. One by one, they were brought to the four-story platform and lay on their backs on the human sacrifice stones in front of the double altars; the chief priest held an obsidian dagger and cut open the chest of the human sacrifice, took out the beating heart and offered it to the Sun God; The priest threw the head off the pedestal, and the next-level priest cut off its head, peeled off the scalp, drilled holes on both sides of the skull and put it on the skeleton frame just mentioned; the limbs of the human animal were dismembered and returned to them The provider, the torso was abandoned, and the blood of the human sacrifice was mixed with corn tortillas as food to communicate with the gods. So when the Spaniards came to the Great Temple, the first thing they noticed was the accumulation of nearly two hundred years on the stone steps. The blood stains and its strong smell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;911&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Aztec human sacrifice scene shown in the Mariabeciano manuscript&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of human animals slaughtered by the Aztecs was quite astonishing. The often cited record in 1487 was that they slaughtered 201,400 people in four days, or 80,400 people. However, this number is unreliable because Tenochtitlan&#39;s population at that time was only 200,000. Considering that the &quot;400&quot; mentioned by the Aztecs actually refers to a large number, for example, the God of War, the youngest son of the Earth Goddess, once killed 400 of his brothers to become the main god, then this record may only mean 201 batches of human sacrifices were killed. Historians vaguely put the number of victims during those four days at 20,000—a staggering number even so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;provider&quot; of human sacrifice mentioned above, this involves the geopolitics of the Valley of Mexico. The Aztecs almost fanatically used human sacrifice to keep the sun rising in the east and setting in the west, praying for good agricultural weather, and maintaining the limited agricultural resources of this wetland city-state on a dry and rough plateau. But they did not want to waste their human resources, so they were keen to go out on conquests and obtain prisoners of war for sacrifice. Later, the surrounding tribes were subdued and were unwilling to continue fighting, and were willing to pay tribute to Tenochtitlan every eight months. But the Aztecs still refused to stop and continued to launch their &quot;crown&quot; wars, which were wars without religious, political, territorial or economic demands, purely to obtain populations for sacrifice, similar to the &quot;headhunters&quot; of primitive tribes. &quot;The behavior eventually evolved into various surrendered tribes regularly offering their populations to Tenochtitlan for slaughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the conventional human sacrifice methods mentioned above, there are two special human sacrifices worth mentioning: one is to sacrifice the sun god and the god of war, and the more &quot;high-end&quot; sacrifice is the captured enemy general. , he was tied by a rope to a large rock and unable to escape, using a feather stick to fight against the native warriors armed with maces and shields. If he can defeat four people in a row and win a fight with a left-handed samurai, he can regain his freedom - of course, this is purely a naked bullying; secondly, in order to sacrifice the rain god, the sacrifice used is a child - The Aztecs believed that the tears shed by children during sacrifices would turn into rainwater to irrigate their fields and bring about a good harvest. As a father, I will not elaborate on the process of this sacrifice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A rain god mask made of two intertwined snakes, with turquoise representing water&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Great Temple Museum also displays all kinds of strange sacrifices: jaguars, pumas, wolves, crocodiles, egrets, spoonbills, and even a large number of stone skulls - these may mean Aziz The Turks are emerging from ignorance and gradually replacing the barbaric human sacrifice. Unfortunately, with the advent of a group of living gods, they no longer had the chance to evolve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stone Skull&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;天外飞仙&lt;/h3>; &lt; p>;Five years after the human sacrifice of &quot;201 and 400 people&quot;, Columbus arrived in the Caribbean and began to establish a colony in Cuba. It took the Spanish 27 years to gain a foothold, and then on February 15, 1519, they sent an expedition fleet consisting of 11 ships, 550 people, and 16 horses to today&#39;s Mexico. Hernán Cortés is considered by Mexicans to be the most evil person in history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cortes first landed supplies at Cozumel Island on the east coast of the Yucatan Peninsula, which is now one of the most important ports on Caribbean cruises. He then led the fleet westward along the Yucatan Peninsula, and was regarded by the indigenous people along the way as a god from heaven: the indigenous people had never seen horses or cavalry, so they believed that cavalry had four legs and could move as fast as Flying gods and monsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cortes knew that he was alone and unable to compete with the entire indigenous camp, which numbered more than five million people. However, he soon discovered that this camp was not monolithic, but composed of Teno. The Tri-City Alliance led by Chititlan ruled a group of weak tribes against two hostile city-states east of the Valley of Mexico. Tenochtitlan&#39;s enemy countries were well aware of its bloodthirsty nature and refused to give in; Tenochtitlan&#39;s vassal countries had been crawling under its tyranny for a long time, constantly paying tributes and human sacrifices, and also complained endlessly. So Cortes wisely formed an alliance with these two city-states to deal with Tenochtitlan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Tenochtitlan side, the Aztecs greatly respected the Toltecs, their predecessors who ruled the Valley of Mexico, and fully accepted the Toltecs&#39; worldview. According to the myths and legends of the Toltecs, they left the central plateau of Mexico and sailed to the East from the Gulf of Mexico to pursue Quetzalcoatl, the main god worshiped by many civilizations in Central America. They would follow the white-skinned feathered serpent in 1519. God returns from the east to the Valley of Mexico. Therefore, when King Montezuma II heard that a group of &quot;floating castles&quot; had crossed the sea from the east and landed in the Gulf of Mexico, his first thought was: the gods have returned to the world! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Restored model of the Great Market of Tenochtitlan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 8, 1519, Cortez led an insignificant expeditionary force and 6,000 indigenous allies on the Central Plateau and then entered Tetra from the south shore of Lake Texcoco via the Long Causeway. Nochtitlan, saw this long-famous water holy city, which was also one of the most densely populated cities in the world at that time. He was received as a god by Montezuma II and placed in the palace of the king&#39;s father. About half a year later, perhaps the Aztecs saw the Spanish ambitions, perhaps the Spanish deliberately destroyed the Aztec statues, and a conflict broke out between the two sides. Montezuma II, who intended to settle the matter, was defeated during the negotiations. Cortés was taken hostage and later fatally wounded in the chaos of the conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year later, in May 1521, Cortes, who already knew the terrain and weaknesses of Tenochtitlan well, returned with 900 Spanish reinforcements and 100,000 indigenous allies. The Aztecs have been suffering for a long time! The former vassal states turned back one after another, creating a situation where the wall fell and everyone pushed back. The Aztecs fought alone, fighting on floating islands and houses in the intricate river network. After 93 days, the entire island city was razed to the ground and Tenochtitlan was destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the defeat of the center of the alliance, the entire Mexico was easily controlled by Spain. The colonists named this place Nueva Espana, which means &quot;New Spain&quot;. Another three hundred years passed, in 1821, before Mexico gained independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Palace of Nations mural shows Spanish colonists conquering Tenochtitlan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Ending&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Take Metro Line 5 from Mexico City Airport into the city. You need to Change to line 3 at La Raza station. La Raza is a large transfer station, almost equivalent to Dongzhimen Station in Beijing or Longyang Road Station in Shanghai. It takes five or six minutes to walk to transfer trains. Every time I pass by here, I will stay for a moment in the middle of the long corridor and carefully look at the Transformers family photos displayed in the glass cabinets on the roadside. It seems that I am transported back to my youth in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five hundred years ago, the Aztecs living here, like the earthlings in the cartoon, ushered in Transformers: Spain, which was technically powerful enough to cause a dimensionality reduction blow to them. people. However, in reality there is no savior as loving and benevolent as the Autobots. They eventually retreated to Tenochtitlan in the center of the great lake, and were massacred by the Decepticons led by the ruthless Megatron. The vast lake was also drained by these extraterrestrial beings, and it became a world that continues today. Sinking Mexico City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is how the Aztec civilization ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[智力残障女性被标“18.8万，交钱结婚”：婚姻介绍还是人口贩卖？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a blogger posted an article saying that the marriage proposal video released by a short video platform anchor was disturbing and attracted public attention. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;matchmaking anchor&quot; whose online name is &quot;Brother Cai (National Blind Date)&quot; has been publishing blind date information on the short video platform for a long time, clearly marking the price of the bride price. Many of the women introduced to the blind date are mentally retarded, and there is no lack of seriously uncomfortable content in the video such as &quot;188,000, pay to get married.&quot; Netizens suspected that the internet celebrity was a human trafficker who clearly marked the price. The anchor said that they are a &quot;regular matchmaking agency&quot;. If you need it, you can go to an offline dating agency for a blind date. After paying the bride price and paying an introduction fee of 20,000 yuan, you can take the person away. &quot;Marry first, fall in love later.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident caused a stir in public opinion, with many netizens believing it to be &quot;human trafficking.&quot; On the evening of October 4, staff from Mile Municipal Government in Yunnan Province told Upstream News that they had paid attention to the matter and that a special work team composed of multiple departments had been set up to verify the matter in groups. A closer look at this incident not only makes it uncomfortable, but also reveals some deep-seated issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the biggest question raised by this incident is, what are the legal and moral loopholes in such a short video matchmaking? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Marriage should follow the principle of voluntariness. &quot;Voluntary&quot; should be understood as being able to express oneself independently, having full capacity for civil conduct, and being able to make legally binding expressions of intention. However, the situation of people with disabilities is quite special. Whether they can exercise their full capacity for civil conduct to register for marriage needs to be considered on a case-by-case basis. If a disabled person only has a physical disability that does not affect their ability to identify themselves, they have full capacity for civil conduct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the disabled person is mentally disabled, they can also be subdivided into people with limited capacity for civil conduct who &quot;cannot fully recognize their own behavior&quot; and people who have no capacity for civil conduct who &quot;cannot recognize their own behavior&quot; . A person with limited capacity for civil conduct can only independently carry out civil legal actions that are purely beneficial, or civil legal actions that are consistent with his or her intelligence and mental health. In other cases, like a person without capacity for civil conduct, a guardian is required to exercise civil rights on his or her behalf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, does the guardian have the right to exercise civil rights on behalf of the disabled person and make important decisions about registering marriage? In this incident, the short videos of &quot;matchmaking anchors&quot; mostly followed the formula of &quot;age + intelligence + slogan + bride price&quot;. They clearly advertised &quot;blind date&quot; and &quot;flash marriage&quot;, and were directed at &quot;getting married for money&quot; from the beginning. &quot;Go.&quot; Do people with disabilities have the opportunity to express their true wishes during this period? Or will matchmaking agencies and guardians consult people with disabilities? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answers to these questions are of course highly questionable. Especially when motivated by interests, guardians may not respect the true wishes of persons with disabilities. Even from a human perspective, guardians face the real incentive of &quot;losing a burden and receiving a large sum of money.&quot; In this matchmaking industry chain, people with disabilities have become the parties with the least say, becoming a cash cow for matchmaking agencies and guardians. This goes against basic human ethics and raises legal questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2021 &quot;55-year-old man married a 20-year-old mentally retarded woman in Biyang County, Henan Province&quot; incident, the behavior of the female father involved once caused huge controversy. As the guardians of the mentally retarded daughter, the father and stepmother single-handedly &quot;arranged&quot; the &quot;marriage.&quot; Afterwards, the official investigation team concluded that it was not illegal for the two to live together, but they could not apply for a marriage certificate. This case shows that the legal validity of &quot;marriage&quot; is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the suspicion of &quot;human trafficking&quot; lingers in the incident, especially when combined with &quot;bride price.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;matchmaking anchor&quot; said in an audio interview, &quot;The normal gift for a girl is more than 150,000, and the minimum is more than 100,000.&quot; &quot;We have to charge a service fee of 20,000.&quot; One-on-one service, every one who comes here is successful.&quot; &quot;Get the certificate within two weeks and take your wife back.&quot; As netizens said, the &quot;clearly marked price&quot; in the name of betrothal gift is indeed directly reminiscent of human trafficking. This is not only visually uncomfortable, but also suspected of real illegal and criminal behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不论这位“婚介主播”多么强调自己的“合法合规”，“拿到彩礼两星期内领证”的操作怎么看怎么都像是变相的人口贩卖，“来一个成功一个”的表述更是让人完全看不到残障女性在其中的发言权，这在根本上已经违背了《中华人民共和国民法典》中“婚姻自愿原则”的法律条文，唯一可以作为补丁的就是监护人的同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;监护人的意见真的就可以代表残障人士的自主意愿吗？这是存疑的。同时，十多万的高额彩礼，最终可以用来改善残障女性的婚后生活吗？这笔钱最终会落到谁的手里，也是不问可知。如果监护人“收钱给人”，那么这无异于银货两讫的人口贩卖，退一步讲也是不折不扣的强迫婚姻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更有甚者，类似“婚介产业”还开发了针对残障女性的“细分赛道”。因为容易被操控，他们甚至还可以“反复回收”残障女性。 “买家”在结婚生子之后还可以“退回媳妇”，然后再“介绍”给下一家去怀孕生产，“婚介所”从中再收取一笔佣金，这又无异于直接倒退回已经进入历史垃圾堆的“生育奴隶制”了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚姻的基础应该是爱与道德，而不是买卖与算计。但如果加入残障人士这个特殊变量，买卖婚姻甚至买卖人口的性质就加倍地凸显出来。面对如此明目张胆的“标价征婚”，有关部门理应拿出不亚于“泌阳事件”的严肃态度，追查其合规性，保障残障人士合法权益，维护婚姻家庭价值观，不能让残障人士成为一手交钱一手交货的现代奴隶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[读《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》的乐趣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk9rrT15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk9rrT15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;村上春树和他的新著《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（CFP图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本作家村上春树喜欢收藏，其中一样他收藏的东西就是古典音乐唱片，特别是黑胶唱片，早前出版的《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》，就是写他所收藏的唱片精选。在这本把书的开本做成跟唱片封套一样的小书里，他说自己在过去60年来，在世界各地逛唱片店，买回来的旧唱片有过万张，他特别挑选一些最喜欢的，写一下喜欢的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上开宗明义说，这书“充其量就是一本个人偏好与兴趣的书，不具任何系统性、实用性目的，没有&#39;这张是这首曲子的必听盘！&#39;之类的推荐意图”。这书就像早前《村上T》的延续，读者很喜欢村上春树，想知道他穿什么的衣服，也想知道他听什么的唱片，如此而已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，古典音乐的每首曲子都有无数的录音版本，不同的指挥、乐团、演奏时间，甚至是同一首乐曲但不同的录制压制技术，都令每个唱片版本独一无二。在今天浩瀚的各个串流音乐平台，也只有不同录音版本的冰山一角。读村上这书的时候，总会有：啊！原来这首曲子还有这个版本，真想找来听听的冲动。不过，想要按图索骥把书里介绍的唱片找回来，很不容易，毕竟村上在书里介绍的唱片，很多都是上世纪五六十年代的产物，要么在旧唱片店里碰运气，也可到著名的唱片交易网站discogs寻宝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上说他挑选唱片都是个人偏好，也因此有不少古典乐迷对他的选择都有意见，但讲到明底个人偏好，自然各人所见所喜都有不同。就像村上自己说他不太喜欢钢琴家布伦德尔（Alfred Brendel），但布伦德尔本来就有很多人喜欢。喜欢哪个版本、哪个指挥，很多时候都是和自己的经验有关，而村上跟著名指挥小泽征尔是好朋友，他就自然更偏好小泽征尔的版本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在个人经验之外，另一个原因就是对乐曲诠释的偏好，有些时候音乐家对乐曲的演绎手法都很有特色（甚至到了哗众取宠的程度），乐迷不埋单（或反过来很喜欢）的原因也相对容易可以说出来。举个例吧：马勒的第七交响曲，如果听克伦佩勒（Otto Klemperer）的版本（跟大部分版本比较，全曲长了差不多20分钟），那种极度缓慢的风格，感觉就像看着远处的火车驶进月台，火车逐渐靠近但又总是永远没到达似的，有人说这是一种张力，但我自己就很不喜欢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论怎样，村上在写这些乐评的时候，始终有他独到的手法，让读者即使只是在读村上的古典唱片短评，也一样有读村上春树文字的乐趣。就如他说钢琴家古尔达（Friedrich Gulda）跟维也纳爱乐（阿巴多指挥）录制的莫扎特第25号钢琴协奏曲，听起来“有一种像是在大阪乌龙面店吃清汤乌冬面般不可思议的安心感”；又或是Thomas Beecham爵士指挥海顿的第94号交响曲，总是有种“风度翩翩的旧时代英国绅士印象，就连第二乐章的&#39;惊愕&#39;（surprise）部分，惊吓方式也是稳健又高雅，这种程度的惊吓就连端着茶杯的妇女也不会吓到红茶溢出来”。这些比喻，非常独到，非常的村上春树。莫扎特也好，古尔达也好，怎会想过自己的作品，竟然变成了一碗大阪的清汤乌冬？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，回到一个重要问题：现在听古典音乐，为何还要听黑胶唱片？又或者更大的疑问是：黑胶唱片怎么会起死回生？黑胶唱片的回归，是人类发展史上其中一个最励志的故事。明明已给时代淘汰，笨重又脆弱，承载量少得可怜，但事实证明：只要有价值，哪怕满满缺点，还是有存在的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村上春树在《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》中说，听黑胶唱片是“那种只要悉心对待，就会有所回应的东西”。在一切都是数位的年代，付出和回应早已变成非常公式的交换，什么都是一个按钮换来一个反应，失去了用心付出所换来的满足。就像你再小心温柔地轻触手机上的串流音乐平台、播放乐曲，播出来的音乐，也绝对不会有任何分别（所以实际上我们也自然不会怎样温柔地轻触手机）。 “有所回应”的特质在现今冰冷的世界已经变得稀有，也因此才会令黑胶唱片在今天复兴起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听黑胶唱片，从买唱片到播放，每一步都讲求“悉心对待”的付出。其中之一是音响播放，无论是听黑胶唱片还是听串流平台，本来就是深似海的学问。像最基本的唱盘、前级后级功放（音讯扩大机）、喇叭，或唱盘所用的唱头和唱针、连接设备的线材和接头，甚至是唱盘上放唱片的唱片垫，全部都讲究。村上春树也说，音响是个“行有余力才能培养的兴趣，这也是没办法的事，只能有此觉悟”。话虽如此，只要不是买几百元货色、只有外表的那种一体化播放唱盘，简单一套像样的入门音响设备，价钱其实也是亲民的，并且已经可反映出黑胶唱片的珍贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是音响设备，买（和找）黑胶碟也是讲求付出的活动。像在欧美等地方，不同社区都有救世军、乐思会等卖二手旧物的店，在这些旧物店里，总会有个角落，放满一箱箱的旧唱片，如果有负责任一点的店员（或是整齐一点的物主），都会把唱片分类放好。这个时候，慢慢蹲下来，把唱片逐张翻一翻、看一看，每一张都是未知，随时遇上心头好。这些旧唱片，很多时候都只是十元八块的价钱，便宜到不得了。跟一般旧唱片店不一样，这些旧物店都是非牟利的，负责人既无暇慢慢定价，也通常没有内行人一样懂得行情，了解货品的价值。所以，很容易在这些旧物店找到宝藏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在旧物店买到的唱片，唱片的状态不一，通常要花更多时间来好好清洁，有时也会买到损毁了的唱片，这些都没法避免，只好在买的时候再仔细检查看看。但像村上春树所说，即使是旧的唱片，只要用心去清洁（清洁唱片也一样有学问），清洁前后的播放音质，还是有显著的分别，至少唱针不会在播完唱片之后积起一堆尘垢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较之下，专卖旧唱片的商店，很多时候都对唱片做基本的清洁，并清楚标明唱片的状态、品相，相应地，定价也会相应地昂贵。比较世界各地不同的唱片店，日本的唱片店，往往是最整齐和最清洁的。难怪好朋友焦元溥老师说，他去日本的中古唱片店，每一次进去就是7个小时，每次都是天光逛到天黑。听他的分享，无论是精神还是财力，都是非常大的付出，当然每次也是换来大丰收吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大城府：泰国那一抹“永恒的微笑”丨古国多少事⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;暗红色的海洋&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如今无论从曼谷考山路包车，或者坐火车约一个小时，当可以远眺到尖塔和金碧辉煌的路牌时，浓厚的历史气息就会扑面而来——坐落于湄南河冲积平原上的大城府，地处暹罗湾潮汐线上方，这个四面被湄南河、华富里河、巴塞运河环绕而形成独特的岛城，有水道通向南方的暹罗湾，可通中国与东南亚诸国，又紧扼北方素可泰的出海门户，成为中、印、欧的地理连接点，更造就了它在贸易、军事、外交上得天独厚的条件：14至18世纪，发达的水陆交通和耀眼的佛教建筑让它的名声享誉东南亚乃至整个亚洲，甚至被目为东南亚最大最美丽的城市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199733&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玛哈泰寺的佛像与遗迹&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1350年，湄南河西岸的罗斟（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今华富里&lt;/span>;）政权首领拉玛铁菩提（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ramathibodi I，乌通王&lt;/span>;）战胜泰国第一个封建王朝素可泰王朝，罗斟与河东岸素攀政权暹国合并，建立阿瑜陀耶王朝，中国史籍称“暹罗”。当曼谷还是名不见经传的小渔村时，阿瑜陀耶王朝定都之地，已是一座繁华“大城”——旅泰华人认为此城最大，故称“大城府”，连王朝都亦称“大城王朝”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在历史文献中，大城府被称为“天堂”，鼎盛时期人口约有100万，三座王宫、超过2000座镀金尖塔式庙宇和4000多尊镀金佛像，让这里处处金碧辉煌；历33位国王、延世417年的王朝，将佛教文化送上巅峰。大城王朝中后期时，明人张燮还在他的《东西洋考》“暹罗条”里写：“其土下湿，气候岚热不齐，民悉楼居，楼密联，槟榔片藤系之甚固，藉以藤席，竹簟寝处其间。王宫高九丈余，以黄金为饰，雕缕八卦，备极弘丽。”16世纪开始，大城府的声名远播欧陆，1512年葡萄牙人首抵此处，大城府逐渐在17世纪成为贸易中心，欧洲各国使节纷至沓来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说几百年前大城府的主色调是金色，而今这里，武断一点而言，市中心只有红褐与焦黑两种颜色：红褐色是建筑早已蒙尘的砖块，烈日烤灼、风雨侵蚀，让凹凸不平的地面与墙面，一起化为一片暗红色的海洋。大城府的诸多古刹，乍看之下是吴哥窟的翻版，但仔细鉴赏之后就能发现，与多用大石块构成的吴哥诸寺不同，这里多用红砖；没有吴哥窟雕花墙壁、百转千回长廊，这里却衍生出许多大城王朝时期独有的建筑风格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;罗卡雅苏塔寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Lokaya Sutha&lt;/span>;）已经不能被称作“寺”，一片蔓生荒草中，巨大卧佛裸露在自然中接受朝拜；建于1491年的帕西桑碧寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Phra Si San Phet，三王庙&lt;/span>;）残存的三座白色锡兰式佛塔一字排开，已成大城府地标：1492年，为供奉父兄骨灰，拉玛铁菩提二世在寺中兴建两座佛塔，开启了泰国用佛塔存放国王骨灰的丧葬习俗，1529年拉玛铁菩提二世驾崩，其子又修建一座佛塔。而今时光还没有把它们摧毁殆尽，旁边历代国王依次修筑的许多小塔虽然破损严重，却依然壮观高耸，如同肃穆的卫兵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;帕西桑碧寺以东，即是以正居院中的宏伟佛塔而闻名的拉嘉布拉那寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Ratchaburana&lt;/span>;）。这座高棉样式的佛塔原本为泰式，系九世王替两位争夺王位继承权决斗而死的兄长举行火葬而建：1424年，因陀罗阇王去世，骑大象自相残杀的两个王子死后，三子从彭世洛南下继承王位，成为波隆摩罗阇二世（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat II&lt;/span>;），建设这座寺庙存放兄长骨灰。穿过如同大三巴一样只剩一面墙壁的大门，四周全是支离破碎的佛像与围墙，仿佛突然掉进遥远的古代。似一根玉米一样的主塔上，楞状塔饰层层叠叠；四周环绕四座锡兰式小塔，乃城中保存最为完整的高棉风格佛塔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城中最古老的寺院则在护城河外东南角，崖差蒙空寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Yai Chaiyamongkho&lt;/span>;）为1357年乌通王为纪念王朝诞生而建，与城内充满沧桑感的废墟式庙宇不同，这里随处可见重建的痕迹，却并不让人觉得突兀，甚至还不如佛塔披挂的黄绫与斑驳的红砖给人的视觉反差强烈。长达28米的洁白卧佛是这里的标志，身披黄色袈裟安详侧卧在白花花的炙热阳光下，淡泊地注视周围饱经风霜的土地与河流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爬上锡兰式主塔，内部有八座佛像，更令人难忘的是一种混合的奇怪味道充溢其间，硝烟夹杂腐败植物的味道，更多的是人体臭气，让人难于呼吸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;柴瓦塔那兰寺，佛像的背影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;繁荣的黑暗倒影&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在游人绝迹之时，崖差蒙空寺的卧佛周遭，徒留一片历经岁月洗涤过后的宁静——主塔四周，许多无头佛像静默着，似乎并不想诉说它们所经历的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿瑜陀耶的名字来源于印度史诗《罗摩衍那》中罗摩的诞生地及凯旋归来后的登基之地阿约提亚（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ayodhya&lt;/span>;），梵语意为“不可战胜之城”或“永恒胜利之城”，但这名字一如谶语：作为继高棉帝国之后第二个东南亚“超级大国”，当大城王朝达到鼎盛时期之时，它与缅甸之间的战争也绵延展开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一切辉煌总有一个终结。 1766年，觊觎大城府已久的缅甸王孟驳率军围城14个月之后，炸塌城墙攻入城中，在15天的烧杀抢掠之后，三万人沦为俘虏，大城府几乎被夷为平地。不可战胜之城却在战乱中破败——这个泰王国历史上持续时间最长的朝代，带着它所有的风华，在1767年戛然而止，只有十几座“洗尽铅华”的寺庙遗迹——红砖上多见黑色火烧污渍，佛像也被火焰熏得黧黑，沉默不语伫立城中，为大城王朝的黄金时代聊作见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府，红的对面是黑。拉嘉布拉那寺之南，玛哈泰寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Mahathat&lt;/span>;）据说是缅甸军队攻打泰国的首要目标：这座始建于1374年即二世王波隆摩罗阇一世（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat I&lt;/span>;）统治时期的寺院曾拥有10余处僧院、立有如丛林般的200余座佛塔，如今寺院正中只剩巨大方形塔基，小塔亦多严重倾斜，摇摇欲坠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;柴瓦塔那兰寺的成排无头佛像&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府诸寺，很多“排排坐”的佛像，无一例外都没有头，地上墙角会“惊现”一双石雕佛脚，抑或一只巨大佛手，观之十分“后现代”。也许正因如此，许多游客喜欢屈膝躲在佛像后，将自己的头从佛像破损的颈口伸出来拍照。其实，那些玛哈泰寺中的佛像与佛塔，身镀黄金，或体内藏有金叶，引得缅军将佛像斩首，或以大火焚烧，令黄金与石头分离，热胀冷缩造成佛像头部、手脚断裂，留下残肢断臂的满目疮痍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大城府如同圆明园。阳光给柴瓦塔那兰寺（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Chaiwatthanaram&lt;/span>;）的高塔涂上金黄，让红砖拥有了狞厉之美，带人回到战火纷飞的时代。当红已变成黑，浮屠兀自伫立，斑驳佛塔、破烂砖墙、黝黑佛像、浩大古迹，毫不留情地掩盖了繁华与覆灭，只有残留的文献与口述的故事世代相传，岁月亦如过眼云烟——盛世的繁荣也会成为幻灭的倒影，一如柴瓦塔那兰寺中，夕阳里高坐于几乎坍塌的基座上的佛像，那恒久的落寞背影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;军队入侵之际，佛寺尽毁，刀落之处，如作家翁达杰语，“菩萨意味深长的巍峨法相倒向地面，坠入土中”。在漫长的时光中，一颗佛头被千年菩提之根紧紧包裹，环绕的枝蔓将它缠绕于其中，形成了树包佛头的奇观，亦是玛哈泰寺最著名的“永恒微笑”。如同吴哥窟中塔布伦寺景色的“终局”一样，东南亚树木的绞杀现象会让植物最终取代寄主，但而今佛像仍在菩提树中闭目微笑，不着一语，仿佛看尽王朝风云变幻，那是一种与事件万物同在、超乎生死的神奇气度，让人们可以一直站在它面前，注视它很久很久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玛哈泰寺的树包佛头奇观&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千千万万人用时间将大城府筑起，大城府又在光影里注视着这千千万万人生成的世界。大城王朝覆灭后，郑信将泰国都城南迁近百公里至吞武里，历经仅15年的吞武里王朝后，1782年曼谷王朝定都曼谷，在新的土地上书写繁华，大城府则愈发淡出人们的视线了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两百余年光阴倏然而过，如今这里更像一个充满乡村气息与休闲氛围的小镇。遗址公园内，草坪、绿树、水塘，一派田园风光；当地人会铺张席子随意野餐，或者租下传统服饰，模仿在此取景的热门电视剧《天生一对》，在遗址中拍照。红与黑的遗址紧挨着新建的民居与寺庙，残砖败石中烟火水乳交融，有种穿越时空的错愕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;邦芭茵夏宫草坪的大象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大城府与曼谷之间，始建于17世纪的邦芭茵夏宫（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bang Pa-In Summer Palace&lt;/span>;）是泰国最大最美的王室行宫，19世纪经曼谷王朝的拉玛四世、五世国王下令修复后，泰国、中国、缅甸、哥特诸式建筑风格俱全；更有典型泰式“三尖顶”的金色水上皇亭，粉蓝、淡紫、纯白的建筑群颇为小清新，搭配上做成可爱象群的热带绿植，邦芭茵夏宫挥别了浓烈的红与惨烈的黑，洋溢着一个新的时代的清爽之绿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运女篮铜牌赛上演朝韩对决，韩国以93比63获胜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258150]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿在防守韩国队球员。本场比赛她16投11中，交出了一份27分9篮板3助攻1盖帽的成绩单。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253069&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿在防守韩国队球员。本场比赛她16投11中，交出了一份27分9篮板3助攻1盖帽的成绩单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月5日，杭州第19届亚运会女子篮球铜牌争夺战在杭州奥体中心体育馆举行。韩国队以96比63胜朝鲜队，夺得该项目铜牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;朝韩女篮在小组赛的遭遇战中，韩国女篮凭借整体出色发挥，以81比62击败了朝鲜女篮，取得了比赛的胜利。 10月5日的比赛虽然只是铜牌争夺战，依旧是一场极具关注度的比赛。有着“朝鲜女巨人”之称的朴津阿缺阵对战中国女篮的半决赛之后，此番再度对阵韩国队复出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，作为神秘且很少外出参赛的朝鲜女篮，站到四强的高度，体现出了她们顽强拼搏的体育精神。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253070&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，作为神秘且很少外出参赛的朝鲜女篮，站到四强的高度，体现出了她们顽强拼搏的体育精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队17号球员朴津阿持球起跳射篮。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253071&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队17号球员朴津阿持球起跳射篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝韩双方球员在比赛中拼抢。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253072&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝韩双方球员在比赛中拼抢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从开场的热身和训练状态就可以看出朝鲜女篮的复仇决心。朴津阿在首节比赛中的效率非常之高，不仅有持球得分，在助攻和篮板上都有出色表现。在攻防两端，朴津阿都有盘活球队的能力，朝鲜队21比15领先第一节。然而进入第二节，朝鲜队的失误非常多，投篮命中率也出现下滑。韩国队中锋朴智修在第二节下半段也有非常出众的表现，不知不觉拿下了17分。半场结束前，韩国队将比分锁定在40比33，压力来到落后的朝鲜队一边。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，在观众席上为朝鲜队加油助威的观众。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253073&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，在观众席上为朝鲜队加油助威的观众。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，韩国队球员朴智修突破朝鲜队球员的防守。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253074&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，韩国队球员朴智修突破朝鲜队球员的防守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队12号球员芦淑英带球突破。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253075&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队12号球员芦淑英带球突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队教练对球员进行指点。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253076&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，朝鲜队教练对球员进行指点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下半场，朝鲜三分钟内将比分追至40平，随后两队中锋各中一个中投，42平。接着朴津阿和队友内外呼应连续出现问题，比赛以44比61朝鲜队落后进入第四节。第四节成了韩国队的表演时刻，尤其是韩国队老将金丹菲不声不响拿到21分，更是以三分球8中5把全队三分球带到25中13。全场比赛还剩三分半钟的时候，韩国队已经84比51领先33分。朝鲜扔进压哨超远三分，比分定格在93比63，朝鲜女篮以30分之差不敌韩国女篮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月5日，比赛结束后，韩国队球员合影留念庆祝。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253077&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，比赛结束后，韩国队球员合影留念庆祝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;打满全场的朝鲜队球员朴津阿虽然拿到全场最高的27分，但双方的账面实力差距太大，面对韩国队全场27中14的三分球，显得杯水车薪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欧洲公厕为什么很少且收费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258137]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;厕所看似小事，却也是社会必需之物，很多时候可以反映出一个社会的历史与当下，中外概莫能外。每个去欧洲旅行过的人应该都体会过厕所之困。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲各国普遍公厕很少，往往方圆几公里或许才能找到那么一个，所以欧洲有找厕所的APP，相比之下，中国找厕所的功能，都被地图APP涵盖了，不是一个热门功能，不能单独撑起一个APP。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了少，欧洲的厕所还要收费。很多欧洲国家例如英国、荷兰、德国等地方，使用公厕都是要付钱的，比如德国的高速服务区或是商场配套的厕所，多数都要收费。就连快餐店、商场、火车站、麦当劳、肯德基的厕所也都是要收费的。比如在德国科隆，麦当劳里面的厕所也要收费。再比如，波兰一家肯德基就贴出告示：店内厕所只提供给顾客，没有消费收据的人如果想使用厕所需付费30兹罗提（约合53元人民币）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收费的形式也五花八门，有专人坐在门口收费，有投币后闸门转动，有些是相信自觉，放一个小费盘。有些店，是厕所门有密码，而密码打印在购物小票上。德国的百货商场中并非每一楼层都设有洗手间，一般在最顶层的餐馆层附近，使用洗手间一般免费，但如果有清洁工人在，一般都要留下0.3欧元左右的小费。如果是在旅游区，还会贴心地提供汇率转换，各国货币明码标价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲厕所的收费，并不便宜，上一趟洗手间少则0.3欧多则2欧的费用。 1欧元等于7.7元人民币，相当于两块钱到15块钱之间，即便收入高些，在欧洲上个厕所也是真不便宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲作为全球最富裕的地区之一，也是“社会福利”最完善的地区，为什么很少有免费的公厕？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是因为历史。在欧洲的许多城市，比如英国伦敦、瑞典斯德哥尔摩、法国巴黎，都有街边半开放的露天厕所。它能包裹住下半身，但只能男性使用。这些露天小便池，在当地的使用频率非常高。这种奇怪的街头小便池在欧洲有近200年的历史了。这也反映了欧洲缺公共厕所是有历史渊源的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个历史路径就导致，人们未必把公共厕所视为一种政府义务。实际上，欧洲很多地方的公厕基本是私营化了的。既然如此，就按市场思路解决问题。厕所要定期保养、维修，还需要请人清洁，欧洲国家多为发达国家，人工成本高，这都造成了厕所的维护费用很高，商家不愿意把它放入一揽子服务中，而是单独收费提供。欧洲的咖啡馆、小酒吧等营业性场所的私人厕所，承担一些公共厕所的作用，当然得先消费再如厕。欧洲人也习惯了付费使用公厕，或者去咖啡店买杯咖啡，顺便解决内急问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲各国情况还不完全相同，在高税收高福利的丹麦，政府就认为，上公厕自由是政府必须达标的一项公共服务。所以，在人口不多的首都哥本哈根市区，公厕的数量足、环境好，还免费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，中国厕所也曾收费。 1970年代后期至1980年代末期，经济发展起来了，中国各城市相继开始建设较高档次的公厕，实现了水冲和机械抽运。公厕等级提高了，成本随之上升，部分城市公厕开始收费，以缓解公厕建设管理资金短缺的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了20世纪末，随着经济的进一步发展，中国人对厕所的要求开始变高，新建住宅小区，厕所从一卫增至两卫。但是，公共厕所的免费，并没有那么早。像青岛这样的中游城市，直到2008年5月1日，公共厕所才实行免费开放，到现在不过15年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;免费公厕，说到底还是政府有钱了。经过改革开放的多年积累，特别是加入WTO后，经济飞速发展，房地产腾飞，地方政府依靠土地财政获得了充裕的资金，才有能力把公共厕所的成本全部承担下来。所以，中国的免费公厕，主要是经济发展的结果。收费与不收费，必然与经济状况息息相关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厕所收费，本质上还是一个政府财政收入和政府公共服务范围的问题。如果说欧洲的公厕情况非常糟糕，那是因为历史、文化、习俗原因，社会也发展出各种替代形式，人们也与之适应。某些国家，免费公厕的福利从未出现，自然也不会有太大的感觉。但如果从免费再次返回到收费，会产生不一样的感知了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[粉黛花海迷人眼丨指尖华夏⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the golden autumn, and Naluhua is in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province Domestic pink grass has entered its best viewing period, and the sea of ​​flowers is like a &quot;pink ocean&quot;, attracting tourists to come to watch, play and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists play among the Nalu flowers and flowers in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;772&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[济南城投公司一次性售1341套现房，房从哪来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>