<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[海上危机专家谈：“我们需要的不是排外战略，而是包容的战略”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259713]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the ocean has become an emerging development space that countries are paying attention to, and a new ocean order is taking shape. At the same time, new issues such as maritime military crises and marine ecological security have also emerged. Are we ready for the new order? How should maritime disputes be managed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now that we are entering a new maritime order, we should do our best to maintain maritime security and avoid entering a state of disorder.” Jayanath Colombaj, former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy, said. He believes that many countries rely on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2023, at the Beijing Xiangshan Forum &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control&quot; group meeting, many Chinese and foreign scholars conducted in-depth discussions on issues such as maritime crises, maritime risks, maritime order and rules, etc. Discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/5b6586d3f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, 2023, a number of Chinese and foreign scholars held discussions at the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing around &quot;Maritime Military Crisis Prevention and Control.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Conflict-prone Period&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is facing tremendous changes, and maritime security issues have been affected A variety of factors influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Ding Yiping, former deputy commander of the People’s Liberation Army Navy, judged: “Various risk factors are superimposed, linked, and amplified, and the maritime situation is affected by them and enters a period of conflict-prone situations.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the one hand, there are traditional maritime security issues, sovereignty disputes, usage disputes, resource development, fishery and other issues.” Ding Yiping mentioned, “On the one hand, there are at least 60 countries involved in maritime usage disputes alone. More than 200 maritime disputes have arisen.” On the other hand, “criminal activities such as piracy, robbery, and terrorist attacks occur frequently.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are living in a maritime crisis.” Jayanath Colombaj is a retired lieutenant general and former commander of the Sri Lanka Navy. He is particularly concerned about maritime security issues in the Indian Ocean and its littoral countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean is the third largest ocean in the world, rich in fish and seaweed resources, and maritime trade is very developed. However, Colombaj noted that countries surrounding the Indian Ocean are still troubled by security issues, &quot;human trafficking, illegal immigration at sea They all occurred in the Indian Ocean, posing a great threat to the maritime order. In addition, there are a large number of military operations in the Indian Ocean,&quot; Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the increasing security crisis, the deterioration of the marine ecological environment has increasingly become a problem for marine governance. In recent years, climate change has led to frequent marine disasters. Melting glaciers, rising sea levels, and rising ocean surface temperatures have caused serious harm to marine and coastal ecosystems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, &quot;Some countries discharge industrial sewage and dump garbage into the ocean, resulting in seawater pollution and serious damage to marine ecology, while disorderly and uncontrolled development has caused the rapid decline of marine resources.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The Indian Ocean that Colombaj is concerned about is also facing ecological damage. &quot;There is a 60,000 square kilometers area in the southern Indian Ocean, and there is a large area of ​​garbage.&quot; Colombaj is worried that if it is not dealt with in time, the environmental problems in the Indian Ocean will become more and more serious. serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the frequent maritime security issues, there are also more complex national games, which are not easy to solve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said, “Because maritime disputes involve historical roots, national sentiments, economic and security interests, the countries involved are unwilling to compromise, and some major foreign countries intervene in other countries’ disputes for their own interests, resulting in disputes and confrontations. It has seriously affected the security and stability of some regions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Colombaj said that whether it is marine security management or marine environmental governance, countries are facing cooperation difficulties. &quot;There are several major obstacles to ocean governance, including a lack of trust, a lack of financial resources, a lack of political vision among leaders, a lack of public awareness, and a lack of broad policies,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;New Maritime Order&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are many &quot;strategies&quot; regarding the Indian Ocean. Colombaj believes that these strategies have led to strategic competition, strategic tightening, strategic dilemmas and strategic differences among a large number of countries surrounding the Indian Ocean, making the Indian Ocean unsafe. Similar to these strategies, there are a large number of joint initiatives in the Indian Ocean region, many of which remain on paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do we, a small country, need so many strategies? What goals are these strategies going to achieve? Can they bring great development to the Indian Ocean region?&quot; Colombaj believes that these strategies are about &quot;order and rules.&quot; The definition is controversial; what the Indian Ocean needs is not an exclusive strategy, but an inclusive strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When things go in the wrong direction, we can look back to the starting point. For example, with the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea adopted in 1982, we need to return to the original consensus.&quot; Colombaj believes that many The country relies on the ocean, and people need an interconnected system for ocean governance. For example, &quot;sustainable and integrated ocean governance and enforcement are needed&quot; and &quot;military means cannot be used once a dispute arises on the ocean.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called on governments, non-governmental organizations, business and the private sector to unite together, because &quot;we can go fast alone, but we can go far together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We often hear that we live in an unpredictable world. Yet it is our (researchers’) job to anticipate the ‘unpredictable’. Now, we are entering a new ocean order. To prevent There is disorder, and we need to find order in disorder,” Colombaj said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retired Lieutenant General Shekhar Sinha, former Chief of the Joint Defense Staff of India, believes that after the end of the Cold War, more and more countries have improved their economies and strengthened their military strength, and the center of gravity of the balance of world power has shifted from the West to the East. , which in turn brings more great power competition. &quot;The intensity of military conflicts at sea will increase and will continue,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar is worried that violations in the military field will inevitably draw out the military, especially at sea, such as warship collisions. At the same time, the operation of military or military assets overseas involves disputes over maritime jurisdiction. The parties involved’s different understandings of history, regulations, conventions, etc. will also intensify the disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shekhar proposed that global commerce is very important and conflicts should not affect the navigation of commercial ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that only 10%-15% of the world&#39;s ships are warships, and the rest are commercial ships. Whenever the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea is violated or violated, there must be a global warning and a law enforcement mechanism to stop such violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Warships account for a very small proportion of global ships. We must abide by relevant rules and protect commerce and trade. Conflicts between major powers are more reflected in maritime conflicts than trade conflicts.&quot; He said . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;China Plan&quot; for Crisis Management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping said that the focus of the maritime security concept advocated by China can be summarized into three aspects - jointly safeguarding maritime and territorial security, and jointly responding to Maritime security threats, respect the maritime rights and interests of all countries, and oppose maritime hegemony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the ocean is public domain, and its security needs to be safeguarded by all countries in the world.” Ding Yiping proposed that we must maintain the maritime order based on international law, respect the peaceful maritime interests of all parties, and oppose the use of The oceans contain, contain, and suppress other countries, and use conflicts in other countries’ maritime interests to stir up trouble. Practice has proven that only by trusting each other, strengthening communication, active cooperation, positive interaction, and joint maintenance can we effectively ensure maritime security and maximize common interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how to prevent and control maritime military crises? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yiping proposed that the first suggestion is to announce a strategy to prevent maritime disputes from escalating out of control and to stop inappropriate behavior by maritime military forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The current extraterritorial maritime military forces, dominated by the United States, conduct high-frequency reconnaissance, surveillance, and measurement activities in the waters surrounding China, especially the provocative acts against sovereignty in the South China Sea and the East China Sea, to control the intensity of the crisis. The increase has posed a serious obstacle to the prevention and control of maritime crises,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, U.S. warships have frequently transited the Taiwan Strait, stimulating tensions in the Taiwan Strait and constantly provoking China. Zhang Yazhong, the president of Sun Wen School in Taiwan, spoke at the meeting and said that the most fundamental and necessary way to establish a cross-strait military mutual trust mechanism, or to prevent and manage cross-strait maritime military crises, is that both sides of the strait must have a &quot;political consensus.&quot; Taiwan should return to the position of the &#39;1992 Consensus&#39;.&quot; He expressed the hope that both sides of the Taiwan Strait would have the wisdom to get rid of foreign influence, and that the two sides would resolve cross-Strait political and military problems on their own and work together to create peace across the Strait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Zhai Huan and Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[保障“外嫁女”合法权益，最高检、全国妇联联合发布6件典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 1, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the All-China Women’s Federation jointly issued a Typical cases of administrative prosecution of legal rights and interests in land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are a total of 6 typical cases in this batch, including Zhi Moulan v. the Natural Resources and Planning Bureau of a certain city in Shandong Province, collective land registration inspection and supervision case, Zhang Moujia v. Jiangsu Province A case of prosecution and supervision of the town people&#39;s government&#39;s decision not to accept the land ownership decision, a case of prosecution and supervision of the people&#39;s procuratorate of a certain district in a city in Hunan Province to protect the rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in land expropriation in accordance with the law, Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi sued a certain sub-district office in Zhejiang Province Cases of prosecution and supervision of failure to perform expropriation, resettlement and compensation responsibilities, cases of Yu suing the people&#39;s government of a town in Jiangsu Province for illegal demolition and administrative compensation, and cases of Zhou suing a village committee of a certain city in Hainan Province for the prosecution and supervision of membership confirmation of the collective economic organization of a villager group . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Procuratorial organs and women’s federations have been studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, proactively strengthening contacts, and establishing information sharing, case transfers, case notifications, and joint supervision. and other mechanisms to strengthen all-round judicial protection of women’s rights and interests. From January 2022 to September 2023, the procuratorial organs handled more than 4,000 administrative prosecution cases involving the protection of women’s rights and interests. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of my country’s urbanization process, rural women have experienced changes in marriage relationships, household registration, etc., which involve the identification of members of rural collective economic organizations, land contract management, land acquisition compensation, or Disputes over expropriation compensation and homestead use are more complex and have become issues of widespread social concern. This batch of typical cases focuses on the protection of the legitimate rights and interests of &quot;married women&quot; in collective economic organizations related to land, adheres to the basic national policy of gender equality, increases supervision of administrative litigation and administrative non-litigation enforcement cases involving the legitimate rights and interests of rural women, and strengthens investigations Verification, through integrated case handling, case management by hospital leaders, government inspection linkage, procuratorate and law linkage, etc., we can properly resolve disputes and promote the resolution of women&#39;s urgent, difficult and anxious issues with high-quality and efficient legal supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; pointed out that the basic national policy of equality between men and women should be adhered to and the legitimate rights and interests of women and children should be protected. The person in charge of the Seventh Procuratorate of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate said that this year is the first year to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and is also the first year of the implementation of the newly revised Law on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests. The administrative procuratorial departments of the procuratorial organs at all levels will adhere to Xi Jinping&#39;s Guided by the thought of the rule of law, we will thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on women and children, implement the Law on the Protection of Women’s Rights and Interests, continue to deepen cooperation with relevant departments such as the Women’s Federation, and work with sincerity and sincerity. Make greater efforts to handle every case with high quality and efficiency, further strengthen the equal protection of rural women&#39;s property rights, promote source governance, effectively enhance rural women&#39;s sense of gain, happiness, and security, and promote the high-quality development of women&#39;s and children&#39;s undertakings make new contributions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;About issuing and protecting rural women&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;Typical cases of administrative prosecution involving legal rights and interests in land&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Notice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;The People’s Procuratorates and Women’s Federations of all provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities directly under the Central Government, the People’s Procuratorate and Women’s Federation of Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In recent years, with the acceleration of my country’s urbanization process, Disputes involving land expropriation and expropriation are on the rise. Due to changes in rural women&#39;s marriage relationships, household registration, etc., disputes involving the identification of members of rural collective economic organizations, land contract management, land acquisition compensation or requisition compensation, and the use of homesteads are more complicated. In order to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s Thought on the Rule of Law, implement the newly revised Law of the People’s Republic of China on the Protection of Women’s Rights and Interests, and increase the number of administrative litigation and administrative non-litigation enforcement cases involving the legitimate rights and interests of rural women. In order to strengthen supervision and better protect women&#39;s legitimate rights and interests, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the All-China Women&#39;s Federation jointly selected and compiled 6 typical administrative prosecution cases for safeguarding rural women&#39;s legitimate rights and interests related to land, which are hereby issued to you for your reference. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;All-China Women&#39;s Federation&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt; span>;September 7, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Protecting the legal rights and interests of rural women in relation to land&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Typical cases of administrative prosecution&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Case 1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhi Moulan v. Natural Resources of a City in Shandong Province Bureau of Resources and Planning collective land registration inspection and supervision case&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Keywords]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Administration The effective judgment supervises the protest against the registration of the homestead use rights of a married woman&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Basic case facts]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Zhi Moulan and Zhi Mourui are siblings. Their father Zhi Mou (died in 2011) has a homestead in a village in a city in Shandong Province. In 2015, Zhi Mourui applied to a certain municipal land and resources bureau (now renamed a certain municipal natural resources and planning bureau) to register a change in the use rights of the homestead involved in the case. The municipal land and resources bureau agreed and issued a collective land use certificate to Zhi Mourui. . On October 12, 2018, Zhi Moulan filed an administrative lawsuit with the People&#39;s Court of a certain district with the Bureau of Land and Resources of a certain city as the defendant and Zhi Mourui as the third party, requesting that the collective land use certificate issued by the bureau for Zhi Mourui be revoked in accordance with the law. . The People&#39;s Court of a certain district made an administrative ruling on April 25, 2019, holding that Zhi Molan is not a member of the collective economic organization where the land involved in the case is located and cannot obtain the right to use the land involved. The land certificate issuance does not affect Zhi Molan&#39;s rights and interests. The ruling was made to dismiss Zhi Moulan’s prosecution. Zhi Moulan was dissatisfied with the effective ruling of the first instance and applied to a certain city&#39;s Intermediate People&#39;s Court for a retrial. The Municipal Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled on June 4, 2020 to reject Zhi Moulan&#39;s retrial application. Zhi Moulan applied for supervision from the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Performance of the Procuratorate’s Duties]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A certain district People’s Procuratorate accepted the case in accordance with the law. After listening to the opinions of the parties, obtaining the court files and the original land registration files involved in the case, and hearing the opinions of the original judge, it was found that: A certain city&#39;s Land and Resources Bureau determined that Zhi Rui was based on the &quot;House Inheritance Agreement&quot; of the house on the homestead involved in the case. The land use rights were obtained by inheriting the house, and a collective land use certificate was issued to Zhi Mourui. However, the inheritance agreement listed five heirs of the house on the homestead, and did not specify that only Zhi Mourui would inherit it. It was also found that Zhi Moulan was originally a member of the village&#39;s collective economic organization. After marriage, he moved out of his household registration because his children were in school, and he is currently living in poverty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After review, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district held that according to the &quot;Regulations on Confirmation, Registration and Issuance of Rural Collective Land Rights&quot; issued by the Ministry of Land and Resources, the Office of the Central Rural Work Leading Group, the Ministry of Finance and the Ministry of Agriculture, &quot;Several Opinions&quot;, members of non-collective economic organizations who occupy rural homestead land due to inheritance of houses may register and issue certificates in accordance with regulations. In this case, although Zhi Moulan was not a member of the village&#39;s collective economic organization at the time of the lawsuit, he was Zhi&#39;s legal heir and had an interest in the registration of the homestead involved in the case. The court ruled that Zhi Moulan was not a member of the collective economic organization where the land involved in the case was located. Members of the organization ruled to dismiss the lawsuit on the grounds that the land certificate issuance did not affect their rights and interests, and the application of the law was indeed wrong. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district submitted a protest to the Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After review, the Municipal People’s Procuratorate filed a protest in accordance with the law. The Municipal Intermediate People&#39;s Court adopted the protest opinion and ruled on November 17, 2021 to revoke the original ruling and instruct a certain district people&#39;s court to continue hearing the case. The People&#39;s Court of a certain district made an administrative judgment on September 26, 2022, revoking the collective land use certificate involved in the case. A certain city&#39;s Natural Resources and Planning Bureau and Zhi Mourui were dissatisfied with the first-instance judgment and appealed. The Municipal Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled on March 6, 2023 to reject the appeal and uphold the original judgment. At the same time, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain city determined that Zhi Moulan met the conditions for judicial assistance and assisted her in applying for judicial assistance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Typical meaning]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The rights and interests of “married women” in collective economic organizations Protection issues have become a common concern in society. The newly revised &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests&quot; clearly stipulates that women enjoy equal inheritance rights as men, and women exercise their inheritance rights in accordance with the law without discrimination. When applying for real estate registration such as rural land contract management rights and homestead use rights, all women and other family members who enjoy the rights must be listed in the real estate registration book and ownership certificate. Although &quot;married girls&quot; who have moved out of their household registration are no longer members of the original collective economic organization, they can be registered as holders of the right to use the homestead by obtaining the inheritance share of the houses on the homestead. In response to a case in which the court ruled to dismiss the prosecution on the grounds that the &quot;married girl&quot; had no interest in the registration of the accused land use rights, the procuratorial organs focused on the focus of the dispute, strengthened investigation and verification, clarified the facts, accurately applied the law, and provided high-quality and efficient legal supervision Promote judicial justice and safeguard women&#39;s legitimate rights and interests. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Case 2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Mou A v. Jiangsu Province A case of procuratorial supervision of a town people&#39;s government&#39;s decision not to accept land ownership&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Keywords]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Administrative effective adjudication supervises the substantive resolution of administrative disputes over the land ownership of married women&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Basic case facts]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Moujia was originally a resident of a community in a town in Jiangsu Province. His parents once owned four tile-roofed houses and had four daughters. The last four daughters all moved out of a certain community due to marriage. Zhang Moujia’s parents passed away successively. In 2005, a community took back the homestead and contracted land of Zhang A&#39;s parents and re-contracted it to Zhang A&#39;s cousin Zhang B for management and signed a land contract management contract. A certain municipal people&#39;s government issued a rural collective land management certificate to Zhang B&#39;s household. Land contract management right certificate. In March 2007, after Zhang A got divorced, his registered permanent residence moved back to a certain community. In May 2013, Zhang B and his wife demolished the house built by Zhang A’s parents. Zhang A and four other sisters sued Zhang B and his wife to the court, demanding that the house be restored to its original condition, but they were not supported by the court. Later, Zhang A&#39;s other sisters issued written declarations voluntarily giving up their inheritance rights. In December 2015, Zhang A submitted an application for confirmation of homestead use rights to a certain town government, requesting confirmation that the land use rights of his parents’ original homestead and contracted land belonged to him, and confirming that Zhang B signed a land use right agreement with a certain community. The contract operation contract is invalid. In March 2017, a certain town government decided not to accept Zhang’s application for confirmation of rights. Zhang Moujia was dissatisfied with the decision and filed an administrative lawsuit. The court of first instance held that the land involved in the case had been recovered by a community and contracted to Zhang Yiyi for contract management. According to Article 14 of the &quot;Measures for the Investigation and Handling of Land Ownership Disputes&quot;, the case of dispute over rural land contract management rights does not belong to a land ownership dispute. Within the scope of accepting the case, a certain town government made a decision not to accept the case, which was in compliance with legal provisions. Zhang A could seek separate rights relief in accordance with the law, and therefore the judgment was made to reject Zhang A’s claim. Zhang Moujia appealed and applied for retrial, but neither of them was supported. Zhang Mojia was dissatisfied and applied to the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain city for supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Performance of the Procuratorate’s Duties]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/0aa31fd6a4b3b38458cba49c40d7ceea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;&lt;span>;Prosecutors conducted on-site investigation and evidence collection&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A certain city&#39;s People&#39;s Procuratorate accepted the case in accordance with the law. After reviewing the original trial files, retrieving related cases, and conducting on-site visits and investigations, it was found that since 2013, Zhang Moujia filed 13 civil and civil lawsuits, including property damage compensation, return of unjust enrichment, and illegal land registration, due to disputes over housing and land involved in the case. Administrative litigation, none of its claims were supported. Although the relevant effective judgments have confirmed that Zhang A obtained the ownership of the house involved in the case and the right to use the homestead due to inheritance, and also pointed out that the people&#39;s government of a certain town should properly coordinate the problem of homestead encroachment that Zhang A has reported for many years, neither of them has done so. A specific and clear ruling was made on this issue, resulting in the disputes involved in the case being &quot;litigated but not decided&quot;. At present, the community involved in the case has been relocated as a whole, and it is not realistic for Zhang A to return to his parents&#39; original homestead and apply for building a house again. Zhang Moujia has been working abroad all year round and has no fixed residence. The essence of his multiple lawsuits is to obtain a &quot;shelter&quot; for him to return to his native place in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After review, the procuratorial organ believes that this case is a dispute over land contract management rights and does not fall within the scope of the People&#39;s Government&#39;s land ownership dispute case, and the final judgment is not inappropriate. However, a certain community took back the land involved in the case through natural household closure without the consent of Zhang A and other legal heirs, which violated the inheritance rights of Zhang A and others. Moreover, after Zhang A and other people moved their household registration back to a certain community, they should also enjoy corresponding rights as villagers. Homestead use rights. The dispute involved in the case has lasted for nearly ten years. After many rounds of litigation, Zhang A&#39;s legitimate rights and interests have not been effectively protected, and there is the possibility of triggering new litigation. The two-level procuratorial organs decided to carry out resolution work in an integrated manner to completely resolve the &quot;year-old&quot; &quot;Program Idling&quot; problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A certain city’s People’s Procuratorate sent a letter to a certain town’s people’s government, pointing out that the infringement of Zhang’s rights exists objectively, and the town government should pay attention to Zhang’s reasonable demands and properly handle the parties’ houses and land. issues, avoid intensification of disputes, and protect women&#39;s legitimate rights and interests. At the same time, the local Women&#39;s Federation was notified of the case, and they jointly went to a certain town government to carry out resolution work. After fully listening to the opinions of the procuratorial organ and the Women&#39;s Federation, the town government convened the Political and Legal Comprehensive Management Center, a community and other departments to discuss solutions, and finally determined that Zhang A could purchase a resettlement house at the demolition and resettlement price to solve the housing problem based on his qualifications as a villager. At the same time, the procuratorate explained to Zhang that it was no longer realistic to rebuild a house and that he should get rid of the burden of litigation as soon as possible and start a new life. Zhang Moujia felt the sincerity of the people&#39;s government and agreed to the plan of a certain town government. On October 11, 2022, Zhang Moujia signed a settlement agreement with a certain town government, and Zhang Moujia withdrew his supervision application from the procuratorial organ. The administrative disputes and civil disputes in this case were substantially resolved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Typical significance]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The newly revised &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests&quot; ” stipulates that women enjoy equal rights with men in terms of land contract management and homestead use. Decisions on matters involving the interests of villagers shall not infringe on women&#39;s rights and interests in rural collective economic organizations on the grounds that women are unmarried, married, divorced, widowed, or have no men in the household. When handling cases involving the infringement of the rights and interests of &quot;married girls&quot; that lasted for a long time, had many related litigations, and overlapped with the civil and commercial banks, the procuratorial organs responded to problems such as &quot;the cases could not be concluded and the procedures were idle&quot;, adhering to the supremacy of the people, procuratorial work for the people, and focusing on the masses. To deal with urgent, difficult and urgent issues, we must accurately grasp the essence of legal relationships, take legal considerations into consideration, comprehensively use on-site visits, work letters, and work with local women&#39;s federations to resolve disputes in a &quot;package&quot; manner to resolve administrative disputes and civil disputes, and effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of rural women. Promote social fairness and justice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Case 3&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A certain district in a city in Hunan Province The People&#39;s Procuratorate&#39;s Procuratorial Supervision Case on Protecting the Land Expropriation Rights of &quot;Married Women&quot; in accordance with the law&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Keywords]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;Administrative cases supervising the expropriation, compensation and resettlement standards of married women and litigation source management&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Basic case facts]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since 2016, a certain district branch of the Natural Resources and Planning Bureau of a certain city in Hunan Province (hereinafter referred to as a certain natural resources and planning branch), in the process of performing land expropriation management functions, has carried out public security household registration The &quot;married girls&quot; Zhang and his son, Wang and his daughter, and Yi and his son who were separately registered in the management system were included in the close relatives of Zhang, Wang and Yi respectively for compensation and resettlement. Zhang, Wang and Yi were all dissatisfied and filed an administrative lawsuit. In June 2017, in Zhang&#39;s administrative litigation case, a certain district people&#39;s court ruled that a certain natural resources and planning branch should collect compensation and resettlement funds on a single household basis, and a certain natural resources and planning branch fulfilled the obligations determined by the judgment in accordance with the law; 2018 In December 2019, in the administrative litigation case of Yi, a certain natural resources and planning branch took the initiative to calculate the resettlement compensation fee based on the standard of a single household; in April 2019, in the administrative lawsuit of Wang, the natural resources and planning branch of a certain The court issued a defense opinion that &quot;daughters married outside the home&quot; should not be compensated and resettled as separate households. In the above three cases, a certain natural resources and planning bureau had inconsistent standards for determining whether the compensation and resettlement funds for &quot;married girls&quot; should be collected according to a single household. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Procuratorate performance process]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The People’s Procuratorate of a certain district is carrying out a &quot;comprehensive In the special activity of &quot;Deepening Administrative Procuratorial Supervision and Protecting People&#39;s Livelihood and People&#39;s Benefits in accordance with the Law&quot;, taking three typical cases of Zhang, Wang, and Yi as examples, through data retrieval, it was found that the entire district was involved in the land expropriation and compensation administration of &quot;married women&quot; There are hundreds of lawsuits filed. After research and judgment, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district decided to carry out supervision of similar cases. By visiting administrative agencies, people&#39;s courts and village committees, collecting case files and reviewing information, we found that the problem of administrative agencies&#39; inconsistent standards for land acquisition compensation and resettlement for &quot;married girls&quot; is quite prominent, and there is also a need for &quot;different defenses for the same case&quot; in administrative litigation. Complain about irregularities and other issues. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d0ba3de88945d923ca901f2017bb5f0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256388 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Prosecutors communicate with administrative agencies on the rectification content recommended by the prosecutors&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;On March 29, 2022, the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district issued a procuratorial recommendation to a certain natural resources and planning branch, suggesting that the bureau: 1. When compensating and resettling &quot;married women&quot;, the legitimate rights and interests of women should be fully protected, Whether a person has the qualifications to be a member of a collective economic organization is comprehensively judged based on whether he or she has registered a permanent residence in the locality in accordance with the law as the formal requirement, and whether he or she actually lives and works in the collective economic organization as the substantive requirement. 2. Develop unified standards for compensation determination as to whether “out-marriage girls” should be compensated and resettled as a single household. 3. Improve the administrative response mechanism, improve the level of administration according to law, and maintain the government&#39;s credibility. After the procuratorial recommendations were issued, a certain district People&#39;s Procuratorate held several joint meetings with a certain natural resources and planning bureau and a certain district women&#39;s federation to exchange opinions and discuss key points for rectification. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On April 27, 2022, a certain natural resources and planning bureau responded in writing, stating that it would further improve the land acquisition, demolition and resettlement policies and compensation determination standards; strictly implement the &quot;three rounds of joint review&quot; mechanism , timely sort out and summarize the situation of cases involving demolition; improve one&#39;s ability to respond to litigation. In May 2022, a certain natural resources and planning bureau formulated a new &quot;Relocation and Resettlement Policy and Compensation Determination Standards&quot; manual, which formulated a unified compensation standard for identity identification and household type identification for &quot;married women&quot;. According to the standard of a single household Calculate resettlement compensation for Wang and other &quot;married women&quot; who meet the regulations and their children. Four full-time lawyers were hired to take charge of administrative response work to plug the problem of irregular administrative response from the source. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain district and the Women&#39;s Federation of a certain district signed the &quot;Opinions on the Collaboration Mechanism for Procuratorial Supervision to Protect Women&#39;s Rights and Interests&quot; and reached cooperation opinions on clue transfer, support for prosecution, resolution of administrative disputes, judicial assistance, etc., and established a long-term mechanism. Since June 2022, there have been no further administrative lawsuits in the district caused by inconsistent compensation and resettlement standards for “married girls”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Typical significance]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Compensation for land acquisition and demolition is related to people&#39;s livelihood and interests. Whether &quot;married women&quot; should be compensated and resettled, and whether the compensation and resettlement standards are consistent, is related to the vital interests of women. In land expropriation compensation and resettlement, &quot;married girls&quot; who are registered separately by rural collective organizations shall have equal rights to resettlement and compensation, and shall be compensated and resettled as a single household according to unified standards. In the performance of legal supervision duties, the procuratorial organs have focused on the supervision of similar cases and identified the deep-seated cases of similar improper administrative behaviors that have infringed on the compensation and resettlement rights of &quot;married women&quot; and have been corrected by the People&#39;s Court but have not been effectively implemented. problems, promote the establishment of a perfect system, ensure that similar cases are handled equally under the same conditions, promote the management of the source of litigation, and fully demonstrate the responsibilities of the procuratorial organs that dare to supervise and are good at supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Case 4&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qian Moujuan, Ji Mou Xi v. A certain sub-district office in Zhejiang Province failed to perform its duties of expropriation, resettlement and compensation for prosecution and supervision&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Keywords]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;Administrative, effective, adjudication, supervision, placement, compensation and social governance of married women’s collective economic organization membership&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Basic case facts]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Qian Moujuan is a villager in a village in a certain town in Zhejiang Province (now a certain sub-district office). After marriage, she still settled in the household of her father Qian. She has a daughter, Ji Mouxi, who also settled in the household. In Qian&#39;s house. In September 2015, Qian Moujuan and her husband Ji Mouxi divorced, and Ji Mouxi lived with her mother. In 2017, a certain town and village where Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi lived were included in the scope of demolition and reconstruction, and Qian&#39;s house was within the scope of expropriation. On September 11, 2017, Qian signed a &quot;House Expropriation and Resettlement Compensation Agreement&quot; with the People&#39;s Government of a certain town. Qian Juan and Ji Mouxi were not included in the resettlement population. Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi filed an administrative lawsuit, requesting to revoke the &quot;House Expropriation and Resettlement Compensation Agreement&quot; and re-sign it; they also reviewed and confirmed that in a certain district government&#39;s resettlement compensation implementation plan, &quot;Although the household registration is registered, she is married to another village and has no The provision that houses with independent legal property rights will not be counted in the resettlement population is illegal. A certain district people&#39;s court ruled to reject the lawsuit. Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi were dissatisfied and appealed and applied for retrial, but they were not supported. Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi applied to the People&#39;s Procuratorate of a certain city for supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;[Procuratorial organ performance process]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A certain city’s People’s Procuratorate accepted the case in accordance with the law, and According to the regulations on integrated case handling, a two-level court case handling team was established, and the chief prosecutor of a certain district People&#39;s Procuratorate handled the case. After reviewing the court file materials, obtaining Qian’s household registration information and members of a certain village’s collective economic organization, and consulting on the formulation background and practice of the district’s collective land expropriation and resettlement population identification policy, it was found out: Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi’s The household registration has been in a certain village since the beginning and has not changed. The two have been living in the village with Qian and his wife. Qian Moujuan is a member of a village collective economic organization, enjoys 6.21 shares of equity, and has a share certificate. After Qian signed a house expropriation and resettlement compensation agreement, the house was demolished, and Qian Juan and Ji faced housing difficulties. &quot;Married to another village&quot; in the resettlement compensation implementation plan is interpreted in practice as &quot;married to a foreigner&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/57b216b92adb942e057f8999a3498c96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256389 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After the efforts of the prosecutors to mediate, Qian Moujuan withdrew the supervision application&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;After review, the procuratorial organ found that Qian Moujuan and Ji Mouxi were members of a certain village collective economic organization from the beginning, and they did not enjoy homestead allocation and resettlement compensation in other rural collective economic organizations. The resettlement compensation implementation plan harms the rights and interests of women and children and should not be used as a basis to deny &quot;marriage girls&quot; and their children access to resettlement compensation.考虑到提抗、审判、执行周期长，且可能引发新一轮诉讼，增加当事人的诉累，为从根本上保障当事人的权益，某市人民检察院牵头召开府检、法检联席会议，研判“外嫁女”安置补偿案件的司法裁判规则，某区人民检察院与区房征办、信访局、街道办事处等共同研究解决方案。经多方协调联动，最终达成对钱某娟、季某熙补偿50万元的方案。 2022年11月14日，钱某娟、季某熙领取补偿款后，向检察机关申请撤回监督申请。该案行政争议得到实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关由该案进一步推动行政机关制定科学、合法、可行的土地征收安置补偿政策。目前，某区政府已修订土地征收安置补偿方案，涉“外嫁女”安置政策得以调整。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;男女平等是我国的基本国策。党的二十大报告强调“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”，充分彰显党中央对妇女儿童事业发展的高度重视。新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》也要求检察机关在履职中加强对妇女权益的保护。检察机关在履职过程中，坚持问题导向，针对将“外嫁女”土地征收安置补偿权益排除在外，违反男女平等基本国策及相关法律规定的现象，通过一体化办案、成立联合办案组、院领导包案、府检联动、法检联动等方式，依法开展监督，妥善化解争议，有效维护妇女合法权益。同时，通过案件办理，推动地方政府在行政管理中重视妇女权益保障，完善土地征收安置补偿政策，有力提升社会治理法治化水平。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例五&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;俞某诉江苏省某镇人民政府违法拆除及行政赔偿检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女拆迁补偿独立基本户行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;俞某系某镇村民，婚前与其父、兄共同居住。 2007年俞某结婚，户口未迁出，并一直居住在本村。因俞某属于与村集体经济组织以外人员结婚但户口未迁出的“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不符合单独分户条件，俞某同其丈夫（外地人）在俞某父亲宅基地翻建房屋240平方米，并多次申请宅基地及建房手续，但一直未能办理。 2017年，当地政府作出房屋征收决定公告，对俞某所在“城中村”改造项目内的居民房屋实施征地拆迁。房屋被镇政府拆除后，俞某向某区人民法院提起行政诉讼，请求判令按照拆迁安置补偿的标准，以房屋产权置换方式对房屋灭失损失进行赔偿。某区人民法院审理认为，俞某与其父亲并未分户，其翻建房屋使用的是其父亲宅基地，未办理房屋建房手续。根据有关规定，案涉房屋不能按照拆迁补偿的标准予以赔偿，鉴于房屋确系俞某所建，可按照房屋重置价予以赔偿（每平方米500元）。审理中，某镇政府表示可以赔偿90万元，法院予以准许。俞某不服一审判决，提出上诉、申请再审，均未获法院支持。俞某向某市人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关履职过程】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某市人民检察院依法受理。经调查核实查明：俞某房屋被拆除后，一直没有经济能力购买商品房，长期在外租房居住；俞某丈夫在原籍集体经济组织无住房、无宅基地；拆迁部门认为俞某是“姑娘户”，按照当地政策，不同意按照“独立基本户”进行拆迁安置补偿；俞某认为其一直在该集体经济组织享有权利和承担义务，系当地村民，在父辈宅基地上分户建房并一直居住，应以“独立基本户”对其进行拆迁补偿安置。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/243bfe7697baf96a7fef9d56cfab37ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，并进行释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;检察机关经审查认为，因俞某未分户且所建房屋未能办理审批手续，终审判决并无明显不当，但俞某的权益并未得到充分保障。本案系历史遗留问题，涉及村民自治规则的正当性、传统观念根深蒂固等问题，争议化解难度大。为此，检察机关联合当地妇联，多次组织当事人协商，赴政府商谈，引导当地政府切实增强男女平等意识，依法保障妇女在农村土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面享有与男子平等的权利。同时，多次赴俞某家实地开展联合走访慰问，为俞某提供心理疏导和关爱帮扶，减少其对立情绪。为进一步厘清外嫁女的相关法律、政策问题，2022年6月23日，检察机关就该案召开听证会，并邀请具有市区两级妇联代表身份的听证员参与。会上，双方围绕争议焦点充分表达意见、听证员现场提问，明晰案件事实，就和解方案进行全面评估与多次磋商。最终镇政府一次性补偿数十万元，合计先前赔偿的90万元，俞某得到的补偿与拆迁补偿的标准基本接近，双方达成和解协议，俞某撤回监督申请。长达五年的行政争议得以实质性化解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》明确规定，国家采取必要措施，促进男女平等，消除对妇女的一切形式的歧视，禁止排斥、限制妇女依法享有和行使各项权益。妇女在土地征收补偿安置以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等权利。针对历史遗留问题，检察机关在办案过程中，坚持系统思维，统筹考虑拆迁安置争议形成的法律问题、社会成因和历史因素，为避免给当事人增加诉累，纾解其面临的现实困难，通过公开听证、联合商谈、入户走访等方式，推动当地政府研究制定合理的补偿方案，促成当事人达成和解协议，实质性化解行政争议，实现政治效果、社会效果、法律效果有机统一。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;案例六&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;周某诉海南省某市某村委会某村民小组集体经济组织成员资格确认检察监督案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【关键词】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;行政生效裁判监督外嫁女集体经济组织成员资格确认行政争议实质性化解&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【基本案情】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周某于1979年10月6日出生，户籍登记在某市某区某村其父亲周某驹为户主的家庭户口中。周某的父母以家庭承包的方式，承包该村土地11.31亩，承包期限至2027年12月31日。 2018年6月13日，周某与外地的冯某登记结婚，但户口未迁出，未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款。 2020年10月，某村决定给户口在本村的每个农业人员发放征地补偿款共计人民币80246元，村民小组以周某属于在本集体没有承包地的“外嫁女”，不具有集体经济组织成员资格为由，拒绝向其支付上述征地补偿款。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2021年1月6日，周某以村委会某村村民小组侵害其集体经济组织成员权益为由向某市某区人民法院起诉，法院判决确认周某未丧失村集体经济组织成员资格，仍系某村集体经济组织成员。某村村民小组应向周某支付土地补偿费80246元。该村村民小组不服，提出上诉、再审申请均未获支持。期间，周某两次请求某镇人民政府、某镇农业服务中心帮助解决确认集体经济组织成员资格问题，镇政府一直未处理，某村村民小组一直未支付土地补偿款。周某向某市某区人民检察院申请监督。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【检察机关监督情况】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/688cf47badc7d124f201da0999dc106f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;检察机关召开听证会，现场释法说理&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;某区人民检察院依法审查认为，某区人民法院判决认定事实清楚、适用法律正确；某镇政府应当依法履行对某村委会某村村民小组不予确认周某集体经济成员资格、侵害其合法权益行为的监督管理职责。 2022年8月22日，某区人民检察院向某镇政府发出《检察建议书》，要求及时协调、监督某村委会某村村民小组确认周某的集体经济组织成员资格，并加强对辖区农村集体成员身份确认工作的指导，避免出现类似侵害“外嫁女”合法权益的情形。同时，某区人民检察院组织公开听证，商请某市某区某镇政府代表、村民小组代表出席听证，邀请人大代表、人民监督员、律师担任听证员，摆事实讲道理，促进实质性化解本案争议。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年9月7日，某镇人民政府作出书面回复，已采纳检察建议，协调村小组人员确认周某集体经济组织成员资格，并已将周某录入集体经济组织成员身份系统，向其出具了集体经济组织成员股权证，并按程序分期向周某支付土地补偿款。 2022年11月1日，周某签署了息诉承诺书。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;【典型意义】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新修订的《中华人民共和国妇女权益保障法》规定，妇女在农村集体经济组织成员身份确认、土地承包经营、集体经济组织收益分配、土地征收补偿安置或者征用补偿以及宅基地使用等方面，享有与男子平等的权利。认定“外嫁女”是否具有集体经济组织成员资格，应当结合户籍、土地承包经营权、权利义务关系等综合认定，确保“外嫁女”应当享有的利益不落空。与他村村民结婚，但户口未迁出，在本村承包土地、履行村民义务，且未在夫家分配过农村承包土地或征地款的“外嫁女”，依法具有集体经济组织成员资格，享有相关合法权益。检察机关履行法律监督职责中，对行政机关不依法履职导致“外嫁女”合法权益长期得不到解决的行政检察监督案件，综合运用检察建议、公开听证等方式，解决实质诉求，促进争议化解，有效维护妇女合法权益。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省教育厅要求：严禁“萝卜刀”等有害玩具进入校园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259751]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 18:09:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南都记者获悉，广东省教育厅发布《关于加强有害玩具教育管理的通知》。其中提到，各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园。同时，学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具；关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，近期一款名为“萝卜刀”的新型玩具在中小学生（幼儿）群体中走红。该玩具是一种外形酷似胡萝卜的彩色塑料玩具刀，由于该玩具本身具有攻击性，存在一定的安全隐患，又会形成心理暗示，激发孩子暴力倾向，对未成年人安全健康成长产生不良影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，广东省教育厅要求，加强对学生的安全教育。各地各校（园）要进一步加大安全教育力度，让学生（幼儿）认识到“萝卜刀”等玩具的危险性，自觉拒绝“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具，做到不购买、不携带、不玩耍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对家长的安全提醒。要采取多种形式提醒家长认真履行监护责任，务必选择正规厂商出产的、适合孩子年龄阶段、有益身心健康发展的儿童和学生用品，不要为孩子购买“萝卜刀”等危险性有害玩具。在玩具使用前，要仔细阅读包装上的警告和提醒内容，做好孩子使用时的安全防范。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;严格对校园的安全管理。各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园，在进行安全教育的基础上，对仍带入校园的此类有害玩具，要清查封存。被封存的危险性有害玩具，要通知学生（幼儿）家长到学校接受教育，在作出承诺之后可由家长领回，并督促其销毁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强对校园及周边的治理。学校要管好校园内商店，不得售卖此类危险性有害玩具。要关注校园周边商店，发现有售卖此类危险性有害玩具的，要报告属地市场监管等职能部门，由职能部门查处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各地教育部门要会同相关部门深入开展儿童和学生用品安全治理，以“萝卜刀”等存在物理危害、化学危害、可燃性危害、心理暗示等危险性有害玩具产品为重点，加大校园周边商铺和流动摊贩管理力度，一旦发现存在售卖危险性玩具产品和学生用品的，要严肃查处。各地级以上市教育局于11月10日前，将排查治理工作情况反馈省教育厅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[间隔六年，茅台为何突然提价？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259745]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 17:18:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月1日凌晨，贵州茅台（600519.SH）发布重大事项公告：经研究决定，自2023年11月1日起上调本公司53%vol贵州茅台酒(飞天、五星)出厂价格，平均上调幅度约为20%。此次调整不涉及本公司产品的市场指导价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是贵州茅台自2018年元旦以来，时隔近六年再次提高出厂价。贵州茅台的核心单品飞天茅台出厂价将从此前969元/瓶，上调至约1169元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一重磅消息瞬间引爆了酒圈。多位行业人士在11月1日凌晨对南方周末记者表示，对于贵州茅台在这个时间点提价，感到有些震惊，并且超出预期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受提价消息刺激，11月1日，贵州茅台集合竞价高开9.82%，成交金额超12亿元。开盘后，贵州茅台股价从上一个交易日的1684.58元/股拉至1850元/股，改变了近期表现略显低迷的走势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height=&quot;843&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YPKoNUOB53mAkbRCOHS90uVPTbDagEXjBDJmiCxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;自2023年11月1日起，贵州茅台的核心单品飞天茅台出厂价将从此前969元/瓶，上调至约1169元/瓶。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1499&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;元&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的市场指导价没有动&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“出厂价我不关心，但我关心1499元的价格是否会提高。”在茅台深夜发布公告后，有茅台消费者如此表示。2018年元旦，贵州茅台宣布将出厂价从819元/瓶调整到969元/瓶，同时市场指导价从1299元/瓶上调至1499元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵州茅台发布的公告中提及：此次调整不涉及本公司产品的市场指导价格。此次价格调整将会对本公司经营业绩产生一定影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月1日上午，南方周末记者以投资者身份致电贵州茅台董秘办，相关工作人员回复：“我们公告写得很清楚，此次调整的是出厂价，1499元的市场指导价是没有动的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于为何这个时间点进行提价，上述工作人员表示：“由于我们已经接近六年没有做出价格调整，充分考量了宏观经济环境、市场供需变化等因素，坚持以市场、顾客为中心，兼顾企业长远发展，市场长期稳健基础上，调整产品的出厂价格，这是一个正常的、合理的企业经营行为。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者不完全统计，贵州茅台从2001年上市以来，此次调价是第八次，此前调价的时间分别在2001年、2003年、2006年、2008年、2010年、2012年、2018年。而此次调整的间隔时间，是茅台上市以来最长的一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期研究茅台公司的鹤禧投资董事长霍东杰对南方周末记者表示：“此前茅台涨价一般是在白酒周期向上的时候，但近期飞天茅台价格比近几年同期都要弱，譬如历史上，中秋期间是涨价的，今年却是跌的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国最大白酒批发市场百荣市场酒商提供的数据显示，2023年10月31日，53%vol贵州茅台酒的散装飞天价格为2650元/瓶，而在2023年6月下旬，散装飞天价格为2820元/瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，多位受访者对南方周末记者表示，此次提价，部分经销商的利润将转给茅台，主要影响的是经销商以及经销商以下酒商的渠道利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑州玺韵实业总经理王占甫认为，目前白酒市场除茅台外的名酒品牌核心产品都倒挂严重，此次提价，一方面是行业老大的担当，还有对集团2023年度增长压力的有效释放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“经销商利润就普茅而言本就是暴利，所以此次调价，对经销商的影响并不大，何况经销商会推高流通价，这是贵州茅台强大的品牌张力决定的，其它品牌没有。”王占甫对南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为郑州资深酒商，11月1日上午，王占甫也在密切关注飞天茅台的流通价格，但截至南方周末记者发稿，他表示：“目前酒商大概率不出货，会观察一下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另有受访者表示，此次提价意味着贵州茅台效益的提高以及渠道利润的再分配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1-9月，贵州茅台实现营业收入1032.68亿元，归属于上市公司股东的净利润为528.76亿元。此时调价，意味着2023年最后两个月，将为茅台带来更多营收及净利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍东杰对南方周末记者表示：“我们初步评估，此次调价，将对贵州茅台明年盈利提升6%。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据方正证券估算，此次茅台出厂价由969元提升20%后，约增厚2023年收入62亿元，增厚幅度约4.2%，约增厚净利润41亿元，增厚幅度约5.6%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国酒业智库专家、知趣咨询总经理蔡学飞认为，此次提价有利于提振目前低迷的行业信心，合理的涨价预期也会刺激和拉动相关消费增长，同时呼应长期以来的资本市场需求。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;茅台提价&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的背后&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对于此次茅台提价，多位受访者表示既在意料之中又在意料之外。毕竟，距离上一次贵州茅台提价，已经过去了近六年，在此期间，茅台何时上调出厂价，一直是市场关注的焦点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期持有茅台股票的一位资深投资者对南方周末记者表示：“从茅台自身讲，前年就强烈希望提价了，但最后没批准，企业诉求很强。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，白酒行业掀起涨价潮，但茅台并没有跟进。在贵州茅台2022年度及第一季度业绩说明会以及2023年6月的股东大会上，茅台董事长丁雄军也多次回应提价问题，他曾表示，要按照价格法等相关法律法规来定茅台酒的价格，定价也会考虑供求关系等因素，“我们一定会充分遵循市场的规律，呼应市场的需求”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位不愿意透露姓名的白酒行业资深人士对南方周末记者表示：“茅台的特殊地位以及经济影响力，决定了茅台的价格调整是极其敏感的，往往涉及企业、政府等多方意见，并且有着严格的论证与保密流程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该人士指出，此次提价确实很突然，但明显有提振信心的意图。另一位长期投资茅台超过二十年的投资机构负责人则对南方周末记者表示：“此次提价，是呵护资本市场政策的一部分。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从企业自身来看，近年来，贵州茅台已经通过减少经销商数量，拓展直销渠道，增加直营店，推出i茅台平台等方法，不断提升直销收入的占比。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年至今，贵州茅台经销商总数从3083家减少到截至2023年三季度末的2082家。千家经销商的减少，带来了贵州茅台直销业务占比的持续增长。2022年，贵州茅台直销业务占比达到40%，2023前三季度，贵州茅台直销收入同比增长44.93%，达到462.07亿元，占总营收的比重约为44.92%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博士过剩愈演愈烈，读博值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;一方面，中国每年博士入学与毕业的人数迭创新高；另一方面，“博士过剩”凸显并愈演愈烈。“核物理博士当城管”“医学博士应聘校医”“博士生争当中小学教师”的新闻屡屡出现，展现出博士生在就业市场上“大材小用”的尴尬。 寒窗十数载，读博还是个好选择吗？</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当世界科幻大会来到中国：“许多超出以往经历的东西”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/oRGacxGspek9vCu9277FP3r5bECe23moCgsqML0z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年建成的成都科幻馆成为10月18日-10月22日举办的世界科幻大会的主场馆。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（成都市郫都区科创新城管委会供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年第81届世界科幻大会的主会场——成都科幻馆，位于一条被称为“科幻大道”周围方圆两公里区域的中心。两年前成都申办成功的时候，这里还是一片旷野。这一本来被规划为“科技馆”的成都市郫都区地块，迅速升级为“科幻馆”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎哈事务所设计的这座科幻馆延续了其对曲线与未来感的追求，在郊区横平竖直的直线丛林里，植入了几瓣人工塑形的曲面。根据官方的说法，那是一片来自宇宙的星云，科幻作家刘慈欣则说，它也像一艘降落在湖畔的外星飞船。不管怎样，这是世界科幻大会，它需要一个视觉意象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是世界科幻大会首次来到中国。最初，世界科幻大会只是美国芝加哥几个不到20岁的年轻人产生的奇想——为全世界科幻迷创造一个集会的平台。1939年，他们在芝加哥举办了第一届大会。通过科幻迷的聚会与自治，全世界喜欢某一部科幻作品的人聚拢在一起，畅聊阅读经验、交换手工艺品、缅怀科幻逝者……八十年来，世界科幻大会传承着这样宽松而富有想象力的基因，生长出了一种独特又持久的科幻文化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从巨大的穹顶式入口进入成都科幻馆，需要经过多道安检。开幕式展示了中国式晚会的一些常用元素——主持人高亢的朗诵、色彩饱和的舞台、撑满空间的群舞，但主办方在其中加入了尽可能多的科幻元素，来凸显这届大会的主题“共生纪元”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国的科幻迷文化与我成长时所接触的文化并没有长达几十年的广泛交流，我还有许多超出以往经历的东西需要学习。”本届大会联合主席本·亚洛表示，“当然，对于世界科幻大会的文化，中国科幻迷也有许多需要了解的地方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“会员文化”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月下旬的成都已经有了寒意，也早早过了学生的暑假时间。2021年成都在申办世界科幻大会的时候，很多学生科幻迷为了能在暑假一睹科幻盛会，纷纷花钱注册第79届华盛顿世界科幻大会会员（约合人民币六百多元），为成都投票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照《世界科幻协会章程》，各种名目不同的会员资格均可以购买，而购买当年的会员资格，就可以给两年后的申办城市投票，也可以为雨果奖的入围作品投票。这种做法类似于“众筹”，历届世界科幻大会的预算绝大多数来自会员的购买支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是世界科幻迷中特有的一种会员文化。1950年代，雨果奖设立不久，就增加了粉丝类的奖项，科幻迷自己写的作品、自己办的业余杂志，也可以站上雨果奖的领奖台，与那些“大牛”们的作品交相辉映。世界科幻大会的三大传统核心议题——雨果奖投票评选、事务会议和未来大会的选址投票，无不与普通科幻迷的参与息息相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“它的魅力就在于它是一种基于创造者社区的精神，每一个人既是参与者，又是创造者。这是文化传统赋予它的东西，不是能够随便取代或复制的。”本届大会联合主席陈石对南方周末记者说，让他感到遗憾的是，对于许多幻迷来说，这是一次无法抵达的大会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月20日，成都组委会在推特上宣布举办日期从2023年8月16日推迟到10月18日。“我身边至少有一百多个幻迷朋友来不了。”大学生千星说。他所在的学校离成都很远，他是少数能请得出假的人。千星穿着一套银蓝色的cosplay服装来到会场，非常显眼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果这些幻迷们能够来到成都科幻馆现场，他们在这座庞大、中空的建筑里，会首先看到大厅里一个高达9米的巨型“笨笨”塑像（电影《流浪地球》里的机器人），到了晚上，围绕它的射灯让它表面的颜色开始流动，制造出各种不同状态的“笨笨”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一楼的两个大型展厅分别为企业展厅与科幻迷展厅。企业展厅的几十个展位绝大多数为中国企业，有卖科幻文创的，也有做投影的，更多的是做科幻出版的。他们展位的声光电效果夺人耳目，与旁边的幻迷展区明显不同。企业展厅是此前的世界科幻大会不曾有过的单元。政府的支持、企业的参与、大量赞助商的品牌推广，都让大会有了更多的官方色彩与商业价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻馆附近没法满足这么多参展商的出行与餐饮需求。一位参展商告诉南方周末记者，“哪种票要怎么走、车怎么安排，议程怎么分布”，都是来了之后自己慢慢摸索出来的；这个崭新的会场周边商业还很稀少，如果不想吃会场内的餐饮如肯德基和赛百味，每天中午得去几公里外找吃的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和企业展区的酷炫相比，科幻迷展区显得朴素许多。一张桌子、一面旗帜、一张介绍卡片或者二维码，他们来自大学社团、国外的科幻组织，还有未成名的业余作者……有点像大学社团的招新现场。藏语科幻社团的桌子上，摆放着多年来出版的藏语科幻作品，一位藏族小伙耐心地给好奇的围观者介绍藏语科幻的历史。这样的氛围，更像此前的世界科幻大会，科幻文学研究学者严锋曾经参加过2019年都柏林世界科幻大会，回忆起那边的氛围，“自由散漫。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻馆二楼与三楼的会议室都被用来举办各种“沙龙”。所谓“沙龙”，就是科幻迷们自己组织的各种研讨会。科幻迷们自己邀请嘉宾，自己定选题，呈报给组委会之后，一般都会通过，然后组委会安排时间、场地，不再过问其他事务。历届世界科幻大会的沙龙场次稳定在三四百场之间。成都世界科幻大会报名的沙龙有四百多场，最终保留了230多场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次成都组委会一共邀请了六百多位嘉宾，其中海外嘉宾180多人（到场150多人），他们构成了沙龙的主力群体。过去的世界科幻大会，官方邀请的嘉宾只占很少一部分，其他参加沙龙的是科幻迷自己邀请的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈石在芝加哥世界科幻大会上也申请过一个沙龙。“我就带个表格，组委会直接跟我说地点、时间，你自己搞就OK了，他们就不怎么管你了。”陈石说，“在中国的文化背景下，可能这样并不合适。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“国外的世界科幻大会，对幻迷圈很有吸引力，但不出圈，他们的核心会员就两万多人，每年来的人变化不是很大，形成了自己的社群文化，要进入这个社群是有文化门槛的。如果我们完完全全照搬那个的话可能会非常惨，这个东西很难进入各个圈层。”当一开始陈石思考要办一届怎样的世界科幻大会的时候，他就已经决定要走一条不一样的路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨枫是科幻类出版企业八光分的CEO，她主编的《中国科幻口述史》也入围了2023年的雨果奖。她参加过多届世界科幻大会。她向南方周末记者回忆着此前的那些沙龙和展览，“那就像是科幻迷的party（聚会），没有多少&#39;高大上&#39;的设计，各种各样的coser（二次元形象模仿者）满场走，也有人围一个小圈子，整天弹吉他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让她流连忘返的还有曾经的跳蚤市场，每一年，科幻迷们都把自己的收藏、手工艺品、二手书拿到世界科幻大会的跳蚤市场拍卖，每个人在一个小牌子上写上自己心仪的价格，价高者得，“几乎每届我都拍到了我喜欢的东西”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“事务会议”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;质询、辩论&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;和&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;投票&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“您好，您的发言并不关涉到是与否的问题，而是另一个话题。”“您好，您的发言时间到了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星的发言不时地被主席台上的计时员打断。这是千星第一次来到世界科幻大会，也和绝大多数中国科幻迷一样，第一次体验事务会议。很多中国科幻迷流连于展区与沙龙，却往往忽视了这个重要会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但老科幻迷们都知道，“去参加事务会议，才能对世界科幻协会、世界科幻大会的组织方式和参与方式有一个深入的理解，而且你会感觉到一些好玩的地方。”陈石说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“事务会议”是每一届大会的重要议程，甚至是核心议程。在这个连续四五天的会议上，会员们经过质询、辩论、投票，对世界科幻大会的各种事务进行监督，也负责修改世界科幻大会的基石——《世界科幻协会章程》的某些条款。英语中，这个章程被称为“constitution”（宪法）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场会议的实践对于大多数中国科幻迷来说，都显得新鲜，甚至有点刺激。“什么是落日条款？”遇到不懂的法律名词，他们在现场也会坦诚地表达出来。他们的问题被来自全世界的人认真倾听。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果亲身感受过事务会议的流程与辩论，就不难理解幻迷圈为何将该会议称为“修宪会议”。成都世界科幻大会的事务会议放在了科幻馆的流星厅，这是一个独立于主馆的小厅，具有会员资格的人可以随时进入旁听、发表意见和投票。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星是在场中国会员中发言最为积极的，几乎每个议题，他都要发表自己的看法，说到忘我处，往往超出发言时间，被要求终止发言——这是一场严格按照《罗伯特议事规则》进行发言辩论的会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今年人来得少，往年更热闹。”八光分影视总监西夏对南方周末记者说。每年事务会议之前会有一个预备会议，讨论事务会议的具体安排。往年的预备会议也热闹非凡，往往主持人开讲没几分钟，就有会员跳出来质疑各种安排，“有的人说要配几个翻译，有的人说屏幕要怎么显示，最后双方各辩论两分钟预备会议要不要开始。”陈石回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于来的人少，副审裁官凯文·斯坦利对陈石透露，2023年应该是预备会议上“扯皮”最少的一届。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流星厅里远远没有坐满，门口放着厚厚的两本书，《罗伯特议事规则》的中英文版本，会员若对辩论流程有意见，可以随时查阅质询。西夏这次带来了自己的“宪法修正案”，他想要增设一个雨果奖奖项，颁给独立电影人制作的科幻电影，他认为目前的“最佳戏剧表现（长片）”这一奖项过于重视商业大片而忽视独立电影了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年代的幻迷大多是科幻小说的拥趸，于是最先设立的雨果奖便是1953年的最佳长篇小说奖，此后慢慢地追加了粉丝杂志、戏剧表演和漫画类的奖项。如果翻看历年得奖的电影，会发现大多数是好莱坞的商业大制作，西夏认为有必要改变这种状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“打个比方，小说的奖项，我们已经有给商业上最成功、最有名的小说发奖，但还有一些粉丝创作的、没有得到商业关注但是圈里面觉得写得很好的小说，雨果奖会给他们颁最佳粉丝作者、最佳粉丝杂志、最佳粉丝播客。这样的奖项电影类也应该有一个。”西夏说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想要在“修宪会议”上通过新的修正案，至少需要两年时间。提案如果能在第一年的大会上辩论通过，就会变成正式的修正提案，第二年再次进行二审辩论，通过之后才算“修宪”成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年进行二审辩论的有两个提案，其中一个是“是否增设雨果奖最佳游戏或互动作品的奖项”。在场的中国会员们似乎对这一提案普遍持谨慎态度，他们质疑“游戏”的定义，尤其是科幻类游戏的边界似乎并不清晰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“辩论时间结束。请支持这一提案的人站起来……反对这一提案的人站起来……”审裁官唐纳德·伊斯特雷克说。最后的投票结果为10：3，修正案通过，这意味着今后雨果奖就要增设这一奖项了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千星最激动的一次发言针对的是一个2023年的新提案。这一由凯文·斯坦利提出的新提案呼吁，此后的世界科幻大会在举办时间上最好在8月1日到9月30日之间，如果超出这一范围，应该和下一届的主办城市进行协商。千星的意见是，除了要和下一届主办方协商，还需要和会员们商量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“会员大会的参与者，有权利知道大会要更改日期。他们和组委会协商，组委会可以不采用这个会员的意见，但是这样协商的环节一定要有，一定要有表达意见的环节。”事务会议的休息空档，南方周末记者采访了千星。他看上去有些激动，大步走上主席台，发言语速慢却有力，希望把这个和会员协商的条款增补进凯文的提案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过投票，凯文的提案获得了通过，千星的增补条款没有获得通过。然而，整场会议都有视频摄录，千星的发言与意见已经被记录，成为了世界科幻大会的永久历史档案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西夏的提案也获得了初审通过。等到明年的格拉斯哥世界科幻大会，凯文与西夏的提案会被会员们再次审视、辩论、投票。《世界科幻协会章程》通过这种方式，让世界科幻大会回应着时代的变化与幻迷的诉求。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;创纪录、创历史&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日晚，第81届成都世界科幻大会颁出了这一届雨果奖。在此之前，本届奖项提名增加了不少有色面孔，中国入围者令人瞩目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国插画师赵恩哲获得了最佳职业艺术家奖，中国科幻迷河流与零始真编辑的《零重力报》获得了最佳粉丝杂志奖，科幻作家海漄的小说《时空画师》获得了“最佳短中篇小说奖”。按照雨果奖的传统，大会组委会要在颁奖之后公开投票的细节和数据，比如2022年芝加哥世界科幻大会的数据现在依然可以在官网上查到。这次大会之后，雨果奖官网上写道：“目前我们并没有此次投票数据的细节。我们将在获得数据的第一时间公布。”成都世界科幻大会中文官网上也暂时未能查到这个数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雨果奖评选委员会负责人戴夫·麦卡蒂在颁奖晚会后对记者说：“海漄的《时空画师》并没有英文译本，它创造了一个无英文译本、完全由中文作品获奖的历史。”这就意味着，给《时空画师》投票的会员可能大多是中国读者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;颁奖第二天，刊载《时空画师》的《银河边缘》（mook）在科幻馆内被销售一空，由于询问的人太多，科幻迷展区的售书摊上不得不挂出“售空”的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样卖得火热的当然还有刘慈欣作品，10月20日下午两点是刘慈欣的签售会，其他作家的签售一般只被安排了20分钟，主办方给刘慈欣预留了三个小时的签售时间。粉丝们早早挤满三楼签售大厅，队伍从三楼一直延伸到一楼，再蜿蜒绕了半圈的会场，很多站到腿酸的粉丝坐到了大刘的书上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来参展的各家出版机构想要在这个会场里签售自己的图书，并不容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希希是一家出版机构的编辑，这次他带来了一位作者的科幻小说到成都，还组织了一个沙龙，希望科幻迷们可以和作家本人好好聊聊，再办一个签售会。一开始，希希把整个流程都申报给了组委会，但到了开幕前几天收到通知，沙龙不能和签售放在一起。“平时的书展活动，作者和读者交流完之后有签售，但这里两个场地一定要分开，时间段也会分开。”希希说。这也就意味着，对作者有兴趣的读者，得跑两趟才能获得签名本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界科幻大会会场里的沙龙、论坛、峰会林林总总，但是除了开闭幕式、雨果奖颁奖晚会之外，还有一场“产业发展峰会”，几乎所有主要嘉宾都被邀请出席了这场峰会，阵容堪比雨果奖颁奖之夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是第一次在世界科幻大会上举办产业发展的相关会议。会上，多项科幻产业发展相关的计划被公布，包括《科幻产业成都共识》、“天问”计划、《2023中国成都科幻产业报告》等，甚至还有科幻产业项目的集中签约仪式，据统计有21个签约项目，总投资达80亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个“产业发展峰会”上，刘慈欣也不再聊文学，而是对产业发展侃侃而谈，：“成都很早就谋划布局科幻产业，相关的产业规划、产业政策、人才政策等均已落地实施。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“科幻全产业链生态圈”“IP打造”“强化科幻之都形象”，面对这些五花八门的新鲜词汇，加拿大科幻作家罗伯特·索耶表示，“看到你们把科幻变成产业，感到非常震惊。”他说，在北美做这些事情的可能是出版商，科幻就是随意的、漫无目的的、没有长期规划的一个事业。这些产业界人士在以往的世界科幻大会上一般不被邀请，来的大多是作家、编辑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都科幻馆所在的这一片区域，也将被打造为成都的科幻高地。据一位接近当地政府的人士向南方周末记者介绍，这里以后可能要建一个科幻产业园，“那条街就是一个科幻主题的街区，一家家科幻企业后续可能会入驻，这一片说是要搞一个科幻露营基地，每年会做科幻作家的训练营和学生的夏令营，而科幻馆本身是一个大型的消费+公益结合的空间，这一圈会打造成一个科幻主题的旅游目的地。”他站在高台之上，手指从这一头划向那一头，划出一个大大的弧线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当地政府做了场馆、交通等保障工作，还发动了很多志愿者，”陈石说，“诉求核心就两点，一是提升成都的城市品牌形象，二是扶持科幻产业。”这届大会还创下了一个纪录——它拉到了有史以来最多的赞助商。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是什么让中国年轻人喜欢科幻？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;午后的幻迷展区，喧嚣异常，即便这一天已经是世界科幻大会的最后一天。一个机器人鼓手在角落里循环敲击着鼓点，家长带着孩子们坐了两个小时的公共交通，现在刚刚入馆，孩子们手上拿着敲章打卡的本子，尖叫着穿梭于各个展台之间。还有一位科幻迷拿着自己写的书在宣传：“我写的书和刘慈欣的世界观截然相反……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这片喧闹海洋之中，有一个人在椅子上打盹儿。他满头白发，牛仔帽放在桌上，双眼低垂，像是进入了另一个世界。他叫詹姆斯·约瑟夫，来自澳大利亚，七十多岁的他已经当了近五十年科幻迷。1975年，世界科幻大会第一次在大洋洲举办，他被科幻的氛围打动，至今已经去过15次世界科幻大会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;詹姆斯对南方周末记者说，这次大会是他去过的最特殊的一届，以前不管是在欧洲还是美国，从来没有见过这么多热情而年轻的科幻迷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年轻，是这届大会的一个关键词。“我今天签的名比过去56年加起来还多。”被找他签名的小学生们团团围住，尼古拉斯·怀特显得有点受宠若惊，学生们顺着摊位，一家一家地打卡、要签名。组委会和成都很多中小学达成合作，组织了很多学生去各种沙龙与论坛旁听，科幻馆里几乎没有冷场的时候。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2025年西雅图申幻组委会成员艾伦·布兰特对南方周末记者说，成都世界科幻大会的规模是他见过最大的。此前这项纪录的保持者是2014年的伦敦，参会人数在1万人左右。而据官方媒体公布的数字，成都的参会者超过了2万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，科幻文学的黄金年代是二战之后的几十年。当时正值美苏争霸，西方经济高速发展，科幻文学顺势而动，成为当时很多年轻人的精神家园。半个多世纪过去，当年的科幻迷们垂垂老矣，像詹姆斯·约瑟夫这样的西方老科幻迷，他们的银发是成都科幻馆里的亮点。“对于美国的科幻作品来说，很多读者都是灰头发，也就是中老年人才会读科幻作品，但是中国相反，年轻人更喜欢科幻作品。这是我的困惑，是什么让中国年轻人喜欢科幻？”罗伯特·索耶在成都提出了这个问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前的每次大会，都会专设一个缅怀区域，这是一个中老年科幻迷怀旧、叙旧的地方。2017年，英国科幻作家布莱恩·奥尔迪斯去世，当年的世界科幻大会就有一个小小的空间，里面展陈着他生前的作品、照片，和一些他收藏的宝贝，一台朴素的黑白电视机，播放他生前的采访视频。2023年，奥尔迪斯的女儿温蒂也来到了成都，她告诉南方周末记者，原本成都世界科幻大会要为这些照片举办一个展览，但后来“因为空间不够”，没能实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨枫原本也打算在大会上办一个缅怀的展览。缅怀的人物是美国科幻杂志《银河边缘》的前主编迈克尔·雷斯尼克。2020年，雷斯尼克去世之后，他的收藏和图书被挂到网上拍卖，八光分买到了大量他的藏品，“你看这个玻璃展柜里全是他的东西。”杨枫指着一个玻璃柜说。一开始，主办方答应给70平米的展陈面积。由于担心错过会期，藏品“花了上万元运费运回来”。后来展区被很多科技企业挤占，只给了杨枫一面玻璃展柜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们的黄金年代确实已经过去了。”严锋说，“而中国的科幻热又有很多网络的特征，我在这里看到很多人追星，听到很多尖叫，特别是对大刘和郭帆这样的人。中国科幻发展起来有它的幸运，网络文化的助推是非常有力的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都本土科幻作家何夕认为，目前的中国科幻处于第三次浪潮初期。“第一次是建国之初百业俱兴，第二次是1979年&#39;科学的春天&#39;，现在是第三次。”他说。另一位已经封笔的科幻作家王晋康也回忆了1990年代中国科幻的低潮期，“那时候中国科幻是野生野长，不太被社会关注，但是也有很多科幻迷，我们到大学里参加活动，都是用粉笔在黑板上写一个&#39;欢迎王晋康先生&#39;，就这样开始交流。那时的简陋也有它的情趣，现在还很怀念。现在确实不一样了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你能在大会的会场里隐隐感到一种科幻文化的冲突，”《零重力报》的编辑零始真对南方周末记者讲述了他的观察，“但我并不认为这种冲突是一种有害的，或者没有意义的东西，这是一个必经的过程。既然你要拥抱一个真正多元的世界，这一步是逃不开的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为大学老师，严锋已经很久没有在国内的学术会议上见过那么多国际友人了，这让他颇为感动，“目前这个分裂的世界，越来越相互隔绝，甚至对抗、敌视，但是科幻肯定是要超越国界来思考人类层面的问题，这也是科幻可贵的地方。”就像刘慈欣曾在不同场合所强调的，“科幻小说里，人类是作为一个整体出现的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦·布兰特说西雅图世界科幻大会已经搞定了场馆，但当地的科幻协会还在和酒店谈判，以期拿到更低的价格。尼古拉斯·怀特说自己有点“嫉妒”成都，明年的格拉斯哥世界科幻大会他估计拉不到这么多赞助：“很显然，成都世界科幻大会得到了当地政府的巨大支持，这在欧洲是很难实现的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（希希、千星为化名，南方周末实习生陈荃新对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[试管婴儿纳入医保：不孕不育是医学问题，也是社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259718]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，广西壮族自治区医保局等部门印发《关于将部分治疗性辅助生殖类医疗服务项目纳入基本医疗保险和工伤保险基金支付范围的通知》，将取卵术、胚胎培养、胚胎移植等辅助生殖项目纳入基本医保支付范围，职工医保与居民医保报销比例分别为70%与50%。新规于2023年11月1日起执行。据南宁市第二人民医院生殖医疗中心主任李荣估算，按上述通知，生育困难妇女做一代、二代试管婴儿，根据险种不同，可报销幅度在4000多元至1万多元不等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一举措，再次引发关注与讨论。此前，已有若干省份将辅助生殖项目纳入基本医保。自今年7月1日起，北京将包括“试管婴儿”、人工授精等在内的16项治疗性辅助生殖技术项目纳入基本医保报销范围；辽宁今年也将胚胎培养、胚胎移植术等18项辅助生殖项目纳入生育保险目录。可以想见，会有更多省份跟进，辅助生殖技术进基本医保或成标配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受惠于这一医保政策主要是两类家庭：一类家庭是高龄产妇有生育需求但难以自然怀孕，另一类家庭是（非年龄因素导致的）不孕不育，如先天因素、生育史、生活方式或环境因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家人类辅助生殖技术评审组专家张学红介绍：一般认为女性生理上的理想生育年龄是22-28岁，或至少不超过35岁，因为生育能力或卵巢功能在35岁之前达到峰值，之后便快速下降，超龄生育风险也会随之增高；而且，根据她的临床经验来看，近年来寻求辅助生殖的患者，平均年龄有年轻化的趋势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一类家庭的辅助生育需求源于：随着结婚与生育的不断推迟，年龄因素导致的不孕人数越来越高。据2017年生育状况抽样调查数据，2006至2016年，中国女性平均初育年龄从2006年的24.3岁上升到2016年的26.9岁。而在大城市，初育与生育年龄更迟，如2022年上海平均初育年龄为30.36岁，平均生育年龄为31.18岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二类不孕不育家庭，除了先天性因素外，生育史也是一个绕不过去的重大因素。2021年，北京大学第三医院院长乔杰发布《柳叶刀中国妇幼健康特邀重大报告》，报告称，2007-2020年间，我国不孕发病率从12%升至18%。在生育史方面，流产尤其是反复流产可能导致术后的输卵管炎、子宫内膜炎，甚至输卵管粘连堵塞、宫腔粘连，进而导致不孕。上述报告显示，2005-2017年，中国人工流产率从20.2‰升至27.3‰。在中国至少经历过一次流产的女性中，重复流产率为65.2%。居高不下的流产率及重复流产率同不孕率高度正相关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因想要一个孩子的愿望强烈而求助于辅助生育技术，如试管婴儿，并不是“洒洒水”的轻松事儿，基本上做一次就成功是撞大运，从取卵到胚胎培养再到胚胎移植，每一个环节都可能出问题而功败垂成，身体遭受的痛苦、精神承受的压力，不足为外人道也。所付出的成本，不仅仅是金钱、时间与精力，更多的是精神上的负担与耗损。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个意义上，试管婴儿纳入基本医保，只能部分覆盖这些家庭所承受的财务成本，但无法从根本上解决不孕不育问题，因为不孕不育既是医学问题，也是社会问题。而一般来说，一个问题，在未出现或萌芽状态就予以重视，该预防就预防，该解决就解决，成本是最低的；等到酿成大规模社会问题再去应对，不仅成本会呈指数级上升，而且效果也难以让人满意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，可以解决的不孕不育问题是：让初育年龄往前推，落到最佳生育年龄区间内，这就要及早婚育；减少流产率尤其重复流产率，这就要降低乃至避免计划外的怀孕。这样比将来求助于辅助生殖技术好。对个人与家庭来说，显然可以这样考量与决策。不过，一个问题一旦上升为社会问题，就没有那么简单了，因为这一社会问题的本质是价值观问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多人把婚育年龄推迟、生育率下降、不婚不育族兴起，归结为生育成本太高。但就生育而言，显然收益端比成本端更重要。现在不少年轻男女追问“结婚组成家庭与生儿育女的意义何在”，本身就意味着生育本能与婚育价值观的骤变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我们生活在一个前所未有的和平与繁荣时代，物质丰裕是空前的，这第一会导致选择压的降低与消失，此时种群更倾向于自我享受而不是牺牲自我享受、含辛茹苦来抚育后代；第二会导致不婚不育观念的兴起，此种观念反过来又会进一步压制婚育意愿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于居高不下的流产率尤其重复流产率问题，从术的层面看，无非是加强避孕措施的问题；从道的层面看，还有一个如何加强性道德的问题。父母应该关心子女的价值观，言传身教子女对性有一个严肃与谨慎的态度：男性当然应该尊重女性的权利与意愿，并负起应有的责任；女性作为自己身心健康的第一责任人，应该保护自己的身体与生殖健康，在中国司法实践上，生育权或生育决定权是女性独有的，这权利的另一面意味着对自己的终极责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[茅台宣布涨价20%，你会考虑买吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR5qcV1BCEtlztjt7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR5qcV1BCEtlztjt7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚，茅台公告：自11月1日起上调53%vol贵州茅台酒（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;飞天、五星&lt;/span>;）出厂价格，&lt;strong>;平均上调幅度约20%&lt;/strong>;。此次调整不涉及产品的市场指导价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是茅台近6年来的首次提价。上一次是2018年1月，53度500ml飞天茅台出厂价由819元提高到969元、零售价格调整到1499元。按照此次20%的涨幅预估，飞天茅台酒的出厂价格或将达到1162.8元左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;茅台涨价对股价也有一定影响。11月1日，贵州茅台竞价高开9.82%，股价报1850元，逼近涨停。虽然开盘后又很快回落，但截至上午11点，贵州茅台仍涨4.74%，日内成交额达134亿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年6月，贵州茅台董事长丁雄军在股东大会上曾表示，什么时候提价、怎么提价，确实要有智慧，“若飞天茅台能够提价，会有更多利润，管理层也是这样想的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;名优白酒市场出现价格倒挂，飞天茅台几乎是一枝独秀。梳理2004-2020年53度飞天茅台出厂价与零售价，不难看出，出厂价一路看涨，零售价涨幅达到757%。其中既有市场供求关系影响，也有消费者“囤货看涨”的心理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年8月，贵州茅台前董事长季克良谈到，“年轻人不喝茅台，那是因为还没到时候”。此次宣布涨价，会对人们的购买意愿产生影响吗？当“茅台冰激凌”“酱香拿铁”“酒心巧克力”陆续出圈，多少人会为那一口昂贵的茅台酒买单？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在3260米的香格里拉高山植物园，普通比浪漫重要]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259715]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;海拔3260米的香格里拉高山植物园。视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在植物园工作是怎样的体验？这已经吸引我很久了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在无数个写稿无能的深夜，我都想辞职去植物园当一枚园丁。梦想很快得以实现，地点居然还在香格里拉。2023年9月，我在香格里拉高山植物园当上了实习园丁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;香格里拉原名中甸，地处云南迪庆藏族自治州。3260米，这里是全世界海拔最高的植物园，相当于1/5颐和园的土地上保护着约一千种高等植物。这里有多种以中甸命名的地方特有种，如中甸刺玫、中甸山楂等，还有些是国家重点保护野生植物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蹊跷的是，这里还繁育着数百种高原植物，它们基本不是奇花异草，甚至“平凡又普通”；大多数植物园属于财政拨款的事业单位，而香格里拉高山植物园却是一个“三无”——“没钱”“没人”“没编制”的民办非企业组织，1999年筹建，2005年开园，靠自己寻找生存之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一切赋予了香格里拉高山植物园遗世独立又浪漫的色彩。然而，短暂的实习和采访结束后，浪漫于我早已消解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这是一个寻找普通种子意义的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;浪漫&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;沿着滇藏公路，从香格里拉县城出发一直往西北方向，楼房渐渐后退，大片金黄的青稞忽然闯入眼前。9月初，夏季积雪融化形成的纳帕海正渐变成嫩绿的依拉草原，马儿在游荡，白色藏式民居在云下发光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;从香格里拉高山植物园看纳帕海。 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在这天堂般美景的一角，就是我要实习的地方：香格里拉高山植物园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月1日9点，从植物园东门出发，穿过野山，路过菌子，爬过木栏，差点摔跤，我到了半山腰的苗圃。今天我的工作任务是，把室内的金丝桃苗搬到室外，拖拉机再把金丝桃运到山顶上的植物园迷宫区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;拖拉机在苗圃装金丝桃。 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;听起来好简单。第一步，换装备。我换上一件红黑格子小熊围裙，长度到达脚踝，套上塑胶手套，抱一个粉色大盆。第二步，进苗圃。一间苗圃长24米，宽8米,相当于一间教室。地上摆着上百个黑袋子，里面装着金丝桃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月24日，江苏淮安，九龙湖公园的金丝桃花盛开。视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;金丝桃是公园和绿化项目的常见花卉，6、7月开花时，顶部纤细一束花蕊灿若金丝，底部花瓣又像蝴蝶翅膀，所以又叫金线蝴蝶。我此刻看见的金丝桃已播种两年，还未开花，长着纤细的小枝和椭圆的叶子，靠近时清香扑鼻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我发现这个植物园和之前去过的都不一样，既没有奇形怪状的盆栽，也不会搜罗全球珍品集锦展览。相反，植物园里有很多类似金丝桃的本土植物，开粉花的中甸刺玫、蓝紫色的中甸乌头，结红果的中甸山楂，矗立的云南松和高山松树……它们的名字就带着本土标签，比如“中甸”“云南”“高山”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中甸翠雀。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;植物园创始人、老园长方震东的办公室也挂着一幅本土植物——轮叶绿绒蒿。59岁的他，体型中等，眉眼像下垂的八字，头发花白，双颧有着高原紫外线渲染的黑红。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;方震东是迪庆维西人，当地缺乏生物人才，他的高考志愿从数学系被改成了生物系，云南大学毕业后回到迪庆高原生物研究所工作。后来，他走遍了迪庆的山脉和山谷，编写了《中国云南横断山野生花卉》一书。快35岁时，方震东想在香格里拉建成一座世界级的植物园，这对当时的他而言，也是一件浪漫的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;方震东在尼汝高山区考察途中。 受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;云南是园艺植物大本营，在一百多年前就已为国外的“植物猎人”知晓。欧洲植物种类至多12000种，而云南有17000种，仅香格里拉就有5000多种。高山峡谷，垂直海拔梯度大，这里成为冰期时植物的避难所和生物多样性的孕育之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位叫乔治·弗瑞斯特的苏格兰人被爱丁堡植物园派到中国，从1904年开始，在横断山脉进行了七次植物探险。他在丽江白沙雇了八个纳西人，把高黎贡山的一株直径达一米多的杜鹃花搬出深山，运到大英博物馆展示；用骡子运出了31000件云南植物种子和腊叶标本，引荐给全世界的园林，标本供爱丁堡皇家植物园的分类学家重新命名和发表新种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;弗瑞斯特从云南带回的杜鹃花和报春至今仍在爱丁堡植物园繁育，标本保存在标本馆里。1990年代，方震东去了爱丁堡植物园。如今回想起来，他依然很受触动，“我们当地的植物资源被外国人重视，我们自己呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;聊到这，方震东突然起身，找出自己那本《中国云南横断山野生花卉》，指着他导师的导师、已故植物学家秦仁昌先生的一段话，一字一字念道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;云南植物之富源，所以贡献于欧美文明之进步者，至远且大，惜乎我国科学落后，国人前此不知利用已有天赋宝藏以厚其生，而反见通都大邑，公私庭院所栽培观赏者，几乎全为舶来之品，为欧美庭园数百年来习见之花卉，一入国境，好之者犹趋之若鹜，舍己芸人，良可叹唉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这段话写于1930年代，可即使到1990年代，不重视本土物种，甚至受到外来物种威胁的情况依然存在。方震东还记得，当时一种原产于南美的紫茎泽兰从云南南部进入，顺着滇越铁路向迪庆靠近。他担心当地的生态系统受外来物种入侵影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;土地利用也在发生变化，天然牧场变为耕地，山坡因挖沙采石而裸露。方震东发现，迪庆原是野生中国兰花资源最丰富的区域，1980年代，他每进一个山沟，兰花不难找到。但1990年代，兰花热兴起，外来的老板一卡车一卡车把兰花买走，此后野生兰花四处难寻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以方震东想建设植物园，“一是保育当地物种；二是开发利用当地的植物资源用于园林建设和栽培”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1999年，高山植物园在云南省发改委和原环保厅论证后立项，先设立筹建办公室，方震东被任命为主任。2001年，园区启动建设，在挖沙采石裸露的伤疤上，种上了植物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;如今，高山植物园已从沙坑长出绿树。&amp;nbsp; 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;现实&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我在苗圃里换好衣服后，二话不说，开干。我蹲下来，用铲子把金丝桃钻出袋，划断地上的根，放进盆里。一袋金丝桃连苗带土约4斤，一盆能装两袋。装好、起身，我运用腰背的力量抱起盆，走10米到苗圃外，取出苗摆好、返回。以此重复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;搬运金丝桃苗。&amp;nbsp; 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2、4、6……我每运一盆，都默默计数，数字上升，很有成就感。可从第10盆开始，起身有点吃力，腰背开始勉强。到第16盆，已经不是吃力的问题了，我大口喘息、心脏怦怦跳。你是不是觉得我弱？可我是在海拔三千米的高原做负重练习，在一个说话速度明显放缓、避免跑跳的地方搬土。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;20、22，我坚持不下去了。10:36，下雨了，大棚漏雨，一个多小时的搬运工作得以停歇，我不知道有多感恩这场雨。站起身来，眼前一黑，光明和对植物园的浪漫想象都在这一瞬消解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“建植物园，会有浪漫消失的时刻吗？”我问方震东。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“有，找钱的时候。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1999年，植物园筹建的办公室仅是临时机构，无法为新聘请的员工交五险。2004年，植物园办公室邀请相关部门开会，研讨管理体制，得出两种方案：一是共建事业单位，中国科学院西双版纳热带植物园和当地政府各出几个编制共同管理，由中央或地方财政拨款经营，这也是国内植物园常见的体制。另一种是民办非企业，自负盈亏，没有财政预算，没有编制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们把第一套共建方案推荐给政府，但是当时政府财政还比较困难，编制可能也紧张，提出来按第二个方案先管着。”方震东说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一方案为后来的经营压力埋下伏笔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;植物园成立民办非企业后，也成立了第一届理事会,方震东成为法定代表人、理事长兼执行园长。压力像山一样涌来，找建设资金、发员工工资，还需要承担当地社区生态补偿。合计下来，每年维护植物园的费用不少于三百万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;虽处于旅游胜地，这里却难以靠游客收入赚钱。9月1日17:28，离闭园还有2分钟，全天买票进入植物园的共六位，两位外地游客，四位本地游客，共收费80元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;曾有员工觉得现在游客都爱打卡拍照，建议“要不跟上时代，做一个樱花大道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;方震东否定得非常直接，“你想看樱花到公园去看嘛，我们又不是公园。”他觉得，更重要的“还是展示被驯化后的当地原生物种，（这才）是我们出发的初衷”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;植物园常常负债。方震东一位好友总是借钱给他，“他是个科学家，不是生意人，只能去写科研报告，接绿化工程，有的（项目）还收不来钱”。一般人的压力最多持续一两个月，而方震东坚持了二十年，靠科研和工程项目支撑，两三年前情况才有所缓解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;建园24年，植物园在20名员工的努力下，建起了香雪药园、林芝云杉采种园、高山松采种园等多个专类园。经营情况虽有好转，可一些设想还停留在纸面上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;靠近植物园南门的指示牌上写着“干热型”“潮湿型”展览温室，循着方向过去，则是两块裸露着碎石的石灰岩。方震东算了一笔账，温室建设有两部分大头，先是基础设施建设，后是物种搜集和栽培。前期投资估计要一千多万，后期维护更费钱，“保暖、控温、控湿都要考虑”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;温室目前还停留在路牌和规划中。&amp;nbsp; 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“累。”植物园现任院长方晔的眼里满是疲倦。三年前，他从父亲方震东手里接手了植物园，想建智慧景区、完善讲解系统，可是都困于没有人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;本地的年轻人更愿意进体制内工作，外地人则嫌偏远，方晔在微博上好不容易招了一个1995年出生的广西大学生，待了4年，“什么都没说”就走了。4年已算很久了，方晔现在招人都不奢望能待这么长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;方晔还是希望植物园能并入事业单位，而在并入之前，这家民办非企业组织还要靠自己寻找出路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;雨停了，我数了数，墙边已经摆上了一百多袋的金丝桃，一位园丁师傅把围裙脱下，我看到他缠绕着一圈又一圈的白色护腰带。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;种子&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高山植物园苗圃育出金丝桃苗的第一步，自然是先有种子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;园丁师傅带我去看金丝桃的种子。一走进苗圃二楼的种子仓库，松香扑面而来。我第一次见到这么多“干货”：高山松的球果像有弹性的褐色小球，鲁冰花的种子像拇指大小的莲蓬，林芝云杉的果则像晒干的坚硬玫瑰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他从一个大麻袋里抓出一小撮说，“这是金丝桃的种子”。我凑近看，它们比沙子轻，比木屑小，风一吹就跑了，随风繁衍，这是自然的生存法则。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但人类搜集种子就难了。临到11月金丝桃出种季，植物园会请村民去野外搜集金丝桃种子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;可并不是所有种子都能靠村民，植物园的员工也得去野外采种子，同时也考察极小种群、搜集标本。极小种群是指分布地域狭窄，受外界干扰严重，随时濒临灭绝的野生植物。要找到它们，异常艰难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;256377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;植物园采集扭黄茅种子。 受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位叫海仙的员工日记记载了考察的“平凡的一天”：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020年8月17日，平凡的一天，世界上有许多大事发生，但暂时与我们无关。我们行走于西藏净地的日喀则地区吉隆县吉隆镇乃夏村的后山，专注于野外调查工作，远离了信息的喧嚣，似乎所有的流言都失去了载体，成了一座座无名的孤岛。处于这样的环境中，我们每天似乎都有很多的话，又似乎每天都在说同样的话。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;“你饿不饿？”……说实话，我也有些饿，但这不算什么……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;只是身体像海绵吸收了山顶雾水，冲锋衣里都是水，湿漉漉的，脱了又像塞在冰箱里面，从脊椎骨直冒嗖嗖的寒气。然后肺里面塞了火炉，冷气吸进去，肺直疼。脚？我已经对它没多少指望了，只希望回到住所前没罢工就好了……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天走得太久，又走得太远。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;从海拔2800米拉升到海拔4000米，只为寻找胡黄连。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;若能采到种子，这些辛苦在工作表格里会化作短短一行。比如：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;海仙、方晔等高山监测队，吉隆镇后山，胡黄连种子。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和普通种子被装在麻袋里不同，那些备受艰辛采回的种子被锁在一个小房间里，尊贵地存储于一个个玻璃罐子或者塑料盒子里，这里是种子库——“高原植物的诺亚方舟”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;种子库里的种子。&amp;nbsp; 梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;小盒子里的绿绒蒿种子像芝麻碎，2022年8月7日在4786米的西藏昌都芒东达山垭口采的。绿绒蒿，又称“高山牡丹”“梦幻之花”，生长在海拔三四千米以上的流石滩或冰川前沿，全株被有绒毛或刚毛，颜色清透夺目。有三种绿绒蒿被定为国家二级重点保护野生植物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;绿绒蒿。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;采回来后，种子需要经过浸泡选种的流程，空壳或不饱满的种子会漂起来被捞走扔掉。但刘琳舍不得将绿绒蒿浸种，因为太难采到，“漂起来的（万一）也能出苗呢，扔掉可惜”。这位植物园副园长身材高大，脸蛋有两坨红晕，桌子上都是植物表格，她管理着种子的收集、繁育、驯化和利用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;成功繁育绿绒蒿的例子少之又少。2022年12月5日，刘琳和同事们种下一批绿绒蒿，一个月后，出苗率不到50%。绿绒蒿“最容易死是长出两瓣叶片的时候，水多它会死，水少也会死，所以很难”。我问她最终有多少苗活下来，她指了指远处的那堆土，“你看这里本来全是，一半已经死了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;工作十几年，对刘琳而言，接受植物的死亡早已习惯。身经百战，关关难过，出苗之后还有炼苗——采取放风、降温、适当控水等措施锻炼幼苗。她还记得第一次种的尼泊尔黄花木，在苗圃温室里养了半年移出去炼苗，一个冬天全死了，两万棵只剩下两三棵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;只能一切重来。他们估摸着，也许是太冻了，移栽的季节不对。所以趁尼泊尔黄花木苗还在温室时，偶尔摆出来在太阳下炼一会儿，结实一点再移栽。这些高原本土植物的繁育，没有前人的经验，“只能试着做”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;像我今天搬运的金丝桃，出苗很容易，但不知道为何，小苗移栽时候容易死。所以他们摸索出了新方案：把袋子灌满土，种子点在土里，等苗长大了，直接把袋子撕开种进地里即可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我能看到的每棵纤纤金丝桃都是奇迹，历经生死。然而金丝桃并不属于珍稀物种，也没有进保护名录，刘琳、园丁师傅们费尽心力繁育的本土植物，最终要去哪呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;修复&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月30日，我跟着绿色和平团队在离香格里拉不远的一条公路看到，一些为修路炸开的山，裸露的地块上种了整整齐齐的杉树，可叶子发蔫发黄，在高寒的山里耷拉着。绿色和平的研究员不无惋惜地说，“这些树估计都是活不成的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘琳说，很多生态修复都是买外来树种，价格便宜，容易扦插，但很难适应当地环境，后期的维护管理也比较难，严重影响成活率。方晔解释，很多人觉得生态修复，就是一两年内检查验收时绿起来就够了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;香格里拉在1980、1990年代遭遇过大规模商业采伐，2010年后，大家意识到了生态修复的重要性。但是方震东感觉，最初的生态修复“根本没有好的理念和思路，绿化公司按现成方案找现成树种，也不管植物能不能适应（环境）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;8月28日，我在香格里拉参加了一场关于生态修复的研讨会，来自云南大学、中国林业科学研究院的专家们也认为真正的生态修复不是单纯种树和绿化：在黄土高原不顾一切地种树，不让间伐，森林过密会给水源少的地方雪上加霜； 火未必是“万恶之源”，对于有的森林，火只是把表层烧焦，种子在火烧后给予时间，则会焕发生机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;研讨会后，方震东带我们去看大果青杄——松科云杉属乔木，国家二级保护植物。他说，政策规定谁砍伐谁恢复，大果青杄被大量用来造林。建植物园时，有课题组也申请退化林地的植被恢复课题，在植物园种了300亩的大果青杄。刚种上时生长很慢，到一米后快速生长，果实红而光滑，观赏性很好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;方震东忽然停下讲解，寻找记者，提醒我记下来。他接着说，香格里拉一处景点有一片大果青杄林地，相继出现病害、虫害。有一种云杉鳃扁叶蜂会把这个树的针叶全部啃光。另外有一种真菌病害，树叶莫名其妙开始黄，紧接着整个树干就干枯，树成片死亡。香格里拉高山植物园也发生过虫害，但后来没有了，也许被其他的生物控制住了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但在很多地方，整片云杉被病害侵蚀，传入当地的落叶松。然而，本地云杉不会长这种病害。“我们跟林业部门建议，今后造林了不要用这个（大果青杄）种，要用我们本地的云杉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;植物园里的大果青扦梁静怡/摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2006年，方震东领会到生态修复演替理论：植物群落是动态变化的，随着时间的推移，一个植物群落被另一个植物群落代替。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从裸露地表开始，草种飞进来演变成草本植被；鸟兽把灌木和乔木种子通过粪便排在这里，演变成灌丛；乔木十几年后长成优势植被，变成森林；不同种类的乔木经过幼龄、中龄慢慢成熟，上百年后成为顶级植被。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;采伐开矿则是重新将顶级植被打回原始的裸露地表，如果没有人为干预，自然依然会重来一轮演替。而方震东团队尝试把上百年的演替时间缩短，比如依靠风鸟兽传播种子要数十年，人工播种插苗则只需几天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;演替的过程中，有的植物被称为“先锋植物”，它们很快萌芽，覆盖住地表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“比如我搬运的金丝桃？”我问方震东。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“对，它算是一种先锋植物，在2000-3300米的海拔范围，在火烧地上能自然生长起来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;香格里拉植物园里的本土植物适应了高寒、恶劣的环境，在生态修复中，后续维护费低，也不容易受到病虫害影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;近年来，生态修复失败的项目纷纷到植物园请教经验。困于经营的植物园也找到生存之道，不再负债。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1129&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;生态修复案例地恢复前后。&amp;nbsp; 受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我去了一片生态修复的案例地。这里曾经因造桥而成为裸露的荒地，石灰岩、碎屑、碎石遍布。从2006年起，借助自然演替的理论，植物园培育的高山松苗、尼泊尔黄花木、皱叶报春、云南沙棘已渐渐成为先锋植物，“占领”了裸露地表。现在，被风吹来的杨絮也在此落了根，长成杨树。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;远处，天葬台的人骨已成碎块，红嘴鸦在松赞林寺盘旋。被人破坏的山野植物慢慢恢复，普通种子在这里生根发芽，岁月漫长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马大勇：关于三部电影的回忆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259586]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;《四个婚礼和一个葬礼》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sALtonw37jkUcz1EzbAPbtJSujus10HVlqo2d0Gf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sALtonw37jkUcz1EzbAPbtJSujus10HVlqo2d0Gf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Four Weddings and A Funeral &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想不到又记起安迪。我说的是安迪·麦克道尔，《四个婚礼和一个葬礼》（Four Weddings and A Funeral）的女主角。诗人朱朱曾经别致地把朱丽叶·比诺什比喻成“春天里第一口冰淇淋”，是啊，每个人都有自己的一口冰淇淋。不同的是，他的冰淇淋是法国货，而我的来自美国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据说《四个婚礼和一个葬礼》是英国喜剧电影的代表，可当年乐不可支的情形已差不多全忘了。淘洗不掉的只剩下安迪那种眼神，温柔而爱怜地望着总显得仓皇、笨拙的休·格兰特，也望着一样仓皇、笨拙的我。她是那种很宽容、很克制的人，允许你犯错，并浅浅地把你拥入怀中。在我二十几岁的那段光阴，安迪一直静悄悄地注视着我的忧伤，不张扬，不耀眼，作我青春时代梦中那朵朴素的奇花。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，把她忘了。时间飞驶，心灵汩没，少年情味渐次消沉，夜晚也不复有梦。于是，安迪成了年轻时的一枚坐标，沉淀在岁月的光影里，一天一天剥蚀、漫漶。十丈红尘腾起的时候，我们心底还剩下什么？曾读某些绮丽的小词，感慨良多，遂题一绝句：“饱食心溺笔头禅，滴粉搓酥事惘然。当年我亦钟情甚，曾对春风写缠绵。”当春天的冰淇淋一点点融化，梦里的奇花一丝丝凋零，安迪，我们都抵挡不住光阴的魔杖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自古美人如名将，不许人间见白头”，一转眼，安迪有六十几岁了吧？在网上已不易找到她青春的底片。奥黛丽·赫本、凯瑟琳·泽塔·琼斯、苏菲·玛索、张曼玉、关之琳、钟丽缇、朱茵……午夜对镜，她们该是如何爱怜地想起自己灿放的红颜？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;《时光倒流七十年》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/vpztrExXnh6Tp89qxkOGuwoYdapFWWvdWJCAtFYr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/vpztrExXnh6Tp89qxkOGuwoYdapFWWvdWJCAtFYr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Somewhere in Time &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“春天的花开秋天的风以及冬天的落阳，忧郁的青春年少的我曾经无知地这么想”，在二十世纪八九十年代的大学校园，再也没有另外的音乐比罗大佑的这首歌更能拨动我们的心弦。我是一个对时光颇为敏感的人，少年时候就会沉浸在她的魔力中不能自拔，再后来看过了穷途，看过了传奇，看过了浮沉，也看过了生死，终于明白时光可以治疗一切，雕刻一切，那就已经走向中年的沧桑了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有很长一段时间狂热地关注时光电影。因为电影是认识时光的途径之一，它有无穷的假设能力，也有无穷的表现能力，带给我无穷的感动和哀愁。同样属于青春岁月的一部电影：《时光倒流七十年》（Somewhere in Time），当结尾处男主角看到硬币上镶嵌着今天的日月，而七十年前的美人瞬间向着时光的那一端飘落，那是怎样的天荒地老的惆怅，又何其令人悚然！时光题材的电影通常有惊人的视觉效果，像《回到未来》，像《黑洞频率》，像《时间机器》，这部没有，它是靠时光本身来制造效果的，如一杯纯正的苦丁茶，没有任何附加的味道。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;《肖申克的救赎》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kcje4CxpjUT7PJW6oRdUxKTdl0CK4IBNe9MBXEOL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;453&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kcje4CxpjUT7PJW6oRdUxKTdl0CK4IBNe9MBXEOL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Shawshank Redeption&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，什么才是时光的味道呢？对我来说，至少，那些画面模糊、跳动的黑白录像带算是一种吧。喜爱上了电影之后，有那么长一段时间是那些黑白光影在陪伴着我，朝夕晨昏，像是看不清也记不住的一个个幻梦。《美国往事》《去年在马里昂巴》《芳芳》《红》《地下》，对了，还有那部永远跳不过去的《肖申克的救赎》（The Shawshank Redeption）。在看过了几十次之后，我至今也不大能说清它的魅力所在，或者，任何阐述和说明都是没必要的，如佛家所云，会成为“文字障”？但是，有些句子我仍可以随意在记忆的仓库中提取（感谢录像带版的字幕组，他们的中文版本比史蒂芬·金毫无逊色）：“我们听不懂里面唱的什么，但那好像是天使的声音，使厚重的石墙消失无踪。在此瞬间，鲨堡众囚重获自由”“忙啊，忙着活，或者忙着死”“有些鸟是关不住的，因为它们的羽翼太光辉了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;羽翼光辉的鸟儿们在我曾经黯淡的世界里盘桓，没有它们的鸣叫，我们将永远是绝望的囚徒。在那个夜晚盯着跳动的黑白光影，听着录像带“咝咝”的回响，我的牢笼也消失无踪，我来到了月亮和星辰之上，咀嚼着时光的味道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是电影。对我来说，它可能意味着一种生存的方法，风定尘落，天空降下了幸福和吉祥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网络实名制，在争论中从“幕后”走向“前台”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 11:45:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;大V们将面临一次前台实名制考验。农健插画&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d7b3195417.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d7b3195417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256323&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;大V们将面临一次前台实名制考验。农健插画&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“全网自媒体要实施前台实名制了。”2023年10月中旬，拥有350多万粉丝的财经博主“洪榕”在微博发布了这则消息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎同时，微博CEO王高飞开始在其微博账号“来去之间”个人信息栏中展示本人真实姓名，标识“自媒体前台实名”，并多次与微博网友就相关话题留言互动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚间，微博发布公告称，将于近期引导社会时事、军事、财经、医疗、法律等专业领域100万以上粉丝的自媒体账号填写实名信息，后续拓展到50万粉丝以上的。B站、微信、抖音、快手等平台亦发布类似消息，对“头部自媒体”施行前台实名制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去的十多年，网络实名制经历了从无到有、从局部到全面的发展历程。从2011年地方文件要求微博用户“后台实名、前台自愿”，2017年微博全面落地这一要求，再到此次，实名制逐步从幕后走向了前台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这迅速引发了社会激辩。在过往，几乎每一次有关实名制的要求一出，都会伴随类似争论。支持者认为，网络实名制可以增强网络活动的规范性和责任意识，有助于肃清谣言、淫秽信息，减少网络暴力或者利用虚假信息发生的违法犯罪，提高网民生活的安全感等；反对者认为，实名制不仅影响了信息安全和公开表达的松弛感，还危及个人信息安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而前台实名制，使得个人信息由少部分平台集中采集变为暴露在广泛的公众视野里，其影响更为复杂多样，亦有学者公开建议：“兹事体大，不宜贸然推出”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不只微博一家&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末观察到，至10月31日晚间，不少100万粉丝以上的微博大V，仍属前台“匿名”状态。在B站、抖音等平台，大部分相关领域的头部自媒体，也未见个人主页展示实名信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据微博公告，平台会引导用户填写需要在前台展示的信息。按照王高飞在其个人页面的内测信息，未来或要求展示的个人信息包括真实姓名、性别、星座、职业、IP属地等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末此前获取的微博发送给大V的私信显示，首批前台实名的自媒体账号需要在10月底之前进行前台实名，50万-100万粉丝的账号在12月底前完成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述私信中提到，此次实名制要求全网所有平台统一执行，“关于前台实名制，微博、抖音、腾讯等平台已经沟通争取过很多次，如果造成困扰，您可以将意见建议通过自己渠道反馈，也可以提交给我们代为转交”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从各大平台已发布的公告信息不难发现，头部自媒体前台实名制已成必然，平台间主要差别在于首批实名自媒体账号的粉丝数量。除了抖音从50万以上粉丝的账号开始推行，其余均是从100万以上粉丝的账号开始，后续逐步扩大到50万粉丝以上的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这次没有标准的、明确的执行文件，各个平台只能基于各自的平台属性和既往的审核重点，摸索推行。”某平台内部人士透露。据其介绍，前台实名与内容审核略有不同，后者有一定的“自由裁量空间”，前者达到一定量级必须执行，其所在平台将对粉丝量较大、对某一领域影响力较大的账号优先要求前台实名。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于此次背景，前述私信中表示，是进一步落实国家网信办的“自媒体13条管理规定”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，国家网信办发布通知，为加强“自媒体”管理，压实网站平台信息内容管理主体责任，健全常态化管理制度机制，要求网站平台应当“对从事金融、教育、医疗卫生、司法等领域信息内容生产的&#39;自媒体&#39;进行严格核验，并在账号主页展示其服务资质、职业资格、专业背景等认证材料名称，加注所属领域标签”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“受多重因素影响，我觉得，应对目前日益严重的网暴问题、构建更良好网络内容生态，是重中之重。”中国传媒大学教授王四新说，近年来网暴问题频繁发生，从2022年开始，相关部门密集出台了多项针对性措施，平台方也是进一步落实各自责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新是国家网信办咨询专家，参与过包括网络安全法、《网络信息内容生态治理规定》等的立法工作。他解释，由于大V往往拥有更广泛的社会影响力，且不乏背景复杂、目的多样的，部分大V背后有自己的团队，其网络活动包括发言、代言等，都有商业利益诉求，实践中难以排除为了经济利益而误导公众的可能性，给信息生态良性发展带来不少负面影响。“前台实名制有利于这些大V增强社会责任感和风险意识、规范他们在网络空间的行为。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于部分微博用户提出的不愿实名问题，王高飞在微博回应，用户可以通过清粉，把粉丝删到100万以下，或者把发帖内容更换到其它领域。前述私信也提到，可以协助用户“检测垃圾粉丝并帮助清理”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，微博公告还称，对于应实名而不愿实名的用户，将部分限制该账号的流量和收入，包括推荐流展示限制、热搜展示限制、广告分成限制、打赏收入限制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前相关细则还不清晰，平台方应该要平衡好前台实名和个人信息安全的问题，比如提前告知的义务，是否有必要在前台展示大V的工作单位和职务信息，其所在单位是否可以拒绝，个人如果不愿意是否有退出机制，需要设置好程序。”中国政法大学传播法研究中心副主任朱巍说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“前台展示什么样的个人信息，区别还是很大的。”朱巍举例，比如一个医生大V，披露其所属职业类型是某科医生，可能会比披露所在单位和职务信息更能减少网暴的发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博前述公告中，涉及前台信息保护的内容为：对于未登录、未通过真实身份信息验证、行为异常以及近期被处置的用户，禁止查看其他用户前台实名信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二十余年演进与变化&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2002年，清华大学新闻学院（现为新闻与传播学院）教授李希光在接受电视台访谈中提到，建议人大应该禁止任何人网上匿名，引发公众热烈讨论。这被媒体认为是网络实名制第一次进入中国公众视野。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在随后十年间，网络实名制开始部分试水。2004年，教育部发布《关于进一步加强高等学校校园网络管理工作的意见》，“网络实名制”被正式写进了官方文件，高校网络论坛开始执行用户实名注册；2005年，腾讯根据深圳公安《关于开展网络公共信息服务场所清理整治工作的通知》，对QQ群的创建者及管理员开展实名登记；2006年，国家新闻出版总署提出《网络游戏实名制方案》，要求网游玩家进行实名注册，以区分成年人与未成年人……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到2011年，实名制要求再次引发较高关注。当年，北京颁布《北京市微博客发展管理若干规定》，提出微博用户在注册时必须使用真实身份信息，实行“后台实名，前台自愿”。随后，微博公开表示，对新用户推行实名注册，并且逐步完善老用户的实名审核。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于为何要求微博用户实名，2012年，时任国家网信办主任王晨公开回应，表示微博具有传播快、影响大、覆盖广的特点，有很强的社会动员力。微博改变了既往舆论传播格局，在反映社情民意，丰富信息服务，进行舆论监督的同时，也使一些负面舆论、淫秽色情、编造谎言等有害信息迅速传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“微博从2009年开始，利用在平台产生的影响力，在许多涉及公共利益的问题上，对公共舆论的形成和走向产生了巨大影响。2011年前后中国发生的许多公共事件，都成为互联网的热炒素材。”王四新进一步阐释，后来形成的一系列管理措施当中，有许多要求是在吸取了这些教训的基础上形成的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新举例，在2011年7月，温州动车事故发生时，“网络上充斥着各种关于事故的谣言，后来逐渐离谱，演变到对中国高铁、国家经济发展模式的攻击”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现有的管理很不适应，对网络信息安全和社会和谐稳定提出了新挑战。”王晨在上述发言中提到。“网络实名的监管要求，也是在这一大背景下提出并逐步开始实施的。”王四新说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，《全国人民代表大会常务委员会关于加强网络信息保护的决定》公布并实施，以法律性文件的形式，明确要求网络服务平台需要对用户进行实名制登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一个有关网络实名制的关注高潮，发生在2016年前后。2016年网络安全法出台，并于2017年施行。该法第二十四条规定：网络运营者在与用户签订协议或者确认提供服务时，应当要求用户提供真实身份信息，不提供真实身份信息的，不得为其提供服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年8月，国家网信办发布《互联网跟帖评论服务管理规定》，要求所有网络平台按照“后台实名、前台自愿”原则，对注册用户进行真实身份信息认证，否则不得向其提供跟帖评论服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同年，微博发布“关于微博推进完成账号实名制的公告”，要求所有用户必须在2017年9月15日之前完成实名验证，否则将无法再发送评论及新帖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;立法和相关规范性要求的颁布，也受一些事件的催动。王四新介绍，2013年发生的斯诺登“棱镜门”事件（美国实施的电子监听计划），引发了高层对国家网络信息安全的高度关注，有关网络安全的立法等相关工作也加快推进。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，电话实名制也给网络注册实名制提供了便利。2013年，工信部要求用户办理固定电话、移动电话、宽带等入网过户业务时，必须提供真实身份信息。并在2015年下旬，停止运营商对非实名号码的服务。而网络服务平台，大多以手机号验证方式完成注册审核。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;国外实名制得失&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前，国际上对于网络环境监管较为普遍。比如，英国出台了通信数据法案，规定网络用户需要登记姓名、住址等个人信息；美国的手机网上通信服务需要绑定可识别个人信息的社会安全号；德国也出台了监管互联网的法律，对提供网上经营活动的商家、网络邮件、电话和手机用户实行实名登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有地方要求公众向市场化服务平台提供个人身份信息。南方周末从美国、加拿大、英国、德国、澳大利亚等国的网民，以及数名曾有多国旅居经历的华人处获悉，目前许多国家的企业服务平台不需要直接进行实名注册，但也有国家要求绑定与个人信息关联的邮箱或手机号。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要求前台实名的并不多。在王四新看来，这次网络服务平台的前台实名制要求，“本质上还是前序网络实名制管理的细化规范，很多工作的开展都不是一步到位的，需要循序渐进，逐步推进。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，在中国的网络实名制既往进程上，几乎每进一步都引发高度关注，尤其是关于社交平台、资讯服务等市场化平台的实名制，往往会引起各方激辩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末检索既往文献和报道发现，实名制的支持者普遍认为，网络的匿名性催生了网络语言暴力、造谣诽谤、网络欺诈甚至违法犯罪等系列问题，近年来频发的网暴事件，也给一些社会事件的当事人，带来严重的身心伤害，而实名制是解决上述问题的良药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在很多自媒体背后是一个团队在操作，往往裹挟一些商业诉求，海量粉丝的自媒体账号有必要公开自己的真实身份，为其网络发言负责。”朱巍说。他补充，有关网暴案件的诉讼，举证责任都在原告，但需要经过法院向平台调取才能取得涉嫌侵权主体的个人信息，而前台实名制也可以简化这个过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而反对者大多认为，实名制抑制了公开讨论、表达真实想法、提出有价值观点的积极性，不利于宣泄情绪、疏导矛盾。近年来，亦有不少腐败案件是通过网络匿名举报的形式侦破的，而实名制会给举报者带来压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无论是社会心理学还是传播学都证实了，在个人信息趋于透明的环境下，人的言行也倾向于从众，而从众的人往往鲜少具备创新意识。从社会发展的角度来说，前台实名不利于鼓励人们活跃思维、勇于创新。”清华大学法学院教授劳东燕说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳东燕还认为，前台实名制未必能解决网暴问题，反而有可能催生某种“精准网暴”。“我是2022年开始使用微博的，一直是实名，多次因参与公共话题的讨论而遭遇谩骂侮辱，有人不仅线上@我的单位举报我，甚至还发展到线下。前台实名制为这些人提供了方便。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有关实名制的担忧中，一个议题贯穿始终：网络实名制会影响个人信息安全。这种担心并非无中生有。2017年，公安部曾有专家对媒体表示，网络实名制的泛化确实影响到了个人信息安全。个人身份证号、人脸识别等采集信息越多，泄露也越多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内已有相关事件。2016年，山东学生徐玉玉因被诈骗电话骗走上大学的费用，郁结于心，最终导致心脏骤停离世。据媒体报道，该案中学生信息泄露，就是不法分子攻击了当地教育局的考生信息系统所致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际上也不乏先例。2005年，韩国一女孩因拒绝清理宠物粪便而遭遇网暴，导致女孩被迫退学并患上精神病。为治理网暴，从当年开始，韩国政府开始逐步要求公众落实网络实名，其间分梯度、分领域渐次推进，并辅以完善立法等措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2010年，共有167家韩国网站执行网络实名制，主要是大型门户网站、新闻网站和购物平台。然而，2010—2012年间，多家平台发生大规模用户信息泄露事件，其中最大规模的波及3500万人，而韩国2010年的总人口仅4800余万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年8月，韩国网络实名制被叫停。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在电信诈骗分子非常猖獗，已经不是你拉黑个别手机号能解决的，因为对方往往用的是虚拟号，随时随地都可能接到诈骗电话。”劳东燕说，她本人曾多次在半夜被电诈电话吵醒，已经不堪其扰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关部门也在强化对个人信息安全的保护。2012年全国人大关于网络信息安全的决定、2016年出台的网络安全法，均对平台采集、使用、保护公民个人信息作出了禁止性规范。2021年，个人信息保护法也正式实施，对个人信息保护作出全方位规范性要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，公安部门打击境内、跨境电信诈骗的力度也在不断加强，除了常规侦破相关案件，还多次发起专项行动，集中打击电信诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新表示，未来互联网信息传播的监管会更加规范，“依法管网、依法用网和依法提供服务，将成为网络文明建设过程中的常态”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>