<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“普洱景迈山古茶林文化景观”，申遗成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256894]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;17th&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s &quot;Pu&#39;er Jingmai Mountain Ancient Tea Forest Cultural Landscape&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The application project&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 45th World Heritage Committee Meeting of UNESCO&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adopted for review&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Inscribed on the &quot;World Heritage List&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the 57th World Heritage in China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 6th World Heritage in Yunnan Province&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pu&#39;er Jingmaishan Ancient &quot;Tea Forest Cultural Landscape&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why it became the world&#39;s first tea culture world heritage&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9 keywords revealed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The secrets of this thousand-acre ancient tea forest Veil&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 1: Ancient tea forest cultural landscape&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ancient tea trees and Primitive forests&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intertwined to create a piece of vitality&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After thousands of years of protection and development&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Formation of forest and tea, harmony between man and earth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Ancient tea forest cultural landscape&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/40d7fba5f26400a681eb3abb272a3f78.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/40d7fba5f26400a681eb3abb272a3f78.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;5 complete ancient tea forests&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9 traditional villages in the ancient tea forests&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And 3 separate protective forests between the ancient tea forests&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;It is the heritage element of this application&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 2: Ten thousand acres of ancient tea forest&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the eye can see are the ancient tea trees all over the mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 28,000 acres of ancient tea forests here&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 3.2 million ancient tea trees&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;It is the largest and best-preserved discovered area in the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The oldest one&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Artificially cultivated ancient tea forest&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/0eb0d4c05da0d15c812aec16d2ee1f91.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/17/0eb0d4c05da0d15c812aec16d2ee1f91.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people on Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guardian of this place for generations An ancient tea forest&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 3: Tea planting under the forest&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The long-standing ethnic groups in Jingmai Mountain are in the original forest system &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Exploring the &quot;tea planting under forest&quot; technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/ 074a611c0cfcd76e66355a6a3f79207f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/074a611c0cfcd76e66355a6a3f79207f.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;251036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is, through understory reclamation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Create ideal lighting conditions for the growth of tea trees&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, utilize the intact ecosystem of the forest&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Prevent pests and diseases from invading&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grow high-quality organic tea without pesticides and chemical fertilizers&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grow high-quality organic tea&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;4&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt; h4>;Keyword 4: Traditional ancient village&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The ancestors of the ethnic groups who have lived in Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;discovered wild tea trees during their migration&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So they settled in Jingmai Mountain &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/84edd83667aa1378e9adb4a468abe978.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/84edd83667aa1378e9adb4a468abe978.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Declaration of heritage area There are a total of 15 villages in the buffer zone&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ethnic groups here are mainly Dai and Blang ethnic groups&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rich and colorful ethnic culture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this ancient tea Lin Xiang echoed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The integration has created a unique development path&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;5&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 5: Protection, inheritance and development&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;The traditional method of growing tea under the forest has effectively protected biodiversity&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The residents here insist on protecting it during development&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulations have been issued to stipulate that residents Over-picking of tea leaves is not allowed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/e0cdd0e24349a88f4f0b6d3af88a7ab2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/e0cdd0e24349a88f4f0b6d3af88a7ab2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;From the original four seasons of picking tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;to only picking tea in spring and autumn a year&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Encourage the development of tea farmers&#39; professional cooperatives&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;......&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In inheritance and development&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Protecting this ancient tea mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;6&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 6: Tea culture&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;Jingmai Mountain has never failed to live up to its reputation as the &quot;World Museum of Tea Culture, History and Nature&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jingmai Mountain&#39;s long-term residents jointly create and inherit tea culture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/91ac7a86aab8af8a47ffca8d54ff52ac.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/91ac7a86aab8af8a47ffca8d54ff52ac.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With &quot;harmony&quot; as the core Local tea culture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Village rules and regulations to protect the ecology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As well as customs and habits of mutual respect and love&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The realization of the relationship between people and tea, people and nature &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Highly connected&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;7&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 7: hospitable tea&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Millennium Brown Ancient Village&quot; Weng Ji&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a saying - no matter whose house you walk into&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;you can taste local tea for free&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/54a5faf3786fcc96e98e1594810f5b17.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/17/54a5faf3786fcc96e98e1594810f5b17.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Nuogang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Handmade tea production is being passed down&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Batch production of tea has also quietly emerged&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also the epitome of how Jingmai Mountain shows people with tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost every household in Jingmai Mountain has it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Own tea workshop&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Growing tea, picking tea, and making tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;have become the daily routine of the villagers&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;8&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Key Word 8: Get rich &quot;gold leaf&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The people on Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Live by tea, sing with tea, and dance because of tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Live in The Blang and Dai people here&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tea cultivation has been their main industry for generations&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/17/70670ed0b17F1C8BCA81359538a95e3e.jpeg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 900 &quot;heart =&quot; 1950 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/2 3/09/17/70670ED0B17F1C8BCA81359538A95E3E .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251043&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now the tea industry has become&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;golden key&quot; for them to get rich through hard work&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guide the good tea industry Development&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is important to protect the heritage value of Jingmai Mountain&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;9&lt;/h4>; &lt;hr>; &lt;h4>;Keyword 9:&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Far mountains, Close houses, cooking smoke, and the aroma of tea&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Pu&#39;er Jingmai Mountain Ancient Tea Forest Cultural Landscape&quot; was successfully applied for World Heritage&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It fills the gap in the current world heritage&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no such thing as Blank space of tea-themed cultural heritage&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/d7b7d790397bb640ca12e0daa471e356.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/17/d7b7d790397bb640ca12e0daa471e356.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251044&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Between the mountains&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Traditional ethnic minority villages shaded by tea forests&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Built on the mountains and living near the tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Far away mountains , close houses, cooking smoke, and the fragrance of tea&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Telling the story of this thousand-year-old ancient tea forest...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高空坠物让我走了一遭鬼门关：应重视建筑老化隐患问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256882]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few months ago, I experienced a thrilling scene and walked through the gate of hell. I was walking on the streets of Hefei when I suddenly heard a loud noise behind me. When I looked back, I was shocked out of my mind. A piece of concrete and ceramic tile mixture the size of a washbasin fell from a building more than ten stories high and hit me about two meters behind me. The debris from the impact splashed on my pants. I was so frightened that I turned pale. I really felt that life was so fragile and that I was so close to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I talked about this distress in my circle of friends and social media, and I was thankful for my good luck. Unexpectedly, netizens have talked about nearly ten people who have encountered similar situations! It turns out that falling objects from heights are not an occasional phenomenon, but a frequent social problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following months, four more incidents of falling objects from high altitudes occurred in my circle of relatives and friends. Two of them happened in the community where my sister lives (which was delivered in 2007): both times, weathered and peeling pieces fell from the top of the building. Once, the mortar hit the seat of the electric motorcycle, but no serious damage was caused; the other time was more serious. It was serious, the roof of the car was damaged, and the property management paid 3,000 yuan in compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme Court&#39;s 2020 &quot;Trends and Characteristics of Cases of Falling Objects Injuring People from Height&quot; report shows that civil cases of falling objects from heights are increasing year by year, and nearly 30% cause casualties. Xu Jianfeng, director of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Information Center, said: 18.16% of cases involved fatalities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professional legal practitioners introduced more detailed and specific technical details of cases of falling objects from high altitude:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the influence of the earth’s gravity, high-altitude objects have huge potential energy and fall close to the ground. At this time, it is converted into kinetic energy. At this time, the speed is fast and the momentum is large. When hitting the human body, the human body will receive a large impulse and force. A 30-gram egg dropped from the 4th floor can break a person&#39;s head; if dropped from the 18th floor, it can break a person&#39;s skull. Even lighter cigarette butts, fruit cores, cans... falling from high altitudes are likely to cause casualties once they hit the human body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 60% of criminal cases caused by falling objects occur in residential areas. They are closely related to the people, are related to personal safety and social stability, and cannot be ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Qingdun Data&quot;: From 2014 to 2020, more than 1,450 high-altitude parabolic cases were concluded by courts across the country, showing an overall rapid growth trend. Among them, in 2020 alone, 451 cases were concluded. These are only the cases concluded by the courts. Many of the cases are minor and the cases where the parties have gone through mediation or reconciliation are not included in the calculation. According to incomplete statistics, there are actually more than 1,000 cases of high-altitude parabolic objects occurring in my country per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are four main reasons for high-altitude throwing cases: those who throw objects for convenience and casually account for the most, accounting for 55.1%; crimes of passion caused by quarrels and disputes account for 29.7%; malicious venting accounts for 13.2%; Laziness accounts for 2% of the cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above four types are classified as criminal cases of man-made thrown objects. In addition, falling objects from heights are also caused by the aging of buildings: the cement and ceramic tiles on the exterior walls of buildings have been damaged by wind, sun, and damage for many years. Rain...peeled off and fell off after weathering. For example, the author was in danger and the vehicle in my sister&#39;s neighborhood was damaged by falling objects, which were all caused by the aging of the building exterior walls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Friends in the construction industry said that most of my country&#39;s high-rise buildings were built rapidly during the &quot;explosive development of real estate&quot; in the past 25 years or so, and it took a quarter of a century to go through four centuries of Western development. The development history of architecture. Many buildings are built quickly and in a hurry to meet the schedule. Of course, the quality of slow work and meticulous work cannot be achieved, and there are many potential hidden dangers. After more than 20 years of exposure to wind, sun, and rain, many buildings lacked maintenance, and problems gradually began to appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Communicate with friends in the construction and property fields and learn about some ways to reduce the risk of falling objects caused by aging buildings. For example: not only should problems such as illegal construction and illegal renovation be dealt with, but also structures such as &quot;parapets&quot; on the top of old high-rise buildings should be demolished; exterior wall tiles can also be transformed into exterior wall paint, so that even if there are paint chips and wall dust falling off , it is not as lethal as the concrete and ceramic tile mixture falling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, in traditional markets in southern cities such as Guangzhou, there were long corridors extending above the storefronts along the street and connecting them to one another. In the past, it was mainly used to shade the sun and rain, and to facilitate attracting customers and doing business. However, this kind of building structure has inadvertently become a buffer for falling objects from high altitude, reducing the casualty rate in accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of falling objects from heights deserves attention and cannot be solved solely by legislation, judiciary, publicity and education. If you wait until after a casualty accident occurs before trying and making compensation, this kind of hindsight will not only fail to solve the problem, but will actually increase social instability. It’s the old saying: As long as your thinking doesn’t slip, there are always more solutions than difficulties. Combined with the current reconstruction of old cities, there are always ways to deal with the problem of falling objects from heights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[新研究发现熬夜比早起更易导致糖尿病]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256896]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 23:00:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Those who consider themselves &quot;night owls&quot; may need to pay attention. A new study in the United States found that the habit of going to bed late and getting up late may lead to a significantly increased risk of type 2 diabetes compared with going to bed early and getting up early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Brigham and Women&#39;s Hospital in Massachusetts found that people with irregular sleep schedules have a higher risk of diabetes and cardiovascular disease, while people who go to bed later and get up later are more likely to develop diabetes and cardiovascular disease. Irregular sleep patterns. Relevant results have been published in the American monthly Annals of Internal Medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers analyzed data collected from 63,676 female nurses between 2009 and 2017, including self-reported sleep type, diet quality, weight, health status, body mass index, sleep duration, smoking behavior, Alcohol use, physical activity, and family history of diabetes, and diabetes status was determined based on participant self-report and medical records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 11% of the participants said they were &quot;sleeping late and getting up late&quot;, about 35% said they had the habit of going to bed early and getting up early, and the remaining participants were labeled as &quot;intermediate&quot;. The results found that before considering other lifestyle factors, compared with the &quot;early to bed and early to rise&quot; type, the &quot;late to bed and late to rise&quot; type may lead to a 72% increase in the risk of developing diabetes; after adding other lifestyle factors, the risk of developing diabetes still increased19 %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research has found that people who have the habit of going to bed late and getting up late are more likely to drink heavily, have a low-quality diet, sleep less, smoke, and have an unhealthy weight and body mass index. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the researchers plan to study the impact of genetic factors on sleep timing patterns as well as cardiovascular disease and diabetes in a larger, more diverse population, and to assist doctors in better designing relevant strategies for their patients. prevention strategies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[回望“民国视觉文化巨人”丁悚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256829]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/9xEJu2ab4W2hSDFIg88TZXFHPJ9QDuyi5eiGNS0H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;604&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/9xEJu2ab4W2hSDFIg88TZXFHPJ9QDuyi5eiGNS 0H. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250575&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Ju, 1920s, Ding Ju’s family collection&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a situation that we use the current (very) fashionable and very popular expressions of &quot;slash&quot;, &quot;cross-border&quot; and &quot;cross-media&quot; to describe it. A person who has absolutely no sense of incompatibility between his work and his career.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 6 years ago, Gu Zheng, a professor at the School of Journalism at Fudan University, began to plan an exhibition to present a person in his heart who has been forgotten by time. The life and works of the &quot;giant of visual culture in the Republic of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/GvmP9yI2YNiSP52i1AApzBfISfpI4zBEhuavppJe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;377&quot; height= &quot;1496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/GvmP9yI2YNiSP52i1AApzBfISfpI4zBEhuavppJe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250564&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanyang Brothers Tobacco Company Monthly Plates, Ding Xue depicts the person, Zhang Guangyu added the scene, circa 1925, 31.8cm×126.5cm, Zhang Weizang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This person’s name is Ding Wei, whose courtesy name was Muqin, was born on September 16, 1891 in Fengjing Town, Jiashan County, Zhejiang Province during the Republic of China (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Jinshan District, Shanghai &lt;/span>;), passed away in Shanghai in 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/IMMjDIVKUAmBvjvAPI2N74B4ZAyLf0ue5QBGCGEJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/IMMjDIVKUAmBvjvAPI2N74B4ZAyLf0ue5QBGCGEJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Higher and Higher&quot; Ding Ju&#39;s comic, 1933, 7.5cm×5.5cm, published on the second page of &quot;Social Daily&quot; on March 20, 1934, Ding Jujia Zang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Wei is the father of the cartoonist Ding Cong. He is not only a prolific painter, but also an art educator and art activist. Cartoons, calendar paintings, newspaper cover illustrations, graphic advertising design; photography, guest roles in operas, radio broadcasts, writing theater reviews, organizing cultural salons... He participated in all kinds of visual expression and communication styles during the Republic of China, and he was also playing and playing. A versatile artist, his creations and life were the subject of intense pursuit by the media of that era, but for a long time afterwards, little was known about Ding Wei and his contributions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oDq2noYQvLsvP41ui0HynRbe0QFPVgcKMcN7s2qo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;634&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oDq2noYQvLsvP41ui0HynRbe0QFPVgcKMcN7s2qo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Saturday&quot; No. 51, cover, Ding Wei, 1915, courtesy of Shanghai Library&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My grandfather was also in the cultural circle during the Republic of China. He was quite a famous celebrity, but no one really knew him for the next sixty or seventy years. In terms of personal factors, he suffered from ear disease in the 1940s, which later developed into deafness in both ears, and he also suffered from ear disease in the 1950s. Glaucoma caused blindness in his right eye. Not only was he unable to draw, but he also had great difficulties in socializing, so he faded out of social activities. In the 1960s, he was labeled as a &quot;reactionary academic authority&quot;, not to mention that in the 1970s, he set things right and restored his reputation, but the process was long. , and it did not immediately apply to him. In the 1980s, the &quot;Creation Society&quot; and the &quot;Literary Research Association&quot; were prominent in modern literature. My grandfather&#39;s circle of friends basically belonged to the &quot;Mandarin Butterfly School&quot; literati, and they would naturally be forgotten. Until a few days ago It was proposed in 2001 to explore Shanghai-style culture. Shanghai&#39;s cultural history before 1949 began to be viewed as a complete cultural ecology. In addition to the pioneering role of the &#39;New Culture Movement&#39;, academic research focused more on the entertainment and media related to ordinary people in the city. My grandfather was also &#39;unearthed&#39; under such a background as all kinds of popular culture.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/13/kHGB49jL85OQuRHlYY08JSOhE8lqpCRCzq8Cd8mM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;674&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/ kHGB49jL85OQuRHlYY08JSOhE8lqpCRCzq8Cd8mM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250573&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Game Magazine&quot; Issue 8, cover, Ding Wei, 1914, Courtesy of Shanghai Library&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1944 to 1945, Ding Ju wrote a column &quot;Memoirs of Forty Years of the Art Circle&quot; for &quot;Oriental Daily&quot;, recording anecdotes about the maritime art scene in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China, including vivid Vivid literary and artistic gossip, exciting and interesting stories experienced and heard personally, avant-garde and open urban culture, etc. In the past two years, Ding Xia, Ding Xue&#39;s grandson, has compiled these words that his grandfather scattered in newspapers and periodicals into &quot;Memoirs of Forty Years in the Art Circle (1902-1945)&quot;. After reading this book, you will find that the sexually promiscuous painter Ding Wei, with humorous and exquisite words, inadvertently drew a map of the heroes of the Shanghai-style art circles during the Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XlugXWoR0j5XqRD5AsFd56A2o7ykkzEAplz1zkyQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XlugXWoR0j5XqRD5AsFd56A2o7ykkzEAplz1zkyQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daqianmen cigarette advertisement, published on the back cover of &quot;British American Tobacco Company Monthly&quot;, Volume 5, Issue 6, 1925, Dingwei, 1925&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dingwei He was an important promoter of the emergence and development of Shanghai&#39;s visual culture during the Republic of China, a pioneer and practitioner of Shanghai&#39;s business culture in the international metropolis, and a leader of rich and colorful Shanghai urban culture.&quot; In the spring of 2023, &quot;Mou&quot; planned by Gu Zheng &quot;Piano Career—Documentary Art Exhibition on the 130th Anniversary of Ding Wei&#39;s Birth&quot; was unveiled at the Liu Haisu Art Museum in Shanghai. The exhibition salvaged a creative Ding Wei from the depths of history through 767 exhibits. In August, Gu Zheng edited and published &quot;Mu Qin&#39;s Career: Ding Xu and Modern Art and Culture of the 20th Century&quot;, &quot;I hope to use Ding Xu&#39;s &#39;pen&#39; and &#39;lens&#39; to show today&#39;s audience what happened in the first half of the 20th century.&quot; The rich and diverse cultural ecology and interests unfolding in Shanghai provide a glimpse into the origin and grand occasion of the &#39;Shanghai Style&#39; new culture.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/13/Jj9mvvvskqC38Np2wivjAPdlsqmfA2TMzbhcTrSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 13/Jj9mvvvskqC38Np2wivjAPdlsqmfA2TMzbhcTrSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250563&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Arhat&quot;, Ding Wei Photography, 1928, published in &quot; &quot;Shanghai Pictorial&quot; Issue 321, February 9, 1928, Ding Ju&#39;s family collection&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13 /UAH1NRmni4BRpJlrdB1RyAf1w8ybipd8uhmX3ykp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/UAH1NRmni4BRpJlrdB1RyAf1w8ybipd8uhmX3ykp .jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;250567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Art Calligraphy Scrapbook&quot;, inside page, Ding Wei, 1920s and 1930s, 32.2cm ×28cm, Ding Ju&#39;s family collection&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Old Painter of the Republic of China&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the old photo, Ding Ju sits upright, wearing a Chinese long coat and round-framed glasses, with a &quot;fresh head&quot; &quot;, the wind spirit is loose and clear, and has a refined and scholarly spirit. Looking at the lower left corner again, he painted the character &quot;D&quot; into a small open umbrella, and connected the character &quot;瀬&quot; underneath which looks like an umbrella holder with &quot;vertical by the heart&quot;. The playful and vivid signature reveals that this &quot;old painter of the Republic of China&quot; &quot;The naughty nature at heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/J20RmYHE0LRFYeERQ9Ndl5hXM8fgJ9huX5xRvGLZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/J20RmYHE0LRFYeERQ9Ndl5hXM8fgJ9huX5xRvGLZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250568&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photograph of Zhang Yuguang, Ding Ju and Liu Haisu, collected by Ding Ju’s family in the early 20th century&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Ding Ju’s colorful labels, he is the cartoonist The most well-known and praised identity. From the 1910s to the 1940s, Ding Wei published more than a thousand cartoons in newspapers and periodicals. His large-scale creations reflected his active exploration of comic forms and visual presentation in newspapers and periodicals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Shanghai’s paper media was developed at that time, and he was responsible for a large number of cover paintings, illustrations and graphic advertisement designs that appeared in newspapers and magazines. The pictures he personally drew were fresh in appearance and unique in conception, which attracted everyone’s attention. The pages of newspapers and periodicals are bright, and readers are eager to see them.&quot; Gu Zheng emphasized, &quot;In that era when it was possible to discuss the treacherous and ever-changing current affairs and public sentiments, cartoons were an important means for Ding Wei to express his opinions and participate in promoting social progress. Whether it is through continuous Whether it is the way of painting that reveals the critical point of current affairs or the single-frame cartoons that are sharp, they are all his specialties. Ding Wei, because of his cartoons and graphic images, contributed greatly to the development of paper media in the Republic of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1909 to 1910 During the year, &quot;Picture Daily&quot;, China&#39;s earliest daily pictorial, published a total of 7 &quot;Mu Qin&#39;s manuscripts&quot;, including comic works such as &quot;I am a Diplomat&quot; and &quot;Don&#39;t You See This Powerful World&quot; by Ding Ju. At the age of 19, when he first tried his hand at crying with a comic pen, Ding Wei had not received professional training, but he was able to outline precise images with smooth simple pens. For example, in the comic &quot;Members of the Autonomous Bureau&#39;s Moneyism&quot;, Ding used an exaggerated technique to draw a giant magnifying glass filled with coins in front of a member&#39;s belly, using the &quot;clear vision of an The hypocritical appearance of devoting oneself to local autonomy only to seek power and personal gain satirizes &quot;the election of autonomous bureau members inside and outside the city is full of strange phenomena.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Ju has been fond of painting here and there since he was a child, and his neighbors praise him as a &quot;child prodigy&quot; who can &quot;paint gods like gods and ghosts like ghosts.&quot; His father died young, and as the eldest son, Ding Wei shouldered the heavy responsibility of supporting the family. When he was 13 years old, he left Fengjing Town and went to Shanghai alone to join his relatives. When he entered the old Beimen Changtai Pawn Shop as an apprentice, he still fell in love with art. Not long after he submitted and published cartoons for &quot;Picture Daily&quot;, Ding Ju entered the Chinese and Western painting correspondence school founded by Zhou Xiang (1871-1933). For nearly a year, he concentrated on sketching, watercolor and oil painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/38lZ7GykqNQWBgpoKxNeZVwgQ0NArpWDyetffPW4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/38lZ7GykqNQWBgpoKxNeZVwgQ0NArpWDyetffPW4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250562&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Landscape - Leifeng Pagoda&quot;, Ding Ju&#39;s photography, 1920s, Ding Ju&#39;s family collection&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mr. Zhou is good at traditional Chinese painting, gold and stone and calligraphy, and he is also very good at poetry. Well, Western painting became a monk halfway, and it seems not as pure and good as Chinese painting. He often makes caricatures for newspapers. His style is like Feng Zikai, and his brushwork and creativeness are even better than Feng.&quot; Ding Ju commented that Zhou Xiang was &quot;extremely perverse in nature. , unwilling to be a trendy work,&quot; and his own signature also comes from the inheritance of this mentor, &quot;His signature is &quot;Zhou Xiang&quot;, written horizontally in parallel, which is the first of its kind for Western-style signatures. My signature on the painting , I was influenced by him, or it can be said that I completely imitated him. His signatures are very vivid and beautiful, while my signatures are clumsy and ugly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Xiang founded the Shanghai Oil Painting Academy, the China Academy of Art and many other Xu Beihong called him &quot;the first person to establish an art school in Shanghai&quot;. Judging from the &quot;Picture Notes&quot; Ding Ju accumulated in the Chinese and Western Painting Correspondence School, Zhou Xiang once taught Ding Ju comic painting (cartoons). &quot;The fun of comic paintings lies in sustenance, so its meaning should be shallow and its meaning should be deep.&quot; Zhou Xiang pointed out that to draw good comic paintings, you need to use exaggerated techniques to deal with the characters, so that &quot;weird shapes make people laugh.&quot; Ding Ju&#39;s later comics practice always followed Zhou Xiang&#39;s teachings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 1911, Ding Ju, Zhang Yuguang, Qian Binghe, Ma Xingchi, Shen Bochen and others co-founded &quot;Funny Pictorial&quot;. Although it only published one issue, it was one of the earliest comic publications in China. In August of this year, the supplement &quot;Free Talk&quot; of &quot;Shenbao&quot; was launched. According to Ding Ju&#39;s recollection: &quot;My debut illustration was &quot;Free Talk&quot; which was first published in Shenbao when it was edited by Mr. Wang Dugen. At that time, there were not many cartoonists, only deceased friends. Brother Shen Bochen can be called the authority.&quot; He has written many articles in memory of his friend Shen Bochen, &quot;I admit that he is an unprecedented success in our country through his caricatures, and he is the only one I have ever admired throughout my life. Not only he The thought has profound connotations, and the harmonious beauty of the structure and lines makes people intoxicated and admired.&quot; What impressed Ding Wei the most was an illustration of Shen Bochen&#39;s &quot;involving a huge disaster&quot;, &quot;The picture is of a house where pigs are being slaughtered, A German drove a group of pigs into the house where pigs were slaughtered. The pigs were part of the Allied Powers. Therefore, they greatly aroused the anger of the British and Americans... It was intolerable that such an unnatural act happened within the scope of his concession. ? This caused great disturbance and almost caused major international negotiations... After this big shock, &quot;Shenbao&quot; did not publish any caricatures until before the war.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XbkMHaz796dWmdrjqmpqfZUFmSFbwxJKRcDpdfmG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/XbkMHaz796dWmdrjqmpqfZUFmSFbwxJKRcDpdfmG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250570&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Pan Xueyan &quot;, Ding Ju&#39;s photography, 1928, published in &quot;Shanghai Comics&quot; Issue 29, 1928, Ding Ju&#39;s family collection&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Ju was a long-term contributor to &quot;Declaration·Free Talk&quot; from the 1910s to the early 1920s , drew a large number of cartoons, illustrations and masthead illustrations, participated in &quot;free talks&quot; many times, and published several game articles, short stories and drama talks; during the same period, he had close contacts with literati such as Wang Dugen and Zhou Shojuan. As the &quot;visual director&quot; of literary and artistic publications such as &quot;Game Magazine&quot; and &quot;Saturday&quot;, Ding Wei has contributed a series of cover paintings and illustrations with great aesthetic interest. In the early years of the Republic of China, he and his colleagues in the art and literary circles jointly created an urban reading culture of leisure, entertainment, and fashion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1914, Chen Xiaodie wrote a poem for the &quot;Two Parts of Spring&quot; painted by Ding Kui, and once expressed emotion: &quot;When reading Mu Qin&#39;s paintings, there are often poems, but I regret that my pen cannot express the meaning.&quot; At that time, he was painting covers for magazines, and Ding Wei&#39;s works were the most common. In 1916, when Zhang Guangyu, who was 9 years younger, met Ding Xu, &quot;Old Ding was already quite successful and famous in Shanghai.&quot; This was Zhang Guangyu&#39;s feeling, and it was also Ding Xu&#39;s true status in society at that time. Ten years later, Ding Ju, Zhang Guangyu, Zhang Zhengyu, Ye Qianyu, Lu Shaofei and others established China&#39;s first comic society &quot;Cartoon Club&quot;. As the first generation of cartoonists in China, these pioneers opened up a new situation for satirical and comic cartoons. The publication &quot;Shanghai Comics&quot; they founded nourished and promoted the younger generations, ushering in the golden age of cartoon art. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 1923, Ding Wei was spotted by a &quot;headhunter&quot; because of his superb painting skills, and joined the British American Tobacco Company to engage in advertising painting creation. As a senior figure in China&#39;s advertising industry, Ding Wei frankly admitted that &quot;artists have no freedom&quot; when they submit to business. &quot;The most painful thing is that not only are manufacturers&#39; advertising hosts very subjective, but most of them lack artistic accomplishment, and it is impossible to understand the author&#39;s ideas. He is often picky and picky and proposes unreasonable revision requirements. A work that was not bad at first has been torn apart beyond recognition, making people laugh and cry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The calendar card that is still talked about today was once the commercial art of the Republic of China. Among them, Ding Ju is also one of the earliest painters of calendar painting. Wang Zengqi once said: Ding Ku&#39;s paintings, &quot;The brushstrokes are somewhere between traditional Chinese painting and comics. There seems to be no such paintings now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/13/uJo6jBBwRRNE2T9rP3NaFGBZrrz9sVN1Nq8EbyX0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;403&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/13/uJo6jBBwRRNE2T9rP3NaFGBZrrz9sVN1Nq8EbyX0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250577&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Inner page of &quot;One Hundred Beautiful Pictures of the Style of the Republic of China&quot;, Ding Wei, 1918, published by China Federation of Literary and Art Circles Press&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Dean of the Academy of Fine Arts&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was riding with Ding Jun in the car. Ding Jun looked around and saw young girls staring at each other. He stared blankly for a moment. I ridiculed him for being rude. Ding Jun said with a smile, &quot;How can I be so lustful? I&#39;m looking for painting materials.&quot; According to Wang Dugen&#39;s slightly ironic account, Ding Wei once &quot;stared&quot; on the bus without hesitation. Women, however, only want to accumulate &quot;painting materials&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years of the Republic of China, &quot;Hundred Beauty Pictures&quot;, which combined paintings of ladies and fashion, became popular. The young Ding&#39;s fame is closely related to the many volumes of beautiful pictures he drew. In August 1916, the Chinese Studies Bookstore launched &quot;Ding Wei&#39;s Hundred Beautiful Pictures&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Volume 1&lt;/span>;). Due to the good response, it was published in February 1917 The second volume was published in the same month, and Ding Kui became famous in one fell swoop; in March of the same year, the Chinese Library released four volumes of &quot;Ode to One Hundred Beautiful Pictures in Ancient and Modern Times&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; span>;), the ancient costume volume was written by Qiu Shounian, with a total of 100 pictures in the upper and lower volumes, and the fashion volume was drawn by Ding Wei, with a total of 50 pictures in the upper and lower volumes; in April 1918, the Shanghai Communications Library published &quot;Ding Wei&#39;s Hundred Beauty Pictures&quot; set&quot;. It can be said that Ding Wei&#39;s beautiful pictures and the &quot;cover girl&quot; he drew for &quot;Saturday&quot; were once all the rage and led the fashion of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In Ding Xue&#39;s hundreds of beautiful pictures, there are ladies, small family biyu, fashionable girls, and graceful village girls. They wear shorts and trousers, braids and buns, fashionable and pleasant, and the furnishings of their rooms are also beautiful. It is full of popular atmosphere.&quot; Xu Tinghua wrote in &quot;Ding Cong&#39;s Dad: Ding Chou&quot;: &quot;In the era of the west wind spreading eastward, new ideas affected the lives of the younger generation, and they also affected Ding Chou. The women in the painting ride horses, skate, go outing, sketch, sketch, play the violin, dance ballroom, drive, and chat on the phone. They are all modern and reflect the advanced aesthetic consciousness of new women and painters at that time. The women are all beautiful and energetic. Exuberant, a new style of life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Zheng pointed out that painting a hundred beautiful pictures at that time not only tested the artist&#39;s sensitivity to reality, but also gave the artist an opportunity to show off his talents. &quot;Through this style, he (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ding Wei&lt;/span>;) used exquisite pen and ink to shape the reality and imagination of women in the early Republic of China, which was in the ascendant to help citizens’ visual consumption.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the autumn of 1913, Ding Ju was invited to join the Shanghai Academy of Graphic Arts (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Later It was renamed Shanghai Fine Arts College&lt;/span>;) and served as the dean. Due to her growing reputation for painting, in addition to teaching at Shanghai Fine Arts College, she was later hired as an art teacher by China Women&#39;s School, Tongji University and Yanmos Girls&#39; School. At that time, female education was gradually accepted by the world. As a teacher in a girls&#39; school, Ding Ju gained the convenience of &quot;getting painting materials&quot;. After mastering photography technology, he also took the opportunity to focus on &quot;Beauty&quot; and take pictures of girls. He once said that photographing &quot;girls from all schools is my duty.&quot; The photos taken by Ding Wei that remain today not only show the scenes of girls attending classes in coeducational art schools at that time, but also capture the style of girls in church girls’ schools at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/ezEQieOi1lxt1oBnrP9SQ64Ad1Zq802HYfm6f5bx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;555&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/ezEQieOi1lxt1oBnrP9SQ64Ad1Zq802HYfm6f5bx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250574&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Wei (second from left) and Zhang Guangyu (third from left), 1922, 22.5cm×40cm, courtesy of Zhang Guangyu Art Documentation Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About Women Ding Wei also wrote about the old stories of teaching in the school. &quot;Song Ziwen&#39;s wife, Ms. Zhang Leyi, is also a student of Yan Mo&#39;s family... She always likes to dress up... She also wears heavy makeup and colorful clothes. Once, Shoujuan, Yunqian and I were watching a movie at the &#39;Odion&#39; on North Sichuan Road. When the show was over, Yun Gu suddenly noticed a very beautiful girl in the crowd in front of us. She encouraged us: &quot;Why don&#39;t you come forward and feast your eyes on it?&quot; At this time, I saw clearly that it was our student Zhang Leyi and said: &quot; Don&#39;t do anything nonsense. Those are our students. What&#39;s the point of being a teacher if they behave like this?&quot; All the niches took a breath. Such jokes were common in the past, because at that time, I was in charge of several schools. , there are also many male and female students, so in the playground, they often don’t even dare to look at them. They don’t claim to be gentlemen, but they are actually seeking their own politics in their position. They have to do this because of their status.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In terms of art education, Ding Wei also made outstanding contributions. He was the first provost of Shanghai Art College, the &quot;source of emerging art&quot;. The principal of the school was Liu Haisu, an &quot;art traitor&quot; who dared to &quot;fight&quot; with the warlord Sun Chuanfang over mannequins. Ding Ju recalled this fellow junior He said, &quot;He was extremely self-confident and refused to follow what others said. He focused on creation in his works throughout his life. However, in the early days, his calligraphy and painting were not unique and his boldness was indeed great. The world ignored the criticism and praise. He goes his own way, whether it is foreign or Chinese painting, a brute force can be observed in his paintings. His career achievements also depend on his unrelenting hard work. If you have a personality like mine, which is pragmatic and step-by-step, I’m afraid a hundred of them can’t compare to one of him.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with many famous artists in Shanghai Academy of Fine Arts, Ding Wei’s influence has not been discovered before. From 1913 to 1918 when he was the dean and then teaching until 1928, he successively served as a teacher in the Western Painting Department, the Technical Normal Department, the Correspondence Department and the Pattern Department. He taught plaster models, copying, sketching, figures, watercolors, pencil drawings, and patterns. Production, advertising graphics and other courses... Despite the numerous achievements in teaching, Ding Wei is modest and self-deprecating: &quot;I have never even stepped into kindergarten, let alone graduated from high school or university, but I am so shameless that I am a teacher in the south, not only in ordinary schools.&quot; , and even as a professor in universities and vocational schools, although the drawing class seems to be an exception, the criticism of &#39;daring&#39; can never be escaped.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;daring&quot; Ding Wei is in the United States During his tenure as a full-time teacher, he indeed made many pioneering achievements: in 1914, he, Zhang Yuguang, Xu Yongqing, Liu Haisu, etc. launched the Zhenqing Calligraphy and Painting Society and published the &quot;Zhenqing Calligraphy and Painting Collection&quot; as a model teaching material; in 1919, he, Jiang Xiaoyu, Liu Yanong, etc. , Zhang Chenbo, Yang Qingqing, Chen Xiaojiang and others established the art group &quot;Tianma Club&quot;. By 1928, the &quot;Tianma Club&quot; held a total of 9 exhibitions, including Chinese paintings, foreign paintings, sculptures, photography and other styles, creating a trend of Chinese art exhibitions. Almost all the famous painters of that era had participated in the &quot;Tianma Club&quot; art exhibition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of sketching instead of copying in Western painting teaching has gone through a long &quot;struggle&quot;, especially on the issue of human body sketching. Ding Ju once argued in his &quot;Essays on Paintings&quot;: &quot;The painter is most qualified. The interesting thing is the sketching of the human body. Regardless of oil painting or sketching, I feel that there are infinite mysteries. Some people say that this is just because you are doing the painting with bad intentions. When you see the naked model, you probably have an incredible feeling. , so I feel that it is more interesting. I said God knows, this kind of interest is caused by the mystery of the various line structures on the human body, and the strange concave and convex contours. No curve in the world can be compared to the human body. Special. Only those who paint know this... To learn about climate changes, you must practice outdoor sketching; to learn the changes in outline and color, you must practice human body sketching.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Learning from the Master. Ding Xue from Zhou Xiang received copying teaching in his early years. While teaching at the School of Fine Arts, he was inspired by Chen Baoyi to develop his knowledge and practice of life drawing. &quot;In the beginning, those who studied Western painting in China were mostly copying, but it was not enough for training. Chen Baoyi advocated sketching as the basic practice... At that time, many teachers did not know how to teach, and I was just one of them. , I was extremely worried beforehand, fearing that I would make future scholars laugh, but he comforted me and taught me not to worry...taught me some important rules in sketching.&quot; According to Ding Ju&#39;s recollection, the studio he built by Chen Baoyi was returned to him. The practice of body photography has provided convenience. &quot;Once Qi Foqing and I found a beauty and wanted to take a nude model. We didn&#39;t have a suitable location for a while, so we took a car to Jiangwan and practiced it at Ji&#39;s Studio. The result was that the light was soft and beautiful for any ordinary photography. It’s beyond the reach of the museum.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Ding Wei was not the central figure in the nude model controversy at the American College, until his later years, he firmly believed that hiring nude models for sketching was a pioneering work of the College of Art. In addition, Ding Wei admitted that he had been obsessed with collecting &quot;nudity photos of men and women from all over the world, both male and female, or singles.&quot; When the collection was at its largest, &quot;there were more than a thousand kinds, and most of them were secret scenes taken by Westerners... There were not many domestically produced ones, and the good ones were There are very few of them, and a single person can still watch them for a while. There are more than ten kinds of Japanese exaggerated pictures, and there are nearly a dozen of them made by famous Western hands. The lines are beautiful and the composition is strange.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/IniMb9aN2l0r5LTI4fxcD6BkFTnDRpn0qlf2UX6s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;666&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/IniMb9aN2l0r5LTI4fxcD6BkFTnDRpn0qlf2UX6s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250576&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; Friends celebrated his birthday at Cangzhou Hotel. More than a hundred celebrities from the art world attended. &quot;Friends and friends joined in very enthusiastically, which shows that he is well-known in the art world and is very popular.&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Lily&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1925, Ding Wei and his family moved to No. 31 Tianxiang Lane, Baylor Road (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today’s Lane 847, Huangpi South Road&lt;/span>;), according to Ding Cong’s recollection: Ye Qianyu lived on the second floor of the alley across the street, Lu Zhixiang lived downstairs, Tewei lived in the back, and Zhang Guangyu lived No. 19. The Ding family is relatively spacious, with the living room on the first floor, Ding Ju and his wife living on the second floor, and the eldest son Ding Cong living on the third floor. For a time, this place became a base camp for talented people: Zhang Guangyu, Ye Qianyu, Lu Shaofei, Wang Renmei, Li Lili, Zhou Xuan, Jin Yan, Nie Er... Every weekend and holiday, talented people from all walks of life come in and out, talk and gossip. , and even &quot;eat and drink&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Miaozi, who later became a frequent visitor, once recorded the first time he walked into Ding&#39;s house in 1932: &quot;It was about a Saturday night, and a lot of movie and drama stars of the time were spread out in the living room and downstairs. In the room of uncle Ding&#39;s family on the second floor, there were three, three, five and five, everyone was enjoying themselves. Some of them called Ding Xue and Mrs. Ding to be their &quot;fake father&quot; and &quot;fake mother&quot;. Because they were unexpected to see so many people at once. Celebrity, I was a little blushing and my heart was beating. I met Uncle Ding’s uncle in a hurry, so I hurriedly hid in Ding Cong’s cabin on the third floor.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gW2gRmYMiXvdHeU5xjwA5lHuuRwCsbrkyVvj8cp7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gW2gRmYMiXvdHeU5xjwA5lHuuRwCsbrkyVvj8cp7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Cong, who was still a middle school student at the time, often sat among these celebrities and listened to their chatter and laughter. Nie Er came to Ding&#39;s house. The young Ding Cong once pestered Nie Er into his upstairs &quot;pavilion&quot; and told him horror stories. &quot;Once Nie Er was drunk, he walked to the patio and climbed along the wall. Go to the attic and sleep.&quot; The big stars of the Mingyue Song and Dance Club would always come to Ding&#39;s house in groups to play when they had free time. According to Ding Ju&#39;s memory, &quot;(Xue) Lingxian was the most jumping among them, and she took the initiative in most of the tricks. At that time, her child Yiyi (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ding Cong&lt;/span>;) was about the same age as them, so Lingxian often ate Yiyi tofu and said, &quot;As a child, Bai Zi (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bai Hong&lt;/span>;) is assigned to Xiao Ding, and I will be the matchmaker. (Wang) Renmei, (Li) Lili, and Hu Jiamen To reconcile the situation, Yiyi was very angry. When he saw them coming, he often avoided the table. Sometimes the pavilion where he lived alone was occupied by them, so he had to not go in.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Renmei, Li Lili, Bai Hong, etc. After becoming famous, they were followed by Zhou Xuan, who was still in the stage of career development. When Zhou Xuan was a trainee at Mingyue Club when she was twelve or thirteen years old, Ding Xuan had known her and cared for her. Zhou Xuan and &quot;Mr. Old Ding&quot; had a very close relationship, and they exchanged letters and exchanged photos frequently. However, in the later narratives about Zhou Xuan, Ding Xia rarely spoke out. Ding Xia said: &quot;I also had such doubts. I once asked about my grandmother and Father. My grandmother completely regarded Zhou Xuan as a child and felt that she should not leave the family; my father said that my grandfather also favored Yan Hua (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhou Xuan in this matter Ex-husband&lt;/span>;). At that time, public opinion was almost on Zhou Xuan&#39;s side, and she was even regarded as the &#39;runaway Nora&#39;. My grandfather had always stayed away from right and wrong. Since public opinion was swayed to one side, he was unwilling to join in the fun and avoided those Tabloid reporter. After Yan Hua remarried, he stopped mentioning the old stories. When he was young, his grandfather was also considered a new-school literati, advocating that women should enter society and liberate themselves. However, in the 1930s and 1940s, he felt that he seemed to be a little behind the times. , he believes that women should pursue career development, but also put family first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the newly published &quot;Memoirs of Forty Years in the Art Circle&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: In Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Collection Edition&lt;/span>;)&quot;, Ding Xia added 12 letters between Ding Wei and Zhou Xuan. &quot;Most of Zhou Xuan&#39;s letters to my grandfather were not dated. The two dated letters were written when she returned to Shanghai for medical treatment in 1957. In the letter, Zhou Xuan also stated that she would visit her grandfather after she recovered. My grandfather was naturally very happy and told several friends about it. However, he did not expect that just over two months after the last letter was written, Zhou Xuan died suddenly, which is really sad.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Among the photos collected by his family, there are many signed photos of celebrities, as well as photos of people from all walks of life taken by him. The gentle-tempered Ding Wei is well-known in the industry as a &quot;nice gentleman&quot;. When interacting with friends, he often takes photos of the men and women around him because he carries a camera with him and has a great sense of service. Ding Ju, who is both a photographer and a fan of Peking Opera, has been close to a number of famous actresses and has left many photos of great documentary value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/40Wyy9aJbc0G6KeGFZkM5dKsIzJW7og5Qmvu9Gso.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;729&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/40Wyy9aJbc0G6KeGFZkM5dKsIzJW7og5Qmvu9Gso.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250569&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; (Xun) Huisheng didn’t recognize me when he was born (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;ding&lt;/span>;). Sha Youtian taught him how to read square characters every day and also copied them. Copybook, considered his talent and intelligence, actually advanced very quickly, and later he even learned to paint.&quot; Ding Wei took a photo of this &quot;illiterate famous lady&quot; leaning on a rockery with his head bent and reading diligently, &quot; One of Huisheng&#39;s greatest strengths is that he is willing to receive advice. Every time he comes off stage, he always asks everyone present if there are any shortcomings on stage today or what needs to be improved. We always tell him truthfully and he will correct them next time he performs again. , he was one of the four famous Dandans, and it was not a coincidence at first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Wei became a photography enthusiast and was influenced by his friend Lang Jingshan. When Lang Jingshan was working part-time in the advertising department of &quot;Shenbao&quot;, Ding Ju noticed his high-end camera. &quot;The mirror case was not brand new, but it was of a good brand, and it was a four-inch large reflector.&quot; However, &quot;it was extremely heavy.&quot; &quot;, Ding Wei teased Lang Jingshan, &quot;No matter where he goes, he always carries this reflector like a chamber pot box with him, never leaving it for a moment. With his warm tone, it really makes people laugh. We got it for him. He was nicknamed &quot;living in a chamber pot box.&quot;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Wei, who is &quot;an excellent photographer throughout his life,&quot; sometimes stood in front of the camera to &quot;pose&quot;, and he was quite playful. In 1924, &quot;Half Moon&quot; published a photo of Zhou Shojuan and Ding Ju. Both appeared in women&#39;s clothing. Above it was a portrait of Zhou Shojuan in women&#39;s clothing when he was 14 years old, titled &quot;Shoujuan Makeup&quot;, with a description next to it: &quot;The so-called Prince Wenyan.&quot; Qianying (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Photographed fifteen years ago&lt;/span>;)&quot;. Ding Wei once took over the chore of drawing illustrations for novels because of this &quot;lovely friend&quot;, &quot;I remember once, I drew the illustrations of &quot;Ten Zhangs of Beijing Dust&quot; and &quot;The Record of Leftover Pink and Residual Fat&quot; for Shoujuan&#39;s &quot;Half Moon&quot;. Zhang is a bather in a bathhouse. They are all naked. There must be no mistakes in the drawings of each person&#39;s body... One picture shows a woman sitting on a low stool and sitting on a copper bed, cutting the nails of a young man... The composition It was difficult to arrange. I said to Shojuan, you have made me miserable. It is more difficult to draw these two illustrations than to draw ten colorful covers... Isn’t it unfair?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Ju and Zhou Shojuan’s friendship It is true that the two had known each other for more than 50 years from the time of &quot;Shen Shen·Free Talk&quot; to when Zhou was 70 years old. In 1964, when Ding Wei was dying, it coincided with the 70th birthdays of Zhou Shoujuan, Zheng Yimei and Tao Lengyue. A group of old friends celebrated their birthdays at the time-honored Xinya Restaurant in Shanghai and took a group photo after dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a serious and even a bit dull photo, which may have something to do with people&#39;s aging mood and current situation. Among the 22 people who took a photo together, most of them were very healthy people in Shanghai at that time. There are many intellectuals, and Ping Yanya, Cheng Xiaoqing, Lu Danan and Yan Duhe are all over seventy years old.&quot; Gu Zheng believed that this group photo was of &quot;extraordinary significance&quot; and made people think deeply about &quot;the heavy fate of individuals in the great era&quot; - four years later, in 1968, Zhou Shoujuan committed suicide by throwing himself into a well in Suzhou. Another year later, Ding Wei died of illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Reference: &quot;Mu Qin&#39;s Career: Ding Wei and 20th Century Modern Art and Culture&quot; &quot;Forty Years of Art World&quot; Memoirs (1902-1945)&quot;, etc.; Acknowledgments: Liu Haisu Art Museum, Gu Zheng, Ding Xia, Hu Yue, Zhao Shuping, etc.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[见闪电掠空，但不觉人生一场空——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（三）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256729]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/15/3VWPjX64PlaoZOYuyeFFEZdsA4MtTJgtN0KXPBwN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/3VWPjX64PlaoZOYuyeFFEZdsA4M tTJgtN0KXPBwN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The autumn scenery of Jiyama Temple along Matsuo Basho&#39;s &quot;Oku no Hosho&quot; tour. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue walking north. Get on the train from Nishinasuno Station, go to Nasushiobara Station, transfer to the Shinkansen to Koriyama, transfer to the main line and get off at Inaashiro Station. In a very small station, a huge public service announcement is very conspicuous on the glass of the station door. On it is a big picture of a sweet girl, and below it is written, &quot;Check everything one by one to be careful of candles.&quot; The Japanese word for a small fire candle is called &quot;火の心&quot;, which is interesting. Waiting for the bus at the station entrance, get off at the Katada stop and arrive at the shore of Inaashiro Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lake Inaashiro is the fourth largest lake in Japan. It is located in the center of Fukushima Prefecture and has transparent and clear water. The beauty of the four seasons of Bandai Mountain is reflected in it, like a sky mirror, so it is also called Tianjing Lake. From Jiantian Station on the roadside (there is just a road sign on the side of the road) to the lake, there is a straight small dirt road. On both sides of the road are harvested yellow-brown winter fields, and at the end of the road is a row of undulating crimson fields. The red tree, above the tree, was a vast sky covered with gray and white clouds. Although there was no actual sound, a loud rumbling sound suddenly rose in my heart. How could he just walk over like this? He must be running away! So he ran over like crazy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The business card of Lake Inaashiro is Hideyo Noguchi. Hideyo Noguchi, the man printed on the 1,000 yen note, is a world-famous bacteriologist who has made outstanding research achievements in serology, polio, rabies, syphilis, etc., which have benefited all mankind. In 1876, Hideyo Noguchi was born into a poor peasant family on the shores of Lake Inaashiro at the foot of Bandai Mountain. He was a poor student who worked extremely hard. After studying at the Medical College in Tokyo, he went to the University of Pennsylvania in the United States for further study and research, and made significant achievements. In 1928, Noguchi Hideyo died of the yellow fever epidemic while researching yellow fever in Ghana, Africa. At that time, the United States took his body back to New York for burial. In Lake Inaashiro, his hometown built the Noguchi Hideyo Museum for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We did not visit the Noguchi Hideyo Museum, but as of this writing, we cannot avoid the local business card. We didn&#39;t have much time at the time, and we had to return to the station to continue our journey north, so we strolled around the deserted lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We stayed at a hot spring hotel in Tendo City, Yamagata Prefecture at night. There is a big black cat lying on the cabinet at the front desk of the hotel. The clerk said that it is the hotel&#39;s signature and the owner. Tendo is the home and production base of shogi. The status of shogi is equivalent to that of Chinese chess, but it is not clear how to play it. I have watched the Japanese movie &quot;Holy Youth&quot;, which is a biopic about the seriously ill genius shogi player Murayama Sei. There are many scenes of chess and competitions in the film, which are quite arduous. At Tendo&#39;s hotel, I got a souvenir from the store, a small red shogi piece, which can be used as a key chain. When I got it and looked at it carefully, I suddenly thought: Does Chinese chess have a production base? In which city? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Return to the trip. We entered Yamagata Prefecture to visit Tateishiji Temple (mountain temple), which is an important relic of the Oku no Hosōdo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the morning, take the bus from Tendo Station to Yamagata Station, store your suitcases here, then continue to get on the bus, get off at Sandera Station, and start climbing the mountain. Lishi Temple, also known as Mountain Temple, was opened as the Taoist temple of Tiantai Sect in 860 by Master Cijue, an eminent monk of Tiantai Sect. The mountain here is steep and there are many strange rocks. After climbing all the way up, there are 870 stone steps from the mountain gate to the inner courtyard. This shrine is long and arduous and quite a tiring journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho wrote in &quot;Oku no Hosōdo&quot; &quot;Thirty Standing Stone Temple&quot;, &quot;... When we got there, it was still dark, so we first settled down in the monk&#39;s room at the bottom of the mountain, and then went up the mountain. Went to pay homage to the monk hall. Along the way, we saw layers of dangerous rocks and boulders, lush old pines and cypresses, and the old earth and rocks were covered with moss, making it slippery and difficult to walk on. Many temples built on the top of the rocks were all The door was closed, and there was silence. Sometimes we crept on the edge of the cliff, sometimes we crawled on the giant rocks, visited the Buddhist temple, and looked at the surrounding scenery. As the saying goes, the beautiful scenery is lonely, quiet and peaceful, and I feel that my heart has become clear and transparent. &quot;It&#39;s gone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the way to the trail, Basho&#39;s famous sentence written here is engraved on the cliff, &quot;The sound of the cicada in the rock is quiet&quot; (Want to know how quiet it is? The cicada chirps deep into the rock). Out of breath, I reached a small flat land in the mountains. On top of stacks of rocks, there was a bronze seated statue of Master Basho and his disciple Zeng Liang resting in the mountains. Basho was wearing a turban and straw sandals, sitting on a tree root, tilting his head slightly and looking into the distance. There was a small cloth bag hanging on his chest, presumably containing paper and pens. Zeng Liang is sitting not far away, wearing a bald monk&#39;s robes, holding a wooden stick in his right hand and a bamboo hat in his left hand. In the chapter &quot;Six Days of Light&quot; in &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot;, Basho specifically writes about Zeng Liang&#39;s change of clothes. When they were in Shenchuan, Zeng Liang and Basho lived next to each other, chopping firewood, boiling water, and doing daily housework for the teacher. When the two decided to travel to Austria together, before leaving, Zeng Liang shaved his head and put on black monk robes. When the two of them walked to the Black-Faced Mountain, Zeng Liang recited a sentence, &quot;The black-haired people shaved off early, and unexpectedly encountered the Black-Faded Mountain. It&#39;s time to change clothes in spring and summer.&quot; Bajiao commented, &quot;The word &#39;change&#39; in it , is not just a simple phrase, but also contains his determination to change his identity and insist on traveling far away. It is sonorous, powerful and meaningful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/15/0LwQbypWyYAFroR2L7GaeWOOhazUMdJB3IvUpv51.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/15/0LwQbypWyYAFroR2L7GaeWOOhazUMdJB3IvUpv51.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho and Kawai Soryo on the way to the mountain temple bronze seated statue. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three of us each found a rock and sat with Basho Zengliang to rest for a while. The mountain breeze is strong and cool. If you stop for a while, the sweat will stop all over your body. There is a branch of miscellaneous trees behind the banana, and the scattered red leaves are shining like gems in the sun. In the distance is the green mountain scenery, and the green and transparent leaves in the backlight are like new green in early spring. This place and this scene should be the same as what Basho and Zeng Liang saw 330 years ago. Think carefully about the integration of time and space, and you will suddenly feel lucky for three lifetimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, keep walking. Basho&#39;s footsteps are ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Oku no Hosōdo&quot;, Mount Haguro in Yamagata Prefecture is a highlight and must be visited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late autumn of 2019, which coincided with the first year of Reiwa, Japan’s new Emperor Naruhito ascended the throne. Haguro Mountain, where an important shrine is located, started from the Suishin Gate. There were many congratulatory posters on the approach to the shrine. . These congratulatory posters are not available in the street market. Along the way from Tokyo, from the market point of view, there was very little content related to the new emperor&#39;s enthronement. This shows that the changes in the Japanese royal family have little immersion and impact on people&#39;s daily life, let alone frequent changes. of the Japanese cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Haguro Mountain is one of the three mountains of Dewa. The three mountains, Mount Haguro, Mount Yudono, and Mount Tsuki, are special sacred places in Japanese mountain belief. Among the three mountains, only Mount Haguro, which is 414 meters above sea level, can be climbed all year round. Mount Getsuki and Mount Yudono are 1,984 meters and 1,504 meters above sea level respectively. Both have closed seasons. The former is from early autumn to early summer, and the latter is in autumn. In spring, ordinary people cannot go. Mount Yudono is considered to be the final place of spiritual practice in the Dewa Sanzan. Its shrine cannot be called by its name, and photography is prohibited, making it very mysterious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/uZBi7vFjm2QSjlgdagUQ0M1lsHJxg3YWpkU8EMz4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/uZBi7vFjm2QSjlgdagUQ0M1lsHJxg3YWpkU8EMz4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250846&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The mountain trail in Mount Haguro. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho and his disciple Zeng Liang arrived at the Dewa Three Mountains in mid-summer in July, and visited all three mountains. . The two masters and apprentices climbed to the Moon Mountain. After reaching a certain altitude, they entered the snow. They were in a trance. &quot;... They entered the cloud pass where the sun and moon travel. Their breath stopped and their bodies froze. Finally, when they reached the top of the mountain, the sun The moon is out.&quot; Along the way to Yueshan Mountain, Basho wrote a diary of his journey, but did not write a haiku. After that, he climbed to Tangdian Mountain, &quot;...and sat on a stone to take a nap. I saw a cherry tree, about three feet high, with half-open buds and hidden flowers. In the snow, spring is not forgotten; the late cherry blossoms are as special as the fragrance of plum blossoms in summer.&quot; The most beautiful scenery of Yudian Mountain should be at the shrine on the top of the mountain. Basho said, &quot;The details of the mountain are forbidden to be disclosed to outsiders, so Stop writing and not record.&quot; During the trip to Tangdian Mountain, Basho still did not write any haiku. Only at Mount Haguro, Basho lamented the beauty of the climb and recited, &quot;It&#39;s rare to find something special. The mountain breeze carries the fragrance of snow and the southern valley is scented.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We climbed Mount Haguro. The route is to climb from Suishenmen at the foot of the mountain to the top of the mountain, and then take a car down the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various shrines along the mountain road. There is Sanzan Shrine on the top of the mountain. When believers worship here, it is equivalent to worshiping all three mountains. I looked at the map and saw that there were dozens of shrines scattered throughout Mount Haguro. Among them is Hayamazhi Shrine, which we passed by while climbing. In my opinion, this shrine is quite appropriate for Mount Haguro, where trees and leaves are the focus of attention. &quot;It&#39;s awe-inspiring, the green leaves are intertwined, and the sun shines brightly.&quot; Basho wrote this haiku about Nikko in &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot;. It is particularly suitable to put it on the scenery we saw along the way to Mount Haguro. Climbing the long and steep mountain road, dripping with sweat and out of breath, I occasionally stopped to look up and saw the bright autumn sunshine blowing in the wind between the leaves. Although I did not feel the &quot;snow fragrance&quot; that Basho mentioned, it was indeed fascinating. , tiredness is completely out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early autumn, mid-autumn and late autumn are quite vague concepts. In terms of time, this trip to Northeast Japan is already in the mid-autumn season, but what I saw along the way was clearly the scenery of early autumn. We entered Tohoku from Tokyo. During our short stay in Tokyo, there was still heat in the air. In Tohoku, where the latitude is high, the red leaves and yellow leaves are already a little bit scattered, while in areas outside Tohoku, such as Tokyo and Kyoto, the red leaves are still green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this greenness is very subtle, it is the greenness that is about to leave, without any lingering flavor. In other words, the departure heel has already stood on tiptoe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The color of leaves has countless levels in a frame. The rotten leaf color is a very rich color system among the traditional Japanese colors. During the Heian period, there was a saying of the &quot;forty-eight rotten leaf colors&quot;. The color of fallen leaves refers to the color of fallen leaves. I understand that the state of fallen leaves should be when the leaves have just fallen off the branches, not after they have fallen to the ground. Among the colors of rotten leaves, the color name &quot;green rotten leaves&quot; refers specifically to the green color that still retains the breath of summer. A very Zen statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the long mountain trail of Mount Haguro, there are fallen leaves the color of decayed green leaves everywhere. In the sunshine, those leaves that are about to fall or change color are like the new green in early spring, tender and bright. Along the way, there are traces of Basho, monuments, statues, and the &quot;Basho Tomb&quot;, which is one of the many in Japan... I took out the &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot; I brought with me and took a photo with Basho to thank him for his kind blessing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new green of early spring has a unique color term called moeki color, which has been used since the Heian period. The moe wood color is a fresh and bright green with a breath as thin as cicada wings. It is said that this color is often used in the armor of young samurai. This scene is described in &quot;The Tale of the Heike&quot;, where a teenage samurai appears lightly wearing moegi-colored armor. It&#39;s hard to imagine how the texture of the armor could be harmonized with a color as delicate as bright green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There seems to be no difference between the green rotten wood color in early autumn and the cute wood color in early spring from the color matching post, at least I can&#39;t see any difference. The difference lies in the breath, in the relationship between these delicate greens and the wind, rain, and sky. The autumn sky is high and distant, and the depth of field is the deepest and most indifferent among the four seasons. It is silent and reticent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The color of green and decaying leaves has been with us since the beginning of this trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book written by Nagasawa Yoko, a traditional Japanese color expert, she regards hagi cakes as the representative food of green leaf color. Hagi, also known as Lespedeza, is one of the seven grasses of autumn. Hagi mochi is a Japanese autumn seasonal food, which is a glutinous rice dumpling filled with bean paste that is common in Japan. If you want to emphasize the occasion, you will add a flowering lespedeza pattern. The red flowers and green leaves are all light and hazy. The soft colors and soft taste are combined into one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a song in &quot;Man&#39;yoshu&quot; that says: &quot;There has been a time like this; Junshang asked, have the Lespedeza flowers bloomed?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trip we set off from Fukagawa, Tokyo. At that time, while looking into the courtyard of Bashoan&#39;s former site, I saw the flowering Lespedeza for the first time. The seated bronze statue of Basho faces the Sumida River. The autumn clouds are low to the horizon, the branches of Lespedeza are trembling in the wind, and the red flowers are swaying. Lespedeza is a simple shrub plant, and its branch and flower shapes are not stunning at all, but its light and contented little playfulness makes people very happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since there are hagi mochi in autumn, there are also corresponding seasonal foods in spring, which are rice cakes and oriole mochi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year in March, I was on a spring trip to Japan. At a restaurant, the shopkeeper served a dessert, a rhombus-shaped rice cake divided into three layers, one pink and one pink. It&#39;s white and the first layer is green. I always like this kind of simple snack, not too sweet, and I ate it happily. Later, when I read the book, I realized, oh, what I eat is water chestnut pancake. This water chestnut cake really has a very important meaning. The orthodox lozenge cake has three colors, peach represents peach blossoms, white represents lingering snow, and green represents spring buds. It is a typical spring snack and an important food during the Peach Blossom Festival in March. March 3rd is Hina Festival, also called Peach Blossom Festival or Girl&#39;s Day, which is derived from China&#39;s Shangsi Festival. During this festival, families with daughters will set up a doll stand in their home, with three, five, seven or nine layers, with figures in ancient costumes placed on each layer from bottom to top in descending order. Doll. The special foods on this day are clam chowder, chirashi sushi, dried mochi and water chestnut cakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called warbler cake is a glutinous rice ball wrapped with fillings and sprinkled with bean flour called warbler powder made from green beans. The traditional color represented by Oriole mochi is Oriole, which is the color of the feathers of an oriole. The tree warbler, also called the primula, has a thrilling call in early spring. There is a haiku in the corner of Basho&#39;s disciple&#39;s room, which says, &quot;The oriole hangs upside down on the branch and makes its first cry.&quot; The color of the oriole I understand is matte yellow-green. This color name was born in the Edo period. Common people in the Edo period were prohibited from wearing bright and bright clothes, so matte orioles were very popular because of their subtle charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know why, but I think it’s more appropriate for glutinous rice dumplings to be green. In small supermarkets in Japan, there are various kinds of glutinous rice dumplings called &quot;Daifuku&quot;. The one I often buy is called &quot;Cao Daifuku&quot;. The light green glutinous rice dumplings are wrapped in light green bean flour and filled with bean paste. &quot;Sodaifuku&quot; is very cheap, about 100 yen each, but if it is served at a formal banquet in the spring, it will be worth a lot of money, and its name will also change, becoming &quot;Obama mochi&quot;. Maybe some people will laugh at me for thinking that the &quot;Cao Dafu&quot; in the supermarket is the same thing as Orioles cake. Maybe there are some differences between the two, but for me, who has dull taste buds, they are the same thing. I ate the last dessert at a spring Michelin-level kaiseki meal, a small green glutinous rice pancake. It was delicious. I thought happily, oh, it’s Sodaifuku. Then I looked at the menu at hand and it said: &quot;Warbler Cake&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From autumn to spring, spring and autumn flow. In spring and autumn, people are accustomed to skipping summer and winter, but these two seasons, which have no direct intersection, are used as synonyms for the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Basho&#39;s &quot;Oku no Hosho&quot;, the first haiku is in &quot;Departure&quot;, &quot;Spring is about to pass, and it is useless to teach birds to sing gracefully and fish to have tears in their eyes.&quot; The last haiku is in &quot;Departure&quot;. In &quot;Ogaki&quot;, &quot;Meat in clam shells, seeing the separation of two eyes, autumn is about to go.&quot; It starts with &quot;spring goes&quot; and ends with &quot;autumn goes&quot;, and the first sentence of the prologue part of &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot; Yes, &quot;The sun and moon are passers-by for hundreds of generations, and the years are also travelers.&quot; It is nothing more than two words, years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You will get tired of singing any song after a long time, but for the songs of the four seasons, generations of passers-by, travelers coming and going for thousands of years, no matter how you sing, there is never enough. Although all the songs will disappear, Basho said, &quot;Precious people see lightning flying across the sky, but they don&#39;t realize that their lives are in vain.&quot; This very powerful haiku is a sentence of summer. I have always believed that summer is the most powerful season. In other seasons, my mood is flickering up and down, and I am not at ease, which is hard to say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[出走半生，归来仍是《小时代》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;&quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; is undoubtedly A good start to the September season. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Yu Shu&lt;/span>; The main CP led by Xin and Zhang Linghe continued the popularity of &quot;Eternal Life Flower&quot; in &quot;Canglan Jue&quot;, and the supporting cast included Cheng Lei, Lu Yuxiao, Young actors such as Tian Jiarui also successfully &quot;served on the table.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But, what is the quality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After ten episodes, I just want to say: &quot;Guo Jingming has been away for half his life, and he is still &quot;Little Times&quot; when he comes back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ac0690abaedf15b3ce46f48519d38909.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ac0690abaedf15b3ce46f48519d38909.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although, after the series started airing, the chief director and The screenwriter&#39;s signature was changed to &quot;Gu Xiaosheng&quot;, but familiar viewers know that Gu Xiaosheng is the pseudonym of Guo Jingming (Guo Xiaosi). The actual controller of Zuishi Culture, the co-producer of the series, is also Guo Jingming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ca271e02d9ed357d3577c8f05408b86e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;524&quot; height=&quot;213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ca271e02d9ed357d3577c8f05408b86e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250378 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In May this year, in the 2023-2024 major drama list released by iQiyi, the director’s signature Still Guo Jingming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The story of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; takes place in an imaginary ancient background. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Gong family is a well-known and upright family in the world. They live in seclusion in deep mountains and valleys, living a nearly isolated life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Broken down, there are four families with their own specialties: Shang, Jiao, Zheng, and Yu. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The wise and brave Gong Huanyu&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Ji Lingchen)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and the frail Gong Ziyu&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;(played by Zhang Linghe)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Is the son of the current leader of Gongmen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e135141865e13db3fe55a92e71dbc31d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e135141865e13db3fe55a92e71dbc31d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250377 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gong Shangjiao of Jiao Palace&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Cheng Lei)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is ruthless and has extraordinary abilities. Gong Yuanzheng (played by Tian Jiarui) of Zhenggong is good at making drugs and is a senior brother-controller who follows Gong Shangjiao all day long. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/355ef4cbc340a4c0ddef87f7c946370d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/355ef4cbc340a4c0ddef87f7c946370d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250379 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5b752f8ebbdb2327527fcad6e00102fb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5b752f8ebbdb2327527fcad6e00102fb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250381&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to these four young masters, the Gong family also has a hilarious and nymphomaniac eldest lady Gong Zishang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Jin Jing)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/febbb14f36052b928d812157e439a979.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/febbb14f36052b928d812157e439a979.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250382 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is also a killer organization in the world called Wu Feng. It has been trying to dismantle the palace for many years and has sent out many undercover agents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the time when the palace is choosing a wife, the Wufeng female assassin Yun Weishan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Yu Shuxin)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Shangguan Qian &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Lu Yuxiao) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sneaks into the Gong family with different tasks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/97aac732115cfd1e8226f4b8b2c7b821.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;459&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/97aac732115cfd1e8226f4b8b2c7b821.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250383 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This was a troubled year. The old leader and first heir Gong Huanyu died mysteriously. Gong Ziyu succeeded him at the critical moment and got the support of his sister Gong Zishang. However, the more powerful Gong Shangjiao is eyeing the leader, and Gong Yuanzheng has repeatedly provoked and secretly caused trouble for him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With their beauty and strength, Yun Weishan and Shangguan Qian stood out from the many brides and lurked next to Gong Ziyu and Gong Shangjiao respectively. Where should their fate go? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a48c9dcbecd2d69d86875b9011b9b6e1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a48c9dcbecd2d69d86875b9011b9b6e1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250386 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although there are many characters and complicated subplots&lt;/span>;, love is undoubtedly the main thread of this drama. In the final analysis, it is the story of a female undercover agent and a male target falling in love. &lt;span>; With a sincere heart, he is entangled, confused, and finally makes a choice between mission and emotion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/0e7be16731d2df118912b0a8c8df50da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/0e7be16731d2df118912b0a8c8df50da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250387 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/acd389bb4cc73e1cdfa5137543e3fdbe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/acd389bb4cc73e1cdfa5137543e3fdbe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250384&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the other side, Gong Shangjiao and Shangguan Qian will stage a fox-rabbit love story. The two high-end game players gradually developed feelings that they did not expect during their testing, mediation, and pulling. For two people whose reason is greater than their emotions, they may have to compete for &quot;who falls first&quot; until the last moment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/353403007bd0ad44965bfa471a0e7e63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/353403007bd0ad44965bfa471a0e7e63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250385 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/9a616aecee21fd328e8babc6aa98574d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/9a616aecee21fd328e8babc6aa98574d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250388&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;From this perspective, what Guo Jingming wanted to film &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; may be a variation of &quot;Lust, Caution&quot;: men and women trapped in identities. They are on guard against each other, but it is difficult to resist physical attraction and the desire to be loved. Love is hard to hold on to, love is hard to find, those who are sober will pull away, and those who are infatuated will leave their tears empty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This requires a detailed description of emotions. It must be written that every decision made by a man in reason is mixed with overwhelming pain and lasting love, and it must be written that a woman&#39;s heart is shattered after all the tricks have been exhausted. I suddenly realized that he was the only one who cared about me. I wanted to write about the weakness of human nature, the burning body of love, and the dark thoughts growing secretly in the coffin-like mansion...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &quot;Yun Zhi&quot; &quot;Yu&quot; is not the ancient puppet version of &quot;Lust, Caution&quot;, but &quot;Tiny Times 5&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like August’s high school days in Chang’an, Shuang Xuetao’s frozen Northeast, and Han Han’s small towns and racing cars, many writers’ creations repeatedly echo their most nostalgic elements. What Guo Jingming likes is just like the &quot;Tiny Times&quot; series of the year, which is noble and decent on the surface, but frivolous on the inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first rule of Guo&#39;s rule: noble people must have the surname Gong. Each play has its own Tang Wanru. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Little Times&quot;, CEO Gong Ming has severe mysophobia and collects expensive cups like crazy. &lt;span>; His face turns pale when he sees fish. He consumes protein powder every day to maintain his appearance from &quot;VOGUE&quot; 》The face torn off the fifth page of the magazine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cc62eb65db10f8e71b62144cbe0bcc65.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;666&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cc62eb65db10f8e71b62144cbe0bcc65.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250391 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; allows us to see Gong Ming&#39;s ancestors and grandfathers: Gong Ziyu, even eating ice cream in June will be cold enough to cry. Cold body is a delicate disease of wealth. ; Gong Shangjiao doesn’t eat chicken and fish because he doesn’t want to see dead fish eyes and dead corns. This must be the source of Gong Ming’s DNA. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The character of Tang Wanru, who loves gags and can’t move his legs when seeing handsome guys in &quot;Little Times&quot;, has also been transferred to Gong Zishang in &quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; . Just like Tang Wanru was out of place among the sisters of the era, Gong Zishang was also an outsider of the Gong family. He was a rich man but he stalked the handsome guards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/89b6c75ce3676cc3b75c65f56ae81e75.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/89b6c75ce3676cc3b75c65f56ae81e75.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250389 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo&#39;s Rules&lt;/span>; Rule 2: Visual impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, &quot;Tiny Times&quot; allowed everyone to re-understand Shanghai&#39;s life and death in a dazzling array of brand-name clothes and dazzling luxurious scenes. The fashionable outfits in it are still fashionable today. Timeless. Many viewers even believe that the most suitable career for Guo Jingming is costume stylist and art director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/bc18d2b2cd46560ea74003226305954e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/bc18d2b2cd46560ea74003226305954e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250392&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When it came to &quot;Cloud Feather&quot;, he became interested in symmetrical composition and wabi-sabi aesthetics. Audiences who like it admit his care in visual effects, while those who don&#39;t think it&#39;s just pretentious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3ae75478e83c90ed0af4ab469cfa6895.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3ae75478e83c90ed0af4ab469cfa6895.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250390 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/75d282ef87285c0bc505e500a0c8eb9c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/75d282ef87285c0bc505e500a0c8eb9c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250393&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/854be081d615cc29d62a30afae09cec7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/854be081d615cc29d62a30afae09cec7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250394&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Guo&#39;s Rule No. 3: Tear it up, be happy, there is plenty of time anyway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a famous tearing scene in &quot;The Feather of the Clouds&quot;, which is comparable to the scene in &quot;Little Times&quot; where &quot;Gu Li was poured red wine by Nan Xiang on his birthday, and the blessing turned rotten and smelly&quot;: The Successor Gong Ziyu was questioned about Germany&#39;s unmatchability and got into a fight with Gong Yuanzheng. Gong Shangjiao walked over and gave each of them a slap in the face, regardless of their respect and power. Gong Zishang was shouting at the side, Gong Ziyu was angry and tearful but did not fight back, opposite Gong Shangjiao had contempt written on his eyebrows, while Gong Yuanzheng had a mocking smile. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ed19b2bb0658976d98266ce188f3b196.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/ed19b2bb0658976d98266ce188f3b196.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;250399 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, he is much more restrained than before. Most of the time in &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; is secretly tearing apart. If he can&#39;t bear it anymore, he will have a fight scene&lt;/span>; on the stage. , it can be seen that it is quite restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo’s Rule 4: Consumption of male sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Jingming always understands the psychology of the (female) audience and shows different types of handsome little fresh meat on the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Little Times&quot; there is Gu Yuan, Gong Ming and Zhou Chongguang, &lt;span>; in &quot;Qing Ya Ji&quot; there is Qing Ming Boya He Shou Yue, in &quot;The Feather of the Cloud&quot; there is the Gong family boy band, &quot;Marry Entering the palace and obeying the regulations&quot; also became a hot topic for a time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cdabb3a80df1a2a1bc2e326ed2de6075.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1431&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/cdabb3a80df1a2a1bc2e326ed2de6075.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250397 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After watching ten episodes, the perception of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; is hovering between two extremes: the plot rhythm is fast and slow, and the audience&#39;s experience is sometimes good and sometimes bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first four episodes quickly introduced the portraits of the Gong family and the Wufeng assassin, and cut to the core plot line quickly. The death of Gong Ziyu’s father and brother pushed the rhythm to the top, and at the same time dropped a double layer of suspense: Who is the murderer? How can Yun Weishan and Shangguan Qian survive the crises? Even the first four episodes are full of plot points such as inappropriate memories of the heroine and slow discussion of plans by the heroine and co-star across the stairs, but overall there are no big problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But when Gong Ziyu was asked to pass the &quot;Trial of the Three Domains&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (a test that must be passed as a sword-wielding successor)&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;At the beginning, the rhythm of &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; had a big problem, and each episode was one hour long and did not convey much effective information. The foreshadowing of the previous situation made the audience think that Yun Weishan, Shangguan Qian and Gong Shangjiao were all people who were doing great things. However, these powerful characters did not advance the development of the plot line, but had meaningless conversations day after day. The conflict between Wu Feng and Gong Men intensified, but Gong Men was still a pool of stagnant water. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What’s even worse is that the plot also repeatedly contains slaps in the face. For example, when the poison in the female assassin&#39;s body broke out in Ban Yue, they were supposed to contact Wu Feng&#39;s superiors on time. The audience tried one hundred and twenty ways for them to escape briefly, but the final solution was to carry on; another example is &quot;Three Domain Test&quot; The first level of &quot;Refining&quot; was highlighted as a dangerous level. Even the talented Gong Shangjiao took more than ten days, but Gong Ziyu actually passed it by grabbing a box with the help of Yun Weishan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/12eca1cda1359ac2fe6745f4fd755ffa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1020&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/12eca1cda1359ac2fe6745f4fd755ffa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250395 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Yunzhiyu&quot; is also very good at throwing up suspense at the end of each episode and resolving conflicts at the beginning of the next episode: for example, at the end of the sixth episode, the guard saw from Yun Weishan&#39;s tricks The shadow of Wu Feng was once again blocked by her in a few words in the seventh episode; at the end of the ninth episode, Yun Weishan pointed out the undercover identity of his aunt Ming Wuji, and in the tenth episode she said that the other party had heard wrongly. These were supposed to be the boosting points of important plots, but what was waiting for them was the feeling of one big step forward and two big steps back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/537bea127b0d8ddd3bc8f71d441c09f8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1058&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/537bea127b0d8ddd3bc8f71d441c09f8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250396 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/4fcfeafe201c307844358a42c7fdeb11.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/4fcfeafe201c307844358a42c7fdeb11.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250398&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In general, the intertwined character relationships in &quot;Cloud Feather&quot; may attract &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the attention of some viewers. However, the excessive and indiscriminate plot advancement will consume everyone&#39;s patience. If this continues, the series is bound to start high and then go low. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s not that we didn’t give him a chance, it’s just that the answer sheet he handed over was still a reimagined version of “Tiny Times.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[旅客吐槽候机厅全是按摩椅？山西太原机场最新回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256892]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thanks very much to all walks of life and passengers for their attention to the issue of &quot;massage chairs&quot; at Taiyuan Airport. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 16, relevant media reports attracted our company’s great attention. In response to media reports and social concerns, Taiyuan Airport immediately formulated a massage chair adjustment plan. We also began to adjust some of the massage chairs in the terminal that night, and all seats were adjusted into place as soon as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Taiyuan Airport will continue to ensure aviation services, create a warm and comfortable waiting environment for passengers, and give you a better travel experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;We are deeply sorry for this incident. Thank you again to the media and travel friends for supervising our work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Taiyuan International Airport Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot; >;&lt;span>;September 17, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[初中两女生投毒全班：犯罪动机值得深究丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256884]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A shocking &quot;poisoning case of middle school students&quot; attracted attention. On September 14, 2023, it was reported on the Internet that a poisoning incident occurred at a junior high school in Shanghai. Many students became ill after drinking unknown liquids. Shanghai police issued a notice that day, confirming the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the police report, at 15:37 on the day of the incident on September 12, the Pudong Branch received a call that many students at the East School of Shangnan Middle School were feeling unwell. After preliminary investigation by the police, the case was committed by Yang Moumou (female, 13 years old), a student of the school, and Zheng Moumou (female, 13 years old), a classmate of the same class. The two returned to the classroom during physical education class that morning and poured a mixture of cleaning and bleaching liquid into the water cups of students in the same class, causing many students to feel uncomfortable. &quot;The students involved were sent to the hospital for treatment and were discharged that night, and have now returned to normal classes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After carefully examining the entire process of this case, there are some questions worthy of analysis and questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, this case still requires in-depth investigation, and the full story of the incident needs to be restored and released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenshots of the leaks posted on the WeChat group showed that 23 people in the class drank &quot;added water&quot;, more than a dozen of them had their stomachs washed, and several students suffered varying degrees of damage to their liver and kidney functions. . If this revelation is true, the number and extent of the victimized students need to be further confirmed by follow-up investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenshots of the revelations also showed that one of the poisoners was the monitor of the class. &quot;He was planning revenge on the class teacher during the summer vacation.&quot; He once formulated a policy of &quot;one poison to kill, two gasoline, alcohol, and hydrogen peroxide to burn to death.&quot; According to the two plans, the girl involved &quot;there were three bottles of unknown liquid in the table. When the teacher went to collect it, (the girl) picked up one bottle and wanted to drink it herself&quot; and &quot;the girl actually had three fruit knives on the table.&quot; In addition, the two girls usually have good grades and have received &quot;key training from the class teacher.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are still doubts about the revelations spread on the Internet, and the motive of &quot;planning to retaliate against the head teacher&quot; is also open to investigation. Let me ask, since the girl involved was targeting the class teacher, why did she poison the entire class? If the &quot;three bottles of unknown liquid&quot; and &quot;three fruit knives&quot; situations are true, I am afraid they are directed at more people than simply retaliating against the class teacher. In addition, the information of &quot;cultivation by the head teacher&quot; and the rhetoric of &quot;retaliation against the head teacher&quot; are contradictory and difficult to justify, and it is difficult to be trusted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the facts of the case, it seems a bit far-fetched for the girl involved to describe her motive as &quot;revenge against the class teacher.&quot; However, the revelations spread online have brought an increase in information after all, adding many details to the case, and many subsequent interpretations are based on these details. Faced with the divergent opinions on the Internet, the police should investigate these details in depth, complete the puzzle of information that has not yet been provided in the police report, and announce it to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the criminal motivation and nature of the crime of the girl involved, as well as the real cause of the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, if the girl involved does have good grades and has no obvious conflict with the teacher, then her motive for committing the crime is indeed a question that still needs to be resolved. Some netizens regard the girl&#39;s long-planned poisoning in this case as a &quot;psychological and mental problem&quot;, which is inconsistent with the basic principle of causality between harmful behavior and harmful results in the criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the girl involved made a criminal plan in advance and took the initiative to carry out the crime, intending to harm dozens of classmates in the class. There is a serious suspicion of deliberate murder or &quot;retaliation against society&quot;. Any &quot;Hidden secrets&quot; and &quot;causes&quot; cannot be the reasons for the two girls to commit poison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior of the two girls was not due to negligence, nor was there any &quot;irresistible or unforeseen reason&quot; behind it. Instead, they knew that poisoning would harm others, endanger society, and even There is a serious suspicion of attempted intentional homicide, which cannot be excused or mitigated for any reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a step back, even if the girl involved, Yang Moumou, has &quot;psychological problems&quot;, does her co-defendant Zheng Moumou also have &quot;psychological problems&quot;? Even if the girls involved were really seeking revenge, did the entire class offend them? Obviously, the criminal motives of the two girls involved deserve further investigation. The police should strictly investigate their social media and social relationships to find possible perpetrators who instigated the crime, or signs that the girls involved were influenced by specific extremist thoughts, and track down these truly reliable crimes. Cause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the aftermath of this case includes punishing those involved and relieving the victims, but there are still areas for discussion in these two aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Lizhi News&quot;, it is reported on the Internet that the parents of the girl involved have apologized in the class group, saying that they &quot;feel guilty for not being able to control their children well because of their dereliction of duty.&quot; According to the current law, the two students involved are under the age of 14 and do not need to bear criminal responsibility or administrative responsibility. They can only order the parents of the students to strictly discipline them. If the victim student has medical expenses and other expenses, the parents can sue the parents of the two students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two girls in this case have committed the crime of releasing dangerous substances, and they have successfully committed the crime. Article 114 of the Criminal Law stipulates that those who set fires, breach floods, explode, release toxic, radioactive, infectious disease pathogens and other substances, or use other dangerous methods to endanger public safety without causing serious consequences shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years but not more than ten years. If &quot;causing serious injury or death to others or causing heavy losses to public or private property&quot;, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of more than ten years, life imprisonment or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that if this case involves an adult deliberately poisoning a minor, then the person involved will definitely face severe legal sanctions and receive a sentence of between three years and less than ten years in prison. However, Article 17 of the Criminal Law stipulates, “A person who has reached the age of fourteen but under the age of eighteen commits a crime and shall be given a lighter or reduced punishment.” In this case, the two girls involved were both under the age of fourteen, which brings problems to their punishment. problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the circumstances of this case, the criminal behavior of the girl involved may not have been a spur of the moment, and a &quot;bug&quot; situation cannot even be ruled out. If this situation is true, this case is that a minor criminal committed a crime with an adult&#39;s mind, but he boldly escaped punishment by virtue of his status as a minor. Is it possible that society can only allow juvenile criminals under the age of fourteen to go unpunished? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current law on the protection of minors seems to only be able to deter and punish adults who harm minors, but it is powerless to deal with the situation of &quot;minors harming minors&quot;; at the same time, according to Article 1 of the Compulsory Education Law According to the provisions of Article 27, the school can only &quot;criticize and educate the students involved in this case who have been suspected of murder, and cannot expel them.&quot; This is obviously seriously inconsistent with the principle of proportionality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, according to the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention of Juvenile Delinquency&quot;, simply &quot;criticizing and educating&quot; or &quot;strictly disciplining&quot; the girl involved in this case is obviously not enough to punish criminal behavior , and cannot comfort the victimized classmates. Therefore, it is necessary to implement the &quot;corrective education measures&quot; in Article 41 or 45 of this law, or to &quot;maliciously increase the age of the offender&quot; so that he will receive the punishment he deserves and give justice to the victim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国庆出行没抢到票？这些方式可提高购票成功率]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256890]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from China State Railway Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;State Railway Group&quot;) that since September 13 Since the first day of transportation during the National Day Golden Week, which is September 27, train tickets have been on sale, and from September 16, tickets have been on sale for the second day of the holiday, which is September 30. Railway train ticket sales are booming. From September 13 to 16, the railway sold a total of 74.05 million train tickets, of which September 15 hit a record high of 22.877 million tickets sold in a single day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the Passenger Transport Department of the China Railway Group said that judging from the pre-sale of train tickets from September 13 to 16, the day before the holiday, September 28, and the two days before the holiday, that is, September 29 to On the 30th, tickets from Shanghai to Wuhan, Shanghai to Xi&#39;an, Shenzhen to Changsha, Shanghai to Changsha, Shanghai to Hefei, Shenzhen to Xiamen, Shanghai to Zhengzhou, Beijing to Zhengzhou, Beijing to Wuhan, Guangzhou to Guiyang and other directions are in short supply at some points. Popular trains with better and faster speeds are more tense, but Beijing to Shanghai, Shanghai to Nanjing, Shanghai to Beijing, Chengdu to Chongqing, Suzhou to Shanghai, Hangzhou to Shanghai, Wuhan to Shanghai, Guangzhou to Nanning, Shijiazhuang to Beijing, Xi&#39;an Some trains to Beijing and other directions still have tickets left, including trains from Shenyang to Beijing, Hong Kong to Guangzhou, Shenzhen to Hong Kong, Nanning to Guangzhou, Qingdao to Beijing, Taiyuan to Beijing, Wuhan to Shenzhen, Wuxi to Shanghai, Kunming to Chengdu and other directions. There are enough votes left. For tickets sold during the pre-sale period on and before September 27, there are sufficient remaining tickets in all directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that passengers travel during holidays are highly concentrated, and trains in some popular directions and hot periods will have ticket shortages. Passengers can choose to travel in off-peak hours according to the remaining tickets at different times and directions. You can choose to purchase tickets through waitlisting, transfer, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No handling fee is charged for railway 12306 waitlisted tickets. After the ticket purchaser submits the waitlisted ticket order, he or she will pay the fare advance simultaneously. The ticketing system will continue to try to honor the waitlisted demand. If there are tickets matching the demand, The system will automatically generate a paid order and notify the ticket purchaser. If the advance payment is greater than the actual ticket price, the system will automatically refund the difference; if the waitlist purchase is unsuccessful, the advance payment for the waitlist order will be automatically refunded in full. Passengers can submit waitlisted orders with multiple combinations of &quot;dates, train numbers, and seats&quot; to extend the waitlist redemption time and increase the success rate of waitlisted ticket purchases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you cannot buy a direct ticket, it is recommended that passengers can meet their travel needs by transferring or taking buses in sections. Railway 12306 will intelligently recommend transfer plans with remaining tickets based on passenger travel needs and remaining tickets for passengers to choose from. In order to facilitate passengers to transfer between trains, the railway department has set up convenient in-station transfer channels at 100 major stations, and arranged station staff to provide guidance services. Passengers can enter the waiting room to wait without leaving the station, effectively shortening the time for transfers. Multiply time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The railway department reminds passengers who use the Internet or mobile phone clients to purchase tickets, the railway 12306 website (including clients) is the only official online train ticket sales channel, and does not charge any additional fees. Dear passengers, please Purchase tickets through official channels to protect your legal rights and personal information security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔡磊：“抗冻”先行者向死而生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the fate of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 997&quot; height=&quot;1496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/k333Jm240kPZM97cSD8bbR0AF9eMm5l4Ix5Abw48.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250528&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/251236&quot; title=&quot;Cai Lei: Hunting Medicine The shock caused by the patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&quot;>;Cai Lei: The shock caused by the drug-hunting patient丨Special article on World ALS Day&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After lumbar puncture , a bottle of liquid was quietly pushed into the spinal cavity of Nanjing (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;pseudonym&lt;/span>;) from outside the body through a needle. A few days later, her family discovered that her hands could support the armrests of her wheelchair and help her stand on her own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years ago, Nan Jing, who was in her early 20s, suddenly found it difficult to lift her left leg. Since then, her condition has deteriorated rapidly, and it has become increasingly difficult for her to walk. Several times while going up and down the steps of the work commuter bus, Nanjing fell to the ground and was almost run over by a vehicle speeding behind him. Soon, she was diagnosed with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early June 2023, Nanjing was enrolled in the clinical trial of a new single-gene drug that Cai Lei and a team of scientists collaborated with Beijing Tiantan Hospital, and has used the drug four times so far. Although her leg muscle strength has not improved significantly, she has made great progress compared to the time before when she had to be helped by her family to stand up. For Cai Lei, who has led the team to develop drugs and fight ALS for more than four years, this is a historic breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Nanjing is lucky, but there are still 500,000 ALS patients around the world who are in urgent need of the attention and assistance of the whole society.&quot; Cai Lei said. &quot;Furthermore, Nanjing belongs to the SOD1 subtype, which accounts for less than 2% of all patients. The other subtypes and the pathology of sporadic ALS are still a mystery, waiting to be explored and solved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because A disease of the motor nerve cells in the brain and spinal cord, patients with ALS gradually weaken their muscles and eventually become completely paralyzed and lose their body functions. For more than a hundred years since its discovery, the pathology of ALS is unknown and there is no cure. Most patients die within 2 to 5 years of the disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly four years ago, Cai Lei, the former vice president of JD.com, was also diagnosed with ALS. In the industry, Cai Lei, who is full of passion, keen insight and action, and good at organizing and cooperating, is like a &quot;hard-working man&quot;. When he got sick, he was in his early forties and had just married and had a son. Being thrown into a sudden desperate situation, he also experienced despair. But within a month after his diagnosis, he decided to mobilize all the resources he had accumulated over half his life to invest in scientific research and drug development for ALS. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s impossible, it can’t be done.” These opinions from inside and outside the industry have never shaken Cai Lei’s belief. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was difficult to get through patient data between hospitals, so he used the most primitive methods to build the world&#39;s largest big data platform for ALS patients through phone calls and WeChat exchanges; he visited the house again and again, He impressed a number of top scientists who were not involved in ALS research, including Chen Gong, Dai Jianwu, Lu Yunfeng, Meng Songdong, and Chen Lingling, to cooperate with him and promote the launch of more than 100 R&amp;D pipelines; he took the lead in signing letters of intent, leading more than a thousand patients and family members to Voluntarily donating brain and spinal cord tissue samples after his death; he shortened the recruitment of patients for clinical trials from the previous one or two years to the &quot;extreme speed&quot; of two hours...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether it is financial or professional, In fact, I am not the strongest candidate in the world to overcome ALS. But I don’t want to just sit and wait for medical progress. I have to do things that others have not done or done.” Cai Lei put the funds, Laboratories, scientists, pharmaceutical companies, hospitals, and patients are connected one by one, becoming the lubricant and booster in many aspects of basic research and the medical industry. He believes that only by making the fight against ALS a cause that is valuable and beneficial to all parties involved can it become a sharp blade to tear through the darkness and let light continuously shine in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is far from a simple inspirational story of an individual fighting against fate, but arousing the goodwill and motivation deep in the heart.” Xu Wanjiao, a medical practitioner who has been engaged in drug research and development for 15 years, sighed with emotion. &quot;Everyone approaches Teacher Cai because Teacher Cai approaches each other. This connection itself is a kind of energy and energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, Cai Lei has been a long-term staff member of Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China. When he was teaching a postgraduate student majoring in accounting at a university, he spoke frankly when faced with the confusion of young students. &quot;They often ask me, how can we be successful and respected? Some students think that our generation has many opportunities and can make money in anything, and is not as competitive as them. I want to say, which era is not fierce? Which era is not fierce? Is success not difficult? Struggle and progress are the life young people should pursue. Helping others can also reduce confusion and emptiness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After falling ill, Nanjing, who works as a clerk in Nanjing, can only use a wheelchair. as a companion. The mother is suffering from terminal cancer and needs to come to Beijing for treatment. The grandmother accompanies her daughter and granddaughter to rent a house and see a doctor in this strange city. Nanjing experienced anxiety and worry, not knowing what she could do. After meeting Cai Lei, she changed. &quot;I have no reason to be decadent. I can sweep the floor, mop the floor, and wash clothes. Whatever I can do is a little bit. Find your own meaning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter what your fate is, strive to continue to create value and live out your own spirit.&quot; This is the wealth that Cai Lei believes he can leave to the world, and his footsteps have not stopped yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suffering from a terminal illness, he refuses to accept the destiny of &quot;going to death&quot;, but is determined to change history. Having been engaged in ALS drug research and development for nearly four years, Cai Lei and his team have built patient data platforms, basic science and clinical trials related to new drug research and development, brain tissue and spinal cord donation, large-scale real-world medical data research, and many other aspects. All have achieved historic breakthroughs. Based on his smart mind and tenacious personality, and driven by the idea of ​​helping others and altruism, Cai Lei&#39;s practice demonstrates the brilliance of human nature and the tremendous energy that faith and action can release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[偷遍上海所有无印良品店铺，小偷夫妻自称“品牌代理”，半年赚26万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256731]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>