<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[现制茶超长配料表“泄密”，能做到真透明吗？丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73540&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70343&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/136405441d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;mmexport1700108368825.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;9599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/136405441d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258519&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73541&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70344&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/d354380823.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;mmexport1700108615676.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;9338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/16/d354380823.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258520&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院国资委原副部长级干部骆玉林被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260729]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 15:08:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Luo Yulin, a former deputy ministerial cadre of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council, for serious violations of discipline. Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Luo Yulin lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original intention and mission, was disloyal and dishonest to the party, was inconsistent with his appearance, and acted two-faced; he violated the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepted private enterprises in violation of regulations Banquets and travel activities arranged by the boss; violating organizational principles, concealing personal matters, seeking benefits for others and accepting property during the selection and appointment of cadres; selfish desires and profit-seeking, long-term illegal acceptance of gifts and money, illegally engaged in profit-making activities, and many A private business owner lends money to obtain large returns and engages in power, sex, and money transactions; his life is corrupt, his family tradition is not upright, his family governance is lax, and he neglects the discipline and education of his family; he has no bottom line in discipline and law, uses public tools for private purposes, and uses power for personal gain. , colluding with unscrupulous businessmen, engaging in power and money transactions, taking advantage of his position to benefit others in business operations, project contracting, etc., and illegally receiving huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Yulin seriously violated the Party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and being suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Party. His nature It is serious and has a bad impact and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Luo Yulin from the party; The treatment he enjoys shall be canceled in accordance with regulations; his illegal gains shall be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues shall be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved shall be transferred together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年中国电影总票房已突破500亿元，国产片票房占比创十年来新高]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260699]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, Nandu reporters learned from the real-time data of the Beacon Professional Edition that as of November 13, 2023 The country&#39;s annual total box office (including pre-sales) exceeded 50 billion, and the top ten box office in the current year are all domestic films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that the top ten films at the box office are all domestic films, including &quot;A River in Red&quot;, &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, &quot;Desperate&quot;, &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot;, &quot;Fengshen Part 1: Chaoge Fengyun&quot;, &quot;Eight Anise&quot; &quot;In the Cage&quot;, &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, &quot;Bear Infested·Stand with Me &quot;Bear Core&quot;&quot;, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Unfamiliar Life&quot;, these ten films all have a box office of more than 1 billion yuan. It is reported that domestic films account for 83.4% of the current annual box office, the highest in the past 10 years; imported films account for 16.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;944&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258492&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨郑永流：学法律的自豪来自两部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu, the first doctor of jurisprudence in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1957 in Macheng County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963－1974&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;went to primary school and middle school in Macheng County and Huangpi County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, studied at the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1983-1986, studied at the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law and received a Master of Laws degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1986-1989, studied at the Law Department of Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1989-1993, served as lecturer and associate professor of the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1993-1996, he served as a visiting professor at the School of Law and Economics, Saarland University, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2004, he served as Acting Professor at the Law School of the University of Freiburg, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2023, he worked at the University of Friborg in Switzerland, the University of Oslo in Norway, He has served as a short-term visiting scholar at the University of Frankfurt in Germany for many times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1997 to 2022, he served as professor at the Law School of China University of Political Science and Law and China Europe Law School. Professor, doctoral supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a distinguished doctoral supervisor at China University of Political Science and Law, legal philosophy and interdisciplinary legal research at China Europe Law School Director. He is a member of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR) and the editor-in-chief of the journal &quot;Philosophy of Law and Sociology of Law&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu (first from the right) held a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu ( First from right) giving a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For our generation, reform and opening up has brought a great turning point in our lives.” October 2023 is the most beautiful time of the year in Beijing. In the autumn season, in a teahouse near Xueyuan Road, Zheng Yongliu recalled his youthful years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1978, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to Hubei University of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law) and became a freshman in the law department. At this time, 4 years had passed since he graduated from high school. During those four years, Zheng Yongliu worked as an educated youth in the countryside and as a fisherman in the lake area. When he took the college entrance examination, he was a surveyor in the water conservancy engineering team of the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County, Hubei Province (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Born in a county town, Zheng Yongliu’s hometown did not have a university. He had never seen a university before. “Everyone yearns for a university, but they have no concept of it. They only know that a university is an ‘ivory tower’. &#39;, it&#39;s a world that you can&#39;t concretely imagine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing undergraduate and master’s degrees at Hubei University of Finance and Economics and Central South University of Political Science and Law, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to the Law Department of Peking University in 1986, where he studied under Chen Shouyi, a legal educator and one of the founders of contemporary Chinese jurisprudence. professor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, Zheng Yongliu graduated and became the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of New China. His doctoral thesis &quot;The Status and Development Path of Law in Rural Reform&quot; began to explore rural legal issues more than 30 years ago, and proposed the &quot;three-dimensional adjustment method of rural development of human ethics-law-policy&quot; and &quot;legal localization&quot;. The idea is extremely groundbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from Peking University, Zheng Yongliu taught at Central South University of Political Science and Law, Saarland University in Germany, University of Freiburg in Germany, and China University of Political Science and Law. In Zheng Yongliu’s view, “the first PhD in jurisprudence after the founding of the People’s Republic of China” was the starting point of his academic career, but it is his subsequent academic research that determines his reputation and academic status. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;This college is worth it&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From graduating from high school in 1974 to taking the college entrance examination in 1978, what were you doing in the intervening years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I graduated from high school, I was 17 years old. My classmates and I all went to the countryside to become educated youth. There was great enthusiasm at that time, and the countryside was a &quot;vast land with a lot to offer.&quot; We have all stated that we want to take root, blossom and bear fruit in the countryside and do not think about anything else. There are many lakes in Hubei. I worked as a fisherman in the countryside for two years. When fishing every day in winter, we have to get up at 5 o&#39;clock in the morning and set the net before the fish wake up. Otherwise, when the sun comes out, the fish will scatter and go out to look for food. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was transferred to the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City) as a surveyor, carrying a ruler and doing measurements everywhere. For example, when building a reservoir, it is necessary to measure the rain-bearing area, which determines the height and thickness of the reservoir dam. If the dam is built too high, it will be wasteful. If it is built too low or too thin, it will be easily washed away, so the watershed must be measured. Because we have not gone through any special study, our job is to go over mountains and ridges to place measuring rulers, trace and post pictures and other auxiliary tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You took the college entrance examination just after it resumed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In August 1977, Deng Xiaoping chaired a symposium on science and education and decided to resume the college entrance examination, which had been suspended for 11 years. At the end of 1977, each province resumed the college entrance examination with its own questions. When the exam notice was sent out, I was at a water conservancy construction site. If you don’t have time to review, you will naturally fail in taking the exam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took the college entrance examination in the second year, I had time to review by chance. At that time, a river in the county needed to be renovated, and the engineering team sent me to a cement factory in another place to purchase cement. The production environment in the cement factory was very bad. Although everyone wore masks and took other protective measures, there was a lot of dust in the factory. In May 1978, I contracted acute pleurisy. At that time, the water accumulation in my right chest was very serious, and I could even hear a &quot;gurgling&quot; sound in my chest when I breathed. A female doctor surnamed Gong said that I should be hospitalized immediately. She would use a particularly thick needle to puncture my back to my chest every day and extract about 100 ml of accumulated water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After about a week of pumping, the fluid in the chest was gone, but the inflammation was still not gone, so I could no longer go to the cement factory to purchase cement. The doctor asked me to stay in the hospital, but I said no, I had to take the college entrance examination. At that time, there were many people living in one room in the hospital, and I couldn&#39;t review. The doctor also understood. She kept me in the hospital for another three days, and then asked me to go to the hospital for injections during the day and stay at home at night. So I went to the hospital twice a day, and rested at home during the rest of the time while reviewing. In the summer of 1978, I entered college. I am very grateful to Dr. Gong. After I was admitted to college, I made a special trip to visit her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you went to college, was law your first choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, law is my second choice. When I was filling out my application form, I preferred literature. At that time, everyone had a literary dream and wanted to be a writer. At that time, the most popular liberal arts subject was what we called &quot;xianxue&quot; - &quot;literature, history and philosophy&quot;. Students with high scores were admitted to the Chinese Department, followed by the History Department and Philosophy. At that time, I applied for the History Department of Wuhan University. In 1978, the key score for liberal arts in Hubei Province was 340 points. I scored 332.3 points, which was a few points short. Later, the key line was lowered to 330 points, and my score was enough, but at that time I had been admitted to the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics, so I missed the history major. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is college life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was particularly impressed. On the first day of college, the school arranged a movie reception and showed us movies. The movie is called &quot;The Black Triangle&quot; and it&#39;s about catching spies in the north. The plot of the movie is average, but there is a song in it that shocked us very much. It was &quot;The Spring Water in the Border is Clear and Pure&quot; sung by Li Guyi. She sang this song using a new so-called breath singing method, which was completely different from the heroic and aspirational singing method popular in that era. That was the first time I realized that the song could still be sung like this. At that time, I felt: I went to the right university. I have never been exposed to these before. If I had not gone to college and lived in a small county, I might not have heard this singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;University opened up a new world for me. The end of 1978 to 1979 was a period of surging ideological trends. At that time, there were many lectures in the school, such as those of Peking University and the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. Many famous scholars came to Wuhan to give lectures and spread some new ideas, which made me even more determined: this university is worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/16/79bc830a15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 79bc830a15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;What should we do when studying law&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After going to college, are you interested in law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the first half of college, I didn’t have much feelings about law. I really became interested in this major because of movies. At that time, every Saturday, the school would show movies in the playground, and we would all watch them for free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there was an Indian movie &quot;Wanderer&quot;, which tells the story of two young people. The woman&#39;s name is Lida. She is a lawyer who represents her friend in court. Raz defended, vehemently. Lida studied law, and we immediately felt that studying law was very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, another movie was released, &quot;Tragedy on the Nile&quot;, which tells the story of a Belgian detective named Poirot who used reasoning to find the killer on the cruise ship. At that time, we felt that this was also related to the law, and we might have to do related work in the future. A classmate in the same class got the nickname &quot;Poirot&quot; because he often imitated the great detective, and his classmates still call him that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the movie, we gained some pride in studying law and felt that we should eliminate violence and bring justice to everyone. At that time, some students from other departments watched these two movies and asked to transfer to our department to study law. Of course, the theory is obscure, but everyone still has a general understanding of &quot;what we should do when studying law&quot; through film and television works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After you have the pride of studying law, you are interested in jurisprudence Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our freshman year, we mainly took public courses and also offered jurisprudence. At that time, I felt that jurisprudence was too abstract and difficult to understand, but the teacher Wang Yajin, who studied in the Soviet Union, asked me to be the class representative of jurisprudence, so I did. At that time, there were no subdivisions in the legal profession, but you might be interested in a certain subject. Some people are interested in criminal law, others are interested in civil law. I am very interested in international law. My graduation thesis is also in the direction of international law, discussing the subject status of international organizations in international law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, the school asked me to stay and teach in jurisprudence. At that time, I thought that if I wanted to stay in school to teach, I would definitely need a higher degree, so I enrolled in a graduate program at this school. Zhang Ruolong, the dean of our Central South University of Political Science and Law, is a professor of jurisprudence, so I studied jurisprudence with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still didn’t feel much about jurisprudence when I was in school, but I felt that since I was a graduate student, I should study hard. It was also at this time that I started to become interested in jurisprudence because I had invested a lot of time in it. But to truly understand and study jurisprudence, it is still at the doctoral level and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you later go to Peking University to study for a PhD in Jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because I have entered the field of jurisprudence and want to continue my studies. At that time, only Peking University in the country was able to recruit doctors of jurisprudence. My supervisor is Chen Shouyi, who is also among the first batch of liberal arts and the first doctoral supervisors in jurisprudence in the country. According to research, in November 1981, the State Council approved four scholars from Peking University: Chen Shouyi, Rui Mu (International Economic Law), Wang Tieya (International Law) and Zhang Youyu (Constitutional Law) of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences as the first batch of law doctoral supervisors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Teacher Chen was getting older, in his eighties, and needed someone to assist him. At that time, Liu Shengping was the director of the Jurisprudence Teaching and Research Office of Peking University Law Department. He was not yet sixty years old and was in the prime of life, so the specific daily work was managed by Teacher Liu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Chen is not in good health. He asks us to come to his home from time to time to talk, mainly about what is happening in the courts and procuratorates and what new problems there are. Another thing is to listen to what we think in theory. What he said the most is that we need to start from China&#39;s reality and understand more about China&#39;s reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your doctoral thesis is &quot;The Status and Development of Law in Rural Changes&quot; &quot;Road&quot;, how did you pay attention to this topic? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I entered Peking University in 1986, the topic of reform was very hot and my thoughts were very diverse. There are many various academic seminars in Beijing. After I arrived in Beijing, I also participated in these academic seminars and met some people from the China Institute of Economic Structural Reform and the Rural Development Institute of the Rural Policy Research Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. At that time, they advocated legalizing reform measures, but they were all majoring in economics and did not know how to legislate or provide legal advice, so they needed some people who studied law, so I went there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two research institutes are think tanks for reform. The Institute of Structural Reform leads urban system reform, especially enterprise restructuring; the Institute of Agricultural Research studies rural issues, including township and village enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the Physical Reform Institute first and then to the Agricultural Research Institute. At the Agricultural Research Institute, I followed them to the Fuyang Township Enterprise Reform Experimental Zone in Anhui Province for investigation and did some empirical research. At that time, there was almost no legal issue in rural areas, and there were only some policies promoted by the annual No. 1 Central Document. After conducting research with people from the Agricultural Research Institute, I felt that I had found a direction and wanted to write about rural legal construction. In 1989, I co-wrote &quot;Promoting the System through the System - An Experimental Report on the Bankruptcy System of Township Enterprises in Fuyang, Anhui Province&quot; with Qiu Chengyi of the Agricultural Research Institute, which was published in &quot;Unfinalized&quot;, an internal journal of &quot;Chinese Social Sciences&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did your experience at the Agricultural Research Institute help you write your thesis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The experience at the Agricultural Research Institute allowed me to understand and use empirical research methods instead of just deducing from theory. Scholars at the institute start from the facts, then make judgments and propose countermeasures and theories for reform. This inspired me a lot, because we used to introduce other people&#39;s theories, from theory to theory, PK was also PK between this theory and that theory. The impression given to me by the Agricultural Research Institute is that it is refreshing, and its examples are all real-life. We went there for about more than a month. We visited township enterprises and factories every day and held discussions with township cadres. This was completely different from my previous experience in college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I proposed in my paper at that time that human ethics, policies and laws should be mutually complementary and cooperative means of adjusting rural development. No one said this at that time. Everyone either only emphasized human ethics, or only emphasized policies or laws. I think these are biased, so I proposed the three-dimensional adjustment. &lt;p>; )&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;789&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu (back row, first from right) takes a photo with Chen Shouyi (front row, first from right), associate instructor Liu Shengping (front row, first from left) and classmates. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Propose a theory of practical legal philosophy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., will all your subsequent academic research be related to jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the doctoral student stage in 1988 to before going abroad in 1993, I mainly focused on empirical research and also did some investigations, including my Several colleagues from the Central South University of Political Science and Law conducted research on farmers&#39; legal awareness in Hubei and published some articles, such as &quot;Realistic Changes in China&#39;s Farmers&#39; Legal Awareness&quot; published in &quot;Chinese Law&quot; in 1992. In terms of discipline, we call it legal sociology. It should be said that in China, I was one of the first scholars to do empirical research. Later I went abroad and did not do much research at that time. On the one hand, I did not have the conditions for empirical research. On the other hand, I had a teaching assignment at the University of Saarland in Germany. I also needed to understand German law and read their laws. Research is still in the accumulation stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China in 1997, I continued to teach sociology of law courses, but my research direction has shifted to legal methods, that is, how to apply legal methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2000, in addition to paying attention to legal methods, I began to study legal philosophy. Jurisprudence and legal philosophy are the same concept, which is to answer the question &quot;What is law?&quot; It not only solves the problem of how to apply and interpret the law, but also forms a new law in the process. Later I summarized it as: law in a static sense is the 1.0 state of the law; after interpretation, the law you create yourself is the 2.0 state of the law. Later, this became my own set of legal philosophy theories. I called it practical legal philosophy because it was created in the process of legal practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The legal philosophy I mentioned today is different from traditional legal philosophy. Traditional legal philosophy is divorced from empirical research, but I proposed a new legal philosophy theory based on empirical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The theory of practical legal philosophy you proposed also partially compensated for the failure of Chinese scholars Are there any research gaps in this area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As we all know, modern legal science is the product of Western knowledge and came to China across the ocean. After more than a hundred years of &quot;apprenticeship&quot; career, Chinese legal scholars want to participate in the world&#39;s mainstream legal dialogue, and Practical Legal Philosophy is the result of such an attempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a theoretical origin point of view, practical legal philosophy continues the tradition of practical philosophy, and also absorbs practical theory, as well as the famous German legal philosopher Kaufman’s idea of ​​​​&quot;actual reality&quot;. Theoretical resources such as the &quot;third way&quot; opened up between &quot;should be&quot; and &quot;should be&quot; strive to integrate the wisdom of several major schools of modern Western legal philosophy. This is a theory that can dialogue with the mainstream of the West rather than talk to itself. It wants to provide an answer to the age-old question &quot;What is law?&quot; and make a Chinese scholar&#39;s own contribution to the world of legal philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now let me explain, what do you think jurisprudence is? What kind of subject? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core question of jurisprudence is to answer &quot;what is the law?&quot; This sounds simple to say, but is more complicated to actually study. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, doesn’t the National People’s Congress enact laws? What&#39;s so hard about this? But that&#39;s not the case. We call formulated and written laws statutory laws. In addition to statutory law, law also has other forms of expression. For example, we call the universal rules of society expressed in the form of concepts and thoughts natural law. Laws made by people do not necessarily contain these ideas, and statutory laws are not necessarily correct. For example, many laws in ancient China were autocratic and authoritarian laws; many laws enacted by Nazi Germany also contained many anti-human and unfair ideas. So natural law is needed to correct errors in statutory law, which is part of our answer to &quot;what is law?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also customary law, which is something that exists in real life and has been observed by us for generations. It also adjusts people&#39;s behavior, which also belongs to the scope of &quot;what is the law&quot;. So in terms of scope, statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all the content of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the most difficult part of studying jurisprudence is that statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all expressed in a static sense. When these concepts are related to facts, it will show Certain deficiencies and weaknesses. As Goethe said, &quot;Theory is gray, but the tree of life is evergreen.&quot; In other words, no matter what the rules are, they can never fully meet the needs of reality. In more professional terms, it is called &quot;there is an asymmetry between facts and norms.&quot; This requires us to constantly combine facts in the process of applying rules to propose our new theory about &quot;what the law is.&quot; This new theory will become binding law on specific cases, so the theory also needs to be constantly updated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We call the previous static law Law 1.0. After Law 1.0 is related to facts, it puts forward new understandings. We call it Law 2.0. Legislation and law amendment can also be regarded as this process, but the procedures for legislation and law amendment are slow and complicated. If a new type of case arises, we cannot wait for the law to be revised before deciding. Therefore, when the existing legal norms are not symmetrical to the facts, we need to judicially interpret the norms. On what basis do you base your explanation? You have to put forward your own theories and opinions in order to explain it reasonably. So at this time, jurisprudence plays a big role. In this sense, although jurisprudence sounds very theoretical, it is also highly practical, so jurisprudence is also a required course for law majors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zheng Yongliu during his study tour at the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/b12ad55cd6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b12ad55cd6 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu while visiting the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The combination of &quot;accidental&quot; and &quot;inevitable&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Does the label &quot;the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; have a big impact on your future life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Judging from the time I got my degree, I am the first doctor of jurisprudence in the country. But when we entered school, there were actually two of us. The other one was my junior sister, and she delayed her graduation by one year. For many years after I graduated, I would not consciously mention it. It’s only in the last five or six years that some people started posting this on social media, and more people followed it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tag does not bring me much added value. Of course, my doctoral thesis is the starting point of my academic work. It can also be said that it established my academic confidence. Later, more people paid attention to me, not just because of this paper, but because I later published a series of research results in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I publish the magazine of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR), which is also the top international publication in the field of legal philosophy, &quot;Transactions on Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy&quot; Three papers were published on Archives for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy, one of which was &quot;On the Practical Philosophy of Law&quot; published in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at your study experience now, I feel that many important choices were An accidental result? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it wasn’t because of illness, I wouldn’t have time to review, and maybe I wouldn’t be able to get into college; if I had successfully become a navy when I was a fisherman , I would not have been admitted to university; if I had studied history in university, I would not have become a doctor of jurisprudence. For example, when I graduated from college, I wanted to engage in practice. At that time, many of my classmates went to work in government agencies, but the school allowed me to stay in school. I originally liked international law, but was assigned to teach jurisprudence. Later, I went abroad, and my first choice was to go to the United States. The University of Wisconsin, a stronghold of legal sociology, accidentally ended up at Saarland University, which ranks among the top universities in legal philosophy in Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is true that there are too many accidents, and there are also inevitable consequences among too many accidents. It is impossible to say for sure. But going to college really opened a window for me to see a bigger world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you were asked to send a message to current college students, what would you do? explain? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes students come to ask me, and I say that I really can’t say anything good, so it’s better not to say it. I am also telling myself now not to educate students or ask them to do what they want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I have to say something, this is not a message. I always emphasize that everyone, not just students, must have their own independent thoughts and not blindly follow fads and mainstream trends. Freedom of thought is the most worthy pursuit. I usually don&#39;t write these things for students, but sometimes when I say goodbye to students, they insist on asking me to write something. I once wrote this sentence: &quot;Tranquility leads to freedom, and freedom leads to scholarship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悔婚拒退彩礼引发血案：当从悲剧中吸取教训丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Surveillance video circulated online shows that at 13:38 on November 11, two people were killed in a mahjong parlor in Liangshan, Sichuan. A woman playing mahjong was killed by two men with knives. According to media reports, insiders revealed that a knife-wielding man and a woman who was hacked were originally lovers and had paid a bride price of 300,000 yuan, but the woman regretted the marriage and was only willing to return 150,000 yuan. The two men are father and son, and the other woman is related to the woman who regretted her marriage. The next day, local police stated that the two assailants were controlled by the police on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tragedy sparked a lot of discussion. A mother said: &quot;Ever since my daughter entered the society, I have taught her that it is OK to fall in love, but you cannot use other people&#39;s money. You are not allowed to accept money or transfers from others!&quot; Some netizens said: &quot;You can go to the court to sue and demand She would not go to this step to return the gift.&quot; However, someone immediately appeared to give their own testimony or quoted the news to prove how difficult it is to return the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nature of betrothal gifts is different from the betrothal gifts in traditional society. There is a wedding ceremony of a scholar in &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Scholars were the lowest class nobles; there were six rites for marrying a wife, which were nacai, asking for name, naji, nazheng, asking for date and personally welcoming. Nazheng was the betrothal gift. This set of common people was imitated and integrated into traditional marriage customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gift is a &quot;new custom&quot; that has emerged in recent years. What is worrying is that betrothal gifts are becoming more and more popular. Not only are the prices getting higher and higher, but there is also a trend of generalization. Betrothal gifts were not available in some places, but now they are beginning to be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current legal definition of bride price is &quot;a gift for the purpose of marriage.&quot; The biggest problem caused by this characterization is that it has given rise to the stereotype that &quot;getting married is starting a business and getting divorced is getting rich&quot;. Some women disappear immediately after taking the bride price, or after receiving the marriage certificate, they refuse to live with the man, and then ask for a divorce in order to keep the high-priced bride price as their own. When more such incidents occur, social problems arise, and the judicial system has no choice but to add some patches to this characterization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Court’s Interpretation on the Application of the Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code of the People’s Republic of China (1) Article 5 stipulates: If a party requests the return of a betrothal gift paid in accordance with customs, if it is found that it falls under the following circumstances, the People’s Court It should be supported: (1) Both parties have not completed the marriage registration procedures; (2) Both parties have completed the marriage registration procedures but have not lived together; (3) Pre-marriage payments have caused difficulties in the payer&#39;s life. The application of the provisions of the second and third items of the preceding paragraph shall be conditional on the divorce of both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In judicial practice, some courts will use their discretion to determine whether and how much the bride price should be refunded based on the length of the marriage. Mastering the stick, but aiming for the yard. Some women have come up with some tricks: maintain the marriage for one year and then file for divorce, so that the probability of the court ruling to return the bride price is very small; install cameras at home, refuse to live as a couple, and use various methods to anger the man and induce him to take action. Photographing it will be evidence of domestic violence, so that the court will justifiably support the woman&#39;s various demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, a man in Zhumadian, Henan Province released a video saying that his wife had domestically abused him and set a fire indoors. The incident occurred at around two o&#39;clock in the morning on June 16, 2023. The video shows: the man was robbed of his mobile phone and was slapped by the woman without fighting back; the woman set fires in many places in the house, and the flames were visible on the sofa, dining table and kitchen trash can, and the man followed and doused them one by one. The man said that he had spent all his parents’ savings in order to get married, spending a total of nearly 200,000 yuan including 100,000 yuan in betrothal gifts. Now, after only four months of marriage, the woman is about to get divorced. “Tell me to get out of here, just a penny of betrothal gifts.” Neither will retreat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, recently, the Henan Provincial High Court concluded a divorce dispute case. In March 2022, the man Xiao Yijing introduced him to the woman Xiaoshuang. In May of the same year, the two registered their marriage; in July of the same year, Xiaoshuang announced that she was pregnant and had an abortion that month due to fetal abnormalities. Subsequently, Xiaoshuang sued for divorce, and Xiaoya agreed to the divorce, but countersued for the return of the 186,000 yuan gift. In both the first instance and the second instance, the court ruled that the parties were divorced, but did not support the request for return of the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoya was dissatisfied and applied for retrial. After the retrial, the court found that: In the original trial, Xiaoya claimed that Xiaoshuang used the name of marriage to obtain property, and said that after the lawsuit, it was found that Xiaoshuang had married 6 men before getting married, and all of them got pregnant and had abortions within a short period of time after the marriage and then divorced. , and all received expensive betrothal gifts. The court held that the bride price was paid for the purpose of getting married, starting a family, and living together for a long time. Otherwise, it would violate the true intention of the party who paid the bride price and should be returned. However, it only awarded a refund of 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you get married once or twice, get pregnant for a short period of time, have an abortion, and get divorced, it may be true; if you repeat this routine seven times in a row, the possibility of it being true is very slim. The woman was probably trying to get the bride price by defrauding her, and the purpose was to establish evidence of living together. But even so, the 186,000 betrothal gifts received for the seventh marriage can still keep 86,000, and the &quot;profit rate&quot; is too high; plus the betrothal gifts received for the first six times, I am afraid it will easily make a profit of one million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, we can have a more profound analysis of why the Liangshan tragedy occurred. Liangshan is a very poor place in Sichuan. After receiving a bride price of 300,000 yuan, only 150,000 yuan was returned. For the father and son, it was equivalent to taking away their entire lives. Moreover, if you really go to court to sue, the court may not order a full refund; even if it orders a full refund, the woman may not fulfill it: currently, more than 10,000 people have been executed for breach of trust due to disputes over betrothal gifts. After the tragedy, the two perpetrators will also pay a heavy price for their actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gifts are something with inherent contradictions: those who can afford the betrothal gifts often do not need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married; on the contrary, only families that cannot afford a betrothal gift or have a difficult time need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married. Moreover, it is a high-priced betrothal gift. In order to afford the betrothal gift, such families often have to live frugally, borrow here and there, and even take out loan sharks. If the latter encounters the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; scheme in order to defraud the bride price, it will be difficult to accept it, and they may resort to extreme measures, causing irreparable consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When facing disputes over betrothal gifts, you should resolve them through reasonable and legal means and safeguard your rights and interests in accordance with the law. However, while pondering the aforementioned tragedy, it is also necessary to reflect on the legal characterization of bride price. The judiciary cannot encourage the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; routine. When only money belongs to money and property belongs to property, marriage can belong to marriage. If marriage becomes a tool for wealth redistribution, it will inspire and encourage the evil of human nature, which will not only harm marriage, but also property, and cause various undesirable things. Tragedy will happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province A fire broke out in the building around 6:50 a.m. today (16th). As of press time, 11 people have been confirmed dead, and the specific casualties are still being counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the situation at the scene, the burning building has 4 floors. A total of 63 people have been evacuated so far, 51 of whom were sent to Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. The rescue is still in progress and the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When talking about chimpanzees, our close relatives, we cannot fail to mention British biologists, animal behaviorists and famous animal conservationists. Jane Goodall is a person who studied chimpanzees, but the “grandmother hypothesis” in this article is not based on Goodall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary film &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot; shot by the BBC and Goodall&#39;s book &quot;The Book of Hope: Jane Goodall on Human Survival, Future and Action&quot; give people a deeper understanding of Learn about chimpanzees and how they live like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 38 years of living with chimpanzees, Goodall discovered that chimpanzees can use tools (putting plant stems into ant nests to detect, using tree sticks to reach into the water to retrieve food), and they can also Making tools (removing leaves from plant stems) breaks the long-held belief that only humans can make tools. At the same time, chimpanzees will also form teams to hunt other small mammals, and wars will occur between different groups of chimpanzees, and weapons will be used in the battles. There are also some chimpanzees that attack and kill their own kind, sometimes just for fun. Chimpanzee society also has a strict hierarchical system. Each chimpanzee has its own status in society. Their overt and covert fights for social status are no less than that of humans. These findings also break the previous belief that war and cannibalism are uniquely human behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to Goodall, other researchers have studied chimpanzees and found that chimpanzees also have a &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model similar to humans, but this model in chimpanzees is much weaker. The &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; means that healthy and surviving grandmothers and grandfathers can help take care of their grandchildren, increase their survival rate, and thus help their children have more children. This health effect, in turn, ensures the inheritance of your grandmother’s longevity genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the University of California, Santa Barbara, compared three groups of chimpanzees, hunter-gatherers, and horticultural producers and found that people’s production contributions in old age also exist, and are far greater. Higher than chimpanzees. Chimpanzees can have a 20% food or material surplus in their gathering and production capacity at age 30, 7% at age 40, and only 2% at age 50. But hunter-gatherers have a production surplus of 66% at age 30, 45% at age 40, and 24% at age 50. A horticultural producer&#39;s production surplus is 64% at age 30, 40% at age 40, and 21% at age 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this comparison, we can know that after chimpanzees enter old age, their production capacity drops significantly, and their ability to help their families and grandchildren also drops off a cliff. Therefore, even if chimpanzees have the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model, its effect is limited. Not big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, a new study completely rejects the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model in chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A team composed of research institutions such as Arizona State University in the United States, the University of California, Los Angeles, and the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in Germany studied the Ngo in Kibale National Park in western Uganda. A 20-year study of the wild chimpanzee community in Ngogo found that female chimpanzees in the community will survive menopause and childbirth, but they will not help their daughters raise grandchildren when they enter old age, nor will they live in nearby. Therefore, chimpanzees do not have a social system supported by grandparents, that is, there is no &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model. But Ngogo&#39;s female chimpanzees still live beyond their reproductive years and beyond, even to old age alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no survival problem in old age for chimpanzees in captivity because humans will provide them with good food, nutrition and medical care. However, chimpanzees in the wild will not be so lucky. Survival mode is more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To study the lifestyle and survival patterns of chimpanzees in the wild, researchers from the joint research team studied 185 female chimpanzees from group statistics collected from 1995 to 2016. Mortality and fertility rates, the proportion of time the observed female chimpanzees spent in sterilization as adults was calculated, and hormone levels were measured in urine samples from 66 female chimpanzees. The female chimpanzees varied in reproductive and sterilization status, survival and age, ranging from 14 to 67 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research process was very arduous, lasting decades and thousands of hours of fieldwork in Ngogo before collecting chimpanzee urine samples to study menopausal hormone levels. . Hormone studies in chimpanzee urine are similar to those in humans, monitoring changes in levels of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH), as well as ovarian steroid hormones including estrogen and progesterone. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These hormonal changes can determine whether chimpanzees have entered menopause. The estrogen levels of human menopausal women are below 100pmol/L, and the progesterone levels are below 2.2nmol/L. By comparing them with female chimpanzees, we can know whether they are menopausal and have entered menopause (sterilization state). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that, like other groups of chimpanzees and humans, the chimpanzees they studied lost fertility after age 30 and became infertile after age 50. Meanwhile, some data collected on hormone levels in chimpanzees show that menopause in Ngogo female chimpanzees is similar to that in humans, starting around age 50. Female chimpanzees reach adulthood at the age of 14, and spend about one-fifth of their adult life in the sterilization period, which is about half of the sterilization period of humans. That is, the old age of chimpanzees after entering menopause is only half of that of humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Menopause for chimpanzees means the beginning of old age, but Ngogo female chimpanzees can live over 50 years old even if they do not take care of their grandchildren and do not live with their children. Chimpanzees are prone to death from diseases originating from humans and have little natural immunity to these diseases, so living over 50 years is considered a long life, and living to 67 years is considered a long life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can Ngogo&#39;s chimpanzees survive into old age without the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model? The answer suggested by the study is that their post-neuter lifespan may be a temporary response to extremely favorable ecological conditions, as the group enjoys a stable and abundant food supply and they are isolated from human-induced stress. Survive longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some researchers such as primatologist Susan Alberts of Duke University in the United States doubt this result because not all chimpanzees will go through menopause. Alberts believes that in most chimpanzee populations outside the Ngogo group, adult females live to be around 30 years old because they are stressed by predators, disease or other factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Alberts admitted that the study&#39;s results were so solid that she couldn&#39;t refute them. But she believes the next step should be to conduct similar long-term studies in larger populations of wild chimpanzees to determine whether Ngogo chimpanzees are unique in that they survive longer beyond their reproductive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[螺蛳粉疯狂布局线下门店，能否成为下一个兰州拉面？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since this year, snail noodle restaurant stores have grown rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiao Lu, a netizen who lives in Guangzhou, said that several snail noodle stores have recently opened in the business district near her home, many of which are chain stores of a certain snail noodle brand. ——This has aroused the curiosity of many netizens: Has snail noodles also begun to focus on offline stores? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the characteristics of &quot;smells bad, tastes delicious, and is very popular&quot;, snail noodles have become a popular Internet celebrity food in just a few years. The sales volume of the channel remains high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with its popularity online, the offline development of snail noodles has obvious shortcomings. What kind of distinction does the online and offline development of snail noodles show? How can snail noodles achieve offline breakthrough? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Hot online sales&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Snail noodles originated from the Liuzhou Night Market in the 1970s. It gradually became popular in the 1980s, but it was mainly limited to the local area, and then slowly spread to all of Guangxi and the neighboring Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, &quot;A Bite of China&quot; brought snail fans more into the public eye, but for people outside the Guangdong and Guangxi regions, it is still only As the name suggests, Luosifeng’s offline stores have not expanded too much to other provinces, and there are no online sales channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2014, Liuzhou’s first prepackaged snail noodle company was registered, and industrially produced bagged snail noodle appeared. At the beginning of 2015, the Liuzhou Municipal Government proposed the development concept of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles, and determined the road for Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles industry to be packaged and industrialized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016 is the first year of live broadcasting. Luosi fans have keenly grasped the trend of the times and jumped on the &quot;Internet +&quot; short video and live broadcast express. The characteristics of &quot;smellful and smelly&quot; are quite contagious and quickly spread out of the circle through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the industry output value of Liuzhou&#39;s bagged snail noodles exceeded 6 billion yuan. The impact of the epidemic, the rise of the &quot;stay-at-home economy&quot;, and the booming live-streaming of goods have boosted the online popularity of snail noodles. In 2020, the annual output value of bagged snail noodles exceeded 10 billion. In 2022, the sales revenue of the entire industry chain of Liuzhou snail noodles will be 60.07 billion yuan, and the sales revenue of bagged snail noodles will be 18.18 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Naturally, the online sales of snail noodles account for half of the total. According to iiMedia Research’s research data, among the channels through which Chinese snail noodle consumers purchase products, online shopping malls rank first with a proportion of 78.70%. Other data show that in 2022, 113 million snail noodle packages were sent through express delivery channels, becoming the first single product in Guangxi with an annual delivery volume exceeding 100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The popularity of snail noodles online is not only due to its close integration with &quot;Internet +&quot;, but also because it fits the &quot;fast food life&quot; of this generation of young people. The characteristics of the food require that the food should not only be convenient and efficient, but also sufficient and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Other instant noodles have few ingredients. Snail noodles are rich in ingredients, including yuba, pickled bamboo shoots, pickled beans, fungus, peanuts, dried radish and other common accessories. Bao snail rice noodles have everything, and they are more attractive to young people’s stomachs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Offline stores have shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with the popularity of online stores, offline stores of snail noodles have obvious shortcomings. plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, there are now more than 40,000 offline stores of snail noodles. Compared with the approximately 500,000 offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen, It&#39;s like a small witch can see a big witch. Not to mention, the annual sales of Lanzhou Ramen are roughly estimated to exceed 400 billion yuan, which is several times that of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, relevant data shows that the average offline catering chain rate of snail noodles is only 15%, compared with 45% for tea drinks. Coffee is 55%, which shows that there is no strong enough brand of snail noodles to go offline, and the risk of &quot;having a category but not a brand&quot; has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only that, there are also some worrying aspects regarding the existing offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the offline stores of snail noodles are mainly concentrated in Guangxi and Guangdong, and the national penetration rate is still relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, iiMedia Consulting data shows that from 2020 to February 2023, most of the new snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong and Guangxi, and the proportion of snail noodle companies in Guangxi is as high as 21.63% and 21.21% of snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong Province. This is much weaker than the national radiation intensity of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, due to the low chain rate, many offline snail noodle stores are small &quot;mom-and-pop&quot;-style workshops with varying tastes and quality, and individual stores are hygienic. The worrying situation has lowered consumers’ trust in offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, rumors spread widely that &quot;there were many mice jumping up and down in the back kitchen of a snail noodle shop in Chongqing&quot;. Although the Municipal Supervision Bureau of Jiulongpo District, Chongqing made a report stating that law enforcement officers did an on-site inspection and found no traces of rats in the snail noodle shop; the video was taken in March this year, because the decoration of the shop next door damaged the flue outlet of the shop, causing rats to enter After discovering the situation in the back kitchen, the person in charge of the store immediately carried out disinfection and repairs and rectifications in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Such rumors have done great harm to the offline stores of Luosi Fen, and also reflect the public&#39;s concerns about food safety issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirdly, offline snail noodles stores only offer a single variety of food, and relying solely on snail noodles will limit the development of offline stores. For example, Lanzhou Ramen Shop not only offers ramen noodles, but also Northwest-style pasta products such as rice bowls, steamed buns, and cold noodles; Shaxian snacks include mixed noodles, steamed dumplings, flat dishes, duck leg rice, and other choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The snail noodles&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;stand out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, compared with the offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks, Sloan noodles are blooming everywhere, and offline stores of snail noodles still have broad room for expansion, but this does not mean that snail noodles should &quot;underestimate themselves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, compared with Lanzhou Ramen, the development route of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of snail noodles is earlier and more mature. There are many ramen noodle restaurants in Lanzhou, but they are also faced with the embarrassment of &quot;having categories but not brands&quot;. This is a shortcoming that Lanzhou ramen is now making great efforts to make up for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To successfully break through, snail powder offline stores must, on the one hand, give full play to the advantages of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; and transform the current few stores into The snail noodle brand continues to grow bigger and stronger, and the chain layout is accelerated. It is necessary to establish both the category and the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, efforts should be made to industrialize the supply chain and build a professional, platform-based supply chain service provider to fill the gap in the snail noodle supply chain business. Blank, so that even small workshop-style snail noodle stores can obtain stable quality snail noodle raw materials, so that consumers can taste snail noodle with stable taste and stabilize the reputation of offline snail noodle stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, as a regional delicacy, if snail noodles want to conquer the stomachs of people across the country, in addition to making authentic snail noodles, we also need to enrich the line. The gourmet food category in the lower store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​way is to focus on snail noodles but also sell other local delicacies from Liuzhou and even Guangxi to enrich consumers&#39; choice space, such as some from Liuzhou Local delicacies, such as Yong Tau Foo Pao, Niu Xianzi, Yun Pian Cake, Miao Sour Pork, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another way is to combine it with local cuisine and move toward integration, launching cross-category meals, stir-fries, soups, etc. This kind of integration poses a very big challenge to the management of chain brands, which must not only ensure standardization, but also successfully &quot;do as the Romans do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although snail noodles have fully opened up the online space, if snail noodles want to continue to break through the upper limit of the industry, they must walk both online and offline. Luosifen offline stores are accelerating the layout. Whether it can create miracles like online stores is worth waiting to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子？社会学家山田昌弘谈日本低生育困境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1559&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6I gnwi5oPp. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese sociologist Yamada Masahiro, professor at Chuo University, specializes in family sociology and emotional society Xuexue, etc., are the authors of &quot;Society with a Few Births&quot;, &quot;The Era of Marriage&quot;, &quot;The Low-Birth Trap&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Masahiro Yamada, a professor at Chuo University in Japan, has been deeply involved in the field of family sociology for many years. Before high school, he once wanted to be a mathematician, but &quot;because I don&#39;t have a family of my own, I decided to explore what family love is&quot; and since then entered the &quot;world of studying messy families.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When teaching in school, he used a lot of family materials to tell the origin, current situation and whereabouts of modern Japanese families. The seminars he held with students were on cutting-edge topics and discussed issues such as: To what extent do people need to &quot;rent friends&quot; when they are lonely? Does &quot;cohabiting partnership marriage&quot; (note: only cohabitation without marriage) explore another possibility beyond the current marriage system? There are more and more single young people in Japan. Where can their emotional needs for intimacy be met? He finally found some answers in cabaret clubs (note: places that provide singing and dancing performances), real or virtual idols, and pets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot;, Masahiro Yamada tries to answer a question: Why are young people in Japan reluctant to have children in recent years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low fertility rate has always been a dark cloud lingering over Japanese society. Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate remaining below 1.6 for more than 30 years. In 2022, it reached a historical low of 1.26. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate below 1.6 for more than 30 years, and it reached a historical low of 1.26 in 2022 . The picture shows a still from the Japanese drama &quot;Obstetrician Kotori&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past thirty years, Japanese society has tried to solve this &quot;stubborn disease&quot;, but with little success. Yamada Masahiro was a member of the Committee on Countermeasures against Birthrate Reduction. Once, a committee member proposed holding a publicity campaign titled &quot;Parenting is Wonderful&quot; to increase the public&#39;s enthusiasm for childbirth. &quot;Many insightful people and policy leaders in Japanese society have ignored for a long time two important factors directly related to the cause of Japan&#39;s declining birthrate, namely &#39;non-marriage&#39; and &#39;the widening gap in the economic level of young people&#39; .&quot; Yamada believes, &quot;For the majority of people who &#39;want to have children but do not have the conditions, so they do not have children&#39;, it is meaningless to carry out such publicity activities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view , young people’s desire to have children is linked to the overall economic status of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1955, the Japanese economy entered a period of rapid growth. The prosperous economic environment gave rise to young people&#39;s positive expectations for the future. They tended to believe that through personal efforts, they could join the &quot;middle class&quot; and live a better life than their parents. A better, richer life. &quot;From World War II to about 1980, people did not think about the great risks in their economic life after marriage. At that time, men could count on becoming full-time employees, and their income would be based on the &#39;seniority system&#39; (note: wages will vary according to merit). (increasing with age and length of service).&quot; In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view, people of that generation firmly believed that their children would grow up in a better environment than themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, the situation reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Entering the Heisei Era (Note: January 8, 1989), Japan&#39;s economic structure was adjusted, and a large number of informal employees (referring to fixed-term employees, part-time employees, dispatched employees, etc.) appeared. Social gaps have arisen in terms of employment, which in turn has led to gaps between the rich and poor families and the educational environment of their children, and the polarization of society has further developed.&quot; Masahiro Yamada said in an interview with Japanese media, &quot;For most informal employees, regardless of whether No matter how hard I try, I can&#39;t earn the income that will allow me to live a prosperous life in the future, nor can I get married and start a family. In other words, my future has become hopeless.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada observed, The Japanese pay more attention to the significance of marriage from an economic perspective and will make a careful risk assessment before making a decision to get married. The evaluation often starts from two perspectives: first, whether the standard of living after marriage will be better than before marriage, or at least not worse; second, whether after marriage, the child can create a better growth environment than oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Behind this view on marriage and childbearing are the unique values ​​of modern Japanese society: the hope to avoid risks in future life. The Japanese regard maintaining a middle-class living standard as their highest goal and believe that in life design, The series of issues of &#39;men and women dating&#39;, &#39;marriage&#39;, &#39;childbirth&#39;, &#39;child rearing&#39; and &#39;children&#39;s education&#39; are not single and separated, but are intertwined.&quot; Yamada Masahiro in the paper &quot;East Asian Characteristics of the Declining Birth Rate Problem&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This awareness of risk also extends to the relationship stage. Yamada found that in Japan, many young people are even losing their desire to fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHK Broadcasting Culture Research Institute once conducted a survey of Japanese middle and high school students and found that the proportions of middle and high school students who &quot;have a crush&quot; were 41% and 54% respectively in 1982. In 2012, this figure dropped sharply to 25% and 31%. In 2014, the Japanese Cabinet Office conducted a survey on young people and found that more than one-third of the respondents preferred to spend time on work and study, and 46.2% felt that &quot;love is troublesome.&quot; In Yamada Masahiro’s view, “trouble” may mean “not cost-effective”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, when the phenomenon of declining birthrate first appeared in Japanese society, demographers held a mainstream view: young people just postponed marriage to enjoy single life, and one day they would get married. . Masahiro Yamada believes that such a logical basis may not be established. Over the past few decades, as Japanese society has gradually developed into a &quot;high-consumption society&quot;, the anxiety and pressure of childcare has also hit young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In December 2022, on the streets of Tokyo, Japan, a couple took wedding photos on the streets hung with Christmas lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China Map/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Japan’s National Institute of Social Security and Population Issues conducted a survey on 30 -Why married women in the 34-year-old age group fail to have the expected number of children? 81.1% of the survey respondents believe that the reason is that &quot;the raising and education of children is too expensive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada’s view, modern society’s expectations for the function of marriage and childbearing are different from pre-modern society. In a society centered on agricultural production, childbirth means supplementing the labor force. Parents place expectations on their children to inherit the family business and take care of their parents later in life. Children are a kind of &quot;productive property.&quot; But after the 1950s, Japan began to &quot;nuclear family&quot; with reference to the family system in Europe and the United States. A couple and their unmarried children became the basic family unit. In modern society, raising children requires a large amount of childcare money, and children have therefore become &quot;consumable property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The significance of children as a labor force no longer exists, and when the nuclear family becomes a principle, it is difficult to expect children to provide support and care in their old age. In addition, parents who can let their children inherit the family business It has also become less.&quot; Yamada Masahiro wrote in &quot;The Low Birth Trap&quot; that unlike European and American parents who enjoy the joy and fun of parenting itself, many times, East Asian parents care about whether to have a &quot;high-value&quot; child—— In the social evaluation system established by external factors such as academic qualifications and work, whether children can take the top spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada believes that East Asian parents often have a &quot;protective feeling&quot; for their children and do not want their children to &quot;live a hard life&quot;. It is also part of the value of parents for children to receive help from their parents when they receive higher education and even become adults. . As a result, the age of responsibility of East Asian parents for their children has been extended indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Japanese sociologist Masahiro Yamada accepted a written interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;East Asian parents take it for granted that they spend money on their children&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;China&#39;s total fertility rate fell to 1.09 in 2022, which is lower than Japan&#39;s 1.26 and higher than South Korea&#39;s 0.78. In 2022, the total fertility rate of the three East Asian countries dropped to historical lows. You have done a lot of research on fertility wishes in Japan. Why are young people reluctant to have children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In East Asia (China, Japan and South Korea), marriage and childcare are first considered from an economic perspective. When people raise children, they will want to spend more money on their children than their parents raised themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past (50 years ago in Japan and 30 years ago in China and South Korea), the lives of most young people’s parents and the lives of young people themselves were relatively poor. And since society as a whole is in a period of economic growth, young people&#39;s future income can be expected to increase. So, at that time, it would be easier, and in fact it was, to spend more money on your own children than your own parents had raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, starting 30 years ago in Japan and 10 years ago in China and South Korea, the children of the previous generation whose parents spent more money to raise them now have to spend money to raise their own children. These young people often have parents who are wealthier than themselves. In China, due to the large number of only children, the cost of this generation of only children is estimated to be more than twice that of Japan and South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在经济增长趋缓的情况下，想要在未来出生的孩子身上花费更多的钱，是非常困难的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;东亚社会家庭现代化的过程，是模仿学习欧美核心家庭的过程，同样的社会模型，为何东亚国家现阶段面对的生育困境比欧美社会更加剧烈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚国家模仿的只是核心家庭的模式，但因为不同的社会环境和传统，这些模式得到的反馈自然也不同。例如，东亚的父母更多地认为给孩子花钱是理所当然的，也能带来很多情绪价值；比起夫妻之爱，更相信亲子之爱。这也导致如果不打算生孩子的话，结婚的必要性就大幅下降了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美认为养育孩子到成年为止，而东亚各国则认为负担孩子的高等教育费用是理所当然的。相比之下，东亚国家的父母要承担更多的育儿责任，甚至在孩子成年后，也经常需要帮助解决孩子遇到的各种问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;过去几年，中国政府出台了一些鼓励生育的政策，比如三孩政策、多地提出建立育儿补贴制度等。你在《低生育陷阱》里说，日本政府没能赶上干预低生育的最好时机，日本的少子化政策因此失败了。日本经验能给其他国家带来哪些教训和启示？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;必须考虑减轻孩子的教育费负担。有四分之一的年轻人对未来感到不安，是日本少子化的主要原因。要采取让年轻人不会对未来过不上富裕生活而感到不安的措施。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要将我们的社会改造成一个无论哪个年轻人都有希望将来能够不让自己的孩子受苦的社会。即，建立一个工作可以重新再来、对双职工家庭同样友好，以及万一出了问题也可以通过社会保障重新自立的社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;能否结合你自己和你的上一代、下一代的经历，谈谈日本年轻人婚育处境和观念的变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;观念本身并没有太大的变化。如果有过上相对好的生活的预期，那就自然会结婚生子。区别可能在于，上一代的人会认为，仅靠丈夫的收入就能过上富裕的生活（大概30年前）。即便在今天，那些能够达到预期的将近四分之三的年轻人也都已经结婚生子，而剩下四分之一的年轻人之所以不选择结婚生子，大多也是因为自身收入不稳定，以及无法预期在结婚生子后能过上相对好的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;婚育事关体面？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提出了一个观点：等待适合自己的对象出现然后结婚，这种从前被普遍接受的想法，如今很难把人领入婚姻。今天的年轻人如果想结婚，需要参加“婚活”（注：寻求结婚对象的各种活动，由山田昌弘首次提出），为何会有这样的变化？难道不参加婚活，就无法结婚了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为让年轻人可以自然相互邂逅的场所变少了。不说男性，就连女性所谓的“即便自己不主动，男性也会主动搭讪”的状况都变少了。不得不由社区或者企业提供一些机会，让年轻男女可以有更多的接触。如果想要找到结婚对象，还是应该积极采取行动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“婚活”在中国叫做相亲。对于中国1970、1980年代出生的人来说，自由恋爱结婚在他们年轻时是普遍的婚恋观，但在如今的年轻人中，门当户对的观念正在被重提。日本社会是否有类似的婚姻观念变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在日本，“先恋爱后结婚”的意识并没有改变。年轻人对恋爱结婚的憧憬和讨厌父母干涉自由恋爱的意识还是比较强烈的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然没有那么在意对象的家庭背景，但婚后的经济生活，即婚后夫妻两人的整体家庭收入是很重要的参考因素。现在的年轻人“中流”意识十分强烈，他们大多觉得在父母身边时处于一种中流的生活状态，因而非常不希望婚后生活会从中流跌落，这也是习惯“规避风险”和“重视体面”的日本社会特征的反映。不过日本没有像中国那样，结婚时男方家庭需要出很多钱的习俗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你似乎非常强调在经济层面上分析婚姻、生育的动机。你提到，在欧美社会，人们将构建家庭（结婚、生子）与经济状况联系在一起的想法并不强烈，但在东亚社会不是，为何东亚社会如此强调这两者之间的关联性？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚人更看重体面，也就是中文里的“面子”。人们不想让别人看到自己过着不幸福的婚姻生活，或有着较差的育儿水平。过着贫穷的生活会有很强的耻辱意识。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，夫妻之间的爱情才是幸福的表现，生活贫穷也可以幸福的意识很普及；而在东亚社会里，即使没有夫妻间的爱情，过着富裕的生活也可能是很幸福的，这种意识十分强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一种观点认为，现代家庭“男主外，女主内”的分工意味着女性要为育儿付出更多的时间和精力，你怎样看待这个现实问题？日本社会对此有何对策？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;女性拥有一定的收入并持续工作，正在逐渐成为富裕家庭生活的前提。既然能够做到“男主外，女主内”的高收入男性人数有限，那么为了在富裕的生活条件下养育孩子，女性外出工作和男性参与家务就变得十分必要了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，通过普及产假和完善幼儿园的建设，这一理想正逐渐变得现实起来。不过日本政府对女性工作与育儿的“两立支援”也显然还远远不够，后续仍需要继续完善工作环境，消除性别歧视，并让更多的女性从事有意义的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;培养“高价值”的孩子，一种扭曲的期待&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，日本年轻人抱有一种“不能让孩子受苦”的想法，这种想法在中国年轻人当中也存在，为什么年轻人会对哺育下一代产生如此强烈的责任意识？ “受苦”的意涵是否随着时代的发展也在发生变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在东亚社会里，让子女接受比自己更好的教育，找到比自己更好的工作，是父母的生活意义所在。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，孩子之间的歧视意识也很强，现如今的年轻人会担心自己的贫穷会让孩子受到欺负。孩子们在一起玩耍的时候，有时也会需求类似Switch游戏机这样的外部硬件。如果不买这些东西，会不会让孩子感到痛苦？年轻父母的这种想法正越来越强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前只要父母能够陪在孩子身边就足够了，但现在越来越多的父母觉得，不能在孩子身上花费足够的金钱会很难受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在中国，未婚适龄男女可能会遭到父母和长辈的催婚，被称为光棍、剩女，带有一定贬义。日本有类似情况吗？你如何理解这种现象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;单身=不受欢迎，这一等式会让人间接联想到，没进入婚姻是不是因为男性收入低，或者是不是因为女性的容貌有问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，因为未婚率高得非常明显，想结婚却做不到的人，和能做到但不想结婚的人都混杂在一起，因而单纯对于未婚者的贬低并不常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样由于未婚率非常高，来自父母的压力已经要比以前小很多了。很多父母会认为，与其让孩子和收入低的人结婚，然后过上不太理想的贫困生活，还不如独身在家。在日本，越来越多的父母认为，与其被奇怪的结婚对象缠住，还不如让孩子保持单身。继承家业的意识在日本正逐渐淡薄（现在70岁以上的人仍然有很强烈的这种意识）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，在前现代社会，子女是一种“生产性财产”，进入现代社会则变为“消费性财产”，需要投入较高的育儿金，拥有一个“高价值感”的孩子成为育儿行为追求的价值，而高价值感由孩子的学历、工作的光鲜程度等因素决定。为什么父母对育儿会有这样的期待？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;孩子的地位=父母的地位，东亚文化圈的这种关乎面子或虚荣心的意识很强烈。从感情上看，这源于父母希望子女在经济上能过着无忧无虑的生活。虽然初心是好的，但随着体面意识带来的比较心理，培养高价值的孩子也就成了一种扭曲的期待。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美的传统则有很大的不同，孩子成年后不再在经济上依赖父母，有着较强的自我责任意识。对于父母来说，孩子在养育过程中很可爱，长大后则只期待情绪交流的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看上去，育儿正在逐渐演化成一种竞争。日本有没有“学区房”“鸡娃”现象？高度竞争的社会是否会对生育率产生影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本的就业市场对学历的要求则相对比较宽松，高中毕业和大学毕业的工资差距在世界上也算小的。也就是说，即使是高中毕业或专科毕业，也有可能过上相对好的生活。父母也没必要那么热心，尤其是那些自己本身也只是高中毕业的父母。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;年轻人结婚意愿消退的一个可能的原因是，越来越多人意识到婚姻是一种契约关系，而契约有破裂风险。为何越来越多年轻人倾向于对结婚这件事做风险评估？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对年轻人来说，将来能否过上中流生活是他们非常关心的事情。在日本，1990年以前，大多数年轻人都可以期待依靠“年功序列制度”过上工资每年都增长的生活，但随着全球化的发展，经济风险越来越大，如今的年轻人已经不能再乐观地认为“将来总会有办法的”。出于这个原因，年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果从一开始就过着相对贫穷的生活，那么一般都不会觉得有什么风险存在，但现在的很多年轻人在未成年时期过着相当充实且富裕的生活。不想放弃这种生活的意识会很强烈。特别是作为独生子女的这一代中国年轻人，这种意识应该会更加强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到一个现象：如今的年轻人甚至连恋爱的欲望都在消退。韩国有“三弃”（放弃爱情、婚姻、生育），日本有“草食男”（恋爱被动、不积极），中国也有一些年轻人觉得恋爱是件麻烦事，为何年轻人会丧失恋爱的欲望？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为现代的年轻人觉得，恋爱感情总是会“降温”的。在欧美，“与相爱的人在一起”就是人生的意义。但是，在东亚各国，这种想法并不普及。在不少人看来，谈恋爱其实就是寻找结婚对象的一种过程，因此他们也认为，和明知道不能结婚的人交往，是在浪费时间和金钱。越来越多的人认为，恋爱本身就是一种需要顾虑别人的不快乐的事。因为色情行业的扩大，尤其在日本，谈恋爱的性价值也降低了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;许多人通过虚拟关系满足恋爱需求，比如时下流行的AI男女友，或是“嗑CP”，在围观他人恋爱的过程中获得情感满足。你怎么理解这些现象？也有人质疑，通过数据计算、金钱付出而获得情感满足，削弱了爱情的复杂性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;虽然我认为这是逃避的一种形式，但对现在的年轻人来说，有越来越多的人认为这是比现实恋爱还要愉快的交流时间。如果现实恋爱的满足度下降了，那虚拟恋爱的价值就会上升。也许现在已经不能说现实中的满足就更优越了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1997年你就命名了日本社会的“单身寄生族”现象，近年，中国社会也出现了“全职儿女”，即儿女们放弃工作，回家承担家务、给父母养老，生活开支由父母负担，部分全职儿女还会得到父母开的工资。你似乎有意强调“单身寄生族”和婚育意愿的关联，能否再展开谈谈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在遇到自己理想的结婚对象之前，在父母身边过着富裕的生活，这种“等待”很可能是没有尽头的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，因为成年后必须脱离父母自立，所以两个年轻人凑一起过日子会比较有利。但是在东亚国家，脱离父母独立，一般意味着孩子能在外面过上比待在父母家里更好的生活。在遇到能一起过上更好生活的结婚对象之前，先在父母家里“等待”也没什么关系，甚至父母也如此期待着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，一直等不到理想的人出现，而就这样慢慢老去的“前”年轻人层出不穷，在日本，人到中年也依然与父母同居的未婚者正在不断增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;人们通常认为，年轻人拥有无限可能，正是积极试错的年龄段。但你却提出“社会为什么对年轻人冷酷无情”的疑问，为什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果能像欧美那样，大多数孩子在成年后就离开父母自立，那么即使在社会中冒险失败，重新来过也确实不是什么难事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，在东亚各国，年轻人会拿自己和父母做比较，越来越多的年轻人认为达不到父母的水平就是失败。在父母的关照下过着富裕生活的人更是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，在日本，很多年轻人认为就业和结婚是不能重新来过的，这也是很重要的影响因素之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困生攒钱看演唱会惹争议，该不该限制助学对象高消费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:43:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765296853&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Exclusive video丨Xi Jinping and US President Biden held the China-US Presidential Meeting.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/ 79e1b7263270835011765296853/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b726327083501176 5296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local time 11 On March 15, President Xi Jinping held a China-US Presidential Meeting with US President Joe Biden at Philori Estate in San Francisco, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，我和总统先生上次会面是在巴厘岛，已经过去1年了。 A lot has happened in the past year. The world has emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic, but the huge impact of the epidemic remains. The world economy has begun to recover, but it lacks momentum, industrial and supply chains are disrupted, and protectionism is on the rise. These problems are very prominent. As the most important bilateral relationship in the world, China-U.S. relations must be thought and planned against the backdrop of the accelerating changes in the world over the past century, so as to bring benefits to the people of both countries and demonstrate responsibility for human progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 50 years, Sino-US relations have never been smooth sailing. There will always be problems of one kind or another, and they will always move forward amid twists and turns. It is impossible for such two big countries not to deal with each other. It is unrealistic to try to change each other. No one can bear the consequences of conflict and confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still have the same view. Great power competition is not the background of this era and cannot solve the problems facing China, the United States and the world. This earth can accommodate China and the United States, and our respective successes are opportunities for each other. China and the United States have different histories, cultures, social systems, and development paths. This is an objective reality. However, as long as both sides adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, they can transcend differences and find a way for the two major countries to get along correctly. I firmly believe that the future of Sino-US relations is bright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The President and I are at the helm of Sino-US relations and bear heavy responsibilities for the people, the world, and history. I look forward to having an in-depth exchange of views and reaching new consensus with Mr. President today on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>