<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[爆款剧都在开售后演唱会，剧粉福利还是“割韭菜”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259330]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are becoming a standard feature of hit dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Following the successful after-sales concert of the popular summer drama &quot;Lotus House&quot;, another hit drama &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; also recently held a famous concert It is an after-sales concert for the &quot;First Season Finale Celebration Wilderness Tour Carnival Night&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, during the live broadcast of the carnival night, complaints such as &quot;embarrassment&quot; and &quot;refund&quot; were hotly searched one after another. This is not a problem with the actors, but with the party planning. , the game session was a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the earlier TV series &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; and &quot;Shan He Ling&quot; to the recent &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, after-sales concerts have become more and more common. It has also become a new way for the platform to make money - how did the after-sales concerts become a trend? How profitable is it? What is the risk of rollover? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;After-sales concerts are becoming more and more popular&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In an era where video websites are competing for hegemony, more and more attention is paid to the &quot;after-sales&quot; of drama series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A drama is not finished after it is aired. If we can provide drama fans with better after-sales service and experience, we can take out more from the fans&#39; pockets. More money can also increase the loyalty of drama fans to the platform, which will help increase the value of platform members. Therefore, after-sales services in the form of after-sales concerts, after-sales parties, after-sales sharing sessions, etc. are becoming more and more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are generally broadcast simultaneously online and offline. Offline tickets need to be purchased at a high price, or only by purchasing a platform membership card can you get the chance to draw tickets. Online live broadcasts require the purchase of live broadcast tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the concert, the main creators gathered together to sing theme songs, restore famous scenes, and play interactive games, which formed the main content of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The trend of after-sales concerts was first sparked by the 2019 &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the series ended, the platform held two Chinese-style concerts in Nanjing, selling more than 16,000 tickets in six price ranges from 627 yuan to 1,980 yuan5 It was sold out within seconds. If you didn’t grab the ticket, you can still buy the platform’s online live broadcast tickets at prices ranging from 25 yuan to 50 yuan. &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; successfully tested the waters, allowing the industry to see the huge market space for after-sales concerts of popular dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, the fairy tale drama &quot;Liu Li&quot; became a dark horse in the summer season and gained many loyal fans. Since it is impossible to gather offline due to the epidemic, the platform has customized a cloud singing party for drama fans. Audiences can pay to watch it at prices ranging from 25 yuan (member price) to 50 yuan (non-member price). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 2021 hit drama &quot;Shanhe Ling&quot; has replicated the amazing popularity of the &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; after-sales concert. There were two consecutive concerts in Suzhou, with the highest ticket price reaching 2,280 yuan (more expensive than a ticket for a first-line singer&#39;s concert). 600,000 people bought tickets online, and it took 14 seconds to sell out. Online live broadcast tickets also cost 68 yuan each. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Afterwards, with the official crackdown on chaos in the entertainment industry, the format of after-sales concerts for popular dramas stopped for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, an improved version of after-sales concerts will return. However, both &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; have significantly reduced the number of offline audiences, with only a few hundred people offline. This can make the approval of performances more efficient, and can also avoid some uncontrollable chaos in the entertainment industry, and avoid Public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Offline tickets are exclusive to high-level members. Only those who have purchased a one-year membership will have the chance to win the lottery. Online viewers can choose to pay to purchase live broadcast viewing tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256320&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Lotus Tower&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The money from drama fans is really good&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The after-sales concert is really a &quot;charity&quot; for the platform. Is it going to give back to the fans of the drama and provide benefits to the fans of the drama? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously not that simple. If it is really a benefit, then should online viewing be free? It may be true that the platform gives back to drama fans, but it must be true that it makes another wave of money from drama fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; has verified how strong the purchasing power of drama fans is. A single offline ticket for &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; was sold to 150,000 by scalpers; online VIP tickets are 30 yuan/ticket, non-VIP tickets are 50 yuan/ticket, and group tickets are 25 yuan/ticket. The total number of people in the live concert room exceeds 3.2 million. If Based on an average of 30 yuan per person, the total online revenue is nearly 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only are the offline tickets for &quot;Ling of Mountains and Rivers&quot; more expensive than those of &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;, but the price of online live broadcast tickets is as high as 68 yuan per piece, but at no point It did not affect the enthusiasm of fans of the drama. The Douban score of &quot;Shan He Ling Born Bosom Friend Concert&quot; is as high as 9.5 points, which shows that fans of the drama are very happy with their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; has changed to a new format. Even if the number of offline concert tickets is limited, they are basically not sold to the outside world. Buying members and drawing tickets can also It provides a great boost to the platform’s membership fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans need to purchase a 448 yuan/year Star Diamond membership (or membership level V7) to get 1 chance to draw tickets, and the number of times they purchase a Star Diamond membership Unrestricted. In order to be able to draw tickets, some fans of the drama bought a 10-year Star Diamond membership in one go. The membership fee also costs 4,480 yuan, which is more expensive than offline concert tickets, and they may not be able to win the lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; is also played in a similar way. Users who purchase the SVIP annual card of the platform can get 10 lottery opportunities, and the annual card price is 488 yuan. The platform limits the number of recharges for the SVIP annual card, which can only be recharged a maximum of 3 times. This avoids excessive consumption by fans and can also increase users’ enthusiasm for paying for prize draws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In short, there are always ways to make money when the platform holds after-sales concerts. In the short term, you can directly collect money from fans of the drama. In the long term, after-sales concerts will become part of the platform’s membership services. If there is a second season like &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, it can also build momentum for the second season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Main actors who have starred in hit dramas will basically attend after-sales concerts. This helps extend the character&#39;s popularity to the actors. What&#39;s more, if other main creators are participating, a single leading actor may be accused of being &quot;insincere&quot; by fans of the drama, and may be &quot;out of touch&quot; or &quot;back-stepped&quot;. . Therefore, as long as most of the core creators agree to hold an after-sales concert, the remaining starring actors will only have the option of &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;It pays to fool drama fans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to character filtering Mirror, drama fans are very tolerant of after-sales concerts. For example, if the actor is not a professional singer, they do not require him to sing well. Drama fans generally have a request, hoping to see traces of the characters in the interactions of the actors, so that the beautiful emotions in the drama can continue offline, and the regrets in the drama can be made up for offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This puts forward high requirements for the restoration and interaction of after-sales concerts - this is why many after-sales concerts have actors wearing costumes from the drama Costumes are used in performances to give drama fans a stronger sense of immersion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; is like this, with a high degree of restoration, full of sincerity, and has been well received. Although &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; received many bad reviews, the restoration of the Qingshui Town part of the play became a highlight of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once the degree of restoration is poor and the interactivity is insufficient, the after-sales concert will instead make the audience laugh and let the audience &quot;get out of the trap&quot;. The previous Cloud Song Concert of &quot;Liu Li&quot; shocked drama fans because the male and female protagonists had almost no interaction on stage. The Douban score of &quot;Liu Li Finale Cloud Song Concert&quot; was as low as 2.4 points. As soon as the after-sales concert ended, the actor dropped a few points. Thousands of fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This time the &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; after-sales concert was criticized, it was not the actor&#39;s problem. Yang Zi&#39;s emotion for the character is still very touching. Tan Jianci was late because of a traffic jam. When he arrived, he sang, danced and adjusted the atmosphere. He was very dedicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The problem mainly lies in the planning of the concert, such as asking the five main actors to pose strange poses in front of the flower arrangements, having Zhang Wanyi recite, and having Deng Wei Cooking, and having Yang Zi and Dai Luwa wearing high heels recreate the fighting scenes in the play... there was little restoration, and the interaction was awkward. It was originally intended to build momentum for the second season, but it actually caused some fans of the show to leave disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts seem to be very profitable, but planning them well is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the characters in the play are like each other, the offline actors may not be familiar with each other in reality. This requires efforts in planning and in the early stages. Coordinate and communicate more with the actors. For example, you can let the actors wear costumes to continue &quot;performing&quot; in the play, or you can use interesting game designs to allow the actors to have more interactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is foreseeable that after-sales concerts of &quot;small scale offline, money to watch online&quot; will become a new normal for hit dramas in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans are willing to spend money to &quot;buy benefits&quot;. However, it is worth noting that if the platform is fooled and really treats drama fans as &quot;leeks&quot;, it will It will damage the credibility of the platform and also have a negative impact on the actors. When the platform wants to organize after-sales services, actors may not participate, members are unwilling to pay, and the platform has completely lost a way to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘家昌自曝家丑为哪般？“先小人后君子”才能财产婚姻两全丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 26 and November 1, 2023, the famous musician Liu Jiachang published two long articles in succession Accusing his ex-wife Zhen Zhen attracted public attention. Liu&#39;s first long article elaborated on his version of the inside story of the &quot;mother and son fighting for the birth&quot; of his ex-wife and their son, while the second long article accused Zhen Zhen of being incompetent in raising her son and &quot;being a shameless mother.&quot; After Liu Jiachang published his first long article, Zhen Zhen also published a thousand-word article to counterattack, and the two of them were &quot;at odds with each other&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Weibo promotion&quot; triggered by celebrities&#39; &quot;divorce essays&quot; once again occupied the hot search, and showed a similar plot to similar incidents in the past: one party took the lead in attacking, and looked eloquent. The words are righteous and well-founded; the other party fights back and refutes point by point, which seems to be righteous and sensible. For a time, public opinion was greatly divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang’s main accusation against Zhen Zhen can be divided into two parts. The first is the issue of division of marital property. Liu Jiachang accused Zhenzhen of transferring Liu&#39;s assets to her name in various ways over the years, including but not limited to company equity, music copyrights and cash income; the second was the issue of his son&#39;s education and growth. Liu accused Zhen Zhen of controlling his son but failing to teach him how to spoil him. He made his son drop out of school again and again and became naughty. He got into troubles including drunkenness, racing, beating people, and soliciting prostitutes. Liu tried his best to encourage his son to make music, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, Liu Jiachang claimed that he &quot;disclosed his family affairs&quot; because of his failed marriage and hurt feelings. He posted a long article accusing Zhenzhen mother and son just to vent his anger so as not to &quot;die unjustly&quot;. It seems inappropriate. It was all about fighting for property, because he also promised to donate his property to charity if he won the lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Liu’s first long article, Zhen Zhen also issued a counterattack, accusing Liu Jiachang of being addicted to gambling and suppressing his son. It was Liu Jiachang who stole his property, not the other way around; Liu Jiachang After the second long article was released, Zhen Zhen also criticized Liu Jiachang for slandering herself and her son, saying, &quot;It&#39;s really shameless.&quot; Their son Zhang Liheng (formerly known as Liu Ziqian) also supported his mother on social media. The &quot;mutual conflict&quot; between the two sides shows that each has his own words, but in order to determine which is right and which is wrong, we should return to the level of facts and legal principles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the property dispute between the two parties, there are many factual issues that are not difficult to prove or falsify. Written evidence can be used to determine whether these properties were earned by Liu Jiachang, or whether they were simply &quot;registered in the name of his wife Zhenzhen&quot; as joint property of the couple. For example, the audit report mentioned by Liu Jiachang, and the Income details, tax return records, property registration records from the three places across the Taiwan Strait and the United States, as well as legal documents regarding music copyrights, company equity, real estate ownership, and the agreements between the two parties regarding the property, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhen Zhen accused Liu Jiachang of being &quot;addicted to gambling&quot;, and Liu Jiachang responded that &quot;he only used his own money for gambling.&quot; Liu Jiachang accused Zhen Zhen of &quot;not filming for forty years&quot; and that all the joint property was earned by herself. Zhen Zhen also personally told the media that every penny earned by Liu was given to Zhen Zhen and her family. It&#39;s not difficult to prove. Liu&#39;s accusation and response can be summarized as, &quot;It is normal for a husband to make money outside and leave it to his wife to take care of, but Zhen Zhen should not assume that she earned all the money.&quot; Whether this argument can be established is the key issue in determining whether the dispute is right or wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second part of Liu Jiachang’s accusation, “Unvirtuous wife and unfilial son,” is even more difficult to verify because of its rich details and specific descriptions. Liu Wen accused Zhen Zhen of failing to teach her son well and his son was naughty and naughty. He was forced to drop out of school in Hong Kong, Shanghai, and the United States. He also got into troubles including drunkenness, beating people, speed driving, and soliciting prostitutes. Zhen Zhen even &quot;solicited prostitutes on behalf of her son.&quot; , these are specific and severe public accusations. Liu Jiachang should be responsible for providing evidence and ensuring the authenticity of the accusations, otherwise it will be suspected of slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang also revealed in the long article that his son was able to successfully enroll in school or escape punishment many times by relying on his connections with &quot;big men&quot; such as Run Run Shaw. If these incidents really happened, there must be others. There are too many informed third parties who can verify one by one, and it does not rule out that there are still many cases that can be verified. Liu Jiachang also mentioned that he tried his best to help his son make music but failed. This can also be supported by the record company and related people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a legal perspective, it is meaningless for both parties to resort to personal attacks in moral trials. The focus should still be on the common property division issues in divorce proceedings. Both parties accuse each other of embezzling their own property. This should be left to professional lawyers who specialize in marriage law and company law to litigate the game. Everything should be carried out according to normal litigation procedures; Zhen Zhen said that the two parties had divorced in the United States in 1987, and Liu Jiachang said It is said that the divorce was filed in Hong Kong in 2015. The truth needs to be determined by courts in many places and even many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whose essay should the public believe? This still requires facts as the basis and law as the criterion in order to arrive at a fairer judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The divorce dispute between Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen has actually been going on for many years. The reason why old matters have resurfaced is because of the property division disputes arising from the divorce, as well as the huge interest entanglement mixed with the relationship between parent and child. Even an ordinary couple will have similar &quot;Rashomon&quot; problems during divorce disputes, let alone a celebrity couple who need to divide huge amounts of property and have huge conflicts of interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Liu Jiachang&#39;s accusations, he is quite resentful of &quot;having his feelings hurt by money&quot; and resentment of &quot;having money hurt because of his feelings.&quot; The impression between the lines is that he was originally He is an &quot;old-school face-saving person&quot; who follows the traditional Chinese marriage and family values ​​of &quot;men taking care of the outside and women taking care of the house&quot;, but he is exhausted physically and mentally by his wife&#39;s deliberate &quot;marriage competition&quot;. The reason why their marriage failed was that they fell into a vicious cycle of &quot;talking about feelings hurts money, talking about money hurts feelings&quot;. Unclear financial decisions and inadequate marriage and love decisions were also important factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing many cases of &quot;peaceful breakup&quot; and &quot;mutual divorce&quot; between celebrity couples, it can be seen that the key to the success of &quot;peaceful breakup&quot; is that both parties have fully completed the notarization of pre-marital property and the division of post-marital property. Procedure, the method of &quot;first being a villain and then being a gentleman&quot; is equivalent to &quot;pursuing common feelings with common interests&quot; rather than &quot;seeking interests in the name of feelings&quot;. Before marriage, clarify the distribution of property and custody rights in the event of divorce. In the end, the respective interests of both parties are better protected, and they will not be reduced to online battles with short essays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the merger of two well-off houses in first-tier cities is like the merger of two companies, and there will be problems in the distribution of large amounts of property. It is best to divide the property before marriage to effectively avoid possible disputes. In comparison, celebrity marriages involve huge amounts of property. Before getting married, they should agree on how to divide property and child custody rights in the event of a breakup. Otherwise, they will inevitably fall into a &quot;complaint dispute&quot;. This time Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen were at odds with each other, which once again proved this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[环状RNA有望成为下一代重磅药物]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259706]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 15:15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;For the invention of mRNA vaccine technology, American scientists Katalin Karikó and Drew Wei Drew Weissman won the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine. The mRNA vaccine has not only saved millions of people around the world from being killed by the new coronavirus, but has also brought tens of billions of dollars in revenue to institutions and scientists engaged in vaccine development and production. This has drawn much attention to RNA, an unstable small nucleic acid molecule. Scientists and medical research and development institutions are working hard to develop new RNA drugs, and circular RNA is expected to become the next generation of blockbuster RNA drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/PeKYI0DjhC680SKp0veP23hYpVIlP2zwrilYSNFF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1248&quot; height= &quot;814&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/PeKYI0DjhC680SKp0veP23hYpVIlP2zwrilYSNFF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256317&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Circular RNA therapy is gaining more and more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nature website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is circular RNA&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Each The DNA molecule of a gene generally contains several exon sequences, separated by introns. It must first be transcribed into a single-stranded precursor mRNA. After shearing by shearing enzyme, the intron part is cut out, and then the exon part is cut out. The exons are spliced ​​together to form a functional mRNA, which then binds to the ribosome and guides it to synthesize proteins. Therefore, mRNA is a &quot;reduced version&quot; of the gene&#39;s DNA molecule, carrying the complete genetic information of the gene in the most streamlined nucleotides. The reason why mRNA can be used as a vaccine is that it can directly instruct cells to synthesize the corresponding antigen proteins, thereby triggering the body&#39;s immune system to produce antibodies to fight the virus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the mRNA vaccine had a bumpy road before encountering the new coronavirus, and it was basically ignored. As a result, Carrico was unable to receive funding, and was transferred, reduced, or even fired from his job many times. Compared with double-stranded DNA molecules of genes, mRNA molecules have a simple structure and are extremely unstable. They generally have a single-stranded linear structure and are easily broken down by RNase. Therefore, the half-life of mRNA in the body is usually only a few hours. Such a short survival time is enough for vaccines, because the mRNA can immediately guide the cells to synthesize antigen proteins after entering the cells. However, for diseases such as cancer, neurological diseases, and genetic diseases that require large amounts of continuous protein treatment, the RNA persists in the body. time is too short. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, RNase mainly &quot;bullies&quot; linear RNA, but has no way of attacking circular RNA. In fact, scientists have discovered that there is a kind of RNA in living organisms that can be connected end to end and likes to circle around itself more than 40 years ago. Through the continuous efforts of scientists, this circular RNA has recently begun to show great medical uses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1976, Swiss virologist Daniel Kola Kofsky and a German research team discovered circular RNAs in mouse and plant viruses respectively. Circular forms are present in viruses, but have not attracted enough attention. In the early 1990s, researchers discovered such circular RNA molecules in human and other mammalian cells and proved that these circular RNAs are the transcript products of certain genes. Later, scientists discovered that circular RNA exists in almost all living things. However, compared with linear RNA, most circular RNA splicing is often chaotic and cannot guide cells to synthesize the corresponding proteins. It is also unclear what the purpose of circular RNA is. In the first thirty years after the discovery of circular RNA, , people have always mistaken it as the product of incorrect splicing during gene transcription, so it has not attracted much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development of RNA sequencing technology, scientists have discovered that circular RNA is very abundant in mammalian cells, highly conserved, far more stable than linear RNA, and plays many functions, and is not dispensable &quot;junk&quot; . Research shows that more than 60% of human genes can produce both circular and linear transcripts. Currently, more than 100,000 types of circular RNA have been discovered in human cells, which is much higher than the number of known human genes (about 20,000). ). Because it is not susceptible to RNase degradation, in some cells, the half-life of natural circRNA can be 2-4 times that of linear RNA, or even longer, while synthetic circRNA can survive in cells for several days, and The abundance of circular RNA in cells can reach more than 10 times that of linear RNA of related genes. Scientists have also discovered that endogenous circRNAs are involved in a variety of biological functions, including gene transcription, protein translation, immune response, cell proliferation and physiological regulation of tumorigenesis, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most circular RNAs lack the necessary structure for ribosome recognition and are generally non-coding, that is, they cannot translate proteins. However, there are also a few that are coding RNAs, and these encoded proteins can also function. normal functionality. In 1995, researchers at the University of Colorado Health Science Center realized the coding function of circular RNA in vitro for the first time. Adding an internal ribosome entry site was crucial. This also laid the foundation for the development of circular RNA as vaccines and protein drugs. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Technological breakthroughs bring hope&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since most natural circular RNAs cannot encode proteins and must be artificially designed and synthesized, scientists have Circular RNA technology has undergone a series of improvements and improvements, and has achieved a series of major breakthroughs. For example, in July 2022, the research team of Howard Y. Chang at Stanford University published an important study in the journal Nature Biotechnology. They made a series of improvements to the structure of circular RNA and optimized the translation process. Modules such as the initiation region, termination region, and internal ribosome entry site are implemented, and modular assembly is achieved, making protein translation easier to initiate and more efficient. Compared with unmodified circRNA, the recombinant protein expression level of modified circRNA can be increased hundreds of times. In vivo experiments in mice have shown that circRNA can be maintained in cells for more than 7 days, and only a small amount of circRNA molecules are needed to maintain high protein levels in cells for a longer period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other major technological breakthroughs include: adding complementary sequences at both ends and in the middle of RNA to allow RNA to automatically form a loop and be more stable; allowing circular RNA to carry longer nucleotide chains, such as more than 12,000 nucleotide dystrophin gene sequence to synthesize more complex proteins; optimize circRNA delivery systems, such as lentivirus or exosome systems, to efficiently deliver circRNA to target cells; use genetic engineering technology Prepare circRNA on a large scale to save a lot of cost and time in circRNA preparation, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to technological improvements, the potential application of circular RNA in the medical field is another research hotspot. In March 2022, Peking University Wei Wensheng&#39;s team published a paper in the journal Cell confirming that compared with linear mRNA vaccines, circular RNA vaccines can induce more neutralizing antibodies and more effective T Cellular response. In May 2023, Zhang Yuanhao&#39;s team at Stanford University published an article in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences proving that circRNA has the potential to be developed into anti-viral and anti-tumor vaccines. They used circRNA prepared in vitro (can encode viral protein antigens) Immunization of mice induces innate activation of dendritic cells, stimulating robust antigen-specific CD8 T cell responses in lymph nodes and tissues. Immunity experiments in mice showed that circular RNA designed for melanoma could significantly inhibit tumor growth in mice compared with untreated mice. This indicates that circRNA can be used as a therapeutic vaccine to induce strong cellular immunity and eliminate tumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with linear mRNA products, circular RNA products have several major advantages. First, circular RNA is more stable and easier to store than linear mRNA. This is because of its structural characteristics, linear mRNA is easy to transport It is degraded by RNase during storage, delivery, etc., so it must be cryopreserved and cold-chain transported. Even if linear mRNA is subjected to a series of modifications such as nucleotide modification, the cost and effect are still not ideal, while circular RNA can be It can be stored at room temperature for about a month and can be frozen and thawed repeatedly. Secondly, circRNA is safer than linear RNA. Research shows that natural circRNA molecules show lower immunogenicity and cytotoxicity. Thirdly, circRNA is safer than linear RNA. RNA-like RNA has the ability to produce prolonged antigens and can induce a long-lasting immune response in the body, thus promoting the production of more antibodies and longer-lasting immune protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, circRNA products are expected to become a better choice in the field of RNA therapy for various refractory diseases such as viral infections, tumors, pathogenic bacterial infections, autoimmune diseases, metabolic diseases, etc. play a greater role in disease prevention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Has received huge investments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Inspired by the great success of mRNA vaccines, some scientists around the world who are engaged in pioneering research on circRNA have also established a number of A circular RNA company was founded, and it quickly became favored and sought after by capital. Some biopharmaceutical giants have also joined the trend of developing circular RNA pharmaceutical products, hoping to take the initiative in future competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daniel Anderson of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) and others founded Orna Therapeutics in 2019. The company’s pipeline products mainly include anti-tumor and anti-infection drugs. and circular RNA therapies for the treatment of genetic diseases, but they are all in the early stages of development. The company plans to launch the first clinical trial in 2024. In February 2021 and August 2022, Orna completed Series A and Series B financing of US$80 million and US$220 million respectively. Merck, a pharmaceutical giant with a history of 130 years, seems to be very optimistic about this startup. It has paid an advance payment of US$150 million and plans to jointly develop circular RNA therapies for infectious diseases with Orna Company, while injecting US$100 million to participate. Received Orna’s Series B financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Laronde was founded by Flagship Pioneering with an investment of US$50 million on May 11, 2021. It received US$440 million in financing three months later, making it the largest environmental investment company so far. This is the largest financing ever received by an RNA company. Since the flagship Pioneer Company once incubated the RNA vaccine star company Moderna of the United States, Lloyd&#39;s Company is also known as &quot;Modena 2.0&quot;. After receiving huge financing, the company is focusing on preventive and therapeutic circular RNA product development and clinical trials. However, on June 12, 2023, a joint investigation report released by the Boston Globe and STAT showed that the company was suspected of falsifying preclinical experimental data. For example, the circular RNA it developed for weight loss drugs only worked in mice. Expression, but not in monkeys. In a subsequent statement, the company also admitted the data fraud designed in the above report and dealt with the relevant responsible persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuanhao Zhang of MIT founded Orbital Therapeutics in September 2022 with Drew Weisman, pioneer of mRNA vaccine technology and winner of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, and others. ) company, which completed a Series A financing of up to US$270 million in April 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China also has a number of start-up companies developing circRNA drugs. Circode Bio was founded in September 2018 by researcher Wang Zefeng of the Max Planck Institute of Computing Technology of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and others. It is the world&#39;s first start-up company to develop nucleic acid drugs based on circular RNA. In December 2021, Huanma Biotech completed Pre-A round financing of more than 20 million US dollars, and in August 2023, it completed another tens of millions of US dollars in Series A financing. At present, the company has reached a research and development cooperation agreement with the American pharmaceutical giant Pfizer to jointly develop circular RNA therapies. Yuanyin Biotech was founded by Professor Wei Wensheng of Peking University and others in April 2021. In June 2022, it successfully completed a Series A financing of more than 280 million yuan. Together with the angel round and Pre-A round of financing, the company has accumulated more than 400 million yuan. The company&#39;s R&amp;D pipeline includes circRNA products for the treatment of infectious diseases, metabolic diseases and tumors. Among them, the fastest-growing product is the circRNA COVID-19 vaccine, which has completed preclinical trials and entered clinical trials. However, due to the global COVID-19 The epidemic has calmed down, and it is expected that the development of the new crown vaccine may be shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, overall, the current research on circRNA therapy has just begun. To achieve what one start-up company predicts, circRNA will start a revolution or achieve 100 therapeutic goals within ten years. The promise of a new drug project still has a long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又见哄抢，还要纵容？？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259965]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Chinese medicinal materials grown by a farmer in Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City, Henan Province were robbed by local villagers, once again causing Internet extremes Big attention. Not long ago, there was an incident of villagers robbing corn in the city. On a wider scale, such incidents of theft and robbery of large growers are common on the Internet. This is closely related to the fact that the place where the incident occurred deliberately downplayed the illegal nature of the villagers&#39; looting and condoned the villagers&#39; infringement of the rights and interests of agricultural investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the robbery of Chinese medicinal materials in Zhoukou attracted attention, the Huaiyang District Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau issued a situation report on November 1, saying that the incident was not a robbery, but the villagers &quot;mistakenly believed&quot; that the growers had harvested for the second time. After finishing, he went into the field to pick up medicinal materials. The growers called the police after trying to dissuade them to no avail. The police quickly arrived at the scene and &quot;persuaded&quot; the people to leave. The report also said that after the second harvest of medicinal materials is completed, it is &quot;a habit for many years&quot; for growers to allow villagers to pick up leftover medicinal materials in the fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pick up&quot;, &quot;years of habit&quot; and &quot;mistake&quot; are clichés. They can be seen in almost every incident where growers are robbed. Half a month ago, after the corn robbery incident in Dancheng County, Zhoukou City, the local Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau responded that &quot;people went to harvested plots to pick up corn.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These excuses are really ridiculous. Even if there is a local habit of &quot;picking up&quot;, even if the growers allow the villagers to pick up after the second harvest is completed, the growers have repeatedly blocked the looting. If the farmers turn a blind eye and don&#39;t hear, is this still &quot;allowed&quot; by the growers? Is this still legal &quot;picking&quot;? In the Dancheng County corn robbery incident, hundreds of villagers also ignored the growers&#39; obstruction and ran to the unharvested plots in front of the harvesters to &quot;pick up&quot; them, forcing the harvesters to stop working to avoid accidental injuries. Is this still traditional &quot;picking up&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case of Gushi County public officials driving patrol cars to steal sorghum, the growers had not yet harvested the sorghum. This cannot be excused by &quot;picking up&quot;, right? But in the eyes of some local people, cutting a few ears of sorghum is not a big deal. &quot;Rural people just like to take advantage of it.&quot; Patrols are arranged to avoid safety accidents, not to stop theft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When local officials faced the looting incident, they not only downplayed it in words and justified large-scale looting, but also in action. Whether it was the robbery of Chinese medicinal materials in Huaiyang or the robbery of corn in Dancheng, after the growers called the police and reported it to the government, the police only came to the scene to &quot;maintain order&quot; and &quot;persuade&quot; the villagers to leave. What order should be maintained? Do we still need the police to maintain order and escort during looting? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to characterize looting behavior? Article 268 of the Criminal Law stipulates that if a crowd is gathered to rob public or private property, the amount is relatively large or there are other serious circumstances, the ringleaders and active participants shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention or surveillance, and shall also be fined; if the amount is huge or there are other special circumstances, If the circumstances are serious, the offender shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than three years but not more than ten years, and shall also be fined. The standards for relatively large amounts and huge amounts shall be determined by each high court. According to the standards of the Shanghai High Court, robbery of property worth more than 4,000 yuan is considered a &quot;large amount&quot;, and more than 40,000 yuan is a &quot;huge amount.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聚众哄抢财物罪只处罚首要分子和积极参加的，对一般参加的，如果不能定罪，还可以进行行政处罚。治安管理处罚法规定，哄抢公私财物的，处五日以上十日以下拘留，可以并处五百元以下罚款；情节较重的，处十日以上十五日以下拘留，可以并处一千元以下罚款。对那些并非哄抢而是盗窃的，可以适用刑法和治安管理处罚法对盗窃行为的规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现实中，警方往往对这些哄抢盗窃行为网开一面。几年前发生在浙江的瓜农三万斤西瓜一夜之间被偷光事件，警方在调查之后，却认定摘瓜者是误信了“种瓜老板不要了”的谣言才去摘瓜，没有盗窃的主观故意，认定不构成盗窃，只是“民事纠纷”，要求种瓜农户走民事程序索赔。陕西西安一瓜农种植的西瓜也曾被村民哄抢，村支部书记的说辞也是村民“听信了谣言”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果“听信谣言”能成为脱罪的理由，那就没有违法犯罪了。想要偷抢东西了，就去散布点“谣言”，然后就可以大摇大摆地去偷去抢。天底下有这样荒唐的事吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一些人以当地农民年老无依、生活无着等为村民辩护。这些理由也是站不住脚的。即便自身生活遭遇困境，那也应该去找政府反映问题，而不是哄抢别人的财产。事实上，这些辩解也完全是想象出来的借口，参与哄抢的村民，绝大多数没有到生活无着的地步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来不少地方类似的哄抢、盗窃事件频发，不能不说与地方政府、当地警方的包庇开脱和纵容有关。事件发生后，当地政府只是“劝导”参与哄抢者交回哄抢的财物，而不对其进行处罚，甚至有些人拒不交回也没什么事。那哄抢者当然不会罢手，下次还会继续抢，而且不会再交回了。相反，如果一次事件后，有关部门果断处罚，该拘留的拘留，该判刑的判刑，杀鸡儆猴，以后还有人敢抢吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，福建漳州也发生过外地养鱼户的鱼被当地村民哄抢的事，当地警方及时立案，对参与抢鱼情节比较严重的三名村民予以拘留，并敦促其他参与的村民“投案”，“退回赃物”。明确宣布哄抢是违法行为，要受到法律处罚，抢到的东西是“赃物”，必须退还，这才是针对此类哄抢的正确处理方式。也只有这样，才能建立和维护当地良好的营商环境，吸引更多的农业投资，振兴乡村。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国工商银行原副行长张红力接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259971]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 15:08:23&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;中国工商银行原党委委员、副行长张红力涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[秋季以来持续偏暖影响几何？会是暖冬吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259961]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this autumn, temperatures have continued to be high in most parts of my country, and winter has been delayed in many places. Many members of the public have questions: Will this year be a mild winter? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a press conference held by the China Meteorological Administration on the 3rd, Jia Xiaolong, deputy director of the National Climate Center, introduced that the national average temperature in October was 12.2°C, 1.6°C higher than the same period in normal years, and the highest temperature in the same period since 1961. Highest. Most of Northeast China, most of Shandong, most of Inner Mongolia, most of Xinjiang and other places were 2°C to 4°C higher. The temperatures in Inner Mongolia, Xinjiang, Tianjin and Liaoning were all the highest for the same period in history. The daily highest temperatures at 140 national weather stations exceeded October’s historical extreme value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since this autumn, the mid-to-high latitudes of Eurasia have been dominated by zonal circulation. my country has been controlled by positive anomalies in the height field. The intensity of the Siberian High has been generally weak, and cold air activity has been weak, resulting in persistent temperatures in most parts of my country. It’s on the high side,” Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that high temperatures and weak cold air will have a certain impact on the development of fog and haze weather and agricultural production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, fog and haze weather has occurred in Huanghuai and other places in North China. Zhang Jiancheng, deputy director of the National Meteorological Center, analyzed that the main reason is that the zonal circulation has been dominated over North China recently and the cold air is weak. North China, Huanghuai and other places are located in the weak pressure field behind the high pressure, and southerly winds have prevailed for a long time. At the same time, accompanied by high humidity atmosphere, vertical temperature inversion structure and special topographic effects of the Taihang Mountains and Yanshan Mountains, the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region has continued to Severe fog and haze weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although winter has already begun in most of Northeast China, northwestern North China, and most of northwest China, the onset of winter in most of the above-mentioned areas is later than normal, and in some areas it is more than 5 days later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jia Xiaolong said that warm and hot weather may lead to low soil moisture, affecting crop emergence and growth, which is not conducive to spring plowing and sowing in the coming year; delaying winter may affect crop growth seasons and cycles, which is not conducive to agricultural production plans and Yield; warm and hot climates can easily lead to excessive growth of crops and are conducive to the overwintering and reproduction of pests and diseases. Severe winter rain and snow disasters and increased risks of pests and diseases in the coming year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Does the continued warmness mean that this year will be a mild winter? What impact will El Niño have on the climate this winter? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Climate Center issued a climate prediction bulletin on the 3rd, stating that the temperature in most parts of my country this winter will be close to or higher than normal for the same period of the year. The temperature has obvious phase characteristics, with the first winter being warmer and the latter winter close to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Whether it is a warm winter depends on whether the temperature can reach the warm winter standard.” Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Monitoring shows that the equatorial central and eastern Pacific Ocean has entered an El Niño state, and an El Niño event is about to form. Affected by this, abnormal anticyclonic circulation prevails in the lower troposphere over the northwest Pacific and South China Sea in winter, the East Asian trough is weak, the East Asian winter monsoon is weak, and temperatures in most central and eastern my country are higher than normal for the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the abnormal anticyclonic circulation is conducive to the transport of warm and moist water vapor from the tropics to the south of my country. In conjunction with the movement of cold air southward, it is easy to cause excessive precipitation in the southern region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Statistics show that in the context of El Niño events, winter temperatures fluctuate greatly, and the number of cold air events that affect our country is often high. It is recommended to pay close attention to the possible adverse effects of periodic low-temperature rain and snow weather processes.&quot; Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困大学生哭诉助学金被挤占：福利如何才能落到需要的人手里？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259963]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of poor college students crying about being squeezed out of their scholarship qualifications has been widely circulated on social networks. attracted great attention. Tianjin Sino-German University of Applied Sciences, which was involved in the incident, said on November 2 that it had set up a special work team to conduct investigation and verification as soon as possible. The subsequent investigation results will be handled in accordance with regulations and announced in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video posted online, a boy said that his father died and his mother married when he was young, and his grandfather also passed away when he was 18 years old. Now he only has his grandma as a relative. Their family is registered locally. poor households. After entering college, he received national scholarships in previous years, but this year, the class held a scholarship qualification selection, and he was not selected. The students who were selected were wearing real AJ sneakers (a sneaker brand owned by Nike, the price Not cheap), using Apple 14 Pro Max mobile phone and iPad Pro tablet, often having dinner parties and traveling. He reported the situation to the counselor, but was forced to move out of the dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this is true, it is really outrageous, and this video has attracted a lot of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, fraud in scholarship applications is nothing new in some colleges and universities. National scholarships for colleges and universities are financial aid provided by the state finance to college students with financial difficulties. They are mainly used to meet the living expenses of students. The average aid standard is 3,000 yuan per person per year (not equal, can be divided into 2-3 levels), about 20% students may receive financial aid. Bursaries are a benefit provided by the state to some poor college students. Since it is welfare, how to distribute it and how to let people who really need it get this money is a very important issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this student, the scholarship qualifications for his class were selected by the whole class because he was not satisfied with the results of the first selection and went to the teacher to report it. As a result, he came last in the second selection. , became the person least qualified to receive scholarships in the class. The whole class selection seems very &quot;reasonable&quot;, but when used here, it is undoubtedly very absurd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is in financial difficulty and who is not is not a matter decided by one person and one vote. If the selection is held, it will become a &quot;connection&quot; competition, and it is inevitable that some students will form gangs and even bribe the vote. As for truly poor students, they may not be able to mingle with better-off classmates due to financial constraints, and as a result, they may not be eligible for financial aid. On social networks, it is not uncommon for a group of people to &quot;unite together&quot; to promote one person to receive a scholarship and treat them to dinner, and then another person will take turns to receive it next time. Such posts are not uncommon. As a result, some colleges and universities have issued notices that award-winning students are not allowed to use their scholarships to treat guests, otherwise their qualifications for future assessments will be cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some schools and classes even ask students applying for financial aid to tell their situations in front of the whole class and &quot;campaign&quot; for financial aid. This is letting people show their scars for others to see, which may cause a huge blow to the students&#39; self-esteem. Although some students are poor, they do not want others to know, especially in public. After all, poverty is not something worth showing off, and not everyone is compassionate. It is common for students to laugh at poor students in school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also not a good idea to let counselors, class teachers, etc. have the decision-making power about scholarship eligibility. First of all, it is difficult to ensure that these people are completely public-minded in the quota allocation process. Maybe most counselors are fair, but it is inevitable that there will be a few who are partial. Sometimes, financial aid eligibility may even become a tool to blackmail students into &quot;obedience.&quot; Secondly, counselors and others may not be able to fully understand the students&#39; financial situation, and lack sufficient and correct information to make correct judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There should be some objective criteria for determining scholarship qualifications, rather than just subjective determination, whether it is the subjectivity of an individual person (identification by the counselor or class teacher) or the subjectivity of the entire class (selection by the whole class) . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the objective standard? Theoretically, it can be whether the student&#39;s family income is below a certain standard. However, schools cannot directly obtain the income and assets of students&#39; families, so many schools ask poor students to provide poverty certificates from village committees or neighborhood committees. But these proofs are not entirely credible. For one, these proofs of poverty are not necessarily true. Especially for many rural areas, when village students are admitted to college, even if their families are not particularly poor, it is not difficult to go to the village committee to issue a poverty certificate. After all, they are all fellow villagers, and a certificate can alleviate the family&#39;s financial burden. Many village cadres will cover the burden unless the family&#39;s income is significantly higher than the village average. Secondly, the poverty standards in different regions are also different. Poverty in economically developed regions and poverty in western regions are completely different concepts. In recent years, there have been frequent cases of government officials visiting &quot;poor&quot; people and being criticized. Although some of them are falsely poor, there are also some misunderstandings caused by differences in regional economic levels. Therefore, the family poverty certificate issued by the place of origin can only be a reference and should not be used as a deciding factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should the scholarship qualifications be determined? This is of course a very complex issue and difficult to achieve completely ideally. But there are still some standards that can be referenced. For example, applying for a student loan can be a necessary condition. In the national student aid policy system, student loans are mainly used to solve the tuition and accommodation fees problems of students with financial difficulties. Nowadays, the tuition and accommodation fees of most schools are much higher than the scholarship standards. If you can pay for tuition and accommodation by yourself, it means you are not too poor. Otherwise, you can apply for a student loan to pay tuition and keep your own money for living expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can also observe students’ consumption on campus. The approach of Nanjing University of Science and Technology is a good reference. In 2016, Nanjing University of Science and Technology analyzed student consumption data in the cafeteria and listed those students who ate more than 60 meals in the cafeteria per month with a total consumption of no more than 420 yuan as aid recipients, and paid money directly to their meal cards. This is a very smart approach. As we all know, food in school cafeterias is much cheaper than outside. If a student eats almost every meal in the school cafeteria and the average consumption per meal is not high, there is a high probability that he is a poor student. Rich students either eat less in the on-campus cafeteria and often eat out and order takeout, or they spend more in the cafeteria and eat well. Eating is a basic necessity for people, whether rich or poor, everyone needs to eat, so using food consumption level as a measurement standard can cover all students. And the level of food consumption is difficult to fake. It is difficult for a person who is accustomed to a high standard of diet to continue to lower his dietary standards for a few months if the economic conditions do not change. Of course, this approach may also be used opportunistically, eating a little in the cafeteria for each meal, and then going out to eat and drink, but I am afraid that there are not many rich people who can persist in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, as a welfare provided by the national finance to poor students, the national scholarship should be used wisely to truly reduce the burden of life for poor students, and should not become Tang Monk meat that everyone wants to eat. Tianjin Sino-German University of Applied Sciences officially stated that it has launched an investigation and hopes that the investigation and handling results will be fair and just. More importantly, the problem of unfair distribution of scholarships occurs in many colleges and universities, and should arouse the vigilance of all colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当一个盲人想要登上珠峰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/olqpWxQWEpUrbnUzTSjDFES4jSoUR9IEeffnviOT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;641&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/olqpWxQWEpUrbnUzTSjDFES4jSoUR9IEeffnviOT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the climb, there were crisscrossing and completely irregular ice cracks underfoot. Zhang Hong You need to use trekking poles to test the location and terrain first, then use your feet to measure the approximate width of the crevasse, and finally dare to step out. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the top of the world&#39;s highest peak, blind man Zhang Hong&#39;s first thought was &quot; Get down quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the mountaineering accidents occur on the way down the mountain.” Zhang Hong said that when climbing, a person’s center of gravity is first. Even if he falls, the mountain will block him. When going down the mountain, “it all depends on the subconscious mind.” . He felt at ease until he returned to Everest Base Camp and took off his crampons - which meant that danger was truly far away. Sherpa (note: local people living on both sides of the Himalayas, usually serving as guides) gave him a cup of milk tea and a few biscuits to satisfy his hunger. The climb to the summit and back nearly exhausted his strength, and he nearly fell into coma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, the cognitive system composed of sound, hearing and touch makes his memories of the world’s highest peak still vivid. He clearly felt the difference in wind at different altitudes: the wind from the glaciers at low altitudes was mixed with freezing cold air, the storms at high altitudes made loud noises, and the strong winds picked up snow particles, ice slag and small rocks, giving people a sticky feel. , like a high wall that is insurmountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hiking across the glacier, the ice on the soles of your feet has a hard texture, and there is a &quot;click&quot; sound like biting potato chips when you step on it. Even with crampons, the risk of slipping is unavoidable. The snow is thick, and the sound of footsteps is muffled in it, giving people a more solid feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 24, 2021, at the 8848.86-meter summit of Mount Everest, Zhang Hong followed the example of his predecessors and left several photos and a 15-second short video. The former became his WeChat avatar, and the latter was the certificate of his record as &quot;the first blind man in Asia to climb Mount Everest&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the news of the successful summit reached Fan Lixin’s base camp, the documentary director had mixed emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was happy that Zhang Hong’s years of hard work had paid off. In 2019, he heard about Zhang Hong&#39;s ambition from a mountaineering friend: a blind masseur eager to climb Mount Everest. Everyone around him thought it was unreliable, but Fan Lixin became curious about this character. Like a gambler, he wanted to film this story that was very likely to fail. In May 2020, the documentary was launched, and the fate of the two &quot;paranoid&quot; people intersected since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is worrying is that due to an oxygen problem, the two accompanying photographers were not able to go up together. The video footage of Zhang Hong’s summit was blank. Fan Lixin cried out that she collapsed, “It’s hard for a clever woman to make a meal without rice.” On October 27, 2023, the documentary &quot;The Invisible Peak&quot; was released nationwide. Fan Lixin filled the gap in the material with a &quot;black&quot; segment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We shot more than 360 hours of material, and it took a year to edit. When editing, I was thinking, if there is no material for this section, why not use a black field and an immersive (Sound experience), immersing the audience into the world of a blind person.&quot; Fan Lixin told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Use this black field to take the audience to the top of the world, following Zhang Hong&#39;s footsteps.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Hong and his wife Xia Qiong. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong has an almost paranoid desire to climb Mount Everest. At that time, he was working as the deputy director of the Traditional Chinese Medicine Department of a hospital in Tibet. He was in his forties, had a stable job, worked with his wife, and had a son. Everyone was puzzled by his &quot;crazy&quot; desire to climb Mount Everest: &quot;This thing is completely unreliable. I have such a good job in my hand, and I have stabilized, and I still want to do this. This is full.&quot; I can hold on.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong admitted that obsession comes from a certain desire to prove something. &quot;I used to label myself as an unfortunate person in society. But the process of climbing Mount Everest taught me one thing: In fact, I am the same as everyone else, and society and nature have no regard for me. I don’t look at it differently.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Mount Everest will not give me more sympathy just because I am blind”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Official filming of the summit Fan Lixin followed Zhang Hong for more than a year. At that time, Zhang Hong&#39;s biggest anxiety during his trip to Mount Everest was money. When the documentary was launched, Zhang Hong received support of US$5,000 from a foundation, but there was still a big gap between the &quot;small one million&quot; RMB. In front of the camera, Zhang Hong took advantage of the wine and asked his brother in embarrassment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t know much about it at the time. To be honest, I was quite anxious. If he couldn&#39;t raise the money, he wouldn&#39;t be able to go even if he wanted to,&quot; Fan Lixin told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &quot;It&#39;s possible that he would become a The story of &#39;Don Quixote.&#39;&quot; Later, through crowdfunding, brand intervention, and hospital support, Zhang Hong was able to scrape together the money one week before departure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong took the traditional route to climb Mount Everest. Take a helicopter or small fixed-wing plane from Kathmandu, the capital of Nepal, to the small town of Lukla, and then hike for 7 days to the Everest base camp, which is &quot;equivalent to initial adaptive training.&quot; After a short rest at the base camp, the team conducted two training sessions. The destination of the first training session is Lobuche, which is more than 6,100 meters high; the second training session involves climbing to the C3 camp at an altitude of 8,300 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Lixin has never climbed a mountain before, and Luo Buche, who was training for the first time, was the first mountain he had climbed. When he was a child, he had an operation on his leg and one-third of his knee was cut off, making it difficult for him to climb Mount Everest with Zhang Hong. He invited two mountain photographers, including the producer who also served as a sound engineer, and the team was streamlined to only four people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbing from the base camp to the C1 camp, the altitude does not increase much, but you have to pass through the Khumbu Glacier, which is known as the &quot;terrible glacier&quot;. There are trenches in the glacier. In the wide ice ravine, two ladders were stacked together to form a bridge, and people and cameras trembled across it. Even Sherpas who have competed with Mount Everest all year round cannot take it lightly. During the filming of the documentary, a Sherpa fell into an ice ravine and hung on by a thread. After the people in the same team worked hard to rescue him, his body was curled up and his ears were purple from the cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbers with normal vision can take one step and look at ten steps, but Zhang Hong can only stare at the current step. Every step is difficult. With every step he took, he silently recited in his heart: &quot;This snowfield accepted me again, and the footprints under my feet carried me again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;When shooting on Mount Everest, the biggest difficulty was the electricity , because the diesel generator needs to come up little by little and can only be charged by solar energy. However, the sun is often not seen for three to five days when climbing, and the documentary team often feels anxious. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everest will not give me more sympathy just because I am blind. There is an ice cave under the glacier, and there is a cliff next to it. The ladder is also shaky, and the difficulty will not be reduced just because I can&#39;t see it.&quot; Zhang Hong was hit by a similar feeling when he climbed the mountain for the first time, &quot;I can feel that I and Everyone is the same, doing one thing in an equal and fair environment, there is no barrier between me and everyone, instead of before I thought that I was an unfortunate and alternative existence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the inability to see, ice climbing poses many obstacles to Zhang Hong. Fan Lixin said that the weather in the Himalayas was bad that year and the road conditions were complicated. When climbing an ice wall, sighted climbers can step on the ice pits that have been stepped on by the person in front of them. But Zhang Hong couldn&#39;t see it. The steel crampons under his feet were difficult to accurately kick into the old pit, and it took more effort than ordinary people to kick out the new pit. When hanging on the ice wall, the climber relies on three points of support, pulling the rope with one hand and smashing the ice with an ice ax with the other hand to pull his body upwards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We can see it, so we probably know where to hit it, and it will get more force. But he can&#39;t see it, so he just chisels randomly. If he chisels once, the ice will fly away and the chisel will be in vain, so he has to chisel again. Climbing an ice wall of more than ten meters is very tiring.&quot; Fan Lixin observed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the first training session, Zhang Hong suddenly lost his temper and said he no longer wanted to climb, and asked for a helicopter to be sent to pick him up. Some people in the team felt that his pace could not keep up with the progress and slowed down the progress. Zhang Hong looked displeased. &quot;He needs to get in touch with the team. He will feel that the risk is too high. He is not afraid that something will happen to him. What he is most afraid of is that he has not really climbed yet, and he is injured just in training, or his physical strength Exhausted.&quot; Fan Lixin told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Above five or six thousand meters above sea level, people’s emotions and thinking are completely different from those in the plains.” Zhang Hong analyzed his mentality at the time, “If you haven’t climbed (officially) yet, it’s better to practice. It’s not worth it if you get injured during the training.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the second training session, Zhang Hong suffered from an attack of cholecystitis, which caused his facial features to twist tightly together in pain. Back at base camp, the camp doctor examined him. Zhang Hong learned from others that the doctor recommended sending him back to Kathmandu for treatment, &quot;even requiring surgery.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Once I went to treatment, the climb almost came to a standstill.” Zhang Hong wrapped himself in a sleeping bag and broke down crying. &quot;Time waits for no one, the weather is bad, and the window period is limited, only a few days. You can&#39;t give up climbing just because of this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He blamed himself for not having a plan for this, but he was also optimistic about it. There is nothing that can be done about the pain, except rubbing the abdomen and massaging the liver and gallbladder meridian. One of the reasons why he climbed Mount Everest was to break the outside world&#39;s stereotype of blind people. Blind people can not only do massage. But as fate would have it, after two or three days of massage, the symptoms were really relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everything is God&#39;s will.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256987&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 24, 2021, Zhang Hong, who has been blind for 25 years, successfully climbed the world&#39;s highest peak, Mount Everest, from the Nepalese side, becoming the first blind person in Asia to climb Mount Everest. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;To the summit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The moment of reaching the summit Come on May 23, 2021 at 7pm. Zhang Hong, the Chinese guide, photographer and Sherpa set off from the C4 camp to the top of Mount Everest. When we were only 100 meters away from the peak, something unexpected happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad weather froze everyone&#39;s oxygen regulator valves, causing oxygen leaks. Taken together, the current amount of oxygen cannot support everyone reaching the summit. Qiangzi is Zhang Hong&#39;s Chinese guide. He has 15 years of experience as a mountain guide, but has never climbed Mount Everest. For mountaineers, the 100 meters that can be climbed in 2 hours is a &quot;huge temptation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hadron finally decided to give up his oxygen, and the two photographers made the same decision. The three of them descended, and Sherpa accompanied Zhang Hong to the summit alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Lixin later asked about the reason for giving up. Qiangzi said that in the three or four years he had known Zhang Hong, he had witnessed his difficulties and grievances along the way. &quot;I really don&#39;t want him to leave again. Maybe he will never have a second chance to leave again in this life. Training, raising money, withstanding the public opinion of the surrounding society, and the doubts of relatives and friends - you see No, why are you taking such a big risk? No one would think that a blind person also has the right to realize his own ideals, pursue his own value in life, and at the same time give his family a voice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three Summers Erba and Zhang Hong were connected on a rope, and Zhang Hong pushed the ascender forward. A Sherpa led the way about 1.5 meters in front. The two of them did not understand the language and only relied on simple English words &quot;go&quot;, &quot;up&quot; and &quot;down&quot; to communicate. There were two Sherpas carrying oxygen behind him, and one of them occasionally patted his legs to &quot;express comfort and encouragement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before climbing to the top, the most difficult section is the &quot;Hillary Steps&quot;, which is a blade-shaped ridge with almost vertical rock walls that &quot;cannot even catch snow&quot;. Zhang Hong estimated that the narrow spot is only about 30 centimeters, which can only accommodate half a foot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hands became his eyes at this time. He supported it with one hand, and used the other hand to explore the way forward along the tip of his toes. After finding the foothold for the next step, he used the other hand to find the support point. Every time he took a step, he &quot;had to stop and rest for a long time.&quot; Zhang Hong said that climbing the Hillary Step was like walking through the artificial rockery he had seen when his eyesight was still intact. The stone gaps were completely irregular and &quot;I didn&#39;t know what to do next.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hillary Steps&quot; are only 12 meters from the peak, but it took Zhang Hong more than two hours. When climbing, he lost the concept of time for a while. He would swing the rope left and right at intervals and ask the Sherpa who was leading the way: &quot;How long? How long?&quot; Sherpa&#39;s answer was half an hour every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The results haven&#39;t arrived after several and a half hours. Maybe I asked how long it would be after 5 minutes, and then asked again after 10 minutes.&quot; Zhang Hong was a little anxious and said several times. No,” “I’m going to die,” “I’m going down.” At first Sherpa ignored his complaints, but the last time Sherpa was also angry. He emotionally agreed to Zhang Hong&#39;s request to give up, and turned around to help him remove the ascender and replace it with the descender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;586&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fan Lixin recalled that there were two or three major cyclones in the Indian Ocean that year, which caused heavy snow and strong winds on Mount Everest. On the day Zhang Hong reached the summit, the wind speed reached 60 kilometers per hour, and people were almost killed. If it blows down, if the clothes are scratched and the down flies off, the consequence will be &quot;instant hypothermia and death.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unwillingness gripped Zhang Hong, and he said to Sherpa: &quot;Go ! Go! Go! &quot;&quot;Keep walking.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While crawling, Zhang Hong suddenly felt his crampons stepping on a soft snow. The further he walked, the thicker the snow became. Until the snow is deep enough to cover the entire sole of the foot. He suddenly bumped into the backpack of the person in front of him. &quot;You summit.&quot; He heard the leading Sherpa turn his head and say to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I didn’t think I had really reached the top.” Zhang Hong recalled, “I didn’t know where I was going, but I just walked like this. Maybe I was too tired and couldn’t take a step from He can react with his concentration.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His senses captured the changes in the surrounding environment before his consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While going up the mountain, Zhang Hong invisibly felt that the mountain he was climbing was like a huge obstacle blocking his face. But in that moment, the barrier disappeared. He could hear the surroundings becoming empty, the kind of emptiness that was unobstructed. He turned his head to the left, then to the right, and listened carefully to the sounds around him. The sound of wind swirling violently on his head made his hair stand on end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They didn’t stay on the top of Mount Everest for a long time. Zhang Hong heard Sherpa say, “Photo, photo,” and quickly took a few photos. It wasn’t until they got down the mountain that they found out, and even took photos for certification. video. He later told Fan Lixin that he only heard various incomprehensible languages ​​blaring on the intercom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When he thought about that moment, it was even a little ridiculous. He had prepared for so many years, prepared many postures and rhetoric to say on Mount Everest, but nothing, just 2 seconds, he He woke up and said, hurry down, this place is too scary, like hell, the howling of the wind.&quot; Fan Lixin recalled, &quot;When he was blind before, he really felt that the world was collapsing, just like in hell. He said that I I have been climbing for 20 years, climbing from hell to flat ground, and then from flat ground to the top of Mount Everest. (When I reached the summit) I felt as if I was in hell again, so I hurried down the mountain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;End of the climb Later, they were trapped in Nepal by a new wave of COVID-19. At that time, it was the most noisy time outside. Fan Lixin counted that more than 70 international mainstream media, including the BBC and AFP, were reporting on him. Zhang Hong said that he was not immersed in the feeling of being under the spotlight at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After he climbed Mount Everest, he discovered that climbing Mount Everest was not the highlight moment he needed at all, but made him understand that the current step is the most important. Because this step has not been stepped on Well, you may just fall and you will be dead. There is no so-called highlight moment at all. The real highlight moment may just begin when you are in the most dangerous moment. The guide in the movie also said: Climbing to the top is not the end. Returning to the top is not the end. Home is the end.&quot; When he was in Nepal, Fan Lixin chatted with him, &quot;He said, now you tell me that where I am standing is the top of Mount Everest, and I believe it because I can&#39;t see it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;He wanted others to think that blind people can not only be masseurs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he first started filming Zhang Hong, Fan Lixin felt that he was a somewhat impatient person, debugging equipment or Zhang Hong would look a little anxious when it was time to replace the battery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impatience comes from his sudden blindness. At the age of 21, he suffered a glaucoma attack and permanently lost his vision. It took three or four years for Zhang Hong to try to accept being unable to see, and his personality changed as a result. He became &quot;emotionally broken&quot; and &quot;bad-tempered&quot;. He failed to get what he wanted, or accidentally knocked over a cup. They will show their impatient side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My wife Xia Qiong captured these moments softly. She once tried to put herself in her husband&#39;s shoes, shut herself in the room, turned off all the lights, and closed the windows tightly. &quot;It felt like the four walls were squeezing in on you.&quot; She realized her husband&#39;s nervousness about danger in an unknown environment. &quot;It was originally a very docile sheep, a free species, but suddenly it was trapped in an invisible black cage.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The environment in which Zhang Hong grew up as a child was closely linked to &quot;blindness&quot;. His father and uncle are both blind. He, who has good vision, sometimes acts as a &quot;blind stick&quot;. The three of them pull a bamboo pole, and Zhang Hong leads the way. On a rainy day, the road was slippery and Zhang Hong fell, taking his father and uncle with him. In rural society, he had long been aware of the plight of blind people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have known their lives since I was a child, and I cannot accept the thought that I will have to live in such an environment in the future.” Zhang Hong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xia Qiong noticed that family background and childhood memories created a self-defense mechanism in Zhang Hong&#39;s heart. Before getting married, Zhang Hong had never taken the initiative to talk to her about his father and uncle. They got acquainted with Zhang Hong when he could still see the world. Later, Zhang Hong lost his sight. She joked that she was &quot;harmed&quot; by Jin Yong&#39;s martial arts novels. She bravely felt that &quot;he should not be left alone with no one.&quot; Tube&quot;. In 1999, the two people, who had been in love for three years, decided to testify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The family elders unanimously opposed it, and his father cried in front of Xia Qiong. Zhang Hong promised her: &quot;I will definitely make your family look at you with admiration.&quot; She thought that maybe it was from that time that he laid the groundwork for her husband&#39;s &quot;constant tossing&quot; in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the two decades before Tibet settled down, Xia Qiong described their life as &quot;precarious.&quot; Zhang Hong studied massage in school, but he was not obsessed with it. After he lost his sight, professionalism actually saved him from being unable to eat. Xia Qiong also learned massage. The couple first worked as masseurs in Chengdu and lived a &quot;suffering&quot; life. Later, I went to work in a massage shop in Shanghai, and the two of them were ranked among the &quot;top one or two in the shop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, when Xia Qiong went home to give birth, she received health care products from Zhang Hong from Shanghai. She knew that her husband was &quot;troublesome&quot; again. Zhang Hong quit his job behind her back and went to work in sales. &quot;He sometimes told people that he couldn&#39;t find a way out in the subway in Shanghai. He was trapped in the subway and at an intersection on the road in Shanghai.&quot; Xia Qiong said, &quot;He wanted to let others I feel that blind people can not only be masseurs, but also do other things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, after climbing the 7,500-meter Muztagh Peak, Zhang Hong decided to prepare for climbing Mount Everest. In order to save money, he adopted the most cost-effective training method - climbing stairs. While climbing, I put on mountain boots and an oxygen-blocking mask, and carried more than 20 kilograms of weight at the same time. I climbed for three to four hours every day. He lived in the hospital&#39;s apartment building and climbed from the first floor to the twelfth floor and then took the elevator down every day. When he met his colleagues in the hospital, he felt pressure. &quot;Countless people around him questioned him, thinking that this guy was not only blind, but also crazy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enduring the strange looks from people around him and the difficulty of raising funds, Countless times, after he got on the elevator, his fingers hesitated and hesitated between the first floor and the floor where his home was located. &quot;I have been struggling like this for two years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some people may think that it is enough for their wives to have enough food and clothing, and for their children to have money and study; some people think that they should set an example for their children, so that the people they love can have a bright face in front of and behind others.&quot; Xia Qiong said that her husband Zhang Hong &quot;may be the latter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zhang Hong successfully climbed Mount Everest, some subtle changes occurred. People in the hospital used to refer to Zhang Hong as &quot;Dr. Xia&#39;s husband.&quot; Now, they call her &quot;Zhang Hong&#39;s wife.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When her son was two years old, Xia Qiong and a relative turned off the lights and asked her son in the darkness: Who do you want to protect when it gets dark? The two-year-old son said sweetly: Protect daddy. Xia Qiong and her female relatives were puzzled: We are all women, why should we protect our father? The son said without thinking: Because dad can’t see. Today, the son feels that his father is &quot;very capable&quot; and &quot;relatively strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;范立欣和夏琼都观察到，攀登珠峰成功之后，生活中的张洪变得松弛许多。失明之后，他曾一度难以接受弱人一等的感受。他和每一个普通人一样有自己的缺点，但他宁愿听到平视的批评，也不要俯视的褒奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“攀登珠峰之前，我在外面那么多年，从来不跟别人讲起我家人的事情，只有我老婆知道，除此之外没有第三个人知道，但是珠峰下来以后，我可以跟任何人分享我家里发生的任何事情，包括我爸爸、叔叔看不见，以前我是没有办法面对，现在我可以从容地面对这些事情。”张洪说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“制造业当家关键在于人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259951]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2008年，胡小燕当选首批农民工全国人大代表。（受访者/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1051&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2008年，胡小燕当选首批农民工全国人大代表。 （受访者/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“一路换乘火车和汽车，整整花了三天三夜，我才来到佛山。所以，我对广东的第一印象，大概就是晕车的感觉。”那是1998年深秋，胡小燕24岁，为了还清家人欠下的两万多元外债，她决定离开家乡四川广安，踏上人生中最远的一次旅行——到广东打工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;35年后，胡小燕已是佛山市三水区工商联专职副主席。 2023年10月25日，在第三场“改革开放45周年身边故事会”上，她回忆起刚到广东打拼的岁月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;十年间，胡小燕从电子厂流水线女工一路升至陶瓷生产车间的管理层，被评选为“佛山市十佳外来工”。 2008年，农民工群体首次有三位代表参加全国两会，其中，就有来自劳务输入大省广东的胡小燕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;改革开放以来，“民工潮”促进了中国的工业化和城镇化进程。作为劳务输入大省的广东，仅1988年，前来务工的外省劳动力就达300万左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;活动由广东省政府新闻办主办，除胡小燕外，还邀请了中国科学院南海海洋研究所二级研究员尚晓东、广东省机械技师学院教师杨登辉讲述自己的故事。三人所处年代、背景各异，他们的共同点是，都是广东的外来人才。尚晓东在恢复高考后考上太原工学院（现太原理工大学），32岁读研，2005年来到广东，攻关物理海洋研究。 1997年出生的杨登辉则是世界技能大赛数控铣项目的冠军，曾就读于广东省机械技师学院，当选第十四届全国人大代表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月26日，云浮市某农业科技企业，工人们在培育花卉幼苗。该公司在当地乡村振兴人才驿站的帮助下，解决了产业人才、技术短缺难题。（陈宇龙/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256983&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月26日，云浮市某农业科技企业，工人们在培育花卉幼苗。该公司在当地乡村振兴人才驿站的帮助下，解决了产业人才、技术短缺难题。 （陈宇龙/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;首批农民工人大代表&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“作为2亿多农民工群体的代言人，我参加了5次全国两会，一共提了20个建议，每一个建议最终都落实到农民工的身上。”胡小燕提到，改革开放以来，农民工群体权益的保障制度一直在变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;农民工是伴随着改革开放而生的群体。 “包产到户”将农村富余劳动力从土地上解放出来，大量农村人口涌入城市寻找机会。这一趋势延续至今，据国家统计局数据，世纪之初农民工数量为7849万人，而2022年的总量超过2.95亿人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1979年确定的四大经济特区，广东独占其三，这催生了对劳动力的巨大需求。胡小燕就这样加入了南下的行列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;农民工的涌现，也让农民工问题凸显。 2006年，国务院的相关文件中提到，当时存在农民工工资偏低和拖欠、职业病和工伤事故多等问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2008年1月，广东省人大常委会选举委副主任杨成勇向媒体透露，广东作为外来人口流入第一大省，拟在选举产生6位农民工省人大代表后，选举产生一名农民工全国人大代表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在那之前，广东在保障农民工的政治权利方面已经走在前列，2000年，深圳市人大换届选举时就产生了四位外来务工人员代表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最终，胡小燕成为首批农民工全国人大代表，但此前，她从未担任过乡、县、市、省任何一级人大代表。胡小燕向南方周末记者回忆：“我不觉得有困难，因为我本来就生活在他们（农民工）的群体当中了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;胡小燕提到：“首批农民工全国人大代表，成为我身上最瞩目的标签。从那以后，我开始学习怎么去调研、写建议、发言，学着如何履职。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;成为全国人大代表后，她利用休假时间走访工友，提出了包括欠薪入罪、医保对接、异地高考、住房福利等建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;几乎同一时间，国家政策也转向考虑农民工进入城市后产生的新需求。胡小燕曾建议“允许农民工子女在打工地参加高考”。 2013年底，广东省正式公布实施随迁子女异地高考实施办法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如今，更多的“胡小燕”成为人大代表。十四届全国人大代表中，农民工代表有56名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月26日，广东肇庆市技师学院内，学生们在练习工业机器人操作。（陈宇龙/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年10月26日，广东肇庆市技师学院内，学生们在练习工业机器人操作。 （陈宇龙/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;科学家与工匠&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;32岁读研的尚晓东，说自己和胡小燕“拥有相同的起点”，都曾是车间工人。只是年代要更为久远。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;转折发生在1978年，尚晓东听说高中同学考上了大学，自己也开始备考。第二年，他凭借自学，考上了太原工学院的物理基础部物理师资班，毕业后被分配到中国人民武装警察部队指挥学院担任教员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;十几年后，他又敏锐地发现，身边硕士多了起来，觉得“再不学习就要落后”。完成天津大学力学系的研究生学业后，又到中国香港、美国深造。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2005年，尚晓东来到广东，进入中国科学院南海海洋研究所。此前，广东刚出台了“关于加快建设科技强省的决定”。 “这里有良好的科研氛围，这里有先行先试、大胆尝试的激情，这正是我们一家选择扎根广东的原因。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刚回国时，海洋观测仪器长期被国外垄断，尚晓东决定带领团队自主研发海洋观测仪器。最终，团队研制出了国际上响应最快的“海洋探测快速温度传感器”，响应时间为7毫秒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在“科技强省”的政策下，广东还希望破解科技与经济“两张皮”的问题。以新技术赋能新制造业，看重的是科技创新与产业的融合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨登辉表示，2014年报读技师学院后，他“每天在和比头发丝还细的东西较劲”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;技工出身的杨登辉，看到了“制造业当家”背后对人才的新需求。 “制造业当家关键在于人”，他认为，除了需要尚晓东这样的科研人才在前冲，还得要大量的高技能人才做支撑。这是他选择留在广东省机械技师学院任教的重要原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨登辉入校后被选入备战43届世界技能大赛的集训队，参训的项目是数控铣，是一种自动加工技术，通过电脑绘图和编程实现零件加工。当时，中国在这一项目没有拿过金牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;想要在数控铣项目取得成绩，必须练好“刀工”：根据零件的不同材料、生产要求选择合适的刀具，还要严格把握零部件的精度，误差控制在0.02毫米以内。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2017年，再次出师的杨登辉拿到了44届世界技能大赛的数控铣项目冠军，那年他仅有20岁。毕业后，他转而加入了技工教育的队伍，指导的学生在2019年、2022年再次取得这个项目的世赛金牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;广东省人力资源和社会保障厅数据显示，目前，广东技能人才总量为1850万人，其中高技能人才631万人，高技能人才占比34.1%。 2023年，杨登辉也成为了全国人大代表，自然将履职重点放在技能人才培养上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“（希望）帮助技能型员工突破晋升的&#39;天花板&#39;，让更多人才在广东施展拳脚、大有作为。”活动现场，杨登辉表达了他的愿景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违法转运火化遗体，蓄意瞒报4死4伤事故，36人被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:36:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;2023年4月2日13时29分，吉林省白山市江源区吉坤矿业有限公司（以下简称吉坤煤矿&lt;/span>;）+290m东一石门南翼二层四上山采煤工作面发生一起较大瓦斯爆燃事故，造成4人死亡、4人受伤（另有4人身体不适，经吸氧后痊愈），直接经济损失1016万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故发生后，吉坤煤矿未按规定报告，采取违法转运和火化遇难人员遗体、封闭事故现场等方式隐瞒事故。接到群众举报后，白山市应急管理局与江源区应急管理局于2023年4月3日至12日到煤矿核查举报案件时，该矿仍未如实报告。 4月13日、14日迫于压力该矿投资人、矿长等4人先后投案自首，事故经白山市人民政府查证属实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，国家矿山安全监察局吉林局公布该起事故调查报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;事故发生经过&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年4月2日白班，矿长李永海组织召开班前作业会，生产副矿长李艳平、总工程师陆万平和技术顾问李世臣分别向各队布置了生产作业任务。会后，采三队队长杨立成向事故班班长王洪昌布置了当班生产任务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王洪昌班组出勤13人，瓦检员1人。王洪昌安排冷军、纪耀敏、张成学和张庆龙在三上山放炮出煤，自己和王俊福、孙成在四上山放炮出煤，李军生和郭文生在五上山打木垛加固，杨连鹏和高才在大巷装车，黄福军和张永胜负责拉煤。路祥负责检查瓦斯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作业人员于8时左右从废旧暖风硐入井，在该处的“矿灯超市”自取矿灯，未携带人员定位识别卡和自救器，8时15分左右到达各自作业地点。 10时左右，为解决五上山工作面的通风问题，通风队长管彦林带领3名工人将设在+290m东一石门四上山和五上山之间的局部通风机后移20米，并从风筒分岔处向五上山接风筒，此台局部通风机同时向三上山、四上山、五上山3个作业面供风。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;13时30分左右，在三上山作业的纪耀敏等人突然看到一股黑烟，风也停了，感觉到呼吸困难，看不见东西，张庆龙和张成学率先往外逃生，纪耀敏和冷军拿工具后随后往外跑，当二人跑至三上山口时发现巷道有风，此时张庆龙和张成学趴在地上失去意识，他俩立即做心肺复苏进行抢救，约5分钟后二人苏醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，正行走到+290m中央水泵房硐室门口的项目部经理刘铁柱感到风流有较大的波动，又看到东一石门方向风流中灰尘很大，于是前去查看，分别看到了受伤的路祥、高才和郭文生（高才和郭文生烧伤严重），并在三上山口听到了冷军的声音，随即返回将路祥送到+290m水泵房，并向调度室打电话报告事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;事故救援过程&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;调度员孟凡军接到事故报告后，向矿长李永海报告了事故，李永海立即将情况报告给矿井投资人王浩铭和法定代表人丛培福，并安排李涛和霍建国组织人员下井开展救援。救援人员先后遇到路祥、张成学、纪耀敏、郭文生、黄福军和张永等生还人员，并派人护送升井。同时在风机开关处发现1人（杨连鹏）被煤炭掩埋，仅外露一条腿，现场确认已死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;救援人员发现四上山口冒落，检查四上山口里侧一氧化碳浓度999ppm（便携式多功能检测仪量程0~999ppm）、瓦斯浓度0.1%、氧气浓度5%，判断四上山内人员应全部遇难，随后继续搜救生还人员。行至三上山口时落煤将巷道堵住，发现三上山里有4人呼救，立即清理落煤进入三上山将重伤人员高才、李军生救出；接着将右腿不能站立的张庆龙架出，最后将冷军救出并护送至地面。 18时10分，生还者已全部到达地面，分别送往医院救治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18时40分，救援人员开始清理杨连鹏遇难处堆煤，将尸体扒出运至地面。随后逐段排放四上山一氧化碳，当排到距离山口13米处，发现遇难人员王洪昌。继续排放瓦斯，在躲避所下方约1米处发现遇难人员王俊福和孙成。至此，遇难人员尸体全部找到并运至地面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;直接原因&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;+290m东一石门四上山与+355m采空区贯通，采空区瓦斯涌出；使用1台局部通风机同时向3个作业地点供风，风量不足，造成瓦斯积聚，作业人员违章放炮导致事故发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;事故瞒报过程&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;事故发生后，吉坤煤矿投资人、实际控制人王浩铭安排矿长李永海自行组织救援，不向应急部门报告；安排王振山和王卫东救治受伤人员和死者善后工作；安排丛培福协助矿长处理事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王卫东将4名较重伤者送到浑江区中医院，后又转至长春市吉林大学附属第一医院，4名感觉身体不适的工人被送到通化市医院进行吸氧治疗。王振山将4名遇难者分别送到了江源区公墓殡仪馆、江源区倪太医院、三岔子林业局医院停尸间、纺织厂殡仪馆，并与遇难者家属达成了赔偿协议。随后以每张五万元的价格向纺织厂殡仪馆馆长王永海购买了2份《居民死亡医学证明（推断）书》（以下简称《死亡证明》），导致2名死者遗体被非法处置。同时王振山安排人员于4月5日下午删除了与事故有关视频监控数据，蓄意隐瞒事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4月3日2时左右，现场救援工作结束后，李永海安排管彦林带领通风队人员入井，在+290m东一石门入风和+355m回风巷原密闭位置构筑“快速密闭”，将事故现场封闭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瞒报核查经过&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4月2日23时起，白山市应急管理局、吉林省应急管理厅、省委巡视组相继接到关于吉坤煤矿事故的举报。 4月3日，白山市应急管理局牵头与江源区应急管理局成立联合核查组，对举报案件开展核查，查看了安全监控系统、人员位置监测系统和视频监控系统，并对4月2日白班52名入井人员询问取证。至4月13日，核查组未发现吉坤煤矿发生瓦斯事故的迹象，对事故当班入井人员取证均表示吉坤煤矿未发生事故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4月13日上午，按照4月12日白山市委会议精神，由白山市和江源区两级政府有关领导牵头，组织公安局、应急管理局等部门成立联合核查组，对举报事项进行深入核查。 4月13日18时，吉坤煤矿矿长李永海、法人代表丛培福、安全副矿长李涛迫于调查压力，经请示投资人王浩铭同意后向江源区公安局自首，承认吉坤煤矿井下发生瓦斯事故，造成4人死亡、4人受伤。 4月14日，投资人王浩铭向江源区公安局自首。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经调查核实，白山市人民政府办公室《关于白山市江源区吉坤矿业有限公司“4·2”瓦斯事故的情况说明》确认：2023年4月2日14时许，吉坤煤矿发生一起瓦斯事故，造成4人死亡、4人受伤。经通化矿业集团公司矿山救护大队现场勘查，启封隐蔽区域密闭全面搜寻，未发现其他伤亡人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;36人被追责：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故调查报告共对36名相关责任人员提出问责和处理建议。其中，12人被建议移交司法机关处理：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对吉坤煤矿矿长、法定代表人、投资人（实际控制人）、总工程师等10人以及江源区中医院门诊科主任、江源区纺织厂殡仪馆馆长等共12名涉嫌犯罪人员移交司法机关立案查处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;8人被建议给予行政处罚：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对吉坤煤矿项目部经理、副经理、安全副总工程师、机电副总工程师兼调度室主任等8人分别实施行政处罚并撤销执业资格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;15人被建议给予党纪政纪责任追究：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对3名驻矿安监员解除聘用合同并责令在吉林省行政区域内不得从事煤矿安全生产工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对江源区应急管理局湾沟镇安监分局局长给予留党察看一年处分并免职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对江源区应急管理局煤监科二室负责人给予政务记大过处分并免职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对江源区人民政府常务副区长批评教育。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对白山市应急管理局分管副局长和执法支队队长、江源区应急管理局原党委书记兼局长和分管副局长、湾沟镇党委书记、镇长、副镇长以及江源区中医院院长、副院长等9名公职人员分别给予党纪政务处分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;吉坤煤矿被罚款、关闭&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对吉坤煤矿发生较大事故并瞒报合并共处500万元罚款，纳入联合惩戒对象；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉坤煤矿未取得安全生产许可证，在技改设计范围外非法生产出煤，属非法煤矿，没收违法所得和开采出的煤炭以及采掘设备，并处罚款，提请白山市人民政府依法予以关闭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海，他们进行了一场现实主义“万梗节”狂欢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259893]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月31日，上海巨鹿路上，cos白娘子和法海的年轻人。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月31日，上海巨鹿路上，cos白娘子和法海的年轻人。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万圣节过去了，但“万梗节”没有过去，这场大型狂欢在上海大都市里还存有余温。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每年11月1日是西方传统节日万圣节，它最热闹的时刻，在于万圣节前夜，小孩们会装扮成各种可爱的鬼怪，逐户敲门，不给糖就捣蛋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海2023年的万圣节来得更早一些，从10月28日开始，这座城市就切换到了魔幻的一面。各大主题乐园和部分网红酒吧都会举办万圣节活动，还有自发的街头聚会。街上出现了造型各异的魑魅魍魉。让人始料未及的是，极具中式风格的互联网梗异军突起，风靡全网，被戏称为一场新潮的“文艺复兴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当华灯初上，一条再普通不过的老街也能变成流动的盛宴。它会是一个童话世界，可以cos（cosplay,意指扮演）各种角色，体验另一种身份；可以是一种释放压力和表达自我的渠道；也可能是一个充满诱惑的流量池，当迈进池中的coser（扮演者）足够瞩目，喜提各大平台热搜榜也有先例，这意味着流量和金钱都将有机会纳入囊中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者采访了十余位“发疯市民”，据他们说，上海已经很久没有这样热闹过了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;10月30日，巨鹿路一带人流攒动。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/66c8c013f9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/66c8c013f9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;10月30日，巨鹿路一带人头攒动。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;巨鹿路上“纯粹的开心”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;出了地铁站，明黄灯光下的人流在往一个方向涌动。即使不用导航，也可以判断出巨鹿路大致的方位，越靠近那里，人流越密集。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万圣节氛围最浓的阵地，就是位于上海市黄浦区的巨鹿路，这是一条以法国邮船公司巨型邮轮“巨鹿号”命名的商业街，诸多具有西方异域风情的历史建筑，在这片繁华地带蔓延交错，其中最具有地标特色的是巨鹿路158号下沉广场，也是历来万圣节最火热的打卡地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日傍晚，上海夜色渐浓，狂欢开始了。有骑着共享单车的如来佛祖不经意间从眼前晃过，浑身散着金光；有身着一袭红装、妖艳魅惑的僵尸新娘和火鬼王；也有身穿长袍的鲁迅，感慨学医救不了中国人；扮盆栽、演名画，甚至头套竖起一个中指，都可以成为一道光怪陆离的风景线……从巨鹿路到复兴公园不到1公里的路程，人流水泄不通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拥挤程度让警察紧张起来。通往巨鹿路的入口已经被警察用铁栏杆围挡，蓝红相间的警灯随处闪烁。交警一边维持秩序，一边重复强调：“我不是cosplay。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使是围栏，也挡不住人流热情，他们从附近大约十米的绿化坡地抄近路，偷偷溜进巨鹿路。南方周末记者跟随人流攀上坡地，从上往下看，巨鹿路如同一条流光溢彩的灯带，攒动的人头几乎占满路面整个空间，缓慢流动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相邻的成都南路则分散了部分从巨鹿路溢出的人流。相对来说，这里寻常许多，道路两旁是两三层楼高的民房，遍布服装店、皮包摊、小酒馆和苍蝇馆子，一位坐在街边的餐厅老板背后是满堂客，“平时没什么人到这里，从上个星期六开始到现在，店里人很多”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;走几步路，就会看到大大小小的黑白无常，他们衔着长长的红舌，黑白两色高帽上各自写有“天下太平”“一见生财”，其中不乏小孩子涂抹浓黑的眼影，扮相可爱。转角遇到白娘子和法海和谐相处，火爆韩剧《鱿鱼游戏》里的面具人靠墙站成一排，乖乖配合游客拍照，与惊悚毫不相干。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现场最受瞩目的是cos蝙蝠侠的男生们，他们体格高大，一方纯黑面具掩住双眼，下颌骨分明，表情冷漠。周边女生时不时传出一阵尖叫“好帅呀”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蝙蝠侠们已经巡游两个来回，每次总能引起现场骚动，他们的杀手锏是一言不合就脱掉紧身上衣，袒露出瓷实的胸肌。一圈又一圈人围上来欢呼，外围游客看不到，只管踮脚将举起的手机探往中心拍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;帅不过三秒，蝙蝠侠们就被警察推出了人群，人群里一阵笑声响起。这是万圣节维持秩序的常规操作，造成人流堵塞的人和“鬼”，都会被警察拎走换个地方，疏导人流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;蝙蝠侠壮男。李子旋摄&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蝙蝠侠壮男。李子旋摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位捧着金元宝的财神爷无疑受到了尊敬，合影游客排着长队，有人对着财神爷双手合十低头膜拜，求她保佑财运亨通。约半个时辰，财神爷被堵得一步没动，金元宝被人摸来摸去，每次要走时，都被合照的人拉住。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老年人的面孔也出现在人群中，他们也忙得不亦乐乎。或许是因为“看不懂，但大受震撼。”一位上了年纪的老人感叹，“我们也接触一下年轻人的东西，热热闹闹的，很好玩，很新鲜。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你不觉得这是一种释放吗？一种压力的释放。”另一位上海爷叔跟南方周末记者搭话，他已经在路边站了两个小时，专心观察和感受狂欢气氛。爷叔是老上海人，但从没有见过这样的气氛，“看到这样的气氛我很开心，我觉得大家也是发自内心的开心，这不是一种节日，大家只是借节日的由头开心罢了，纯粹的开心”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“一起发疯，释放压力”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;巨鹿路附近的地铁口出现了新奇一幕，很多人围在一起交流专业。以至于地铁口又被堵塞。有人说是学法律的，有人是学土木工程的，也有人学建筑的，大家都因为在对口行业不好混，叫苦连天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;引发强烈共鸣的是被围住的男孩小谢，他扮相憔悴，嘴唇煞白，胸前挂的纸牌上写了四个大字：学建筑的，还端着装有两团卫生纸的外卖盒，一副穷困潦倒的模样。“确实这个行业不是很景气，我工作也不顺利，所以就借此机会可以一块发疯。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大家都在发疯，正好我也想发疯。感觉好爽，把内心的压力释放出来。”小谢刚干了一件大胆的事，2023年10月他裸辞了。那是一段“想卷卷不动，躺又不敢躺”的工作，大家下班不敢离开座位，自己被领导追着提工作要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更出圈的打工人，是同一条街上游荡的乙方扮演者李秋白。他妆容粗暴夸张，面部涂抹的深色眼影和高光使其看似颧骨突出，脸颊凹陷，方格衬衫领口夹一张写有“乙方”的A4纸，活脱脱呈现了一个被甲方长期压榨的憔悴打工人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;乙方coser。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1194&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乙方coser。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我cos一个刚刚交完班的一个角色，没有想到效果这么好。”李秋白的确刚刚交完班，到达巨鹿路已是深夜，临时决定表演一个疲惫的乙方，一直有人围上来合照。他的社交账号浏览量已经“爆掉了”，不少网友留言表示有共鸣，“有的人看段子，有的人照镜子，这样的评论很多”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可能是因为疫情之后，没有一个能大家放得开的这种活动，之前几个节日虽然是放假，但也各种票抢不到。”李秋白说，如今到了一个可以全员发疯的节日中，自己反而有了一个发泄的出口。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这里，李秋白还遇到不少不用任何装扮的穷鬼，以及怨气深重的甲方，还有人高举牌子：“平时扮演自己就已经很辛苦的人万圣节什么都不用扮也是OK的。”李秋白将这类cos总结为：用现实主义的表达手法，呈现打工人最恐惧的事情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚，不少coser称刚下班就过来了。一位纣王在公司化完一副庄重的戏剧脸谱，走街串巷地找两位素不相识的妲己组CP；一位28岁的年轻人专门从浙江省嘉兴市驱车赶来，她cos宫崎骏经典动画角色无脸男，弓着腰默默站在路边，前后有一百多个人围过来合影。因为第二天还要上班，她又连夜回嘉兴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王公子选择用另一种方式释放自我，她扮演了和自己同为37岁的海绵宝宝。平日里，她从事公司商务工作，张口闭口谈的都是性价比、公司最大效益，但在万圣节来临前，那副自制的黄色毛毡板方壳，使得她纯粹地成为快乐的化身。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王公子此前cos海绵宝宝走进欢乐谷时，立马成为焦点，甚至被游客误认为是园内专业的工作人员。一大群叽叽喳喳的小孩子跟在她屁股后面，塞给她糖果，还抛出十万个为什么：蟹老板给你放假了吗？为什么不带小蜗一起来玩？蟹堡王的秘方是什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那晚，王公子说，一行人都玩疯了。一旁cos海底捞服务员的同事迪迪西原本是个典型的i人（指性格内向的人），在这种氛围下，直接重塑为e人（指外向），她会主动凑到一些游客面前，疯狂表演无实物扯面，双手在空中胡扭一通，但扯得自我陶醉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当晚，迪迪西还采访了cos卖79元眉笔的”李佳琦“，对方拉长声音回应“哪里贵啦？一直都是这个价格，真的烦死啦。”迪迪西当场爆笑。这则视频后来意外出圈了，王公子和朋友们都惊呆了，眼前的社牛女孩，还是以前那位在人前不敢讲话、假装埋头看手机的迪迪西吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她第二天清醒之后更i了，回想起来觉得自己好尴尬，有一点点丢脸。”迪迪西的朋友向南方周末记者回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没过几天，迪迪西就带着比自己更i的两位朋友杀向巨鹿路，她化上浓妆，又e回去了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;街头有人cos学计算机的。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;街头有人cos学计算机的。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“趁着热度涨点粉”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;陈研志又上了热搜。2022年，他一身安陵容的打扮，穿着溜冰鞋翩翩起舞，就曾上过一次热搜。毕竟，《甄嬛传》是全民“电子榨菜”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个民间的欢乐海洋中，这次万圣节也成为流量的狂欢，不少视频团队游走其间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她就是这么火爆。”cos安陵容婢女的阿莹略有得意，她告诉南方周末记者，在决定表演“安陵容在船头唱歌”场景后，几个广告人组成的团队做了精心策划，在短视频平台发了“解冻”预告，寓意安陵容回归，还做视频邀请函，附有路线规划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们找的是货拉拉把道具船拖过去，刚从货拉拉下来，就有好多人喊安陵容。”10月28日晚，安陵容坐着船一出场，就被人流包围，直接分走了附近其他coser的流量。他们戴上廉价的假发，穿着与剧中一模一样的服装，船头的安陵容手持莲花，蓝牙音响里播放音乐《江南可采莲》，众人跟着合唱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时团队拍摄的短视频，点赞量飙升到数万。到了第二次在复兴公园出场时，现场直播有上千人观看。“蛮好玩的，大家不约而同有非常多的创意，终于看到上海人民的松弛感了。”阿莹说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前安陵容妆造的出圈，也启发到了杭州男孩醒醒。在这次万圣节中，他以cos向太的形象火出了圈。在其传播最广的一段视频中，醒醒穿着团队临时花了400元买来的粉红色大衣，一脸富贵相。有人问他怎么看待向太儿媳郭碧婷，他微微一笑：模仿道：“挺好操控的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，向太本人隔空回应：“衣服太low了，他应该模仿得更漂亮点。”这让醒醒团队受了惊，原本大家调侃，万圣节cos明星的阵仗，足以收到全网明星律师函，但火到这种程度，还是让人猝不及防。“我们其实是有点害怕的，怕万一向佐团队找过来说我们有什么问题，但他们最后只说互动一下，那就去互动了。”醒醒团队工作人员阿眯对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿眯介绍，醒醒本职是一名自媒体美妆博主，向太妆造火后，有不少合作商家找上门，“非常多人私信我们谈合作，要醒醒去扮向太互动，我们拒绝了，挺怕被骂的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人忐忑，有人欢喜。当看到向太和安陵容在网上爆火后，那英的扮演者这英也动了心。“那我必须去呀。”11月1日，她在南方周末记者采访的电话那头模仿那英的口吻。此前，她买来《妻子的秘密》剧中黎明朗的衣服，最低配版的墨镜、发夹和话筒，连去巨鹿路三晚，模仿那英不断输出“那言那语”，“我一张嘴，他们就嗷嗷叫唤”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;效果立竿见影。这英版的那英，走到哪里都自带流量，即使是戴上口罩，摘掉眼镜，换上朋友的衣服，还是会被人认出来，狠狠体验了一把明星被追的待遇。“他们以为我是真的那英，所有人尖叫，说太像了，喊&#39;那姐，别跑&#39;，&#39;那姐，给我拍照&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我去之前我就知道会出圈，只是不确定会出圈到什么程度。”三天下来，这英的抖音粉丝涨了近十万，她紧紧抓住流量密码，“万圣节当晚回到家后，我还开了一场直播，希望可以趁着热度涨点粉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在10月31日现场狂欢中，一声嘶吼突然让噪杂的人群顿了一下。“还让不让人过了？”一个陷在人流里的外卖小哥发了火，他的车轮此刻寸步难行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但很快气氛就恢复了，这样的场景并不陌生，时不时就有外卖员在沸腾的人群里嚷嚷：“让一让，超时了，超时了。”在这场分不清楚真真假假的狂欢活动中，很难不让人怀疑，他们是在cos外卖小哥。在采访期间，也有人向南方周末记者投来疑惑的眼神，问“你是在cos记者吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到临近午夜时分，巨鹿路的人流逐渐淡了下来。跨过这个夜晚，上海又将回归大都市节奏紧张的一面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（文中受访者姓名均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>