<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[硬气王哲林爆扣韩国队，中国男篮领先14分胜韩国队进入半决赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258064]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:38:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72924&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69778&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game. .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/04/fd3be43b1c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252974&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin dunked during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At noon on October 3, 2023, in the quarter-finals of the Hangzhou Asian Games men&#39;s basketball team, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team defeated the South Korean men&#39;s basketball team 84-70 and advanced to the Asian Games. The top four. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team was tested in the group stage, it ushered in the Korean team, one of the most popular teams in the Asian Games. Compared with other strong Asian teams, the South Korean team is basically playing with all its main players in this Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72925&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69779&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game. &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/11f464e5ae.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 252975&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Hu Mingxuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72927&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69781&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/1ecd290854.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhao Rui made a layup during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhao Rui A layup in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1ecd290854.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252976&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023, China Team player Zhao Rui made a layup during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72922&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69776&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Hu Jinqiu made a layup during the game..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Hu Jinqiu A layup in the game.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/29ccbb6270.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252977&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 3, 2023, China Team player Hu Jinqiu made a layup during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72921&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69775&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin dunked..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin dunked.&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/85b7583835.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252978&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin dunked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Chinese men&#39;s basketball team mastered the rhythm and was excellent in offense and defense. It showed full strength and led by 20 points in the first half. In the second half, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team made relatively more mistakes, but it remained tough on the defensive end and firmly held on to its advantage. In the end, it defeated the South Korean team 84-70 and reached the semifinals. From this game, we can see the fighting spirit of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball players. Zhu Junlong and Hu Jinqiu took the initiative to fall to the ground many times to fight for the ball; Zhao Rui made a strong breakthrough in the opening stage and scored consecutively; Du Runwang completed the task of outside shooting brilliantly, and on the defensive end And tried their best... The Chinese men&#39;s basketball team really worked hard to win this game. In the whole game, Du Runwang had 16 points, Hu Jinqiu had 14 points and 7 rebounds, Zhao Rui had 8 points but had 6 turnovers, Zhu Junlong had 16 points, Zhang Zhenlin had 9 points, Hu Mingxuan had 10 points, Zhao Jiwei had 5 points and 8 assists, and Wang Zhelin had 6 points. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72923&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69777&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Previously, Chinese men&#39;s basketball coach Djordjevic has made it clear many times that the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team&#39;s goal in the Hangzhou Asian Games is to win the championship..jpg&quot; alt=&quot; Chinese men&#39;s basketball coach Djordjevic has made it clear many times before that the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team&#39;s goal in the Hangzhou Asian Games is to win the championship.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/1653a91397.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252979&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chinese men’s basketball coach Djordjevic has made it clear many times before that the Chinese men’s basketball team’s goal in the Hangzhou Asian Games is to win the championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In previous interviews, Chinese men&#39;s basketball coach Djordjevic has made it clear many times that as the defending champion, the goal of the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team in the Hangzhou Asian Games is Win the championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72926&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69780&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the men&#39;s basketball 1:4 final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team, watched from the sidelines. .jpg&quot; alt=&quot; On October 3, 2023, during the quarter-finals of men&#39;s basketball at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team, watched from the sidelines.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/0174378d7c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252980&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, in the quarter-finals of men&#39;s basketball at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and leader of the men&#39;s basketball team, watched from the sidelines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Next, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team will face the Philippine men&#39;s basketball team, which has defeated us in the World Cup, in the semi-finals at 20:00 on October 4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72928&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69782&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the audience cheered for the Chinese team..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 3, 2023, the audience cheered for the Chinese team Audience.&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/04/092dbe47ab.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252981&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 3, 2023, cheer for the Chinese team live audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[莫斯吾冰川：人迹罕至，傲然挺立丨眼睛在旅游⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 11:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王笛：茶馆里的历史学家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV10jWfkJLuh9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/k7XSaOnKmcU72AMhUa66c91RrEJSV 10jWfkJLuh9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Di at Heming Tea House in Chengdu People&#39;s Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Hua Xiaofeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Public Space&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Historian Wang Di&#39;s &quot;Teahouse: The Decline and Renaissance of Chengdu&#39;s Public Life 1950-2000&quot; is in Chengdu Xing Bookstore held a new book sharing session. The founder of the bookstore, Zhang Feng, set up a traditional tea seat in front of the stage at the entrance of the bookstore: a table, three bamboo chairs, three bowls of tea, and a thermos. Zhang Feng, as the host, sits on the right. Sitting on the left is artist Wang Hai, who was Wang Di’s classmate at Chengdu No. 3 Middle School. Wang Di sat in the middle. When he didn&#39;t need to talk, he poured water for the two people around him from time to time. This made Zhang Feng feel embarrassed. Wang Di said: I am Dr. Tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The night after the event, Wang Di and I chatted until more than 10 o&#39;clock under the street lamp of Youxing Bookstore. Wang Di realized that it was very late and asked Zhang Feng who was waiting aside: &quot;When will the bookstore be open?&quot; Zhang Feng said: &quot;It can stay open as long as we like.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few months Previously, before the COVID-19 epidemic was over, Zhang Feng and Lingzi, who was studying for a doctorate in anthropology at Cambridge University, hosted a sharing session by Wang Di at the Dunba Bar in the suburbs of Chengdu. There was no theme and they could talk about whatever they wanted. Wang Di spoke from 7:30 pm to 12:00 midnight. Lingzi paused the chat to let the more than 100 listeners sitting around take a break. Wang Di thought he was done. But Reiko told him that it was just halftime. Wang Di was going to fly to Macau the next morning. I thought he would say, it’s too late today, so let’s just stop here. Unexpectedly, he said, today I will lay down my life to accompany you. The activity lasted until about 1 o&#39;clock in the morning. This is an amazing and vibrant atmosphere in Chengdu’s public space, and those who participate in it will lose track of time. This is the Decameron, but it is much more than the Decameron. I met Brother Feng in both Youxing Bookstore and Dunba. He seemed to be constantly posting about various activities in Chengdu’s public spaces. I admired his energy and he said it was nothing, it was very simple and it didn&#39;t take any time. I also met lawyer Zhang Ying again. She came to participate in Wang Di&#39;s sharing session. The &quot;Bright Dialogue&quot; she hosted is still running. She hopes that people can learn the awareness of thinking instead of just speaking. Skill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that Wang Di is back in Chengdu, he has been invited to many activities, almost all of which he talked about from morning till night. He was very patient with all kinds of questions, even though he had answered many similar questions many times. He has appeared in various media. He enjoys speaking to the public about his historical research and writing. His name is connected with &quot;street culture&quot;, &quot;pao brother&quot; and &quot;teahouse&quot; in the main fields of his research. He is concerned about the relationship between people and space, communicating specific words and objects. He thinks about the significance of history to the present and is willing to spread his thoughts to a wider scope. He became one of the most popular historians. At the sharing meeting, Zhang Feng talked about the rising &quot;public history&quot; and called Wang Di &quot;the historian in the teahouse.&quot; The background of their conversation was transparent. I could see behind the background board. Old aunties were sitting comfortably on bamboo chairs chatting. A courier guy wearing a helmet was walking with takeaways. People on motorcycles were walking by. Pass. This is a natural superposition of the lives of Chengdu citizens, forming a richly layered visual landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Teahouse: The Decline and Revival of Public Life in Chengdu, 1950-2000&quot; can be referred to as &quot;Teahouse (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Part 2&lt;/span >;)》. In &quot;Teahouse (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Part 1&lt;/span>;), also known as &quot;Teahouse: Public Life and Microcosm of Chengdu 1900-1950&quot;, Wang Di I have compared teahouses in Sichuan and other places, such as teahouses in Guangdong. &quot;Guangdong is generally called a teahouse. On the surface it looks like a teahouse in Sichuan, but it obviously serves the middle class and is different from the &#39;popular&#39; teahouses in Sichuan.&quot; When describing Guangdong teahouses, Wang Di used the word &quot;grand&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Macau, in order to intuitively compare with Sichuan teahouses, Wang Di took us to a Cantonese-style teahouse in the Grand Lisboa for morning tea. This teahouse is more like a fine restaurant, with far more dishes on the table than tea sets. The waiter brought us barbecued pork cakes and carrot cakes from a cart. There are already roast goose, shrimp dumplings, soup dumplings, siomai, beef brisket and fish soup on the table. This sumptuous morning tea costs more than a thousand patacas. The surrounding design is also very thoughtful. The wall decoration is designed with a steamer-like texture, giving people a feeling of steaming steam. Wang Di had been in such steaming heat. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The turning point&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;That day happened to be the time for the college entrance examination in the mainland, and schools in Macau began to have holidays. High school students in Macau do not need to take the college entrance examination. They all go to university through application. Wang Di feels that children in the mainland are too involved now. &quot;We like the imperial view of history, but we actually advocate being a superior person. We look down on ordinary people, so we hope that our children will not be ordinary people. Let every ordinary person live with dignity. This is what we should advocate. This is what I The reasons for emphasizing the civilian view of history.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mW0sgmuN7YkrFjGnaL409XWSgtaZHI3NHYzg1FwI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/mW0sgmuN7YkrFjGnaL409XWSgtaZHI3NHYzg1FwI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252387&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 17, 2023, Wang Di shared the new book at Xing Bookstore in Chengdu &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Wei Yi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di thought of his past. When the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, Wang Di happened to be on a business trip in Shanghai. He has returned to Chengdu to work for two years. Before that, he worked in the countryside in Meishan, Su Dongpo&#39;s hometown. His elder brother had already gone to the Yunnan Production and Construction Corps. He could not have gone to the countryside, but if he didn&#39;t go to the countryside, there would be no future and no job arrangement. &quot;I still want to go to the countryside. If I go to the countryside, I may have the opportunity to be recommended to go to university.&quot; Wang Di volunteered to go to the countryside and performed very well, but still did not get the chance to be recommended to go to university. In 1975, through recruitment, he returned to Chengdu and joined the Brick and Tile Factory of the Machinery Branch of the Chengdu Railway Bureau. &quot;Burning bricks and tiles is absolutely hard physical labor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am in the brick kiln class. The brick kiln is oval, and the fire is immortal. Along the edge of the fire, there are many kiln fire cycles. After entering, it is like a tunnel. You transport bricks out of the kiln. In this weather, dog days, when you enter, the fire is It was hot. I only wore shorts and a mask when I went in. I was covered in sweat. Only my two eyes were exposed. The kiln dust was very heavy. Several people piled bricks up, the rhythm was as fast as doing exercise. At that time, the food stamps were rationed. Ordinary residents were given 26 kilograms per month. Because we were doing heavy manual labor, the food stamps were 46 kilograms. When you see this comparison, you know how heavy this labor is. Generally, factories work on an 8-hour working day, but we work on a 4-hour working day because we can&#39;t be too tired. This is a place no one wants to go. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working in the brick factory for more than a year, Wang Di was transferred to the labor union because he could draw. He painted many paintings and painted many slogans. He wanted to be a painter but had no chance. He failed to become a painter, but this amateur skill still gave him the opportunity to escape from heavy manual labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The changing times gave him the opportunity to go to college. When China and the United States established diplomatic relations, he truly felt that times had changed. Wang Di, who had just entered college, wrote the following words in his diary on December 16, 1978: &quot;What an outstanding initiative and a great step. China and the United States have officially established diplomatic relations. The grievances accumulated over the years will be It was quickly eliminated. In the morning, we were in the political and economics class in the first teaching building. When we heard this important news, everyone flushed with excitement. When we heard that Vice Chairman Deng would visit the United States in January next year, we all clapped. This fully illustrates the will of the people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Xspu7YCSZb2PIyHt7ntjioMvMMeTtwV4asBjCpVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Xspu7YCSZb2PIyHt7ntjioMvMMeTtwV4asBjCpVg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252388&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Di’s graduation photo from the History Department of Sichuan University&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although many years have passed, the scene of that day is still imprinted in Wang Di&#39;s mind. More than two hundred people from the 77th and 78th classes of the History Department took political economics classes in the largest classroom in the first teaching building. Because it is a large class, the classroom has radio and amplification equipment. During the break, one of the students turned on the radio. Through the loudspeaker, everyone heard the news about the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States being broadcast by the Central People&#39;s Broadcasting Station. The noisy classroom fell silent, and then everyone applauded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teaching building of the University of Macau is very quiet. An art exhibition by University of Macau faculty members is being held in the library. Three of Wang Di&#39;s paintings participated in the exhibition, but he was busy with work and had not seen them yet. He took us around the library several times before we found the exhibition hall. His paintings are placed in the most conspicuous position in the exhibition hall. The three portraits are of Fairbank, James Scott and Carlo Ginzburg, three scholars he admired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When writing a preface to Barbara Tuchman&#39;s book Stilwell, Fairbank said: &quot;For a long time, the United States has tried to make China more like itself - this is a waste of time. Quixotic efforts, but failed many times, and now this kind of effort is rising again... &#39;In the end, China went its own way, as if Americans had never been there.&#39;&quot; Wang Di feels Fairbank&#39;s lifelong efforts were to strengthen the understanding and friendship between the people of China and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wang Di was teaching undergraduates at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, he collected American media reports on the May Fourth Movement so that students could write papers based on these original materials. These sources, to his surprise, were largely unused by historians. &quot;The American media mainly reports on major events in China, and also includes some introductions and analyzes of Chinese society and culture, as well as China&#39;s economy and education. The personal records I used and the media interviews with individuals are from their The China you see with your own eyes has details, stories, and feelings, which to a large extent make up for the lack of personal destiny and experience behind major events.&quot; Wang Di has always emphasized individuals and details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macao is one of the important birthplaces of the Revolution of 1911. Sun Yat-sen practiced medicine here, and there is a statue of Sun Yat-sen in front of Jinghu Hospital. Wang Di recommended me to visit Morrison&#39;s tomb. &quot;It&#39;s near the White Pigeon Nest, and it has a sense of history.&quot; When Wang Di&#39;s historian friends Yang Nianqun and Sun Jiang came to Macau, he took them there. Morrison edited and published the first English-Chinese dictionary, the Chinese-English Dictionary, was the first to translate the Bible into Chinese, and opened the first clinic integrating Chinese and Western medicine in Macau. He is a pioneering figure in Sino-Western exchanges, and Macao has historically been a bridgehead for Sino-Western exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the residence of the University of Macau, a waterway passes through the sea under the balcony. On one side of the sea is Macau and on the other side is Zhuhai. Seeing the coast reminds Wang Di of his fishing days in the United States. He has two major hobbies: fishing and growing vegetables. He planted many things on the balcony - Tianqi, cucumbers, fungus... and put aside his hobby of fishing. &quot;It&#39;s not always good for a professor to fish on the coast next to the university.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(laughing)&lt;/span>; On his balcony, he I never saw anyone fishing on the tidal flats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di has taught at universities in mainland China and the United States. Now that he has come to Macau, he feels that he has gained another perspective on thinking about history. Being at the junction of China and the West is helpful to his research. During the three years of the epidemic, many academic conferences have been suspended. After having this meal with us in Macau, Wang Di is going to Hong Kong to attend a meeting of Chinese and foreign historians. The conference does not require everyone to write a paper, but just talks about some recent ideas. Wang Di plans to take a bus to Hong Kong and take the Hong Kong-Zhuhai-Macao Bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reading&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Macau, Wang Di rarely went to teahouses. He likes roadside stalls. He introduced us to a shop near White Pigeon Nest to eat curry beef soup. &quot;The shop is right on the street, and diners eat on the street. It&#39;s delicious. I eat it every time I pass by.&quot; Children who come from such a shop facing the street, in the words of Wang Di&#39;s classmate Wang Hai, are &quot;street eaters.&quot; Baby&quot;. Wang Hai said that he is a &quot;street kid&quot;. Unlike Wang Di who grew up in a compound, &quot;street kid&quot; needs stronger ability to get around. Wang Hai feels that artists can get away with it, but historians cannot. This is the difference between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, Wang Di had a conversation with Liushahe, which made him feel nervous. When he was a child, he and Liushahe lived in the courtyard of the Sichuan Federation of Literary and Art Circles, and he and his brother would go to Liushahe to listen to stories. Also living in this courtyard are Sha Ting, Ai Wu and others. Wang Di&#39;s historical writing has literary and aesthetic self-requirements, which is probably related to the influence of the humanistic environment he grew up in. But those were not peaceful days. When he wanted to study, he had to sneak into the library of the Federation of Literary and Art Circles Library. It was an era when reading was like a thief. Wang Di only attended elementary school for three years, and did not complete middle school or high school. In high school, due to political review, he almost lost the opportunity to enter a higher education. But his habit of reading helped him. When the college entrance examination suddenly resumed, he was not so unprepared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, Wang Di was 21 years old and working in the railway bureau trade union. Train tickets are free and you can walk everywhere. The union provides good benefits and will be allocated some scarce goods. His parents felt that the job at the Railway Bureau was an iron rice bowl. Even if he went to college, the job assigned after graduation would not necessarily be better than it is now. They suggested that he wait for another two years. After working for five years, he could study with pay, and he could return to school after graduation. original unit. After listening to his parents&#39; advice, Wang Di did not take the college entrance examination in 1977. On the day of the college entrance examination, he happened to be on a business trip to Shanghai. Although he was a worker at that time, he &quot;worked for work&quot;, that is, doing cadre work as a worker, which seemed quite comfortable. In Shanghai, he happened to see candidates entering the college entrance examination examination room. Such a scene is a stimulus to him. He felt very lost, &quot;a feeling of being abandoned by the times.&quot; At that moment, he decided that he must take the exam next year, &quot;I can&#39;t wait any longer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He prepared secretly and did not dare to tell his parents. &quot;What if I give up again if they try to persuade me?&quot; At that time, he lived in a work unit and went home once a week. He didn&#39;t mention it when he got back, and only told his parents after the exam. The parents are still very happy. My grades were pretty good, and I did particularly well on the history test. I originally wanted to study Chinese, but actually I still wanted to draw. I felt that studying Chinese and art had something to do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met Wang Di at Chengdu Heming Tea House, he had just attended the 40th anniversary party of his college classmates the night before. Students still remember that Wang Di was the first student admitted to the History Department of Sichuan University in 1978. He scored 96 out of 100 points in history. When he went to report, it was No. 1. &quot;Actually, I didn&#39;t know what historical research was at that time. I just liked reading some history books.&quot; The composition of my college classmates was very complicated. When I first entered school, the youngest student in the class was 16 years old and the oldest was 32 years old. &quot;Now I can&#39;t tell my age, almost all of them are retired. There are groups of students who specialize in traveling, groups that specialize in drinking, and groups that specialize in playing mahjong.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among college classmates like Wang Di are still there There are very few people working. Wang Di is a chair professor at the University of Macau and can retire at the age of 70. For the 40th anniversary party, the students planned to go to Anren Town for two days. Wang Di has something to do and has to return to Macau. The classmates in Chengdu decided to get together in Chengdu one day in advance in order to meet Wang Di. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di behaves in a low-key manner. Every time he returns to Chengdu, he comes and leaves quietly. This time I returned to Chengdu, there were many public events, and I couldn’t hide them. Everyone gathered together. &quot;I don&#39;t want to be the protagonist and let others do the activities for you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He went to see his parents. My parents are in their nineties and live in a nursing home. A large number of books in Chengdu had been unused for many years, so he donated them to Sichuan University and let the graduate students divide them. Now, he misses those books a little bit. It was with those books that he wrote his first book - &quot;Out of the Closed World&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After so many years abroad, he used the newly collected research materials to write &quot;Street Culture&quot;, &quot;Brother Pao&quot;, &quot;Teahouse&quot; and other works. Chengdu Shuangliu District is currently preparing to build a Wang Di Documentation Center. The materials he collected will be placed here in the future and can be used by other researchers in need. Wang Di just visited this place. The documentation center has two floors and is very beautiful. Wang Hai is helping him do this. Wang Hai appeared in many of Wang Di&#39;s activities. He has a completely opposite personality to Wang Di. Even the word &quot;social cow&quot; is not enough to describe him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Macau, there are not many books on Wang Di’s bookshelf. He hardly collects books now. They are too heavy and inconvenient for him to use often. He mainly reads e-books and often listens to books. He has bad eyesight. He showed me the e-books he was reading, including Scott, Hayek, Wang Dingjun, and the newly minted Nobel Prize winner in Literature Anne Ernault. He wanted to tell the story of &quot;Tea House&quot; in the voice of a virtual century-old man, similar to Ernault&#39;s &quot;Unauthorized Autobiography&quot; in &quot;Years of Time&quot;. While Erno recalls himself, he also triggers the memories of others, and the resonance of memories shows the evolution of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di has been looking for these resonant moments in his memory. A lot of these moments are sinking. For example, when he was making bricks in a brick and tile factory, he was crowded into a large shed with twenty or thirty workers and had no private space of his own. While the workers were sleeping, he read under the lamp, but no one said that he kept the lamp on so late that it affected their sleep. The workers also made him a table out of scrap wood so that he could read and draw. &quot;It&#39;s probably the experience during that period that had a subtle influence on my later public view of history and the perspective of the lower class.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Youxing Bookstore, Wang Di talked about his generation, both Urban intellectuals who have been farmers and workers may be a unique generation in Chinese history. At the age of 22 - neither too early nor too late - he passed the sudden college entrance examination and turned his destiny around. At the age of 31, he became the youngest associate professor in the history department of a Chinese university at that time. When everything seemed to be going smoothly, he made the decision to go to the United States to study for graduate school and start over. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In the United States&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When Wang Di, associate professor of the History Department of Sichuan University, was preparing to continue his studies abroad, he received admission notices from the history departments of two American universities. One is Johns Hopkins University and the other is Columbia University. He chose the former and studied for a doctorate with the famous American historian William Rowe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;William Luo recommended Wang Di to read &quot;Cheese and Maggots&quot; by Carlo Ginzburg. This is Wang Di’s first time reading a micro-historical work. Ginzburg used the Inquisition archives to write the spiritual history of Menocchio, a small rural miller in northern Italy in the 16th century. Menocchio saw the universe as a piece of cheese riddled with maggots. The original work is in Italian, and the English version Wang Di read happened to be published by Johns Hopkins University Press. He read this micro-history classic countless times, and later in the New Cultural History discussion class he taught, he went over the details of the book with his students again and again. He believes that such intensive reading and discussion are more useful than giving students a long book list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di writes micro history. His three major topics were fully discussed with William Luo. When William Luo teaches his students, he doesn’t just tell them what he is good at, and then just let the students write about what they are good at. &quot;The students themselves have to have this impulse, and the teacher helps to deepen it. It does not mean that the teacher has a big idea and then assigns it to the students.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he discussed writing his doctoral thesis with William Luo, there was no &quot; The word &quot;street culture&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(street culture)&lt;/span>;. &quot;I introduced this concept first, and he said yes. I think students should think independently and deepen continuously. The teacher should make the problem concrete, rather than letting the teacher think for him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di has been practicing this Take a microscopic view of history. He feels that this requires more adaptation and understanding for us readers who are accustomed to historical writing having great significance and grand narratives. It’s not about more and more detailed historical writing, it’s about micro history. &quot;If we write a book about Zeng Guofan or Hu Shi, no matter how detailed and detailed it is, it will not be what we call micro history. One of the prerequisites of micro history is to write the history of ordinary people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ginzburg advocated paying attention to &quot;the persecuted and subjugated people&quot; because these people are often &quot;dismissed or even completely ignored by many historians as marginal figures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wang Di was writing his doctoral thesis &quot;Street Culture&quot; using micro-historical methods, his supervisor William Luo was writing &quot;Salvation - Chen Hongmou and the Elite Consciousness of Eighteenth-Century China&quot;. William Luo believes that this Qing Dynasty official, who was born in Hengshan Village, Lingui, Guangxi, can see the mentality of the elite at that time. This is a model of &quot;managing the world&quot; and the epitome of the prosperous Qing Dynasty. Obviously the research that Wang Di is interested in is different, but this does not prevent them from going to the Library of Congress to look up materials together. &quot;This may be the place with the most books and materials in the world.&quot; Luo William went to find Chen Hongmou, and Wang Di went to the teahouse. William Luo would ask Wang Di how to translate these lines of Chen Hongmou&#39;s poems appropriately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6ctY5BDmIsGaal8JWH6ziptVp4brWrixf8H8sMXY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6ctY5BDmIsGaal8JWH6ziptVp4brWrixf8H8sMXY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Di shared with readers in Chengdu&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Hua Xiaofeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;William Luo He expressed his thoughts in the introduction to &quot;Salvation&quot;: &quot;Now it seems that narrative works and intensive reading of historical texts are completely necessary. The emphasis on micro history has made the detailed study of the personal lives of historical figures extremely valuable. High status. &quot;Cheese and Maggots&quot; by Italian historian Carlo Ginzburg is a classic in micro-historical research. This makes me suspect that in this era, a scholar spent a lot of time studying a male elite Is it the most effective way to do research with an important political figure? Many articles published by Giovanni Levi, a high-spirited Italian historian, in the &quot;Annals&quot; eloquently prove: those who study big figures, such as Proper treatment, like the study of small figures, can help us understand past history.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people will also think that Wang Di&#39;s micro-historical research is similar to another historian Yang Nianqun&#39;s study of emperors. research will produce conflicts and contradictions. Wang Di doesn&#39;t see it that way. &quot;Actually, what we are saying is not contradictory. History is indeed determined by emperors and elites in many cases. He is telling the truth, but what I express is a view of history. Those who rule people should study it, and the people who are ruled should also study it. Yang Nianqun Studying the emperor does not mean that he agrees with the emperor&#39;s approach.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Di learned a lot from William Luo, including that a mentor does not dominate everything. Wang Di now teaches students New Cultural History at the University of Macau. Read original English works such as &quot;Cheese and Maggots&quot; by Ginzburg and &quot;The Return of Martin Guerre&quot; by Natalie Zemon Davis. Read a book every two weeks, 3 hours a week, and discuss a book 6 hours a week. He works out every detail with his students. He encourages students to think independently and put forward different opinions to teachers with reason and evidence. Sometimes the opinions are right, but sometimes they are not necessarily right. The opinions of both teachers and students are not unquestionable. &quot;This is a way of dialogue, not to prove who is right or wrong. Sometimes everyone uses the same information in different ways. There are multiple perspectives for interpreting history, but everything is based on careful reading. Go up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned before, Wang Di also received an admission notice from the History Department of Columbia University that year. The person who admitted him was historian Zeng Xiaoping &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Madeleine Zelin) &lt;/span>;. Her representative work is &quot;Zigong Merchants: Entrepreneurs in Early Modern China&quot; 》. When Wang Di&#39;s doctoral thesis &quot;Street Culture&quot; was published by Stanford University Press, one of the anonymous external reviewers was Zeng Xiaoping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/DGR4RJsBSdLmhTvu9Dw6YAKtsXlcI4mdZ4e3SaqI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/DGR4RJsBSdLmhTvu9Dw6YAKtsXlcI4mdZ4e3SaqI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Di growing vegetables on the balcony&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Fang Yingzhong/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Xiaoping wrote six or seven pages of comments for &quot;Street Culture&quot;, which is equivalent to a small essay. She gave Wang Di many suggestions for revision, one of which was: the point of view of this book is not very clear. This troubled Wang Di. &quot;I asked William Luo how to highlight the main points. William Luo told me a method. He said, you use one sentence to summarize each chapter, and then you combine these words in each chapter into a paragraph, and the theme of that paragraph This sentence is your main point. This is amazing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, &quot;Street Culture&quot; won the Best Book Award from the American Society for Urban History Research. Wang Di is very grateful to Zeng Xiaoping and Luo William. He has benefited a lot from the strict review questions and the effective methods to solve them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;William Luo is over seventy years old, less than ten years older than Wang Di. Sometimes, Wang Di would ask William Luo for advice. 2019, co-recommended by William Luo and his colleague Tobie Meyer-Fong at Hopkins ，王笛被选为该校的杰出校友&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（Soecity of Scholars）&lt;/span>;，这是很大的荣誉。王笛原本2020年春天要到美国参加颁奖典礼，并参加校长主持的晚宴，已经邀请罗威廉参加，但因为疫情限制，最终没能成行，这是他疫情期间最大的遗憾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在美国史学界，华裔教授获得认可并不容易。王笛说起何炳棣和黄仁宇，认为他们两人是美国华裔历史学者的两个极端例子。 “何炳棣的研究方式是美国史学界的正统，讲究实证，能得到专业上的承认，他一帆风顺，1970年代就担任美国亚洲学会会长，这是很不容易的。黄仁宇是另一个极端。他的书是大历史的写法，比如《万历十五年》，缺乏个案的研究基础，在美国史学界很难被接受，所以他的书在美国的出版屡遭挫折，最后他甚至失去了教职。黄仁宇的书纵横上下千年，读起来很舒服。今天，黄仁宇在读者里的名声远远大于何炳棣，《黄河青山》读起来比《读史阅世六十年》要震撼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛当年在德克萨斯A&amp;amp;M大学任教时，是历史系唯一一位华裔教授。上了年纪之后，最让王笛头疼的是交通不方便。大学里有机场，他要回中国，需要先从大学城坐小飞机到休斯顿、奥斯汀或达拉斯，然后飞到洛杉矶或旧金山，再飞到北京或上海。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在美国教了17年的书，从助理教授做到正教授，觉得要换一个环境了。当澳门大学向他抛出橄榄枝的时候，他接受了，2015年来到澳门大学。经过一年适应之后，他留了下来，曾担任澳门大学历史系主任，并担任讲席教授至今。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;波澜翻滚&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在澳门，王笛很多时候在食堂吃饭，或者在家用面条和速冻水饺解决问题。偶尔做川菜，也是采取最简单的办法，用火锅底料煮各种配菜。澳门大学横琴校区通过海底隧道与澳门相连，这里就像一个小社会，王笛因此能够远离尘嚣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的书桌斜对着阳台，落地窗外的船就这么从现实和历史的交通要道通过。他像生活在历史和现实之间。他是同时有历史感和现实感的学者。他希望能借助对历史的思考，对当下有所意义。 “历史充满偶然性，没有规律，但历史可以帮助我们思考。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛办公室外的墙上有许多图片和照片，有他从事专业研究的介绍，有日常生活的照片。其中一张2000年大学同学聚会的照片，同学们在打麻将。王笛不会打麻将，在研究茶馆之前，他也很少去茶馆。他看上去不像典型的成都人。他的同学王亥这样的“街娃儿”可能才是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛当年也许比王亥更想成为一个画家。他的书里经常有他的插画，比如我们正在聊天的鹤鸣茶社。他根据照片画了一张。他给《历史的微声》画了很多人物头像。 “这合乎我的理念，他们是我崇敬的人，我从他们那里汲取的思想和思考，展示这些需要借助艺术的手法，需要一些插图。我不喜欢简单放照片。《那间街角的茶铺》我也是画了插图的。画插图的想法，是我和这两本书的责任编辑李磊商量后的共识。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些年，王笛在国内出版的书很多，多到各出版社需要排队，避免在宣发上撞车。他对人民文学出版社正在推出的“王笛作品系列”很满意，“责任编辑李磊光是每本书的书名就想了好多作为备选。在文学性表达以及大众阅读和推广方面，也给了我很多提示和建议，并且安排了上海书展我和许纪霖的对谈，还有我和张明扬在上海思南的活动。”王笛说，在美国二十多年，他出版的东西并不多。 “我1991年去的美国，到了2015年，24年我只出了两本英文书和一本中文书，很少吧，但好多东西就是积累，积累之后会有爆发。”王笛今年67岁。有一种说法，60岁到70岁是一个历史学家的黄金时期。王笛正处在这样的时期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来鹤鸣茶社的路上，他一直在听书。 “我眼睛不好，眼睛留着写作。”他是珍惜时间的人，早上起来，漱口刷牙，做饭吃饭，他都在听书。他说他的生活是三书：写书、读书、教书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在澳门，按照王笛的指点，我在白鸽巢前地一所教堂后边的角落里，找到了马礼逊的墓。墓前的地盘上，有几位工人在拉线测量，估计是教堂和墓地需要修缮。几个小孩在教堂前踢球，球进到院子里，他们才会跑过来。白鸽巢前地是一个公共空间，这里最多的是下象棋的老人。传统像石头一样坚固。王笛说，在香港和旧金山都会看到类似的景象，那种从传统中延续下来的公共空间的构成部分，有的不以时间为转移。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年9月的成都双流彭镇观音阁茶馆前，我同样看到了下象棋的人，他们在那里坐了一早上。王笛《茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（下）&lt;/span>;》中转述了张戎在《鸿：三代中国女人的故事》中的回忆。成都的许多茶馆在“文革”之初被强行关闭。 “一个男孩甚至一掀棋盘，棋子全撒落在地板上，大叫着：&#39;不要象棋！你不知道这是资产阶级的爱好吗？&#39;随后把棋子棋盘都扔到河里，一些学生在茶馆墙上刷标语。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“破四旧”运动中，茶馆受到了冲击，在那里，喝茶“被视为旧社会的陋习，茶铺被看作藏垢纳污、阶级异己分子与落后群众聚集之所，强行取缔、关闭了茶馆”。此时，老虎灶在成都居民生活中仍然占有重要地位。 20世纪60年代的成都居民家中，燃料缺乏，老虎灶提供的开水比自己烧开水方便便宜。在茶馆喝茶少了，但买开水回家泡茶的人并没有减少。茶铺起到水铺的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在茶馆研究的问题上，王笛关心的是，是否地区或地方的研究可以提供理解中国社会和文化的普遍性知识。 “微观研究的意义在于，能够为把对历史的认识上升到一个更广义的层次提供个案分析，其不仅能丰富我们对地方的知识，而且有助于我们对中国的理解。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家与社会关系问题，是西方研究中国历史的一个着眼点。在1980年代末和1990年代初，罗威廉使用公共领域&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（public sphere）&lt;/span>;这一概念来研究近代中国时，遭到不少学者反对，他们认为哈贝马斯的概念不适用于中国。 “20世纪下半叶的中国有相当长一段时间，便处于有&#39;国家&#39;无&#39;社会&#39;的时代，国家掌握了政治、经济、社会、文化的一切资源，这是此前任何政权未能实现的。传统的&#39;公&#39;的领域也几乎不复存在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;姜文导演的《让子弹飞》已然是当代中国电影的经典之作，其中的桥段脍炙人口，在各种社交场合被频频引用。电影改编自马识途《夜谭十记》中的《盗官记》。在《盗官记》里，有这么一段对成都茶馆的细致描述：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们去过成都吗？那里有一个少城公园，少城公园里有一个鹤鸣茶社。在那里有一块颇大的空坝子，都盖着凉棚，面临绿水涟漪，是个好的风景去处。凉棚下摆满茶桌和竹椅，密密麻麻坐满喝茶的茶客，热闹得很。到处听到互相打招呼、寒暄问好的声音，到处是茶倌放下铜盘叫着“开水”的声音。这是一个普通的茶座，那些做小生意的、当教员的等等小市民们，就在这里来谋事，说合，讲交情，做买卖，吵架，扯皮，参加“六腊之战”，“吃讲茶”……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是曾经的鹤鸣茶社，许多情状还在，许多则已成往事。比如说“六腊之战”，指的是每年六月和腊月是学校教员受聘期满的月份，教员们为了争取继续聘用，四处奔走，为生活而战。 “吃讲茶”则是双方发生争执时，会请袍哥主持公道，双方在茶馆谈判，或和或打，就看这茶吃得怎样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/SM7mhTluQgqDzzOqCC5msjUxrmhRjmqhEIuapyiR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;623&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/SM7mhTluQgqDzzOqCC5msjUxrmhRjmqhEIuapyiR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252386&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在成都鹤鸣茶社拍摄茶客&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（华小峰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马识途的小说写的是民国时的事情。 1949年之后，马识途的回忆是这样的：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;既然茶馆不再是能支持革命的地方，我们必须坚决地消除它们。因此，茶馆倒闭了。尽管人们不喜欢这种不便，但他们除了无条件服从外，无能为力。实际上，一些有识之士认为我们可以取茶馆之益而去其之弊，当然，这样的话，茶馆的弊处将会完全被消除，茶馆将成为一个文化活动中心以及宣传教育的场所。但当局没有听见这些声音，因此，茶馆在四川大地上几乎消失殆尽。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛觉得鹤鸣茶社的历史几乎可以单独提出来独立成书，鹤鸣茶社的历史就是一部波澜起伏的电影，而不同人的眼中，有不同的茶和历史——&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看到同样的历史资料，人和人理解不一样。我们今天在鹤鸣茶社，可能不同的人有不同的感受。有的人可能看到脏乱差，有的人看到的是人和人在聊天社交，有的人看到茶倌在忙着掺茶，有的是看到谋生的人，有的看到掏耳朵的人，有的是看到我们在这聊天，摆着书，还有人在旁边照相。每个人看到的都不一样。本来这就是一个大千世界。卡尔·波普尔说，我们写不出整体的历史，包括鹤鸣茶社，我们都写不出整体的历史。我们看到的只是通过个体的眼睛，或者个体的研究者来理解的历史，任何历史都只是部分的历史。每个人写的都是碎片，不可能是全面的历史。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有的人说成都很好啊，有的人说成都就是大家无所事事。同样的事情，有的是积极的，有的是消极的。大家的经历不一样。有的工作很满意，有的始终找不到好工作，能说感受是一样的吗？历史就这样复杂，没有标准，也没有规律。相信历史有规律是很可怕的事情。过去的三年，病毒让全球都改变了。这有什么必然性啊。三年前，没有人预见得到疫情对世界的改变。所谓规律，是可以预见到的未来，历史真的不是这样的，很多时候只是人的一念之差。我们的现代社会，整个人类文明，不是人为设计的，一个社会自然进化可能更合理。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛从鹤鸣茶社旁边人头攒动的餐饮店里买了几碗水饺，这是我们的午餐。他说起吃的历史。 “我读幼儿园的时候，吃不饱饭，我还记得，小孩子跟着老师去其他班看看有没有剩下的饭，没有啊。这样的饿肚子的事情，就是人为设计的结果。”王笛生于1956年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他表达了他对整个中国历史的看法。 “我们要让社会充分发展。举个简单的例子，如果大家都在泰坦尼克号这样的大船上，如果在正确的航道上，大家没感觉有什么，一旦出现问题，大家就都完蛋。如果我们分乘50条船往前走，看起来缺乏效率，但哪一种选择更安全，这是非常简单的道理。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（上）&lt;/span>;》的尾声，王笛用了《寻梦》作为标题。他用非常感性的笔触描述了1949年的最后一天：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在过去的50年里，他们所光顾的茶馆，他们视为理所当然的坐茶馆的生活习惯，竟一直是国家权力与地方社会、文化的同一性和独特性较量的“战场”。他们每天到茶馆吃茶，竟然就是他们拿起“弱者的武器”所进行的“弱者的反抗”。这也即是说，弱小而手无寸铁的茶馆经理人、堂倌和茶客们，在这50年的反复鏖战中，任凭茶碗中波澜翻滚，茶桌上风云变幻，他们犹如冲锋陷阵的勇士，为茶馆和日常文化的最终胜利，立下了汗马功劳。如果他们知道自己在捍卫地方文化中所扮演的关键角色，就不会嘲笑这位通过时间机器突然降临、要为他们撰写历史的小同乡了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小同乡”指的是王笛自己。 2023年9月，王笛第九次来到成都双流彭镇观音阁茶馆，时间机器仿佛再次启程。他毫无意外地再次看到了在那里打牌的甘大爷和胡大爷。老板李强用老虎灶上取下来的水壶给他们的茶杯里倒入鲜开水，波澜翻滚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在王笛叙述的那些试图改变世界的大人物眼中，他们想着的是世界的波澜翻滚，而不是这碗茶。王笛在《历史的微声》最后一章中，提到了他脑海里浮现过的一个画面：“帝王或者英雄站在高高的山巅上，俯瞰整个大地，为自己马上要创造历史，而心潮澎湃，豪情万丈。极目望去，在他的眼中，是乌泱泱的人海，芸芸众生，小如蝼蚁。对他来说，面对这样的人海，多一个不多，少一个也不少，个体在这里已经失去了意义；个体的命运，在这里是无关大局的；芸芸众生之间，是没有区别的，甚至看不清他们的面孔。他们没有自己的故事，也没有自己的历史，当然也就没有自己的未来。如果这些芸芸众生为了帝王或者英雄所谓的&#39;宏大事业&#39;而死去，就无声无息地化为了尘土。在宏大的历史叙事中，个体是整体完全可以忽视的东西，这就是整体史的本质。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在观音阁茶馆，王笛走到甘大爷和胡大爷旁边，再次拍下了许多照片。而正在打牌的两位大爷对此习以为常，连眼皮都没抬一下。每天上午都出现在茶馆里，用一杯一块钱的茶度过一个上午，这样波澜不惊的生活也许才是最正常最让人安心的生活。王笛告诉我，“人民能够日复一日、年复一年预期到他们能够过着安静和平的生活，难道这不就是最宏大的叙事吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;真实是什么？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;王笛在办公室收到了四川大学学报寄给他的期刊。期刊的开篇便是他写的论文《“啯匪”和“会匪”：哥老会起源的新思考》。秘密会社一直是他所关心的主题。当年的《袍哥》是这一研究过程中的插曲。和袍哥有关的大量材料需要更丰富的形式来表现。对沈宝媛论文的研究，更像是对《奶酪与蛆虫》的一次具体的借鉴。 “原本并不打算写微观史，只是正好有这么一个资料。”意大利偏远地区的故事勾起他对四川乡下一起案件的联系。这正说明文明当中的许多形式具有共性，我们跟世界并不是那么不一样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近他会写到“三支半香”，会写到哥老会现实和精神的起源。他会运用霍布斯鲍姆《传统的发明》所提到的理念。袍哥联系着更繁复而未明的历史。如何认识这些故事，如何认识文本，如何认识档案，是重要的事情。 “不要认为记载在档案上的东西就是历史。档案的真实性并不比别人写的小说更真实。”王笛说起二十四史。 “二十四史就是官修的历史。这是皇帝希望我们相信的历史。许多历史经过伪造、修改，甚至销毁。如果没有二十四史，今天留给我们的历史，也许不是更少，而是更多。这些官修的历史有多少真实性？我敢说百分之一的真实性都没有。官修的历史只能代表官方，跟每个人的经历有出入。我反复强调，一个学者要有批判精神，包括对史料和历史写作的批判，没有批判的话，你的写作没有任何意义。当然，每个人都没法写出完全真实的历史，我们只是力图写出接近真实的历史。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TTdxD1WmktHHLBUgJQWhAr8LLxHBF2fPhclLVsnm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TTdxD1WmktHHLBUgJQWhAr8LLxHBF2fPhclLVsnm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王笛在澳门大学校园里&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者方迎忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和王笛站在下班高峰期的成都合江亭附近的路边等车。往西边走一段路，就到新南门。以前，成都还有城墙城门城楼的时候，南门叫“江桥”，南城楼是“浣溪”。顺着锦江往西边的方向看，看到的是和其他城市差不多的天际线，看不出这是成都。往东不远的地方是九眼桥遗迹。成都许多地方只剩下一个地名。那些貌似还在的地方，跟往年已经不一样。锦里、宽窄巷子好像是古色古香的街道，但保留下来的东西并不多。王笛原本住在大慈寺对面，庙里曾经有一个文博大茶园，“非常壮观”。他觉得这里曾是最有成都茶馆文化特色的地方，但已经有了翻天覆地的变化，成了太古里。文博大茶园长大的孩子和太古里长大的孩子看到的成都，哪个更真实？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都是和茶馆相连的，茶馆让成都成为成都。 “到口子上啖三花”曾经是成都人的口头禅，就像北京人说“您吃了吗”一样。不一定真的去喝茶或吃饭。一种可以成为日常口语的指代物，说明这件事情在日常生活中的重要。在口子上，在街角，那种传统茶铺不好找了。所以，游客们会去双流彭镇的茶馆打卡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王笛在观音阁茶馆门口跟老板李强聊起过去。他觉得观音阁茶馆现在的“两张皮”挺好。 “一张皮”是网红打卡之地。他们在这里喝一碗茶10块钱，买了茶可以喝茶休息拍照。 “另一张皮”是当地茶客的日常生活，以甘大爷和胡大爷每天雷打不动出现在茶馆为标志，他们用的是大茶杯，茶叶不一样，1块钱。两者相辅相成，构成了一个传统和现实融合的空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是成都历史为数不多的“活化石”之一。未硬化的室内泥地，土木结构的空间，竹椅、温水瓶、茶碗、老虎灶，各种嘈杂声随之而来。这是现实的声音，也是历史的回声。这是王笛所说的“历史的微声”。这里，普通的个体不是一个个抽象数字，而是一个个具体的人。他们喝着茶，打着牌，聊着天，将生活日复一日地进行下去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访魏纪中：亚运会溢出的正面社会效应越来越大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258062]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;87岁是一个早该退休的年龄了，但魏纪中计划工作得再久一些。 “新中国最健康的人”马约翰的一句话一直激励着他：“一个人要为体育事业干50年。”现在，他完全可以自豪地说：“我已经远远超过了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/dgb5qbv2Pj6F9dC6VsYbUwdejdtsaFRLQLWAI50a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/dgb5qbv2Pj6F9dC6VsYbUwdejdtsaFRLQLWAI50a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月22日，亚奥理事会终身名誉副主席魏纪中在亚奥理事会与杭州亚组委媒体吹风会上回答记者提问。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1958年，摆在魏纪中面前的有两条路：一条通往人民文学出版社，这符合外界对一名南京大学法国文学专业毕业生的期待；另一条路通往国家体育运动委员会（现国家体育总局），这源自一个年轻排球运动员的内心期盼。魏纪中决定遵从内心。他的英语和法语流利，这使他很快参与到新中国体育的外联事务中，是国内与国际奥委会主席萨马兰奇接触最多的人之一。在他六十五年雄心壮志的体育工作中，他几乎参与了新中国所有体育大事件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1986年起，魏纪中开始担任中国奥委会秘书长，然后成为中国奥委会副主席。魏纪中相信，体育能够向世界展示更“开放”的中国。深谙国际体育事务规则的魏纪中曾在国际排球联合会、亚洲奥林匹克理事会等担任多个重要职务。人们认为，魏纪中是2008年北京申奥成功的关键人物之一，他为申奥提出了不少建设性意见，是中国奥委会与国际奥委会之间的“桥梁”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杭州亚运会期间，魏纪中仍然保持着充沛的精神，他的工作排满行程，要一直待到亚运会闭幕。作为亚奥理事会终身名誉副主席，魏纪中参与亚组委的官方新闻发布会，接受媒体采访，回应亚运会举办的相关问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月29日，魏纪中在杭州接受了南方周末记者专访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“越来越多国家和地区希望举办亚运会”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;杭州亚运会是中国举办的第三次亚运会。三届亚运会的举办背景有什么不同？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1990年我们办北京亚运会，当时主要是改革开放后的对外需要。那届亚运会本来应该由日本广岛举办，后来我们通过亚奥理事会与日本广岛组委会协商，让他们把1990年亚运会先让给我们，然后他们再办1994年亚运会，日本广岛组委会同意了，这样我们就取得了1990年在北京举办亚运会的资格。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年广州亚运会，政治背景发生了一些变化。小平同志南方谈话以后，改革开放进入一个新的阶段，在这样的背景下，广州开始申办亚运会。而杭州举办亚运会，是在整个改革开放取得明显成就的基础上，我们要进一步开放，用开放来促进改革。在这样的大背景下，我们又申办了杭州亚运会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三次举办亚运会，整个国家的大环境和世界的大环境都有所区别。所以我说，每一届亚运会的举办，都有它的意义，而且除了体育的意义以外，还有不同的社会和政治意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/FSA2O42Krc4eDfhf3DkveyWV4GpZ9TkYDjONwvS9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/FSA2O42Krc4eDfhf3DkveyWV4GpZ9TkYDjONwvS9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，夜幕下的杭州奥体中心体育场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚运会目前一共举办了十九届，这是你第十一次参加亚运会。在你看来，亚运会越来越难办了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的看法正好相反。从现在情况来讲，希望举办亚运会的国家和地区越来越多：下一届在日本名古屋，日本以后还有卡塔尔和沙特阿拉伯等国家和地区接着举办。因此，亚运会越来越难办，和实际情况不符。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，从我们办亚运会的意义来说，除了促进体育运动发展，亚运会溢出的正面社会效应越来越大了。 2006年，卡塔尔以举办亚运会为契机，使卡塔尔从比较单一的石油输出经济，变成现在比较全面的开放型经济。卡塔尔当时只有一个国际饭店，没有什么高楼，你今天到（卡塔尔首都）多哈去看看，面貌全部改变了。从多哈（亚运会）以后，很多国家和地区已经认识到通过办亚运会所溢出的社会效益和经济效益，可以促使整个国家的发展，这一点大家的认识越来越一致。而且亚奥理事会也帮助各个国家和地区在办亚运会的同时，使它能够产生比较持续的社会效应和经济效益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;为了让更多国家拿奖牌&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1990年北京亚运有27大项308小项（金牌），杭州亚运会设40大项481小项（金牌），亚运项目数量多、类型多、金牌多，亚运会为何会考虑设置如此多的项目，这是否会降低体育的竞技性？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们为什么增加了这么多项目？目的就是促进亚洲体育运动发展，主要是发展中国家体育运动的发展。根据多年摸索，我们发现，（这）主要靠政府的支持和全社会对于体育的认同，这两点通过亚运会能够实现。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们设立更多项目就是为了使得更多国家和地区的运动员能够在亚运会当中取得好的成绩，也就是说，能够拿到奖牌。一个体育现在相对还不太发展的国家，通过运动员在亚运会上的表现，能够拿到金牌或者奖牌，对人民是一个鼓舞，政府也会满意。政府满意了之后，就会对于其他体育运动有更多的支持。因此，我们亚奥委采取了开放的政策，这些开放的政策，就是要让一些体育欠发达国家的运动员有机会来参与亚运大家庭的活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥运会主要是一些精英运动员的比赛，当然也照顾到群众性，但主要是精英运动员的比拼。因此，国际奥委会和组委会负担一切费用。而亚运会是付费参加的，也就是说每个运动员和官员每人每天要交50美元。当然，这50美元是不够（覆盖成本）的，组委会补贴给他们一些。比如，杭州亚运会运动员的餐食标准是500元，这一项就超过了缴纳的费用。政府愿意付费来让运动员参加比赛，这就说明政府对于体育运动的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，参加亚运会的运动员越来越多，已经超过奥运会参赛人数，这就说明亚洲体育运动是在发展的。我们设立更多的项目，特别是一些地方性的传统项目，就是要让更多国家和地区的奥委会能够在运动会上取得成绩。现在来讲，我们参赛的国家和地区的奥委会获得奖牌的比例已经超过80%。这样做确实能够推动发展中国家和地区的体育运动和发展，社会对于体育运动的认同度越来越高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;电竞是杭州亚运会颇受关注的项目之一。关于电竞入亚，亚奥理事会、国家体育总局和杭州亚组委进行过多次研究讨论。最终的决定是怎么作出的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;电子竞技是从电子游戏发展产生的，和传统体育类似。传统体育的一些项目，包括像足球、篮球、排球，也是从一些民众娱乐项目过渡到正式比赛项目。电子游戏和电子竞技有一个很大的而且涉及面很广的群体，职业选手来自这个群体，他们传统体育的天赋可能不那么高，却在电子竞技方面可能有更大的发展。既然有这么一个群体存在，我们就不能忽视。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于电子竞技，我们有一个认识的过程。电子竞技是体育，这个有争议，因为电子竞技与辞典里对体育的定义不符，但是从运动的观点来讲，电子竞技的竞技性一面与运动的定义有一定相符的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛泽东主席说“发展体育运动，增强人民体质”，把体育和运动区分开来，这两者有共同点，也有不同之处。我同意这样一个观点，电子竞技是一个运动项目，同时也是一个文化创意项目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们和国际奥委会在这个问题上不断沟通，电子竞技也不断改善，国际奥委会逐渐承认了电子竞技在不少方面和传统体育有共同之处。因此，国际奥委会首先提出来奥林匹克运动的虚拟化，现在又成立了电子竞技委员会。这就是说，我们传统体育的认识和电子竞技的认识是相向而行，开始融合，目的就是要使更多年轻人或者爱好者能够进入奥林匹克大家庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于电子竞技如何进入这个综合性的运动会，现在大家正在探讨。杭州亚运会把它作为一个与传统体育并列的项目。其他综合性运动会，比如英联邦运动会、南美运动会或者非洲运动会等，采取的是另外一种方式，就是把电竞作为一个业态和传统体育业态并列起来，一个大的运动会的范围之内，有两种业态的情形。如何更好地融合也在探讨之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“举国体制还是适用”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一直有一种声音，尽管我们举办了亚运会和奥运会，在大部分体育赛事中具有金牌竞争力，但是似乎大众体育或者说群众对体育的热情仍然不够，你是怎么看这个问题的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;关注金牌是很重要的，但是过度关注金牌就会引发我们过去所谓的“锦标主义”。如果陷入锦标主义，有的时候就会产生一些负面影响，比如不择手段地去取得锦标。结果是重要的，但是结果不能代表一切。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们不能忽视群众体育。通过办亚运会、办奥运会，群众对于体育运动的认识，不断地提升。比方说，我们在办2022年北京冬季奥运会之前，就提出几亿人参与冬季运动的倡议，而且在冬季奥运会举办以前基本上实现了。这说明人民对于体育运动的认识不断提高，因此参与热情也是高的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，我们如何把他们很好地组织起来？竞技体育和群众体育是两个方面，但这两个方面是互通的。我们贯彻这样一个方面，竞技体育那些专业运动员，是从群众体系中产生的；专业体育的提高，必然又会给群众体育指导。所以我觉得，普及和提高，变成互动的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你有一个观点，举国体制仍然是我们在竞技体育中的优势所在。现在一些大球类项目的发展遇到一些困境，你认为现有环境下，职业化的路径在何处？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;举国体制对于竞技体育和群众体育都适用。实际上，这种举国体制、集中训练精英的方法，在其他国家也是有的。这是一种专业性体育，奥林匹克运动也是从业余性逐渐过渡到专业性，以及最后接受一定程度的职业性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基本的路径就是群众性、专业性和职业性。从专业性到职业性，这里有商业化的问题，关于商业化的问题，我始终记得萨马兰奇主席生前告诉我的一句话：体育绝对不能被商业所控制，但是体育可以利用商业。因此，现在我们有些项目的发展是走市场化道路，但是还要有政府很好的支撑。举国体制还是适用，问题是，怎样来体现举国体制？方式方法可能要改革或者改进。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我决定不了，而且我也不参与决定”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你为中国体坛做了许多建设性工作，外界现在有一些争议，比如插手中国女排教练和中国乒乓球教练的任命等，你怎么回应这些争议性问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我从事体育工作六十多年了，但是从我来讲，始终是一个执行者，我不是什么体育运动的领导者。过去网上有一些误会，认为我可以决定一切。不，我决定不了，而且我也不参与决定。整个运动员、教练员的选拔问题都是由专业人员和政府体育领导机构决定的，我只不过根据给到我的任务，或者接受上级的指示去执行，所以我想利用这个机会也澄清一下，我决定不了排球的教练人选，也不会插手乒乓球运动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我没有那么大能力，也没有这么多权力，说我决定这一切、我干预这些决策，我觉得这个是（因为）大家不太了解（情况）。当然我有一些看法可能是错误的，我接受大家的批评，但我绝对不能够决定什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从1958年大学毕业至今，几十年如一日奋斗在体育一线，仍未退休。你对体育的激情来自何处？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;体育主要是我的兴趣和爱好，虽然我87岁了，但是在杭州亚运会，我还是要从早晨7点工作到晚上10点。虽然我退休了，还是应当在需要的时候发挥一些余热。不是说我一定还要做什么，但是一旦国家或者某些国际体育组织有这样的需要，那么在我的能力范围内，我还是尽量去做，因为体育事业是关系到民众健康、民族精神和群众关注度的一个公益事业。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这两年，国内的体育项目、人员管理日趋收紧，你观察到，国内整个体育环境有哪些比较大的变化？怎么对待这些变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;魏纪中：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在处在一个新老交替阶段。在这种新老交替的时间里，需要有一定的磨合期。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得现在从（体育）管理层来讲，可能是处在一个磨合期，在磨合期里面发生一些这样或那样的问题是自然的。正是因为在磨合期，所以群众对于这些问题的看法会有不同，这也是很自然的。群众的这些意见，可能有的是比较准确的，有的因为信息差的原因不那么准确。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;运动员的交替，教练员的交替，这是一个过程，这个过程需要磨合，需要逐渐完善，因此我们一方面要尽量缩短这个过程；另外我们也要承认有这样一个过程，从管理层到群众，我们共同出力或者献策，使得这个过程的磨合更加顺利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么要学英语？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258046]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;最近公开的一次访谈，任正非提到了自己关于英语学习的看法，他说：“在农村学英文困难，这我理解，但是熬一熬，不就熬出来了吗？可能口语表达不那么好，但是有文字的识别能力也行啊。”这话对市面上甚嚣尘上的一些看法挺有针对性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;必须说明，一门学科对个人日常生活有没有用，不能作为是否进入学校让学生学习的标准。要说日常生活的用处，物理、化学、历史、地理又有多大用处？小学上到三年级能算账、能写字就够了。比较而言，随着大众教育水平的提高与国际交流的扩大，英语与日常生活的结合越来越密切：查阅了解某些知识与技术、看产品说明书、去国外旅游，都会用到英语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;维基百科的信息显示，截至2020年3月25日，W3Techs预测前一百万互联网网站使用的语言文字百分比中，英语占比59.3%。中文为1.3%。更熟悉地使用英文，对于一个人增长见识，是非常有用的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从国家层面来说，很大程度上，中国人学习外语是为了学习国外先进的技术。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何教学，都是一个呈金字塔型的层层筛选体系。中国有庞大的体校制度，从小学阶段就开始为体育发掘、输送人才，这就是中国体育健儿在各种赛事上获得奖杯的基础。同样，只有每个人都从一年级开始学加减法，到了初中学牛顿三定律、高中学动量守恒、机械能守恒定律，最后才有十万分之一、百万分之一的奥数冠军、诺贝尔物理奖得主。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英语也同样如此，只有从小学就开始学，大学要考英语，才能筛选出最尖端的人，他们熟练地掌握英语，能够从事各种研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人说，哪有必要都学，尖端人才学好英语就好了。但是，在小学初中高中的时候，没人能预料到后来。如果学校体系给出英语不重要的信号，高考再屈从于这个趋势，降低英语比重，必然影响高中生对英语学习的态度与热情。如果高中生普遍英语基础不好，必然影响本科生英语的整体水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有些学校，本科生的有些科目是英语教学，这有利于提高学生的专业英语水平，进而有利于紧跟国际先进水平。比如，一个中国学者在国外期刊上发表一篇学术论文，最常见的语言就是英语。发表的过程，有外国同行专家审稿，给出意见，发表就是一种认可。这有利于中国这个领域的学者，向着正确的技术方向发展。实际上，这就是一个技术扩散的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如果学生高三毕业后，英语普遍都差，英语授课就无法进行，后续的在国外发表英语论文的可能性就会变小。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，技术扩散，并不只发生在发表论文、参与国际研讨会这种“高层次”，生产中的各个领域、各个层面都存在技术的扩散与交流，很多时候，比我们想象中的场景更接地气、更普通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这段时间，生成式AI火了，美国在这方面领先，中国也在加快追赶。要想使用国外的生成式AI，从网络设置、注册、写提示语、学习技巧都需要语言能力。比如，在AI生成图像与视频上，一个英语熟练的图形、家装、海报设计师，就比一个缺乏语言能力的要快，后者甚至不会去接触这个新东西，因为语言难度太大。这就可以给前者领先半年、一年，甚至几年的时间，这会赢得客户，最终优势被固化下来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再比如，一个做工艺品的小老板，如果能经常上国外的技术交流网站，就能发现很多奇思妙想。有时候技术扩散，就是“看一眼”的事。但是，如果没有英文基础，他根本不会去这些网站，既没有能力找到这些网站，也没有意识去做这件事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人主张少学英语或降低英语分值的一个很重要的原因，就是觉得英语对农村孩子不公平。但论文《LDFA方法及其在项目功能差异分析中的应用研究》，根据国家教育考试中心的数据，采用完全随机抽样的方法，抽取了2500人的英语考试成绩，发现城市和农村在高考英语成绩上，没有显著差别，甚至农村还高上0.45分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这在意料之外，却在情理之中。实际上，很多研究都发现，英语特别是应试英语，没有需要。语言学习无非是多读、多听、多背，熟能生巧。在智能手机普及的时代，英语环境的成本非常低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，无论从个体生活的意义，还是国家技术进步，抑或城乡教育公平，都不应当轻视英语学习，这样我们的孩子才能接触与发现更大的世界，从小到大不仅能开阔视野，长大后还能在专业领域提高知识与技能。这一点，至少在未来相当一段时间内仍是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[专访编剧芦苇：好的电影都有社会意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257491]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1460&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/4KPKFBskeYDrgulnOVPH0EoLBcUkSvZLTvnf5oxp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;芦苇编剧的《霸王别姬》《活着》《图雅的婚事》等电影在戛纳、柏林等国际电影节斩获大奖。图为《活着》剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芦苇今年72岁，从不使用社交媒体，日常联系只通过电话，多年来习惯于用纸笔写作，保持着一年写一部电影剧本的频率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月中旬，他告别西安的亲友，经广州乘飞机去美国，这次行程除了要看望很久没见的儿子，还要为下一部剧本做资料搜集。 “在美国写剧本有一个好处，就是清净，没人干扰我，不像这儿，比如有活动了，你不去也不行，都是熟人和朋友，不去让人觉得端架子，很容易给人产生误会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1415&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/E4P7jDSbckucwFf3kCK8HXCBhPw9w7CHhycwgDTD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;芦苇与张艺谋、吕乐、赵季平合影(从左至右)，四人作为电影编剧、导演、摄像、音乐堪称行业顶配。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国的职业编剧中，很少有人像芦苇这样与影史上的三代导演都有过合作，在过去四十年间见证了中国电影的潮起潮落。 1988年，他署名编剧的第一部作品《疯狂的代价》，就成为当年的票房冠军。此后，《霸王别姬》《活着》《图雅的婚事》等一系列作品在戛纳、柏林等国际电影节斩获大奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;远行前日，他的书房略显凌乱，墙上和桌面都是大大小小的绘画和摄影作品，靠墙的木板上钉着一张字条，上面是芦苇的手书：“下定决心，写好《刀客七星传》！这是完成夙愿的关键一役。全力以赴，誓不罢休。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2015年上映的跨国大制作电影《狼图腾》之后，芦苇的创作精力更多地花费在小成本电影上，这让他渐渐远离了资本的中心，在他看来，电影没有大小，只有好坏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“编剧的工作不存在退休，我现在就只写我喜欢的东西，不考虑其他。”他对南方周末记者说，“小成本电影稿酬虽然低，但这不是钱的问题，好处是没有负担，选择自由度大。关注度高低不是我要考虑的问题，我只管我的剧本如何。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1402&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/RVm6I0pKoRHCUk9vemwHCwLUjTSDvhQkrC9ER3HY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1995年，芦苇与姜文(右)在西安拍摄《秦颂》期间。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芦苇最新编剧的藏地故事《洛桑的家事》还没上映，他已经写完了武侠题材的新剧本《刀客七星传》，紧接着想把“赤脚医生”孙立哲的故事搬上银幕，反映“知青”一代人的往事。 “孙立哲从北京到陕北下乡，自己学医术救了很多人。鉴于现在看病难，我就写写孙立哲，等于是一个仰望吧，我希望中国的医生都能够变成像孙立哲这样的人，中国人民就有福了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创作之外，芦苇的公共言论也引人注目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，在中国电影诞辰百年之际，芦苇和好友王天兵一起做了一场名为《中国电影什么时候能长大》的对话，比较尖锐地批评了包括张艺谋、贾樟柯、娄烨在内的中国导演，认为他们不懂写故事、主题混乱。他曾直言不讳地批评《无极》，与曾经的老朋友分道扬镳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导演陆川的《南京！南京！ 》《王的盛宴》曾被芦苇狠狠批评过，2013年，他却在出席芦苇新书《电影编剧的秘密》发布会时表示：“我一度很自信，写剧本是按照商业片故事片的逻辑，拍摄时却想着颠覆，幸亏后面在人生的十字路口遇到了芦苇，和他深聊后，感觉自己当时是不对的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Ta0G4w0jM7lD47dWQsZBKrodMftFgHM2giAEsMzj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《霸王别姬》获金棕榈奖后，导演陈凯歌(左)与芦苇合影。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1281&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/wxqP5AVXWMVEdnvQZH5Y4aipKbgEDI9rLDT4KG9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1992年，芦苇与巩俐(右)在《霸王别姬》摄影棚。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;芦苇受好莱坞电影的影响很大，看重电影的可看性以及社会意义，从事编剧工作三十多年，他谈电影的“类型”多过电影的“艺术”，并且认为编剧没有奥秘。在最近出版的新书《电影编剧没有秘密》里，芦苇首次披露了《霸王别姬》剧本写作的详细内幕，让部分影迷有些意外的是，这部目前唯一获得戛纳电影节“金棕榈”大奖的华语电影的剧本，芦苇对创作的要求是一定要“类型化”，故事要好看，还要合情合理，要真实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说：“第一本书的书名，说电影编剧有什么&#39;秘密&#39;，我不喜欢，我觉得电影编剧没有秘密，无非就是规律而已，这次出版的新书我就想要告诉大家这点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月9月，南方周末记者在西安采访了芦苇，彼时全年最重要的“十一”黄金档期并没有取得预期的票房成绩，中国内地电影市场罕见地出现整月只有五部新片上映，定档11月上映的新片只有三部的严重“片荒”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当被问及对中国新电影的看法，他说：“中国电影剧本合格的不多，有的电影明显是剧本的问题，投资很大，费劲很大，但是基础不好。剧本就是电影的基础，这个基础不牢固，电影肯定不会精彩的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的大学是在电影院里完成的&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你以前是学美术的，最初进入西安电影制片厂担任的是美工，后来是如何转型成为电影编剧的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最开始在我的人生计划和理想里面都没有做编剧这个准备。后来接触电影，做的也是电影美术。有一天我突然醒悟到，剧本的写作也是一种造型艺术，和美术是相通的。我过去是拿色彩画画，现在是拿文字画画，道理是一样的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我进入西影厂完全是偶然的，招工的时候告诉有这样一个单位在招人，但是工种恐怕是炊事员，我虽然不太愿意当炊事员，但是我想这个单位不错，是跟艺术有关系的，那时候根本不懂电影，只是觉得可以接触到艺术，所以就进来了。我心想哪怕是当炊事员，在这个单位总还会有机会的。结果我一天炊事员都没当，人家知道我会画画，看了我的画就说：“没问题，你去当美工吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做电影美术，不可避免要接触到电影剧本，因为要根据剧本内容来决定你工作的内容。美术做得多了，就能看出剧本的问题，剧本应该怎么写，怎么写是有意思的。那时候有所谓的青年摄制组，所有的创作人员，包括美术啊，摄影啊，都要在一块开会讨论剧本，我就经常给一些剧本提意见，后来提得多了，有时候被导演用激将法说“那你写，说这个不好，那个也不好，那你自己上吧”，我也就真的自己上了。结果写出来的剧本，他们也觉得真是比原来的要好，这也给了我一个信心，原来剧本是可以写好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你最早署名编剧的作品是周晓文导演的《疯狂的代价》吧，这部片子在当年很轰动，是1988年的票房冠军，但这并不是你第一次参与编剧工作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一部是《他们正年轻》，但是没通过，当时吴天明当厂长，他知道我会写剧本，就比较注意我。后来我又写了《最后的疯狂》，那个电影还有点反响，当年卖了很多钱，再后来我又写了《疯狂的代价》，这时候我就署名编剧了，吴天明非常扶持我，对我说：“你想当编剧我调你去文学部，你想当导演我调你到导演组，想干什么你说，我支持你。”我当时听了这话之后，觉得厂长这样厚待我，心里对他是非常感谢的，我说我还是写剧本吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么在编剧和导演的选择当中选择了编剧，两者的区别是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我对编剧还是比较懂的，可是导演我不懂。我觉得编剧是设计师，导演是施工的工程师。经常会出现工程师看不懂设计师的创意，他就会改你的图纸，把图纸改到他的意思，所以最终的成品可能和设计师想象的不同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我做过导演，拍过一部戏叫《西夏路迢迢》，当年还得了金鸡奖最佳导演处女作奖，国际上也得了几个奖。但是我不认为我是好导演，我的导演业务不行。天性不适合当导演，很不喜欢指挥人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这几年，随着电影行业的进步，编剧的重要性也慢慢凸显了，除了高校开设的编剧专业，社会上也开始有了编剧班，在你年轻的时候，却几乎没有专门的地方学习编剧，你是如何自我提升的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;就是看电影，电影跟别的东西不一样，像理工科的知识，最好是受到系统的训练。电影是一个很直观的艺术，通过看电影就可能学会，通过分析和研究，就可以成为内行，不需要怎么学。我别说上什么电影专科学院了，连正常的教育都不完整，初二就下乡去宝鸡的山村里当农民了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我比较幸运的是，因为我父亲在西安人民大厦工作，那是一个做接待工作的单位，他是汽车队的队长，负责接待一些外国专家和高级干部，所以我很早就有机会看一些外国电影，比如《静静的顿河》《卡比利亚之夜》《偷自行车的人》……其实上世纪五六十年代的院线还是相对丰富的，直到1960年代中期，“文革”要开始了，电影才开始“一刀切”，到“文革”后期，才开始有一些朝鲜电影进来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我做电影的时候，看电影还是很困难，到了1980年之后才慢慢好转，逐步有了一些外国电影进来，那时候学电影就变得容易了。除了西影厂工作的便利可以看到一些电影，北京已经开始举办美国电影周、西班牙电影周之类的活动了，那时候一张票大约是两毛五分钱，但是没有关系买不到，只能买黑市票，有的电影票能炒到十元，当时的工资很低，只有三十六元，但特别想看的还是要看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我印象深刻的电影很多，比如《巴顿将军》《黑神驹》《猜猜谁来吃晚餐》《原野奇侠》等等，当时要从西安坐火车去北京，没有多余的钱住旅馆，就找到一个朋友家安顿下来，然后天天去买黑市票。巴拉德导演的《黑神驹》讲的是一个孩子和一匹黑色的马之间的友谊，我非常喜欢，一口气看了五遍。那时候看电影，主要是学习电影的画面感，把心得都记下来，对电影的构成建立理解，我的大学是在电影院里完成的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;阅读在你的职业生涯里同样重要，在特殊年代你参加了读书会，当时的时代氛围是什么样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1973年，我们开始组织一个读书小组，算是一个读书会吧，有十多个志同道合的朋友，加入的条件就是要有一定的学养，对理论感兴趣。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们没有组织形式，没有名称，就是以朋友聚会的名义进行一种学习交流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们读的都是理论书，比如艾思奇的《辩证唯物主义历史唯物主义》，拿它作为提纲，我们一章一章地讨论它，再把每个人对它的见解发挥一下。这本书在当时是一本正统的书籍，用这本书来学习是没有危险的。 “九一三事件”后，中央提倡要学习理论，还指定了几本马列的经典著作，我们都系统读过，比如《资本论》的导言、《反杜林论》《路德维希·费尔巴哈和德国古典哲学的终结》《共产党宣言》，其实那时候我们已经开始对社会局势有了自己的思考，感觉马上要发生一些改变，只是不知道这种改变会朝向哪里，就想要靠阅读搞清楚一些问题，这是我们学习的动力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当时想要弄清楚一些困惑，你对自己的未来又是如何判断的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我光知道我有爱好，认为一定要努力实现自己的追求，但是到底怎么实现其实没有想法。我当时就是一边读书，一边学艺术。为了找书，我还去各个大学的图书馆偷书，后来被发现了，在派出所关了三天，好在我们的运气比较好，那个所长很善待我，总觉得偷书的孩子是因为爱看书，让我写个保证就回家了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们那时候是一个信息贫乏的时代，极度封锁的时代，任何信息都没有。今天是一个信息爆炸的时代，两者都不正常，一种处于饥饿状态，一种是吃得太饱了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/Qyt8OmzfXj1AoMyxgd7KOdT2kQ7CgSZmU344Rw3n.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;写《霸王别姬》的电影剧本，芦苇前前后后用了一年多，其中大部分时间在做各种调研。图为该片剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不能把《霸王别姬》写成纯艺术片&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;回到《电影编剧没有秘密》这本书，你似乎对好莱坞电影格外推崇，是因为1980年代你主要观看的是美国电影吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;各国都有，但是不可否认，好莱坞在全世界范围内影响最大，而且美国电影是很好的学习对象，因为他们的电影构成最清楚。这可能也是美国人的特点，比较朴实和直接。学习之后就是实战，写剧本就是一本写完再写一本，不断地朝新的目标迈进。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你反复强调《霸王别姬》要写成类型片，这和它的巨大投资有关系吗？你在书里谈到这部电影的时候还强调剧本是给导演和投资人看的，越简洁越好。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;编剧要根据成本来进行创作，一定要这样，因为我是搞专业的，《霸王别姬》的投资在当时来说是很大的一笔钱，我觉得不能把它写成一部纯艺术片。我记得从我一开始写剧本的时候，吴天明就告诉我，某个戏的成本是多少，别给写超了。后来陈可辛找我改编哈金的《等待》，我第一个问题就是投资多少，这是我的一个习惯，后来他说上不封顶，我才放开写，虽然故事是小故事，但我的背景是大场景。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《霸王别姬》也是小说改编的，你在这本书和王天兵分析了小说和剧本的差别，还认为原著小说是二流的，为什么会有这样的看法？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不认为这是一部经典小说，就是一部普通意义上的市井言情小说，陈凯歌曾经给我来了一封信，谈到他希望我们把小说的文本重新来一遍。原著作者后来是在电影的基础上又重新出了一版小说，即使这样，电影和小说的很多地方还是不一样，结尾就有很大的不同，很多人物也都是我们新加进去的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;小说里的程蝶衣和段小楼最后在香港相逢，但你的结尾是程蝶衣自刎，为什么要这么改？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这恐怕和很多京剧艺人的遭遇有关系，我希望《霸王别姬》这个电影每个细节和情景都有出处。比如袁四爷这个人物，电影里最后枪毙他的时候，他迈着戏步向刑场，那是武汉枪毙一个姓高的“戏霸”的时候的真事。程蝶衣被批斗的戏来自“文革”的时候，文艺界人士在北京国子监游街的往事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这个剧本前后筹备了多久？你对成片满意吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;写的时间并不算长，主要是调研，前前后后一年多。调研要到处跑，要去北方昆剧院的资料室，也要去中国艺术研究院戏曲研究所，还要去北京大学的图书馆，再就是北京图书馆（现国家图书馆）。我当时在图书馆旁的旅馆租了一间房子，每天晚上都去泡图书馆，拿个本子去抄资料。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影最后拍得很好，要说遗憾就是一些细节还是可以继续推敲，可以做一点学术研究，还有就是一部分表演可以更好，比如老太监最后的表现，我也觉得太装了，对这个角色的理解不对，当然这都动摇不了最后的成色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1450&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/17/fGe3gz4vjqub2b1rDUyKYLAlZKu7kmPmqkiwPewU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;215559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;芦苇(左一)、葛优(中)和老腔艺人在《活着》片场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《活着》改编自余华的代表作，你觉得和《霸王别姬》比哪个难度更大？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;《活着》的难度大，因为这篇小说写得很好，所以不好轻易改动，改动的时候心存忌惮。在写《霸王别姬》的时候，我的精神是自由的，内心觉得就应该根据我的来，小说不对；但改编《活着》，我就想尽量地不要动小说，当然该动还是得动，毕竟是两个载体。比如《活着》的小说里福贵的儿子是抽血抽死的，现实中这也太罕见了，观众接受有问题，下笔有点狠，超出了我们的生活经验，我就改成了出车祸。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从结尾看，《活着》最后给了人一些希望，不像原著那么残酷，好像也比《霸王别姬》显得温情一点？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这部电影讲的是家庭生活，风格有点不一样，但两者的品质是一样的。我应该是写完《霸王别姬》不久就写了《活着》。缘起是我之前和张艺谋合作了一个关于陕西皮影戏的电影，他还去采了外景，后来他看了《活着》，又和我说先做这个吧。我也喜欢这篇小说，就答应了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我当时拍了一个关于陕西老艺人演出皮影戏的纪录片，张艺谋很喜欢，觉得特别有魅力，当时他在我家看的片子，很兴奋，当晚就住在我家，我们聊了一夜，说一定要把皮影戏放到银幕上，后来我们就把这个元素放进了《活着》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;让他成为一个活着的人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得那个时期算不算中国电影比较好的时候？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当然是，一个是政策相对而言比较宽松，再一个影人也非常有奋斗的精神。大家愿意团结起来拍个好电影，那时候个人的诉求好像都没有了，只是想把电影拍好。名利心比较弱，电影也没有开始市场化。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《霸王别姬》拍完之后，陈凯歌就叫我到北京去，我就去了，他说他成立了一家公司。我对这个事是有点怀疑的，因为成立公司的话，动机就不一定那么单纯了，你就有压力，不像在体制内。我说了一句话他可能没听懂，我说“你搞公司我不以为然，我觉得你要受累”，其实就是指这样的话搞艺术就不那么纯粹了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然这之后我也是愿意和他继续合作的，紧跟着他要拍《风月》，找我来做编剧，我一看是上海“拆白党”题材，那我就去上海做调研，想看看到底是怎么回事。我去上海文史研究馆看了资料之后，发现历史上没有“拆白党”，所以我就不愿意写这个剧本。只有我相信才能写出来剧本，不相信就没办法写，我和陈凯歌说了之后，他问我能不能虚构，我说这我不行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外当时我劝他，《霸王别姬》已经成功了，下面能不能拍一个小投资的、但是我们又很想拍的电影，可是他还是拍了《风月》，虽然基本上是《霸王别姬》的原班人马，但是票房很失败。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你还批评过第五代导演不会写剧本吧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我是说他们不太会讲故事，他们对戏剧性比较陌生，在学校学习的都是艺术品，崇尚的也是艺术品，没有对情节下过功夫，电影学院似乎也不太重视情节，强调艺术家风格和艺术家性格。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;很多导演拍出过杰作，但后来的作品却越发让人失望，你是怎么看待这个问题的?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这很正常，比如运动员状态好的时候可能创造世界纪录，状态不好的时候，也就是一般的水平，也要面对失败，面对被淘汰的结果，电影人也一样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你和很多导演都会有意见不一致的时候，比如《赤壁》《白鹿原》，背后的原因是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我没有和吴宇森不愉快，他和制片方一块找到我写一个赤壁的故事。后来我写的剧本他没用，他用了他爱人的剧本，我就把我的版本出书了。主要我和他对《赤壁》的理解不一样，我觉得赤壁是战场，是斗争，他觉得主题是和平。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍《白鹿原》我和导演闹得很不愉快，他不理解《白鹿原》的主题，认为是人和土地的关系，但我觉得这本书说的是父与子的斗争，是两代人的冲突。何况他的关注点也不在电影，因此有人说这个版本的《白鹿原》就是“田小娥传”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有没有哪个剧本是你写了还没拍，拍不了会觉得遗憾的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;刚写完一个剧本，关于河套地区历史的，是一个清朝刀客的故事，叫《刀客七星传》。我一直对武侠片情有独钟，也很喜欢河套民歌，我就想做一部会唱歌的武侠片。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对新片一直保持关注，之前也经常点评一些新电影，你对最近上映的国产片有何看法？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;拍上海的《爱情神话》还是不错的，但也有它的问题。比如三个女性角色都太漂亮，不像是市井之辈，一看就是电影（人物）；还有男主角的形象有问题，是个老好人，太概念化了，有点简单。以我对老好人的理解来说，他们可不那么简单。这些削弱了这部电影的戏剧力，但是这个故事很好。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在塑造电影人物的时候，如何让角色更加令人信服？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;你要理解他，把人物放到一个生活的场景里面去。不要概念化，不要简单化，不要扁平化，让他成为一个活着的人，一个有情感、有灵魂、有情感诉求的人。我们拍英雄人物的时候往往会有误区，英雄人物都是有七情六欲的。真善美，只有真才能善，才能美，一些电影老是让人不信服，就是不真，这类电影不能找马屁精来拍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这几年主旋律电影再度成为一种重要的电影现象，你会写主旋律电影吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;会啊，我写过两个。有史以来最伟大的电影里，也有主旋律，就是爱森斯坦的《战舰波将金号》，这是苏维埃主旋律，后来被视为蒙太奇理论的集大成之作。我一直不服气，其实我父母都是老八路解放军，我认为主旋律是可以拍好的，我自己写的两部可惜没有拍，将来有机会我还是想拍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;近来的电影里，你似乎很看好《我不是药神》，原因是什么呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;芦苇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;它有深远的社会意义，看病难是全社会的共同心声，刚好这个电影把这个问题揭示出来了，所以我觉得它有社会意义。从艺术的角度，这部电影还可以继续推敲，但这部电影有不凡的意义。好的电影，比如《乌鸦与麻雀》《小城之春》都有深远的社会意义。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天成奇峡：云蒸霞蔚的“世外密境”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“失去对身边美好的感知”：社交媒体还是我们自己的问题？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258048]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Yan Fei, a professor of sociology at Tsinghua University, said: Social media brings people far away, but we But I lost my perception of the beauty around me. This remark triggered a lot of discussion, with both praise and criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One criticism says that experts from the pan-humanistic society tend to fall into reflection on &quot;new technologies&quot; and &quot;new trends&quot;, giving people a sense of criticizing for the sake of criticizing. However, this does not mean that Yan Fei’s statement is without value. Whether it inspires resonance or triggers refutation, it shows that it has touched many people and must be right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has social media brought to us? Is it empowering us, allowing us to better control our lives, helping us contact and discover the larger world, and achieving better selves? Or is it going too far and consuming us, and we are being included and swallowed, becoming this &quot;superorganism&quot; &quot;Human flesh input and output terminal, everyone produces fragments, and is fed fragments? The answer may be different for everyone. Different views on a technology can reveal its different aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a positive perspective, social media has indeed reduced the cost of communication. You can establish links with strangers in distant places without leaving home and just inputting and clicking a few times, sharing your opinions with each other and getting timely feedback; Moreover, in the online world, everyone can take off the mask they wear in real life and reveal their true self without worrying too much about offending others with their honesty. Some people will unite into a community based on common knowledge background, values ​​or hobbies, find an ecological niche that suits them, and find the meaning of survival. For those who feel lonely and out of tune with the people around them offline, it is also a kind of happiness to find that &quot;I am not alone&quot; online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, with the deepening popularity of mobile Internet and smartphones, more and more freelancers can work from home or even anywhere, especially for knowledge workers. For these people, social media is already an infrastructure for doing work, or a productivity tool. Others’ criticism and reflection on social media are just clouds and noise to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, barring a massive catastrophe, it is impossible for us to return to the state of things before social media for long. In this sense, all criticisms and reflections on social media are irrational and fleeting, while those that are reasonable can at best promote the improvement of social media. Of course, each of us is free to choose, and can independently decide the frequency and type of social media use, and the appropriate proportion and time of online and offline life. Therefore, we cannot treat our mental weakness and disability as Blame it on social media or something else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this general premise, we may admit that Yan Fei’s statement sees a problem. Of course, what appears to be social media’s problem is actually our own problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A netizen said, &quot;I feel very close to my heart&quot;. He said that he likes to watch the dusk of vegetation and other things captured in the video, but he doesn&#39;t want to see it in real life. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course life that is staged or filtered is not real life. You have a choice. You can put down your phone and go for a hike to watch the sunrise or watch the sunset on your balcony. Connect with the real world and real people and feel the beauty around you. You can also keep your phone in your hand. The algorithm will continuously push content to you based on your needs and desires, keeping you high until you feel dizzy, exhausted, and left with a sense of consumption and emptiness afterwards. Of course, you can also use your phone sparingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, you want to accompany your children to enhance the understanding and relationship between parents and children, or go outdoors with family and friends on weekends to enjoy a quiet time. But if you pick up your mobile phone, turn into a heroic fighter on social media, and scold Fang Qiu, then you may have really ignored the people around you who need care and &quot;lost the perception of the beauty around you.&quot; But as long as you step away, social media is just a dead thing to you, and a responsible person will not shirk his responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another netizen retorted: If there is beauty around us, do we still have time to use social media? Don’t we all just want to get rid of the chicken feathers around us and find our fantasy world through social media? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Properly withdrawing from real life, relaxing and letting yourself go is harmless and beneficial. The way of civility and martial arts is to relax. However, escaping from real life is not advisable. You cannot live a failed life in the real world and become a great hero in the virtual world. Those who &quot;abandon treatment&quot; in the real world will find it difficult to &quot;resurrect with full health&quot; in the virtual world. If the virtual world becomes an anesthetic for you to escape from real life, it will only amplify and intensify your failures in real life. Every time you log off the Internet and return to reality, you will face endless spiritual emptiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Needless to say, real life means daily necessities, responsibilities and pressure. We can take a break from stress, but eventually we have to face it. It is better to face it sooner rather than later. The vast majority of parents cannot support you for a lifetime, and the idea of ​​&quot;full-time children&quot; is just self-deception. A person&#39;s growth, a person&#39;s spiritual growth into a qualified adult, fundamentally lies in stimulating one&#39;s inner motivation and courage, using one&#39;s natural talents and acquired abilities, claiming one&#39;s own responsibilities, and doing one&#39;s own business. If you take it up, the reward is the unparalleled sense of accomplishment when you accomplish something, and a mentally stronger self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the vast majority of people who need to fight in the real world, social media should be an adjuvant and a snack, not an anesthetic and a meal. From the perspective of receiving effective information, social media should not be fully committed to delivery. Some social media have reached the pinnacle of deliberately creating &quot;information cocoons&quot;. For the same news event or hot post, the comment areas for men and women can be completely different to accurately cater to your thoughts, or to be precise. How can you not be afraid of controlling your cognition? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, what social media brings to you, whether you dominate it or it dominates you, fundamentally depends on your independent choice and how you use it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从卖寿衣到“古装大佬”，它凭什么抢占了半壁戏服江山？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257711]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cao County has always produced coffins and shrouds, monopolizing 90% of Japan&#39;s The coffin market above. In 2008, Caoxian County encountered a popular online costume sales market, and local residents began to switch to selling costumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking at the entire development history of Hanfu industry in Caoxian County, being down-to-earth, not making excuses, making up for whatever is lacking, and being open-minded to ask for advice... have become its most prominent development labels. In this In the process, Caoxian vividly demonstrated the true qualities of Shandong people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Know&quot; tells you how Caoxian County transformed from shrouds to costumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72816&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69684&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;5863&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252254&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72817&quot; group-id=&quot; 0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69685&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 2.png&quot; alt= &quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4530&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; data-key= &quot;252255&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72818&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69686&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4875&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252256&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id= &quot;72819&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69687&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b3e2c3432d.png&quot; img-title= &quot;Cao County 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;3435&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ b3e2c3432d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252257&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[私搭浮桥18人获罪案启动再审：“原判决适用法律确有错误”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258058]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;September 2023, Taonan, Jilin, a convenience bridge to be completed. Interviewee Photo courtesy&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;881&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Taonan, Jilin, the soon-to-be-completed convenience bridge. Photo provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of 18 people who were convicted of privately building a pontoon that once attracted widespread attention has made new progress. On September 27, 2023, the Baicheng Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jilin Province made a retrial decision, believing that the original judgment was indeed erroneous in the application of law and met the conditions for retrial, and decided to bring the case to Baicheng Intermediate People&#39;s Court for trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The criminal verdict of the Taonan City People&#39;s Court shows that from 2005 to 2018, Huang Deyi and others secretly traveled along the Taoer River from Zhenlin Village, Wafang Town, Taonan City to Ping&#39;an Village, Ping&#39;an Town, Taobei District, Baicheng City. Build a hull pontoon bridge, intercept passing vehicles and collect bridge tolls. The toll is 5 yuan for a small car and 10 yuan for a large car, totaling 52,950 yuan. For the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, Huang Deyi was sentenced to two years in prison, suspended for two years. Another 17 relatives were sentenced to prison terms ranging from one year to three months in prison, all with suspended sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A legal person close to the case told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;According to our country&#39;s judicial practice, the court is very cautious in initiating retrials and usually undergoes very strict review.&quot; The legal person analyzed that correcting the original judgment There are two possibilities, one is not guilty, the other is a reduced sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Retrial decision letter. Provided by the respondent&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252967 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Retrial decision letter. Respondents provided&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Whether it is a forced request&quot; or the focus of the retrial&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;The original judgment was indeed wrong in applying the law&quot; mentioned in the retrial decision, analyzed by the above-mentioned legal experts , according to the judicial interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court, to constitute the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, there must be certain hooligan motives and coercive objective behavior, and disrupt social order. The focus of the retrial of the case will be on whether Huang Deyi&#39;s relevant behavior constitutes the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, that is, whether Huang Deyi has the subjective intention to commit the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble and the objective behavior of forcing others to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, the focus of the retrial may be on whether Huang Deyi had objective behavior of forcing others to cross the bridge. Specifically, whether Huang Deyi forced others to cross the bridge.” The legal person believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter in July 2023, Huang Deyi explained that the reason for building the pontoon bridge was because his family had land on the other side of the river, and at the same time, his ancestors were boat builders. Huang Deyi said that the charging standard of &quot;5 yuan for a small car and 10 yuan for a large car&quot; was determined after discussion with the villagers crossing the bridge. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252355&quot;>;Village Bully Involved in Gangs , destroy lanes, return bridge tolls? Those convicted of building bridges respond to the controversy&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are different opinions in previous media reports regarding Huang Deyi’s claim that there is no mandatory toll. . In July 2023, Gu Tianfu, the party secretary of An&#39;an Village, which is only separated by a river from Zhenlin Village, said in an interview with the media that Huang Deyi had deliberately dug up the river channel, so that villagers passing by had to walk across his bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment determined that the amount of charges was 52,950 yuan. In previous interviews with Southern Weekend reporters, many villagers claimed that it was more than this amount. A villager who had also built a pontoon bridge on the Taoer River estimated that the amount built by Huang Deyi The fees charged by the pontoons may amount to millions of dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the determination of the amount to be collected will have an impact on the retrial judgment, the above-mentioned legal experts analyzed that the retrial decision stated that the original trial was an error in the application of the law, and the retrial stage should focus on the application of the law. &quot;This case is not a crime of amount. Whether Huang Deyi constitutes a crime and the sentencing has no absolute correspondence with the amount.&quot; At the same time, Article 469 of the Interpretation of the Criminal Procedure Law stipulates that, except for the protest of the People&#39;s Procuratorate, the retrial shall generally not increase the penalty of the defendant in the original trial. &quot;From this point of view, it is unlikely that Huang Deyi will be given a heavier sentence in the retrial.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the criminal verdict of the Taonan City People&#39;s Court, in addition to building a pontoon bridge, Huang Deyi also organized 17 relatives to guard the bridge. If any of the other 17 people involved in the bridge guarding case engaged in forcible behavior, would it have an impact on the case and Huang Deyi? The above-mentioned legal person said that if others forcefully demand it, he himself may not commit a crime because there is no intention to commit a crime together, but the premise is that Huang Deyi himself does not know about this behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The new bridge will be completed and opened to traffic at the end of October&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to the case itself, the &quot;floating bridge imprisonment&quot; has attracted attention, and the travel needs of villagers have also attracted local attention. In July 2023, &quot;Taonan Release&quot; issued an article stating that it plans to build a convenience bridge near the original pontoon bridge, which will be completed before the autumn harvest. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252709&quot;>;Struggles for land, crossing rivers And bridge demolition: the dilemma of 11 illegal floating bridges behind the &quot;privately built floating bridges&quot; case&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, the location of the convenience bridge was not in the original Near the floating bridge, it was built in Yushu Village, Fushun Town, about ten kilometers downstream. On September 30, Yushu Village Party Secretary Wang Zuoxiang told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why the Bianmin Bridge was built near Yushu Village was because the river surface in this section is narrower than that in other places. Other river surfaces on the Taoer River are four to five hundred meters long. Width, &quot;Our place is more than 200 meters wide.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the river narrow and it is easy to build a bridge, it is also because it is at the &quot;center point&quot;. There are two rivers in Taonan, the Taoer River and the Jiaoliu River. About 67 administrative villages are distributed on both sides of the two rivers. Before the new convenience bridge was built, there were only three bridges on the 156-kilometer-long Taoer River, namely No. 1 Bridge, Manchudai Bridge and Zhenxi Bridge. Wang Zuoxiang said, &quot;The bridge is located here and can be accessed from both the north and the south. After the bridge is repaired, it will be about 20 kilometers away from the Manchudai Bridge and about 35 kilometers away from the Zhenxi Bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public signboard for the project It shows that &lt;a>;&lt;/a>;&lt;a>;the newly built convenience bridge is made of steel plate material, with a length of 327 meters and a width of 5 meters. The investment is 6.852 million yuan, and the planned completion time is October 31, 2023. &lt;/a>;Wang Zuo Xiangxiang, the local autumn harvest begins in mid-October every year. &quot;Now our Taonan side has basically completed the construction, and the bridge deck has been paved.&quot; However, because the Taoer River built by the Convenience Bridge is the dividing line, one bank is Taonan City, and the other side belongs to Taobei District, Baicheng City. On September 30, Wang Zuoxiang told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;There is a branch of the river in Taobei District, about 50 meters wide, which has not been repaired yet. Now the bridge is a Duantou Bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taonan A staff member of the Propaganda Department of the Municipal Party Committee told a reporter from Southern Weekend: &quot;The situation I know currently is that they are accelerating the construction of the bridge. The main body of the bridge has been basically completed. The &#39;Duetou Bridge&#39; is the approach bridge to the other side. In the process of our bridge construction, It must be guaranteed. If the project is started and implemented, it can be completed in two or three days. It is not very complicated. There is definitely no problem with the bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zuoxiang believes that after the convenience bridge is completed, It will definitely be more convenient for people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait. But he has new worries. He believes that after the bridge is completed, there will be a lot of vehicles coming and going, and his Yushu Village is only about 3 kilometers away from the convenience bridge. The vehicles entering and exiting will &quot;clearly use our village&quot; and will crush the village. There is a 4-meter-wide cement road, and the risk factor for villagers&#39; travel has also become higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He hopes that the relevant departments can repair the damaged roads in the village in the future, and at the same time, set up signs at the intersections around the convenience bridge, such as marking intersections or T-shaped intersections. “我是一村之长，这事我得对村民出行安全负责。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[规避现代认知框架的陷阱：读葛兆光老师序言有感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhWQU0xWSXD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhW QU0xWSXD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Gangsheng has two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had time to read Teacher Bao Gangsheng’s new book &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot; (Guangxi Normal University Press, 2023), just after reading the preface by teacher Ge Zhaoguang, I felt that this book must be very interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have read Bao Gangsheng&#39;s &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; (Peking University Press, 2015) and his works on democracy. I do not study political science, but am interested in discourse analysis, so the so-called Reading is just a superficial reading out of curiosity about political science discourse, especially the cognitive evolution of terminology and the presentation of discourse. Bao Gangsheng’s academic foundation and keen awareness of issues are absolutely top-notch. Just because I read his &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, I am full of expectations for his new book, but I also have some mixed thoughts about what Teacher Ge said in the preface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is positive about Bao Gangsheng’s approach to the history of ancient thought from the perspective of modern political science, and believes that this is promoting the dialogue between Western theory and Eastern thought. He believes that it is meaningful to re-examine ancient thoughts from the perspective of modern political science. I completely agree with this, but I feel that in doing so, we must avoid the traps of modern cognitive frameworks. Cognitive frames have many functions, one of which is what William James called &quot;selective attention.&quot; One consequence of selective attention is that we pay too much attention to the similarities or differences between the objects being observed, ignoring the fundamental differences or similarities between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Give an example. When Bao Gangsheng introduced China&#39;s political outlook in &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, he mentioned three different political outlooks, one is modern, one is ancient, and there is also the Soviet model, that is, class rule. Let&#39;s not talk about this for now. . In the words of Bao Gangsheng, in the ancient political view, &quot;politics&quot; &quot;is most commonly understood to refer to the activities of the monarch and his ministers in ruling the country and governing society.&quot; Simply put, it actually means &quot;monarchy.&quot; According to Bao Gangsheng’s explanation, the modern political outlook is “the Chinese translation of English politics” and is a foreign concept. He quoted Sun Yat-sen&#39;s view that &quot;the management of people&#39;s affairs is politics.&quot; There is another sentence before: &quot;Government is a matter for everyone.&quot; Therefore, the politics in Sun Yat-sen&#39;s mind is &quot;administering political affairs by the people&quot;, which is the so-called &quot;democracy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to teacher Gao Quanxi in the book &quot;Modern Western Political Thought&quot;, the ancient Western monarchy is completely different from the ancient Chinese monarchy. If Bao Gangsheng’s summary and Gao Quanxi’s statement hold true, “monarchy” politics and “civil rights” politics are different concepts and belong to different cognitive frameworks with essential conflicts. Western &quot;monarchy&quot; theory and ancient Chinese &quot;monarchy&quot; or &quot;royal power&quot; also belong to different cognitive categories. According to the most basic assumptions of discourse analysis, terms generated by different cognitive frameworks and categories belong to different semantic fields and form different semantic relationships with related words. Two questions arise: 1) Is it appropriate to use different cognitive frameworks to explain political concepts expressed in the same text? 2) Is it appropriate to use words with different semantic relationships to explain the same term? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why I have such doubts is because there are many such examples in &quot;Political Science&quot; that I think are specious. For example, &quot;Confucius believed that politics should be upright. If the king above is upright, the people will be upright.&quot; When commenting on the concept of Confucius, Bao Gangsheng mentioned &quot;The Wealth of Nations&quot; and &quot;Theory of Moral Sentiments&quot; written by Adam Smith. He seemed to think that &quot;virtue&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; are synonymous with Confucius&#39; &quot;rectitude&quot;, as if It is said that Confucius&#39; &quot;benevolent government&quot; and &quot;ethics&quot; are highly similar to Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook. Is it really like this? Is Confucius&#39;s moral outlook centered on &quot;royal power&quot; and based on the differential order pattern the same as Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook based on the concept of equality centered on &quot;civil rights&quot;? If traditional ethics are virtues, then why did Lu Xun think that ethics cannibalize people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example, &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; is based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;The master of the Ming Dynasty guides his ministers with only two handles. The two handles are the virtue of punishment. What is the virtue of punishment?&quot; Killing is called punishment, celebrating reward is called virtue.&quot; This passage makes the following judgment: &quot;The principle here is close to the management philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organizations, that is, organizational management should pay attention to clear rewards and punishments.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t understand the philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organization management. Is such a simple principle of clear rewards and punishments the fundamental principle of modern industrial and commercial organization management philosophy? Are the premise of this principle for industrial and commercial organizations to be the same as Han Fei’s? What are the standards of modern principles? What are its basic assumptions? Do the two involve the same semantic relationship? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same section, the author draws this conclusion based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;If a person does not die, the coffin will not be bought. Love does not mean hating people, but benefits from people&#39;s death&quot;: &quot;In fact , Han Fei had a perspective similar to Adam Smith more than 2,000 years ago, and he had elaborated the &#39;economic man&#39; hypothesis and the methodology of individualism to a certain extent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;As an economic concept, doesn’t “economic man” have different basic premises and presuppositions? Is the core semantic term of &quot;individualism&quot; as an ism just &quot;profit&quot;? Are their semantic fields the same as Han Fei&#39;s? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw Teacher Ge’s high-level summary of some of the book’s viewpoints in the preface, such as “summarizing Taoism using methodism, weakness, inaction, and abandonment of wisdom.” Based on past readings, I even had the idea You shouldn’t have unreasonable doubts if you haven’t read the original work. I don’t know how the discussion of the book unfolded. Taoism&#39;s &quot;following the Tao, being weak, doing nothing, abandoning wisdom&quot; all have their own specific historical context and intertextual relationship. Is the &quot;wisdom&quot; mentioned in &quot;Qi Zhi&quot; a general sense? In terms of semantic relationship, can &quot;abandoning wisdom&quot; be separated from &quot;extreme sage&quot;? Although the political thought of Taoism is mentioned in academic circles, those who do not talk about &quot;governance&quot; but pursue &quot;governing by doing nothing&quot; and do not talk about &quot;law&quot; but hope for &quot;a world of supreme virtue&quot; generally use &quot;quan&quot; as the core meaning. Xiang’s “political thought”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Teacher Ge’s perspective in writing the preface is different. He criticized that &quot;some people always want to advocate &amp;nbsp;&#39;interpret China by China&#39;&quot;, meaning that these people attempt to study ancient Chinese thought in isolation from the world&#39;s modern pluralistic knowledge system. I totally agree with this. I think of Takeuchi&#39;s &quot;Asia as Method&quot; and Maruyama Masao&#39;s &quot;China as Method.&quot; The methods they advocate do not exclude the world&#39;s diverse knowledge systems. They just hope to use China&#39;s historical experience and traditional thoughts as one of the world&#39;s cognitive systems and methods. The reason why those advocates of &quot;explaining China in terms of China&quot; are problematic may be because they want to break away from the world&#39;s diverse knowledge system and develop a system that only they (here, they themselves) understand, and cannot communicate with others because they ignore consensus. The mystical explanation system of dialogue; or because its purpose is not to explain China in terms of &quot;China&quot;, but to explain China from the perspective of traditional &quot;rulers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is right in criticizing that these people always want to &quot;advocate going back to ancient times&quot; to find a &quot;whole must and tail&quot; explanation system. If these people have any basic respect for common sense, they should know that they cannot go back after receiving modern education. According to the basic assumptions of pragmatics, the context on which cognition is generated is not reality, but a construction, which is the result of selecting specific parameters. The so-called ancient context is actually a modern construction they made for a special purpose and based on their chosen cognitive framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, what Teacher Ge said: modern concepts and re-division and integration, &quot;allowing the originally chaotic ancient culture to present an understandable face&quot; should refer to allowing ancient culture to be understood in the modern cognitive environment. However, any contemporary &quot;rediscovery&quot; of ancient documents is actually a cognitive reconstruction of ancient times based on modern knowledge or experience. Therefore, how close this understanding is to the original face of the research object also depends on different perceptions. Know the choice of framework. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I am not opposed to re-examining ancient ideas from the perspective of modern political science to present different modern understandings. I just want to say that the premise of this kind of review is that we cannot ignore the historical semantic fields and semantic relationships of various conceptual systems, and we cannot cut them off to suit their needs. What cannot be forgotten is that the reason why we can find modern elements in ancient concepts, that is, the so-called &quot;ancient concepts&quot;, is more because we have replaced the cognitive framework and placed related concepts in different semantics. field, a new semantic relationship is constructed based on the new semantic field. But because the words are still words from the past, it is very easy to mistake our construction for the original semantic items of these words. This is what I think is the trap of modern cognitive frameworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book &quot;Political Science&quot; actually has a clear understanding of the differences in historical semantics. As the book points out, ancient Greece, the source of Western political science, had a fundamentally different view of politics: “In the eyes of the ancient Greeks, politics was the governance and management activities in which citizens of the city-state participated. The concept of politics at that time itself included citizen participation. The meaning of city-state affairs. Only the participation of citizens in the governance and management of city-state affairs can be called politics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, although the political words of &quot;royal power&quot; and &quot;civil rights&quot; have not changed, they Do they belong to the same semantic field? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had the chance to read &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot;. &amp;nbsp;These are at best a record of random thoughts caused by reading the preface of the book posted online. I will wait until I have time to read it. , be sure to read the original work carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 18:25:27 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>