<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 17:59:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers of 99 Charity Day They introduced matching donations. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a charitable organization with strong fundraising capabilities, the China Children’s Charity Aid Foundation (referred to as Children’s Charity Society) has recently fallen into disarray. In the midst of the donation turmoil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, Ke Mouxiao was accused of using the Children&#39;s Charity Society&#39;s &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Assistance&quot; project (hereinafter referred to as 9958) to defraud families of seriously ill children out of nearly 1,000 yuan. 10,000 life-saving money was detained by the police. The Children&#39;s Charity Association publicly stated that Ke Mouxiao was not its staff and had only served as a volunteer in the Hebei Langfang Team Cooperation Organization of the 9958 Project. But the controversy has not yet died down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many parents of children who were deceived said that they participated in the &quot;matching donation&quot; initiated by Ke Mouxiao and transferred the funds to Ke Mouxiao. They expected that within a period of time Afterwards, a return higher than the principal amount will be obtained, and the excess will be donated by the enterprise. Because this kind of &quot;matching donation&quot; is a normal operation mode in the charity sector, and families of seriously ill children are accustomed to it, there is no doubt about the authenticity of the project initiated by Ke Mouxiao. (For details, please see Southern Weekly’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685?source=131&quot;>;China Children’s Charity Association volunteers are involved in nearly 10 million yuan in aid, and families with serious illness are in trouble again. Matching donation scam&lt;/a>;》)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the &quot;matching donation&quot; that parents of children with children are accustomed to, is it a arbitrage donation in a gray area? According to relevant laws and policies, it is illegal for charitable organizations to induce parents of children with self-raised funds to participate in matching donations or donate for their own use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Does the Children&#39;s Charity Association know about such &quot;matching donations&quot;? Southern Weekend reporters discovered that deficiencies in the management and operation of charitable organizations provide a breeding ground for the alienation of matching donations. The more money is raised, the more matching donations are made - with the same goal, the people who need the money most take their money out of their pockets, boosting the charity&#39;s fundraising figures. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Who dares to do it if you can’t get the money back?”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s the 99 Charity Day in September every year. Li Shan (pseudonym) from Guangxi I want to raise more life-saving money for my daughter who is suffering from leukemia. He decided to participate in &quot;matching donations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;99 Charity Day is a national charity event jointly launched by Internet companies and hundreds of charity organizations, enterprises, and celebrities. September 9, 2015 is China&#39;s first Internet Charity Day. In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers introduced a popular foreign method-matching donations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Matching donation is matching donation. After one donor donates a sum of money to a charity organization, another donor (usually a company) will randomly or according to Donate a certain percentage of money to the same charity organization. The original intention of the matching donation model is to encourage the public to participate in donations. According to its original intention, the donation amount including corporate matching should not be used for the donor himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Charity Law also clearly stipulates that when a donor and a charitable organization agree on the purpose and beneficiaries of donated property, the donor&#39;s interested parties shall not be designated as beneficiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Li Shan has never heard of the above regulations. On the eve of the 99 Charity Day in 2023, Li Shan opened a &quot;Donate Together&quot; charity matching donation project for each of the three charity matching projects launched by the Children&#39;s Charity Society: &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot;, &quot;Girls in Need Guarantee Plan&quot; and &quot;Aiding Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot;. ” fundraising link and named it after his daughter, who has leukemia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Donate Together&quot; is a charity game launched by Tencent Charity Platform. Users click the corresponding button on the public welfare project homepage and fill in the target amount and sponsor information to generate a link. Donors open the link and enter the amount to donate. Subsequently, this donation information and the corresponding matching donation will be recorded in the initiator&#39;s &quot;Donate Together&quot; and can be publicly queried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the public information and implementation plan of the project, the recipients of &quot;Sunflower Guarding Children in the West&quot; are children in need in the western provinces under the age of 18. &quot;Girls in Distress&quot; The &quot;Guarantee Plan&quot; will provide long-term assistance to girls in need across the country, and the goal of &quot;Assisting Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot; is to allow children in need to go to school with peace of mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I really don&#39;t understand this.&quot; On September 17, 2023, Li Shan listened to a reporter from Southern Weekend introduce the above three projects and said that he neither I don’t know who these projects are aiding, and I don’t know whether my behavior counts as a donation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But before that, in the three days from September 7th to 9th, Li Shan raised more than 210,000 yuan for these three projects through &quot;donate together&quot; , including several &quot;donations&quot; worth 3,000 yuan and 4,000 yuan. According to the rules, Tencent will donate more than 22,000 yuan to this end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan explained to Southern Weekend reporters that these &quot;donations&quot; were all his own money. &quot;The people who &#39;donated money&#39; were some relatives and friends. I gave the money to them first and then asked them to donate it to the project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan said frankly , for the more than 200,000 yuan he &quot;donated&quot;, he had no intention of using it to aid children or girls in need in the west. &quot;We are all short of money ourselves.&quot; He believes that the money &quot;donated&quot; and matched by enterprises will eventually come back to him. &quot;Who dares to do it if he can&#39;t get (the money) back?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that in the three days from September 7th to 9th, a total of 12,000 people participated in the above-mentioned activities in the form of &quot;donate together&quot; For the three projects, they &quot;donated&quot; a total of more than 8.86 million yuan. Each &quot;donate together&quot; raised an average of 45,900 yuan, and the largest single &quot;donation&quot; was 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251851&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A &quot;Donate Together&quot; link initiated by a parent of a seriously ill child for the project of &quot;Aiding Children in Distress to Dream of Going to School&quot;. (Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Self-raised, self-donated, self-used&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Through &quot;matching donations&quot;, the money &quot;donated&quot; can be returned &quot;with interest&quot;. Li Shan began to form this understanding in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he was hospitalized in Dongguan with his daughter. In order to seek medical treatment for his daughter, who has not yet entered elementary school, he claimed to have spent at least 700,000 yuan in two years. He remembers that day, the patient next to him took out 2,000 yuan and asked him to &quot;donate&quot; the link he had opened for him, and at the same time help answer the questions (according to the rules of the platform, those who answer the questions will have a chance to get more matching donations). The patient told him that after doing so, the platform would randomly match an undetermined amount of matching donation, and &quot;after certain procedures,&quot; the patient would not only get the matching donation, but &quot;the principal can also be returned.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the eve of 99 Charity Day in 2023, Li Shan joined a &quot;matching donation group&quot;. He said that the organizer of the group is a staff member of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, and the group members call him &quot;teacher&quot;. Southern Weekend reporters were unable to confirm whether the organizer was an official staff member of the Children&#39;s Charity Society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tencent Foundation has provided a matching donation of 299.99 million yuan for all charity projects participating in the 2023 99 Charity Day activities. According to the matching donation rules announced by the platform, starting from 10:00 am on September 7th to 9th, every user donation greater than 1 yuan may receive a random amount of matching donation. The daily matching donation amount is on a first-come, first-served basis while supplies last. Together with the funds donated by donors, it will be transferred to the donated charity projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Li Shan’s understanding of “matching donation” is obviously different. &quot;He (the group organizer) told us when to start investing, and then we started donating money.&quot; Li Shan recalled that through mutual communication among patients in the group, he learned that as long as he launched the &quot;Donate Together&quot; fundraising link in the designated project , find someone to donate money and help answer questions, the &quot;teacher&quot; can apply for a &quot;matching donation&quot; for him, and the principal can be returned through &quot;relevant procedures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the start of the 99 Charity Day, the &quot;teacher&quot; announced the &quot;quota&quot; in the group, and he signed up in the group; after signing up, he sent it to his relatives and friends Transfer money; at 10 o&#39;clock on the day of the event, while there is still a matching donation quota, you must &quot;raise it yourself as soon as possible, otherwise you will not be able to vote later and the link is full&quot;; after the event is over, wait for the refund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Within three days, Li Shan &quot;donated&quot; more than 200,000 yuan to three projects initiated by the Children&#39;s Charity Association. &quot;No parent asked why he donated to these projects. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information of the project shows that a total of 54 people initiated &quot;Donate Together&quot; within three days of &quot;Assisting Children in Distress to Dream of Going to School.&quot; Two years after the project was launched, it has completed its fundraising goal and raised 4.35 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of press time, &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; has reached the public fundraising goal of 5 million yuan. In addition to Li Shan, 102 people have launched the &quot;Donate Together&quot; &quot;. 78 people participated in the &quot;Donate Together&quot; program of the &quot;Girls in Distress Protection Plan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5944ffaa94.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/5944ffaa94.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251852&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; has reached its public fundraising goal of 5 million yuan. (Internet screenshot/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It can be seen from public information on the Internet that during the 99 Charity Day, most of the link names of &quot;Donate Together&quot; are named after children. Naming; often multiple accounts repeatedly &quot;donate money&quot; to a link, with a single amount reaching a thousand yuan; multiple names appear in different projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fundraising link is named after the child, allegedly to facilitate later repayment. Wang Qiang (pseudonym) who once worked in a local team of 9958 said that after the 99 Charity Day, parents would send screenshots of &quot;Donate Together&quot; named after their children to the financial staff of the 9958 local sub-center, who would then make statistics on each donation. How much money did each parent actually invest? The &quot;Donate Together&quot; page will display the funds raised by parents and the amount matched by the platform. The self-raised portion will be returned to parents after the 99 Charity Day. “This is the money in the account of the Children’s Charity Association.” The matching donation portion will have to wait until the platform transfers the matching donation funds to the Children’s Charity Association, “and then through the local people’s charity.” It will not be returned to parents through organizations or other channels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Qiang also explained to Southern Weekend reporters that when allocating the matching donation amount, parents need to provide the staff with an invoice consistent with the total allocation amount of the foundation, &quot;For example The principal is 50,000, and the matching donation is 20,000. Parents must provide an invoice with a face value of 70,000 to the foundation, otherwise the accounts will not be balanced.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The content of the invoice provided by the parents of the children must be related to the child&#39;s condition. Invoices for hospitalization, outpatient services or purchased medicines are all acceptable.&quot; Wang Qiang further mentioned . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 17, Li Shan said that he had not received the refund yet. After the Ke Mouxiao incident was exposed, he was worried that he would not be able to get back the money he invested. &quot;(The staff) didn&#39;t say when they would give us the money. Before the incident, they said we would submit the child&#39;s information and wait for the foundation (Children&#39;s Charity Society) to give us the money back, but now we are in a panic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Southern Metropolis Daily, some parents who have successfully received &quot;matching donations&quot; have presented bank transfer slips, and the payee was the Children&#39;s Charity Association. However, Sun Dandan, director of the platform communication department of the Children’s Charity Society, said that some parents received funds from the Children’s Charity Society not because of “matching donations”, but because they met the rescue standards of the 9958 project, and local teams or rescue stations submitted the funds for their children. If the information and situation are evaluated and meet the rescue standards, the rescue funds will be released according to the rescue process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tencent Charity reported on September 13 that although Ke Mouxiao’s behavior did not occur on the Tencent Charity platform, based on the platform operating rules, industry self-discipline conventions and user-oriented principles, the following was made: Decision: Suspension of fundraising for all 9958 projects pending official investigation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The team calls on parents to donate large amounts&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Does the Children&#39;s Charity Association know about Li Shan&#39;s &quot;matching donations&quot;? A WeChat group communication record obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that it was at the call of staff and volunteers that many parents of seriously ill children actively participated in the so-called &quot;matching donations&quot; on the 99 Charity Day in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This group is called &quot;Core Personnel of the Four National Branch Centers of the Children&#39;s Charity Society Project&quot;, with a maximum number of more than 70 people. The leader of the group is Wang Yu, whose name is the deputy secretary-general of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, Director of the 9958 Rescue Center of the Emergency Rescue Department. Almost all the 9958 project staff shown in the 2022 annual report of the Children&#39;s Charity Association are in the group, in addition to the &quot;responsible persons&quot; of various 9958 local teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Emergency Relief Department is also known as Project Department 4. According to the official website of the Children&#39;s Society, the 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Relief Center is established under it. The 2022 annual report of the Children’s Society shows that the 9958 Rescue Center of the Emergency Rescue Department has 16 staff members, which is the largest department in the Children’s Society. Its 9958 children&#39;s emergency rescue project was established in 2012 and is an independent brand project of the Children&#39;s Charity Association. Over the years, this project has established 25 relief sub-centers across the country in Weinan, Henan, Shanxi, Tai&#39;an, and Shijiazhuang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since August 2023, the staff member whose group nickname is &quot;9958-Cao Lifang&quot; has frequently shared information and reminders related to 99 Charity Day in the group. According to the WeChat public account &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue&quot; and the 2022 annual report of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, Cao Lifang is the director of the fourth project department of the Children&#39;s Charity Society and also serves as the director of the 9958 Rescue Center. During the 99 Charity Day, he was also the coordinator of the 9958 project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 23, Cao Lifang informed the group that &quot;the platform is conducting a donation matching test&quot; and asked staff to make small donations to participating projects and experience the event process. . &quot;It is not recommended to allow parents to participate in the test. It is impossible to determine the amount of parents&#39; investment, which will take up the remaining fundraising space of the project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 29, she said again Reminder, &quot;Participating children should pay attention to whether the disease type is consistent with the project. If the disease type is not specified, the project will treat it as all diseases. If the project specifies autism, premature infants, and congenital heart disease, the team will ask the parents to respond accordingly. Disease type, if the item is for girls, please ask the team to check that boys do not use it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Two days later, she shared with everyone the matching donation for 99 Charity Day Understand the rules. For example, if you need help from friends to answer the question &quot;Whether you answer correctly or not, you will have a chance to get a matching donation,&quot; parents can follow the training materials of the Children&#39;s Charity Association to learn to improve their charity status, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The team can directly call on parents to donate large amounts, and 80% of the donations must be completed on the 7th.&quot; Cao Lifang said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A charity figure who once worked in 9958 explained to Southern Weekend reporters that on the 99 Charity Day, many parents of children with children will invest money in multiple projects. , the platform has a high probability of matching the most funds to the project with the largest donation amount. &quot;A friend can only help the parents of the same seriously ill child once a day, and large donations will get the most matching donations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 4, Cao Lifang informed everyone in the group: &quot;Parents who participate in 99 Charity, please transfer money to relatives and friends in advance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the matching donation started on September 7, the group nickname was shown as &quot;9958 Platform Development Department-Xu Jiawen&quot; (the annual report showed that this name&#39;s position was &quot;9958 Relief Center Project Officer&quot; ) notified in the group, &quot;Public donation is a voluntary and free act. Please mobilize and regulate management to jointly protect the credibility of the industry.&quot; But more than half an hour later, the group nickname was &quot;Jia Zhen, 9958 Platform Development Department&quot;. Said, &quot;Parents with high allocation should hurry up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above-mentioned charity person explained that &quot;high allocation&quot; refers to the platform&#39;s matching donation ratio on that day is relatively high. &quot;Hurry up.&quot; &quot;Reduce&quot; is because after the matching donation starts, the amount of matching donation will be smaller as the time goes by, until the matching donation quota for the day is completely used up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At around 19:00 on September 7, &quot;9958 Platform Development Department-Xu Jiawen&quot; released statistical results in the group. On that day, the fourth project raised more than 82.44 million yuan and received allocation. Donated more than 5.61 million yuan. The Shijiazhuang team raised a total of more than 29.64 million yuan (including 1.82 million yuan in matching donations), ranking first among the 17 local teams; the Tai&#39;an team raised a total of 19.51 million yuan (including 1.16 million yuan in matching donations), ranking second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 23, Southern Weekend reporters called the mobile phone numbers reserved by Cao Lifang and Jia Zhen on the public platform, but no one answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6e635b278e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6e635b278e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251853&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, the fundraising rankings of various local teams were released in the &quot;Core Personnel of the National Branch Centers of the Four National Branches of the Children&#39;s Charity Project&quot; group. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; Volunteers&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”, execution fees, fundraising rankings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than 80 million yuan raised in one day, confirming the success of Erci In recent years, it has left people with the impression that it has super fundraising capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public financial reports show that 714 million yuan in donations will flow into the Children&#39;s Charity Association in 2022; this number will be 838 million yuan in 2021 and 838 million yuan in 2020. It’s 834 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, 9958, as the star project of the Children’s Charity Society, has generated revenue of 322 million yuan (2020), 262 million yuan (2021) and 262 million yuan respectively in the past three years. 227 million yuan (2022), accounting for about one-third of the total annual revenue of the Children&#39;s Charity Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, public data does not show how much of the annual fundraising of the Children&#39;s Charity Association is strictly public donation, and how much is for matching donations. self-donated for personal use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tencent Charity Regulations in 2023 stipulate that during the 99 Charity Days, fundraising organizations can use 20% of the income matching donations for the operation and development of the organization. This means that the higher the amount raised by an organization, the more matching donations it will receive from the platform, and the more incentives it will ultimately receive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, during periods other than matching donations, each fundraising organization can receive up to 2 million yuan in unrestricted donations as incentives. This part of the incentive payment is first come, first served, and the institution does not have to use it for project execution. At around 15:30 on September 7, Xu Jiawen informed everyone in the group: &quot;The backstage non-matching rewards have reached 2 million (ten thousand), and no new incentives will be obtained.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this matching donation controversy, The Children&#39;s Charity Association stated that it has never entrusted Ke Mouxiao to personally raise funds for the 9958 project. Ke Mouxiao is not a staff member of the association, but a volunteer of the 9958 Langfang team cooperation organization. However, Wang Qiang and the above-mentioned charity people said that this kind of personnel cooperation mechanism is common in the Children&#39;s Charity Society. Many people who organize fund-raising in the name of &quot;9958 staff&quot; are not official staff of the Children&#39;s Charity Society, but they are raising funds He has greater authority and is also under pressure to raise funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qiang told Southern Weekend reporters that after he joined a local 9958 team as a staff member, he did not sign a labor or labor contract with the Children&#39;s Benevolent Society or the local 9958 rescue center. He said that his usual salary is paid by local non-governmental organizations or enterprises, and the same is true for his colleagues around him. In a sense, Wang Qiang&#39;s identity is the same as Ke Mouxiao, and he is also a &quot;volunteer&quot;, but in external publicity, he is called the operations specialist of the 9958 team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Wang Qiang cannot be considered a volunteer in the strict sense. According to the &quot;Volunteer Service Regulations&quot;, volunteer services should follow the principle of free payment. Some legal scholars once suggested that the behavior of raising funds for patients and collecting execution fees is more like the professional fundraisers commonly seen in foreign charitable relief. It is only because the current domestic fundraising system is imperfect that all parties call this group &quot;volunteers&quot; &quot;. (For details, see Southern Weekend’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/203083&quot;>;Suspicions about “matching donations” among “fundraising volunteers”&lt;/a>;”)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; During the several years of working in 9958, Wang Qiang felt that he was &quot;like a businessman.&quot; If you only do your job, your monthly income will not exceed 4,000 yuan. If you want a higher income, you need to find more families with seriously ill children and help them raise funds publicly on several Internet platforms as &quot;volunteers.&quot; Wang Qiang described the fundraising link as an &quot;online project&quot; and claimed that he could get an execution fee of 3% or more of the total fundraising amount, but he did not produce a transfer voucher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with public donations without specific beneficiaries, parents of seriously ill children have a stronger motivation to raise funds and can help &quot;volunteers&quot; reach their fundraising goals faster. In fact, Ke Mouxiao himself may be a parent of children with serious illnesses. Information about his fundraising for children with blood cancer in 2021 can be found on the Internet, as well as bank statement receipts in which he is the payee and a charity organization is the payer. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Some parents are so pitiful that they will kneel down and beg you for a fundraising project.&quot; Wang Qiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even different teams will compete for &quot;business&quot;. The aforementioned charity worker who worked at 9958 told Southern Weekend reporters that he had previously worked with a seriously ill child in a cancer hospital and had collected the child’s information and was preparing to take photos of the child, write fundraising copy, and upload it to the Internet the next day. , &quot;As a result, the parents refused to let me take the photo the next day, and asked me for a letter of authorization (for the agency) to publicly use the child&#39;s photos before I left. Later I found out that someone from another team had snatched the child away.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9958 will also conduct internal team fundraising rankings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 20, 2023, the group nickname was &quot;9958 New Media~Sun Shuo&quot; (the annual report showed that the name and position were &quot;9958 Rescue Center&quot; &quot;Project Officer&quot;) published in the work group the ranking of the amount of funds raised by teams from various regions on the Kuaishou platform from August 11 to August 18: the Beijing team raised 51,000 yuan, the Guiyang team raised 5,320 yuan, and the Anhui team raised 5,320 yuan. The total amount raised was 3,326 yuan, the Lanzhou team raised 1,912 yuan, and the Tai&#39;an team raised 801 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s still far behind other team teachers.&quot; A person with the nickname &quot;Taian Team Mengmeng&quot; said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;September 9, the 2023 99 Charity Day is coming to an end. Xu Jiawen reported the data of the 9958 project in the group over the past three days: the total fundraising received in the three days exceeded 134 million yuan, and the total matching donations received exceeded 11.81 million yuan. She also attached a ranking chart of the total fundraising of each local team from high to low: the Shijiazhuang team ranked first, raising more than 36.4 million yuan; the Tai&#39;an team ranked second, raising more than 28.04 million yuan; the Weinan team ranked third, Raising more than 27.36 million yuan; Shanxi team ranked fourth, raising more than 20.74 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Thank you to all the teachers for their efforts during the event. Teachers have worked hard.&quot; Xu Jiawen said in the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters were unable to obtain the list of local teams established by 9958 through public channels. However, according to the above chat records, there are at least Shijiazhuang, Tai&#39;an, Shanxi, Guangdong, There are 17 teams in Shanghai, Weinan, Qingdao, Lanzhou and Baoding. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Vague information disclosure&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How the funds raised by the Children’s Aid Society from the many projects of 9958 will be used. According to regulations, it needs to be disclosed, but it is open to the public. To varying degrees. The death of female college student Wu Huayan in 2020 once plunged 9958 into controversy over insufficient information disclosure and over-age rescue. (For details, see Southern Weekend’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/174760?source=131&quot;>;&quot;Wu Huayan&#39;s death&quot; triggers reflection by public welfare individuals&lt;/a>;&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The disclosure of vague project information has created convenience for donations and matching funds to return to the hands of Li Shan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take the projects Li Shan participated in as an example. Among the three projects that Li Shan &quot;donated&quot; under the organization of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot; and &quot;Guarantee Plan for Girls in Distress&quot; have not yet entered the implementation disclosure period, and &quot;Assisting Children in Distress to Go to School Dream&quot; (referred to as &quot;School Dream&quot; ) project has been established for nearly two years, and it has disclosed several aspects such as project progress and finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The information disclosure of public welfare projects is related to their own scope of assistance. For example, medical assistance projects should disclose the list of recipients, types of diseases, and information about medical institutions. and rescue standards. However, there are contradictions between the existing public information of &quot;School Dream&quot; and its own purpose of assistance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The project introduction states, &quot;A donation of 10 yuan can support a child to buy a set of school supplies. A donation of 50 yuan can support part of a child&#39;s living expenses. &quot;. However, its 2022 financial disclosure details stated that the more than 2.06 million yuan allocated to recipients were all medical subsidies for recipients, and the corresponding living allowance was not announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The student aid program provides tuition fees, which are usually recorded as &#39;living allowances&#39; in financial terms, unless the children being rescued need medical treatment at the same time.&quot; Enyou Finance co-founder Zhou Zaoying found it difficult to understand the problems with this detailed list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;School Dream&quot; has disclosed the financial expenditure invoices for 2022 on the Tencent Charity Platform. In June, October and December, the Children&#39;s Association will realize the dream in Tai&#39;an City The Public Welfare Development Center (referred to as Tai&#39;an Dream Realization) allocated 3.39 million yuan, 1.63 million yuan, and 270,000 yuan respectively, and indicated that nearly 1.292 million yuan came from the &quot;School Dream&quot; project. The 2022 audit report of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society also shows that Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng, as a &quot;large payment object&quot;, received a rescue activity fee of 1.287 million yuan from the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the executor of the public introduction of &quot;School Dream&quot; is the 9958 Beijing Xiangyang Group Rescue Center, and Southern Weekend reporters did not find that Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng has a public business relationship with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The invoice information sent to Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng by Children&#39;s Charity Society shows that the reviewer and payee of Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng are both Li Mengmeng. According to the 2022 annual report of Tai&#39;an Yuanmeng, Li Mengmeng is the chairman of the organization and You Guobao is the administrative person in charge. According to the content released by the 9958 WeChat public account, the above two people are also the directors of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team. Southern Weekend reporters also discovered that Li Mengmeng’s WeChat nickname and avatar were consistent with the “Taian Team Mengmeng” in the above-mentioned Children’s Society work group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 23, a Southern Weekend reporter called Li Mengmeng. The other party said he would not accept an interview and refused to disclose the specific nature and whereabouts of the funding. Southern Weekend reporters called the charity’s platform department, communications department and children’s emergency hotline, but were unable to get through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Mengmeng raised funds as the director of the 9958 Tai&#39;an team, and also executed the project as the legal representative of Tai&#39;an Dream Realization. From an optimistic perspective, &#39;going to school Meng&#39; is a national public welfare project. If she is familiar with the situation in Tai&#39;an, she can implement it more efficiently locally.&quot; Zhou Zaoying said. But from a pessimistic perspective, “Insufficient and difficult-to-explain information about projects may lead to a crisis of public trust in the public welfare industry.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7a90c82ab7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7a90c82ab7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251854&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The invoice shows that in June 2022, the Children&#39;s Charity Association allocated 3.39 million yuan to Tai&#39;an Dream. (Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Who does fake matching donation harm?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;&quot;Donations must be voluntary and gratuitous. If parents invest money in public welfare projects on the premise of returning donations and obtaining matching donation funds, it is not even a donation.&quot; Legal Research and Services of Shanghai Fulen Social Organization Lu Xuan, chairman of the center, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people believe that some parents of seriously ill children are also in need of public welfare assistance, and it is understandable to obtain matching donation funds through self-donation. But Lu Xuan doesn&#39;t see it that way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Very bad.&quot; Lu Xuan analyzed that the public welfare nature of a charity organization determines that its mission is to help unspecified objects in society. If project staff encourage parents of seriously ill children to donate money to the project before arranging allocations, it will become a &quot;specific target&quot; to be helped. In addition to constituting a donation arbitrage that violates the principle of good faith, it also violates the public welfare nature of a charitable organization. The principles of “openness, fairness and impartiality” that should be followed in the selection of project beneficiaries that do not comply with the Charity Law. This may prevent the needy people who are more in need of assistance from receiving relief funds, and also detract from the overall social evaluation of the charitable organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ma Jianyin, associate professor at Beijing Normal University Law School, also does not believe that the behavior of &quot;first investing money in public welfare projects and then taking money from the foundation&quot; is a donation. &quot;This is a false donation made to obtain matching donations. If the evidence chain is complete, it is a kind of &#39;fraudulent donation&#39;.&quot; Ma Jianyin analyzed that the deceived in this behavior are the main ones who use funds to make matching donations. &quot;They You can hold the organizer accountable or report it to the civil affairs department.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Parents of seriously ill children who need help from public welfare organizations often have limited income and do not have the strength to do so. Strong social ties may be to vulnerable groups in society. A legal expert who studies social organizations analyzed to a reporter from Southern Weekend that if this group learns that they can make &quot;donations&quot; through organizations, they will have a very strong motivation to participate, &quot;because they will feel that they are the beneficiaries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this kind of behavior will hurt more potential targets who also need help, and deprive other disadvantaged groups of the public support that may belong to them. In addition, it will also make it difficult for public welfare organizations that are already lacking in resources to develop. The industry generally calls for separation of fundraising and use in charity fundraising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, Cao Lifang sent a document called &quot;Children’s Association 99 Charity Day Self-Discipline Convention&quot; to the above-mentioned work group. Each team leader was also required to sign and fingerprint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 7 of this self-discipline convention states, &quot;Put an end to any form of extortion of matching donations.&quot; If there is any violation, &quot;I will bear all the responsibilities and consequences arising therefrom and accept all the handling of this matter by the Chinese Children&#39;s Benefit Association.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;With the issuance of internal regulations, does the organization no longer have management responsibilities?&quot; Lu Xuan analyzed that even if the staff of the local teams do not have direct labor or employment with 9958, Labor relations, but these people have actually provided services to 9958. Through the exchange of funds between institutions, it can be proved that there is a certain contractual relationship between several entities. &quot;If the local team of 9958 makes a mistake, it doesn&#39;t make sense for the local team to take responsibility in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从寻找F-35战机，看失事战机“僵尸飞行”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257548]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of September 18, 2023, local time, after an intensive 28-hour search, the U.S. military The wreckage of a previously missing F35B fighter jet was found in a field northeast of Joint Base Charleston, South Carolina. Aerial videos circulated on social platforms showed that there was a large area of ​​charred land on the field, and the woods on one side were in a mess. A large number of trees were knocked down, and there were obvious signs of excessive fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before, an F-35B &quot;Lightning&quot; II Joint Strike Fighter had an accident during a routine exercise. The pilot chose to eject to escape in an emergency. After that, the fighter jet continued flying in a &quot;zombie state&quot; and lost contact over South Carolina. In order to recover the missing F-35B fighter jet, multiple U.S. military services and departments jointly launched a &quot;missing notice&quot; on social media to solicit clues from the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bizarre incident involving a large-scale search for fighter jets has sparked heated discussions on the Internet, with many people finding it unbelievable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Carolina Congresswoman Nancy Mace asked on social media: &quot;What happened? How did you lose an F-35? Why is there no tracking equipment? You have to ask the public to help find it. Fighters and turn them in?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Air force training bases are generally established in the suburbs of cities, and radar deployment cannot be comprehensive. When the aircraft stalls and is at a lower flying altitude, it is not uncommon for the radar to fail to detect the target. More What&#39;s more, the F-35B fighter jet has excellent stealth capabilities and its radar reflection surface is extremely small.&quot; Wang Qunhuai, a former naval officer, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is not unprecedented for fighter jets to fly away without pilots. There have been fighter jets that flew nearly a thousand kilometers long distances after losing control of the pilot, until they ran out of fuel and crashed in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Where did the fighter jet go?&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;If you have any clues that can help us find the F-35 fighter jet, please call the Base Defense Operations Center. &quot;On September 18, 2023 local time, the United States Joint Base Charleston released an &quot;Opportunity Notice&quot; on social platforms, which attracted public attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The missing fighter belongs to the 501st Fighter Attack Training Squadron of the 2nd Air Wing of the U.S. Marine Corps, which is mainly responsible for pilot training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 17, a US military pilot flew an F-35B &quot;Lightning&quot; II fighter jet and took off from Joint Base Charleston to perform a training mission. But not long after, the fighter plane suddenly had an accident, and the pilot chose to eject to escape at a critical moment. At about 2 p.m., the pilot landed safely in the Charleston community and was later taken to the hospital, but the whereabouts of the F-35B he was flying was unknown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A spokesman for Joint Base Charleston told NBC that after the pilot ejected, the fighter jet was in autopilot mode, complicating tracking. Agence France-Presse reported that the fighter jet will continue to fly in a so-called &quot;zombie state&quot; until it crashes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that an F-35 fighter plane was accompanying the flight at the time of the incident. But the pilot did not continue to follow the drone and chose to return to base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the fighter plane disappeared, the U.S. military quickly joined forces with the Marine Corps, Navy, FAA, Civil Air Patrol and local law enforcement agencies in South Carolina to surround Moore, north of North Charleston. A three-dimensional search was conducted from the air and on the ground in the area of ​​Terry Lake and Marion Lake. In the evening of September 18, several search aircraft circled an area of ​​woods and farmland near the town of Starkey in Williamsburg County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a day and night of searching, a spokesperson for the U.S. Marine Corps confirmed that the wreckage of the F-35B fighter jet was found in a field in Williamsburg County. The crash site is about 129 kilometers from Joint Base Charleston. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The F-35B combines many advantages such as stealth, short takeoff, and vertical landing, and has a high level of versatility and interoperability. It is one of the most advanced and popular fighter jets in the world. &quot;Shepard Media, a well-known British defense media website, commented. But it is such an advanced fighter plane that is known as the &quot;main killer of future air combat&quot;, but it has set off an Internet group ridicule in the United States of &quot;Where have the fighters gone?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ABC News contributor and retired colonel Steve Ganyard complained, &quot;Even though it is a stealth aircraft, it is really surprising that such an expensive and complex aircraft can disappear. Ridiculous.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is not as easy for radar to capture stealth fighters as people think.&quot; Wang Qunhuai pointed out that on the one hand, the air warning radar has a high elevation angle, and the electromagnetic waves emitted basically propagate in a straight line. It can be effectively identified only when it flies to a high enough altitude; on the other hand, the F-35B fighter&#39;s maximum flight speed can reach up to thousands of kilometers per hour, and it can fly hundreds of kilometers in a few minutes. Once the transponder loses its function, it is basically invisible to the radar. You can only search with your naked eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The F-35 fighter jet is equipped with a Longbo lens. Wang Qunhuai said that this is to deliberately increase the reflected signal and make it easier to be detected by air traffic control radar when landing. &quot;Of course, when stealth flight is required, the Longbo lens The lens will be retracted”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the U.S. military considers the accident to be a Class A accident, the highest level of severity, but has not revealed the name of the pilot involved or the cause of the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first time that an F35-B fighter jet has suffered a Class A accident. Four months ago, an F-35B fighter jet of the US military stationed in Japan had parts falling off during flight training, and the fighter jet subsequently returned to the Iwakuni base. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;MiG-23 across Europe&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The mysterious disappearance of advanced fighter jets is surprising, but this is not the first time in history. The &quot;zombie flight&quot; experience of the MiG-23 fighter more than thirty years ago is more legendary than the F-35B. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, the Berlin Wall still stood high between East and West Germany, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, headed by the United States, and the Warsaw Pact, headed by the Soviet Union, were in a tense confrontation in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public records, on the morning of July 4th, Colonel Nikolay Skuridin, who had just finished his vacation, boarded a MiG-23 fighter jet as usual and flew from near Kołobrzeg, Poland. Take off from Bagiz Air Base. For this experienced pilot, this was just an extremely ordinary flight training. He did not expect that this day would be recorded in the history of world aviation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Skuridin piloted the plane to climb to an altitude of 150 meters, he suddenly found that the thrust of the engine afterburner had dropped sharply. When he realized that the plane had begun to fall, Skuridin immediately reported it to the ground command center. Engine failure problem. After receiving the tower&#39;s instruction to abandon the aircraft and parachute, he decisively pressed the emergency canopy ejection button. The MiG-23 fighter canopy detached from the fuselage, and Skuridin was safely ejected from the cockpit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, the unmanned MiG-23 fighter jet did not die in the Baltic Sea as expected. Instead, it suddenly raised its head and climbed upwards under the action of ejection, and soon resumed normal flight. gesture, flying westward over northern Poland and across what was then the Democratic Republic of Germany (East Germany). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the air defense radar stationed in Poland recognized the fighter plane, it mistakenly thought it was a routine training and its flight trajectory was not interfered with. In less than half an hour, the MiG-23 fighter jet entered the territory of the Federal Republic of Germany (West Germany) and was detected by the NATO warning radar deployed in Hamburg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the alert, the NATO military command urgently dispatched two American F-15 fighter jets stationed in the Netherlands to intercept. Compared with the US fighter jets, which were waiting in a tight formation, this MiG-23 fighter did not make any evasive maneuvers and maintained its current speed and flew smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When American pilots who were ready for air combat approached the MiG-23 fighter, they found that the fighter had no canopy, no pilot, and no ammunition. As a result, the NATO military command lifted the interception order and ordered two F-15 fighters to follow the MiG-23 fighters. Subsequently, the MiG-23 fighter jet flew westward through Dutch airspace and entered Belgium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 10:30 a.m. local time, 80 kilometers away from the Belgian capital, a MiG-23 fighter jet that ran out of fuel crashed into a house in the town of Kortrijk-Belleheim in western Belgium. Wim Dral, a 19-year-old boy who was sleeping, died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, the Soviet Union was looking for the wreckage of MiG-23 fighter jets in the Baltic Sea. It wasn&#39;t until they saw reports from Western media that the Soviet Union knew that its fighter jets continued to fly unpiloted for 79 minutes, traveling more than 900 kilometers across Poland, the Democratic Republic of Germany, the Federal Republic of Germany, the Netherlands and Belgium, and finally landed in Belgium. crashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 6, Belgium protested to the Soviet Union over the plane crash. In the end, the Soviet Union paid approximately 625,000 euros in compensation to Belgium, most of which went to Dral&#39;s family. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cornfield Bomber&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot; Jedi encounter&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;生&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Dayton, Ohio, USA, is the hometown of the Wright brothers, the inventors of the aircraft. It is home to the U.S. Air Force Museum, the oldest and largest military aviation museum in the world. According to the official website, the museum houses about 400 aerospace vehicles dating back to World War I. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the various aircraft on display at the U.S. Air Force Museum, one of the F-106 fighter jets with a large delta wing design and a wasp-waisted fuselage does not seem to be conspicuous. But the legendary experience of its aftermath has been passed down orally from generation to generation of American pilots. They regarded it as a lucky fighter and affectionately called it the &quot;Cornfield Bomber.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 2, 1970, pilot Lieutenant Gary Foster took off in the F-106 fighter jet with tail number 580787. At the same time, three other F-106s took off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a routine tactical confrontation training that took place at Malmstrom Air Force Base in Montana, USA. According to the original plan, Lieutenant Foster will form a team with one of the pilots and conduct a peer-to-peer air combat exercise with two other F-106 fighters. However, due to a problem with the drag chute of one of the aircraft, the originally scheduled two-aircraft confrontation project turned into a &quot;one-on-two&quot; &quot;battle.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But when Lieutenant Foster piloted the F-106 fighter jet to an altitude of 10,000 meters, the fighter suddenly stalled and fell into an extremely dangerous horizontal rotation state, and then rapidly dropped to an altitude of about 3,657 meters. Foster attempted the spin recovery procedure multiple times without success before ejecting himself from the cockpit of the aircraft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the weight reduction of the fighter plane after the pilot ejected, the center of gravity changed, and the explosive force of the seat rushing out of the plane pushed the nose of the plane downwards. The F-106 fighter jet got rid of the rotation and flew without warning. Under human control, it enters a stable gliding state and flies smoothly in a straight line at a speed of more than 300 kilometers per hour. And this is exactly the approach speed of the F-106 fighter jet for landing under normal conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foster, hanging on the parachute, could only watch as his plane flew further and further away. He then landed in a nearby mountainous area and was rescued &lt;span>;by a local resident using a snowmobile&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The F-106 fighter jet he was flying landed safely in a cornfield near Big Sandy, Montana after flying for a certain distance. It even perfectly avoided the center of the field during taxiing. Rock pile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the local police arrived at the landing site, the aircraft engine was still running normally and the radar was still scanning. One hour and forty-five minutes later, the F-106 fighter ran out of fuel and the engine automatically shut down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, technicians from the Logistics Center at McClellan Air Force Base in California arrived at the scene. They were surprised to find that except for a few meters of scratches on the belly of the aircraft, the damage to the entire fighter jet was minimal. One rescue official even said that if the damage was less serious, he would fly the fighter directly back to the base. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Qunhuai&#39;s view, it is a rare thing for a manned fighter plane to land on its own without human control, and it is basically difficult to achieve. &quot;Aircraft landing is one of the most dangerous aspects of flight. It requires deceleration and descent to maintain the appropriate speed and altitude. The attitude and thrust of the fuselage must also be adjusted to adapt to the runway position and airflow conditions. If there is a problem in any aspect, it may Posing a threat to the landing of aircraft.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;War History Online&quot; website stated that the thick snow on the ground provided a buffer for the fighter planes to land lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the F-106 fighter was transported back to California, Air Force staff repaired it, and the fighter was subsequently put back into service. In 1979, Foster flew this fighter into the sky again to participate in training at Tyndall Air Force Base in Florida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1986, this F-106 fighter aircraft numbered 580787 was retired and subsequently donated to the U.S. Air Force Museum. A few years later, all F-106 fighter jets were retired from the U.S. military and completely bid farewell to the stage of history at the beginning of the 21st century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[超“潮”！杭州亚运会开幕式的中式浪漫细节]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257519]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The evening of September 23&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Held in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/254915ccf2ad57ad9fd7a8bf4127acda.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/254915ccf2ad57ad9fd7a8bf4127acda.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;251769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony was themed &quot;Tide Asia&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Presenting an epic picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/d8965edd72e7460a1ad6640a1a391f41.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;998&quot; height=&quot;516&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/d8965edd72e7460a1ad6640a1a391f41.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the romantic Chinese details at the opening ceremony? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s take a look↓↓&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The five-star red flag and the beautiful rivers and mountains are in the same frame&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony, the five-star red flag entered the scene&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/113dfe346ea641241d9d713533e00e6b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;753&quot; height= &quot;424&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/113dfe346ea641241d9d713533e00e6b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dang Mei The rivers and mountains and the five-star red flag are stunningly framed together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This scene is absolutely beautiful! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/21b1af400cf0fb531b1befc20cf1c3bc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;751&quot; height=&quot;422&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/21b1af400cf0fb531b1befc20cf1c3bc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251770&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The whole place was excited! The Chinese sports delegation enters the venue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/00ed01e32ff8894166c5846c6f43c841.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;468&quot; height=&quot;312&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/00ed01e32ff8894166c5846c6f43c841.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;251771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the Chinese sports delegation entered the venue&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Singing the Motherland&quot; sounded and the whole place was excited! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/855a12dc90b7d9abbd7c61e02fffba58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/855a12dc90b7d9abbd7c61e02fffba58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251768&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Qin Haiyang and Yang Liwei serve as flag bearers&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese delegation consists of 1,329 people&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them 886 athletes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;407 will participate in 38 major events A small competition&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/401fe6dcb5612723582820c87ad4e7de.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style= &quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;756&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/401fe6dcb5612723582820c87ad4e7de.gif&quot; data-key=&quot; 251774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2c13b27bb61d2712af91bef80f028c3f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2c13b27bb61d2712af91bef80f028c3f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251773&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/8ae77ea6de049cccf7c7254ee29e7574.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/8ae77ea6de049cccf7c7254ee29e7574.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251775&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Dancing on the ink painting is so amazing&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0e3612c6710e7439d9a4d4d839acad47.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1547&quot; height=&quot;842&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0e3612c6710e7439d9a4d4d839acad47. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The live performance is full of Chinese style&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dancers in blue dresses&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the ink painting scroll Dance on the top&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The skirt is full of ancient buildings&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/56890b6aa69140ca6f24e046e30ec363 .gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /56890b6aa69140ca6f24e046e30ec363.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the scene changes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A huge lotus leaf blooms on the water surface&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/241cc68604b11023cb4f6a0009468f8d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/241cc68604b11023cb4f6a0009468f8d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/a297502f7c0c230d4838bd0d0b0e993d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/a297502f7c0c230d4838bd0d0b0e993d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251780&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plucking lotus leaves in the fields in the south of the Yangtze River&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;Shows the picturesque scenery of Jiangnan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7acbca835fed4d95ab9578dfdf4b7714. gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 7acbca835fed4d95ab9578dfdf4b7714.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251777&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenery of lakes and mountains transforms into the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far away is Hangzhou Gongchen Bridge&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7227ba118f5e0557b0e3dc1c4d22dedb.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot; 180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/7227ba118f5e0557b0e3dc1c4d22dedb.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lantern flies up, Blessings fill the sky&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3D dual wires dance with the tide&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/cb3ee83f8277450f92d40e8e11601998.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/cb3ee83f8277450f92d40e8e11601998.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3D Dual Wire Technology is used in a large sports venue for the first time&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three-dimensional actors and actresses flying in the air with the tide Dance together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/fa31bc5b144375c18135d90f6a855a65.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/fa31bc5b144375c18135d90f6a855a65.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251781&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2ef01dad5618a2259346fe82ac0a043d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/2ef01dad5618a2259346fe82ac0a043d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251787&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the ground screen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cross tide, first line tide, turning tide, fish scale tide, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiantang tides come and go&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ff07a37f056e8d3500debd2ee749af77.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1835&quot; height=&quot;1033&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ff07a37f056e8d3500debd2ee749af77.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tide of Qiantang River recedes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spectacular &quot;tide trees&quot; grow on the beach&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a natural ink painting&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/24/b6568a95f14f1cf907245071f4915917.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b6568a95f14f1cf907245071f4915917.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251784&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ebb and flow, the cycle goes back and forth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tide &quot;irrigates&quot; Tree of the Earth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three Little Ones&quot; played &quot;Water Waves Piano&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/0b183e711d7634282dc53990d314c6c0.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/0b183e711d7634282dc53990d314c6c0.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mascots of the Hangzhou Asian Games are Chenchen, Congcong and Lianlian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tide the tide. The piano, with waves as keys&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plays the rhythm of youth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/e7c3846d9b645959e3dbd466cada5411.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/e7c3846d9b645959e3dbd466cada5411.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ 478a26620674162a53deb0e0cb1f6c9d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/478a26620674162a53deb0e0cb1f6c9d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital people light the main torch&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first lighting ceremony with the participation of &quot;digital people&quot; in the history of the Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Across time, space and national boundaries&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ce082e171957d53d52544072ace4031b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ce082e171957d53d52544072ace4031b.gif&quot; data-key= &quot;251790&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b3d7106e79df9cc18660c91508b02874.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/b3d7106e79df9cc18660c91508b02874.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251792 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Digital People&quot; composed of more than 100 million &quot;Digital Torchbearers&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Together with the last torchbearer Wang Shun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jointly use methanol Fuel&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Light up the main torch tower of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ae4694e4e310ac14ff6ec493e95f8fd3 .gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;608&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /ae4694e4e310ac14ff6ec493e95f8fd3.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251791&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the fire of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearts follow the tide, hearts are together&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearts are looking toward the future, Aida&#39;s future! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成败张炘炀：忘掉神童的人设，找回生命的意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some media released a video interview with the topic of the current situation of &quot;16-year-old PhD student&quot; prodigy Zhang Xinyang. Zhang Xinyang is 28 years old. After graduating with a doctorate, he worked as an external teacher at Ningxia Normal University. He resigned in August 2021. He is currently working on projects with friends to earn money. He said that he currently only has a few thousand yuan on his card. In the eyes of many people, this does not match his &quot;prodigy&quot; persona. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video begins with a splice of two paragraphs. The first paragraph is what he said to his parents when he was 16: &quot;It was you who wanted me to stay in Beijing the most. You should work hard for this (buying a house).&quot; The second paragraph is that he now says, &quot;I am already very satisfied in life and have no desires. If I really need anything, I can just call my dad. They still owe me a house in Beijing. It should be worth more than 10 million now, (Reporter: Are they willing to give it to you?) So what if you don’t want to, you have to be willing if you don’t want to.” Then he grinned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The intention of the splicing is somewhat obvious. Sure enough, after reading it, many people criticized Zhang Xinyang&#39;s remarks and values. As the discussion deepened, more and more people discovered that there were many secrets to the matter, and they felt more sympathy and regret for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, the reporter asked him if he was a child prodigy. He said no and seemed very humble. However, the reporter asked him what his IQ was like and how it compared with Wei Shen and Liu Jiyu. He said it was around 140, &quot;should be at the same level, slightly lower than them.&quot; He was still very confident in his intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is Zhang Xinyang a child prodigy? I think so. He showed extraordinary intellectual talent since he was a child, and then continued to skip grades. He was admitted to university at the age of 10, but his test scores could only pass two books. And his father seems to have an obsession. He wants to prove that his son is a child prodigy, and he wants his son to maintain his character as a child prodigy. He actually did not allow him to repeat the above 985 university. It seems that if he went to college a year later, the glory of the child prodigy would be dimmed. , this character cannot be saved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter asked &quot;If you had not taken the college entrance examination at such a young age, would it be possible for you to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University?&quot; He replied, &quot;It is unlikely, precisely because according to my intelligence, even in an ideal world Under the current situation, there is a high probability that it is a 985 university.&quot; This answer is very modest. If he waits a few years later to take the college entrance examination when his mind is more mature, it would be possible to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University, or it would be a good choice to go to the junior class of the University of Science and Technology of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, in this way, you can make your knowledge system more complete and solid, and you can do better in the exam. Secondly, people with high IQ can be much better than their peers in terms of knowledge. However, their understanding of world affairs and human nature and social survival skills generally cannot be learned in advance and can only be gradually improved with age. This is not only important for interpersonal relationships. Relationships are crucial to personal mental health, and they are not irrelevant to the college entrance examination. For example, you need to have this understanding to write a good college entrance examination essay. No matter how high the IQ of a 10-year-old child is, the degree of socialization is incomparable with that of other 18-year-old classmates. It is difficult to write a high-scoring essay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xinyang went to college at the age of 10, and went to Tianjin Engineer College; when he was 13, he went to Beijing University of Technology for his master&#39;s degree; and when he was 16, he went to Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics for his doctorate. The undergraduate school was very responsible and focused on cultivating him. The tutor helped him contact a German school to study for graduate school. “They may be better at cultivating geniuses than us.” Because German schools stipulate that 14-year-olds can go to school alone. “We advised him to &quot;Father (wait one year)&quot;, but it seems that in his father&#39;s opinion, waiting one year will disqualify the child prodigy, and insisted that he should go directly to graduate school after his junior year. Just imagine, if Zhang Xinyang went to Germany when he was 14 years old, his life path would be completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, he asked his parents to buy a house and studied for a doctorate at the age of 16. In 2011, his father asked him to stay in Beijing after graduation, so he asked his parents to buy a house instead. &quot;Originally, he wanted me to stay in Beijing the most. You, you should work hard for this (buying a house)&quot; caused an uproar in the public opinion. Everyone thought that a genius&#39;s ideological level was so low. Saying this reflects that Zhang Xinyang&#39;s understanding of human nature is not as good as his intelligence. Making counter-requests was actually a form of rebellion against his father&#39;s excessive control over his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the backlash, rebellion and backlash against my father’s actions have been out of control, and it took me 8 years to complete my PhD. If he had enough motivation, he might have finished reading it long ago. His resentment towards his father and his mentality of giving up and lying down made him lose the motivation to make progress. This is Zhang Xinyang&#39;s own tragedy and the tragedy of his family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Zhang Xinyang said this: &quot;Twelve years ago, I was keen on the household registration house in Beijing, but now it is completely the opposite, that is, I have no idea of ​​buying a house at all. Is it not good to have no job, no house and no mortgage? Do you think that because the name on the house book belongs to you, this house is really your home?&quot; The flat and angry mentality is clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview, he complained about his father&#39;s extreme control over him and expressed how he would raise his children in the future: &quot;I don&#39;t want children easily. Once I decide to have children, I will support them throughout my life. As long as they do not violate national laws, he will You can do whatever you want to do. If he strongly expresses what I did at that time, then I will let him take this path.&quot; This is not so much a look into the future, but an indictment of his father and his mind. A portrait of an ideal father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaohui, Zhang Xinyang’s doctoral supervisor, once said: Zhang Xinyang is indeed the best among his students, but he entered school too quickly, resulting in that his mind and psychology are not very mature. If he can determine If you are determined to learn and work hard in a certain field, you will definitely achieve great achievements in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaohui felt that Zhang Xinyang had suffered too many setbacks, and felt pity for him, and gave him a piece of advice: &quot;At this age, you can no longer hesitate and make decisions about what to do. If you don&#39;t do anything else, just do (mathematics) ) This big problem has been solved. If you run out of talents, you can go into business, and maybe you can make a career. Don’t just lie down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem is that Zhang Xinyang’s super high IQ is still there , but the enthusiasm is gone. Humans are animals of meaning. Without spirit, it is like losing their soul. I hope that Zhang Xinyang can let go of all the misfortunes of the past, find the meaning of his existence, and re-energize his strong motivation to make a difference without wasting his talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, I also hope that parents all over the world will give their children the space to grow freely and be wary of that kind of pathological control. Whether a child is a genius or a human being, every child has a purpose for coming into this world. Don’t interfere or manipulate too much. Only in this way can the child&#39;s personality and soul be protected from harm and shine with the beauty they deserve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[模特踩八仙桌拍宣传照惹争议，涉事方道歉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257499]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Shenzhen fashion is powerful &quot;The project team&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;released a set of promotional photos&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, this set of photos caused a stir&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many netizens are strongly dissatisfied&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The organizers of the project have encountered a wave of dissatisfaction&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Unexpected public opinion storm&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, a set of promotional photos released by the &quot;Shenzhen Fashion Power&quot; project team caused Netizens are hotly discussing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0a2a397842c44445b0c68ed2aabf0bf7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;661&quot; height=&quot;956&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0a2a397842c44445b0c68ed2aabf0bf7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251734 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the photo, &quot;the model stepped on the Eight Immortals Table of the Chaoshan Ancestral Hall to take a promotional photo&quot;, which aroused dissatisfaction among netizens, and the related topic once became a hot search topic on Weibo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0c87c834990b8752664db9a4bc014209.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;326&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0c87c834990b8752664db9a4bc014209.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251735 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many Chaoshan netizens said that this is an ancestral hall where Chaoshan people recall their ancestral merits and unite the people of the clan. The models scratching their heads and posing and stepping on the Eight Immortals Table is a trampling on the culture that has been passed down for thousands of years. , cannot be forgiven. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/924a193445b5da72872ba39b0979662d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;1055&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/924a193445b5da72872ba39b0979662d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251733 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;What is Chaoshan Ancestral Hall? &lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ancestral halls, also known as ancestral temples and ancestral halls, are also called family temples and ancestral halls. They are halls and places for worshiping ancestors, worshiping gods, or establishing images of meritorious sages. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ancestral halls first appeared in the Warring States Period. In the Han Dynasty, they were only tomb temples. From the Wei and Jin Dynasties to the Sui and Tang Dynasties, family ancestral halls appeared in the Song Dynasty, and after the Yuan Dynasty, ancestral halls for worshiping ancestors appeared. Ancestral halls are common throughout our country. As temples of blood worship, they have a long history and an indelible status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Deeply influenced by Chinese traditional culture, there is also an obvious clan tradition in the Chaoshan area. Throughout the ages, Chaoshan people have built a large number of ancestral halls, which is the Chaoshan people&#39;s &quot;return to the original&quot; heart. The expression of &quot;respecting ancestors and respecting ancestors&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are many ancestral halls in Chaoshan area, including private ancestral halls, ancestral halls, family temples, and ancestral halls of famous sages and officials, represented by Hanwengong ancestral hall, distributed in four villages and six miles. An ancestral hall has a history, a culture, feelings, and rich and colorful stories. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The architecture, stone carvings, Chaozhou wood carvings, porcelain inlays and other crafts of Chaoshan ancestral halls are exquisite and exquisite. The genealogy and family history carried in the ancestral halls are closely related to the Chaoshan ethnic groups. In the hearts of tens of millions of Chaoshan people around the world, Chaoshan Ancestral Hall is the most important spiritual holy place to &quot;remember nostalgia&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;What is the &quot;Eight Immortals Table&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Eight Immortals Table is also called the Square Table. When worshiping, Chaoshan people use it to place offerings and incense candles, and when doing happy events, it becomes a dining table. The Eight Immortals Table often appears in Chaoshan weddings, gardening, giving birth to boys and other happy events. The Eight Immortals table placed in the Chaoshan ancestral hall is mainly used to place sacrifices. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;The project party urgently apologized&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Faced with the strong anger caused by the promotional photos&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;CIQICHINA, the party involved, responded&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the organizer of the project issued an apology statement on the Internet, apologizing The statement mentioned: All published content has been deleted and content rectification and reflection are being carried out. I accept everyone’s criticism and solemnly apologize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/316f8cd0bb1c85f9b34f838f0f7b6f47.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1057&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/316f8cd0bb1c85f9b34f838f0f7b6f47.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251737&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3650890747aa8bdb472bfef4ca7f330f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3650890747aa8bdb472bfef4ca7f330f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/226123ce0d9f20bc1b3afa0d1d3d89a3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/226123ce0d9f20bc1b3afa0d1d3d89a3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Netizens believe that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;it is necessary to do cultural homework to promote the &quot;national trend&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Netizens have expressed their opinions on the promotional photos involved&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some netizens said that the ancestral hall is &quot;Chongzong &quot;Ancestor Worship&quot; place, and the model in the promotional photo is stepping on the &quot;Eight Immortals Table&quot;. Making such uncivilized behavior in such a place not only fails to let people understand the fashion elements, but also cannot tolerate this kind of behavior. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/9f5efd8604c93d18163e4ce50516a045.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/9f5efd8604c93d18163e4ce50516a045.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251741 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/5482651b79e8416236f4e30a50aa1a58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;198&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/5482651b79e8416236f4e30a50aa1a58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251739&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some netizens have also reflected on this matter. They believe that &quot;national trend&quot; has become a fashion trend in recent years, and literary and artistic creators have an obligation to first promote the &quot;national trend&quot; in new and innovative ways. &lt;/span>;Do your homework, respect and inherit traditional culture, so that the public can understand the creator&#39;s intention to promote &quot;national trends&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/df9a8f64b595413602375280201f4f9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;165&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/df9a8f64b595413602375280201f4f9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251742&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f1364ab10c8fe300422e5a5082855533.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1077&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f1364ab10c8fe300422e5a5082855533.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/661d176a1b3b98e29fc90ed48054b975.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/661d176a1b3b98e29fc90ed48054b975.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不健康的零食正在打败正餐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257535]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/LZfngpA9mLXPD7TQd3qljGCP8fD8aLQnmkSsrBQn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/LZfngpA9ml aLQnmkSsrBQn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this world, there are almost no people who don’t like snacks. For children, childhood without snacks is bleak, and for adults, life without snacks is incomplete. Simply put, snacks are all foods other than meals. On September 15, 2023, a study published in the &quot;European Journal of Nutrition&quot; pointed out that unhealthy snacks are counteracting the effect of healthy meals, thereby increasing the risk of obesity, stroke, cardiovascular and other diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A research team from King&#39;s College London in the UK studied the snacking habits of 854 people and came to two-quarter conclusions. A quarter of people&#39;s daily energy intake comes from snacks, but a quarter of people offset the benefits of a healthy meal with unhealthy snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the UK is a country that loves snacking, with 24% of people’s daily energy intake coming from snacks such as cereal bars, pastries and fruits. Snack eaters (95%) eat an average of 2.28 snacks per day, of which 47% eat two snacks per day and 29% eat more than two snacks per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quarter (26%) of those who took part in the study reported eating healthy meals but poor quality snacks such as biscuits, crisps and cakes. Just cancel out their healthy meals. The so-called healthy meals refer to foods recommended according to dietary guidelines, such as a balanced diet based on cereals. The daily meal should include cereals and potatoes, vegetables and fruits, livestock, poultry, fish, eggs, milk and legumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unhealthy (poor quality) snacks are highly processed and sugary snacks. The classification of snacks is now roughly divided into original product snacks, initially processed snacks and deeply processed snacks. The first two are healthy snacks and the latter are unhealthy snacks. Take the potato chips that Westerners like to eat as an example. If they are cooked potatoes or potato chips with a little salt, they are original and primarily processed snacks. If they are fried and baked with various seasonings and made into potato chips, they are deeply processed snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although highly processed snacks account for only 1/3 of the average person’s daily food intake, their impact on the body can offset healthy meals, resulting in higher body mass index (BMI) and higher visceral fat. and higher triglyceride concentrations, all of which are associated with metabolic diseases such as obesity, stroke, cardiovascular disease, and diabetes. This is a classic example of bad money beating good money when it comes to nutrition and health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Brits, popular snacks are biscuits, fruit, nuts and seeds, cheese and butter, cakes and pies, granola or cereal bars. Among them, unhealthy foods are cakes, cookies, pies, donuts, pastries, candies, ice cream and frozen dairy desserts, while nuts and seeds are among the healthier snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese people also like to eat snacks. In 2018, the &quot;Report on the Development of the Snack Industry in the Context of Consumption Upgrading&quot; released by the Ministry of Commerce of China pointed out that the total annual output value of China&#39;s snack industry has reached 2.21564 billion yuan. Although in recent years, snack manufacturers and sellers have promoted natural, whole grain, sugar-free, and additive-free snacks as popular labels for healthy snacks, unhealthy snacks are still flooding the market, including fried foods and pickled foods. , processed meat products (dried meat, floss, sausage, ham, etc.), biscuit foods (including all processed biscuits), soda and cola drinks, convenience foods (mainly instant noodles and puffed foods), canned foods, plums Candied fruit foods, frozen dessert foods (ice cream, popsicles, ice cream, etc.), barbecue foods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spice strips, a famous Chinese snack that is widely loved by people at home and abroad, is an unhealthy snack (famous diver Quan Hongchan said that she likes spicy strips the most, and some manufacturers even sent her snacks. A cart of spicy strips). This is a type of cooked food product close to gluten type. It is made from wheat flour and/or other cereal flours as raw materials, added with salt, oil and other auxiliary materials, and processed through ingredients, extrusion cooking, molding, seasoning, packaging and other processes. There are less than 10 kinds of ingredients, but more than 10 kinds of food additives, and some even 20 kinds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This snack is high in oil and salt. A pack of spicy strips has a net content of 100 grams, of which fat accounts for 25 grams. According to the recommendations of the &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents&quot;, the average daily edible oil intake per person is 25-30 grams. The oil content in a pack of spicy strips is equivalent to people&#39;s daily fat intake. At the same time, a pack of spicy strips contains 7.3 grams of salt. Also according to the guidelines, the daily salt intake of healthy adults should not exceed 6 grams, children aged 2-3 should not exceed 2 grams, and children aged 4-6 should not exceed 3 grams. Children aged 7-10 years old should not exceed 4 grams. Elderly people over 65 years old should not exceed 5 grams. The salt content in a pack of spicy strips exceeds the recommended salt intake for adults and far exceeds the recommended amount for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For children, it is this kind of unhealthy snacks that develops their later eating habits and tastes, lays the foundation for year-round intake of unhealthy diets, and also contributes to cardiovascular disease, kidney disease, obesity, and diabetes. Hidden dangers have been laid. Of course, unhealthy snacks also rely on their addictive properties to attract people and affect their health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another recently published study shows that highly processed foods, whether snacks or meals, rewire the brain&#39;s reward circuitry and activate the brain in a manner similar to cravings for cocaine. Highly processed foods can trigger addiction related to drugs or alcohol. One mechanism is that highly processed foods cause the release of dopamine in the brain (similar to amphetamine) and can lead to withdrawal symptoms (at least in children and teenagers), two hallmarks of addiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Highly processed foods contain large amounts of sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors or preservatives, and contain other ingredients such as hydrogenated fats, fillers and starches to maximize flavor (called optimal taste point), thereby attracting people to continue eating. Moreover, hydrogenated fat or non-dairy creamer (creamer) tastes better than natural milk. Many people like to add it to their coffee. This delicious agent is also widely used in processed beverages and makes people addicted. This kind of fat is more harmful and difficult for the human body to decompose, and will aggravate the development of vascular diseases such as arteriosclerosis. Processed fructose, which is sweet and delicious, is also commonly used in beverages such as hydrogenated fat or non-dairy creamer, which can increase the occurrence of metabolic diseases and lead to addiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course you have to eat snacks. The easiest way is to replace unhealthy snacks such as biscuits, potato chips and cakes with healthy snacks such as fruits and nuts. There are many healthy snack options, including fresh, natural foods. Vegetables such as cucumbers, tomatoes, cherry tomatoes, etc.; fruits such as strawberries, mangos, apples, pears, etc.; milks such as pure milk, sugar-free yogurt, low-salt cheese, etc.; beans such as sugar-free soy milk, tofu pudding, edamame, etc.; Original nuts such as walnuts, almonds, cashews, hazelnuts, pine nuts, dried fruits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not impossible to eat biscuits and pastries, but you should choose those made with low sugar, salt and grains. The time when you eat snacks is also crucial to your health. If you eat snacks after 9 pm, your blood indicators will be worse and it will have a greater negative impact on your health. Therefore, you should not eat or eat less snacks after 9 pm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叙利亚总统19年后再访华：加深两国政治互信，寻求经济合作]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257517]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 21, there was a gentle breeze in Hangzhou. As the plane landed at Hangzhou Xiaoshan International Airport, Syrian President Bashar Assad&#39;s visit to China officially began. This is Assad’s first visit to China in 19 years since 2004. During this trip, Bashar will also attend the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria are both countries with ancient civilizations. From their connection through the “Silk Road” to the connection between the “Belt and Road” initiative and Syria’s “Look East” strategy, economic and cultural exchanges between China and Syria have continued to deepen. In fact, friendly relations will become stronger over time. What is the deep meaning behind Assad’s visit to China? How can China-Syria relations be further developed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Sun Degang, director of the Center for Middle East Studies at Fudan University, and Wang Jin, associate professor at the Institute of Middle East Studies at Northwest University, pointed out to Nandu and N video reporters that Bashar’s visit to China not only hopes that China will continue to work on the reconstruction process of Syria There are also economic considerations in playing an active role. Wang Jin also emphasized that future exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria and an important guarantee for the development of bilateral relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“This visit to China will help deepen political mutual trust between the two countries”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Syrian National News Agency, Bashar led a high-level delegation in On September 21, he set off for a visit to China and participated in relevant activities in Beijing and Hangzhou. Nandu reporters noticed that Bashar’s last visit to China was in 2004, which was also the first visit to China by a Syrian head of state since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Syria in 1956. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c2fb9eec2add497b898cc7fa7ac85d2d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c2fb9eec2add497b898cc7fa7ac85d2d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251764&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. Xinhua News Agency/AP&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria have a profound friendship. Syria was one of the first Arab countries to establish diplomatic relations with the People&#39;s Republic of China and one of the sponsors of the restoration of China&#39;s lawful seat in the United Nations. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations 67 years ago, China-Syria relations have maintained healthy and stable development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The diplomacy of the heads of state plays a leading role in the development of China-Syria relations.” Sun Degang believes that China and Syria have the same views on safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and also have a common understanding of the multi-polar pattern. Diplomacy has played an overt role in deepening practical cooperation between the two sides in many fields.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this visit to China, Bashar had already visited Iran last year, and this year visited Oman, Russia, the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia and China are the sixth stop of his visit since the civil war broke out in 2011. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 19 years, Assad visits China again. What is the deep meaning behind it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the world is undergoing major changes unprecedented in a century, and global peace and development are facing increasing uncertainties and unstable factors. Against the background of the &quot;reconciliation wave&quot; emerging in the Middle East, Sun Degang believes that the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China will help deepen political mutual trust between the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Bashar’s visit to China is first of all hoping to receive political support from China, including continuing to support Syria in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and continuing to play an active and constructive role in Syria’s reconstruction process. , to properly promote the reconstruction process in Syria.&quot; Wang Jin analyzed to the Nandu reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, the Syrian civil war broke out. Iran firmly supported the Bashar al-Assad government. The League of Arab States (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Arab League&quot;) suspended Syria&#39;s membership. Saudi Arabia and many other Arab countries closed their offices in Syria. embassy, ​​Syrian diplomacy has entered a state of relative isolation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0fdbc92fb640cd041da104ad87aabb0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0fdbc92fb640cd041da104ad87aabb0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251765&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The war-torn town of Deir ez-Zor in eastern Syria, taken on September 10, 2013. Xinhua News Agency/AFP&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this situation, China has always maintained relations with Syria and defended fairness and justice in global human rights governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“China and Syria have a very solid foundation of political mutual trust.” This year marks the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. Sun Degang told Nandu reporters that Syria has always supported China’s “Belt and Road” initiative and the global development initiatives and global security initiatives, and firmly supports China on the South China Sea, Xinjiang-related issues and other issues; China also firmly supports Syria in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, has upheld justice on many occasions in relevant votes of the United Nations Security Council, and defended Syria&#39;s national sovereignty and territorial integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nandu reporter learned that as a permanent member of the Security Council, most of the vetoes used by China in relevant votes of the Security Council are related to the Syrian issue. China has always spoken out fairly and acted in accordance with the merits and in safeguarding the interests of the Syrian people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The &#39;reconciliation tide&#39; in the Middle East has brought peace dividends to Syria&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On March 10 this year, Saudi Arabia and Iran reached the &quot;Beijing Agreement&quot;. The three parties signed and issued a joint statement announcing that Saudi Arabia and Iran agreed to resume diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China is a sincere friend of Arab countries, and Chinese wisdom is constantly recognized by Arab countries. On April 29, when meeting with Zhai Jun, the Chinese government’s special envoy for the Middle East, Assad congratulated China on successfully mediating the resumption of diplomatic relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, and believed that reconciliation between Saudi Arabia and Iran would have an important and positive impact on the international pattern and regional situation. Syria thanks China for its active work in promoting Syria to improve relations with other Arab countries, and welcomes China to play a greater role in maintaining regional peace and stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Syrian civil war, Saudi Arabia announced its severing of diplomatic relations with Syria in 2012 due to its opposition to the Assad government. Two months after Saudi Arabia resumed diplomatic relations with Iran this year, Saudi Arabia and Syria also announced on May 9 that the two countries had resumed diplomatic relations. Sun Degang told Nandu reporters that China has promoted the normalization of relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, driving a &quot;tide of reconciliation&quot; in the Middle East and bringing peace dividends to Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“With the resumption of diplomatic relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, Syria’s relations with Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Egypt, Turkey and other countries have further improved, and Syria’s external living space has been greatly improved. This will also help to enhance China-Syria relations, Deepen bilateral cooperation,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 10, Bashar was invited to attend the Arab League Summit Council meeting in Saudi Arabia. On May 22, Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said that China congratulated President Bashar on attending the Arab League Summit Council meeting and on the reunion of the Arab family. Syria&#39;s return to the Arab League fully demonstrates that Arab countries&#39; strengthening of unity and cooperation through dialogue and consultation is the aspiration of the people and the general trend. It also fully demonstrates that Arab countries have the ability to take their future and destiny into their own hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin believes that China’s global security initiative has effectively promoted world peace and development. “We hope to form a new security concept around the world that does not sacrifice mutual security. Rather, they are concerned about each other&#39;s security and form a bond of common interests in cooperation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;China and Syria have economic cooperation advantages&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2011 After the turmoil in Syria, the economic and trade cooperation between China and Syria was affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the bilateral trade volume between China and Syria will be US$427 million, a year-on-year decrease of 11.65%. Among them, China’s imports were US$20 million, a year-on-year increase of 124%; China’s exports were US$425 million, a year-on-year decrease of 11.93%. China mainly exports mechanical and electrical products, light industrial products, etc. to Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin admitted to Nandu reporters that due to the long-term sanctions imposed by Western countries, there are certain difficulties in cooperation between Syria and China, and it is necessary to understand rationally and steadily promote economic and trade cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his observation, the prospects for China-Syria economic and trade cooperation are very broad. &quot;Syria is rich in natural resources such as oil and has a superior geographical location. It is adjacent to the Mediterranean Sea and is an important bridge connecting Europe and Asia. Therefore, China and Syria have very great economic cooperation advantages.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noted that previous meetings There is no shortage of products from Syria at the CIIE. Damask rose is one of the oldest rose species in the world, and the essential oil extracted from it is called &quot;liquid gold&quot; by locals. At the CIIE booths, in addition to the fragrance of rose essential oil, there are also Syrian products such as olive oil and castile soap. Many Syrian companies feel the potential of the Chinese market at the CIIE. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-Syria relations have a long history. Aleppo and Palmyra in Syria were important cities on the ancient Silk Road. On January 12, 2022 local time, China and Syria formally signed the &quot;Memorandum of Understanding on Jointly Promoting the Construction of the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;, and Syria officially joined the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Syrian political analyst and author Kosay Abido believes that the cooperation agreement between the two countries can be expanded to areas such as food, pharmaceuticals and technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the new historical conditions, China’s “One Belt, One Road” initiative is aligned with Syria’s “Look East” strategy. China’s participation in Syria’s economic reconstruction has become deeper and more substantial, and China-Syria relations have reached a new level. steps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Currently, the Syrian government forces have controlled most of the land, and post-war reconstruction is on the agenda. I think the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China will focus on cooperation with China in practical fields.&quot; Sun Degang analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noticed that the Syrian Minister of Economy and Foreign Trade was also among the Syrian delegation visiting China. In this regard, Sun Degang believes that this reflects Syria&#39;s hope that China will leverage its infrastructure advantages in the reconstruction process of Syria, including transportation, electricity and other infrastructure construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the economically powerful Gulf Arab countries are willing to provide financial support to Syria, and China leverages its infrastructure advantages, relevant cooperation can steadily promote Syria&#39;s economic and social reconstruction.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Syria had already shown its willingness to seek economic cooperation with China before visiting China. According to reports from the Syrian Arab News Agency and the Russian Satellite News Agency, on April 29 this year, when Bashar met with Zhai Jun, he specifically mentioned that it was becoming increasingly necessary to abandon the use of the U.S. dollar and that trade between countries could be settled in RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin analyzed to reporters from Nandu that Syria’s visit to China also has economic considerations. &quot;Syria also hopes that China will provide more economic support and assistance, especially welcoming more Chinese investors to invest in Syria and participate in Syria&#39;s socio-economic reconstruction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 6 this year, southern Turkey approached Two strong earthquakes occurred in the Syrian border area within 12 hours, and China actively provided assistance. &quot;China will also be an important force in improving people&#39;s livelihood in Syria in the future.&quot; Sun Degang believes that the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China, in addition to deepening political mutual trust and strengthening economic and trade exchanges, will also help China and Syria strengthen cooperation in health, education, sports and other fields. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson Hua Chunying said on 9 It was announced on March 21 that Syrian President Bashar al-Assad will attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Asian Games is a sports event for Asian youth and an important platform for cultural exchanges. &quot;This is a very important moment.&quot; Wang Jin believes that Assad&#39;s attendance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games will bring important opportunities for people-to-people diplomacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Leaders gather at this international cultural and sports event to share each other’s views, and head-of-state diplomacy also adds luster to this international event.” He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sports represents youth, health, and vitality, and is related to people&#39;s happiness and the future of the nation. It is reported that the Syrian team will participate in six competitions including wrestling, boxing, and weightlifting at this Asian Games. Athletes from China and Syria gathered together to add color to the diversity of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Syrian president&#39;s coming to China to attend the opening ceremony of the Asian Games has sent a signal - he hopes that China and Syria can strengthen cooperation in the humanities field.&quot; Sun Degang told the Nandu reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria are both ancient civilizations. The exchanges between the two countries were connected by the &quot;Silk Road&quot; and continue to this day. The &quot;Silk Road&quot;, called the &quot;Road of Semiramis&quot; by the ancient Assyrians, started in China and passed through the land of Syria to Europe and the Maghreb region. The Syrian Minister of Culture once said that this road has enabled the Syrian people and the Chinese people to get to know each other and established a bridge for cultural exchanges. Customs, beliefs, and lifestyles have also influenced each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, ancient Chinese silk fabrics and ancient porcelain are collected in museums in Syria. The &quot;Stele of Popular Chinese Nestorianism in the Qin Dynasty&quot; collected by the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum in China has ancient Syrian inscriptions... each piece is precious. Cultural relics bear witness to the long history of cultural exchanges and mutual learning between the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/cf852266838b78b9744c286623c27e8d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/cf852266838b78b9744c286623c27e8d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251766&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Recently, the &quot;Syrian Ancient Cultural Relics Exhibition&quot; was displayed at the Guangdong Provincial Museum. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 20 this year, the &quot;Syrian Ancient Cultural Relics Exhibition&quot; co-organized by the Guangdong Provincial Museum and the China Cultural Relics Exchange Center was displayed at the Guangdong Provincial Museum. The exhibition brings together 210 pieces/sets of exquisite cultural relics from 9 Syrian museums including the National Museum in Damascus and the Aleppo Museum, as well as 4 Chinese museums including the Dunhuang Academy, the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Museum, the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum and the Guangdong Provincial Museum. It paints a picture of the magnificent civilization and history of ancient Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin told reporters from Nandu that China and Syria are both countries with ancient civilizations, and exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations are of great significance to China and Syria. &quot;Both countries advocate dialogue among civilizations. In recent years, China has proposed the principle of exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, which has been welcomed and supported by Syria and recognized by the Syrian government and people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-Syria relations have been affected by the rise of Eastern civilization. The common attributes are closely linked, and the two countries have great potential for cultural cooperation. Syria actively appreciates China&#39;s global civilization initiative, which promotes mutual respect among different civilizations and breaks down the &quot;clash of civilizations theory&quot;, &quot;civilization superiority theory&quot; and &quot;Western civilization-centered theory&quot;. In Sun Degang’s view, China-Syria cultural exchanges are a vivid reflection of China’s global civilization initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the future, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria, and an important guarantee for the development of relations between the two countries. They will add luster to exchanges and mutual learning among world civilizations,&quot; Wang Jin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[羊奶、牦牛奶、骆驼奶……小众奶有号称的那么神奇吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257529]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission selected 32 liquid milks with high sales for evaluation, including I don’t know if the results of some niche milk products may surprise you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, with the development of the economy and the diversification of consumer demand, there are more and more milk varieties on the market. In addition to cow&#39;s milk, there are also goat milk, and the uncommon buffalo milk, &quot;Niche milk&quot; such as yak milk and camel milk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, these &quot;niche milks&quot; are claimed to have miraculous properties. For example, camel milk is said to be rich in high-quality protein, vitamins, calcium, iron, amino acids, taurine and folic acid. Regular consumption of camel milk can enhance human immunity and delay aging. The drinks of centenarians in Xinjiang are indispensable for camel milk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is yak milk. Because yaks are distributed in high-altitude areas in Tibet, Sichuan, and Qinghai and are resistant to cold, low temperatures, and hypoxia, the dairy products they produce are known as &quot;natural concentrated milk.&quot; It is said that yak milk is rich in nutrients, such as lactoferrin, A2 protein, conjugated linoleic acid, etc. In short, it is higher than other cow&#39;s milk. It is said that &quot;drinking one cup of yak milk is worth drinking several cups of ordinary milk.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under these publicity, &quot;niche milk&quot; has gradually become a new consumer favorite in the dairy market. On an e-commerce platform, the transaction volume of imported plant milk increased by 176% year-on-year in 2019, and the imported goat milk powder increased by more than 50% year-on-year. The market size of yak milk products has increased from 400 million yuan in 2014 to about 1.45 billion yuan in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, are these niche milks so magical? This evaluation by the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission answers this question to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nutrition refers to the biotin that can be obtained from food and is necessary for the body. When people eat, food enters the body, is digested by the gastrointestinal tract, and absorbs the nutrients in it, supplying energy to the body, forming and renewing body tissues. Nutrition is divided into seven major nutrients: carbohydrates, proteins, fats, vitamins, minerals, water, and dietary fiber. In 1973, an expert committee organized by the WHO confirmed a total of 42 essential nutrients for the human body. Any one of these 42 species cannot be deficient, otherwise related nutritional deficiency diseases will occur. Therefore, whether something is nutritious can be quantified. For dairy products, the main function of drinking milk is to supplement protein and calcium, which are indicators that dairy products must be labeled. Then, the nutritional content of dairy products can be quantified through experiments and quantitative comparisons can be made. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This experiment by the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission compared 32 niche milks, including 6 buffalo milk, 7 yak milk, 6 camel milk, 6 goat milk and 7 cow milk ( Milk is mostly mid- to high-end products), with prices ranging from 1.5 yuan/100mL to 25.4 yuan/100mL. The results show that the protein content of 32 samples is 3.0g/100mL-4.3g/100mL. Among them, buffalo milk and cow&#39;s milk ranked first and second in protein content, with average values ​​of 4.2g/100mL and 4.0g/100mL respectively. Goat milk had the lowest protein content, with an average value of 3.2g/100mL. In terms of calcium content, camel milk has the highest calcium content, with an average value of 164.0mg/100mL; followed by buffalo milk, with an average value of 152.3mg/100mL; goat milk has the lowest calcium content, with an average value of 123.3mg/100mL. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is a commodity, a very important indicator is cost performance. The average price of camel milk is relatively high, reaching 22 yuan/100ml, which is nearly eight times the price of buffalo milk, but there is no obvious advantage in nutritional value. Generally speaking, buffalo milk and cow&#39;s milk have relatively high calcium and protein contents, making them the most cost-effective products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This result may be unexpected by many people, but it is reasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the modern dairy industry, the breeds of dairy cows are slowly developed through long-term industrial production and technology; the breeding methods are also constantly developing towards improving the nutrition of milk; the cost of feeding is also Gradually reduced in the fierce market competition. This ensures that the milk we usually drink is the most cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the niche milk industry is small in scale, relatively backward in development, and naturally not cost-effective. For example, yaks have a low degree of artificial selection and are primitive cattle breeds. Their reproduction mainly relies on free mating within the group, which may lead to population degradation and reduced production performance. The daily milk production of yaks is low and the lactation period is short. The average annual milk production is mainly for feeding calves. Although there is also scientific research and improvement, the investment in a small industry is definitely not much. So, to some extent, yak milk is destined to be expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, to a certain extent, the nutrition of milk is not important, because the same protein and calcium can be obtained in lower-cost ways, such as eating eggs to obtain protein. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a traditional understanding in China that the nutrients are all in the soup. Following this idea, one would think that liquid milk is rich in nutrients. But actually, the nutrients are in the solids. Under normal circumstances, the human body needs about 50 to 60 grams of protein a day. The protein content of 100 grams of protein powder is about 75 grams. In natural food, a pound of pork contains about 100 to 120 grams of protein; a pound of chicken breast has 150 grams of protein; and each ordinary egg contains about 6 grams of protein. In other words, 5 pounds of milk is equivalent to 1 pound of pork, and 7 pounds of milk is equivalent to 1 pound of chicken breast. Milk itself may not be a cost-effective nutritional product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, for a healthy person with normal financial status, protein deficiency will not occur. This small difference in the protein content of dairy products is simply unimportant and not worth the extra money. What&#39;s more, the nutritional needs of the human body in different eras are different. In the era of poverty, people lacked protein, fat, and sugar; in the current era of abundance, protein, fat, and sugar may exceed standards. What people lack are vitamins, minerals, and fiber, and what they focus on is nutritional balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, there is nothing wrong with drinking niche milk, but don’t place unrealistic hopes on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会盛大开幕，电子烟花、数字点火仪式让人耳目一新]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257523]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the five-star red flag was displayed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games The lighting effect when entering is Chinese red.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4ef85dd71d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4ef85dd71d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 23, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games, the lighting effect when the five-star red flag entered the venue was Chinese red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At about 20 pm on September 23, 2023, the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou was held in the main gymnasium of Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, eight people including Sun Haiping and Guo Jingjing will serve as flag bearers of the Olympic Council of Asia.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/26640b53ec.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/26640b53ec.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251795&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, eight people including Sun Haiping and Guo Jingjing served as flag bearers of the Olympic Council of Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 1&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/b307bc106c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ b307bc106c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251796&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The opening ceremony was themed &quot;Tide from Asia&quot; and was divided into three major chapters: &quot;National Style and Elegance&quot;, &quot;Qiantang Tide&quot; and &quot;Hand in Hand&quot;, which symbolized In the new era, China is integrating with Asia and the world, rushing forward like a wave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 2&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/d8fc4e904c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ d8fc4e904c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​of the highlights of the opening ceremony of this Asian Games is that no physical fireworks will be set off throughout the event, and instead electronic fireworks will be set off through digital technology. At the opening ceremony, the fireworks on the central three-dimensional screen and the ground screen were dazzling. The rumbling explosions and the enthusiastic applause and shouts of the audience resounded on both sides of the Qiantang River. Previously, the opening ceremony chief director Sha Xiaolan told the media: &quot;With the setting off of physical fireworks, a large amount of smoke, dust and other pollutants will be produced in the air, which is not conducive to environmental protection. We have made great determination to cancel the physical fireworks show.&quot; The team. It was decided to convey the concept of environmental protection to the world at the opening ceremony, a moment that attracted much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the electronic fireworks set off through digital technology at the Hangzhou Asian Games are a green expression of the sense of ritual.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/24/854ec36666.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/24/854ec36666.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, the electronic fireworks set off through digital technology at the Hangzhou Asian Games were a green expression of the sense of ritual. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, on the three-dimensional net screen spanning the entire venue, the &quot;digital torchbearers&quot; carrying the enthusiasm of hundreds of millions of people slowly ran through the venue and met with the final Torch bearer Wang Shun jointly lit the main torch tower of the Hangzhou Asian Games named &quot;Tide&quot;. The glory that symbolizes lighting the Asian Games flame does not only belong to a specific person, but to the hundreds of millions of ordinary people who care about the Asian Games. This is the first digital lighting ceremony in the history of the Asian Games, leaving a wonderful and classic memory for the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the huge digital torch bearer and athlete Wang Shun lit the main torch of the Hangzhou Asian Games together.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6d8f1d2745.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/6d8f1d2745.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, the huge digital torchbearer and athlete Wang Shun lit the main torch of the Hangzhou Asian Games together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Chinese sports delegation entered the Asian Games.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/24/4fc7fd346a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /4fc7fd346a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Chinese sports delegation entered the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, basketball player Yang Liwei and swimmer Qin Haiyang served as the flag bearers of the Chinese sports delegation at the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/da141cab3b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/24/da141cab3b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, basketball player Yang Liwei and swimmer Qin Haiyang served as the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games in China Flag bearer of sports delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games is based on the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot;. In addition to the host city of Hangzhou, five co-hosting cities including Ningbo, Wenzhou, Huzhou, Shaoxing and Jinhua have also been set up. Among them, the Chinese sports delegation consists of 1,329 people and will participate in 38 major events and 407 minor events. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 3&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/d21731e4e6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/d21731e4e6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the opening ceremony of the Asian Games was performed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/c665c31fe8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ c665c31fe8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[交友软件和心理咨询流行，我们对爱和自由却更迷茫？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/XAVJTAyaS1jmJuYTnvk1hphirbXo9dezQQZw2tEJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1438&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/XAVJTAyaS1jmJuYTnvk1hphirbXo9dezQQZ w2tEJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common question asked by a sociologist who studies love and emotion is: Why is this a sociological topic? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eva Yiros has long experienced this, &quot;Love is accompanied by modernity. In this sense, it is of extremely important significance to sociology. The famous sociologist Tu Ergan discussed the relationship between bachelors and suicide, Marx and Engels wrote about the relationship between marriage and profit, love and profit, and Max Weber studied sex, even if these are not the core of their works.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leave aside society. Study’s persistence in modernity. In fact, Eva Iros&#39;s works are all about her own confusion. A few years ago, when she was still studying for a Ph.D. in the United States, it was her boyfriend&#39;s birthday. However, she was financially strapped and could not afford to invite her boyfriend to a restaurant, so she had to do it herself. &quot;But when I wanted to cook for him, I realized I needed to buy candles, cook some fancy food, and I didn&#39;t even have a tablecloth. To create a romantic dinner atmosphere, I needed to spend money, and I didn&#39;t have any money at the time .&quot; Her first book later published, &quot;The Utopia of Consumer Romance: Love and the Cultural Paradox of Capitalism,&quot; was related to this experience. In the book, she focuses on the close connection between romantic love and consumer culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/wO6qeoIC9QkxpJ1sO1z55d0m29hmfIdYK68V3NV0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/wO6qeoIC9QkxpJ1sO1z55d0m29hmfIdYK68V3NV0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an Emotional Society Scientist, Eva Yilos has always been curious about changes in emotional practices and related ideas. In the 19th century, when love entered the public sphere from the family sphere, dating culture also emerged. At that time, European and American romantic literary works focused on describing people&#39;s unremitting pursuit of romantic love - &quot;Madame Bovary&quot; depicts a woman who pursues Romantic love escapes the family several times, but in the end the woman is in debt and has no choice; &quot;Wuthering Heights&quot; writes about a pair of childhood sweethearts, Heathcliff and Catherine. Catherine decided to marry Edgar out of the consideration of being well-matched, and Heathcliff felt humiliated. He ran away in anger and returned to the manor a few years later for revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Very different from this, contemporary love is often filled with more rational calculations. Eva Iros believes that the development of Internet technology has destroyed people’s pursuit of romantic love. “We no longer rely on bounty hunters or good luck harvested on Ferris wheels to find love, as we did before, but through cost-benefit analysis. Looking for a match.&quot; Today&#39;s popular dating software is probably the best example, as she wrote in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chinese translation in 2023 Published in April), &quot;Most of the magic of love is related to the scarcity of the partner&#39;s resources. As the saying goes, scarcity is the most valuable thing. This scarcity will in turn bring surprise and excitement. Compared with Under the circumstances, what dominates the current Internet is a surplus economic system and too many options, which forces the self to make choices and make optimal choices. Internet technology happens to integrate two ways of finding oneself: psychology and consumerism—fueling the need for people to find the best (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;financially and psychologically&lt;/span>;) deal for themselves.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SyjPK1W4qQR6A6dtbCgz5qYOb9FGYSkoWlffmOpX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1596&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SyjPK1W4qQR6A6dtbCgz5qYOb9FGYSkoWlffmOpX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our The interview started from the phenomenon of psychological counseling craze, and talked about the impact of the popularity of dating software on intimate relationships, as well as her role in &quot;The End of Love&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Chinese translation published in September 2023&lt;/span>;) refers to the &quot;negative structure of contemporary relationships&quot;, that is, &quot;whether freedom undermines the formation of meaningful romantic bonds.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She does not intend to point out that modern love is always unhappy. On the contrary, she summarizes the manifestations of fulfilling the promise of modern love and intimacy - &quot;equality, freedom, the pursuit of sexual satisfaction, gender-neutral care and autonomy&quot; Sex,&quot; arguing that as long as people fulfill the above promise &quot;in heterosexual or homosexual intimate relationships,&quot; their intimate relationships must be happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s just that,” said Eva Iros, “what is more urgent for a scholar to pay attention to is unhappiness.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/lshhUuojPVwn97OODu7Ev8YHkfdFWAF2oEgkq28q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/20/lshhUuojPVwn97OODu7Ev8YHkfdFWAF2oEgkq28q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Eva· Yilos sociologist, professor of sociology and anthropology at the Hebrew University of Israel. He has taught at Northwestern University, Princeton University in the United States, and Ecole Supérieure des Sciences Sociales in Paris, France. He has won the EMET Award, Israel&#39;s highest scientific achievement award. He was hailed as &quot;one of the 12 most influential thinkers in the world&quot; by Germany&#39;s Die Zeit. He is the author of &quot;Utopia of Consumer Romance&quot;, &quot;Why Does Love Hurt&quot;, &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot;, &quot;The End of Love&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Psychology is a practice of coping with uncertainty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, psychological counseling has become very popular among the younger generation in China, and many people have entered the psychological counseling room. The opportunity is often a breakup or setbacks at work or school. They expect to gain a better self through psychotherapy. But this often points to individuals blaming themselves - if the goal is not achieved, then I didn&#39;t work hard enough. You also mentioned in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot;, &quot;If a woman keeps falling in love with those unpredictable or loveless men, then she can only blame herself. If she does not blame herself, she must at least learn to change herself. &quot;Why do everyone believe in this logic? What does this have to do with neoliberalism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You asked a very good question. Why do some narratives have more adherents than others? Why are some narratives so powerful that it is difficult for us to think beyond them or explain what is happening to us? Let me try to give a few different explanations: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, psychologists and psychoanalysts have long known about organizing themselves into experts through degrees, certifications, and university courses. Through their organizational capabilities, they quickly gained legitimacy as a discipline that sought to heal, improve, and overcome disorders and deficits, perfectly suited to the core missions of modern institutions: to promote progress, promote moral reform, alleviate suffering, Increase happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, modern institutions are fundamentally utilitarian, and psychology applies this utilitarian philosophy to the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third reason lies in the profound changes in society. All social relations tend to be democratized, which sociologists call social roles (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Reporter&#39;s Note: In sociological theory, &quot;social role&quot; stipulates a specific scope of a person&#39;s activities and the rights, obligations, and behavioral norms that are commensurate with the person&#39;s status. It is society&#39;s behavioral expectations for a person in a specific position&lt; /span>;) no longer plays a fundamental role. That is, people are fathers and husbands, mothers and wives, girlfriends and friends, but they don&#39;t know how to play their roles in them, and all of these roles come with people&#39;s personalities and true selves. This means we no longer have guidelines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The demand for psychology comes not only from the disappearance of social roles, but also from the disappearance of clear guidelines and authority. Individuals should know from within who they are and what they should do. But the problem is, they often don&#39;t know what to do. Psychology is a practice of dealing with uncertainties: Who am I? what should I do? Should I prioritize happiness or responsibility? In a world pre-ordained by society and the divine universe, the answers to these questions are obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5RXnjGIsyIRQfkM8GJTfAJCw9jZOMTpqad9p4akl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;961&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5RXnjGIsyIRQfkM8GJTfAJCw9jZOMTpqad9p4akl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;Love in the Evening&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The demise of traditional romantic love&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​of the changes in modern love is the popularity of dating software, such as Tinder and Hinge , similar software is also very popular in China. People who use dating apps to date often complain about how instrumental it is—you have to introduce yourself and ask the same questions every time you meet someone new. You also mentioned in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot; that some interviewees expressed a certain boredom and cynicism. Do you think this cynicism marks a radical departure from traditional romantic culture in modern online love? Could you please explain it in detail? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2016, dating app Hinge found that 1 in 500 swipes on the app exchanged phone numbers . That same year, the company further surveyed 300 of its users, revealing that 81% had never found a long-term relationship on any swipe-based dating app ( ;&quot;>;Data comes from &quot;The Atlantic Monthly&quot;&lt;/span>;). However, Internet dating sites have always been extremely profitable because of their ability to commodify the hope of meeting someone, and that hope keeps people willing to continue using them despite feelings of disillusionment. I think this oscillation between disappointment and resilience is at the heart of people&#39;s use of online dating. Yes, I think it does represent some departure from the traditional model of love, but it also wants to preserve the traditional model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, traditional romantic love occurs in a small social network. Many times, people know each other, either through their parents or reputation, and belong to the same circle. In comparison, the social relationships of online encounters are more diffuse. Another change is that people’s choices have become incredibly wide. This is completely new and changes the ecology of human relationships. Generally speaking, we develop emotional attachments to others based on what we think is possible. If you live in a village you can only choose from this range. But if the choices expand, you think you have a better choice and quickly move on to the next person. Breaking up is also much less expensive because you think you can find someone who is your equal or better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this departure just influenced by the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Technology cannot operate in a cultural vacuum. Without sexual liberation, people wouldn&#39;t have a variety of partners, and this departure wouldn&#39;t happen. Dating software has achieved and completed sexual liberation, changing the way people used taboos and morals to define sexual behavior in the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Imagination has always been a part of romantic love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;People who use social software to make friends have a more detailed definition of relationships and have developed many terms, such as hookups and FWB (friends with benefit), which refer to relationships that are both friendships and include sexual relations. They There are no commitments and constraints, and there is no emotional attachment), situationship (referring to the relationship between two people being closer than friends, but not to the level of lovers), etc. Why are modern people’s relationships more fragile and uncertain than in the past? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Simply put, it’s because we have the freedom to do what we want with our relationships and ourselves. Individuals are no longer defined by social roles and rules; they must create them themselves, which also creates chaos and uncertainty. Chaos and uncertainty are considered psychological categories, but I think they should also be sociological categories, because many situations in chaos and uncertainty are defined by individuals, and the rules of behavior of individuals are different from those of traditional society. The way things work is often very different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The traditional imagination of romantic love is based on the body The attraction is also based on accumulated experience in the past; and the Internet separates imagination from people&#39;s real encounters, allowing the two to occur at different points in time. Therefore, some people often face the dilemma of &quot;turning up as quickly as possible&quot; and then give up the idea of ​​using dating apps to find love. What kind of person can establish a private romantic relationship on the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I’m not sure we can determine who can establish relationships in the network. Are you talking about being in a relationship with someone you have never met and will never meet? Or is it a relationship that begins online and continues offline? Imagination has always been a part of romantic love, and you will attribute many fictional virtues to the one you love. Sometimes people fall in love with someone they&#39;ve never spoken to. Laura and Petrarch are one of the most famous lovers in the history of the Western Renaissance, but in fact they almost never communicated. Petrarch loved Laura as one would love the Virgin Mary, or, in other words, he loved Laura as a teenager falls in love with a pop singer. The difference with the Internet is this - you already know a lot about this person, except for the most important thing: how their physical presence affects you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Love, freedom, commitment phobia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Another dilemma of dating software is the difficulty in establishing a relationship between both parties. In &quot;Love, Why Does It Hurt?&quot; &quot;Although commitment phobia seems to apply to both men and women, no matter from a time perspective or a cultural perspective, commitment phobia is unique to men. In comparison, women are more willing to enter into relationships.&quot; committed relationship.&quot; What makes this difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Men cultivate power and control, which means they cannot allow themselves to be vulnerable. Women, on the other hand, are responsible for almost all of the caregiving work in society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the above context, those who advocate sexual freedom Is the dating market exacerbating gender inequality? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It goes in contradictory directions. Encounters between opposite sexes became more sexualized, that is, sex was the goal and people&#39;s worth was largely determined based on their sexual attraction. A very attractive woman will have more power in the sexual realm than many men. But overall, the sexual realm is still dominated by powerful men who have control over young, attractive women. Trump and Melania are a classic example of what scholar Paola Tabet calls a heterosexual bargain: women STKaiti;&quot;>;preferably beautiful&lt;/span>;) provides sex, and the man gives her power (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;in the form of money or social connections&lt; /span>;). Traditionally, in the realm of sex, men have power and women have sex, and they trade. In a sexually free marketplace, the situation becomes even more complicated when there are no taboos or prohibitions on people accessing sex. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Modern love advocates love, marriage, and sex Freedom, which emphasizes that people have the freedom to enter into relationships, actually means that people have the freedom to leave relationships. You call it the negative structure of contemporary relationships. Although freedom is often given a positive connotation, this is not necessarily the case in intimate relationships. How do you view the relationship between love and freedom? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The history of freedom is complex. When we talk about freedom, it is mostly seen in terms of political and economic aspects, such as natural human rights. Capitalist markets provide a lot of freedom for the circulation of goods and contracts between workers and capitalists. But there is also a history of emotional freedom that perhaps predates both previous histories: that of the individual&#39;s claim to autonomy from fatherhood, monarchy, and community, in which love plays an important role. Tristan and Isolde or Romeo and Juliet survive in our classics precisely because they illustrate the process by which individuals gain freedom from community. In the West, love and freedom are synonymous, an affirmation of individual autonomy. But this freedom has become what I call the “negative structure of contemporary relationships,” which is the freedom for people to say no and refuse to enter a relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Having studied the sociology of emotions for many years, do you think intimacy Is the only direction for relationships to become more negative and alienated? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think we have higher demands on intimacy now: respect; expression of our true selves; education us; pique our interest. This far exceeds what we expected from it in the past. We get more intimacy from our relationships than we did in the past, but we’re also more attentive to our own emotions and whether we’re being respected—which can make relationships more fluid and easier to ignite ( explosive). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to Chen Meiyi and Huang Qiuye for their help with this article. Reference sources: France Culture, GUERNICA.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国代表团夺得杭州亚运会首枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257521]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 09:15:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/de131f0c0533d7f014cf4bd26920a3b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1974&quot; height=&quot;1125&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/de131f0c0533d7f014cf4bd26920a3b 9. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251793&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 24, the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, women&#39;s rowing In the lightweight double sculls final, the Chinese pair Zou Jiaqi/Qiu Xiuping won the gold medal. This was the first gold medal produced in this Asian Games and the first gold medal won by the Chinese delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>