<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[吸食除尘罐的女孩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The girls hallucinate after smoking dust cans. (Nongjian/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1152 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Girls hallucinate after smoking dust cans. (Nong Jian/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The night Chen Minru was burned by the fire, she had a hallucination: a disheveled monster slowly approached with a rolling electric saw. A pair of red eyes stared at Chen Minru&#39;s best friend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I quickly protected my bestie, which scared me to tears.&quot; When I woke up in the middle of the night, nothing happened. Chen Minru looked around and saw that most of the people in the room were already asleep. Eight young people under the age of 20 were crammed into three beds, seven women and one man, four of whom were underage. The high-pressure gas dust canisters they had just smoked were scattered all over the floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;High-pressure gas dust removal tank, a liquid spray device used to clean computer keyboards, cameras or dead corners of dust in car interiors. The main component is HFC cleaning gas, which is sprayed In an instant, the liquid will turn into a strong airflow. Its slogan reads: The airflow is strong enough to easily blow a 132-gram mouse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of June 17, 2023, eight people, including Chen Minru, smoked dust canisters in Room 501 of Rulan Hotel in Shangluo City, Shaanxi Province. &quot;Sucking that thing can cause hallucinations.&quot; 17-year-old Chen Minru told Southern Weekend reporters that the gas emitted from the dust removal canister smells astringent and is not easy to inhale. &quot;When I started smoking that day, my face still hurt a little, and then I started hallucinating. I woke up and wanted to smoke.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Minru didn&#39;t pay attention to the bottle of the dust collector. Instructions: Do not expose to environments above 40 degrees Celsius, and do not throw into fire. The product description also states: Keep away from heat sources to prevent the can from exploding. That day, there were forty or fifty bottles of dust removal cans in the room, some of which had not been finished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At about 3 o&#39;clock in the morning on the 18th, Chen Minru pressed the lighter, and 19-year-old Guo Zhen was sleeping soundly in the next bed. The fate of the two girls was completely reversed. , the two families behind them fell into the abyss together. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I forgot how many cans I smoked”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the light on the ceiling exploded with a bang. Chen Minru&#39;s face was closest to the lighter and caught fire first, rolling around on the ground crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several girls woke up one after another, with sparks lighting up on their bodies, and they ran around the room anxiously. The door couldn&#39;t be opened, so they ran into the bathroom and turned on the shower. &quot;But the water was hot, scalding, so we ran out again,&quot; Chen Minru recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen is still asleep, and her reaction is much slower. Afterwards, she recalled that when she was picked up by a good friend, she was still in a daze and lost her mind when she saw the fire in front of her. The curtains and quilts against the wall were full of fire, and they burned more and more intensely. It wasn&#39;t until about 10 minutes later, when Guo Zhen opened the door that was locked from the inside, that he noticed that his hands had turned out and his knuckles were clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This scene was photographed by residents in the building opposite the hotel. A video taken that night showed a raging fire coming out of the window of Room 501, and the crackling sounds were mixed with the girls&#39; calls for help. Eight people ran down the stairs from the fifth floor and stopped a patrolling police car on the road. Ambulances and fire engines arrived later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In the early morning of June 18, 2023, residents near the incident site took photos of the fire. (Photo courtesy of the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early morning of June 18, 2023, Residents near the scene took photos of the fire. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was past 6 o&#39;clock in the morning, and Chen Shuai had not yet entered the door of the emergency room of Shangluo Central Hospital. He was far away&lt;span>; I smelled the smell of burning skin, &quot;My hair was so fried that I couldn&#39;t even recognize who it was&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;Eight burnt-black children lay on stretchers, spread out in a row. Chen Shuai saw a red-haired girl and was sure it was his sister Chen Minru. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen’s mother He Weili came earlier. Guo&#39;s father recalled that at 4 a.m. on June 18, his wife received a call from the police saying that her daughter was in the hospital. She rushed in and hugged a girl and cried. Guo Zhen next to him made a trembling voice, &quot;Mom, I&#39;m here,&quot; and then fainted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The doctor diagnosed that among the eight people, Chen Minru and Guo Zhen had the most serious burns, and they were recommended to be sent to a large hospital in Xi&#39;an for treatment. Their burn wounds were distributed on the head and face, front and rear trunks and limbs, and the grades were all between II and III. The burn area of ​​Chen Minru&#39;s body surface was as high as 75%, and that of Guo Zhen was 60%-69%, both of which were extremely severe burns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The remaining 6 people suffered minor injuries. The mildest one only injured the skin of the calf, and you could go out for activities the next day. Five people suffered burns all over their limbs, and they have been healing by applying medicine at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A girl with burnt limbs concluded that there are two &quot;culprits&quot;, one is the cigarette lighter, and the other is Xu Kexin who organized everyone to smoke dust cans . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Kexin, a 15-year-old girl from rural Shangluo. People in the circle who hang out with her say that Xu Kexin&#39;s family is poor, but she has never been short of money since she came out to join the society early, and her food and clothing are of a much higher standard than those in her circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She said, she smoked &#39;Mrs. Shuang&#39; and let me try it.&quot; In early 2023, when Guo Zhen was playing with Xu Kexin in Xi&#39;an, he touched the high-pressure dust removal tank for the first time. The smell was so disgusting that I couldn&#39;t inhale it, but I finally came to accept it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also saw Xu Kexin smoking from another unnamed aluminum can. &quot;It was a very big can. She said that after smoking it, it felt much better than a dust can.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Shangluo, Shaanxi, the place where the dust collector explosion occurred. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/6743675af5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /6743675af5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shangluo, Shaanxi, where the dust tank explosion occurred. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen recalled that on the night of the incident, Xu Kexin &quot;couldn&#39;t wait any longer and really wanted to smoke&quot;, so she booked a room at the Rulan Hotel and invited her friends to come over and smoke together. I placed two orders for the dust removal canister. I bought it in stock in the same city at a high price of 80 yuan per can, and it was quickly delivered to the hotel room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It costs about ten yuan to buy a bottle online, but it costs 80 yuan to buy it from others.&quot; On the evening of October 9, Xu Kexin told me on the phone A reporter from Southern Weekend said that he bought forty or fifty dust removal cans that night. “That thing makes me want to sleep as soon as I hit it. I forgot how many cans I smoked.”&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“I can’t control it, there’s nothing I can do”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 9, a Southern Weekend reporter walked into Chen Minru&#39;s ward and was greeted by a strong smell of burn cream. She was supporting the board with her elbows and heels, lifting her bandaged legs in turn, and slowly moved laterally to the hospital bed by the window, so that she could be closer to the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the 4th month after Chen Minru was burned. Her body has been skin grafted twice, and her face is covered with pitted scars. &lt;span>;The skin&lt;/span>; is as solid as plastic. surface, even reflective. This is completely different from the girl with lively eyes in her circle of friends and short video account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the video, Chen Minru has fair skin, big eyes, and pouty lips. She has a figure that is envied by her friends. She is 165cm tall and likes to wear short shorts and JK uniforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photos of Chen Minru before she was burned. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/93b62d9453.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/93b62d9453. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photo of Chen Minru before being burned. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen was lying on bed No. 30, two wards away from Chen Minru, with his whole body covered with gauze, except for his arms and The hand can move to a small extent, but other parts cannot move at all. Like Chen Minru, she was dressed exquisitely in short videos in the past, and there was no hint of her ordinary family background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is posted by people who live in a mixed society and do not learn well.&quot; In 2022, Chen Shuai added his sister WeChat for the first time, browsed the circle of friends, and felt She has changed a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Minru has two brothers. 23-year-old Chen Shuai is the eldest, but Chen Minru and her brothers have not seen each other several times since they were young. In 2009, when Chen Minru was 3 years old, her father was imprisoned for a crime. Her mother, Pan Yafang, was so stimulated that she became mentally ill and the family fell apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;My grandma took her two brothers to her hometown. They favored boys over girls and didn&#39;t want me.&quot; Living a wandering life with Pan Yafang made Chen Minru often hate herself. She stared at the ceiling of the ward and shed tears, &quot;Everyone in my family hates me, so I shouldn&#39;t have been born in this family.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;When Chen Minru’s grandmother heard about it, she cried and explained, “The family’s conditions are not good and we can’t afford to support her.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Chen Minru was five years old, she followed Pan Yafang by train to Xi’an to make a living. . Xi&#39;an is too big, and Pan Yafang only knows the old train station. The mother and daughter live at the foot of the city wall next to the train station, filling their stomachs with food every day at the aid station that helps homeless people. After wandering for a period of time, Pan Yafang would take her daughter back to Shangluo and stay with her sister or brother. She had no money and was reluctant to spend money. Chen Minru claimed to have learned how to steal money from relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pan Yafang always has disheveled hair, a touch of chicken blood, and three strings of colorful plastic beads on her wrists and neck. These are all magic weapons she begged from the temple to ward off evil spirits. Chen Minru said that her mother did not know how to cook and did not live at home. She often danced outside. As a result, Chen Minru was lost for more than ten days. She lost her footing and fell into a pool, almost choking to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is not a home at all, it feels like a stranger.&quot; Living in a muddle, Chen Minru became a typical rebellious girl, she described I am &quot;a bit of a mixed bag&quot;. I entered a vocational middle school through my relatives&#39; connections. I don&#39;t want to go to school and often spend the night at my friends&#39; houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Chen Shuai, who was working outside, returned to Shangluo and worked in a car factory to make money. He took the initiative to contact Chen Minru and had a serious chat. If Chen Minru was willing, he could assume the role of father. Chen Minru agreed without hesitation, &quot;My brother said that he will do his best to control me until I am 18 years old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Shuai restrained his sister&#39;s first One condition is that you don&#39;t want to hang out with people from society. Chen Minru obviously didn&#39;t listen. She would still skip classes to find friends. She also beat a fourteen-year-old or fifteen-year-old child so badly that the police called Chen Shuai after getting drunk. In Shaanxi dialect, he described his sister as a &quot;second-rate person&quot; with no brains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zenghu said that he also received many calls from the police station, all because of his daughter Guo Zhen. Either Guo Zhen asked a group of friends to beat others, or someone asked a group of friends to beat Guo Zhen. &quot;He stayed like that all day and didn&#39;t study.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If this accident had not happened, Guo Zhen and Guo Zenghu would still be strangers. They had already verbally severed the relationship between father and daughter and had no relationship for two years. connect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I can&#39;t control her. She has a boyish personality and is very wild.&quot; He Weili said that the couple had nothing to do with this daughter. Guo Zenghu was helpless. He was 57 years old and still had to worry about his daughter. &quot;If I can&#39;t control it, I won&#39;t be called to come here. I won&#39;t come back for a year and a half.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since he was 17 years old, Guo Zhen ran away from home. I worked several jobs, and finally worked as a waiter at a bar with two friends. Guo Zenghu didn&#39;t know about Guo Zhen&#39;s early smoking and drinking, but he wasn&#39;t surprised when he heard, &quot;In rural areas, people make different kinds of friends. They are like this in their circle. It&#39;s okay to just follow those kids.&quot; Good habits”&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 9, 2023, Shangluo, Shaanxi, He Weili takes care of Guo Zhen for dinner. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255334&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, in Shangluo, Shaanxi, He Weili took care of Guo Zhen for dinner. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I just don’t want to go home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That was not the case at first. Guo Zenghu missed Guo Zhen when he was a child, &quot;very well-behaved, very well-behaved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Guo Zhen was six or seven years old, he would clean the house. When Guo Zenghu and his wife came back from planting corn in the fields, their little daughter would bring them face wash. Once, when Xiao Guo Zhen was helping to boil water, he accidentally put his arm into the iron pot of boiling water and burned a large area of ​​his arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;What I value most is this daughter.&quot; The Guo family has three daughters. In the past, family conditions were not good, and the eldest dropped out of school midway through school; He was sent to a relative&#39;s home for foster care. Finally, there is the third child, Guo Zhen. Guo Zenghu is determined to raise his little daughter well without leaving any regrets. &quot;I will let her study hard. Whatever she can learn, the family will do everything possible to show it.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Zhen is also quite successful. After elementary school, he was admitted to the best private junior high school in Shangluo. Guo Zenghu moved his family from the countryside to the city. During the high school entrance examination, Guo Zhen was admitted to Shangluo Middle School, the best local school. However, within a year, he was expelled from the school for fighting. Guo Zenghu hates that iron cannot be made into steel, &quot;The two women often said that I was partial and thought that I valued Guo Zhen the most, but I didn&#39;t expect that it would end up like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I came from my hometown to study in the city and turned bad. .&quot; In Guo Zenghu&#39;s impression, the junior high school teacher notified him several times to go to school and suggested that Guo Zhen transfer to another school, stop being in the city, and just make some friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in Guo Zhen&#39;s view, this matter became a knot in her mind because she was afraid of Guo Zenghu. Since elementary school, she has not dared to let her father attend parent-teacher meetings, fearing that he would lose his temper after hearing bad comments. Whenever he couldn&#39;t solve a question, Guo Zenghu picked up the broom and chased her in front of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the junior high school teacher reported the problem, Guo Zenghu’s attitude became more severe. &quot;My dad started scolding me, and I had to stare at the book every day. I was very good at that time, but the teacher said that I was hanging out with the second-rate people in the outside world, and wouldn&#39;t let my good friends play with me, and kept targeting me. &quot;Guo Zhen said, feeling aggrieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During that time, the teacher assigned a lot of homework, and Guo Zhen gradually became more and more stressed. &quot;I am not good at studying, so they don&#39;t understand. If I don&#39;t do well in the exam, I will When it comes to me, I don’t praise myself for passing the exam, I have no motivation, and I feel like I can’t stay at home. In addition, I fell in love with someone in class, and we had a quarrel, so I cried all night.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;She began to suffer from insomnia frequently, and was frightened by nightmares in the middle of the night. She screamed nonsense, and took the initiative to show He Weili the scars on her wrists. &quot;Mom, what if I jump into the reservoir and a fish bites me?&quot; &quot;I What if I climb to the roof and survive the fall but become disabled?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Weili has never studied. She doesn’t understand this, so she takes her daughter to Xi’an. I spent eight to nine thousand yuan to see a doctor in a big hospital, but no problem was found. &quot;The doctor said that the baby is under too much pressure and the family is too strict. If the baby is given some time and space to relax, it might be better.&quot; He Weili guessed that the baby has been beaten and scolded by her father since she was a child, which made her depressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The burn scar on his arm when he was a child was covered up by Guo Zhen quietly &lt;span>;writing&lt;/span>; a pattern in a non-mainstream style. The pattern is of a scarred two-headed teddy bear. One head has an expressionless face, and the other head has empty eyes wide open, revealing a mouth of fangs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guo Zhen&#39;s tattoo on his arm scar. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/be5077424b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /be5077424b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zhen’s pattern on the arm scar. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Guo Zhen&#39;s emotional problems, Guo Zenghu also had a headache, &quot;I&#39;m stupid and the baby is a girl. I don&#39;t know what to do.&quot; Communicate.&quot; In this way, Guo Zhen was &quot;relaxed.&quot; He found that his daughter&#39;s temper was getting worse and worse. &quot;I hit her lightly, and she wanted to make the building collapse and jump off it again. In the end, she didn&#39;t even come into the house. As soon as I talked about her, she went out to live. She didn&#39;t answer the phone calls and didn&#39;t reply to messages. You think this is the last thing. What can we do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It wasn&#39;t until Guo Zhen was expelled from Shangluo Middle School when she was in her first year of high school that Guo Zenghu beat her again and proposed to sever the relationship between father and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He not only beat me, but also called my sister to come back and beat me. My sister hit me on the head with a lamp.&quot; After the beating, Guo Zhen moved out Every time He Weili asked her to go home, she would first ask if her father was at home. &quot;He only knows how to curse, and keeps hitting me, slapping me, and hitting me with a stick. Anyway, he just doesn&#39;t want to go home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​day, Guo Zenghu bumped into me on the road. When he got to Guo Zhen, whom he had lost contact with for a long time, he slapped her several times in public. For the first time, Guo Zhen had the idea of ​​fighting back, so she called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When mentioning this incident, Guo Zhen cried so hard that he couldn&#39;t breathe. &lt;span>;He&lt;/span>; Wei Li on the side was &lt;span>;very&lt;/span>; surprised. She had never seen her daughter shed a single tear after the dust canister explosion accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;A downtrodden family&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen saw Guo Zenghu, who always had a straight face, cried every day. &quot;He lay next to me and looked at me every day, and cried as he watched.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hospital began to say that the hope was not very high.&quot; Guo Zenghu recalled, When he first went to the hospital in Xi&#39;an, the doctor told him to be mentally prepared because Guo Zhen&#39;s lungs were severely burned. &lt;p>; After the skin was removed, the skin was still eroded. &quot;The more I look at it, the more hopeless it becomes. The worst-case scenario is that I want to jump off the building, but I can&#39;t hold it up anymore.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Zhen took the initiative to give up the treatment, &quot;I don&#39;t want to be treated anymore, you can go back and don&#39;t worry about me&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I really don&#39;t want to care about her, but &lt;span>;she&lt;/span>; is my woman after all, so I can&#39;t bear to leave her.&quot; Guo Zenghu really didn&#39;t Qian continued his treatment. He was just a worker working at a construction site. During chestnut harvesting season, he collected chestnuts everywhere. He had saved less than 100,000 yuan over the years, and raised more than 300,000 yuan with relatives. It was not enough to put it all in. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Shuai experienced exactly the same suffering as Guo Zenghu. After Chen Minru&#39;s accident, he borrowed money from all the relatives he knew and didn&#39;t know to collect 400,000 yuan. After staying in the hospital for 40 days in Xi&#39;an, he couldn&#39;t afford it anymore, so he had to take his sister back to Shangluo Central Hospital for continued treatment. Later, he owed more than 40,000 yuan to Shangluo Central Hospital. After being urged to pay the fee over and over again by the hospital, he stopped going to the hospital, and Chen Minru was forced to stop taking medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If she learns well, I will give her my life, but she won&#39;t obey.&quot; Chen Shuai retracted his head &lt;span>;in&lt;/span>; his collar, The voice is deep. At first, the 23-year-old boy refused to be interviewed several times. He wanted to be cruel and stay away from everything about his sister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the years, Chen Shuai&#39;s performance is actually not much better than Chen Minru&#39;s. Although it has been taken over by grandparents, it is also in a free-range state. At the age of 8, he followed the second-rate kids into the supermarket to steal snacks to satisfy his hunger. When he grew up, he spent all day in Internet cafes just to have a place to live. At the age of 13, he started working outside to make money on his own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Approaching this strange sister made his already tight life even worse. In just one year, Chen Minru first fell seriously into a ditch while riding an electric bicycle. She fainted and was admitted to the hospital several times because of her weak body. Once Chen Minru had an appendicitis attack, and the operation cost 20,000 to 30,000 yuan, which was all handled by Chen Shuai. What made him especially heartbroken was that Chen Minru was absent from class without telling him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She said she went to school. I asked the teacher, and the teacher said she didn&#39;t go. She didn&#39;t go home, she just hung out.&quot; Chen Shuai was furious, &quot;As long as you tell me that you don&#39;t want me to care about you, I will never care about you in the future.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;Chen Minru also had a firm attitude and replied, &quot;Don&#39;t worry about me.&quot; Since then, the two have lost contact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until the day before the incident, the Dragon Boat Festival was approaching. Chen Shuai had not seen Chen Minru for two months. He took the initiative to send a message saying that his family had made rice dumplings. Chen Minru also hoped that the relationship between brother and sister could be eased and promised to go back to her hometown to eat rice dumplings in two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The brother and sister met again in the hospital. Chen Shuai hated and felt sorry for this sister, &quot;At that time, I really wanted to leave her alone. This was all She did it herself&quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fire caused by the dust can completely overwhelmed Chen Shuai. He quit his job, sold his motorcycle worth 13,000 yuan, was almost penniless, and had a debt of more than 400,000 yuan. Even if he didn&#39;t go to the hospital, his mother and sister would have to rely on him for food and money. He had no intention of looking for a job anymore. He slept during the day and thought wildly at night. He felt that life was hazy. &quot;I don&#39;t know what I should do now, and I have no motivation to do anything.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Regret and nostalgia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For a moment, Guo Zenghu thought that his deviant daughter was about to get back on track, &quot;There needs to be someone.&quot; That’s it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;On the afternoon of the accident, she called the cargo puller and moved all the large and small boxes of things back.&quot; Guo Zenghu heard his daughter say that he would be in Live at home. &quot;When I saw it, she didn&#39;t live outside anymore. She seemed to have changed her mind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What Guo Zhen didn&#39;t tell Guo Zenghu was that she was kicked out by the landlord. , because Xu Kexin always takes her friends to play in rental houses. That night, after Guo Zhen went out, He Weili made several calls to ask her to go home, but Guo Zhen still didn&#39;t answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The real change of heart is in the hospital bed. Guo Zhen told her father again and again that she really knew she was wrong. But when he learned that Guo Zhen would still keep in touch with Xu Kexin, Guo Zenghu was so angry that he scolded Guo Zhen again and again for his unrepentance. &quot;She still hasn&#39;t repented of herself and is still in contact with those people. Now I just want to do my best to take good care of the baby. After she is cured, she will do whatever she likes, and I won&#39;t care about her.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But for Guo Zhen, she only has these friends. They all come from rural areas and have similar family backgrounds and preferences. &quot;I am happy to be with them. Say whatever you want to say.&quot; What, do whatever you want to do”&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;She didn&#39;t listen to me.&quot; Guo Zenghu was scared just thinking about it. The hospital said that Guo Zhen would not be able to return to normal skin after recovery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For girls, the most important thing is their face.&quot; After the accident, Chen Minru, who was originally talkative, became &lt;span>;rejected&lt;/span>; into a man of few words. She was particularly worried about the disfigurement, and kept thinking about the past scenes in her mind. She obviously had many opportunities to avoid this disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t know how to smoke that thing, and I can&#39;t light it up.&quot; Chen Minru said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If time could go back to the past, I would not come back from Jiangsu.&quot; The day before the incident, Chen Minru had just returned to Shangluo from an internship in Jiangsu. It is said to be an internship, but it is actually a summer labor dispatch job arranged by the vocational school. She was sent to a television factory by her school. She wore dustproof clothing and stood on the assembly line in the workshop for 12 hours every day, from 7:00 in the morning to 7:30 in the evening. After two months, she earned More than 5,000 yuan. To her, this was a huge sum of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although the days of working were hard, the staff dormitory was spacious and life was smooth. After thinking about it, Chen Minru also regretted why she didn&#39;t listen to her brother&#39;s words in the first place. &quot;It was too confusing at the time. I got used to that state over time.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After being transferred back to Shangluo from Xi&#39;an for hospitalization, Chen Minru heard about a similar accident that happened in Shangluo. A group of children gathered together to smoke dust cans. One of them, a 13-year-old boy, swallowed 40 pills in order to seek happiness. &quot;It is said that the hallucinations he had were particularly terrifying. They were all green, happy and painful.&quot;&lt; span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the online shopping platform, a suspected smoker looks at the dust can Product reviews. Internet screenshots&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;975 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the online shopping platform, suspected smokers commented on dust removal can products. (Internet screenshot/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the boy huddled on the ground, twitching all over, foaming at the mouth, and asked his friends to call 120. &quot;A few other people didn&#39;t dare call the police. When they finally dared to call an ambulance, the person was already dead when they arrived at the hospital.&quot; Chen Minru sighed, &quot;At least I&#39;m still alive, so I&#39;m lucky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she quickly changed her mind. Every night, every inch of skin and bones in the body aches. What made her even more uncomfortable was that her mother, who had no ability to live independently, did not know how to take care of others. She was chatty and kept talking about herself. She would also suddenly lose control of her emotions, pointing at Chen Minru and yelling at her for having no conscience, and quarreling in the ward. Continuously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I might as well just die.&quot; Chen Minru turned her head away, tears overflowed, and she shouted with all her strength, &quot;Can you see how pitiful I am, and don&#39;t do it again?&quot; You&#39;re talking about me.&quot; But after calming down, Chen Minru felt distressed again when she saw Pan Yafang eating moldy leftovers, &quot;I have hated her during these years of wandering, but it&#39;s not easy for her to drag me down so much.&quot;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of October 21st, Chen Minru posted a post on Moments. It was a video taken with her best friend. In the video, she puffed out her cheeks. , a cute pet filter is added to the tip of the nose, shaking the head and looking cute. She wrote three words: &quot;I miss you very much.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(Chen Minru, Guo Zhen, Xu Kexin and Pan Yafang are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>; Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不出奇葩政策”：搞好中国足球，“不做什么”比“要做什么”更重要丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259252]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, Song Kai, the new chairman of the Chinese Football Association, made it clear at a symposium that &quot;the Chinese Football Association will never We can no longer introduce weird policies, this is the bottom line, and the policies introduced must meet social expectations.&quot; This statement aroused widespread attention and heated discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Song Kai is facing this time when he takes office is that the aftermath of the anti-corruption storm in football is raging, and all walks of life are annoyed and critical of Chinese football. Chinese football is still at a low point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Kai’s speech that “no weird policies can be made” has won him a lot of praise. There is no other reason. In the past few years, the Chinese Football Association has launched many bizarre policies that achieve half the result with half the effort or even be counterproductive. Take the &quot;New Policy for U23 (Under 23) Players&quot; launched by the Football Association in the past few years as an example. The original intention of this policy is to allow young players to get more playing time in the league and to cultivate more outstanding domestic players. However, in the process from policy formulation to implementation, the outside world has witnessed a farce of &quot;weird and unlimited&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2017 professional league season, the Chinese Football Association’s regulations are that there must be two U23 players in the 18-man roster, and one of them must start. As a result, in order to ensure results first, each team implemented the operation of &quot;replacing young players when they come on&quot; and &quot;replacing them in stoppage time to improve data&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 season, the Football Association upgraded this policy to &quot;the number of U23 players playing must not be less than the number of foreign players playing.&quot; This policy ultimately backfired. Each team would rather not recruit foreign players than give U23 players a chance. How to arrange U23 players to appear on the court to &quot;brush data&quot; has even become an &quot;arithmetic problem&quot; for the coaches of each team. In 2023, the U23 policy has to be cancelled. Over the course of six or seven years, this policy became a typical example of &quot;mission creep,&quot; with goals and means completely out of touch and a huge waste of resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The weird thing about the U23 policy is that it goes against the fundamental laws of football and the market laws of professional leagues. If young players are capable, they can get playing time without the help of policies; young players who are incompetent will not win the starting position even if they are given time forcibly. Forcibly asking for &quot;given opportunities&quot; seems to be training young players, but in the end it hurts everyone&#39;s interests. Not only did this operation of forcibly converting effects into causes arouse ridicule from the outside world, but the process of removing seedlings to encourage growth also yielded a lot of feathers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U23 policy is just one of the many weird policies of the Chinese Football Association. Therefore, if you want the work of the Chinese Football Association to &quot;comply with social expectations&quot; and if you want to do a good job in Chinese football, what you should consider is not necessarily &quot;what the Chinese Football Association should do&quot;, but &quot;what the Chinese Football Association should not do&quot;. I&#39;m afraid this This is the lesson that the new Football Association leadership team should remember. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Song Kai&#39;s speech, &quot;no weird policies&quot; is the keynote of the argument, and he also has the vision of &quot;the youth competition system must remain stable&quot;, showing his ambition to bring order to things. In fact, by extending this line of thought, we can also think deeply about what kind of binary relationship the &quot;Chinese Football Association&quot; and &quot;Chinese Football&quot; should have in order to better meet social expectations. Or to put it more directly, can we really only rely on the Chinese Football Association to improve Chinese football? The answer is probably not so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To evaluate whether a country&#39;s football is prosperous, we cannot simply use the national team&#39;s performance as the criterion. In addition, there are many fields such as the league system, football industry, and football culture. In these areas, a national football association does not have the ability to take over everything, nor does it have the power to issue orders. It is completely unreasonable to expect that football in a country can be revitalized by administrative hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Football is a very scientific sport. Only by returning to objective laws can we truly improve football, and this requires the joint efforts of the whole society. The Chinese Football Association still should not overestimate its own capabilities, let alone artificially expand its own power, hoping that it can fundamentally improve such a huge compound concept as &quot;Chinese Football&quot; on its own. Rather than saying that the goal of the Chinese Football Association is to be a good manager of Chinese football, it is better to say that it should strive to be a good service provider, do a good job in administrative services, let private football institutions make their own decisions, and let the market judge the choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Chinese football does not lack a folk foundation. The high attendance rate of the Chinese Super League and the popularity of the &quot;Village Super League&quot; all show the potential of Chinese football culture and the possibilities of the football industry. What the Chinese Football Association should do is respect the autonomy and self-construction of the private football system, and at least not use &quot;weird policies&quot; to destroy the football soil that is still growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentine star Valdano once said, “Football does not belong to any one person. Everyone must have a sense of ownership of this wonderful sport, and football also needs everyone to have a little control over it. Otherwise, excessive concentration of power will inevitably lead to corruption. Even in the football industry, no one can surpass this law.&quot; From the separation of management and management to &quot;good service&quot;, the Chinese Football Association&#39;s statement of &quot;no weird policies&quot; is just a step forward The first step is to hand over this wonderful sport of football to everyone who loves football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259242]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与熊猫为邻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/ZYWGGcKQBM7O1YhwAkAkp75RvRfakwsD4D6GD7Xe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1259&quot; height=&quot;916&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZYWGGcKQBM7O1YhwAkAkp75R vRfakwsD4D6GD7Xe. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;An infrared camera captured a wild giant panda passing by&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t doubt my skills.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhong Junde, a legendary hunter from Pingwu County, Mianyang, Sichuan, squinted his eyes and pointed The opposite hillside. His hair was gray, and his thin body looked very flexible. When he was talking proudly, he would squint his eyes, stand up from the back of the chair, and cross his legs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There&#39;s a wild boar there,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was calm on the hillside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If you stay one more day, I will kill the wild boar for you right away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The old man is joking again. Now, if anyone is hunting in this mountain, they will definitely avoid him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the legendary hunter Zhong Junde was imprisoned for reselling panda skins, he hunted forest musk deer, tufted deer, &quot;four different species&quot;, as well as countless muntjacs and wild boars. At the peak of his career as a hunter, he and his accomplices knocked down nine takin in three days and harvested a total weight of more than three tons of meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, he is the captain of the Xinyi Village patrol team, leading a group of former hunters to patrol the mountains. They know very well what should be in the forest and what should not be there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are absolutely sure in which season to set hunting snares and in which season to fight against poaching.” He said, “Know them (them) as well as you know yourself.”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/FIC7PnPtR8FgnJQroVD5UH03ETwB22IMLxvHaCPf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/FIC7PnPtR8FgnJQroVD5UH03ETwB22IMLxvHaCPf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255304&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;Zhong Junde shows off the crossbow he used to hunt. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Hui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hunters, villages and mountains and forests&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eat on the mountain &quot;Mountain&quot;, hunting has a long history in mountainous areas, and Pingwu is no exception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hunters possess unique knowledge of nature. They master 72 kinds of spells and can divide the mountains into yin, yang, male and female according to the movement trajectory of the sun. In their eyes, the mountains are not made of soil and vegetation but are spliced ​​together by the movement trajectories of different animals. The mud rolls Falling and swaying vegetation are simply meant to reveal the movement of animals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tibetans eat tsampa, and we Han people like to eat dry rice. The same goes for animals.&quot; The old hunter understands wild animals the same way he understands humans: takin like to eat leaves on the treetops, and furry ones on the cliffs. Grass, so they have to stay in Yinshan; but muntjac and tufted deer like Yangshan. Giant pandas are a little more complicated. They move with the seasons: from May to July, they run all over the mountains looking for fresh bamboo shoots; in hot weather, they like to sit in the mountains; in winter, because they want to give birth, they look for half-baked bamboo shoots. In a place that is yin and half yang, there is water, food, and sunlight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KLZ7vbgwAk3tMr0RFpHxZuL4ZxSuEpPyk8U0yvVq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KLZ7vbgwAk3tMr0RFpHxZuL4ZxSuEpPyk8U0yvVq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255308&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The tufted deer at the Laohegou Nature Conservation Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wu Yuchen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhong Junde, who was born in 1961, thought that after he and his father shot a panda when he was 7 years old, Meaty, smelly animals are hard to swallow. Hunters at that time did not like to hunt pandas because of this, and sometimes they just encountered them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Takin are usually the most popular among hunters. When he was 14 years old, he learned that his father, who was busy reporting to the village to earn work points, had failed to kill a takin. Zhong Junde made an appointment with a friend, took a shotgun, and shot the takin where its front legs and chest were connected. The takin fell into an eternal sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hunger and poverty can lead hunters to carry takin carcasses heavier than themselves. The corpse was packed in a hollow backpack made of palm tree fiber. The smell, similar to that of goat, would stay on the body of the person carrying the meat for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, there was a sudden rush for panda skin and musk on the market. Some people once believed that musk had the effect of &quot;reviving the dead&quot; and that sleeping on panda skin could bring good luck. The men took their earthen cannons and bullets smelted from toothpaste lead and tramped through every bamboo forest and bush. Locals recalled that panda skins were once sold for a whopping price of 500,000 yuan a piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What followed was a crackdown that lasted for many years. In 1987, the Supreme People&#39;s Court issued a judicial interpretation stating that reselling and smuggling panda skins could lead to the death penalty. However, the severe crackdown has not led to a sharp decrease in poaching. Xinyi Village is the hardest hit area for panda poaching. Of the more than 160 households in the village, more than 40 heads were arrested and imprisoned, making the village a so-called &quot;widow&#39;s village.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When many old hunters reminisce about the past, they will mention their life experiences before entering the jungle day and night: getting married, having children, and having children again. Faced with a life of poverty and the pressure of raising a family, men will not give up hunting easily - the mountains are their almost only reliance. How many cents does a pound of corn cost? How many yuan does it cost to work in a provincial capital every day? But what about musk? The price per gram is directly equivalent to gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Fushou Village, not far from Xinyi Village, hunter Qiang Qinggui became famous for capturing 13 forest musk deer in a row in one winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WjRgUuinuvnQDoULJOJMmetEbPVUM0RKpqgZuzEb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WjRgUuinuvnQDoULJOJMmetEbPVUM0RKpqgZuzEb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qiang Qinggui shows off his abandoned hunting tools in Fushou Village, Pingwu County, Mianyang City. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daily life in these villages is closely linked to hunting, and most villagers know about it even if they have not participated. Peeling off a panda&#39;s skin requires an incision under the panda&#39;s armpits to keep the fur intact; most people born before 2000 had eaten antelope beef, boiled or braised, at village banquets. People who eat beef have no reputation.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a village where all boys go into the jungle to find prey, Gan Mingdong saw himself as a hunter since he was a child. He was born in Gaocun, Pingwu County, in 1994. There is only one street in the town that can be seen at a glance. His parents couldn&#39;t find any other way to survive, so they went out to work after he was 6 years old. The education his grandfather, a veteran, could give him was that his pocket money was two yuan a day, and &quot;if there was a fight, give him five yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the boys hunt together, excitement dominates their actions. After hunting prey, hormone secretion reaches its peak, and is strengthened through repeated competitions. But Gan Mingdong vaguely felt something strange. The moment he got the animal carcass, he would feel sad for no reason. But &quot;the next time I hunted, I was even more ferocious and excited.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also disliked those who hunted just for fun or to improve their marksmanship. Although the elders who believed in Buddhism handed him a shotgun, they also told him: Only shoot meat when you have to eat it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides hunting, the only things left are love and fighting. The latter, fierce confrontation between people, is the main content of his life. He fights at least three times a week, collects protection money, and then gives the money, along with his mother&#39;s salary, to those whose bones he has broken. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gan Mingdong is known far and wide for his naughty nature. One time, his parents were not at home, so he couldn&#39;t get into the house and slept on the street all night. There were countless relatives and friends in the village, and no one gave him a meal. In the morning, he was woken up by wild dogs that kept coming to harass him. He went to the river dam to wash his face, shot a brown river crow with a slingshot, and roasted it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The village is like &quot;a dead end&quot;, &quot;the end of the world&quot;. People seek survival in the mountains and forests, and hunt as a guarantee and evidence of their own existence. The prey are like small gold mines scattered in the mountains, so densely distributed that no one would think that they would disappear one day. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Panda or black bear, which one do you prefer?&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of another group of people in the world, the lives of &quot;prey&quot; are as equal as our own. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1996, Liu Xiaogeng, a student from Sichuan Agricultural University, graduated and came to work in Tangjiahe National Nature Reserve. His idea is very simple. In such a mature protected area, there are many foreign exchanges. I can learn advanced things from my foreign colleagues and use them for my use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-seven years later, looking back now, the &quot;lesson&quot; that impressed him most came from an American young man who did black bear protection in Minnesota. The other party asked: Do you prefer pandas or black bears? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiaogeng was speechless for a moment and made a hasty choice: Panda, which is cuter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The American young man said that I prefer the Asian black bear because the crescent-shaped spots on its body are very beautiful, much better than the crescent spots of the Minnesota black bear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiaogeng discovered for the first time that a person&#39;s original intention to protect animals can be as simple as: liking it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, Wang Dezhi, a junior student majoring in environmental biology and ecology at Peking University, went to Qinling for an internship. On the hillside less than 200 meters away from the station, a wild giant panda was eating bamboo. This is the second daughter of the panda family studied by her tutor Professor Pan Wenshi. Professor Pan called its name softly: &quot;Hope.&quot; &quot;Hope&quot; chewed and turned around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 26 years, Wang Dezhi still remembers that moment: &quot;A wild animal, a very calm look, had a huge impact on my heart.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Original ambition Wang Dezhi, a forest farm boy studying microbiology, made a decision at that moment: &quot;I want to do research on wild animals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Pan Wenshi, a master of Chinese biology, &quot;research&quot; on wild animals actually means &quot;Protect&quot;. What he often said in front of students was, &quot;We do a lot of research and publish a lot of papers, but if this animal is gone, how useful will these studies be?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student, Wang Dezhi followed Pan The professor studied white-headed langurs in Chongzuo, Guangxi for eight years. He and his classmates guarded a sugar cane field and used telescopes to observe the monkeys on the karst mountains. A little monkey that he has observed since birth, Wang Dezhi calls it &quot;Yiyi&quot;. For a while, they disappeared one by one, until the villagers brought a little monkey whose right arm was broken off by a animal trap. Everyone used fire-tempered machetes to cut off Yiyi&#39;s remaining arm. He lay quietly in Wang Dezhi&#39;s arms throughout the whole process. Later, I fed it my favorite leaves, and each one stretched out his right hand habitually. That was another unforgettable moment for Wang Dezhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This kind of monkey lives on the rock wall, which is the most important way for it to avoid enemies. On the rock wall, you must climb on all four legs-grasp at three points to form a flat surface. The other (hand and foot) reaches the fourth point (to move).&quot; Wang Dezhi said, &quot;Losing that hand means that it can no longer live on the rock wall.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One by one Became a creature walking on land. Not long after, it got lost and was never seen again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals set traps to capture this rare animal, perhaps hoping for some kind of &quot;medicine&quot;. This made Wang Dezhi angry. But eight years of guarding the sugar cane fields made him gradually realize, &quot;There is little value in simply blaming anyone. What should really be done is to find some opportunities so that both (people and animals) can live a better life.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, Liu Xiaogeng was invited to Laohegou Forest Farm in Pingwu County to conduct a background survey. A new protected area was being planned. This is an area surrounded by the homes of legendary hunters. Zhong Junde and Qiang Qinggui both live around Laohegou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GFdGBGJRQkytLIvjdn0WsHE9HWzVh2kPRcXtTjFG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GFdGBGJRQkytLIvjdn0WsHE9HWzVh2kPRcXtTjFG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Jian, director of Laohegou Conservation Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingwu is known as the &quot;No. 1 panda county in the world&quot; and has built multiple protection areas within its jurisdiction. District, according to the results of the fourth national giant panda resource survey, there are 335 wild giant pandas in Pingwu. Laohegou State-owned Forest Farm is located in Gaocun Township, Pingwu County. It connects two national nature reserves, Tangjiahe (Sichuan) and Baishuijiang (Gan), and is equivalent to the giant panda corridor of several major reserves in the two provinces. Infrared cameras have captured images of giant panda mothers and their babies walking through the forest farm; at the end of 2011, images of wild giant pandas eating antelope beef at night were also captured here. Laohegou is a transportation thoroughfare for giant pandas and has a complex and diverse ecosystem. However, it was not within the jurisdiction of any protected area at the time, so it became a popular place for poaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Dezhi’s view, the conservation value of Laohegou is self-evident. The core point of the hope that it can be built into a protected area is that historical conditions have given it natural protection opportunities. Since the 1970s, this area has been an old forest farm. There are no farmers living or grazing livestock. The environment is pure. The core threat to the ecology is poaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After two years of background investigation, Liu Xiaogeng stayed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, the Western Sichuan Nature Conservation Foundation (Sichuan Taohuayuan Ecological Protection Foundation) signed a 50-year entrustment management agreement with Pingwu County. The Taohuayuan Foundation will raise funds to be fully responsible for the ecology of the public welfare protected area. In terms of protection work, Laohegou became the first pilot project in China where the government entrusted the management of protected areas to private organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Taohuayuan Foundation was initiated by well-known Chinese entrepreneurs, artists, and philanthropists and focuses on non-profit environmental protection of nature reserves. As of 2023, the foundation manages six protected areas in five provinces, with a total area of ​​527 square kilometers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, the Taohuayuan Foundation registered and established the Laohegou Nature Conservation Center in Pingwu County, with Liu Xiaogeng as director. Wang Dezhi also joined as chief scientist and became one of the planners of Laohegou Reserve. He hopes to seize the opportunity here for both people and animals to live better. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Utopia&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Brother Chen seems to have been looking after Lao Hegou for half his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xianghui, born in 1971, is a native of the local area. Everyone calls him &quot;Second Brother&quot;. When he was young, his second brother inherited his father&#39;s business and entered Laohegou Forest Farm. In the 1990s, he watched thick birch trees fall down in front of him and sold them to various places at a price of 500 yuan per cubic meter. After a few years of such an ordinary life, the second brother suddenly discovered that the forest farm where he was supposed to take care of his whole life, like his father, was empty. &quot;The trees were all newly planted, and there was not a single animal in sight.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, China began to implement a natural forest protection project and stopped logging operations in the area. Forest farm workers faced tremendous pressure. Brother Chen also tried to go out to work, went to Guangdong, and later returned to Pingwu County, and finally returned to the forest farm: &quot;You are from this place, you have to rush back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first few years of the 21st century In 2007, the second brother guarded the empty forest farm, eating three meals a day, accompanied by the TV, and his life was even emptier than the forest farm. Morels sprouted on the roadside, and fresh bamboo shoots grew on the mountains, but he didn&#39;t even bother to touch them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story took a turn after a phone call. In 2011, Brother Chen received a call saying that an organization wanted to establish a protected area in the forest farm, and he immediately agreed to join. He has seen people from Wanglang Reserve (also in Pingwu County) wearing jackets and outdoor shoes that are &quot;so majestic and enviable&quot; and have income that ignites hope in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/M1vqZ1rYecs1vcIoqzZQ1Yek6NcAYTixQ2HaDLZS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/M1vqZ1rYecs1vcIoqzZQ1Yek6NcAYTixQ2HaDLZS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After dark, ranger Chen Xianghui leads a team to watch wild animals at night. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first group to investigate were experts on amphibians and reptiles from the Chengdu Chinese Academy of Sciences. The second group is from the Wuhan Institute of Aquatic Biology... He follows these teachers, helping to drive, helping to make traps to mark animals, and then helping to release them after weighing them. Life has real content, and the days go by very fast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I will follow the protection center wholeheartedly,&quot; said the second brother. At the end of March 2013, while hiking over the mountains with people from the conservation center, my second brother discovered an animal excrement that he had never seen before, and immediately called an expert for consultation. A few days later, he took 12 infrared cameras into the mountain and set them up. A month later, he checked the photos and called the leader of the county forestry bureau on the spot: We have photographed a tiger here! The other party replied: Tiger is a hammer! Do you know Shaanxi&#39;s &quot;Zhou Laohu&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I knew it was a golden cat, so I just made him happy.&quot; The taciturn second brother made a rare joke. As long as he could remember, he occasionally heard from old people that there were &quot;leopards&quot; in the mountains, &quot;actually golden cats.&quot; This was the first time he had seen this species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiaogeng and various experts conducted two years of background surveys. At the peak, forty or fifty scholars gathered here to study 13 different categories of animals. The survey identified seven main categories of protected objects represented by giant pandas and their habitats, as well as poaching, the biggest threat to the ecology. The root cause &quot;lies in the pressure on villagers&#39; lives and development outside the protected areas.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the designers of the blueprint for the Peach Blossom Spring Conservation Area, Wang Dezhi recalled that the founding team conceived a conservation plan for Laohegou that was entirely based on scientism. &quot;On the one hand, the protected area should be managed in the most scientific way; on the other hand, such a great conservation plan mainly advocates not only paying attention to the interior of the protected area, but also paying attention to the villages outside the protected area (Fushou Village, Xinyi Villages are included), they are an extension of protection. This design also won a British award,&quot; Wang Dezhi said, &quot;At that time, I thought the design was simply a utopia, so beautiful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the excitement, the scientists did not realize that in the eyes of the villagers, their work had a different meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Becoming a neighbor&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As early as his student days, Wang Dezhi had experienced the melancholy of an ecological protector through repeated communications with farmers in protected areas. and loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eight years they spent in Chongzuo, Guangxi, to the monkeys, Wang Dezhi and the others were observers; to the aborigines, the wall between the protectors and them had never been broken. Wang Dezhi believes that protecting the ecology at that time would only start from the &quot;appearance&quot; - locals hunted monkeys in order to use their bones to make wine to treat joint diseases, so Pan Wenshi promoted the upgrading of the local health center; in order to retain the trees on the mountain, the team Promote the construction of biogas digesters; in addition, we also helped build a local primary school. Starting from education, we hope to change the way people think about problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The benefits of the outpouring of resources were immediate, with locals becoming &quot;cooperative&quot; - ​​in front of the protectors. Once the protector leaves, they will immediately abandon the methane pit and return to their accustomed habit of chopping wood and burning fires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Laohegou, in order to get villagers around the reserve to give up hunting, the conservation center has also thought of many ways to try to find new sources of income for the villagers. But all of them took a turn for the worse after seemingly being successful. For example, when villagers were encouraged to standardize pig raising, the conservation center promised to purchase pigs at a price 20% higher than the market price. However, when it came to the acquisition, the villagers learned that they would not accept the pigs, let alone the African pigs. Sudden factors such as swine fever cannot be recycled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People are full of opinions, saying that you guys lied to us.&quot; The protection center was also aggrieved, &quot;Everyone is in a stage of exploration. How can we do business!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The conservation center also helped communities around the reserve build a mead factory. The directors of Taohuayuan paid a high price to buy the products and sold them to the directors at a high price. In the first year, the mead factory received a profit of 6.3 million yuan, half of which covered the cost and half of which He devoted himself to conservation work and achieved gratifying results. As a result, the business failed again the next year: &quot;The directors reported that the wine was too unpleasant to drink.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Business can’t be done, and Laohegou doesn’t look good. In Gouli, 26 patrol lines have been designed throughout the area, and more than 80 infrared camera locations have been deployed. But in the eyes of the villagers outside the ditch, Laohegou is the back mountain of their family. Going to the earth temple there to worship does not require anyone&#39;s permission. Whether killing chickens or burning incense, it has been their tradition and freedom for thousands of years. They board vans and come and go in groups, which puts pressure on the management and fire prevention of the protected area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Conservation Center attempts to use local thinking to break down barriers. During the sacrifice, they also pooled their money to donate a chicken, &quot;specifically saying that this is a chicken from the protected area.&quot; They also said that when working on the same piece of land, they should worship the same god. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Becoming a neighbor” is a set of ideas that are still being explored. In addition to anti-poaching in the reserve, rangers at the conservation center spend more than 400 hours doing community work every year. In the view of the foundation, most man-made threats to protected areas come from surrounding communities, and making friends with residents is the long-term way to discover, prevent, and eliminate man-made interference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the protection center, everyone has to &quot;go to the countryside&quot; and visit the community. Ma Jian, the vice president of the foundation, lives in Shenzhen and is currently the director of the Laohegou Conservation Center. When he was in Laohegou, he was more like a village director: walking on the village road, nodding hello to the villagers, saying hello and pushing away the farmer&#39;s door familiarly. He opened the door and sat down on the bench. While eating melon seeds, he asked the host if the injury on his hand was feeling better and if his son and daughter had gone home during the Chinese New Year. &quot;Has your son who is a chef gained weight? No, people say that if a chef is not fat, he is not a good cook.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/q3Y5jOg1k7ipvMT2v5NLCt8ovucLbTabvxqV2hpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /25/q3Y5jOg1k7ipvMT2v5NLCt8ovucLbTabvxqV2hpD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255310&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Jian visited the countryside in Fushou Village, Pingwu County. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chatting is not the only purpose. Brother Chen, who is already the deputy director of the conservation center, can sometimes tell who is hunting secretly just by walking around the house. Once, he found goral hair in the crevices behind a farmer&#39;s house in Xinyi Village, and found pheasant feathers in the bushes. That night he took the village secretary to the farmer&#39;s house. Early the next morning, the farmer retrieved two more animal traps from the forest and handed them over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since they are &quot;neighbors&quot;, the relationship between the conservation center and the surrounding villages should also be to help each other. &quot;People used to be suspicious. You fenced off the land and all the money was taken away by you.&quot; Ma Jian believes that the rangers need to understand the villagers, and the villagers also need to know what the people in the old river ditch are doing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the conservation center will launch an ecological tour guide training. 115 villagers signed up for the first phase. After passing the training, the villagers will become tour guides and can take tourists as long as they comply with the management regulations of the national park. There is no need to pay money to the protected area to experience it, and the guided tour fee belongs to the individual villagers. If you violate the regulations, just like driver&#39;s license management, you will be deducted 6 points to retake training, and if you are deducted 12 points, your tour guide qualification will be suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to brew mead is no longer the responsibility of the conservation center. They only do ecological planning to clarify the areas and quantities where bees can be kept. What should farmers do while complying with the regulations of the protected area? It just depends on their own abilities and wishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When farming is busy, the conservation center will take time to help farmers harvest corn; villagers picked wild vegetables, pears, and persimmons, and also picked a few handfuls and sent them to the conservation center. Sometimes, several villages will jointly hold a banquet, and Laohegou must also put on a program like other villages, even though it is not an administrative division of a natural village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effectiveness of this mutually beneficial neighborly relationship lies in the subtleties of daily life. Qiang Qinggui, who is fond of tobacco, will skillfully stub out the cigarette butt with his fingers and put it into his pocket after finishing smoking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t litter, that&#39;s what Teacher Ma taught you,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;We still have to &quot;live on the mountain&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The key result of becoming neighbors is to unite the indigenous peoples and protect them together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, with the support of the Taohuayuan Foundation, Xinyi Village and Fushou Village in Pingwu established their own patrol teams. Every year, these veteran hunters harvest dozens of hunting traps from the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The patrol team in Xinyi Village was naturally led by Zhong Jun. This old man, who was both good and evil, organized eight old hunters to start an anti-poaching campaign. Others asked him why he did this, and he replied: I will do it even if you don’t pay me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I was a little selfish at the time.” He confessed, “There weren’t many people in our ditch, just a few old people at the top of the house. People from outside came into my ditch to hunt. Whether it&#39;s digging for medicine or digging for medicine, all our resources have been taken away. We have formed a patrol team. No matter whether outsiders are hunting animals in my ditch or digging herbs in my ditch, I will catch you. I&#39;m not allowed to pick it up and take it away.&quot; But for this kind of thing, &quot;I have to have an organization to support me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UwtejEavJeswwrbiYclSQclkBXsUTQJvZXIIm5oU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UwtejEavJeswwrbiYclSQclkBXsUTQJvZXIIm5oU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255312&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhong Junde’s home is in the mountains and forests. The mountain next to it was once one of Zhong Junde’s main hunting positions. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Lei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The village secretary firmly supports it. In the eyes of the secretary, this is an opportunity to avenge the shame of the &quot;Widow Village&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;matchmaker&quot; of Peach Blossom Spring also came at the right time. Taohuayuan also provides equipment to the community patrol team, including infrared cameras, batteries, etc., buys insurance for the rangers, and distributes uniform clothing. If the work is done well every year, the foundation will also give certain rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Locals said that Taohuayuan’s “matchmaking” approach allowed Zhong Junde to “turn what was previously ‘evil’ into ‘righteous’”. The same is true in Fushou Village. Qiang Qinggui, who was famous for hunting forest musk deer, became the captain of the village patrol team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The spear of the past has become the shield of today. The changing role of the hunter has changed the face of the mountains and forests, but time has also passed. They are all old. Qiang Qinggui is like a cheetah in old age. His strong muscles have begun to relax, he walks with a cautious gait, and one of his eyeballs is gray due to injury. The average age of Zhong Junde&#39;s team is nearly sixty. They are all looking for a successor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nikG5oZe3oCOhIuQSocfEGW2DKrxPZCzmFQrYNwL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nikG5oZe3oCOhIuQSocfEGW2DKrxPZCzmFQrYNwL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255313&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Young rangers formed a team to patrol the mountains. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The little hunter has grown up. In the protected area, Taohuayuan is recruiting full-time forest rangers. Gan Mingdong, a former naughty boy, successfully applied for the job with his only specialty and love - mountain climbing. He is nimble and dexterous, and can move through the mountains and forests as easily as a monkey darting between vines. In the year he first became a ranger, Gan Mingdong patrolled more than 1,700 kilometers, which is equivalent to the distance from Mianyang to Beijing. The roads the panda has traveled and where it will appear have already been drawn in his mind. Every step of walking in the mountain forest, every hunting snare and animal trap removed, judging the installation location of infrared cameras based on their whereabouts, and capturing every rare animal, all turned a natural hunter into a natural ranger, &quot; I feel that I still have some value.&quot; The young man who was &quot;definitely going to jail&quot; in the eyes of his relatives is now &quot;doing something serious&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People in the village have gradually seen the benefits of protection. Not only have they driven away outsiders who plundered resources from their own land, they have also attracted tourists who are willing to spend money to see animals in the mountains and forests. &quot;That&#39;s how gold and silver are created.&quot; Zhong Junde understood the meaning, &quot;It&#39;s what we used to call &#39;supporting the mountain and eating the mountain&#39;. This means relying on the mountain and eating the mountain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In In the village, people now respect Zhong Junde for his ability to protect animals rather than harm them. This respect is even stronger than when poaching was prevalent in the 1980s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When and how did the change in concept occur? The improvement of laws and the improvement of people&#39;s living standards may be necessary conditions. In Wang Dezhi&#39;s view, what is more important is &quot;seeing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone is increasingly convinced that if the environment continues to be destroyed, our descendants may have no future.&quot; Wang Dezhi said, &quot;No kind of life can live alone on the earth. , because we cannot eat ourselves. If we regard every life as a point, there will be such a connection between the points, and you can always find a connection, which is the energy transferred from the outside world to ourselves. But When such a species disappears, it means that all the connections related to it disappear.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working in Laohegou for 10 years, Liu Xiaogeng went to Taohuayuan&#39;s public welfare protection in Xianghai in Jilin areas, where the main threat to ecological conservation is overgrazing. In the past, the protection of Xianghai mainly relied on law enforcement, but objectively speaking, the contradiction between protection and development will not be resolved because of effective law enforcement. Instead, the conflicts are accumulating year by year. Moreover, public welfare organizations do not have the power to enforce laws, which requires them to get involved in the lives of local people. Liu Xiaogeng mainly relies on &quot;persuasion&quot; to guide people to herd properly. 508 households raise cattle and sheep, and more than 398 households have &quot;discussed&quot; with Liu Xiaogeng. In order to avoid Director Liu from herding cattle, the common people had to go out in the middle of the night. As a result, Director Liu went to herd cattle at 3 o&#39;clock in the morning. Due to &quot;human sentiment&quot;, overgrazing in Xianghai Protected Area was reduced by 70% in the second half of 2022 - first become &quot;neighbors&quot;, and then find a way to break the situation together, outsiders, indigenous people, nature, everyone is here On a line. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A moment of connection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Perhaps everyone in Laohegou has experienced that moment of (re)connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hunter who frightened forest musk deer encountered a panda that accidentally rolled down while building a road. All the workers on site, who were 30 years old or even older, surrounded the round animal, and every man wanted to touch it. The panda was frightened away by the touches from the men. Qiang Qinggui said, &quot;The hair of giant pandas in the wild is darker than all black and whiter than all white.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The longer Gan Mingdong works as a ranger, the more he likes to look into the eyes of animals. , reading their thoughts from it, he has seen the pure eyes of the newborn takin, and has also seen the twilight in the eyes of the old takin that died the next day when it was looking for its own resting place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dezhi’s moment came when a herd of takin blocked his car and refused to give way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/h8TWfWk1kPIoAZnKroUMYJ3lvf4bdnhhw3kZ9J54.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1658&quot; height= &quot;1106&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/h8TWfWk1kPIoAZnKroUMYJ3lvf4bdnhhw3kZ9J54.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the Laohegou Nature Conservation Center, a ranger encountered a takin while watching wild animals at night. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, I really felt that this place (Laohegou) had become a home for wild animals. , this is what we hope to achieve most, to return nature to nature.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the encounter rate of animals alone, the protection work of Laohegou and its expansion area has achieved remarkable results. The original poaching and deforestation activities have been basically eliminated. Infrared cameras deployed over the past ten years have taken more than one million photos and recorded 120,000 minutes of animal activity images. Among them, a video of an Asian golden cat eating captured by an infrared camera has been viewed 500 million times online - it can be said that hundreds of millions of netizens have also established a connection with this agile and ferocious big cat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KjLXAN1LNWCu9GGSgjHEfIPmlpdx7qAQBwDomn2c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KjLXAN1LNWCu9GGSgjHEfIPmlpdx7qAQBwDomn2c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255314&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During patrol on the mountain, ranger Gan Mingdong checks the field infrared camera. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sun Xiaochen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to work arrangements, Liu Xiaogeng was transferred from Laohegou. In the early spring of that year, he encountered three hooded deer, one of which was giving birth. When the rangers passed by, the two free-moving hooded deer did not instinctively run away, but chose to guard the birthing doe. Liu Xiaogeng regarded this as a gift from ten years of forestry work, and he was satisfied, outweighing the sadness of parting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the deserted tea pavilion on the second floor, the legendary hunter Zhong Junde overlooked his small courtyard and said that during the New Year, this was Huaguoshan - his child, who was adopted by him after his brother passed away. The children, his grandchildren, and the descendants of his sister&#39;s family were all gathered here. They have enough food and clothing, sufficient storehouses, and a safe life. At this moment, his arrogance completely faded away, and a face that had experienced the vicissitudes of the mountains and forests shone with the soft light of motherhood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We saw forest musk deer during night viewing. This was the luck that Ma Jianlai had been trying to encounter for three years since he was the director of the Laohegou Conservation Center. But we never saw the pandas drinking water by the stream. It is said that they were the most naive at that time. But there are moments of connection: after wading through a river filled with prehistoric white domes, walking uphill, the breeze blows, pink-white Sichuan rhododendrons fall on my shoulders from the air, and the bushes below my waist are covered with Full of berries. If you lower your head and search carefully, you can still see the lanceolate double tower. Near the stream, blue-purple Corydalis sichuanensis emerges from the cracks in the rocks. Its stamens have a rose-colored halo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老师被挖走、学生招不满，崩塌的县中何去何从？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;More than two thousand counties are the foundation of China, connecting cities on one end and rural areas on the other. It is a haven for essayists in small towns, and it contains the deepest and most profound emotions. The county is the stabilizer among them. When the education gap between urban and rural areas gradually widens, faced with poached teachers, dissatisfied students, and challenges from “super middle schools”, where should the county go?</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为何偏偏喜欢你——纪念陈百强去世三十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/23QvzqkdPVNYg95r2IWY5JXs9EwpHgUtc1Qg5Pu7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/23QvzqkdPVNYg95r2IWY5JXs 9EwpHgUtc1Qg5Pu7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Baiqiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What do you want in life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, the 4K restored version of the movie &quot;Encore&quot; was re-screened in Hong Kong. It will also be screened in Xiamen as the closing film of this year&#39;s Golden Rooster Chinese Film Festival to commemorate the 30th anniversary of the death of starring Chen Baiqiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Encore&quot; is director Cai Jiguang&#39;s debut film, starring Chen Baiqiang, Leslie Cheung, Paul Chung, and Weng Jingjing. It was released in 1980 and was Chen Baiqiang&#39;s first starring role. At the age of 22, he played the real role of Ken, a middle school student in the film, and developed various youthful entanglements with Paul played by Paul Chung, Gigo played by Leslie Cheung, and Julie played by Jingjing Weng. The next year, Chen, Zhang and Zhong starred in another youth-themed movie &quot;Unemployed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Chen Baiqiang, who has been singing all his life, is as famous as his contemporaries such as Leslie Cheung and Anita Mui, he rarely appears in movies and TV dramas. In addition to &quot;Encore&quot; and &quot;The Unemployed&quot;, the only movies in which he had more roles were &quot;Merry Christmas&quot; in 1984 and &quot;An Autumn Fairy Tale&quot; in 1987. Chen Baiqiang did not have this ambition, but these films have inadvertently become some precious records in his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5kKprcddnKSC1DKnCBmJ5Vax0CzMKye4FCUaImKf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5kKprcddnKSC1DKnCBmJ5Vax0CzMKye4FCUaImKf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1984 movie &quot;Merry Christmas&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie, Chen Baiqiang&#39;s character settings are pretty much the same: a rich man, a good boy, talented, caring, Ambitious, youthful and loyal, and do not give up their ideals for money. In the camera, he looks gentle and elegant, with a slight smile on his face. But the years of hardening are still captured by the camera: in &quot;Encore&quot;, the childlike facial features and the cheerful sunshine in the eyebrows have not yet bloomed. In &quot;Autumn Fairy Tale&quot;, the red lips and white teeth have a hint of melancholy and an inexorable melancholy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1987, Chen Baiqiang&#39;s career had entered the second half. 1985-1986 was the darkest moment in his life experience. During this period, he was ill and everything was not going well. His relationship with the gambling king&#39;s daughter He Chaoqiong was opposed by the He family. The media was not very kind to him, with widespread rumors that he was infected with AIDS, then that he was schizophrenic, and then that he committed suicide. Sometimes the newspaper office also received a breaking news call saying that &quot;Chen Baiqiang was dead.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How can I not mind if you call me, because someone said that I am infected with that disease. When I walk on the street, passers-by look at me like a monster, point at me, and say many things that cannot be done. The words touched my ears.&quot; Chen Baiqiang recalled. In response to the rumors, he took a test at the suggestion of others but refused to make the test results public. Perhaps as a countermeasure, he also wore a T-shirt with the words &quot;I GOT AIDS&quot; printed on it on the plane. This rumor was not completely broken until he was hospitalized in a coma in 1992 and the doctor tested negative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His album &quot;Top 100 84&quot; released in 1984 contains a large number of works adapted from European and American songs, and is unique in the Hong Kong music scene where adaptations of Japanese songs are popular. However, due to misalignment with public taste, none of the songs became his masterpieces. He put great effort into preparing for the concert, imitating the prince&#39;s appearance and performing wearing a crystal mask, but he was criticized by the media and public opinion. He said: &quot;I have been depressed in my heart, and at the same time I found that someone would deliberately hurt me... I was very fragile at the time and attached great importance to external news reports. I didn&#39;t know how to fight back, so I fell into a confused low ebb. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He then released the albums &quot;Loving You Deeply&quot; (1985) and &quot;When I Think of You&quot; (1986), but the company received little publicity for them and the sound was weak. The Hong Kong music scene has also changed from the original competition between Leslie Cheung (Kwok Wing) and Chan (Bai Qiang) to the one between Alan Tam (Alan Tam) and Leslie Cheung (Kwok Wing). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These negative emotions condensed into Chen Baiqiang&#39;s face in &quot;Autumn Fairy Tale&quot; - delicate, handsome but tired. &quot;Autumn Fairy Tale&quot; director Zhang Wanting recalled that during filming, Chen Baiqiang performed very well and could usually pass it in one take. However, he always pursued perfection and chased the director to take another shot and another. &quot;He is a perfectionist, always pursuing better and wanting to be the best.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/afNS1AhKBWjPIaKU27X6IU7yebNSFqV5mwORT0la.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/afNS1AhKBWjPIaKU27X6IU7yebNSFqV5mw ORT0la. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Chen Baiqiang (middle) with Tony Leung (left) and Andy Lau&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File photo/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Filmmaker Chen Xinjian and Chen Baiqiang have known each other for many years and played Chen Baiqiang&#39;s uncle in &quot;Encore&quot;. He believed that Chen Baiqiang was unhappy deep down. &quot;That kind of unhappiness is like the core of the earth, burning like a raging fire. He has many happy moments and many friends, but every happy time is quickly evaporated by the fire.&quot; He said, &quot;He has a lot of pressure on himself. The requirements are very high, and if the performance is not good enough, you will be unhappy for a long time. If you perform well, you will be happy for a while, and then you will start to worry about the next performance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such emotions also appear in Chen Baiqiang&#39;s songs. In 1987, he released the album &quot;Dream Man&quot;. The title song of the same name was &quot;I Love Baiyun&quot; he composed in 1980 - it was re-released with new lyrics added by Chen Haiqi. The original song &quot;Look at the white clouds, free and unrestrained, hopeful, unpredictable, floating by, you can only lead the way, the dancing clouds, leaving in a hurry without leaving behind, floating in the distance, the back becomes more and more beautiful&quot; has become &quot;This dreamer is floating away. For whom, I have spent my whole life with a heartbroken heart. At this moment, I think that love is eternal. I have gone back and forth a thousand times in vain. I love secretly without stopping. I leave in a hurry and never stay. My back becomes more and more beautiful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more widely circulated piece of this album is &quot;My Story&quot; composed by Chen Baiqiang and lyrics by Xiang Xuehui. After the composition was completed, Chen Baiqiang thought it was a reflection of himself. He originally wanted to write the lyrics himself, but was unable to do so. He described his feelings to Xiang Xuehui, and Xiang wrote the current lyrics. During the recording, Chen Baiqiang cried several times and said that the song was a true self-narration. &quot;The face that hides the stories of the past, walking in and out of the day, the blank eyes peeking every day... Time continues to deceive me, there will always be a new day... The painful rumors are very tiring, the past has no trace, trapped in There are many walls, but no one can rebuild happiness from the past.&quot; This autobiographical song resonated with music fans and was rated as one of the top ten Chinese hits of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four years later, Xiang Xuehui filled in the lyrics of another song &quot;Life Cannot Be Determined&quot; for Chen Baiqiang: &quot;I don&#39;t pretend to be free and easy, and I can&#39;t distinguish between sadness and joy...Who knows my heart?&quot; Hot, who knows that there is no need to say it anymore, I still want to be short of it all my life, I don’t want to expose me to others anymore, you will make someone feel lovable...&quot; This song is considered to be a reflection of Chen Baiqiang&#39;s inner feelings at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Ailin, a disc jockey of Radio Hong Kong and a good friend of Chen Baiqiang, believes that Chen Baiqiang is a very sensitive person and this is where he succeeds. He is very sensitive to emotions and can bring that feeling out in his songs. But at the same time, he is also very painful because he is sensitive and cares about what others think of him. &quot;His music can come out, but his personal emotions cannot.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;His melodies are rarely happy. Most of his music represents his character, which is relatively lonely.&quot; With Chen Baiqiang Summarized by Xu Riqin, who has collaborated on many albums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/chsHHuxl9wwBeS4tmG6aQjlKcM2CFEol5v3pylVM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;521&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/chsHHuxl9wwBeS4tmG6aQjlKcM2CFEol5v3pylVM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 1981 movie &quot;Unemployed&quot;, Chen Baiqiang (right) and Leslie Cheung&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, Chen Baiqiang released the album &quot;What I Want in Life&quot;, and the title song of the same name &quot;Life&quot; &quot;What do you want&quot; was rated as one of the top ten Chinese golden songs and one of the top ten golden songs of the year. His unhappiness is concentrated in this song: What do I want in life? I can never see clearly in my confusion. I didn’t expect that what I lost is already everything I have. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the later period, Chen Baiqiang kept himself to himself. He didn&#39;t want to face people and lost his previous glory.&quot; said Huang Baigao, a manager who worked with Chen Baiqiang. Later in his career, Chen Baiqiang&#39;s original works gradually decreased. Chen Jiaying, his agent at the time, recalled that on the one hand, Chen Baiqiang was worried about his lack of creative power. On the other hand, the Four Heavenly Kings also appeared. He put more pressure on himself, and his creations decreased. &quot;He doesn&#39;t always greet people with a smile. He drinks to numb himself in the later stage. Only after drinking does he have the courage to talk about his feelings and make himself emotionally high. In fact, he is a tragic figure, not a comedy.&quot; Chen Jiaying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1990, Chen Baiqiang refused to accept any job. Chen Jiaying once received a call from him late at night: I am at home, have a sip of champagne and take a sleeping pill. When he put down the phone and rushed to Chen Baiqiang&#39;s home, Chen was already in a coma. Fortunately, he was sent to the hospital in time and there was no danger. &quot;After he was fine, I tried very hard to encourage and enlighten him. Unfortunately, he always had his own outlook on life. No matter how much I tried, he always saw things in gray.&quot; Chen Jiaying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/myP13ivIia50mV4Z6qnaZlezzmEYLHFHC278agpN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/myP13ivIia50mV4Z6qnaZlezzmEYLHFHC278agpN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1993, Chen Baiqiang passed away, and his close friends Anita Mui, Chow Yun-fat and others supported him&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;Some media photographed Chen Baiqiang&#39;s residence at that time, located at Royal Garden, 9A Kennedy Road, Central and Western District, Hong Kong. It was built by him himself and was all black. Entering the room, the entire 2,000-square-foot area is almost pitch black: black carpet, black walls, black sofa, black dining table, black dining chairs, black marble candlesticks, and a shiny black piano. The only colorful thing is the wallpaper on the living room wall. painting, a work by the Italian abstract expressionist painter Adevor. The bedroom has black bedsheets, black bedding, black pillowcases, black carpet, black slippers, black cloakroom, black desk, black crystal metallic lion decoration, black beauty couch... Only the floor lamp is not black. The media described him as &quot;very repressed.&quot; Chen Baiqiang also has a house near the Royal Garden. The style is completely opposite. The whole house is white. This was regarded by the outside world as an externalization of his melancholy mood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From January 30 to February 1, 1992, Chen Baiqiang held three &quot;Farewell Shanghai Concerts&quot; and announced his farewell to the music scene at the end of the year. Chen Jiaying recalled that the performance was very successful. &quot;He was so happy and felt that he had accomplished something.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, 1992, Chen Baiqiang was found unconscious in his residence and was sent to the hospital for rescue. He remained in a coma for 17 months. On October 25, 1993, Chen Baiqiang died of brain failure at the age of 35. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Xtf4hgIb42kB0WfH2lysMf4eRxF4K1sQgHNOVB0M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;638&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Xtf4hgIb42kB0WfH2lysMf4eRxF4K1sQgHNOVB0M.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Baiqiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(&quot;Breakthrough&quot;/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I just like you&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ten years ago, in 1983, Chen Baiqiang’s career reached its peak. He released the album &quot;I Just Like You&quot;. The soulful song of the same name was quickly sung by fans and ranked high on major charts. His status in the music scene has also skyrocketed. Musician Lin Yifeng believes that this song expresses the psychology of the crowd at that time: eager to be understood, but afraid of being hurt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the most widely circulated of his many golden songs, and it is also the one that best represents his characteristics: fresh, simple, and slightly sad. Compared with his various attempts in the future, this kind of soothing, gentle and noble love songs are more integrated with him. Represented by this, Chen Baiqiang is closely connected with the memory of Chinese music, which continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singer and actor Zhong Zhentao analyzed that Chen Baiqiang uses the Qi method of Cantonese opera when singing. Coupled with his personal temperament, he is good at performing minor-key songs and can interpret old and traditional melodies in a modern way. When he was a teenager, Chen Baiqiang often went to see the performances of the Wenner Band, where he met Zhong Zhentao and Alan Tam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1982, Chen Baiqiang released the album &quot;Talking&quot;, in which the song &quot;Take Care of Tonight&quot; was adapted from the 1961 classic old song - composed by Wang Fuling and sung by Cui Ping. After the Cantonese version of Chen Baiqiang&#39;s &quot;Take Care of Tonight&quot; was released, it won the first Top Ten Golden Melody Award, and the album sold more than 250,000 copies. At the same time, &quot;Ripples&quot; composed by him also won the Top Ten Chinese Golden Melody Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moving forward, his first album &quot;First&amp;nbsp;Love&quot; released in 1979 has become very popular, and the song &quot;Tears Flow for You&quot; soon ranked among the top ten Chinese hits. Chen Baiqiang became an instant hit and became a popular star in the Hong Kong pop music scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/nke2yavYUhXZMaKLvUYi5ZubhS74jLVWWbyZ7OEj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/nke2yavYUhXZMaKLvUYi5ZubhS74jLVWWbyZ7OEj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255286&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Baiqiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hong Kong at that time, he adapted and sang Japanese songs are the mainstream. Chen Baiqiang has adapted a few songs, including songs from Europe and the United States, as well as a large number of original works, which makes him particularly eye-catching among other singers. He is handsome, can sing and write, plays the piano very well, can also play the guitar, is good at drawing, and has excellent clothing taste. Such an almost perfect image made his popularity rise rapidly after his debut. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People were curious about where he came from, and the results of the media exploration did not disappoint them. It was a growth history of a noble son that met people&#39;s expectations: On September 7, 1958, Chen Baiqiang was born in Hong Kong, and his father Chen Pengfei was. Founder of Jinbao Watch Company in Central. His father liked him very much and planned to train him to be his successor. But his mother was not a big family. Throughout his childhood, he and his mother lived elsewhere. Perhaps because of this, his personality is different from other children. He is calm and smart, likes to be neat and tidy, and is polite to others but keeps a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Baiqiang has had a strong musical understanding since he was a child. He can hum the tunes of many songs after listening to them once. He learned to play the electronic keyboard and piano without a teacher, but he had no interest in studying and said that he &quot;had a headache when I saw textbooks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In middle school, he was already a famous figure. Deng Ailin was the emcee at a school event and found that the girls were discussing a boy who was handsome, played the piano well, was self-taught, and could compose music. When the later singer Lin Shanshan met Chen Baiqiang for the first time at the third-grade dance of middle school, she danced in front of Chen Baiqiang with all her energy, just to let Chen Baiqiang talk to her. Chen Baiqiang invited her to watch a movie. She looked at Chen Baiqiang&#39;s profile the whole time and thought to herself: He is smiling, he has an expression, and he is showing his true feelings. Can she keep this moment? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, his father initially did not support Chen Baiqiang’s music dream and only wanted him to follow his example and become a businessman. The two quarreled many times until Chen Baiqiang was tired of studying and dropped out of school. He occasionally served as a guest singer for some bands, and sang in Winner&#39;s band and on the radio. It was also during this period that he met Zhong Zhentao and Alan Tam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7b4pm9iVK2Q8mIn4M53MEWrAIj0o3qMF3jEaIldL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1498&quot; height= &quot;999&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7b4pm9iVK2Q8mIn4M53MEWrAIj0o3qMF3jEaIldL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1981, Chen Baiqiang and Weng Jingjing starred in the TV series &quot;Breakthrough&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father finally agreed with Chen Baiqiang&#39;s choice and sent him to the San Francisco Conservatory of Music in the United States for further study. In 1977, he returned to Hong Kong and happened to participate in the &quot;Yamaha Electronic Keyboard Competition&quot; and won the championship. Subsequently, he won the third place in the &quot;Hong Kong Pop Song Writing Invitational Competition&quot; with his self-composed English song &quot;The Rocky Road&quot;. The following year, he once again won the third place in the &quot;Hong Kong Pop Song Composition Invitational Competition&quot; with his personally composed English song &quot;The Sunrise&quot;. He soon attracted the attention of EMI Records and became a signed singer under the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Musician Huang Zhan recalled: &quot;In his &quot;little demon&quot; era (probably meaning that others are small and very elf), he often played with us, so his artistic ability, It’s better to have more people. Danny (Chen Baiqiang’s English name) has been playing the piano for two years and is already very good at it. I was a judge at the Yamaha Electronic Piano Competition that year, and everyone agreed that he deserved to win the championship. Because of his performance , emotional and delicate. There are many who compete with him who have studied longer than him, but none are as good as him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Baiqiang has been taking selfies with his camera for a long time. In the winter of 1979, he set up his camera by a bench on the streets of New York, lay down, looked at the camera, and gave his future self a smile. He also went to the Greek seaside, set up a tripod and camera, and took pictures of himself smiling, with the wind blowing his hair and clothes, and the waves rolling behind him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chow Yun-fat said: &quot;Danny (Benny Chan) is just a big boy. Don&#39;t treat him as an adult, but love him as a child and cherish him...&quot; Chen Xinjian commented on that time Chen Baiqiang: His sadness, coupled with his dark eyes, fascinate many young girls. He makes people feel like a protected, pitiful, kitten in the rain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The combination of various factors makes Chen Baiqiang’s image even more lovable. When Priscilla Chan was still in school, she loved Chen Baiqiang so much that she asked all the boys around her to wear Chen Baiqiang&#39;s hairstyle and make up to look like Chen Baiqiang. And she skipped class to watch Bai Qiang Chen&#39;s movie &quot;Encore.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Baiqiang in this movie has fixed an ideal image of a boy: clean and thin, with short hair and a white shirt, bright eyes, a slightly sad smile, and persistence for his dreams. He originally only lived in every girl&#39;s dream, but he actually appeared in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If they knew his later life, how many people would wish to stop at this moment and say to him: &quot;I just like you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: italics , italic style_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Reference materials: &quot;Emotional Photos of Chen Baiqiang&quot;, &quot;Remembering Chen Baiqiang This Way&quot;, &quot;The 30th Anniversary of Chen Baiqiang&#39;s Farewell&quot;, &quot;The Immortal Legend·Chen Baiqiang&quot;, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从鼠头牛肉到鼠头鸭脖：校园食堂安全谁来负责？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259224]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 23, 2023, in response to the food safety incidents that occurred at North China University of Science and Technology and Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College, The Food Safety Office of the State Council interviewed the main responsible persons of the governments of Tangshan, Hebei and Nanchang, Jiangxi, and required the local governments to strictly implement their territorial management responsibilities and resolutely maintain the bottom line of campus food safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The food safety incident at Jiangxi Vocational College of Technology in early June 2023 caused a sensation on the entire Internet, and even gave birth to the new term &quot;rat head and duck neck&quot;. The North China University of Science and Technology food safety incident occurred recently on October 10. The same student ate something suspected to be a rat head in the canteen. The store claimed it was beef. Different from the &quot;rat-headed duck-necked incident&quot;, North China University of Science and Technology issued an announcement on the same day, admitting that food hygiene problems occurred in the school cafeteria, and terminated the entrusted operation contract with the relevant company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The appearance of rats in the kitchen of the canteen is nothing new. If the kitchen is not cleaned well, it is easy to attract rats. The canteen of Jiangxi Polytechnic College has been punished for this before. But the appearance of rat heads in meals is really shocking and incomprehensible: How irresponsible must one be for food safety to turn a blind eye to rats in meals? These two campus food safety incidents alarmed the Food Safety Office of the State Council, and they interviewed the main responsible persons of the local government. The high standards showed the serious nature of the incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food is the most important thing for the people. Food safety is a top priority. According to the definition of the Food Safety Law, food safety means that food is non-toxic and harmless, meets appropriate nutritional requirements, and does not cause any acute, subacute or chronic harm to human health. This is the minimum requirement for food. Food cannot contain harmful bacteria, viruses and other microorganisms, nor can it contain toxic and harmful chemicals. Of course, there should be no vector organisms like mice that can carry bacteria, viruses, parasites and other hundreds of pathogens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The country has always attached great importance to food safety. In September, when the school year just started, the State Administration for Market Regulation, the Ministry of Education, the Ministry of Public Security, and the National Health Commission jointly issued a document calling for effective strengthening of school food safety work. Less than a month later, the rat head beef incident occurred in the canteen of North China University of Science and Technology in Tangshan. The cafeteria management company &quot;committed crimes against the wind&quot;. On the surface, it is a problem with the company that operates the cafeteria, but in fact, there are huge loopholes in the logistics management of the university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The canteens of North China University of Science and Technology and Jiangxi Vocational College of Technology, two universities that have been exposed to food safety problems, are outsourced to third-party companies. But even if it is outsourced, the school still has the first responsibility for the food safety in the canteen and should effectively supervise the third-party company to ensure food safety. But in reality, many colleges and universities often become &quot;hands-off shopkeepers&quot; after outsourcing their canteens. They are indifferent to the daily management of the canteen. If there is a problem, they put all the blame on the supplier and terminate the contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we all know, business in schools is good business. Canteens on campuses of primary and secondary schools can sell them for astronomical prices, let alone universities. Whether it is an ordinary university such as North China University of Science and Technology or a higher vocational college such as Jiangxi Polytechnic College, in addition to enjoying tax benefits, its canteens may also receive subsidies from the government, and the customer base is very stable. Although the food in school cafeterias is generally cheaper than in the outside market, there is still considerable profit margin, so there are still many companies vying to bid for the operation of university cafeterias. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the bidding process and the operation process after winning the bid, are there any hidden exchanges of interests between the operating company and the school&#39;s logistics managers? After the incident involving a rat with a duck&#39;s neck at Jiangxi Vocational College of Technology, the school initially vigorously defended the contractor, immediately reporting that the rat&#39;s head was a duck&#39;s neck, and forcing students who discovered the problem to write a written explanation to &quot;clarify.&quot; This series of operations makes it difficult not to have doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to schools, local government departments are also responsible for supervising food safety in school cafeterias. During this interview, the Food Safety Office of the State Council pointed out that there are problems such as the weakening of territorial management responsibilities for food safety in the two places and the absence of industry management responsibilities of competent authorities. Food safety is the legal responsibility of the market supervision department, and the market supervision bureau should perform supervisory duties on all food business units within its jurisdiction, including local school canteens. However, in the Jiangxi Polytechnic College incident, the local Municipal Supervision Bureau not only failed to strictly perform its duties, but also spoke nonsense and endorsed the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, most universities are at a higher level, and local regulatory authorities may have difficulties in daily supervision. For example, North China University of Science and Technology is a key university in Hebei Province and a department-level unit. Jiangxi Vocational College is also a higher vocational college in Jiangxi Province. The administrative level of these schools is higher than that of the local municipal supervision department. Even the person in charge of the logistics management department may have a higher level than the local supervision department. For example, the director of the Changdong Branch of the Market Supervision Bureau of Nanchang High-tech Zone, who endorsed the canteen of Jiangxi Polytechnic College, is only at the department level, while the leader of the logistics department of Jiangxi Polytechnic College is at least a division-level cadre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, territorial management and industry management responsibilities should not be weakened or absent due to their level. Universities, regardless of their level, should accept the supervision of relevant local departments. Similarly, local regulatory authorities should treat units within their jurisdiction equally and strictly supervise them regardless of their level. In the case of the rat-headed duck-neck incident at Jiangxi Vocational College of Technology, a joint investigation team composed of Jiangxi provincial departments stated in the investigation report that relevant responsible units and responsible persons, such as the school and the local municipal supervisory branch, will be severely dealt with in accordance with laws and regulations. But almost half a year has passed, and there is still no information on whether and how the relevant responsible persons have been dealt with. And if there is no serious accountability for those responsible for supervision negligence, I am afraid that food safety supervision in school cafeterias will still be empty talk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花里胡哨blingbling的美甲，如今成了猛男的最爱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/28304bdf2ee9033aa0ddc5cfd9f349a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/16/28304bdf2ee9033aa0ddc5cfd9f349a4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the nude pink nail caps, flowing silver metal lines outline the outline of the nails; the fingers are spread out, and the bright manicure with cool graffiti patterns is eye-catching; He is holding the steering wheel of a luxury car and wearing a famous watch, but the most eye-catching thing is the matte black manicure on his hands...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Who do you think it is when you see these pictures? A woman is sharing her latest manicures. In fact, the owners of these beautiful manicures are all men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Open a social media platform and search for &quot;boys&#39; manicure&quot; and you will open the door to a new world. More and more men are showing off their manicures on the Internet, just like showing off their latest clothes or new limited-edition shoes. Some are showing off the same manicure as a couple with their girlfriends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether it is a &quot;straight man&quot; with a big beard or a &quot;little fresh guy&quot; who is meticulous in dressing up, everyone does not worry about being criticized because of the manicure on their hands. People say &quot;girl&quot;, more and more men are enjoying the satisfaction brought by exquisite manicure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Style on the fingertips&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In modern times, doing manicure is a matter of one&#39;s will Things, but in ancient times, manicure was not something you could just do if you wanted to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In ancient Egypt, nail color symbolized personal identity and status. Archaeologists have discovered that Nefertiti, the legendary Egyptian beauty with great beauty and queen of Pharaoh Akhenaten, used henna plant juice to dye her fingernails and toenails rust red, symbolizing of nobility and power. Red manicure is exclusive to the royal family, and civilians are restricted to using light colors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more unexpected is that in ancient times, manicure was not an exclusive decoration for women. The history of men&#39;s manicure can be traced back to ancient Babylon around 3200 BC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, men had to do manicure before going to war. This was one of the important rituals. Soldiers will paint their nails in different colors according to their class: the upper ones will be painted black, and the middle ones will be painted green. They believe that this can intimidate the enemy and enhance morale. It can be seen from this that those who do manicures are the real macho men. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In ancient my country, manicure was also a symbol of class. As we all know, working people work with their hands, and there is no way to grow or dye nails. Therefore, manicures are mostly popular among ladies from famous families. Zhang Hu, a poet of the Tang Dynasty, wrote in a poem: &quot;The ten slender fingers are red as jade bamboo shoots, and the flying geese are gently restrained in the green strings.&quot; The &quot;red jade bamboo shoots&quot; in the sentence refers to the bright red nails painted with kodan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Are men in ancient my country insulated from manicures? Not necessarily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the north wall of Cave 335 of the early Tang Dynasty Dunhuang murals, the ministers in front of the emperor under the seat of Manjushri Bodhisattva have feathers on their heads, and one of them has his fingernails painted black. Not only that, the princes of ethnic minorities under the &quot;Vimalakīrti Sutra&quot; on the south side of the east wall of Cave 220 in the early Tang Dynasty in the Dunhuang murals, and the Uighur king and his attendants in the statue of the Xixia king on the south side of the east wall of Cave 409 of the Western Xia Dynasty, all have stained hands. nail. Some scholars believe that the color of fingernails should initially be red because the pigment gradually turns black due to long-term oxidation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be seen that &lt;/span>; from ancient times to the present, from China to the West, men’s manicure is not an unheard-of, absurd and weird thing. The &quot;hippie&quot; movement that was popular in the West in the 1960s and 1970s brought men&#39;s manicure into the field of popular culture. The representative figure of &quot;hippie&quot; culture, rock singer Bob Dylan, appears in public with bright and colorful manicure. British rock icon Mick Jagger also loves to show off his glossy black manicure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Under the guidance of these rock masters, fingernails, which are about 1 square centimeter in size, have gradually become a new position for men to express themselves and show their personality. On social media, many men share their manicures. Fashion trendsetters prefer bright black, tough lines, and graffiti patterns, while sophisticated men prefer everyday nude styles. Showing your own fashion style and trendy charm through personalized nail art styles has become a new way for men to express themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/e0288260745ac57acd46fb38166b5b2d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/e0288260745ac57acd46fb38166b5b2d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254162 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Manicure is an attitude towards life&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is a scene in the 15th episode of &quot;Friends&quot; Season 4. Chandler follows Rachel to the salon and is Rachel flirted with trying a manicure. Seeing all the women coming and going in the store, Chandler felt a little uncomfortable. While complaining that &quot;there are no other men here for manicures&quot;, he blew on the manicures. The micro-expressions on his face revealed his secret inner thoughts. . Rachel choked him back: &quot;Getting manicures won&#39;t hurt your masculinity!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In recent years, the &quot;appearance economy&quot; has exploded&lt;/span>;, and many Men are paying attention to their beauty needs. More and more people are using skin care products and going to beauty salons to receive beauty services. Abroad, it is very common for men to have manicures. Hammer &amp; Nails, a men&#39;s specialty store specializing in hand and foot care, already has more than 200 stores in the United States. Even during the 2021 COVID-19 pandemic, business revenue still maintained a huge growth of 270%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A survey by the Japanese beauty industry-related research organization &quot;HOTPEPPER Beauty Academy&quot; pointed out that in 2022, 5.7% of Japanese men have used manicure services, and on average, one person in less than 20 people has done so. Nail art, this has also hit a new high in the past five years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back at my country, data from the young people’s lifestyle platform “Little Red Book” shows that between July 2021 and June 2022, the number of searches for “men’s manicure styles” increased for half a year. A month-on-month increase of 302%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After experiencing the first manicure in his life, a man posted a post with emotion, &quot;I always thought it would be weird for boys to do manicures, but I didn&#39;t expect them to look good.&quot; He added #boymanicure It’s also a cool label; there are also men who said that their first manicure was brought to them by their girlfriends. After the experience, they exclaimed “it smells so good” and posted pictures of couple’s manicures to spread the word; there are also male fans. When I get a manicure, I think that after my nails are trimmed, polished, and painted with nude nail polish, my hands will look cleaner and more refined, making me more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internet social media provides technical support for people to construct their ideal self, and its rise has also made modern people&#39;s aesthetic standards gradually become symbolic. The popularity of manicures for men shows that manicures are gradually getting rid of the labels of &quot;exclusively for women&quot; and &quot;girly&quot;, and are endowed with social symbols such as &quot;cool&quot; and &quot;trendy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people are eyeing the trend of male manicure and are preparing to &lt;span>; take the plunge. According to Beiqing.com, Zhang, a student from the Academy of Fine Arts, started a business in a Shenzhen market. He set up a stall in the trunk of his car, specializing in male manicures. Similarly, a group of boys from Southwest Airlines Vocational College formed a club called &quot;Boy Manicure Group&quot; to provide manicure services to teachers and students. Classmate He Hao is a member of the club. He said, &quot;I feel great when I bring happiness and beauty to others!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For students like Zhang and He, In the eyes of generations of young people, beauty is gender-neutral. As an expression of the pursuit of beauty, manicure is also a form of artistic expression to a certain extent. &quot;On the road of pursuing art, we can enjoy ourselves as much as we can, and everyone who loves beauty is equal.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坠楼死亡的剖析》： 一部重在“关系”的电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2ZooYQNktZA0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2 ZooYQNktZA0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Palme d&#39;Or award-winning work &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; at the 2023 Cannes Film Festival is like a juggler throwing three balls at the same time. The execution is dazzling. It is both a strong plot thriller about an unsolved case and a family film about a broken marriage. In terms of scene presentation, it is also a legal drama in which all dramatic conflicts occur in the courtroom. Director Justine Trier is indispensable for being able to accomplish these three missions at the same time. The Cannes jury awarded her the grand prize undoubtedly in recognition of these visible advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the surface text, &quot;Analysis of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Falling from a Building&quot;&lt;/span>; ) also hides some more complex and even theoretical intellectual issues. How can we distinguish between truth and falsehood when we cannot grasp the whole story? When truth and narrative come into conflict, can we persist in our pursuit of the former, or will we be conquered by the emotional power of the latter? From &quot;Battle of Solferreno&quot; to &quot;Sibyl&quot;, director Trier has been obsessed with exploring the complex relationship between text and reality. However, in &quot;Falling&quot;, which seems to be a straightforward commercial genre film, she has pushed her reflection on &quot;narration&quot; to the extreme. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A famous bisexual female writer who is stuck in the quagmire of an unhappy marriage is seizing a rare opportunity to be interviewed by a girl from the literature department, and flirting with her ambiguously while drinking. But noisy music was playing upstairs at this moment: her husband - a man who had just resigned from his university teaching position and tried to write full-time like his wife - was aware of his wife&#39;s schedule and deliberately did not want his wife&#39;s (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Interview and Flirtation&lt;/span>;) plan succeeded. The interview had to be interrupted, and the girl and the son of the family left one after another to avoid the embarrassing and noisy situation. When the visually impaired son came home from a walk, the guide dog that led him first discovered the shocking fact: the music was still playing, the sun was still shining in the Alpine sky, but the child&#39;s father had blood all over his head. He fell into the snow and died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it suicide, accident or homicide? The medical examiner could not find sufficient evidence to prove or rule out any of these possibilities, so the only person present at the time of the incident, the deceased&#39;s wife Sandra, was accused of being a suspect and had to be investigated. In the next two hours of this film, we have to work with the judge, lawyers, jury and son Daniel who was unable to witness the scene to find the truth through our own eyes and clues provided by all parties. In this process, the relationship between Sandra and her husband Samuel will be cut into pieces and dismantled by a cold scalpel like the latter&#39;s corpse, and will face the most severe inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the overall setting, we can see the organizational structure of the entire film. This is an intricate network intertwined by various relationships. Everyone is trying to determine their position in the relationship with others, but they are often lost in the flow and change of relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;705&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;where The most eye-catching thing is naturally the relationship between Sandra and Samuel. Through the few words and fragments of evidence in the court, we can piece together some aspects of this relationship before Samuel&#39;s death: it was due to the uneven shouldering of family responsibilities between the two parties, the imbalance in the sense of worldly success, and the social and cultural differences between the two parties. Differences in background, different emotional appeals, and fundamental differences in personality and attitude towards life, gradually fell apart. We seem to be watching another &quot;Marriage Story&quot; or &quot;The Kramers&quot;. Neither party has made an unforgivable mistake. Everyone has their own reasons and difficulties. Even so, the two people who still love each other will still move forward. Resent and hurt each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But beneath the surface, the film also constructs a more subtle relationship: the relationship between the audience and the heroine. The legal drama format, which occupies most of the film, firmly places the audience in the position of the jury in the court. Through the guidance of facts, reasoning and emotions, we pour empathy into one of the prosecution and defense parties. And together they share the same hatred against the other party. As the truth continues to be revealed and lies continue to be exposed, our trust relationship with all parties is also undergoing subtle adjustments: at first, we will instinctively resent the inference of Sandra&#39;s guilt and the prosecutor&#39;s lawyer who questioned her; As the trial progresses, we discover that Sandra is not as honest as we first thought. As a result, the emotional balance shifts slightly: every word Sandra says from now on will be more questioned in our hearts. At the same time, every difficulty issued by the prosecutor, even including the various questions they raised before, It also makes more sense in our hindsight. The strategic game between the prosecution and the defense in the film is certainly exciting, but the psychological game between the director and the audience, based on the latter&#39;s emotional identification with the heroine, is closer to the focus of the entire film and allows the film to retain suspense. The secret to keeping it until the very last moment—and even until after the film is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At its true core, the film sets up ambiguous and complex relationships between texts of different materials. The entire film adopts a realistic audio-visual and narrative strategy, but whenever the prosecution and defense raise speculations and memories that cannot be verified by facts during the trial, the camera will start from the perspective of son Daniel sitting in the auditorium. It presents a &quot;psychological image&quot; with a highly subjective fantasy color. Sometimes it is a picture of the father committing suicide, and sometimes it is a picture of the mother punching the father in a rage. As these images accumulate, they finally become &quot;reality&quot; near the end of the film: Danielle testifies in person, reciting a suicidal monologue from his father&#39;s lifetime on the witness stand. However, the father&#39;s voice never appears in the flashback sequence shot by the director, and the son&#39;s narration also adds a bit of ambiguity that is indistinguishable from truth to falsehood because of this carefully placed misplaced detail. We can&#39;t help but wonder: Is this monologue his son&#39;s true memory, or is it a narrative he made up to the judge in order to save a family that is at risk of complete collapse? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film does not reveal the answer to us until the end. But the truth may not be very important. The judge was obviously emotionally moved by Daniel&#39;s words, and the situation was reversed. Sandra was acquitted, and Daniel also re-accepted this mother whom he might not trust, but loved enough. The most intriguing aspect of &quot;Falling&quot; is precisely related to its complex emotions towards &quot;narration&quot; itself: on the one hand, it retains ontological doubts about all narratives, but on the other hand, it unconditionally believes The emotional animal nature of human beings, thereby believing in the infinite power of narrative itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about &quot;narration&quot; confirms the significance of this film being able to exist independently from similar marriage stories; as for the truth of the entire case, it may only be grasped by that language that does not understand the language but is insightful. In the hearts of Border Collie Guide Dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 23:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当家中老人失能失智：关切老龄化引发的三大社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued the &quot;About Organizing and Carrying out Central Financial Support for the Central Financial Support for the Disabled Elderly People with Economic Difficulties&quot; &quot;Notice on Care Services&quot; stipulates that the recipients of assistance are tentatively designated as elderly people who have been included in the scope of minimum living security, have been assessed as completely disabled, and have voluntarily moved into a nursing home. The amount of assistance is the difference between the actual charges for staying in a nursing home after deducting the minimum living security allowance and two subsidies for persons with disabilities that the elderly have received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from a few years ago, there are more than 40 million disabled or semi-disabled elderly people in China, many of whom are also suffering from dementia, such as Alzheimer&#39;s disease. As the population ages, this number will only continue to increase. Data from the Ministry of Civil Affairs shows that as of the end of 2022, there were 280.04 million elderly people aged 60 and over in the country, accounting for 19.8%; among them, there were 209.78 million elderly people aged 65 and over, accounting for 14.9%, a year-on-year increase of 0.9 and 0.7 percentage points respectively. Increases of 12.68 million and 9.22 million. Due to China&#39;s sluggish fertility rate, the number of newborns has almost halved in six years, and the rate of social aging is quite fast. This has led to many social problems that require our serious concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the age and physical and mental conditions of the elderly, we can sort out the specific problems they face according to the timeline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, when the elderly are still &quot;younger elderly&quot;, their physical condition is generally better, and their ability to live, work and study has not significantly declined; there are also a few elderly people who have always been in good health and mentality. These two types of elderly people do not need or need the care of young adults for the time being and do not pose any social problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as we get older, our physical functions and mental abilities will continue to weaken. A considerable number of elderly people will be driven by the instinct of seeking life and hating death, and they will turn to health regimens that claim to help health and longevity. They are particularly keen on health care products and health care equipment. It is not uncommon for people who used to be very frugal and spend two cents of a penny to suddenly turn into buying and selling or even spend a lot of money; there are also a considerable number of elderly people who long for the warmth and affection of family. Although I have no children or my children are not around, I feel extremely lonely. Under the meticulous care and emotional attack of the sales staff, it is very refreshing to spend money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;elderly economy&quot; is essentially a careful hunt for the elderly and &quot;defrauds the elderly economy.&quot; The public prosecutor and the law should show their teeth and carry out a powerful crackdown to protect the legitimate rights and interests of the elderly. Children should also care about their parents&#39; mental and emotional needs, make more phone calls and spend more time with them; if possible, try to live with their parents so that parents can enjoy the rewards of raising children in their later years, so as to avoid the situation of &quot;the children want to be raised but the parents don&#39;t wait&quot; regret. In this regard, some young people may make reasonable remarks, such as &quot;small family&quot;, &quot;independent space&quot; and &quot;border&quot;. If you have never accepted or asked for a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult, and you have repaid your parents for their upbringing financially and emotionally, you may have the confidence to say this. But it is unjustifiable if you receive a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult and then refuse to fulfill reciprocal responsibilities. According to natural law and customary law, parents have the right to assert their own rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, now is the era of smartphones and mobile Internet, and many public transportation services, government services, and convenience services have become online and digital. A considerable number of elderly people have been left far behind in this era and have become &quot;digitally disabled groups&quot;. They do not use mobile phones or use simple-function elderly machines, cannot understand how to use those apps, and do not know how to make electronic payments. On the one hand, the government and enterprises should reserve non-digital service channels for the elderly and provide them with guidance in a conspicuous way; on the other hand, the platform should demonstrate social responsibility and launch an &quot;aging-friendly&quot; APP version to make the operation quick, simple and convenient. Older people get started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children should have patience and love for their digitally disabled parents, teach them to use the apps they need, or provide regular guidance and help, just like your parents patiently taught you ancient poems over and over again when you were a child. Like arithmetic, this is about feedback and feedback. In addition, parents should be alert to prevent telecommunications and network fraud, and should &quot;not give any personal information, do not give money, and do not cooperate with the other party in any operation.&quot; They should inform themselves when they have questions or before making major financial decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, as body functions and organs continue to age, the vast majority of the elderly will experience a stage of disability, semi-disability or even dementia. The resulting need for medical care will have a negative impact on the lives of their children. constitute a great challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national elderly care strategy is &quot;9073&quot;, that is, 90% of the elderly are provided with home care, 7% are provided with community care, and 3% are provided with institutional care. A 2023 Beijing survey found that more than 99% of the elderly in Beijing choose home care, while less than 1% choose institutional care. Therefore, except for some completely disabled elderly people who are supported by the government, the vast majority of disabled elderly people still rely on their children to take care of them. Children generally have to contribute both money and effort, and the most important part is contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disabled elderly people can only eat three meals a day in bed or in a wheelchair. If they lose the function of their hands or have dementia, they need to be fed, just like parents feeding themselves when they are one or two years old, and they must also help with defecation. , wipe your body or take a bath regularly; use a wheelchair to push outdoors on sunny days, so that the disabled elderly can enjoy the sunshine and breeze, feel happy and refresh their spirits; lying in bed for a long time, you must turn over regularly, otherwise the blood circulation will not be smooth, which will lead to vascular embolism or bedsores. ; If dementia is superimposed, it will be even more troublesome. Some elderly people will have delusions, become violent, and even smear feces all over the house, making it difficult to clean up. The odor will also attract complaints from neighbors... Disability and dementia For the elderly, it is generally impossible to hire a nanny to take care of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, as the mainstay of the family, you are in middle age, you have seniors and juniors, you have unlimited responsibilities on your shoulders, everyone relies on you and you have no one to rely on, this kind of pressure It&#39;s unprecedented. If you add a mid-life workplace crisis, it will be even more stressful. Therefore, as aging intensifies, this social problem will become more serious. But it is obviously difficult to solve this problem with a &quot;socialized&quot; system solution that transfers costs to society, unless robots are smart enough to replace human care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aging, two kinds of disability, and three major problems are all social problems that require serious consideration and treatment by the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[探访“山地之王”：高仙芝的高原足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259129]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 20:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQpFK5sNsyUlf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQp FK5sNsyUlf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aerial view of the Pamir Mountains&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, I set off from Kashgar and cycled along the Karakoram Highway to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir. Since my country’s Khunjerab Port does not allow cycling to pass customs, I need to take a transit bus in Taxkorgan County, check the bicycle as luggage, and continue riding after arriving at Khunjerab National Park on the Pakistani side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Khunjerab Pass is 4,783 meters above sea level. On one side of the border with my country is the wide-open and wide-open valley terrain of the eastern Pamir Plateau. The climate is arid and the vegetation is sparse. It is rare to see a tree at the foot of the mountain. Surrounded by a courtyard wall - it is a family of Tajik herders; entering Pakistan, it quickly transforms into a valley terrain with surging rapids - this is a canyon cut by the Hunza River in the southeastern part of the Pamir Plateau. It collided left and right in the mountain knot formed by the intersection of the Karakoram Mountains, Himalayas and Hindu Kush Mountains, and fell rapidly. From the border line of Khunjerab Pass to the entrance of Khunjerab National Park where Pakistan conducts border inspection, it is a short 40-kilometer journey, and the altitude drops by about one thousand meters; from the border inspection to Sost, the Pakistani port ), a distance of about 38 kilometers, and the altitude has dropped by nearly a thousand meters - which is naturally great news for cyclists. By the time I rode all the way downhill to the Ganish village in the eastern part of the Hunza Valley, the altitude had dropped to about 2,400 meters, which was only half of the Khunjerab Pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far south of Ganish, I saw a pedestrian rope bridge flying north and south over the raging Hunza River, and a warm current suddenly surged in my heart - more than 1,200 years ago , Gao Xianzhi, a famous general in the Tang Dynasty, used a similar rope bridge in the lower reaches of this river to block the way of the fierce enemy troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A pedestrian rope bridge over the Hunza River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;Kashmir&#39;s &quot;Great Game&quot;: Smoke and dust flying to the west of Jinshan Mountain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Gao Xianzhi rushed to the rope bridge, the prospect of the expeditionary force he commanded was not good: facing a surrendering enemy The fortified city, as well as a large number of enemy reinforcements coming all the way, while our own army has been on the march for more than three months, traveled more than 1,500 kilometers, and faced the extremely harsh geological and climatic conditions in Congling (&lt;em>; After continuous fighting in the wind and snow, the lone expeditionary force advanced deeply into the enemy&#39;s territory. They did not understand the language, had no siege equipment, lacked logistical supplies, and could not get reinforcements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a difficult situation may have been encountered by Alexander the Great during his legendary expedition to Asia and Europe. However, Alexander stationed his troops to the west of Congling and never crossed over. Gao Xianzhi&#39;s mission was precisely to cross the Congling to regain the lost territory. What&#39;s more, his military strength, animal power and material resources were far less than Alexander&#39;s expeditionary force. This may be why Gao Xianzhi later He was called the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot; by one of his rivals, Sahib jibal al-Sin. Sahib is the Turkic word for &quot;master&quot; , jibal is &quot;mountain&quot; in Arabic, and al-Sin is of China)&lt;/span>; reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi is a descendant of the Goguryeo royal family. His ancestors were the Fuyu people who emerged in the Hunjiang River Basin and the middle reaches of the Yalu River in Northeast China. &quot;Gao was their surname&quot; and established the Goguryeo regime during the Western Han Dynasty, which lasted seven hundred years. For a long time, it once occupied Liaodong to the southwest, and then crossed the Yalu River to the southeast and entered the Korean Peninsula. After the Goguryeo regime perished under the military attacks of the Sui and Tang dynasties, the Tang Dynasty moved the defeated Gao royal family to the Central Plains and Longyou. Gao Xianzhi followed his father Gao Sheji into the army and became a border guard in the Tang Dynasty. He grew up in the Hexi Corridor. He grew up in a military camp, and when he was a boy, he was transferred to the Anxi Protectorate with his father, which is today&#39;s southern Xinjiang, Pamir Plateau and Central Asia Hezhong region. He rose to prominence in his twenties and was promoted to general, the same level as his father. Later, he was further recognized by the leader of the Qiang people and the governor of Anxi, Meng Lingjin, and was promoted to deputy governor of Anxi and commander of the four towns. The horse envoy is equivalent to Fumeng Lingjin&#39;s deputy and the military chief of the entire southern Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth year of Tianbao&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (747 AD)&lt;/span>;, Gao Xianzhi received an edict from Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, appointing him In order to serve as a military envoy, I made my fourth expedition to Congling after the failure of my three predecessors to recapture Xiaobolu - the Pakistani-controlled Kashmir where I rode to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254967&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cycling in Hunza, Pakistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (Gilgit-Baltistan) is divided into two parts, Gilgit and Baltistan. The origin of the division can be traced back to the Greater and Lesser Bulu. The original name of this place was Boloristan, which means &quot;mountain country&quot;, where &quot;stan&quot; means &quot;country&quot; in Turkic language. Today, there are five &quot;stan&quot; countries in Central Asia, including Kazakhstan, and Pakistan in South Asia; Bolor means plateau and mountainous area - this place name is famous in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty and is translated as &quot;Bolu&quot;. It is the junction area of ​​the four kingdoms of Tang, Tubo, Tianzhu and Dashi, and is divided into the western and western regions. Xiao Bolu in the Sa Valley and Big Bolu in the upper reaches of the Indus River in the east - the goal of Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition was Xiao Bolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Big and Little Bolu were originally one country, and their territory included most of today&#39;s Pakistan-controlled Kashmir and the northern part of Indian-controlled Kashmir. It was a must-win place for Tubo in its Western Region strategy. At the beginning of the seventh century, Tubo annexed the ancient Shangshung Kingdom in the Ali region and unified the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. From then on, it began to implement its Western Region strategy based on the Ali region, and launched a nearly two-year-long war with the Tang Dynasty around Bolu, that is, the Kashmir region. The &quot;Great Game&quot; between Tang and Tibet for centuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hunza Valley&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tubo is backed by the Himalayas. It borders the Tang Dynasty in three directions: north, east and south. Why do we have to choose Kashmir to decide the outcome? Tubo initially launched the main attack on Datang on the Hehuang and Jiannan fronts, but failed to open up the situation. After occupying the Ngari region, Tibet tried to seize southern Xinjiang via the northern Qiangtang Prairie and across the Altyn Mountains. After being blocked again, they had to turn to expand northwest along the Shiquan River/Indus River Basin, intending to bypass the Himalayas and enter through the Ladakh region. Kashmir eventually joined forces with the Western Turks in the north to deal with the Tang Dynasty. In short, Tubo was like a lion trapped on a high platform. It was attacked head-on by the Tang army in Qinghai, Sichuan, Yunnan and Xinjiang. It was unable to get down to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. In the end, it had to choose to go down the mountain from Kashmir, where there was no Tang army, and take a detour. Congling attacked the western border of Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Belu Kingdom, located on this expansion route, became a &quot;soft persimmon&quot; that Tibet fought against with all its strength, and soon split into two countries: the Belu Homeland became a Tubo vassal state, known as &quot; The Great Burud&quot; was roughly located in today&#39;s Baltistan area; another royal family moved westward to the Hunza Valley and established the &quot;Little Burud&quot;, which was roughly located in today&#39;s Gilgit area, relying on the Hunza River and Gilgit The Te River&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(called Suyi River in ancient times)&lt;/span>; and the Indus River line up with deep valleys and natural chasms to resist the Tibetan invasion. King Xiao Bolu did not hesitate to send an envoy to ask for help from the Tang Dynasty, saying that Bolu was the gateway to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty. If it fell, all the countries in the Western Regions would fall to Tubo, and the Western Regions would no longer be controlled by the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Bo Lu, Ximen of the Tang Dynasty. If he loses it, all the Western countries will fall to Tubo)&lt;/span>;, and was finally canonized by Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty and became the Tang Dynasty Subject to the country. In the tenth year of Kaiyuan (722 AD), the Beiting Protectorate of the Tang Army sent 4,000 cavalry reinforcements to Xiaobolu to attack Xiaobolu. He repelled the attack of the Tibetan army and won nearly twenty years of peace for Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 740 AD, Tubo instigated the Tuqishi Khanate in the northern grasslands to rebel against the Tang Dynasty through marriage, and contained the main force of the Tang army in the Western Regions in the northern Xinjiang. On this occasion, he proposed to Xiao Bolu to &quot;borrow a road&quot; and build a rope bridge on the Suyi River. The Tubo army, which successfully crossed the natural barrier of the Suyi River, immediately turned against the foreigners and occupied Xiaobolu. King Su Feng of Xiaobolu was forced to marry the Tibetan princess, and together with more than 20 surrounding small countries, they rebelled against Tang and surrendered to Tibet. The Tibetan army was able to occupy the entire Bolu and get a glimpse of Congling: they captured Lianyun Fort, the fortress of the Tang army guarding the Wakhan Valley, the main road to Congling, opening the way to the north to Central Asia to make friends with the Turks, and cutting off the capital of Anxi. The road from Hufu to the Zhaowu Kingdoms in the Hezhong region also formed a condescending military advantage over the four Anxi towns of the Tang Dynasty located in the Tarim Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the unfavorable situation that a gap was opened in the defense line of the Western Region, the Anxi Protectorate had to concentrate all its efforts in order to regain Bolu and block the &quot;downhill&quot; channel of Tubo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The barren and pure river valley in Hunza region&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Recovering the Wakhan Valley: The captives should be frightened after hearing this&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the most convenient way to go from China&#39;s Pamir Plateau to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir is to go south along the Hunza Valley, or That is to say, follow the Karakoram Highway, which was historically one of the important passages along the southern route of the Silk Road to South Asia. It’s just that in ancient times, caravans used to go through the Mingtie Gaidaban, and when China and Pakistan planned and built the Karakoram Highway in the 1960s, in order to avoid the military threat of the Soviet Union—Tajikistan, which today occupies most of the Pamir Plateau, was Afghanistan, a republic of the Soviet Union, was also under Soviet hostage at the time. The Soviet army deployed an army division in the Wakhan Valley and built missile launch sites and airports. It was eyeing my country&#39;s southern Xinjiang - so it chose the east of Mingtie Gaida Ban. , far away from the Sino-Soviet border and the Khunjerab Pass with complex mountains to achieve better strategic concealment. The cost is that the China-Pakistan Highway on the Pakistani side has a large gap and is easily damaged by natural disasters such as landslides and mudslides. For example, in 2010, a landslide formed a barrier lake, causing the China-Pakistan Highway to be interrupted for five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Gao Xianzhi went on an expedition to Xiaobolu, he neither took the Mingtiegaida Ban nor the Hongqilafu Pass, because this line of mountainous terrain was already controlled by the Tibetan army at that time. If he took these passes, it would be difficult. Faced with the huge risk of being attacked from the front and rear by the Tibetan army stationed in Lianyunbao, cutting off the food route. Therefore, what he chose was to first pull out Lianyunbao, the nail that was driven into the Congling Mountains, and then go south through the Yasin Valley parallel to it on the west side of the Hunza Valley, and attack Xiaobolu in a roundabout way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lianyun Fort in the Tang Dynasty was located in Sarhad, the last village in eastern Afghanistan today. It guarded the east entrance of the Wakhan Valley, and continued eastward into the Sino-Afghan border area. desert areas. The Wakhan Valley, also known as the Penchi Valley or the Wakhan Corridor, is a valley between the Pamir Plateau and the Hindu Kush Mountains. It stretches more than 600 miles from east to west and is an important cultural passage in the history of China and India. An important part of the southern route of the Silk Road. Zhang Qian of the Han Dynasty &quot;emptied out the Western Region&quot; and went through Congling to the Hezhong area to search for the Dayue clan; nearly 120 years before Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition to Xiaobolu&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;(629 AD)&lt;/span>;, &quot;Tang Monk&quot; Xuanzang crossed the Wakhan Valley into South Asia after seven days and nights; the two great empires of Britain and Russia in modern times launched the &quot;Great Game&quot; in Central Asia, and finally used this As the dividing line and isolation zone between the north and the south, the valley demarcated the respective spheres of influence of the two countries, thus introducing the name &quot;Wakhan Corridor&quot;, and generously arbitrarily assigned this then Chinese territory to Afghanistan. It became an abrupt appendix at the eastern end of Afghanistan&#39;s territory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tibet defended the Lianyunbao Fortress at the east entrance of the Wakhan Valley, &quot;weaving wood into a city based on mountains and rivers, cuttings and cliffs in the valley&quot;. To the east, you can enter southern Xinjiang along the Taxkorgan Valley, and to the north you can cross The Pamir Plateau enters Central Asia. To the west, you can bypass the Hindu Kush Mountains and enter South Asia, or you can go to the Transoxiana region along the Pench River. To the south, you can rely on the Hindu Kush Mountains to protect the newly occupied Big and Little Burrows. It can be said that it is connected in all directions. , strategic location. In order to fight steadily, Gao Xianzhi must first clear out the Tubo advance position, and then go south to regain Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was unable to go to the Wakhan Valley to visit Lianyunbao in person, so I had to first take the China-Pakistan Highway to reach the small Buludu city of Gilgit - today&#39;s capital of Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (Gilgit), and then walk along the Gao Xianzhi&#39;s march route went in the opposite direction, first going westward along the Gilgit River, then northward along its tributary Yasin Valley, and reaching the southern slope of the Hindu Kush Mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tashkorgan Stone City&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the old and new Tang books According to records, Gao Xianzhi commanded 10,000 infantry - equivalent to half of the mobile troops of the Anxi Protectorate - from Qiuci in the fourth lunar month of 747 AD >; (Today&#39;s Kuqa)&lt;/span>; Set out and spent more than a month along the southern foot of Tianshan Mountains via Diazhuangcheng &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Aksu)&lt;/ span>;, hold Sede&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Bachu)&lt;/span>; and go west to Shule&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Today&#39;s Kashgar)&lt;/span>;, and mobilized some border guard cavalry along the way, and then followed the Taxkorgan River Valley southward to Congling to guard the capture&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Shouchu&quot; is a small military town in the Tang Dynasty)&lt;/span>;, which is the stone city outside Taxkorgan County today - &quot;Tash&quot; means &quot;stone&quot; in Turkic language. In the first ten days of the seventh lunar month, the Tang army, together with about 20,000 vassal troops from the Western Regions, crossed the Congling Mountains and arrived at Telemanchuan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now Khorog, Tajikistan )&lt;/span>;. Gao Xianzhi divided his troops into three groups here. He led the main force of the Tang army back to the west side of Lianyun Fort. He also sent two groups of troops from Kashgar and Aksu to surround Lianyunguo from the north and east respectively. It was agreed on the 13th day of the seventh lunar month. A surprise attack was launched at the same time at day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historical records show that the Tubo army held on to the mountain and rolled logs and stones to &quot;cover the sky&quot;, making it difficult for the Tang army to succeed. Gao Xianzhi issued a strict order to his brave generals Li Siye and Tian Zhen: &quot;If we don&#39;t reach the sun, we must break the enemy!&quot;. The &quot;Old Book of Tang&quot; once wrote a biography of Li Siye, saying that he was born in the military and was &quot;seven feet long and extremely brave.&quot; Facing the intensive defense of the defenders, he and Tian Zhen held the double-edged Mo Dao and led a troop of Mo Dao soldiers. The commando team found another way and &quot;climbed first at the most dangerous place&quot;, that is, climbed up from the cliff that the Tubo defenders did not expect, and rushed into the enemy&#39;s stronghold from a high position. As expected, they captured the building before noon, which was garrisoned by more than 10,000 Tubo troops. , a fortress with a compound defense system composed of mountain fortresses and mountain foot camps, beheaded 5,000 people, captured more than 1,000 people, and won the largest tough battle of the expedition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tang army recaptured Lianyun Fort, drove the Tubo out of Congling, and regained the Wakhan Valley, the passage connecting the Western Regions. The next step was to cross the Hindu Kush Mountains, recapture Xiaobolu, and clear out the The threat of the Tibetan army to the Wakhan Valley. It was mid-August at that time. Today&#39;s Wakhan Corridor is only passable from June to August of the year. The mountains are blocked by heavy snow at other times. The climate in the Tang Dynasty was also the same. Presumably considering the weather factors, Gao Xianzhi did not delay at Lianyun Fort, leaving more than 3,000 weak soldiers behind. He led his elite infantry to march lightly and quickly, and ran for three days and nights, arriving at Darkut Pass (Darkut Pass, &lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today&#39;s translation is Dakot Pass). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wakhan Corridor, with the Hindu Kush Mountains in the background. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Crossing the Hindu Kush: The vast sea is covered with hundreds of feet of ice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Pakistan and Afghanistan are bounded by the Hindu Kush Mountains in the Wakhan Corridor. This Persian name was first seen in the narrative of the medieval Arab traveler Ibn Battuta. It is literally translated as &quot;Hindu (Hindu Kush)&quot;. &quot;Hindu&quot; killer (Kush)&quot;, which means that a large number of Indian slaves captured from the hot areas of South Asia froze to death while crossing this high and cold mountain; some people also interpret it as the &quot;Mountain of India&quot;, which means crossing southward This mountain range enters the Indian subcontinent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tanjuling Pass is located in the eastern section of the Hindu Kush Mountains, but it is not a pass that runs through this mountain range - because there are two watersheds and two mountain passes here. The eastern end of the Hindu Kush Mountains originates from the Pamir Plateau and has the characteristics of mountain twists and turns. It is divided into parallel north and south branches near the Tanju Ridge: the north branch is the border line between Pakistan and Afghanistan, and south of the south branch is the north and south branches. The Yasin River Valley runs east-west, while the Yarkhun River runs east-west between the north and south branches. Tanjuling Pass is a pass on the South Branch, with an altitude of 4688 meters. There are glaciers on both sides of the pass, making it difficult to cross. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So is there any other way? In fact, there is. After crossing the northern branch of the Hindu Kush Mountains, you can go west along the Yakun Valley, bypass the southern branch, and then cross the famous Shandur Pass (Shandur) eastward into the Gilgit Valley, and then you can go down the river to Xiaobo. law. However, this route is still extremely rugged and difficult to travel today in the 21st century. There are no paved roads in the Yaquin Valley. Most of the road sections are simple gravel roads located on steep cliffs and halfway up the mountain, and can only accommodate one vehicle passing through at low speeds. I was going to get a flat tire every minute, so I had to store my bike and hire a motorcyclist to take me into the Yaquin Valley. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shandur Pass is the birthplace of polo. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is conceivable that the road conditions here 1,300 years ago would have been much worse than now. If Gao Xianzhi led his troops to go around the Yakun Valley, it would probably take an extra month to go. It would be mid-to-late September. The Tibetan reinforcements were already waiting in Xiaobolu Yiyi, and the Hindu Kush Mountains and the Pamir Plateau would soon be It will be impassable due to the severe cold, which means that the Tang army&#39;s return route will be cut off - I guess this is why Gao Xianzhi decided to race against time and led his army to risk crossing the Tanjuling Pass &quot;straight down for more than forty miles.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the soldiers who serve as soldiers and eat food do not have such strategic insight. After finally climbing up the ice and snow to Tanju Ridge, they looked at the rolling glaciers at their feet and asked Gao Xianzhi in panic: &quot;Where does the ambassador want me to go?&quot; - &quot;Ambassador&quot; is the honorific title given to Jiedushi in the Tang Dynasty - —Do you want us to slide down from the top of such a steep glacier? Are you taking us to Little Bolu or Yama Hall? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thousands of years ago, Stein, a British-Hungarian explorer, wrote after an on-site inspection of Gao Xianzhi’s march route: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I stood From the shimmering snow at the top of the mountain pass, peering down to the steep slopes that lead to the end of the Yasin Valley at 6,000 feet, we can understand why the Tang army refused to move forward at first, how difficult it was for them to struggle forward later, and how brave Gao Xianzhi was. clear! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1200&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tanjuling&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Gao Xianzhi Soldiers cannot be driven by personal bravery. He anticipated the weakness of human nature and knew that soldiers did not dare to climb the ice and go deep into the enemy&#39;s territory, so he quietly sent more than 20 of his trusted aides, dressed in Berrut clothing, to climb up Tanju Ridge in advance to wait for the large army. While the soldiers of the Tang Dynasty were wondering on the top of the mountain, these impostors came forward with smiles, claiming to be the defenders of Xiaobolu stationed opposite the mountain pass. They came to surrender to the king on behalf of the defenders of Anuyue City. Bo Lu has cut off the only way for Tibetan reinforcements to pass. This great (&lt;em>;false&lt;/em>;) news made the soldiers of the Tang Dynasty suddenly feel that victory was in sight, so they obeyed the general&#39;s order with confidence and crossed Tanju Ridge and entered the Yasin Valley. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to historians’ research, Anuyue City is located in today’s Gupis Town, where the Yasin River merges into the Gilgit River. The biggest pass on the way to the capital. I cycled along the paved road from Gilgit to Chitral. When a primary school on the roadside was getting out of school, three to five hundred girls wearing black hijabs happily poured out of the school gate&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(local boys and girls each attend half-day school)&lt;/span>;, which temporarily blocked the road. After they dispersed into the streets, I saw the chain bridge built with Chinese aid on the north side of the highway across the fast-flowing Gilgit River. After crossing the bridge and going up the river a short distance away, I could see a clear tributary flowing from the northwest. Entering the big river, it is the Yasin River, which is formed by melting snow from Tanjuling Glacier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Yasin Valley under Tanju Ridge&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conga The total distance from Nuyue City to the southern foot of Tanju Ridge at the source of the Yasin River is nearly 70 kilometers. It is also an unpaved simple dirt road. It took me three hours to arrive by car. Gao Xianzhi led his army over the mountains and ridges. Four days. When there was only one day left on the mountain road, good news came: Anuyue City had really sent an envoy to greet the Tang army. Perhaps the guard knew that the main force of the Tibetan army had been gathered and annihilated in Lianyun Fort, and the Tang army had crossed the dangerous Tanju Ridge. The Suyi River could no longer stop its troops, so they decided to surrender to the Tang Army in Kaicheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what came to my mind was another scene: the Tang army soldiers looked at the two groups of Hu people in surprise. They both claimed to be the defenders of Anuyue City, and both claimed to be surrendering, but each other I don’t know each other, and I can’t communicate with them. The latter group had a Persian look, with their high noses and deep eyes, but the former group looked similar to me. They spoke in a nonsensical way and looked at each other awkwardly...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cut the Indus Valley: Ximen, the charioteer, stands to show off his victory&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from Anuyue City, go east along the Suyi River to Niduo, the capital city of Xiaobolu, the distance is about One hundred and ten kilometers. Niduo City is located at the intersection of the Hunza Valley and the Sui River Valley. The original site of the city is unknown, but according to historical records, it should be located on the west bank of the Sui River. Today it is Gilgit, the capital of Pakistan-occupied Kashmir and is named after the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About sixty miles further down the Sui River from Niduo City is the mouth of the Sui River where it merges into the Indus River. From there, going down the Indus River is what was known in ancient times as the &quot;Land of Five Rivers&quot;. &quot;Punjab Plain&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Punjab&quot; means &quot;Five Rivers&quot; in Hindi)&lt;/span>; - the five rivers originate from the Himalayas The tributaries at the southern foot of the mountain range merge into the Indus River one after another, forming a fertile alluvial plain that gave birth to ancient Indian civilization. From here, you can go upstream and pass through the spectacular grand canyon from the river mouth to Skardu. You can enter Dabolu and finally cross the Himalayas to reach the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Karakoram Highway goes south along the platform on the right side of the Hunza River, Gilgit River and Indus River, taking a beautiful U-shaped bend near the mouth of the Gilgit River and descending to the shore. Then cross the Gilgit River through a road bridge, and on the other side is Highway S1, which leads along the Indus River to the India-Pakistan confrontation area in Kashmir. Its strategic value is very important. During Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition, a rope bridge made of rattan was built where the highway bridge is now. It was built by Tibet by tricking Xiao Bolu into &quot;borrowing the road&quot;. It is &quot;one arrow wide&quot;, which means that the span of the vine bridge reaches the archery range of the time - about two hundred meters. This vine bridge is the only way for the Tibetan army to pass from Dabolu to Xiaobolu and even north to Congling. It can be said to be the key to the throat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was said that Gao Xianzhi led his army to Niduo City, and the Xiaobolu nobles who were loyal to Tibet held on to the capital and refused to let the Tang army enter the city. Gao Xianzhi fell into the dilemma described at the beginning of this article: if Niduo City is not captured as soon as possible, once the Tibetan reinforcements arrive, the Tang army, which has lost its retreat, will inevitably fall into a pincer attack from both sides and be surrounded and annihilated under Niduo City in the coming severe winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Gao Xianzhi did not assume the posture of attacking the city - of course, he did not have the manpower and material resources to storm the fortified city. The top commander of the expeditionary force first sent an envoy to stabilize King Xiaobolu, claiming that the Tang army neither planned to attack the city nor destroy the Tengqiao, but intended to pass through the Tengqiao to attack the Tibetan army of Dabolu; secondly, he used The gold and silver property lured the pro-Tibet nobles who guarded the city, and tricked them into the Tang camp and beheaded them all; and the most important task, Gao Xianzhi handed over to the pioneer Xi Yuanqing: rush to the mouth of the Suyi River to destroy the Tengqiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The road from Niduo City to the mouth of the Suyi River was a military road laid by the Tibetan army. The road condition must be good, but by the time Xi Yuanqing marched sixty miles to Tengqiao, the sun had already set on the snow peak on the west side of the canyon. behind. In the deep dusk, he saw a flock of birds flying in the mountains opposite, and smoke and dust rising up - that was another army coming at full speed. Xi Yuanqing didn&#39;t waste any time and immediately ordered his soldiers to cut off the cane together. As soon as Tengqiao fell into the extremely fast Suyi River, which the ancients called weak water, a large group of Tibetan reinforcements rushed to the other side. Unfortunately, it was too late to cross the river. GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Old Book of Tang&quot;: It was late in the evening, and it was just cut. The Tubo soldiers and horses arrived, and it was no longer possible). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254976&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The fast-flowing Suyi River is also called weak water. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This vine bridge took a year to build. Now the Tang army controls the west bank, and Tubo The army could not rebuild the vine bridge, and it was impossible to cross the river on foot. They had no choice but to look at the river and sigh, then returned to Dabolu dejectedly. The Tubo side&#39;s &quot;Dunhuang Tubo Documents·Chronicle of Major Events&quot; records this under the entry of the Year of the Pig in the Tibetan Calendar: Bolu Kingdom, Kodi )&lt;/span>;The defenders were defeated by the Tang people and the defenders fell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, the Tubo defenders were annihilated, the Tubo reinforcements were blocked, and the pro-Tubo faction was killed. The defeat of Xiaobolu King Su suddenly became the party that was besieged on all sides and had to surrender to Gao Xianzhi. The king and his Tibetan queen were sent to Chang&#39;an as prisoners, while Xiao Bolu was renamed the Quy Nhon Army and guarded here by a thousand Tang troops. The entire battle to recapture Xiaobolu lasted four months, but the actual combat process lasted only more than ten days. Except for the half-day bloody battle at Lianyun Castle, it could be said that the victory was achieved without any bloodshed in Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stein once commented: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A large number of armies passed through the Pamirs and Hindu Kush. Make this your first time. The mountains were high and there was a lack of supplies. I wonder how to maintain the supply of the army at that time? Even the modern general staff headquarters would be helpless... This brave Chinese general marched through more dangerous and difficult terrain. Compared with the famous European generals, from Hannibal to Napoleon to Suvorov, they crossed the Alps. , I really don’t know how many times more than that. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ultar Glacier and Baltit Castle in the Hunza Valley&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Epilogue: A place for horse riding in the sky above the snow&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ten Years of Tianbao&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (AD 751), Gao Xianzhi was transferred from the Anxi Protectorate. Two years later, the new Anxi Jiedushi Feng Changqing, the successor he single-handedly promoted from Cao Mang, sent troops to recapture Dabolu, thereby completely cutting off the Tibetan invasion of the four towns of Anxi via Bolu and Congling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this battle was the last expansion of the Tang Dynasty in the Western Regions. Only two years later, the Anshi Rebellion broke out, and the Central Plains fell into raging war. The Tang Dynasty, which was on the verge of extinction, was no longer able to manage the Western Regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, Tubo also changed its strategy against the Tang Dynasty. When faced with the strong troops of the Tang Dynasty, it detoured to Bolu to attack one of its four towns in Anxi. Instead, it used the Tang Dynasty to repeatedly mobilize Hexi elites to quell rebellions in the interior, which led to local rebellions. With the opportunity of empty troops, they resumed their main attack on the Hehuang area, seizing the Hexi Corridor connecting the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty and the Central Plains, and then defeated the towns and countries in the Western Regions that had lost contact and were isolated. The ruling system of the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty collapsed. By the beginning of the ninth century, the Anxi Protectorate had completely fallen, and the north and south of the Tianshan Mountains were not re-incorporated into the territory of my country until the Qianlong period of the Qing Dynasty. Therefore, it was called &quot;Xinjiang&quot;, which means &quot;new return to the homeland&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for why Gao Xianzhi was transferred out of the Western Regions at the height of his military power, that is another story of ups and downs. &lt;p>; The two moved to the Western Regions and traveled all over the north and south of the Tianshan Mountains.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>