<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“很多男生一个引体向上都做不了”——部分高校大学生身体素质下降现象调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261292]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I was dangling on the horizontal bar and couldn’t pull up even a pull-up. I ran 800 meters in more than 5 minutes. Mi went upstairs and her legs were trembling...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from &quot;Xinhua Viewpoint&quot; recently visited some colleges and universities and found that the physical fitness of some students is worrying. Many boys find it difficult to do pull-ups and cannot do long jumps while standing. Many students lack explosive power in sprinting and have a &quot;fear of long-distance running.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Basic Standards for Physical Education in Colleges and Universities&quot; issued by the Ministry of Education in 2014 requires strengthening the management of physical education in schools, innovating education and teaching methods, guiding students to exercise scientifically, conducting physical health tests on all students every year, and guiding students Carry out targeted physical exercise. How to implement relevant requirements and continuously improve the physical fitness of college students? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;No energy&quot; &quot;Can&#39;t run&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;40% of the boys in our school failed to score in the pull-up event in the physical test, and many boys could not do any of them. The excellent rate of physical tests is declining every year.&quot; The person in charge of the physical education department of a university in Shandong said that more than ten years ago, most of the boys You can get 10 or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter once went to Yunnan University to conduct on-site research on the physical examination class. Most of the boys&#39; 1000-meter scores were below the passing mark; a girl in a certain class ran 800 meters, and in the last 50 meters, it was obviously very difficult. After crossing the finish line, she bent her back with a painful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/fabf0c9660d9229a8ec8f53802c8c9ce.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259555&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In November 2021, girls from Yunnan University ran 800 meters. (Imposed photo) Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin, director of the Key Laboratory of Sports and Physical Health of the Ministry of Education at Beijing Sport University, once participated in the revision of the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and has long been concerned about the physical fitness of college students. Health status. &quot;Even though the passing standards for some projects have been lowered based on the students&#39; physical condition, the physical test results are still unsatisfactory,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin said that taking the university men&#39;s 1,000 meters as an example, the 60-minute pass in 1989 was 3 minutes and 55 seconds, and in 2014 it was 4 minutes and 32 seconds, a decrease of 37 seconds. This is equivalent to the fact that students who just passed the long-distance race in 1989 have reached the finish line, while students in 2014 are still running hundreds of meters away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the results of the Eighth National Student Physical Fitness and Health Survey released by the Ministry of Education showed that college students’ physical fitness is seriously declining, and problems such as obesity and lack of endurance are prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A physical education teacher in Beijing said that in order to avoid physical examinations, some students will buy &quot;medical records&quot; and pretend to be sick to take leave, claiming that they have hydrops in the knee joints and meniscus damage. &quot;We cannot distinguish the authenticity of the &#39;medical records&#39; one by one, and we are also afraid that students will have accidents, so the number of students exempted from the test remains high.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some students even find &quot;shooters&quot; to pass the physical test. The reporter saw on social media that some college students posted &quot;asking for a substitute test&quot; or &quot;take the test&quot;, mainly focusing on middle and long-distance running and other events. Some college students said that on the one hand, they are looking for a &quot;substitute&quot; because of their poor physical fitness, and on the other hand, because the physical test scores are linked to the evaluation of excellence and awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Why has physical fitness declined? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s investigation found that the decline in physical fitness of college students is not only due to students’ unwillingness to exercise, but also related to the fact that some colleges and universities do not pay attention to physical tests and have unreasonable physical education classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities do not strictly implement the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot; and do not pay attention to physical tests. According to the &quot;National Student Physical Health Standards&quot;, when students from ordinary high schools, secondary vocational schools and ordinary colleges and universities graduate, those whose test scores do not reach 50 points will be treated as completed or dropped out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the sports department of many colleges and universities said that due to various considerations, this regulation is not strictly implemented in many colleges and universities, and some even directly ignore it, causing students to have psychological problems with physical exercise and testing. slack off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimin revealed that in response to random inspections and reviews of college students&#39; physical health tests, some colleges and universities learned that when the expert team came, they would specifically look for students with good sports scores to cooperate, resulting in distortion of the physical test data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some colleges and universities have unreasonable physical education courses. To improve the physical quality of college students, college physical education classes play an indispensable role. The reporter&#39;s investigation found that the current physical education courses in many colleges and universities are similar, out of touch with the sports needs of college students, and affect their enthusiasm for class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nowadays, physical education classes basically still take track, field, football, basketball, etc. on the playground, which is similar to more than ten years ago.” Some college students reported that young people now like yoga, exercise for fat loss, and outdoor development. There are almost no such &quot;new physical education classes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhang Yimin, compared with the physical education and health curriculum standards for primary and secondary school students, there is no unified curriculum standard for physical education classes in colleges and universities. Many undergraduate colleges usually only offer physical education classes in the first and second grades, and students have obviously insufficient time for physical exercise and poor results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Education’s student physical health sampling review data shows that as of 2020, the failure rate of college students is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Some college students are not willing to exercise. The interviewed physical education teacher said that some students were playing mobile phones on the side of the playground during physical education class. “In the past, students were often seen fighting for space on the football field, but now there are only a few people here and there.” “During morning exercise time, there are very few students doing exercise”…&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Li Jinglei, a graduate student at a university in Shandong, said that there are no physical education classes at the graduate level of the school, and sports are all dependent on individuals. Only one-tenth of the students in the class do regular physical exercise, and even if they want to play basketball, there are not enough people. Either it’s too hot in the summer and too cold in the winter, or there are other entertainment activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some college students interviewed even said: &quot;If you are too lazy to walk to the cafeteria to eat, why do you exercise?&quot; &quot;How can you go for a morning jog when you can&#39;t even get up to attend professional classes at 8 o&#39;clock in the morning?&quot; Is it fun or is surfing the Internet boring?&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Take multiple measures to improve the physical fitness of college students&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewee said, Improving the physical fitness of college students not only requires &quot;self-pressure&quot; of college students, but also requires the joint promotion of relevant departments and schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts said that relevant standards should be strictly implemented to increase students&#39; attention. In 2021, the &quot;strictest physical education regulations&quot; issued by Yunnan University have triggered heated discussions on the Internet: starting from freshmen enrolling in the fall of 2021, if they fail the physical test in any academic year, they will not receive a diploma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not the first initiative of Yunnan University, but a regulation of the Ministry of Education.” Wang Zongping, dean of the School of Physical Education of Yunnan University, said that after the school strictly implemented relevant regulations, the passing rate of students’ physical examinations has increased significantly, from 2018 to 2018. 68.6% increased to 90.3% in 2022. &quot;Now students pay more and more attention to physical exercise. Every night at eight or nine o&#39;clock, they can be seen exercising on the school playground.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/6f013ab51d63be9baab170a213fc67bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259556&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On November 21, 2023, the male 1000-meter physical test site of Yunnan University. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Ranran&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Bo, director of the Physical Education Department of Tsinghua University, suggested that schools can offer more special courses based on their own conditions to help students increase their interest in sports. At present, Tsinghua University insists on offering physical education courses for four-year undergraduate students, involving more than 50 courses such as competitive sports, leisure sports, traditional ethnic sports and physical therapy courses, and offers sports elective courses for graduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the composition and evaluation methods of physical education classes should be optimized to prevent falsification of physical tests. Cheng Shouyun, a physical education teacher at Hefei University of Technology, said that the school has carried out an integrated reform of physical education inside and outside the classroom, and has included &quot;physical fitness&quot; as one of the required modules in the &quot;Second Classroom Transcript&quot; as a hard indicator for student graduation. Physical education class scores are linked to students&#39; extracurricular exercise. Class tests and final assessments in physical education classes account for 60 points, theoretical study accounts for 10 points, extracurricular fitness accounts for 30 points, and running exercises in extracurricular fitness account for no less than 60%. Other appointments can be made through the smart system Sports should not exceed 40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prevent fraud such as taking exams on behalf of others, Hefei University of Technology adopts the method of verifying student ID cards, and the test can only be carried out when the person and ID are combined; Anhui University uses dual authentication of ID card and facial recognition detection. Once a substitute exam is found, The phenomenon will be investigated seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is particularly important to integrate physical education with education to develop good exercise habits. At Tsinghua University, undergraduate freshmen will gather together to experience the sports tradition and spirit of &quot;without sports, there would be no Tsinghua University&quot; through the &quot;First Physical Education Lesson&quot;. There are also many students who have found their favorite sports and gained their own sense of accomplishment and belonging by participating in the Freshman Barefoot Games and Campus Marathon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Colleges and universities can help students master 1 to 2 sports skills and develop lifelong exercise habits through measures that suit their own characteristics, and create a campus that is open to all students, runs through the entire process, and educates people in all aspects Sports culture.&quot; Liu Bo said: &quot;The inherent educational value of physical exercise can be transformed into excellent qualities promoted in social life, which will benefit students throughout their lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 12:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国全额缴清联合国会费，缴费比例33年增长19倍丨漫热点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261308]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;776&quot; height=&quot;10000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/1e46a127c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259589&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[凯雷出售“麦当劳中国”：新基金募集压力“倒逼”项目退出？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261290]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Carlyle, a large global PE institution, once again &quot;takes action&quot;, but this time he is selling assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, McDonald&#39;s Global agreed to acquire Carlyle&#39;s 28% stake in McDonald&#39;s China Mainland, Hong Kong and Macau Strategic Cooperation Company (hereinafter referred to as &quot;McDonald&#39;s China&quot;). After the transaction is completed, McDonald&#39;s Global, as a minority shareholder, will increase its shareholding ratio from 20% to 48%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the acquisition requires regulatory approval and is expected to be completed in the first quarter of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, the acquisition price is US$1.8 billion, and Carlyle will receive a return of approximately 6.7 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If it weren’t for the current VC/PE market project withdrawal slump, Carlyle might have been able to sell it at a higher price.” A partner from a domestic PE institution lamented to reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters have learned from various sources that the industry generally believes that Carlyle’s sale of McDonald’s China shares at a relatively low price is likely to be closely related to the current difficulty in exiting VC/PE market projects and its sluggish performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of November, Carlyle announced its third quarter financial report of this year, which showed that the total revenue for the quarter was only US$562 million, a simultaneous decrease of about 50%, and the net profit was only US$81.3 million, a year-on-year decrease of 71.05%. The main reason for Carlyle&#39;s revenue decline in the quarter was that it was difficult to exit projects, which resulted in a 76% drop in performance income from exited investment projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Carlyle’s fundraising scale this year has been basically the same as in 2022, but far lower than the same period in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“To change this situation, Carlyle urgently needs more project exit cases, but given the current sluggish IPO market and the increased risk of a U.S. economic recession, Carlyle may have to sell at a lower price More high-quality projects and create more project exit cases to win LPs’ commitment to Carlyle’s new fund.” Analyzed the partner of a domestic PE institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, project mergers and acquisitions between industrial capital and PE are quite common during periods of increased macroeconomic fluctuations. However, this time industrial capital had the upper hand in M&amp;A negotiations because during the previous period when the Federal Reserve implemented extremely loose monetary policies, industrial capital raised a large amount of funds by issuing bonds or borrowing from banks at extremely low interest rates; in comparison, PE However, due to the sluggish IPO market and the sharp interest rate hikes by the Federal Reserve in recent years, institutions have encountered difficulties in project exit and new fund raising. As a result, PE institutions have to sell high-quality assets to industrial capital at low prices to create more project exit cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nowadays, industrial capital with abundant funds has become the taker for PE institutions eager to exit the project, but the former will also force the PE institutions to make more concessions in order to obtain more generous bargain hunting profits. &quot;A M&amp;A fund manager pointed out to reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;behind&quot; Carlyle&#39;s sale of McDonald&#39;s China shares&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Reporters have learned that in April, the market began to hear rumors that Carlyle was planning to sell its shares in McDonald&#39;s China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, people familiar with the matter revealed that Carlyle and Trustar Capital, a private equity subsidiary of CITIC Capital Holdings Co., Ltd., are offering to sell part of McDonald’s China Company for US$4 billion. Among them, Carlyle Lei will sell 28% of McDonald&#39;s China Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person familiar with the matter also said that Carlyle and Xinchen Capital were in discussions with the Government of Singapore Investment Corporation (GIC) and Abu Dhabi’s sovereign wealth fund Mubadala Investment Co, hoping that they could Participated in the acquisition, and their overall valuation of McDonald&#39;s China Company was US$10 billion, that is, the 28% stake held by Carlyle was valued at US$2.8 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it was McDonald&#39;s Global that finally made the acquisition. And Carlyle is the only one selling equity in McDonald&#39;s China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of many PE industry insiders, McDonald’s China is actually an important high-quality asset in Carlyle’s PE investment portfolio. In 2017, CITIC and Carlyle acquired McDonald&#39;s businesses in mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau for US$2.08 billion and obtained 20-year franchise rights in the two places. CITIC and Carlyle formulated a plan for McDonald&#39;s China The &quot;Five-Year Plan&quot; strives to expand the number of McDonald&#39;s restaurants to 4,500 by 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, McDonald&#39;s has more than 5,500 stores in mainland China, Hong Kong and Macau. In recent years, McDonald&#39;s China sales have maintained a growth of more than 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They believe that an important factor that forced Carlyle to decide to sell this &quot;high-quality asset&quot; was weak performance. The recent third-quarter financial report released by Carlyle showed that both total revenue and net profit experienced significant year-on-year declines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This will definitely affect Carlyle’s new fund-raising.” The aforementioned domestic PE institutional partner believes. Normally, when a PE institution plans to issue a new fund to raise funds, it will first return most of the investment principal and income of the previous fund to investors (LPs) to boost their interest in continuing to invest in the new fund. confidence. On the other hand, if the previous fund project exits slowly and cannot return sufficient principal income to LPs, it will affect the rise of LPs to continue investing. In this case, PE institutions can only sell high-quality projects to industrial capital at low prices to create more project exit cases and return principal and interest, in order to win the &quot;commitment&quot; of LPs to continue investing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sharp contrast, in July this year, large European PE institutions completed the fundraising of their ninth M&amp;A fund, with a scale of 26 billion euros, setting a record for the largest fundraising of a M&amp;A fund. This is mainly due to the fact that CVC has achieved the exit of a number of large-scale investment projects in the past year, including the sale of Messer Industries shares to Messer and the sale of energy exploration company Neptune Energy Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rob Lucas, managing partner of CVC, said that the exit of these projects will help promote the fundraising of new funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Obviously, Carlyle’s management team also realizes that without enough project exit cases and return of principal interests, the new phase of fund raising will face many challenges, especially it will be difficult to convince LPs Continue to inject capital.&quot; The domestic PE institution partner said frankly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;Industrial capital is waiting for PE to make more &quot;concessions&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to selling equity in McDonald&#39;s China, Carlyle has recently been operating multiple sales projects to further increase its Number of project exits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, there were market rumors that Carlyle was seeking to sell German software company SER and Japanese cosmetics supplier Tokiwa Corp. At the same time, Carlyle also plans to sell off its shares in AmbioPharm, a peptide active pharmaceutical ingredient CDMO (contract development and manufacturing organization) company, valuing the company at approximately US$1 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of industry insiders, this means that Carlyle is selling more projects to quickly reverse the decline in financial performance and return more investment principal profits to LPs. Earn their “commitment” to continue investing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the current economic environment, it will not be easy to sell the above projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the first six months of this year, global PE funds received less than US$37.7 billion through exit channels such as portfolio listings and acquisitions, falling to the lowest level in the past 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Even though the market recently expects the Federal Reserve to cut interest rates soon and the U.S. economy remains resilient, industrial capital is not enthusiastic about acquisitions.&quot; The person in charge of the above-mentioned M&amp;A fund told reporters. The reasons are: First, more and more industrial capitals are not optimistic about the future global economic development prospects, and would rather retain more funds to &quot;overwinter&quot; than to rush into mergers and acquisitions and encounter the risk of M&amp;A failure; secondly, some industrial capitals also know that PE Institutions are eager to create project exit cases to return principal income to LP (for the purpose of raising funds for a new phase of funds), and are waiting for PE institutions to further lower the project sales price, thereby obtaining higher bargaining returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This forces more and more large PE institutions to make more concessions on price in order to complete project mergers and acquisitions and exit as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, Tiger Fund transferred its remaining shares in Flipkart, a large Indian e-commerce company, to Walmart for a total transaction value of US$1.4 billion. This corresponds to a valuation of Flipkart of US$35 billion, which is lower than Tiger Fund’s previous investment in Flipkart. Valuation of Flipkart at US$38 billion in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Currently, most industrial capital with abundant funds are not eager to make acquisitions. They are still evaluating whether acquisitions can have an immediate boost in improving corporate performance.&quot; The head of the M&amp;A fund said bluntly . This has made PE institutions even more anxious, because the global IPO market downturn in the past two years has prevented PE institutions from returning considerable principal returns to LPs, which is causing LPs to question the project exit capabilities of PE institutions. Once this situation continues, more and more LPs will eventually vote with their feet for PE institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is foreseeable that in order to achieve more project mergers and acquisitions and exits, many large global PE institutions can only continue to lower their status and lower project sales prices, and strive to create more project exit cases. This must not be allowed. LPs continue to question their ability to exit projects, because this will greatly weaken the industry reputation and image of these large PE institutions in the VC/PE market.&quot; He analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“23000塔卡薪资抗议”：国际大牌背后的孟加拉国“血汗工厂”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261306]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Working 8 hours a day during the day, there are usually 2 hours of paid overtime. I haven&#39;t asked for it in six years of work. Leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem, a machine operator at a garment factory in Gazipur, Bangladesh, told Southern Weekend reporters that although there is meager overtime pay, if workers forcefully ask for leave, they are likely to be laid off verbally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Bangladesh government adjusted the minimum wage standard in 2018, the monthly income of garment workers has remained at 8,300 taka (equivalent to RMB 530) for a long time. This money can hardly afford to live with inflation and high prices due to the new crown epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Bangladesh’s cheap labor has brought huge profits. According to statistics from the National Bureau of Statistics of Bangladesh, in 2022, the production value of the textile industry will account for more than 13% of Bangladesh&#39;s total GDP, and the country relies on clothing exports to make US$55 billion in profits every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the silent volcano erupted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/1706045b48.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/1706045b48.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259581&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;During this round of protests, Bangladeshi police are using sticks to drive away female garment workers. Picture provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October 24 to November 14, 2023, tens of thousands of ordinary Bangladeshi workers launched a &quot;Taka 23,000&quot; protest in Dhaka, the capital of Bangladesh, and its surrounding cities. Wage protest” (equivalent to RMB 1,472). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Six years ago, after passing a mechanical operation test and a simple interview, Fahem entered this garment factory. Because he is engaged in a more technical position, his salary is 10,500 taka (equivalent to RMB 672) per month, which is slightly higher than the 8,300 taka of an ordinary garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Most garment workers are women, and their situation is even more difficult.&quot; Fahem said. When Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact several female garment workers, they were unable to get a reply because they were unable to communicate in English. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem mentioned that some female workers don’t even know how to type on their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/73ff85113b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/73ff85113b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259582&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The income of female garment workers in Bangladesh is only half that of female workers in India and Cambodia. The latter two also have a large number of female garment workers in their countries. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fahem did not directly participate in this &quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest.&quot; The city of Gazipur where he is located is a textile industry city in Bangladesh, 25 kilometers north of the capital Dhaka. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early November, Bangladesh’s Minister of Labor and Employment Sufian announced that the minimum wage for workers would be raised to 12,500 taka starting from December 1. Bangladeshi textile workers hope that employers can triple the minimum wage to 23,000 taka - garment workers believe that 23,000 taka is the baseline for maintaining food and clothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gazipur, Asuriya and other industrial cities are the core areas of the &quot;Taka 23,000 salary protest&quot;. Police in Asuriya, Bangladesh, said that more than 10,000 local workers protested along the highway. During the protests, about 300 factories closed down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At least four workers were killed and thousands injured in violent protests, according to the Bangladesh Garment Workers Federation. The police have launched 40 criminal cases so far, with more than 20,000 workers accused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/9ca9fdd311.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/9ca9fdd311.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259583&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Bangladesh is one of the very few Muslim countries that allows women to work outside the home. They can work in various places such as banks and universities. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;More than 100,000 workers across Bangladesh participated in the wage increase movement.&quot; Tohidur Rahman, chairman of the Bangladesh Garment Workers Federation, is one of the organizers of this protest one. He told Southern Weekend reporters that every year, he submits a salary increase plan to the Bangladesh Ministry of Labor and Employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Individual workers dare not make any demands to their employers for fear of being fired.” As one of the representatives of the local union, Fahem did not go directly to the streets. He was avoiding arrest by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When prices and rents rise, the salary cannot sustain my life, and I cannot lose this job.&quot; Fahem told Southern Weekend reporters that in order to support his family, he can only hold on to his &quot;job.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Female Workers Manufacturing&quot; in Bangladesh&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Being a garment worker is a common occupation in Bangladesh. &quot;Most people only need to receive very little training to stay and work.&quot; Jon Hossain, a Bangladeshi, told Southern Weekend reporters that his friends would also choose textile engineering when they went to college. major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Bangladesh, more than thirty private and public universities train textile industry graduates every year, further increasing the number of technical talents in the textile industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the factory where Fahem works, it is more common to see female garment workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a study by the Ethical Trade Initiative, more than 50% of the 4 million textile industry workers in Bangladesh in 2022 will be women. In the 1980s, female workers accounted for as high as 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/7d7b73aa51.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/7d7b73aa51.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259584&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Lunch for Bangladeshi female workers. Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Setting, cutting threads, and packing boxes, female workers will sit in the hot and stuffy workshop for 10 hours a day, repeating these processes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Including overtime, Rima needs to work 62 hours a week. The weekly output of her production line must reach 1,000 pieces of clothing.&quot; American author Maxine Bedart&#39;s book &quot;Amplified Desire&quot; A book chronicles the work of Rima, a Bangladeshi garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book mentions that every working day, Rima can only go to the toilet after completing her production target. If she falls behind, her manager is nearby, loudly urging her to work faster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Labor rights activists in Bangladesh and the United States believe that Bangladesh’s garment industry provides young women with opportunities to move from the margins of society to the center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hazy, a female worker, once worked in a garment factory, sewing shirt pockets, &quot;every day until she couldn&#39;t sew anymore.&quot; But she still &quot;loves it here.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can decide my own life, and I can also make money to support my family.&quot; Hartz believes. Some relatives and friends praised her as &quot;the only one in the family who earns a salary.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While being squeezed by their employers, Bangladeshi garment workers also face potential safety hazards at work. The collapse of the Rana Plaza garment factory in Savar, Bangladesh, in 2013 killed more than 1,130 people, making it one of the world&#39;s worst industrial disasters&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of salary, the monthly salary of 8,300 taka for female workers is far from enough to live on. In a study on &quot;Basic Rights to a Living Wage&quot; by the U.S. non-profit organization Microfinance Opportunities and the C&amp;amp;A Apparel Foundation, the income of female garment workers in Bangladesh is only half that of female workers in India and Cambodia. The latter two also have a large number of domestic workers. Garment worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f17f5bedbb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f17f5bedbb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259585&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;In addition to working, they also have to bear the burden of family. Since the Bangladesh government adjusted the minimum wage standard in 2018, the monthly income of garment workers has remained at 8,300 taka (equivalent to RMB 530) for a long time. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Li Chunhua&amp;nbsp; Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bangladesh is one of the very few Muslim countries that allows women to work outside the home. They can work in various places such as banks and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina is a woman, and she has provided more preferential policies for women in Bangladesh.&quot; Jon Hou, Ph.D. in International Investment Law, China University of Political Science and Law, Bangladeshi Sain told Southern Weekend reporters that there is no tuition fee for women in Bangladesh to go to college, while men have to pay. &quot;It&#39;s just that many women get married early and give up their studies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hussein smiled and said, if in the factory If there were more male workers, it would be easier for protests to break out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who will bear the cost of salary increase? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bangladesh, a South Asian country with a population of less than 200 million, is one of the largest clothing manufacturers in the world. According to statistics from the Bangladesh Manufacturers Association, nearly 3,500 garment factories in the country employ 4 million people, and they supply well-known European and American brands such as Levi&#39;s, Zara and H&amp;amp;M. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics, the inflation rate will rise to 9% between 2022 and 2023, the highest value in 12 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unequal wages have attracted the attention of international big names. In September 2023, 18 brands including Levi&#39;s, H&amp;amp;M, Gap, and Puma wrote to Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, calling on him to re-establish minimum wage standards to meet the basic needs of workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/d03de605c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;486&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/d03de605c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;A group of garment workers gathered on the outskirts of Bangladesh in an attempt to protest against unequal wages. Picture provided by respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We recommend that the Bangladesh government adopt an annual minimum wage review mechanism to keep pace with macroeconomic changes.&quot; The letter stated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Bangladesh government reviews the minimum wage every five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If you want to support workers’ demands for wage increases, clothing brands in European and American countries also need to increase order prices.” Farooq Hassan, chairman of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association, lamented that although these brands have publicly They shout support, but when costs rise, they threaten to &quot;buy goods from other countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2023, a study of 1,000 garment factories in Bangladesh by the University of Aberdeen in Scotland and the initiative &quot;Transforming Trade&quot; found that more than half of the factories experienced at least one of the following situations: order cancellation, refusal of payment , price reduction or delayed payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study also found that 37% of brand companies engaged in &quot;unfair behavior&quot;, including H&amp;amp;M, Gap, etc. After the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, some companies still want to order at the original price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large brands such as H&amp;amp;M do not directly open factories in Bangladesh. They sign contracts with local factory owners. Factory owners need to pay all upfront costs, including raw materials, factory equipment, and worker wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For many small garment factories, it is very difficult to raise wages for employees.” Bangladeshi Jon Hussain told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of Hussein&#39;s friends sold part of his property and opened a small clothing factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/33e9261a6c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/33e9261a6c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259587&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Bangladeshi police patrol near the factory. Picture provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The export price has been negotiated between the factory and the brand. If employees need a salary increase, many small factories will close.&quot; Hussein mentioned that due to insufficient production levels , most small factories are also unable to purchase automation equipment, and once workers take to the streets, the factories are forced to stop production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protests forced the closure of hundreds of factories. Kalpona Akter, president of the Bangladesh Garment and Industrial Workers Federation, mentioned that the suspended factories supply almost all well-known European and American brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The low cost of international FMCG brands is not unrelated to the low income of workers in exporting countries. When brands seek lower prices from OEMs, worker wages will only stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the COVID-19 epidemic, international brands canceled approximately US$40 billion in orders from factories around the world, and factories and workers paid the price. At that time, the workers&#39; rights alliance launched many labor movements on social media, some of which claimed to have caused major brands to repay nearly US$22 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起诉“停止大象表演”败诉，野生动物表演等于虐待吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261296]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新嫂燕球丨云间夜话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261246]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fish Balls. Visual China | Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/b6156a5182.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/24/b6156a5182.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fish balls. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Songjiang River in Shanghai was called &quot;Yunjian&quot; in ancient times. When I first moved to Songjiang, it felt a bit like &quot;between the clouds&quot; - empty and silent, misty and deserted. There are no acquaintances. Naturally, there were no familiar delicacies. I thought I would start a lonely life and start everything from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, I was suddenly called by my name on the quiet road that day. I couldn&#39;t help but be startled. I took a closer look at a fat lady, but I didn&#39;t recognize her, but she smiled and said, I often watch on TV. I see you here, why are you here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turned out to be Jin Mei, my childhood neighbor. Hearing that her mother was still alive, she couldn&#39;t help but be surprised: New sister-in-law, is she still there? ! It&#39;s about ninety, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ninety-seven!&quot; Jin Mei replied. I immediately asked to see her. Because when she was a child, she was a popular idol in the alley. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;New Sister-in-law&quot; is probably called famous by a group of old people. The reason must be that she was a bride in the alley back then. It is said that many people want to see a new wife who can&#39;t cook and make a fool of herself, but the new sister-in-law&#39;s skills make many older people feel inferior to her. What makes many women obey the most is that she actually raised eight boys and one girl in one go. Her youngest daughter Jinmei is my classmate. Behind her back, the old ladies call her &quot;Laikehang&quot; (a kind of foreign chicken that is very good at laying eggs). ). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although her ancestral home is Shaoxing, she is more proficient than ordinary people when it comes to &quot;being a good person&quot;. When people in Shanghai say that people &quot;can be a good person&quot;, they are praising a kind of &quot;intelligent frugality&quot;, which is left-brained and right-brained. Living a life by discussing things is not just living a stingy life. For example, using mature loofah tendons to wash dishes is far better than sponges, but the price is negligibly cheap; cutting discarded sweatshirts into strips of cloth to tie into mops is much better absorbent than yarn; buying meat at a &quot;small market&quot; You can be precise enough to buy only 2 taels, which is enough to fry shredded pork for a meal. This is in contrast to the honest and honest people in the north who often buy half a fan, forming a &quot;precision&quot;. When you go to a restaurant to eat, most of the leftovers have to be packed up and re-cooked at home, called &quot;zaluo soup&quot;. The most typical one is the invention of the &quot;fake leader&quot; in Shanghai, which uses the least amount of fabric to maintain the greatest dignity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But these &quot;life skills&quot; are just &quot;mere&quot; in the eyes of the new sister-in-law. She has her own unique skills, and they are beyond everyone&#39;s imagination, which makes the whole alley admire her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin’s sister-in-law’s hometown has a lot of bamboo shoots, and every year a lot of bamboo shoots are brought there by people. In order to preserve them, Xin’s sister-in-law always boils the bamboo shoots in a large pot of salted water, cuts the cooked bamboo shoots into pieces, and air-dries them. The old soup used to cook the bamboo shoots is not changed, and is cooked batch by batch. Finally, the old soup is slightly thick, and the large bottle and large wine bottle are poured in sequentially. The whole process does not touch the water, and the wine bottle is sealed with oil paper. This is the &quot;soy sauce&quot; for her cooking. &quot;. They call it &quot;bamboo shoot oil&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, good red soy sauce cost 27 cents per catty, white soy sauce (fresh soy sauce) cost 21 cents per catty, and MSG was even more expensive. But with the bamboo shoot oil, her family never buys soy sauce and MSG. My grandmother often orders me to go to her house and buy a bottle. The freshness is better than the soy sauce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new sister-in-law also pickles bacon every year, adds coarse salt and pepper, and pours some sorghum wine. The strange thing is that she is reluctant to throw away the reddish marinated meat water. She &quot;makes meat with meat&quot; and uses the marinated meat water to cook braised pork. Just add a little red soy sauce to make the meat very red and fragrant. Neighboring, the kind of fragrance between &quot;bad&quot; and &quot;wax&quot; is almost indescribable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what we miss the most is her &quot;Yanqiu&quot; - the new sister-in-law Yanqiu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Specially difficult period&quot;, given that her family is a &quot;super-large family&quot; of 11 people, with eight boys and eight &quot;tigers&quot;, it is natural that there is a serious shortage of meat resources. Anyone who wants to eat meat Their thoughts were not only &quot;immoral&quot;, but directly &quot;cheating&quot;, but the new sister-in-law&#39;s &quot;Shaoxing-style wisdom&quot; actually solved them as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time she stopped at the market, a storm would rush through her eyes - in the fish stall, there were dead white fish (silver carp), as cheap as mud, the most undesirable, and the new sister-in-law would kill them with a move. &quot;Here are two, big ones!&quot; The stall owner was so flattered that he offered them at the lowest price. In the meat stall, people walked around the milk fat pork, the loosest fat on the pork belly, and the stall owner often felt worried about it. At this time, the new sister-in-law waved her pink arm and said, &quot;Two pounds here!&quot; The stall owner was like Feng Lunyin. Not only did he cut the meat wide, but he also charged the floor price, and often even refused to charge for the meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Mei and I love watching our new sister-in-law make swallow balls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw her quickly removing the scales, gills and internal organs of the fish, and then rinsed it clean. Then cut in two halves from beginning to end, remove the total bones and thorns, cut off the fish head and belly stalls (for the use of fish soup), and the remaining two large fish, fish skin down, placed on the chopping board, nail giving away The fish tail, the fast knife is vertically, scrape the fish from the outside to the inside, and when the fish skin and the underpurring red meat are left, the new cricket said, many people do not understand, greedy this red meat! In fact, the red meat must not be asked, the fish is fishy, ​​it is fishy! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fishing meat, the new cricket repeatedly chopped it, saying that the fishbone was chopped, and then put it in the container, stir it with two pairs of chopsticks clockwise for a few minutes, put the salt, and stir the foam until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foaming until the foam , Pick up milk fat. Mix the cooked milk fat meat with lard residue, add starch and ginger dandruff, and mix the fish paste and stir well. Because of the abundant raw materials, she makes the fish balls bigger. Such as table tennis, even as big as tennis, finally cooked in the boiling water pot, white and crystal clear like snow, tender and smooth entrance like tofu, not fishy and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reason why we see a swallow ball every time, because we can try one first, and how happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That night is the carnival of eight boys and her husband &quot;open the big&quot; -when the ball of the big pot is on the table, you must use the soup spoon to use the soup spoon to use the sketch spoon. One by one is strictly allocated. If they come from them, it may be a dining table with a bloody three -foot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the story is not over yet. &quot;Eight Tigers&quot; ate the swallow ball, and the next day, there must be the by -product &quot;fish&quot; of Yanqiu waiting for them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The stomach beheaded yesterday, after the new cooked cooked, removed the fish and thorns, it was still chopped with milk and fat, mixed with the fish, put it into the soup, put the vinegar, put the salt, and put it. Sprinkle the celery leaves or minced garlic, the aroma strikes, the freshness is slightly sour, and the brown rice in the large pot is instantly exhausted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A group of old women headed by my grandmother are jealous, and often quietly comment: This dish is actually from Hangzhou cuisine. And make delicious. Who wants this dead white fish? If you ca n’t sell it, it ’s rotten; who buys this milk fat? Can&#39;t be sold only with oil residue. But she was tompied by her, and the countertop of the New Year&#39;s Eve can be on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gradually, everyone put down the shelf and asked the new puppet; gradually, the fish stalls and meat stalls in the vegetable field were noticeable. P>; &lt;p>; Gradually, we have the most popular, most affordable, and most raised home dishes for us. What is given by the neighbors, the official name of the outside world is the &quot;Xinyan Swallow Ball&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How many years have passed, and the time is almost vicissitudes of the sea, and it is gone, but how many generations, especially the &quot;eight tigers&quot; eat the cheapest and most delicious &quot;big&quot; and grow up , And joining the job, and the marriage -even gradually entered the old realm, Wu Nai&#39;s new sister -in -law was still alive! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I was standing in front of her bed, to be honest, she was old and I couldn&#39;t remember me, but when she talked about her swallow ball, she actually had a flash of eyes. Pursting his mouth and said, &quot;... Unfortunately, there was no oil at that time. The practical fried is better! ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10月全国查处违反中央八项规定精神问题9567起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261314]]><description> &lt;DIV>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 23:09:54 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced on the 23rd to announce the monthly report data of the report on the investigation and punishment of the eight central regulations. The report shows that in October this year, a total of 9,567 cases of mental problems that violated the eight central regulations were investigated and dealt with nationwide, 13,770 people (including 97 prefecture-level cadres and 886 county-level cadres) were criticized, educated, helped and dealt with, and 9,333 people were given party discipline and government sanctions. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the notification, in October this year, a total of 4131 formalism and bureaucracy issues were investigated and punished, and 6,389 people criticized and handled 6,389 people. Among them, the most problems were investigated and dealt with in the aspect of &quot;non-responsibility, inaction, random acts, and false acts in performing duties, serving economic and social development, and protecting the ecological environment, which seriously affect high-quality development&quot;. 3,660 cases were investigated and dealt with, and 5,718 cases were criticized, educated, helped, and dealt with. people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the notification, in October this year, a total of 5436 issues of hedonism and extravagant winds were investigated and dealt with. Among them, 2,405 cases of illegal collection and delivery of valuable specialties and gifts, 765 cases of illegal payment of subsidies or welfare, and 1,254 cases of illegal eating and drinking were investigated and dealt with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx. run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一根跳绳卖78元？杭州中考专用绳调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261288]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;h4>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;The skipping rope of this brand is a bit heavy. Originally, the child could jump more than 190 times per minute, and it can only jump 160 times with this skipping rope. Can&#39;t buy. &quot;Mr. Huang, a citizen of Hangzhou, said that his son will take the entrance examination next year, and the sports test project will choose skipping rope. Since the brand of skipping rope chosen for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination was &quot;Hengyou&quot;, in order to familiarize the children with the rope used for the exam in advance, he had no choice but to buy this skipping rope after being designated by the school teacher. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;I checked the rope of the same category on the Internet, only a dozen dollars, it costs 78 yuan.&quot; Similar to Mr. Huang, a elementary school in Shangcheng District, Hangzhou City, Ms. Lu, the parents of the second grade, said that 39 students in the children&#39;s class, at the request of the teacher, almost everyone bought the &quot;Heng You&quot; brand jump rope. Some parents also bought two, one to practice at home, and the other to practice. &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In August 2020, the Ministry of Education, including the Ministry Teaching auxiliary software or information &quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; During the prohibition of the order, why do some schools recommend buying this rope? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Some sports teachers in Hangzhou in Hangzhou admit that the primary and secondary grades are primary and sixth, and rope skipping is a must -have sports project; in middle school, it is also one of the projects in the middle school entrance examination. Because the Hangzhou high school entrance examination is &quot;Heng You&quot;, some primary schools have also used &quot;Heng You&quot; to jump rope. &quot;It is better to use it at night. We will recommend that parents buy the&quot; Hengyou &quot;rope training, but the teacher does not compulsory the teacher, and the school will also provide corresponding skipping rope to meet the needs of students.&quot; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; A junior high school student in Hangzhou told reporters that because &quot;Heng You&quot; is more expensive, she usually uses a few dollars of rubber ropes when practicing at home; Use the school&#39;s &quot;Heng You&quot; rope exercise. &quot;Some classmates with good family members in the class also bought the&quot; Heng You &quot;rope with Bluetooth counting function. The one requires more than 140 yuan.&quot; Some class teachers or physical education teachers in Hangzhou primary and secondary schools allow parents to buy the brand rope by verbally notifying or issuing links of parents. Hengyou Sports Taobao flagship store customer service said that Hangzhou ’s high school entrance examination rope provides“ Hengyou ”. Many schools in Shangcheng, Gongshu, and Xiaoshan in Hangzhou recommend buying this rope. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Coach Huang Huang, a &quot;skip -skipping class&quot; in Hangzhou, told reporters that more than 20 primary and secondary school students who came to him here also felt that the middle school entrance examination was heavy and rope. Other ropes are good. &quot;In order to cope with the exam, children can only report to class training.&quot; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;Span>; &lt;strong>; How can the &quot;Heng You&quot; rope become a special rope for Hangzhou middle school entrance examination? &lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Is there a standard for the rope for the middle school entrance examination? Shen Hao, deputy dean of the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute, who is responsible for the purchase of sports equipment in Hangzhou Entrance Examination, said that neither the country and the province did not have the standard for the middle school entrance examination. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; It is understood that the national skipping standard specifies the length, diameter and diameter and weight of the rope, but this standard is the recommended standard. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;Actually &#39;Hengyou&#39; skipping rope is designed according to adult standards to design the length of the rope and the thickness of the handle. &#39;Hengyou&#39; jump rope is too heavy, it is not easy to jump, and it is easy to break, &quot;said some primary and secondary school sports teachers in Hangzhou. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; It is understood that the producer of &quot;Hengyou&quot; is Shenzhen Hengkangjiaye Technology Co., Ltd. Tianyancha shows that the company was founded in 2006 and is a company that is mainly engaged in cultural, educational, gongmei, sports and entertainment. Rope skipping product. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The relevant person in charge of Hangzhou Flying Bird Sports Products Co., Ltd. acknowledged that since entering the Zhejiang market in 2011, &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope is the test rope for the sports test of the Hangzhou middle school entrance examination; the current market It has covered all the main urban areas of Hangzhou, selling more than 100,000 foundations in Zhejiang a year, of which more than 70%of them are elementary and middle school students. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; So how does the &quot;Hengyou&quot; rope become a special rope for Hangzhou Entrance Examination? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;From 2011, the Education Department of Hangzhou City was leased and used the middle school entrance examination sports equipment produced by Shenzhen Hengkang Jiaye Technology Company. Public bidding methods, leasing uses sporting goods produced by the manufacturer, the annual lease fee is 800,000 yuan. &quot;Shen Hao said. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Some skipping manufacturers said that they also tried to enter the scope of sports rope in Hangzhou high school entrance examination, but it was difficult to find it. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Reporter&#39;s &quot;Single Source of Source of the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute of Education Examination Equipment Leasing Projects&quot; announced by the Zhejiang Provincial Government Purchasing Network (January 2019) Seeing that the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute intends to use the &quot;single source&quot; procurement method (lease) to purchase the sports examination equipment of Hangzhou Star Education Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The application reason given by the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute is: &quot;Over the years, the Hangzhou City High School Entrance Examination Sports Examination has always used Shenzhen Hengkang Jiaye Technology Co., Ltd. The original equipment leasing service party is Hangzhou Star Education Technology Co., Ltd. The original equipment leasing service party. The equipment system is stable and the service response is fast. The specific consideration of the integrity and software management platform is in line with the &quot;condition of the&quot; condition purchased by the unique supplier&#39;s office. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;p>; &lt;spna Over the years, Hangzhou Sports High School Entrance Examination has been leased the equipment of the &quot;Heng You&quot; manufacturer, including skipping rope, rope skipping tester, etc., so it has formed the result of &quot;Heng You&quot; for the current high school entrance examination. In addition, this company is an earlier manufacturer of smart counting rope skipping. Compared with the number of candidates in the eyes of the monitoring teacher&#39;s eyes, this intelligent count is fair and efficient. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;Leasing the sports test equipment to the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute does not make money. Our more markets are primary and secondary school students, that is, under the sports examination mechanism of primary and secondary schools Policy market. &quot;The person in charge of Hangzhou Flying Bird Sports Products Co., Ltd. admits. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;span>; &lt;strong>; Breaking the hidden brand monopoly, so that parents and schools have more options &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;pan>; Some rope -skipping manufacturers said that countable skipping rope is not a high -tech product, and manufacturers can produce. &quot;I hope that by improving the bidding methods and the establishment of a rope standard for sports examinations for primary and secondary schools, parents and schools have more options.&quot; The cost of counting the number of middle school entrance examinations does not exceed 8 yuan each; a rope for the middle school entrance examination with a counting function does not exceed 20 yuan. Yuanhe 148 yuan, there is huge profit margins. &quot;A brand merchant producing skipping rope in Zhejiang revealed. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The &quot;Anti -Monopoly Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that organizations with administrative agencies and laws and regulations authorized by managing public affairs shall not abuse administrative power, eliminate and restrict competition. &quot;If the education examination department has no reason, the skipping rope of a certain brand has been used for a long time, especially when the market products have not been widely investigated, and the procurement method is simply specified through the&quot; single source &#39;procurement method. Principles. &quot;Said the staff of the market supervision department of Zhejiang Province. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The relevant person in charge of the Hangzhou Education Bureau said: &quot;We are also reflecting on whether we can refer to other places to improve the current sports skipping evaluation method of high school entrance examinations. Including whether students can allow students to take ropes to take the exam, whether they can choose more brands of rope skipping equipment, etc., to avoid unnecessary troubles and burdens to students and parents. &quot;&lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打着“国家补贴”的幌子欺诈乡下老人，何以屡屡得逞？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261196]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 21:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recently, I turned on the phone camera as usual and wanted to see what parents were doing, but found that the door at home was locked locked. It was not until the phone father knew that in the past few days, there was a market for selling goods in the neighboring villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I asked a few aunts in the village, and we only learned about the relevant situation: One week ago, a bunch of foreigners who fucking calls chose to open a place beside the village road and set up a shed. Some people are specifically guarding. The elderly enter the venue for free. There are many small benches inside, with large horns. The young people preach the efficacy of a certain product on the stage, and then encourage the elderly to buy. Obviously, this is a product sales meeting, only two obvious features: First, the sales location is in the village, located in pure rural areas; second, the market is an old man and a clear rural left -behind elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since it is a marketing meeting or a merchant to advertise, it is not as violated, but it is still full of &quot;routine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About daily arrangements. It is understood that this promotion will generally last 6-7 days, and the first 4-5 days will explain relevant knowledge so that the elderly believe it is true. One of the universal tricks is based on the characteristics of the product to promote the product, and exaggerate the problems of the elderly in some aspects of the elderly. For example, when promoting the water purifier, how can the water quality commonly applicable in rural areas not good, what harm to the body is, the purpose of the purpose, the purpose of the purpose It is because the elderly feel that if they do not buy their products, the consequences will be very serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second trick is to frequently use some scientific and technological methods during the explanation process, such as on -site inspection of water quality, using special instruments, professional testing methods, through scientific and technological methods such as academicians and scientists, to convince the villagers to believe This is scientific, advanced, developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third trick is that a group of people will &quot;perform&quot; in the process of explanation, there are foreigners and locals, and there may be people who are prestigious in the local area. Foreigners, but the locals should always believe it? The high probability involves buying a small number of local people through money and other methods. The goods are sold for 1-2 days. That is, there is a process of moving the first movement, the reason to serve people first, the brainwashing, buying the hearts of the people, and finally harvesting (money). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About identity changes. A few days ago, the merchants used various videos, words, performances, and other methods. The purpose was to gain the trust of the elderly. In the process, the merchants turned into many roles. A few days ago, they were foreigners. Members, they are rural rejuvenation to help people. They are psychologists who are familiar with and know the psychology of the elderly. They are health guardians who care about the health of the elderly. The essential role — the profit is the merchant of the picture, the villain and wicked of the old people who fraud the old people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About what sells and gifts. They eventually sold a certain brand of water purifier, and then the objects they were given were divided into two types: a few days ago, it was pumping paper, washbasin, toothpaste, toothbrush, laundry powder, and laundry fluid. Only those who came to the scene. The next two days is a range hood, a wall breaking machine and a warm and cold air conditioner. Obviously, most of the gifts a few days ago were cheap and practical in rural areas. As long as you go, people will give you, people go, there are more people, it is easy to cover some watcher’s eyes. One of the elderly in the country, especially for the elderly in the countryside. They will feel, &quot;Are they all fools, no? I&#39;ll see it too.&quot; The gifts in the next two days are also very practical, but the person with a clear eye knows that it is not cheap, but the condition is that you have to spend money to buy net net Water heater, people are delivered. In other words, the things they sell and the things they are sent are not cheap. This method of selling a large piece to send three large pieces makes many elderly people feel that this merchant is full of sincerity. This is not the kind of adulterer in the general sense. Some elderly people even stood up to speak for them, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if they were deceived in the end, thousands of pieces were gone, but at least four real things were in hand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About price. Taking the main sales water purifier as an example, my mother told me that the price was 2980 yuan. I simply searched on the regular e-commerce platforms such as Jingdong and Taobao. To similar products with good quality. Faced with such a huge price difference, the compensation tricks of merchants include intimidation, bragging and gifts. What is even more angry is that my mother told me that the merchant would say that the price of 2980 yuan still enjoyed the price after the state&#39;s subsidy policy on science and technology products went to the countryside. That is to say, the original price may be 4980 yuan. Now it is a merchant to benefit the people. After deducting 2,000 yuan in state subsidies, the villagers have a rare opportunity and opportunity for 2980 yuan. As soon as this remark, the old people&#39;s preparations were easily defeated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; About those who enter the venue. My mother told me that those people are very friendly. At seven o&#39;clock in the morning, the car will go to the village entrance on time, dragging the old people in the village, and preparing for breakfast, steamed buns, milk and other breakfast for the elderly. At the scene, some people poured tea and asked for warmth, and the service was quite thoughtful. At 12 noon, the car was sent home to cook and eat on time. At two in the afternoon, the car will appear in the village on time and wait for the elderly; at 5:30, they send the old people to their own houses. A friend of me who was so big with me told me that last weekend, their village also had similar activities. He wanted to enter the shed to see. The person who did not want to be discouraged by the door was obvious. Only the elderly could enter. Middle -aged people, do not give in. Obviously, the merchants are afraid of young people or middle -aged people. The reason is that they are worried that young people or middle -aged people will dismantle their play in public. Young or middle -aged people publicly oppose them, which will seriously affect the elderly people. Purchase psychology to reduce the willingness to buy the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above is the relevant situation I heard or learned, causing me to think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of them is that the basic fact is that some merchants are fraudulently the ignorant elderly people in the countryside under the guise of &quot;expanding domestic demand&quot; and &quot;enjoying subsidies for national science and technology products to the countryside&quot;. To be honest, the production companies of many products exist, but under market -oriented conditions, although many companies exist stubbornly, the main products have long been eliminated by the market. Especially in the urban market, they have been saturated. What should I do? Of course, the company wanted to move the tentacles down to occupy the urban and rural markets. There is no doubt that this is a measure for enterprises to expand domestic demand. However, the quality of such products is hard to say, but the price is many times higher than the price of similar products on online shopping. It is undeniable that there are fraud and fraud in the process of product sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Second, the abnormal moves of the elderly in the countryside are worthy of scrutiny. First, why do the old people who have been used to eating in clothes on weekdays are used to most of their lives, but they will not hesitate to face large orders of nearly 3,000 yuan. I think there is a problem of transferring a family (words) right (power) transfer here. Nowadays, many people at home are basically purchased online by children outside. You buy, I use it, I used it, I used it, big use, now I am old, don’t buy it, you don’t need to buy it. That&#39;s it. I didn&#39;t contribute much to this home. At least not as big as before. The old people are more passive to accept gifts and users. The selection, screening and purchase process is a deprivation of consumer power. Now there is such an opportunity, I pay, I buy, I am a master, I am happy. It was finally discovered that he was fooled and deceived. Although they would be distressed, they would accept the reality frankly. &quot;Where is the money not to use money? I buy something to spend money? Thousands of, do you think I don&#39;t know? It&#39;s expensive to buy something? &quot;My mother would stun me in this way, facing my bitter discouraged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Secondly, knowing that it is probably a scammer&#39;s drama, knowing that there is no free lunch in the world. Why do the old people do not &quot;bias towards Hushan&quot; and do n’t believe in evil? This is mainly because many elderly people stay in the countryside for a long time. They are kind and simple, honest and loyal, and are easy to sympathetic. The complexity of the society is not enough to understand. We often use the fatal weakness of the old people to succeed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A grandfather who finally spent 800 yuan buying ostrich said, &quot;You (young people) cannot say that they are all scammers, they are not easy, they are greedy for black every day, and they are intimate with us. They are right to serve us. They are right to serve us. Hello, I ca n’t say that I ca n’t buy anything at once. I ca n’t look like a person. ”Obviously, during the shopping process, the elderly felt that it was more than a pure money transaction, but also the emotional feedback, that is, others, that is, others It is good to us, take care of us, and we should also &quot;treat each other with courtesy&quot;. This &quot;etiquette&quot; method is to buy people&#39;s things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Third, why do the old people choose not to consult the opinions or suggestions of children outside their children. The author learned that in the past few days of the sales meeting, many elderly people were silently acting, going silently, buying silently, and silently, they would not take the initiative to inform the situation in foreign children. Of course, they were worried that their children would worry about them, even Scold them. As an old man, of course, they love face more, and they will feel that their faces are not dull by being blamed by their children. Of course, it is not what they are happy to see. In fact, many elderly people are accustomed to &quot;maverick&quot;, &quot;What am I doing, what to buy, you are less aggressive, I haven&#39;t been old, I haven&#39;t reached the point of dementia. I have my judgment and idea , You&#39;re less governing your spare &quot;, this should be the true mentality of many elderly people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, another possibility is caused by the so -called &quot;broken relatives&quot; phenomenon, that is, many children who are outside do not contact their parents on weekdays, and the concern is relatively scarce. When I encountered this, they suddenly &quot;care&quot;, and the old people would feel that young people were &quot;falsely false&quot; and &quot;too fake&quot;. Yesterday afternoon, a cousin of my cousin called his father at the market several times, so that he would not buy any ostrich grandma. Unexpectedly, his father was annoyed and said angrily, &quot;It&#39;s not your money, I am willing to spend, you are less than less. &quot;Tube&quot;, then hung up the phone and turned off the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Third, it is very scarce to make fun, in many rural areas. My mother went to the scene for six consecutive days. I didn&#39;t understand it, but my father said that it&#39;s okay, &quot;Anyway, it&#39;s okay, play it, okay, just don&#39;t buy something.&quot; The &quot;strategy&quot; of her father was to prevent her mother from taking cash, not taking her mobile phone, and then she was not allowed to borrow money from others. Every night, my mother was cheerful. She said that she met who met yesterday, who I met today, whose daughter was married, whose son had bought a house, and the steamed buns sent today are good. Obviously, the mother&#39;s mind is not at the sales session, and she is not in the product. She cares about seeing her friends every day and chatting with her friends. Yeah, the current rural areas, young people have entered the city, the children are going to school, that is, the elderly, one village and another village are not far away, but they are not near. For mothers nearly seventy years, there are no special. Things will not go to the neighboring villages. On weekdays, I just wander around in the village. With my father every day, you look at me, I look at you, and occasionally mix a few words, saying that her old age is very full, and it is not boring at all. Obviously, she will be lonely, she will be lonely, she will do nothing, social networking is her actual demand, and she will go around every day, which can make her extremely happy for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I can&#39;t help but think of when I was a kid. At that time, there were often acrobatic group performances in the village, and occasionally someone came to the village to play movies. The scene was spectacular and lively. Time has moved. In today&#39;s villages, many people lock in front of the door all year round. The resident population in the village is only the elderly. The hollow villages or hollow villages abound. Obviously, the resident population has decreased sharply, and there is no or few public entertainment activities that make the elderly more lonely, which will inevitably seriously affect the quality of life of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, for the deception of the elderly (easy) in the countryside, I think young people may wish to be free and free, and might as well encourage them to see, stroll around, and tell them that they can be vigilant. However, there is a basic fact that it is difficult for us to say or bite in advance that they buy them as fakes or crickets. This takes a period of test to see if the effect of trial or consumption can be determined. If in the end, I found that the items they bought are really inferior products. They are really fooled and deceived. They do not have to get angry or angry, because they will gain something, such as meeting and chatting with old friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology of Guangzhou University) &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold; &quot;>; (This article is only the author&#39;s personal point of view, does not represent the position of this newspaper) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山东莱荣高铁被举报偷工减料存在质量隐患，官方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261300]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 19:51:12 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On July 20, the media reported that there were some thread pile construction in the construction of the Lai Rong high-speed railway station in the construction The pile has not reached the design of the pile, the design changes are not completed, and there are problems such as hidden quality hazards. The National Railway Administration, the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government attached great importance to it and immediately established a joint investigation team composed of the Shanghai Railway Supervision and Administration Bureau and the Shandong Provincial Department of Transportation to conduct investigations in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The joint investigation team regulated more than 120 professionals nationwide to conduct field surveys, and organized 10 railways, geology and other aspects to conduct technical guidance. It lasted more than two months, carried out geological exploration and drilling inspection, interviewed 14 relevant units and 83 people, reviewed more than 29,000 pieces of data in 130 categories, and formed an investigation report and more than 100,000 words of investigation supporting materials. After the investigation was completed, seven experts, including academicians of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, were invited to demonstrate the investigation and conclusions. The joint investigation team verified the issues reported by the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The length of the construction pile of some threaded piles in the construction of Sanjie Company has not reached the problem of design piles. The joint investigation team entrusted a testing agency to carry out drilling and sampling tests on the threaded piles subcontracted by China Construction Eighth Engineering Group Co., Ltd. to Sanjie Company and other units for construction in accordance with relevant specifications, and simultaneously carried out infill geological exploration; it entrusted a professional agency to supervise the whole process and conduct quality and safety inspections on the roadbed foundation. Comprehensive Evaluation. Through the infill geological survey of the subgrade base constructed by Sanjie Company, it is shown that the thickness of the granite weathering layer and the fluctuation of the weathering layer interface in this section vary greatly. After on-site inspection and comprehensive analysis and evaluation, the construction pile length of the threaded piles in this subgrade section is consistent with the height and low fluctuations of the bearing layer revealed by the infill geological survey, and the &quot;unable to drive&quot; phenomenon has occurred. The construction pile lengths of some threaded piles have not reached the design pile length. , but the threaded pile pile end has entered a better bearing layer, which does not affect the quality and safety of the composite foundation. No corners-cutting was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the problem of uncomfortable design change procedures. After investigation, when the threaded pile construction did not reach the designed pile length but the pile end entered the bearing layer, the participating units only met on site to confirm and failed to perform design change procedures in accordance with regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After comprehensive investigation and evaluation, the compound base inheritance capacity reflected by the media meets the project requirements. It does not affect the safety of railway operations. At the same time, the settlement deformation was observed and evaluated after the completion of the composite foundation. The results showed that the actual measured and evaluated post-construction settlement of the entire Lai-Rong High-speed Railway line met the specification requirements. The acceptance results of the joint debugging and joint testing of the Lai-Rong High-speed Railway and other acceptance results show that the Lai-Rong High-speed Railway meets the track smoothness requirements during the operation of 350km/h high-speed railway and meets the safety and stability requirements of high-speed train operation. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The investigation found that during the construction period, the three -Jet company and the China Construction Eighth Bureau had conflicts in terms of construction progress and engineering payment. In June 2021, the construction has been withdrawn. . The investigation also found that there were problems in construction management such as inadequate on-site management and irregular project subcontracting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the conclusions of the survey, in response to the problems in design changes, construction management, and engineering subcontracting, the Shanghai Railway Supervision and Administration Bureau shall impose administrative penalties for relevant responsible units and 7 responsible persons according to law; in accordance with relevant regulations, in accordance with relevant regulations, in accordance with relevant regulations, Construction unit China Construction Eighth Engineering Bureau Co., Ltd., Supervision Unit China Railway Second Institute (Chengdu) Advisory and Supervision Co., Ltd., Design Unit China Railway Fourth Survey and Design Institute Group Co., Ltd. and Construction Unit Shandong Lairong High Speed ​​Railway Co., Ltd. Responsible persons are punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[活到110岁可领每月3500元津贴？四川“长寿之乡”真有老人领过]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261294]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-24 19:58:28 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;June 1, 2022, Meishan, Sichuan, the Golden Autumn Song Band Carry out the theme event of &quot;June 1&quot; International Children&#39;s Day in Changshou Arch Plaza. Visual China &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3606e94891.jpg &quot;border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;753&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3606e94891.jpg&quot; data- &quot;259567&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; June 1, 2022, Meishan, Sichuan, the Golden Autumn Song Band of the Pengshan District Senior Association, to celebrate the &quot;Six One&quot; in Changshou Brach Plaza Square International Children&#39;s Day theme event. Visual China &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 21, 2023, the Social Affairs Bureau of the Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District, Sichuan issued a notice of adjusting the standards for adjusting the issuance of seniority allowances to raise Older allowances distribution standards. One of the contents of the content caused heated discussion -the standard of each person&#39;s allowance was adjusted to 3,500 yuan/month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Can you get this money for this money?&quot; &quot;In order to receive the 3500 yuan, you have to live to 110 years old!&quot; In the comments, netizens teased, and some people questioned that the standard was too high and lacking sincerity. Because the discussion was enthusiastic, the news appeared on the hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;It&#39;s really time before, it has been a few months.&quot; A civil affairs system in the district and county under the jurisdiction of Meishan City responded to reporters in the south weekend, &quot;Longevity Culture &quot;is a major local characteristic. After the launch of the elderly allowance, 110 -year -old people who have met the standard have enjoyed this policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District belongs to Meishan City. Public information shows that the cumulative allowances issued by Meishan City have exceeded 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Not more&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The above notice shows that the adjustment standard for the adjustment of the older allowance is: 80 to 89 years old, 30 yuan, 30 yuan /Month/person; 90 to 99 years old, 100 yuan/month/person; 100 to 105 years old, 1500 yuan/month/person; 106 to 109 years old, 2500 yuan/month/person; 110 years old, above, 3500, 3500 Yuan/month/person. The adjustment standards for the adjustment of the older allowance will be implemented from January 1, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Tianfu New District is a national new district under the jurisdiction of Sichuan Province. It consists of the Chengdu area of ​​Tianfu New District and the Meishan District of Tianfu New District. The Meishan District of Tianfu New District includes the original two towns and towns in Pengshan District, Meishan City, and 5 townships in Renshou County. The Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District was established in 2015 and is the county level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the notification caused heated discussion, the Social Affairs Bureau of the Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District confirmed the authenticity of the notice to the media. According to the relevant person in charge of the bureau, the previous elderly allowance was distributed separately in accordance with the standards of Renshou County and Pengshan District. Last year, after the bureau took over the specific matters of the payment of old-age allowances, it decided to adjust the payment standards based on the actual situation in the jurisdiction, &quot;so that more elderly people can enjoy this inclusive system.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;At present, there are no elderly people over 110 years old in the new area, and there have been more than 50 elderly people over 100 years old.&quot; The above is responsible for being responsible for People introduce to the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters learned that before, the amount of older allowances in Pengshan District was relatively low, and Renshou County was relatively low and did not divide the age group over 110 years. In fact, the standard of Pengshan District is uniformly adopted in the Meishan District of Tianfu New District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Pengshan District is the main living habitat of Peng Zu, the ancestor of Zhonghua Shouxing. As of the end of 2022, there were 55 elderly people over the age of 100 in Pengshan District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;They (Meishan District, Tianfu New District) have two towns and villages, which were planned by Pengshan, so many people benefit the people&#39;s policy standards are the same as us.&quot; Pengshan District A staff member of the Social Rescue Station told the Southern Weekend reporter that the policy of distributing allowances to the elderly began in January 2020. Among them, the age group of the 110 -year -old was not more. After the policy was launched, some people had enjoyed this benefit. &quot;We once sent an old man over 110 years of age (3500 yuan per month).&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The staff member said that after the launch of this policy of benefiting the people at the time, it was launched. A 110 -year -old man meets the highest standard and receives a few months of allowances to return to the ground. At present, the oldest old man in the jurisdiction is 107 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The staff said that there are a lot of elderly people over 100 years old in the jurisdiction, more than 80 years old. The distribution of allowances to the elderly is the policy of benefiting the people in the call of the whole province. In June 2017, Sichuan issued a notice of the &quot;Office of the Sichuan Provincial Aging Working Committee, the Sichuan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, and the Sichuan Provincial Department of Finance on the establishment of an elderly allowance system for the elderly over 80 years old (Sichuan Aunt Office [2017] No. 45)&quot;, decided In 2017, the elderly subsidy system over 80 years of age was comprehensively established. The notice also states that various places can appropriately improve the distribution standards according to the level of economic development, and encourage regional regions to establish a system of older people over 80 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The implementation of the old-age allowance system of Meishan can be traced back to January 2018. In December 2017, the Office of the Aging Working Committee of Meishan City, Meishan Civil Affairs Bureau, and Meishan City Finance Bureau jointly released the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Establishing an Elderly Allowance System&quot;, saying that the per capita for the elderly who are 80 years old can be at the age of 80. Starting from January, he applied for an elderly allowance (except for the suspected crime was detained and the penalty was not executed), and stopped after his death. The funds will be settled by the government at the same level, and the municipal finance will provide appropriate subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;June 222, 2022, Sichuan, Renshou County, Renshou County, Meishan City, Sichuan Province, middle -aged and elderly people dance and strong body. Visual China&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/24/00654dfd71.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 730 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image /23/11/24/00654dfd71.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259568 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; June 2022, Meishan City, Sichuan Province, Sichuan Province In the south square of Renshou County, middle -aged and elderly people dance and strengthen their body. Visual China &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Publish hundreds of millions of agents for 110,000 elderly people &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; July 6, 2023, Meishan City Government&#39;s official website &quot;Meishan City City The Civil Affairs Bureau&#39;s letter to the No. 174 of the Third Session of the Fifth National People&#39;s Congress revealed the implementation of the old age allowance system of Meishan City: to issue an elderly allowance for the elderly for the elderly in Meishan households at the age of 80, and the standard is 80 to 89 years old. Each person is no less than 25 yuan per month, 90 to 99 years old per person per month, and 100 yuan per person for 100 years or old per month. As of now (July 6, 2023) More than 110,000 elderly people distributed more than 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The staff of the Social Rescue Station of Pengshan District introduced that they will choose many soil methods to sink to the community to promote the elderly allowance policies, such as making buses for distribution. Propaganda on the public announcement column of the community and village committee. &quot;This is an inclusive policy with great publicity. (People) should know that there are this policy. Some elderly people who follow their children to live in other places may give up applying. Everyone has already applied. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; In addition to the elderly allowance, we will also issue 600 yuan condolences on the birthday of the elderly. &quot; A staff member of the Civil Affairs Bureau of Dongpo District, Meishan City, said that the elderly allowance standards in each district of Meishan City will be different, but the difference is not very large. For the first month of the age of 80, the elderly who meet the standards can apply for the community where the household registration is located. If the elderly are inconvenient, it can be handled by the family members to carry the identity card of the elderly. After filling in the form and verification of the staff, the payment will be issued on the social security card on a monthly basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;It&#39;s not a joke, it is really a hair.&quot; Mr. Xie of Huangfeng Town, Pengshan District this year is the youngest grandson of Luo Shuwen, a century-old man. He introduced to the southern weekend that there are 1,500 yuan of older allowances per month and 100 yuan of NTunnon pensions on time to issue a grandma&#39;s social security card.逢年过节或者生日宴，也会有政府的人前来看望，“有时候封红包，有时候是带点慰问品”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;罗淑文今年101岁，她还有一个小自己5岁的妹妹，也活到耄耋之年。谢先生介绍，奶奶出生于大户人家，读过私塾，属于有文化的“大小姐”，规矩很多，“吃饭的时候不能翘腿，手不能抬太高。小时候很害怕奶奶”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;罗淑文在人生中途也“吃过很多苦”，很早丈夫便撒手人寰，她一个人支撑起整个家族。 “她就像我们家的CEO。”谢先生说，奶奶直到晚年，儿孙满堂，才又开始享起清福。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“前几天还跟她开玩笑，争取再过几年，咱们领3500（高龄津贴）。”谢先生说，眉山市整理出全市的百岁老人名单，制作了一份百岁老人名录手册，发放了他们一份。翻阅这份名录，百岁老人足足有好几百人，光108岁的老人就有几十位。 “一说百岁老人，110周岁，网友觉得不可想象，我们这里真有不少。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>