<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[第十届北京香山论坛，高端对话探讨全球安全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:37:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held at the Beijing International Convention Center from October 29th to 31st. With the theme of &quot;Common Security and Lasting Peace&quot;, the forum is the largest since the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, and the number of foreign representatives has reached the highest level ever. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[神舟十六号航天员乘组平安抵京]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:44:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office, the astronauts who successfully completed the Shenzhou 16 manned mission The team arrived safely in Beijing on a mission flight on October 31, 2023. Leaders of the Space Station Application and Development Stage Flight Mission Headquarters came to the airport to greet them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arriving in Beijing, the three astronauts will enter the isolation and recovery period, undergo comprehensive medical examinations and health assessments, and arrange for rest. Afterwards, he will meet with the news media collectively in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[县文联有奖征文，获奖者多是内部人：如此吃相太难看丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259655]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In a prize-winning essay competition sponsored by the Federation of Literary and Art Circles at the county level, most of the winners are members of the editorial boards of publications under the Federation of Literary and Art Circles. He has edited 12 award-winning works, nearly half of them. This &quot;big event&quot; in the literary world has attracted a lot of attention recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Huashang Daily, the real-name authentication was the WeChat public account &quot;Yuzhou Xinsheng&quot; (Yuzhou is the old name of Fangcheng County) of the Henan Federation of Literary and Art Circles. On October 26, an article titled &quot;&quot;Qingfeng&quot; was published. Fangcheng&#39;s article &quot;The list of prize-winning essays for literary and artistic works announced&quot; stated that the &quot;Qingfeng Fangcheng&quot; prize-winning essay competition jointly sponsored by the Fangcheng County Commission for Discipline Inspection and the Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles was a complete success, and 25 works won one prize each. Second and third prizes and encouragement awards (this is the original text, but the announced list of winning works is actually only 23). What is shocking is that among the 23 award-winning works shown on the list, 12 are written by the same person &quot;Qiao Junli&quot;, including 1 first prize, 1 second prize, 4 third prizes, Encouragement awards for 6 articles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One person has won almost half of the awards. With such strength and talent, who is Qiao Junli? The list of editorial board members of &quot;Voices of Yuzhou&quot; attached at the end of the article shows that Qiao Junli is the editor-in-chief of this publication. An article previously published by the official social media account of the Fangcheng County Procuratorate showed that Qiao Junli is also the vice chairman of the Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles. The Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles is one of the organizers of this essay competition, and &quot;Voices of Yuzhou&quot; is the organizer of the event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking a closer look at the list of winners, at least 18 of the 23 award-winning works were written by members of the editorial board of &quot;Voices of Yuzhou&quot;. In addition to Qiao Junli&#39;s 12 articles, there is also Chief Editor Guo Shuan (Chairman of Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles) won the second prize for one of his works; Xiong Mouxiang, deputy editor-in-chief, won second prize and third prize for two works respectively; deputy editor Li Mouyan, editorial board member Liang Moufeng, Planner Wu Mouhua also won an award for one article each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I organized a prize-winning essay competition, and more than one of my own won the prize. There were also more than ten articles that won the prize at the same time, which is really amazing. &quot;Qingfeng Square City&quot;, where is the Qingfeng? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As we all know, in order to ensure fairness and impartiality in various formal public competitions, selections and other activities, the judges must remain neutral and should not have any interest in any contestant, and usually stipulate that one person can only win one award. . Even the lottery promotions organized by many commercial enterprises stipulate that employees and their families cannot participate, otherwise even if they win, they will be invalid. Not to mention that the Federation of Literary and Art Circles, as a social organization, is supported by public finance in China and is a public institution. As the organizer and organizer of the event, Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles and its affiliated publications should maintain an objective and neutral stance to ensure the fairness of the award selection. As a result, the leaders of the Federation of Literary and Art Circles and members of the editorial board of the publication participated in the competition in person and won most of the awards. If you are both a referee and an athlete, how can you talk about the fairness of the game? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first Yangtze River Reading Award held by &quot;Dushu&quot; in 2000, Wang Hui, editor-in-chief of &quot;Dushu&quot;, and Qian Liqun, a judge, both won awards for their works, which caused huge controversy. Self-evaluation and self-awarding are of course inconsistent with the principle of fairness. To put it bluntly, in a sense, it is &quot;sharing the spoils.&quot; If the author believes that his work is good enough to qualify for the award, he should avoid suspicion. Not only should he not serve as a judge, he may even have to resign from the relevant position of the organizer, otherwise he should not participate in the award evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The essay competition in Fangcheng County may also involve the issue of private allocation of public funds. Based on the bonus amount alone, this may not seem like a big deal. The first prize in the competition is only 500 yuan per article, the second prize is 400 yuan per article, the third prize is 300 yuan per article, and the encouragement prize is 200 yuan per article. Editor-in-chief Qiao won awards for 12 of his works, and the total bonus was only 3,300 yuan. However, Fangcheng County was once a poor county, and it was only removed from poverty in 2019. According to the 2022 Government Work Report of Fangcheng County, the county&#39;s GDP in 2021 is 29.3 billion yuan. Based on the county&#39;s more than 870,000 people in the seventh census in 2020, the per capita GDP is about 33,000 yuan, and the per capita disposable income of urban residents 33,574 yuan, and the per capita disposable income of rural residents is 16,315 yuan. In other words, the bonus Editor-in-Chief Qiao received from this prize-winning event is equivalent to 1/10 of the county’s annual per capita disposable income in cities and towns and 1/5 of the county’s annual per capita disposable income of farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this prize-winning essay competition jointly sponsored by the Discipline Inspection Commission and the Federation of Literary and Art Circles, the source of prize money is probably financial funds. In such an essay competition, almost all the winners are from the same family, and one person won nearly half of the awards. People have to suspect that this is a clever pretext to use public funds to pay for themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is also a possibility that no one is interested in the essay competition, so the leaders of the Federation of Literary and Art Circles have to take action personally. According to the above, this essay competition will start on November 20, 2022, and will close on June 30. Although &quot;literary enthusiasts from all walks of life responded actively, mobilized extensively, and devoted themselves to creation,&quot; only 49 works were collected in more than half a year. It can be seen that there are not many &quot;literary enthusiasts&quot; in Fangcheng County, or they are not interested in such competitions, so few people submitted articles, and the quality of the submissions was also poor. In order to avoid the embarrassing situation of no one winning the award, Editor-in-Chief Qiao had to add his own works to the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if this is the case, the Federation of Literary and Art Circles cannot shirk its responsibility. As an organization of local literary and art workers, shouldn’t the Federation of Literary and Art Circles know how many literary workers and lovers there are in their county? It should be possible to estimate how many responses the essay call will receive. For a competition that is known to be uninterested, it is still planned and organized, and in the end one of one&#39;s own people comes forward to support the appearance and win the prize. This further strengthens the suspicion of &quot;creating a clever name to pay for oneself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, similar phenomena do not only exist in Fangcheng County, but there are many other more serious ones. For example, the top leader of a state-owned enterprise in Yunnan once distributed tens of millions of yuan in &quot;rewards&quot; to himself under various names, but was eventually punished for corruption and other crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the organizers of this essay competition is the County Commission for Discipline Inspection, but it is ironic that such a scandal has occurred. Under the attention of public opinion, the Fangcheng County Federation of Literary and Art Circles has deleted the list of winners and claimed that it was a &quot;preliminary evaluation result&quot; that was released without the consent of the organizer. The next step will be to organize experts in the city to re-evaluate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fangcheng County also set up a special investigation team for this purpose. In the early morning of October 31, a situation statement was issued. The preliminary investigation determined that there were problems in the selection process and the selection results were invalid. As for the subsequent investigation and handling, &quot; released in due course. The public is looking forward to the final results of the investigation team. Perhaps the most appropriate solution is to cancel this essay solicitation and recover the funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[反向合资，中外车企探索合作新模式丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259659]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:02:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1408&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf . png&quot; data-key=&quot;256200&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, GAC Group issued an announcement that the board of directors reviewed and approved the &quot; Announcement on Related Transactions Regarding the Reorganization of GAC Mitsubishi.&quot; GAC Group acquired 30% and 20% of the equity of GAC Mitsubishi held by Mitsubishi Motors Co., Ltd. and Mitsubishi Corporation respectively for a consideration of 1 yuan. After the reorganization is completed, GAC Mitsubishi will become a wholly-owned subsidiary of GAC Group, and GAC Aian will Utilize the GAC Mitsubishi plant to increase production and expand capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is not just Mitsubishi. With the rise of China&#39;s local car brands in recent years, joint venture brands such as Suzuki, Renault, Acura, Jeep, etc. have gradually withdrawn from the Chinese market. Some car companies will choose to use another model. Cooperate with domestic enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Stellantis Group, the world’s fourth largest automobile manufacturer, and Leapmotor jointly announced that Stellantis Group plans to invest approximately 1.5 billion euros (approximately 11.6 billion yuan) to acquire approximately 20% of Leapmotor. % of the equity and obtained 2 seats on the board of directors of Leapmotor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with Volkswagen&#39;s acquisition of approximately 4.99% of Xpeng Motors&#39; equity for approximately US$700 million in July, Leapao&#39;s cooperation with Stellantis is more in-depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stellantis will not only participate in the Chinese market as a strategic investor of Leapmotor, but the two parties will also form a joint venture company, Leapmotor International, to jointly develop the international market. Leapmotor holds 49% of the shares and Stellantis Group Holds 51% of shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 1984, Beijing Jeep, the first Sino-foreign joint venture car company, was born. Foreign car brands came to China with technology and brands. China&#39;s modern automobile industry has gone through nearly 40 years of development with the &quot;market for technology&quot; model. In 2017, in the face of fierce competition and technological progress in China&#39;s new energy vehicle market, foreign car companies have begun to explore new models of cooperation with Chinese car companies, and &quot;reverse joint ventures&quot; are becoming a new option. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/frontier -risk-and-preparedness&quot;>;&lt;u>;OpenAI forms new team to assess &quot;catastrophic risks&quot; of artificial intelligence&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 26, artificial intelligence Intelligence research company OpenAI announced the formation of a new team, Preparedness, to assess and mitigate &quot;catastrophic risks&quot; associated with artificial intelligence. The team&#39;s main mission is to &quot;track, assess, predict and protect&quot; potential major problems caused by artificial intelligence, and work to mitigate &quot;chemical, biological and radiological threats&quot;, as well as the &quot;autonomous replicating&quot; behavior of artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : With the development and application of artificial intelligence technology, human society is also facing a series of challenges in industrial development models and regulatory models that go beyond traditional experience. Many countries have drafted and formulated new regulatory measures on artificial intelligence, but people must be the ones to untie the bell. The active participation and action of large model manufacturers will be a force to help artificial intelligence develop better. (Recommended by: Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cArAd1qxXVblfdwAAqTk5g&quot;>;&lt;u>;Huawei releases unmanned open-pit mine solution&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25 On September 1, Huawei, together with China Huaneng Group, Xingsheng Open-pit Mine, Jiugang Group, and Tongli Heavy Industry, jointly released the &quot;Unmanned Solution for Open-pit Mines&quot;, in which key unmanned technologies such as heavy-duty remote control and driverless driving have been commercialized on a large scale. , the efficiency is the same as that of manual operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remote control of open pit mine reinstallation can realize the transition from human-machine interaction to machine-machine interaction for piercing and shoveling. The piercing operation ranges from 1 person and 1 drill on site to 1 person and 3 drills remotely. The mining and installation site is 100% manual. 80% remote automatic remote control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Pain points such as poor mining conditions and high safety risks have long restricted the development of the coal industry. In March 2020, eight ministries and commissions of the State Council issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Accelerating the Development of Intelligent Coal Mines&quot;, proposing that all types of coal mines will be basically intelligent by 2035, and coal mining may become a pioneer in the intelligent transformation of traditional industries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin .qq.com/s/YWywXP_xGCpSUqkijrXv3A&quot;>;&lt;u>;China Telecom Research Institute completed the world’s first operator NR&amp;nbsp;NTN live network test&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25 On the same day, the China Telecommunications Research Institute announced that it would work closely with China Telecom Shanghai Emergency Communications Bureau and China Telecom Satellite Corporation, jointly with Beijing Jiefeng Chuangzhi Technology and Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications to complete the world&#39;s first operator NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp; based on geosynchronous orbit satellites. &lt;/span>;NTN (non-terrestrial network) terminals are directly connected to the satellite live network environment test and verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The test results show that under the 5MHz low-bandwidth spectrum resource, the NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;NTN network based on geosynchronous orbit satellites can still provide stable voice, SMS and broadband data services. As an important portable solution in the national emergency communication service system and comprehensive information service system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Satellite communications are an important part of 5G-Advanced and 6G, and the three major operators are actively exploring them. In September 2023, China Mobile joined hands with ZTE and Keysight Technologies to complete the first domestic operator NR&amp;nbsp;NTN low-orbit satellite laboratory simulation verification. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;04&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.excision .bio/_files/ugd/80a6fd_de98df6a38d042658595374af17d658a.pdf&quot;>;&lt;u>;The world’s first HIV gene editing therapy clinical trial data released&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25, American biotechnology company Excision announced positive interim data from its Phase 1/2 clinical trial of its ongoing CRISPR gene therapy EBT-101 in the treatment of HIV-1 (a type of AIDS virus) infection. Among the first three clinical trial participants, treatment with EBT-101 resulted in no serious adverse events or dose-limiting toxicities, and all reported adverse events were mild and reversible; all participants had &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; in their blood. span>; EBT-101 was detected and the treatment resulted in positive biodistribution; these data support advancing this clinical trial to the next dose level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;EBT-101 is a therapy that uses CRISPR gene editing in patients, aiming to cure HIV infection through a single intravenous infusion. It is also the world&#39;s first human clinical trial using CRISPR gene editing to treat AIDS. . The therapy was approved by the U.S. FDA for human clinical trials at the end of 2021 and received fast-track status from the FDA in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The existing standard treatment for AIDS is antiretroviral therapy, which can prevent the HIV virus from replicating in the body, but cannot clear the HIV virus. Patients need to receive long-term continuous treatment. The discovery of CRISPR was a breakthrough in the search for a potential cure for AIDS, and EBT-101 is the first CRISPR therapy to target an integrated virus in humans. The destination of &quot;curing HIV infection&quot; is still far away, but there are people on the road and continue to make progress. (Recommended by: Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“快枪手”邱礼涛的反驳：“我花的时间没有人们想象得那么短”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259633]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[依法查处，数百个非法涉外气象探测站向境外传输数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this year, national security agencies, together with meteorological and security departments, have carried out special management of foreign-related meteorological detection nationwide in accordance with the law. , investigated more than 10 overseas meteorological equipment agents, inspected more than 3,000 foreign-related meteorological stations, and found that hundreds of illegal foreign-related meteorological detection stations transmit meteorological data overseas in real time, widely distributed in more than 20 provinces across the country, posing risks to our national security Hidden danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256145&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Illegal weather detection equipment installed by an overseas company&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Set Illegal meteorological detection equipment in our residential areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of these illegal foreign-related meteorological detection sites are directly funded by overseas governments, and some observation points are set up around sensitive places such as military units and military industrial enterprises to conduct altitude measurements. Approval and GPS positioning; some are deployed in China&#39;s main grain-producing areas to correlate the growth of China&#39;s crops and grain yields; some are even transmitted to foreign official meteorological agencies in real-time at long-term, high-frequency, and multiple points to serve foreign homeland security and weather monitoring. The relevant equipment is small in size, easy to install, difficult to find, and can automatically collect and transmit over the network in real time. For relevant foreign-related meteorological detection activities, they failed to apply for an administrative license for foreign-related meteorological detection from our meteorological authorities, failed to submit meteorological data to our meteorological authorities, and transmitted meteorological data overseas without the approval of our meteorological authorities, violating the &quot;Foreign-related Meteorological Observations and Data&quot; &quot;Administrative Measures&quot;, &quot;Data Security Law&quot; and other relevant regulations. National security agencies, in conjunction with meteorological and confidentiality departments, investigate and deal with relevant illegal activities in accordance with the law, and promptly block illegal activities of exporting meteorological data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有丢下战友的习惯”：走进“生死在一起连”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:30:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin/ &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In northern Guangdong in September, the hot and humid air after the rain is breathless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the roar of engines, unmanned reconnaissance, firepower raids, impact breakthroughs... According to the company&#39;s &quot;roundabout and outflank&quot; tactics, the Second Company quickly took over Set fire points from multiple directions to complete the mission of seizing control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second company of a brigade of the Army&#39;s 74th Group Army conducting an offensive and defensive drill. In recent years, the officers and soldiers of this company have participated in various types of offensive and defensive warfare drills and competition exercises for many times. The training footprints have been all over the coast of the South China Sea, the Lingnan jungle, the depths of the desert and the Gobi plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company was born in the flames of the Anti-Japanese War and grew up in the flames of war. It has the title of &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; and &quot;Unite and Grow Together&quot;. , fight together, live and die together”. Entering the period of peace-building, the company has been reformed and moved three times, but it has always inherited the spirit of &quot;life and death together&quot; and worked hard to forge the company into &quot;a hard piece of steel.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life and Death Together&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soldier Wu Shanjie will never forget the scene when company commander Zhang Peijin carried him on the plateau competition field. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the heat in Yunnan was unbearable. At that time, the competition between &quot;good warriors&quot; was in full swing: a ten-kilometer run, bunker construction, reconnaissance, bomb dropping... There were many competitions, and they were very physically demanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At first, Zhang Peijin led six soldiers from his company to participate in the competition and was always far ahead. However, during the last armed three-kilometer run event, Wu Shanjie suddenly suffered from leg cramps and fell to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to regulations, one team member is allowed to fall behind in this project without affecting the overall assessment results. Wu Shanjie, who was in unbearable pain, asked the company commander to put him down so as not to affect the final result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Peijin, who has participated in multiple subject assessments continuously, has already seen his clothes soaked with sweat and his physical strength is close to the limit. Looking at Wu Shanjie who fell to the ground, he gritted his teeth and said, &quot;&#39;Life and Death Company&#39; has no habit of leaving behind its comrades.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As soon as he finished speaking, Zhang Peijin picked up Wu Shanjie on his back and sprinted towards the finish line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the long journey of the last kilometer, Zhang Peijin got tired, so other comrades took over and took turns carrying Wu Shanjie until the end. The second team, which could have achieved better results, only finished fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Of course there will be regrets.&quot; Zhang Peijin confessed to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;But compared with the results, it is more important for the comrades to stand side by side and rush to the finish line. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Never abandoning any teammate is a glorious tradition inherited by the Second Company from the smoke-filled war years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the honor room of the Second Company, a sculpture based on the story of a stretcher silently tells the origin of the company&#39;s name and also interprets the meaning of &quot;life and death together.&quot; &quot;The spiritual connotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 1946, the company was ordered to cover the retreat of the main force. Soldier Zhu Jicai was shot in the leg and injured. Due to the hot weather and lack of medical treatment, his wounds became infected and ulcerated, and he was unable to walk. In order not to drag down the company, Zhu Jicai took the initiative to ask his comrades to put him down and continue marching. But faced with the encircling enemies, his comrades were unwilling to leave him behind. They made a simple stretcher out of branches and vines and carried him while marching and fighting with the red flag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the critical juncture of life and death, the entire company dealt with dozens of times the enemy for more than 80 days. Not a single soldier was left behind. The mission was successfully completed. After the war, the company was ordered to Awarded the honorary title of &quot;Life and Death Together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past seventy years, the company has participated in more than 120 battles such as the Benxi Defense War, the Tashan Blockade, and the self-defense counterattack against Vietnam. Entering a new era, it has successively completed major tasks such as adjustment of the organizational structure, relocation of defenses, and cross-regional base-based exercises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company fought in the north and south, its numbers were adjusted several times, and its location was constantly changed, but the glorious tradition of &quot;living and dying together&quot; has never changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the war years, my comrades rushed to the battlefield together. They dared to hand their backs to me, and I was willing to take bullets for them. This is the difference between life and death. Let&#39;s &#39;spirit together.&quot; After serving in the army for 11 years, Zi Guangyong has his own views on company spirit. He said that in peaceful times, this spirit is more reflected in daily training and every detail of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He gave an example. On the training ground, if a comrade was feeling unwell, he would help him carry his gun; during the exercise, if the task was difficult, they would complete it together. &quot;It&#39;s like a football match. You can&#39;t win the game just by playing alone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; review the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/30/41dc7516ed.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/41dc7516ed .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; relived the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Zhang Yongjin/photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Practice more with brothers&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; &quot;These five years in the Second Company have taught me what brotherhood is, and also made me regard the army as my second home.&quot; Tibetan young man Zeren Tashi told Southern Weekend reporters. It’s hard to imagine that when he first came to the army, he couldn’t even speak Mandarin well and “didn’t want to chat with others.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2018, Zeren Tashi enlisted in the army from Ganzi, Sichuan. From the snowy plateau to the southeastern coast, Zeren Tashi clearly felt acclimated to the new environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Worried that others would not understand what he said, and not wanting to worry his family by talking to them, Zeren Tashi, who was already introverted and sensitive, became increasingly withdrawn and depressed. During breaks, he would always go to the basketball court to play alone. When other comrades came over to play, he would quit and give up the court to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Zeren Tashi fell into deep self-doubt, his comrades came. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bing Luojiang came from Guangxi in the same year. He was carefully aware of Zeren Tashi&#39;s emotions and used his own Mandarin as an example, but he was still a &quot;social cow&quot; , encouraging Zeren Tashi. From that time on, the enthusiastic Luo Jiang took Zeren Tashi to chat with his comrades every day to help him actively integrate into collective life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company also opened &quot;a window&quot; specifically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Whenever I encounter Chinese characters I don&#39;t know during study, my comrades will explain them to me carefully.&quot; Zeren Tashi said, and the company commander also encouraged He must be brave enough to show himself in front of everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, during the subject demonstration activity organized by the Second Company, Zeren Tashi gave a sharing lesson to the company, and his confident behavior won the audience. Applause, &quot;There was a great sense of satisfaction at that time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Second Company has more than a dozen ethnic minority soldiers from Tibetan, Zhuang, Li, Mulao and other ethnic groups. Some of them are leaving their hometown for the first time, and some are recent college graduates, with different personalities and physical qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How to make them feel the warmth of home in the company, the company has its own &quot;unique secrets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company produces a &quot;Knowledge of Soldiers&quot; for each recruit, including various aspects such as physical condition, family situation, interests and hobbies. &quot;In daily life, the backbone of the company cadres will take the initiative to talk to the recruits, understand their actual situation, and help them solve the difficulties in life.&quot; Instructor Wang Gaosheng told Southern Weekend reporters that during the training process, the squad leader will also teach them hand-in-hand. Integrate into the company as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he first joined the Second Company in 2022, Mulao soldier Qin Guoxing had not had time to get familiar with the company, but reality poured cold water on him. He is a graduate of the 211 College and is regarded as the &quot;proud son of heaven&quot; in the eyes of his parents and friends. However, in the second company where there are many experts, his business ability is often only at the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tin Guoxing felt frustrated and often tossed and turned at night and couldn&#39;t sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Comrade Wang Lei saw Tan Guoxing like this and decided to help. Wang Lei is a &quot;veteran&quot; with solid and outstanding abilities and qualities. He took the initiative to play the role of a small instructor, training with Tan Guoxing, and teaching skills step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Qin Guoxing and Wang Lei have become a &quot;pair&quot; with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In daily training, Wang Lei led Qin Guoxing to strengthen physical training, while Qin Guoxing helped Wang Lei answer questions in theoretical studies. In helping each other and competing, the two not only improved their performance, but also forged a deep friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Practice more with your brothers and you won&#39;t feel like you are walking alone.&quot; Qin Guoxing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Big things on my mind&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These are all obtained by our ancestors with blood and sweat. You need to find a way to fill the remaining vacancies. .&quot; On the day of joining the company, the company commander led the recruits to stand in front of the wall of honor, pointing to the wall of honor medals and saying, &quot;If the honor of the company is lost from your hands, it will be a disservice to the revolutionary martyrs of the second company.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;A unit with excellent military training results&quot;, &quot;A top company in basic subject competition training&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of an advanced unit&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of a model company&quot;... Enter the second company In the camp, a &quot;luxurious wall&quot; covered with honorary medals is shocking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past few decades, the Second Company has been rated as an advanced company in comprehensive construction or an advanced unit of the &quot;Four Irons&quot; for 27 consecutive years, and has won the second-class collective merit 7 times, 18 times of collective third-class merit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Lan Zhihao was still in the first company of the recruits, he had seen this wall through the window. He knew that this must be a heroic and honorary unit, and he was very eager to be assigned to the second company after the recruit training was completed. As a result, his wish came true. He was surprised, happy and full of energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zeren Tashi&#39;s mood seems a bit complicated. He is proud to be a member of the &quot;benchmark company&quot; of the entire brigade, but also worried about not being able to keep up. The pace of training. In his words, &quot;I feel like I&#39;m done, and I might be choked in training.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Defending the honor of the heroic company has become a major issue that weighs on the minds of every officer and soldier of the second company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in the main battle unit with so many strong men, such a goal is easy to say, but to achieve it requires extraordinary hard work and sweat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, a major training mission was held in Yunnan, and company commander Zhang Peijin led the entire company to participate. In order to win the victory, the Second Company began to make key preparations from the beginning of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;One month before the exercise, we organized soldier training during the day and worked overtime at night to deduce plans and study tactics.&quot; Zhang Peijin recalled, &quot;The backbone of the company also accompanied us. Stay up late with me, just to increase the chance of winning in the final battle.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite adequate preparation, the accident still happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the live-fire shooting session, Zhang Peijin and artillery technician Xiang Jinwen&#39;s company command vehicle suddenly experienced a transmission failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When changing the target and shooting, I can only hear the sound of the motor inside, but the shell cannot be fired.&quot; Xiang Jinwen made an instant judgment , &quot;It must be a jammed bullet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Without any hesitation, Xiang Jinwen quickly raised the armored vehicle&#39;s gun, opened the back cover to determine the specific location of the jammed bullet. , and removed the fixing device of the artillery, and took out the shells with bare hands. The entire process, from problem arose to troubleshooting, took just over a minute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the artillery roared and the shells accurately hit the target, Xiang Jinwen&#39;s hanging heart was completely relieved. He said, &quot;This is a super-level performance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the Second Company stood out in the inspection and evaluation and was rated as an &quot;advanced unit against actual troops.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bite the &quot;hard bones&quot; together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2015 4 In August, the company made personnel adjustments, and Xiang Jinwen was recommended to the Second Company for development because of his &quot;excellent professional quality.&quot; He feels very lucky because the Second Company is the model unit in the division. From the cadres to the recruits, everyone is proud to be here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To date, Xiang Jinwen has stayed in the Second Company for more than eight years, and he has experienced several important milestones of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, in order to adapt to future combat needs, the second company installed brand-new main battle equipment, which has better maneuverability, stronger firepower, and can achieve rapid Intersperse to achieve the effect of surprising and defeating the enemy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All kinds of new equipment made the entire company excited. However, the ensuing practical difficulties of &quot;lack of teaching plans, lack of standards, and lack of talents&quot; also plagued the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The equipment is highly informatized and coincides with the retirement of many experienced technical backbones. The new equipment has brought us great challenges.&quot; Xiang Jinwen recalled, &quot;Every time the live-fire shooting results were very unsatisfactory.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Short-stop shooting requires that the armored vehicle must pause briefly and fire while moving. Aiming and shooting puts forward higher requirements for the cooperation of the driver, communicator and shooter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;From parking to launching to destroy the target and then to the vehicle moving, the whole process only takes six to eight seconds.&quot; Xiang Jinwen said, &quot;If the cooperation is not good, , it is easy for the vehicle to impact again before the shells are fired.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The field training time is very tight, in order to squeeze out time to get along with teammates. Xiang Jinwen had almost no rest during that period and stayed on the training ground with his comrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The heat in July and August is unbearable. After being exposed to the sun, the temperature inside the armored vehicle can reach more than 50 degrees. If you stay in the vehicle for a long time, it will not last long. Clothes can be squeezed out of water. Xiang Jinwen described that as soon as he got off the armored vehicle, he felt dizzy and &quot;wanted to vomit but couldn&#39;t.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fortunately, Xiang Jinwen and his team performed at a high level every time they fired live ammunition, and also achieved excellent results in the assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;显然，装备迭代更新带来的不仅是装备适应的难题，还需要与之相匹配的战术手段和战法打法，推动连队备战转型和能力升级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;为了尽快形成战斗力，时任连长王小林带领全连干部骨干自制规范、自编教案，“摸着石头过河”进行战术演练。他们白天扎在训练场，晚上铆在装备间，两个多月潜心钻研，最终实现了战斗力全面提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“那个时候，每天晚上都是熬夜钻研，经常到凌晨一两点。”对于当时熬夜加训的情形，向进文记忆犹新，隔天一早也不赖床，继续早起学习新装备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在同类型连队中，二连第一个接受检验，第一个开展课目示范，实现了旅队“当年形成战斗力”的目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为旅队里的“标兵连”，二连上下一心攻坚克难的案例数不胜数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“连队日常担负着多个科目攻关和战法研究重任，但这些工作艰巨而又复杂，仅靠我个人的力量根本没有办法完成。”每当陷入到瓶颈时，身边的战友都会主动围拥到张培金身边，白天一起在训练场上打磨优化战术战法，晚上加班加点总结经验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张培金说，“我知道我不是一个人在战斗，我还有一帮兄弟帮我一同分担。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在今年旅组织的排战术考核中，二连一排被抽中代表连队参与考核。在与十几支分队同台竞技后，二连凭借在无人装备操作上的优势，远远把其他单位甩在后面，在考核中夺得第一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“为了迎接考核，我们排夜以继日进行操练，尤其是突出夜间无人装备使用。现在所有主战装备操作手，都熟练掌握了连队无人装备的操作使用方法。”排长刘楚十分自豪，“这块硬骨头，我们一起啃了下来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生冯嘉怡、蒋来、林曦、张馨怡对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄防长绍伊古：对话应该以公平对等、互相尊重的原则为基础]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“地产界胖东来”，藏在河南县城里]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/3yjITVsPZdpbDWKMqUtLmROFxXokwM5Z19pD9tM5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/3yjITVsPZdpbDWKMqUtLmROFxXokwM5Z19pD9tM5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256134&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;冶都开发的一个楼盘。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者卫琳聪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在头部房企纷纷爆雷的当下，藏在河南县城里的小房企却引起了外界的注意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为前来参观的人太多，甚至影响了公司的正常运转，河南冶都置业有限公司（下称冶都）将对外接待时间限定为一周一次，每位参观者300元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这家扎根濮阳市清丰县的小型房企2022年接待了三百多组参观，不止地产同行，医疗、教育、餐饮等各类企业纷至沓来，称其为“地产界胖东来”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与超市界传奇胖东来一样，冶都也力求提供超一线水准的产品和服务。在其所建楼盘，标配健身房和阅读室，小区垃圾桶一天刷三次，员工餐厅下水道一天洗两次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，冶都2010年才开始从事房地产开发，10年间只开发了6个楼盘，全部位于清丰县。这个地处河南东北部的县城总人口75万，2022年全县GDP237.7亿元，大约只有河南建业地产2021年收入的一半。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清丰县向南170公里，位于商丘市的河南金沙置业集团有限公司（下称金沙）同样访客盈门。2023年10月底，北京一家地产咨询机构将金沙作为标杆房企，组织12省40余家房企高管前来参观交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金沙的体量也不大。公司16年来开发了40个楼盘，分布在商丘8个县市。这个豫东城市2022年GDP在河南18地市中排名第7，刚刚突破3000亿元，不到郑州的1/4。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，在均价五千多元的县城里，金沙的楼盘卖出了过万的价格，小区物业还为业主提供婚嫁服务、免费体检等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位河南地产业资深从业者告诉南方周末记者，其实在2021年之前，本土地产圈很少注意冶都、金沙这样的县城房企。“现在这个阶段，大家都在思考，房地产未来的发展方向可能是做产品、做服务。”其中一位说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;县城里的“豪宅”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2018年，冶都在清丰县交付了第二个楼盘。这个楼盘拥有淡黄色的外立面，欧式大门在县城鹤立鸡群。正是在前一年，冶都提出“精细化”理念，公司总部也建在这个楼盘旁边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月底，冶都将交付第7个项目。加入公司十余年的公司高管孙朝阳告诉南方周末记者，为了让外立面更好看，公司在上面花费了4个月时间。“色彩、线条一遍遍调整，把几个涂料供应商都搞得没脾气了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一处已经交付的小区，楼下的绿化树被修成了圆球形。一位工作人员带着河南腔对南方周末记者说，这是公司去日本学习回来后改进的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小区的保洁员看到访客立马停下手中的扫帚，微笑问好，年轻的脸上还化着妆。按照工作要求，她一天要用高压水枪把小区每一个垃圾桶从里到外清洗三遍。冶都招聘保洁员要求45岁以下，每月工资5000多元，比县里平均水平高一倍。安居客显示，目前冶都在售楼盘每平方米均价5000元左右，普遍比同区域房源价格高七八百元。尤其是在大本营清丰县，当地新房均价仅3000元左右，冶都堪称县城里的“豪宅”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金沙则在近日的官方微信推送中称，其位于商丘夏邑县的一个楼盘，在门口移植了“7棵珍稀松树”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者以购房者名义咨询，金沙置业顾问表示，公司开发的楼盘价格普遍较区域项目更高，高端项目均价能达到1.5万/平方米。据安居客数据，这一价格比商丘新房均价高出1万元/平方米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更早喊出“精细化”口号的是永威置业集团有限公司（下称永威）。永威置业2005年成立于河南郑州。河南房地产圈曾流传一句顺口溜：“永威有三宝，建材、景观、物业好。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金沙直接把永威的顺口溜拿来用。永威一位负责人告诉南方周末记者，为了学习永威，金沙创始人杨利民甚至在永威开发的楼盘买了房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰德咨询公司总裁宋延庆从事房地产咨询和投资二十多年，他向南方周末记者解释，精细化是在建筑过程中对品质进行把控。假设地面、墙面、天花板上有三条缝，精细化施工要保证三条缝对齐，避免出现错缝、破坏美感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他介绍，早在2013年前后，各大房企就已提出精细化理念，但房地产市场迅猛发展，高杠杆、高周转模式大行其道，规模取代质量成为更重要的指标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;永威从2007年开始走精细化路线，以郑州为大本营，累计开发36个项目。其位于郑州北龙湖的高端项目均价超过6万元/平方米，是当地知名豪宅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初永威也曾向同行学习。在郑州本土房企康桥地产负责品牌营销工作的张莹倩告诉南方周末记者，康桥就是依靠品质打出名声，后起的永威曾从康桥挖走几十人的团队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张莹倩入行超十年，她表示，各大房企发展之初，都在品质上竞争，不惜成本打造标杆项目。“从0到1的时候主要是依靠产品，所以都走精细化路线，因为只能通过产品来获得第一批种子客户。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尤其在河南房地产市场上，由于房企数量众多，对品质的竞争更为激烈。中国房地产业协会数据显示，2022年河南房企数量超过8000家，位居全国第4。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过高速发展，郑州房企已度过原始积累阶段，而县城房企正在经历从0到1的突破，曾经发生在郑州市场的品质竞争正在县城重新上演。张莹倩透露，近两年金沙又从康桥地产高薪挖走营销、工程、设计等负责人。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;高杠杆的教训&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在棚改政策刺激下，2016年前后，河南房地产市场也开始起飞。国家统计局数据显示，2016年郑州商品房销售面积超过3000万平方米，较上一年增加一倍还多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“简直就像捡钱一样。”在冶都负责品牌策划的王志兴对南方周末记者说。那个时候，他在安阳市做新房销售代理，经常一开盘就清盘，销售火爆到连售楼部都不需要，打个广告语就开始卖房。各楼盘之间不比质量，更看重位置和价格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外来房企也更多地进入河南。继恒大、碧桂园之后，融创、金科、蓝光等规模房企相继在2016年前后进入河南攻城掠地。本土房企则排队上市，建业更是逐步下沉，到2019年覆盖了河南一百多个县级城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙朝阳亦回忆，当时县域市场也一片火热。“只要手里拿了地，不用关注什么产品，就能快速销售、快速回款。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但冶都反而放缓拿地，公司当时想要“慢一点、稳一点”，这和创业之初遭遇的挫折有关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年，冶都初涉房地产，创始人程晓锋曾通过钢材贸易赚到第一桶金，他的父亲在安阳钢铁集团工作，带领他从老家安阳到隔壁濮阳清丰县拿了一块地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1980年出生的程晓锋十几岁就进入社会闯荡，早年做过厨师、开过货车，在冶都引起关注后也极少公开露面。他长时间待在公司，几乎认识每一个员工，经常在公司讲起当年创业的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时在安阳、濮阳一带投资房地产门槛并不高。王志兴2011年入行，他记得当时只用交地价10%的保证金就能拿地，他代理销售的第一个项目占地70亩，只交了210万元就启动开发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙朝阳介绍，开发第一个楼盘时，公司自有资金少，主要靠银行、个人等外部借款。因为缺乏开发经验，项目亏了一个多亿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《凤凰周刊》报道，2012年，安阳爆发民间集资崩盘事件。当地自2009年起大兴民间借贷，产生了三百多家高息揽储公司，至少两百多亿资金卷入其中，流向地产、能源等领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地一位房企高管回忆，安阳集资对整个区域的金融环境产生了极大影响，银行开始抽贷，个人借款要求提前归还。冶都也受到影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是从第二个项目开始，冶都便不再借助外部融资。“就想着不能挣快钱。”孙朝阳说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当时的市场行情下，地价不断被推高。到了2018年，濮阳一亩地飙到180万元，只靠自有资金的冶都并无优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一重限制在于，冶都当时没有多少员工。县城企业招人难，人员储备也不足以支撑公司扩张。直到2020年，冶都发展了10年，员工人数才增加到一百名左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和冶都一样，金沙在前几年市场火爆时动作也不多，郑州地产圈的从业者们对其知之甚少。其中一位资深从业者总结，受资金和人员限制，在大房企狂飙突进的阶段，县域房企难以与其竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;逆势发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;河南的独特之处在于，县域市场依然给当地小房企留下了生存空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河南省政府公布的数据显示，2022年河南常住人口城镇化率为57.07%，这一数字比全国平均水平低8.15个百分点。清丰县统计局数据显示，2022年当地城镇化率仅35.12%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国性房企在大规模扩张时也曾进入县城市场，一度对本土小房企造成冲击。孙朝阳介绍，2018年前后，碧桂园、建业等相继进入清丰县，冲击之下，冶都的销量一度下滑20%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但县城房价低，利润空间有限，对大房企来说并不是重点市场。加之公司体量大，管理半径难以触达县城。经过几年发展，碧桂园在清丰县只开发了两个楼盘，建业则与当地开发商合作，以轻资产方式进行开发。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对扎根县城的小房企而言，这块利润较薄的市场却是安身立命之地。孙朝阳认为，区域市场的购房需求依然存在，尤其是一部分投资需求转换成了二次置业需求。通过精耕细作，在控制成本的前提下提高质量，县城房企在这部分客群中赚到了利润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年以来，在“三道红线”等房地产政策调控下，信贷环境收紧。叠加新冠疫情对经济环境的影响，高杠杆、高周转模式受到冲击，依靠这一模式发展起来的大房企纷纷爆雷。而县城里的小房企反而逆势发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙朝阳介绍，2020年冶都开始走出清丰县，3年间新开11个楼盘，员工增加了三百多人。这段时间市场不景气，县城地价回落，冶都抓住机会一口气拿了五百多亩地，土地成本比2018年高价期省了不止两个亿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;能逆势拿地源于公司负债率低。冶都用自有资金开发项目，不使用银行贷款，目前现金流在保证公司正常运转的情况下还有富余。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老板原话，我们可以停半年什么都不干。”王志兴说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样在2020年后快速发展的金沙，也在官方微信公号中宣称，公司负债率常年保持在5%-10%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/u4BoW0srd2cdubOGlD0MGp9PIheyOoeZb7GocKLC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/u4BoW0srd2cdubOGlD0MGp9PIheyOoeZb7GocKLC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256135&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;冶都将售楼部改造为生活体验馆，旁边学习胖东来开设了一家超市。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者卫琳聪/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“卖馍能挣几个钱？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在县城站稳脚跟后，扩张的欲望同样出现在小房企身上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年国庆假期后，金沙前往郑州和各大开发商会谈合作，想要进军郑州，在豪宅区北龙湖打造标杆项目。张莹倩参与了会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种从打造产品到规模扩张的路径让张莹倩感到熟悉。康桥地产在最初靠产品打出名声后，金融机构和咨询公司纷纷上门，劝说老板学习高周转模式，扩大规模。最终在2019年前后在上海建了分部，开始向南方扩张。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但刚走出河南就遭遇行业寒冬，康桥地产扩张受阻。如今，张莹倩又在朋友圈看到，当初劝说自己老板扩大规模的咨询公司，又前往金沙交流了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来找冶都合作的人也多起来，有些有钱，有些有地，开出优惠条件邀请他们去郑州、进北京。“行情不好的时候（寻求合作）会更多。”孙朝阳说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但冶都并没有答应。公司目前的发展规划依然没有超出濮阳所在的豫北地区。“谁都想往外走，但更应该认清自己。我们现在没有能力跑到外面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更大的问题是，高杠杆、高周转模式营造的规模神话已经破灭，房企还能走向哪里？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管逆势扩张，但冶都也难免受到市场环境影响。王志兴表示，现在公司在清丰的4个楼盘加起来，月销量才一百多套，以前一个楼盘就能达到这样的水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冶都想出的办法是向服务转型。2021年，程晓锋提出在小区开设面点房，售卖手工馒头。员工们觉得不可思议，“卖馍能挣几个钱？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这个想法还是被执行，并从面点房拓展到超市、干洗、家政等各项服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，冶都在总部旁边开了一家500平方米的超市。王志兴介绍，2022年仅为了学习如何开超市，公司就花了一百多万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同在河南的胖东来是重点学习对象。冶都超市配备了和胖东来同款戴森洗手池，斥资两万多元，还提供茶水、婴儿车、免费充电等服务。商品同样和胖东来一样自采自营，馒头、面条和豆芽甚至是自己生产的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;超市工作人员向南方周末记者介绍，公司计划在清丰县人流量大的地方再开三家同等体量的超市，小区里开设规模较小的店。但目前第一家店尚未盈利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冶都的想法是做衣食住行全链条的配套服务，未来还要做餐饮、开药店。不仅针对业主，也面向全县百姓。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“公司希望未来把服务作为核心赢利点，地产只是&#39;顺带&#39;。”孙朝阳说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，张莹倩、孙朝阳为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长相与年龄不符意味着什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259588]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;People are growing older all the time, but their appearance does not necessarily keep pace with their age. When the appearance does not match the age and clearly looks older or younger than the actual age, different people will have different explanations for this. Especially if you look older than your actual age, it is often interpreted as premature aging. In fact, many scientific studies support the reasoning that there are actually signs of aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A long-term follow-up heart study in Copenhagen found that gray hair, facial wrinkles and male baldness are several obvious signs of aging, which may indicate that people have a higher risk of myocardial infarction, especially People with much longer gray hair have a significantly higher risk than those without gray hair. In addition to these specific external characteristics, the general feeling of &quot;looking older&quot; also has reference significance for assessing health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to guess a person’s age based on visual information alone due to the interference of external factors such as clothing and grooming. In 2016, researchers from the Institute of Public Health at the University of Southern Denmark conducted a comparative study on nearly two hundred groups of identical twins and found that even if twins have the same genes and very similar looks, people can still tell the difference between their faces. Read the clues to aging too quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These elderly twins were over 70 years old as early as 2001. Researchers asked people to guess the age of the elderly people through their ID photos. The results found that whether it was changing their faces or dressing up, it would affect the age of the elderly people. People&#39;s perceptions of the age of the elderly. Statistics more than a decade later also show that the older twin is more likely to die earlier. Facial cues become a predictor of risk of survival or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although many studies have discovered some health secrets hidden behind the face, there are not many studies that systematically analyze the relationship between appearance and aging. In order to clarify what it means to look inconsistent with age, in March 2023, researchers from Erasmus University in the Netherlands and other institutions tried to investigate how people&#39;s perceived age is related to a series of aging by analyzing more data. relationship between diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Look younger and healthier&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As expected, the results were as expected. Corresponding to the higher risk of older-looking people, those who looked younger than they actually were Younger people, who are at lower risk for many age-related diseases, also have better cognitive function overall. Relevant research was published in the British Journal of Dermatology, providing a certain reference for scientific face reading. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of appearance and age inconsistency is very common in daily life. In order to understand this phenomenon more scientifically and deeply, we must first distinguish three concepts about age. In addition to sensory age, which can be assessed by people&#39;s appearance alone, chronological age and physiological age are also more valuable references for health and aging. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daniel W. Belsky, an associate professor at Columbia University School of Public Health who has long studied aging issues, told Southern Weekend reporters, “Actual age measures the time since birth, while physiological age It is a measure of health. A physiological age value can be understood as a person&#39;s typical health status at this actual age.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, according to the normal aging rate, a person in good health will Their biological age should be close to or even consistent with their actual age. But in reality, some people&#39;s biological age will deviate significantly from their actual age, showing an atypical health state. Among them, if the biological age is younger than the actual age, it means that the overall health status is better than that of the average person of the same age, while the biological age is greater than the actual age, the degree of aging is deeper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The analysis of sensory age in the latest research actually explores the possibility of identifying aging through a simple way of vision, and the results show that looking younger is indeed associated with a higher risk of various diseases. lower. Specifically, looking five years younger than your actual age has a significantly lower risk of osteoporosis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, cataracts, and hearing loss, as well as better cognitive performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These results are based on the analysis of health data of more than 2,600 European middle-aged and elderly people. It is worth noting that the age distribution of the people included in the study ranges from their fifties to their eighties and are in the process of age-related diseases. Significantly elevated stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people’s bodies are not necessarily young&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although current relevant research focuses on middle-aged and elderly people, it does not mean that the rhythm of maturity and aging is only in It starts to accelerate suddenly after entering middle age. There is evidence that among young people in their twenties and thirties, as their chronological age steadily increases, the gap in their biological ages begins to appear. Looking at specific manifestations, people who age faster have poorer physical abilities, cognitive decline, and brain aging. These people often feel that their health is getting worse and they look older. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant research was published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) in 2015. What&#39;s even more cruel is that these observed aging gaps occur between the ages of 26 and 38. The same 38-year-old is not yet middle-aged, but the physiological age of different people is obviously different. Daniel Belsky, now an associate professor in the Department of Epidemiology and Center for Aging Research at Columbia University, was involved in the study. Over a period of nearly 12 years, researchers recorded changes in a range of physiological indicators in nearly a thousand participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aging is a process that begins early in life. We can see signs of it in healthy young people, and some people age faster than others already at a young age. Therefore, maintaining a healthy lifestyle and seeking an environment with clean air and water are safe and reliable, and creating opportunities to participate in social interactions is also a priority.&quot; Daniel Belsky told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;In some aspects , this is all self-evident. But it is important to realize that even in youth, which we tend to think of as indestructible, our lifestyle and environment can influence the trajectory of our aging, with long-lasting consequences.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;At present, it is not easy to study aging, because compared with the life span of animals such as mice, which can be quickly observed in animal studies, the time span from birth to death in humans is much longer. After entering middle-aged and old age, the increase in age-related diseases makes it easier to observe people&#39;s aging. Relatively speaking, the signs of aging in young people are less easy to detect. However, when it comes to delaying aging, young people actually have more time and opportunities to make changes to improve their own health. Therefore, identifying the signs of aging as early as possible and understanding the laws of aging are of great significance to alleviating the pressure on global public health in the context of aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Perceiving the Signs of Aging Early&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I’m not sure individuals really need to measure their biological age.” explains Daniel Belsky, Popular Aging needs to be measured in medical research, not only to identify factors that accelerate or delay aging, but also to evaluate the effectiveness of some anti-aging projects, policies, life interventions and drug therapies. &quot;However, for those who do want to know more about their aging and health, there are a range of tools on the market that can help estimate biological age, from blood tests to DNA tests. These tests themselves are not dangerous, but the results should Interpret with caution, and it is best to interpret relevant results with the help of healthcare professionals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, a research report published in &quot;The Lancet Healthy Longevity&quot; It shows that chest X-ray examination, an already widely used technology, may be used to assist in the assessment of human aging. By training and developing related artificial intelligence models, the researchers used chest radiographs to estimate the age of the client. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that for relatively healthy people, the age estimated by artificial intelligence through chest X-rays has a strong correlation with the actual age. But for people with pre-existing medical conditions, the difference between estimated and actual age is associated with multiple chronic conditions, identifying increased risk for hypertension, interstitial lung disease, chronic renal failure, and more. This means that common picture information such as chest X-rays may become an aging biomarker to help people evaluate the status of chronic diseases and even predict life span, while improving the level of personalized intervention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these methods that rely on medical equipment, looking at faces directly and roughly assessing aging and related health risks based on whether appearance matches age is obviously more concise, although the accuracy is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that, including looking at faces to assess sensory age, many relevant studies currently include thousands of samples, but the sources are relatively single and lack sufficient representation. Differences actually play an important role in sensory age assessment, which is also an obvious limitation of related research so far. Whether the health implications of appearance and age mismatch are effective in all types of communities remains to be confirmed by more research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparative studies on skin aging have long found that the skin aging trajectories of Asians and Europeans are very different. Taking Chinese and French women as an example, a small sample study shows that Chinese women start to develop wrinkles on their faces almost ten years later than French women. This time difference will make Chinese women look significantly younger at this time, but by the age of four In their teens, Chinese women will experience rapid aging in terms of facial wrinkles, showing a non-linear trend. In comparison, French women&#39;s aging in this aspect is relatively stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such as this, due to the differences in facial development between different races, the accuracy of applying the sensory experience of one group to predict the age of people in another group will be relatively limited. In addition, there are cultural differences in how people dress in different societies. If we understand the phenomenon of appearance and age mismatch in a cross-cultural context, we may find different rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Efforts to delay aging&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, when it comes to looking at faces, whether appearance matches age is only one aspect. In 2022, biological research also found that there may be a connection between physical attractiveness and health indicators such as immune function. After a series of experiments and tests, researchers found that people who were more physically attractive also had better immune performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Summer Mengelkoch, an experimental social psychology researcher at Texas Christian University who participated in this study, told Southern Weekend reporters that although a person who cares too much about physical attractiveness may appear They are very superficial, but their research shows that when people pay attention to the physical attractiveness of their partners, they may actually care about more than just looks, and may also use this to select a healthy partner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latest research starts from the gap between sensory age and actual age, providing more evidence for scientific face reading. By identifying the signs and risk factors of aging as early as possible, you can take action to slow down aging. In May 2023, researchers from Harvard Medical School found in studies on mice and humans that physiological age will fluctuate in both directions under the influence of stress. When stress is excessive, physiological age will increase, and after recovery from stress, physiological age will increase. Age will reverse repair. This may provide a suitable entry point for future interventions targeting aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether we are middle-aged or still young. To promote healthy aging, the things we can do are actually the same. Eat a healthy diet, do a lot of physical activities, and participate in family activities. , socializing with friends and community, cultivating a sense of purpose and meaning, and avoiding toxic stress and pollution.&quot; Daniel Belsky emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The scientific community is now developing new drugs that can slow down physiological aging and extend the healthy life cycle. At the same time, we already know how to promote healthy aging by changing the environment in which we live—reducing pollution, ensuring safe and secure housing, and providing affordable and healthy food. We should invest in these areas as well. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从魂魄、中阴身到幽灵Vs魔鬼：万圣节话中西之鬼异同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259582]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every year before Halloween comes, all kinds of creative and scary costumes bloom everywhere, and you can constantly watch short videos. Although today&#39;s Halloween is no different from &quot;Cosplay Festival&quot;. But its original &quot;ghost-driving&quot; element is still vaguely visible - even though in modern society, ghosts and gods have long become the objects of ridicule played by humans. However, various countries&#39; understanding of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; still follows thousands of years of tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a wonderful discussion and definition of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; in &quot;Book of Rites·Jiyi&quot;: &quot;Zaiwo said: I heard the names of ghosts and gods, but I don&#39;t know what they mean. The Master said: Qi is also , the prosperity of gods. The prosperity of souls, the prosperity of ghosts. The combination of ghosts and gods is the ultimate teaching. All living things must die, and after death they must return to the earth. This is called ghosts.&quot; Zaiwo didn&#39;t understand what ghosts and gods were, so Confucius told him: &quot; God is essence, and ghost is soul. All living things will die, and after death they will return to dust, which are called ghosts.&quot; - Confucius played a homophonic joke here: ghosts are all living things. ultimate destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of this, in China’s oldest traditions, ghosts and gods are often not clearly distinguished. As the saying goes, &quot;Ghosts are ancestors, and ancestors are also ghosts.&quot; The Confucian attitude towards ghosts and gods is also very interesting. Confucius once said: &quot;Respect ghosts and gods and keep them at a distance.&quot; He also said: &quot;If you can&#39;t serve people, how can you serve ghosts?&quot; In short, he tried his best to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods, and even showed an agnostic tendency to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Confucianism places great emphasis on respecting ancestors and offering sacrifices on time. If ghosts and gods do not exist at all, then what are they worshiping? Confucius added another patch to this: &quot;Sacrifice to the gods as if they were present, and sacrifice to the gods as if the gods were present. Confucius said: If I don&#39;t offer sacrifices, it would be as if I didn&#39;t offer sacrifices.&quot; In other words, when offering sacrifices to ancestors, it seems as if the ancestors are really in front of you; when offering sacrifices to gods, It was as if God was really in front of me. Confucius also said that if I do not personally participate in the sacrifice, the sacrifice will be the same as no sacrifice. From this, it can be seen that Confucius emphasized that those who participate in the sacrifice should have pious emotions in their hearts. According to Confucianism, sacrifice is a moral ritual used to unite the community, rather than a religious ritual used to pray for blessings and ward off disasters. Therefore, salutes are just out of recalling the feelings of ancestors. As the saying goes, &quot;sages teach with Shinto.&quot; And the sacrifices are mainly for the living people to see: &quot;Be careful and pursue the long distance, and the people&#39;s virtue will be strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From today&#39;s perspective, Confucius&#39;s view is very advanced. However, on the other hand, it seems to be contradictory to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods while requiring people to worship sincerely. Mohism, the lifelong enemy of Confucianism, once seized this point and vigorously ridiculed Confucianism. Contrary to Confucianism, Mohism strives to prove the real existence of ghosts and gods, so it regards sacrifice as more important than Confucianism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Taoism, the attitude is more distinct than that of Confucianism. It is believed that after death, one returns to heaven and earth, and there is no such thing as ghosts and gods. Therefore, &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; sings with drums and pots, and &quot;Liehzi&quot; believes that death means eternal rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when Mozi argued that &quot;the ghosts and gods must be solemnly sacrificed&quot;, he also exposed his true thoughts: &quot;Although the ghosts and gods are asked to die, this can still bring joy to the crowd and get relatives in the hometown&quot;—— &quot;Even if there are really no ghosts and gods, we can still connect with the villagers through ritual gatherings.&quot; This is the same as Confucianism, which shows that Mozi&#39;s own belief was not so firm. After all, it is hard to imagine that monotheistic believers would say, &quot;Even if there is really no God, belief in God can have the following benefits...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the Mohist school, which emphasizes ghosts and gods the most among the local schools, has this kind of attitude towards the existence of ghosts and gods. Attitude, it is not difficult to understand why the early setting of the underworld in Chinese mythology is so monotonous. Before the introduction and prosperity of Buddhism, although China had the concept of the underworld, it was still very simple: the underworld is the destination of the soul and is controlled by the Lord Taishan, but there is no such thing as hell; and although the story of reincarnation appeared very early, it is not It is regarded as a fixed procedure in the underworld, and is just an anecdote similar to &quot;seizing the body&quot; in later generations. Therefore, there is no concept of reincarnation and rebirth. For the ancients, death still means eternal separation and tranquility. As the saying goes, &quot;What is the way to die? The body is supported by the same mountain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going to hell after death is also the oldest view of life and death in China. It is still used as a euphemism for death to this day. There is also a famous story here, where Zheng Zhuanggong dug into the ground to meet his mother:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zheng Zhuanggong decided that his younger brother had rebelled, he was very angry with his mother Wu Jiang who favored his younger brother. He put Wu Jiang under house arrest in Yingdi, and swore a poisonous oath: &quot;It&#39;s not as good as Huangquan, and we won&#39;t see each other again.&quot; This means we won&#39;t see each other until we die. As a result, Ying Kaoshu, an official of Yingdi, successfully persuaded Duke Zhuang of Zheng and aroused his family affection and filial piety. But Duke Zhuang still used the oath of poison as an excuse, so Uncle Yingkao said: &quot;This is easy to do. We can dig tunnels until the yellow spring water is dug out, and build an underground courtyard there. Can&#39;t you guys meet?&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;So Zhuang Gong, mother and son were able to meet in the tunnel. They hugged each other and cried, and reconciled as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people were speechless when they first read this paragraph: they reconciled as before, but the problem is that Zheng Zhuanggong and his mother didn&#39;t like each other at first... And the Yellow Spring is really a yellow spring? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Huangquan Temple comes from burial. After death, people go underground, not just Huangquan. Most scholars believe that the original meaning of Huangquan is underground water, because many three-generation ancient tombs are located below the water level. When Buddhism brought reincarnation in, it combined with the view of Huangquan to create &quot;Hell&quot; (Naluka) - the Indian native &quot;Naluka&quot;, which is more similar to a parallel universe or an alien space. After death, people will enter this Space is judged; but Chinese tradition believes that after death, people must go underground. Therefore, the Buddhists had no choice but to move &quot;Naluojia&quot; underground, which gave it the name &quot;Hell&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reincarnation of Buddhism is inherited from the traditional setting of Hinduism. There are actually similar theories all over the world. For example, the ancient Greek philosopher Plato often mentioned reincarnation in his books. But for most civilizations, this theory is just an anecdote, not a universally accepted assumption. Only in South Asia, reincarnation is the axiomatic basis of all religions and philosophies. Even the reason why the Buddha became a monk was to find the right path to escape the suffering of reincarnation. Buddhism believes that if all living beings are freed from reincarnation, it means the end of all &quot;suffering&quot;. This is what Buddhism says &quot;all living beings are suffering&quot;. Beings who are not in the &quot;reincarnation&quot; are no longer sentient beings, but Buddhas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Buddhist theory of reincarnation is obviously in conflict with China’s native sacrifices. In order to solve this conflict, there are various patches, such as &quot;Ghosts line up in the underworld waiting to be reincarnated, and they have to live during the lottery.&quot; This &quot;lottery&quot; state between two reincarnations and two deaths is called the &quot;bardo&quot; in Buddhism. But this patch is still incomplete - the emperor wants to offer sacrifices to his ancestors. Is it because the ancestors have waited hundreds of years and still not passed away? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after Taoism absorbed the concept of reincarnation, it added another patch: humans have three souls and seven souls, and the three souls are the heaven soul, the earth soul, and the life soul. What dissipates after death is not the soul, but the soul. The three souls reincarnate after death, the heavenly soul goes to heaven, and the earthly soul lives in the ancestral hall or tomb. Therefore, before a person&#39;s life soul is reincarnated, all the money burned is for the life soul. The soul of life is reincarnated, and what is burned is for the soul of earth. Different Taoist schools have different patch theories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in modern times, Christianity has brought heaven into the world, and the situation has become even more confusing: After death, a person can enjoy the sacrifices of his descendants in the underworld and enter the six realms of reincarnation. Can he also watch his descendants in heaven at the same time? Some people have tried to reconcile this: after death, people enter Hades to be judged. After the verdict, the guilty go to reincarnation or hell, and the innocent ascend to heaven where they are, and accept sacrifices, perfect. In fact, these are not important, because the Chinese people&#39;s attitude towards life and death still comes from Confucianism: everything is a moral ceremony rather than a religious ceremony, and everything is to comfort the living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Christian attitude towards ghosts, it is also very interesting to study in detail: the devil (Satan, the devil) or demons (that is, the fallen angels who follow the devil) we often call, although they are translated as &quot;ghosts&quot;, But it is not the same thing as Chinese ghosts. The ghost that the Chinese talk about is closer to the ghost that the Europeans talk about. According to the Bible, after death, the soul will sleep with the body, waiting for the arrival of judgment and resurrection in the last days. People who belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death, which the Bible calls the new heaven and new earth; people who do not belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death. Imprisoned in Hades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Christianity believes that ghost phenomena in the world are all illusions made by Satan, and there are no ghosts in the world at all. Some Christians believe in the existence of ghosts, but are opposed to any form of communication with them because the Old Testament repeatedly warns against ghost communication rituals. Therefore, we can see that ghosts rarely appear in European and American ghost films. Vampires, werewolves, and cursed children are the common protagonists - but even these ghosts are also opposed by Christianity. Therefore, every year on Halloween, there are still Christian churches in Europe and the United States advocating a boycott and advocating that if children come to ask for candy, they can be given a Bible or a cross as a gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>