<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整中国人民银行职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258495]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:25:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China Institutional Establishment Network reported on October 12 that the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued a notice on the adjustment of the Chinese People&#39;s Notice prepared by the bank&#39;s responsible organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Establishment of Responsible Organizations of the People&#39;s Bank of China&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(September 24, 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In accordance with the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and upon approval by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, the People&#39;s Bank of China is hereby notified of the following adjustments to its responsibilities, structures, and establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1. Regarding the adjustment of main responsibilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(1) The Financial Stability and Development Committee of the State Council and its office will no longer be retained. The responsibilities of the Office of the Financial Stability and Development Commission of the State Council will be transferred to the Office of the Central Financial Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Transfer the daily supervision responsibilities of financial holding companies and other financial groups to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(3) The responsibility for establishing and improving the basic system for financial consumer protection will be assigned to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;II. Regarding the adjustment of organizational structure&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(1) The Secretariat of the Office of the Financial Stability and Development Commission of the State Council, located at the People’s Bank of China, will be included in the central financial Committee Office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) The People’s Bank of China will no longer retain the Financial Consumer Rights Protection Bureau. The responsibilities of coordinating and promoting related inclusive finance, originally undertaken by the Financial Consumer Rights Protection Bureau, have been transferred to the Financial Markets Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(3) The Macro-Prudential Administration will no longer assume the daily supervision responsibilities of financial holding companies and other financial groups. The Department of Financial Markets&#39; responsibilities for coordinating Internet financial supervision and formulating and organizing the implementation of macro credit guidance policies related to the real estate finance field will be assigned to the Macro-Prudential Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;3. Regarding the adjustment of administrative establishment and leadership positions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Based on the transfer of responsibilities, the People&#39;s Bank of China will reduce the administrative establishment of 30 people and the number of 6 departments and bureaus accordingly. Level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the People&#39;s Bank of China has 20 internal institutions, an administrative staff of 714, and 87 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整国家卫健委职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258497]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:26:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Responsibilities of the National Health Commission&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; (September 24, 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Optimization and Adjustment Plan for the Discussion and Coordination Institutions of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot;, and after being submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, it is now The National Health Commission’s responsibilities, structures, and staffing adjustments are notified as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. The Ministry of Science and Technology’s responsibility for organizing and formulating plans and policies for science and technology to promote health development will be assigned to the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The National Health Commission’s organization, formulation, coordination and implementation of policies and measures to deal with population aging, and the specific work of the National Working Committee on Aging will be assigned to the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The China Association on Aging, which is managed by the National Health Commission, is now managed by the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Transfer four administrative staff and one department-level leadership position from the Ministry of Science and Technology to the National Health Commission. The three administrative staff of the National Health Commission will be transferred to the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the National Health Commission has 19 internal agencies, an administrative staff of 444, and 81 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整生态环境部职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:27:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 12, the China Institutional Establishment Network released the &quot;General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjustments to the Ministry of Ecology and Environment&quot; Notice on the Establishment of Responsible Organizations&quot;: According to the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and the &quot;Optimization and Adjustment Plan for the Discussion and Coordination Institutions of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot;, and after being submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, the responsibilities, institutions, and establishment adjustments of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment are now The notice is as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Incorporate the Ministry of Science and Technology’s responsibilities for organizing the formulation of plans and policies for science and technology to promote ecological environment development, and its internal social development science and technology department with 4 administrative staff and 1 department-level leadership position. Ministry of Ecology and Environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas air pollution prevention and control leading group and its offices will no longer be retained. The Department of Atmospheric Environment of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment will no longer display the brand of the Atmospheric Environment Administration Bureau of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection Office, an internal agency of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, was renamed the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection and Coordination Bureau, and its responsibilities were stated as “responsible for the daily activities of the State Council’s Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection Leading Group” &quot;Work&quot; was revised to &quot;undertake specific affairs of the Central Ecological Environmental Protection Inspection Leading Group Office&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has 21 internal agencies, 504 administrative staff, and 79 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整工信部职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:29:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 12, the China Institutional Establishment Network released the &quot;General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting Industry and Information Notice on the establishment of responsible agencies of the Ministry of Chemical Industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Responsibilities of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and the &quot;Coordination of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot; &quot;Organizational Optimization and Adjustment Plan&quot;, which has been submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology&#39;s responsibilities, institutions, and establishment adjustment matters are hereby notified as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Organize the Ministry of Science and Technology to formulate high-tech development and industrialization plans and policies, guide the construction of science and technology parks such as national independent innovation demonstration zones and national high-tech industrial development zones, and guide the science and technology service industry, technology Responsibilities such as marketing and the development of science and technology intermediary organizations are assigned to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The State Council’s Leading Group for Promoting the Development of Small and Medium-sized Enterprises and its office will no longer be retained. The relevant specific work will be undertaken by the Small and Medium-sized Enterprise Bureau of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The High-tech Department of the Ministry of Science and Technology will have an administrative establishment of 25 and 4 bureau-level leaders; the Achievements Transformation and Regional Innovation Department will have an administrative establishment of 6 and 2 bureau-level leaders. The number is transferred to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has 23 internal agencies, an administrative staff of 725, and 110 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西安某大学女生被63页PPT控诉出轨：如此行为侵犯隐私吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258474]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州警方：编造“广州地铁遭恐怖袭击”谣言嫌疑人被抓获]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258493]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/c82153854f91b207d8f0e5d238279f5e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;582&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c82153854f91b207d8f0e5d238279 f5e. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253974&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 12, a rumor about the Guangzhou Metro went viral on the Internet According to the news, the Guangzhou police quickly filed a case and launched an investigation. At about 18:19 that day, they arrested the suspect Tan Mou (male, 23 years old, Guangxi) who deliberately fabricated and released the information in a village in the city of Tianhe District. After interrogation, Tan confessed that he made up the rumor to show off his ability to generate specific pages through computer programming technology. At present, the criminal suspect Tan has been criminally detained by the police in accordance with the law, and the case is still under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police remind: The Internet is not a place outside the law. Illegal and criminal acts such as fabricating and deliberately spreading Internet rumors will be severely punished by law. Please do not believe or spread rumors, and work together to maintain a clean space on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[太原理工大学书记郑强婚内出轨？山西省纪委回应：正了解相关情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258482]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen reported that Zheng Qiang, secretary of the Party Committee of Taiyuan University of Technology and Internet celebrity professor, had an affair with his ex-girlfriend, causing extensive attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, the informant stated that Zheng Qiang called his girlfriend in the early morning of one morning in July 2015 and was discovered by him. The two parties broke up a few months later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whistleblower said that he and Zheng Qiang met once in March this year, and the other party advised him to be cautious. This year, he reported it to the relevant school authorities and disciplinary inspection departments, but so far there has been no result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection responded: It is understanding the relevant situation. Zheng Qiang himself released information through his public account saying: The report is untrue and the police have been called. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, Zheng Qiang commissioned a law firm to issue a statement, saying that the above-mentioned content posted by netizens was seriously inconsistent with the facts and that it had protected its rights through legal channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02d6806979a40195e6c55dfd834494d8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height=&quot;874&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02d6806979a40195e6c55dfd834494d8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253918&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d4b37d8ce7d1da72a49bde39c21207d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d4b37d8ce7d1da72a49bde39c21207d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the &quot;Professor Zheng Qiang&quot; public account issued a &quot;Stern Statement on the Recent False News Related to Comrade Zheng Qiang on the Internet&quot; stating that the account &quot;Huaqu&quot; has recently published and spread false information on the Internet. , it has been confirmed that the real name of the publisher is Lv, who is a criminal released from prison. All the text and picture content published are maliciously fabricated and fictitious false information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statement stated: In March 2023, Lu contacted Zheng Qiang in the name of a &quot;fan&quot; and told his personal experience and feelings about serving time in prison, hoping to get relevant help. In June 2023, Lv contacted Zheng Qiang again, hoping to get Zheng Qiang&#39;s support in his social work and asked to introduce resources to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Lv’s actual request was for me to come forward as a guarantee for a loan of 10 million yuan, which was directly and sternly rejected. So Lv began to continuously fabricate all kinds of false information and evidence, and successively passed the online My personal reputation was defamed in various ways, both online and offline, with the intention of blackmailing and extorting property, and posing a threat to my personal safety. In late June, I took the initiative to report to the leadership of the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Explain the relevant circumstances of the incident.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qiang emphasized in the statement that Lv published false information and the content was fabricated to extort and extort him, seriously damaging his personal reputation. Cause extremely bad effects and great harm. &quot;If I have any words or deeds that violate disciplines and laws, I am willing to accept the review and handling of the organization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 12th, the staff of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Taiyuan University of Technology responded that they have paid attention to the public opinion and yesterday In the evening, several departments of the school held meetings overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 12th, staff from the Propaganda Department of the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision stated that they were understanding the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of press time, the reporter contacted Zheng Qiang himself many times, but no calls were answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Qiang’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qiang, male, Han nationality, from Wuyishan, Fujian, born in September 1960, member of the Communist Party of China , Ph.D., professor, doctoral supervisor. Distinguished professor of the &quot;Changjiang Scholars Award Program&quot; of the Ministry of Education, winner of the National Science Fund for Distinguished Young Scholars, national candidate for the &quot;New Century Talents Project&quot;, expert enjoying special government subsidies, director of the Key Laboratory of Polymer Synthesis and Functional Structure of the Ministry of Education . He is currently the Secretary of the Taiyuan University of Technology Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1978 to 1982, he studied at Zhejiang University for his undergraduate degree (Bachelor of Science); from 1985 to 1988, he studied for a master&#39;s degree (Master of Engineering) at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University); from 1990 to 1992, he studied at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University). Studied for a doctoral degree at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University). From October 1992 to October 1994, China and Japan jointly trained doctoral students to study at Kyoto University in Japan. In December 1994, he received a doctorate in engineering from Sichuan United University (now Sichuan University); 1998 He was promoted to professor of Zhejiang University in 2001. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as deputy dean of the School of Materials and Chemical Engineering and director of the Department of Polymer Science and Engineering of Zhejiang University, deputy provost and executive vice dean of the Undergraduate College of Zhejiang University, and dean of Qiushi College. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From February 2009 to November 2012, he served as deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Zhejiang University. During this period: from October 2009 to October 2011, he served as vice president of Guizhou Academy of Sciences (temporary position);&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;From May 2012 to June 2017, he served as President and Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Guizhou University;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2016, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Zhejiang University (department level);&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 In April 2010, he was appointed as Secretary of the Party Committee of Taiyuan University of Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[早教机构成“爆雷”高发区，千亿蛋糕怎么也不香了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/cfe30e52f0d700dbc5f19cc233ad4c0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/10/cfe30e52f0d700dbc5f19cc233ad4c0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former &quot;early education star&quot; Mejim is now caught in the storm of store closures in many places across the country. According to media reports, many Mejim stores in many cities across the country have suddenly closed, making it difficult for parents to refund their fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not only Magim, but also early education institutions such as Nanadazhen and Gymboree have also been in trouble recently. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Once upon a time, the early childhood education industry with a market worth hundreds of billions was very prosperous, and famous early education institutions such as Mejim were developing very rapidly. Why has the situation changed so suddenly now? What is the future of the early childhood education industry? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The high-profile &quot;100 billion market&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From the birth of a child to primary school Education in previous stages can be called early education. Based on the physical and mental development characteristics and brain development characteristics of infants and young children, providing them with scientific, rich, and appropriate information stimulation and training can develop children&#39;s physical and mental potential and promote their all-round development. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early education can be divided into two stages: 0-3 years old, infants and young children do not go to kindergarten, but early education can already be carried out; after 3 years old, children can formally When entering kindergarten, in addition to systematic early education in schools, early education institutions outside schools also play a supplementary role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For a long time in the past, the concept of early education in China was not popular, and many parents were not aware of the function of early education. After the 1990s, with the continuous development of China&#39;s economy and the closer economic and ideological exchanges with foreign countries, foreign early childhood education concepts began to influence Chinese parents, and a number of early childhood education institutions came into being. However, the industry is still in its infancy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second decade of the new century, the early childhood education industry has truly ushered in rapid development. As Chinese people become richer, they pay more attention to their children’s education and are more willing to invest in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people born in the 1980s and 1990s have become parents. Young people are more likely to accept some new educational concepts. They pay more attention to their children&#39;s early education than their parents, believing that this is the first and most important thing for children. But it is also the &quot;starting line&quot; that has been ignored in the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, foreign early childhood education institutions represented by Mejim have entered our country in a large scale. The more mature and systematic operating models they represent have emerged from first- and second-tier cities. It continues to spread to third- and fourth-tier cities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Data from Zhiyan Consulting shows that since 2014, the number of investment events in the domestic early childhood education service industry has increased, and the amount of investment has increased significantly. The number of investment and financing events in 2014 was nearly 50, and it exceeded 110 in 2015. From 2015 to 2018, there were more than 90 investment and financing events every year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From 2012 to 2016, the amount of investment in the early childhood education industry has increased year by year, exceeding 4 billion yuan in 2017. In 2018, the investment amount soared to 9.644 billion Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to &lt;/span>; research reports, the market size of my country’s early childhood education industry has increased year by year from 2016 to 2020, with the market size reaching 327.6 billion yuan and 327.6 billion yuan respectively in 2021 and 2022. 350 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the number of newborns is decreasing each year as the fertility rate declines, the early education market, a &quot;hundred billion cake&quot;, is still favored by the outside world due to its huge population base. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/f504711fea7233163eb90242fcedefc6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/f504711fea7233163eb90242fcedefc6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253570 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;From unlimited glory to the edge of thunder&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the pre-epidemic era, the early childhood education industry has been in a state of expansion: various online and offline institutions have shown their respective Supernatural powers; there are various subdivisions - English, mathematical thinking, Chinese language, children&#39;s songs, picture books, young children&#39;s animation, etc., all of which have formed specialized tracks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2018, Mejim successfully landed on the A-share market and became the “No. 1 early childhood education stock”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Meijim’s 2018 financial report shows that the company’s total revenue in 2018 was 265 million yuan, and its total profit was 60.49 million yuan; in 2019, the company’s total revenue increased by 137.35% year-on-year %, to 630 million yuan, and the total profit increased by 302.54% to 243 million yuan; as of Q1 2019, there were 451 US Jim centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The arrival of the epidemic has had a huge impact on all offline industries, and Mejim is no exception. Mejim&#39;s total revenue in 2020 was 356 million yuan - almost halved compared to 2019. The total revenue in 2021 was 336 million yuan, and the total revenue in 2022 was 154 million yuan - only half of 2021. Revenue in the first quarter of 2023 was only 29.54 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company&#39;s operating profit is even worse. The total profit in 2020 was -531 million yuan, and the total profit in 2021 was -57.4551 million yuan. The total profit was -610 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sluggish early childhood education industry raises the risk of “explosion” because almost all early childhood education institutions are in the form of prepaid consumption, that is, the institutions sell lesson packages to parents, and a lesson package can easily cost It costs tens of thousands of yuan, and the course package covers a period ranging from a few months to a few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in August 2018, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Development of Off-Campus Training Institutions&quot;, it put forward clear requirements for early childhood education and other off-campus training institutions to collect tuition fees from &lt;span>;educated persons: &quot;No A one-time charge for a time span of more than 3 months.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, it is common for early childhood education institutions to charge a one-time fee for a time span of more than 3 months, and it has even become Industry practice. When the institution is operating normally, the course package format will be more &quot;favorable&quot;; once the institution becomes unsustainable and the offline institution closes, parents will have no place to take the remaining courses they purchased and would like&lt;/span>; a refund. But it is also difficult to get a refund, which is like a &quot;thunder&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that the epidemic is an important reason for the difficulties encountered by many early childhood education institutions. In fact, the crisis of many early childhood education institutions has already been laid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, blind expansion leads to a sharp increase in costs. Early childhood education institutions are mostly offline education. They are usually rented in bustling shopping malls, with an average area of ​​about 200 square meters. The monthly rent and labor costs are very high, and the monthly operating costs can easily reach tens of thousands of yuan. If customer renewal and new acquisition are not ideal, you will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the pre-epidemic era, many early childhood education institutions were eager for quick success and expansion too fast, and had already shown signs of operational difficulties. The impact of the epidemic has completely erupted the crisis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Secondly, due to the rapid development of the early childhood education industry in the past few years, many people want to get a piece of the pie and have opened early childhood education institutions. Due to the lack of standards and insufficient teachers in the early childhood education industry, many practitioners do not even have kindergarten teacher qualification certificates and can directly take up their posts after simple training. This has also resulted in the overall level of the early childhood education industry being low, and many parents have lost trust in early childhood education institutions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Under the impact of the epidemic, many parents found that their children actually grew very well without attending early childhood education classes. They couldn’t help but reflect on whether the early childhood education classes they enrolled in before were paying attention.&lt;/span>; IQ tax. Nowadays, many parents will search for relevant information on social media when registering for classes. Once there are more voices of &quot;distrust&quot; of early childhood education institutions, parents&#39; willingness to register for classes will decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, although the epidemic is over, early childhood education institutions have not &lt;span>; experienced the rapid recovery expected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Standardized development will have a future&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early childhood education is still a market worth hundreds of billions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the fertility rate has declined, Chinese parents currently attach great importance to their children’s education; under the “double reduction” policy, the early childhood education industry has not been greatly affected, but instead the discipline The weakening of training has made many parents more willing to invest in their children in aspects such as painting and physical fitness, and these are areas that early childhood education has always been involved in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The early childhood education industry is now facing difficulties, which is an opportunity for the industry to take a break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, in the pre-epidemic era, although the early childhood education industry developed rapidly, it was generally in a state of barbaric growth: there were no standards and a lack of regulations. &lt;span>;For example, my country&#39;s nurseries and kindergartens adopt a &quot;dual-track system&quot; model. Childcare services for infants aged 0-3 years old are separated from care and education for children aged 3-6 years old. The former is managed by the Health Commission and the latter is managed by the education department. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of curriculum connection, our country currently has clearer educational suggestions for the learning and development goals and child care work of children aged 3 to 6 years old. Relatively speaking, children aged 0 to 3 years old There is a lack of educational advice for infants and young children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This gives many early childhood education institutions room to fish in troubled waters. Although parents spend a lot of money to send their children to institutions, there is actually no way to judge whether the courses are reasonable and whether the teachers are qualified. I don&#39;t know if it has any effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as this &quot;fuzzy&quot; space exists and the standards of excellence and inferiority are not clear, it will be difficult to establish the rules of survival of the fittest. To establish industry norms, not only early childhood education institutions need self-discipline, but also relevant departments such as education need to gather industry experts and issue relevant standards so that early childhood education has rules to follow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, regarding the current prepaid consumption problem that is common in early childhood education institutions, it is necessary to effectively strengthen the supervision of funds to prevent early childhood education institutions from misappropriating funds, which in turn triggers the risk of thunderstorms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early childhood education institutions should be more cautious when expanding and not misappropriate consumers&#39; money to do risky things. Only when funds are safer, the industry is more orderly, and parents&#39; trust is established, can the early childhood education industry truly develop in the long run. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《大宅门》导演郭宝昌去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258485]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On October 11, 2023, Guo Baochang died in Beijing at the age of 83. He lost his father when he was young, was sold into a mansion by his biological mother, went through labor reform, directed more than 30 film and television dramas, and once mentored Zhang Yimou... Throughout his life, he has tasted the warmth and ups and downs of human relationships, experienced the ups and downs of the world, and learned to survive carefully in the cracks. No loss of heroism and courage. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“旧式太太”与“新女性”：香港作家笔下的五四婚姻与女性命运]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258421]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/SDR2BRTIWWWHLJOKQPovkipsqx1v2adqelohmrupn.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 842 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;1206&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/medias/ima/ima GE/23/10/11/SDR2BRTIWHLJOKQPOVKIPSQX1v2adqelohmrupn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253795&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Huiyin is China&#39;s first female architect. When she was critically ill, she asked to see Xu Zhimo&#39;s ex-wife Zhang Youyi, and the two finally met. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A century ago, an ordinary village in southeast England witnessed an extraordinary event. The village is called Shaxton, and the protagonists of the incident are two young Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boys have been studying in the United States and the United Kingdom for more than two years, and the girls just left a conservative small town in China a few weeks ago; the boys are auditors at Cambridge University, and the girls have only learned basic daily English for a few weeks. ; The boy wants to be a pioneer in the new era and become a blockbuster, while the girl just hopes to adapt to life in a foreign country and have the opportunity to learn some new knowledge; the boy falls in love with a girl who comes from a reformist family and is studying in the UK at the time. Not long after the girl arrives in London, she vaguely notices her husband. There is another person that I like, but I still hope that my husband, who has always regarded me as a &quot;country bumpkin&quot;, can communicate more with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This couple is Xu Zhimo and Zhang Youyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1921, less than nine months after Zhang Youyi was sent to England by her parents-in-law, Xu Zhimo suddenly filed for divorce and left without saying goodbye a week later, leaving her who was more than three months pregnant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2001, Hong Kong scholar and writer Kong Huiyi passed through Shaxton. The size of the town expanded and the old houses were demolished, but the practical and boring temperament did not change. She thought at the time: The struggle of a young Chinese woman in the early 20th century was buried in this inconspicuous place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, she thought again: How could the story of Chinese women be buried in just one or two places? The idea eventually evolved into a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese women&#39;s movement began in the 1880s, with two major slogans: &quot;anti-foot-binding&quot; and &quot;promoting women&#39;s education.&quot; At that time, both the reformers and the revolutionary men believed that self-improvement was the basis for national salvation, so they included women&#39;s issues on the social reform agenda. At this time, the expectations for women were still limited to being good wives and mothers. Although they had greatly developed physically and mentally compared with their predecessors, they still only fulfilled their traditional family roles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The New Culture Movement broke the traditional family operating model of elders and younger ones, striving for personal and individual liberation. This new trend created another ideal image of free and independent women. To be called a &quot;May Fourth&quot; new woman with an independent personality, she must meet several conditions: receive education in a new-style school; have a career after graduation; be independent in marriage; and participate in public life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, education is the foundation. For adult women, they are unable to strive for new educational opportunities, so in the era of drastic changes, they are labeled as backward and feudal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi hopes to break this simple label division and &quot;explore whether the women of the May Fourth era can be revalued in a fair manner and whether the world they face can be seen from their perspective.&quot; In &quot;May 4th Marriage&quot;, she went against the tradition of male-centered biographies and turned her pen to seven women: Zhu An, Xu Guangping, Jiang Dongxiu, Cao Peisheng, Zhang Youyi, Lu Xiaoman, and Lin Huiyin, trying to explore through their life circumstances the problems faced by women at that time. practical problems, depicting the various faces of Chinese women in the period of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The trend of &quot;escape from marriage&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether it is the new cultural movement or the new concept of women, they all have the same core issues: marital autonomy and divorce. Since most young people had entered into arranged marriages at that time, there was a trend of &quot;escape from marriage&quot; - young men leaving home alone to start a new life in order to get rid of their old wives. According to a 1922 women&#39;s publication, 70% of the old-style wives abandoned by the new youth in Henan Province ended up committing suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality of marriage and divorce in the new cultural period is a mirror that reflects how the drastic changes in social norms affect women from different backgrounds, and how they deal with the tide of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi wrote about Zhu An, hoping to &quot;find their voices for a generation of women who have suffered a lot and are speechless.&quot; When Lu Xun started his second marriage, he did not abandon his first wife Zhu An financially and nominally. However, the blow to Zhu An was emotional and spiritual. When she was still alive, Lu Xun and the people around him regarded her as a gift that could not be refused. She might be worthy of pity, but not respect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous biographies surrounding Lu Xun, descriptions of Zhu An often tended to indicate that he was &quot;inadequate&quot;. Kong Huiyi pointed out that this historical perspective of discrimination against old women is based on prejudice and does not really reflect the mentality and personality of the person involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu An was interviewed by reporters in her later years. When talking about her relationship with Lu Xun and Xu Guangping, she once said: &quot;Mr. Zhou was not bad to me. There were no quarrels between us. We each have our own lives. I He should be forgiven... Mr. Xu treats me very well, she understands my thoughts, and she is willing to support me... She is indeed a good person.&quot; It can be seen from her words that she puts Lu Xun and Xu Guangping on an equal footing with herself On the other hand, she had no jealousy towards Xu Guangping, but instead established a mutually respectful relationship with her. This is no easy task, and this shows that her heart and character cannot be summed up simply by the label &quot;old woman&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu An was sacrificed between the old and the new. In contrast, Xu Guangping had the opportunity to receive modern education and enter the world of new women. However, the marriage relationship established through free love and personal choice caused Xu Guangping to lose his original independent status. She had her own career before she and Lu Xun lived together. After arriving in Shanghai, she actively looked for a job. However, she later became Lu Xun&#39;s secretary and assistant, embarking on a completely different path than she originally expected - becoming a virtuous person in the new cultural norms. A good wife and mother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guangping has always kept three hundred yuan in savings as &quot;emergency money&quot; and publicly told Lu Xun and his friends that if their relationship breaks down, the money can temporarily maintain her livelihood until she resumes her life. Get a job. A meager three hundred yuan became Xu Guangping&#39;s only way to maintain his independent personality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The traditional concept of &quot;men taking charge outside and women taking charge inside&quot; has not been diminished by the New Culture Movement. When Lin Huiyin faced Liang Sicheng, who was pragmatic and capable and treated her well, she could not help but complain that she was burdened with housework and was unable to develop her talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1950s and 1950s, although many women had successful careers, they were unable to get rid of the dilemma of marriage and love throughout their lives. Cao Peisheng is an extreme example. She married the husband arranged by her parents at the age of sixteen. With the support of her brother studying in the United States, she continued to study at the Women&#39;s Normal School when she was eighteen. When her husband&#39;s family decided to have a concubine, Cao Peisheng resolutely left the marriage. Soon after, she fell in love with Hu Shi. At that time, Hu Shi had been married to Jiang Dongxiu for six years and had three children. Hu Shi failed to divorce, and the two fell in love for three years, but the hopeless relationship was finally shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first female professor of agriculture in China, Cao Peisheng has made extraordinary achievements in cotton and potato research and genetics. However, her bitter love with Hu Shi lingered throughout her life. She filled in a lot of words, constantly remembering the passionate love that year. After his death, he was buried on the only road from his hometown to Hu Shi&#39;s hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Huiyi believes that Cao Peisheng’s situation reflects the conflict between old and new culture. New women and their love partners often cannot control the compass of life. Although their eyes are on the new world, they are faced with the reality created by the old tradition. Stumble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/hr2KLTa7VdEADCwhMyt0UrsUlRnkbZScs5KLBFGv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/hr2KLTa7VdEADCwhMyt0UrsUlRnkbZScs5KLBFGv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1930, Xu Guangping took a photo with her husband Lu Xun and son Zhou Haiying. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Between the Old and the New&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Cao Peisheng was born in 1902 In that year, the Qing government issued an edict to &quot;anti-foot-binding&quot; and &quot;promote women&#39;s education.&quot; There is a gulf between what government says is one thing and how society works is another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actual effect of the ban was very small. The custom of foot binding continued to flourish until the early years of the Republic of China, and Cao Peisheng was not spared. She left her hometown in 1915 and followed her married brother Cao Chengke&#39;s family to Wuchang. Cao Chengke asked a tutor to teach his sister instead of sending her to a new school. This also shows that although the slogan of &quot;promoting girls&#39; education&quot; has been shouted for more than ten years, the results are still limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the new cultural transformation stage, the boundaries between the old and the new are far less clear-cut than imagined. Xu Guangping was born in Guangzhou. His mother is from Macau and his maternal grandfather is an overseas Chinese. However, his mother&#39;s family attaches great importance to the &quot;three-inch golden lotus&quot;, so they forced Xu Guangping to bind his feet. However, his father did not agree. However, the reason was that Xu Guangping had been married since he was a child. , she will marry into a country family in the future, and her small feet will be an obstacle to her married life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elders on the father&#39;s side did not allow girls in the family to study, thinking that it would dampen the ambition of boys. Xu Guangping&#39;s mother, who had studied with her brothers, raised objections and won the opportunity for her daughter to enter a private school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Guangping’s parents had conflicting views on their daughter’s foot-binding and schooling issues, which reflected the social background at that time: even though they lived in Guangzhou and Macau, which had a lot of contact with the outside world, the people’s understanding of “new” and “old” The measurement is still uneven, there is no fixed standard, and opinions are mostly affected by personal experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, the term &quot;new woman&quot; also has multi-layered connotations. 《五四婚姻》简体版新增的江冬秀，不曾上过新派学堂，也没有自己的职业，但她婚后学会了用白话文写信，尝试过写自传，二十年北京生活使她蜕变，她拥有自己的观点和社交圈，还为梁宗岱的发妻争取权益，出庭担任他们离婚官司的证人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她不囿于任何框框，既不是&#39;从夫&#39;&#39;从子&#39;式的传统女性，也不是夫唱妇随式的新派芸娘，更不是爱时髦打扮的洋化太太。”在孔慧怡看来，有独立人格、个性的江冬秀，也是一名非典型“新女性”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相对于“跳出框框”的江冬秀，看似新潮的陆小曼实际上却是“掉进罅隙”的那个。她的身上，反映出当时社会另一种普遍存在的新女性形象——闲在家中，装束时髦，日常生活由购物、票戏、打牌、跳舞构成。早年，她进出交际场所，是大家艳羡的对象，徐志摩让她离开了原本的生活轨道，新的社交圈子使她不得不面对另一种新女性标准的审视。在徐志摩的朋友圈中，没有谁会认为过惯了官太太生活的摩登女子是他们心目中的新女性。陆小曼像个迷路的人，掉落进文化夹缝。这其中，家庭的影响不可忽视，她能参照的女性典型——她的母亲交游的圈子，就是这样的上流太太。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新文化名人的原配中，当属张幼仪出走得最远。今人将她的名字与成功的事业女性挂钩，却容易忽视旧女性长成新女性，需要具备的种种条件。在这点上的省思，是本书对女性身份投去的深切注目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只身受困英国，成为张幼仪命运的转折点。投奔身在欧洲的兄弟后，她重拾婚前读师范学校的理想，在德国念了三年多的书，这对她回中国后的道路产生了决定性影响。后来，便是人们津津乐道的故事：出掌上海女子银行，担任云裳服装公司的经理，蜚声沪上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，事业有成后的张幼仪，对于自己少受新式教育这点，依然感到自卑，无法释怀。晚年的她对侄孙女张邦梅追述往事，说：“在中国，女人不算什么：在家从父，出嫁从夫，夫死从子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本书中，最后出场的是林徽因，她也是七位女性中出生最晚的。作为许多人心目中五四新女性的佼佼者，林徽因在事业与婚恋上达成了难得的平衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名豆瓣网友为《五四婚姻》写下评论：“留待最后的林徽音实在别有深意，这种力量感既有家庭（父亲）的有意栽培，个人的敏感睿智，也离不开梁思成内在稳定的&#39;自在&#39;——也是几段关系中仅有的平等、自主，尽管如此，也难逃抚育和家庭琐务的烦累，更不用说时代大浪的次次锤击。而作者也早已言明转身之难：要年轻、要有家底、要有明理支持女性的父兄——张幼仪的幸运，是个人的卓然，也实在是命运的馈赠。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“直到今时今日，女性还面对很多传统压力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;本书人物的编排次序似乎别有意味，你是否有过特殊考量？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;动笔之前，我就觉得一贯对所谓旧女性和新女性的描写都未能展示文化剧变时期的实情。要改变传统对女性的定论，除了作者的基本立场，还得有充实可靠的材料，而就第一手资料而言，我始终认为先天不足。怎么补救呢？选择在生命线上曾经交汇的人物，可以为读者提供重叠的视觉效果，让大家更能体会事情并非黑白分明。我觉得这本书有点像缺了一些方块的拼图游戏，只有依赖现存方块的融合和对比，让读者大概看出全局的模样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;七位女性，产生种种对照，其中曹佩声与张幼仪似形成了鲜明对比，一位事业有成但终身困于爱情，一位秋扇见捐却在职场上焕发光亮。你最初在阅读、梳理这些女性的人生经历时，会否直观体会到一种映照之感？或是经历了认知的深化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;她们的际遇有某些相似的地方，比如都是婚姻失意后，得到可贵的进修机会，也在各自的行业为女性写下新一页。我想她们人生路上表现的分歧，主要是性格使然。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;收集材料的时候，我没有刻意做对比，但写书的过程就像跟书中人物交朋友，认识会深化，像在现实中交朋友一样，会抱着理解的心态看她们的人生，常常有“人之不同，各如其面”的感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你强调新文化转型阶段新与旧之间的畛域并不如想象中分明，这是否你写作此书的重要出发点之一？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这的确是很重要的一点。我对黑白分明的论述一直抱着怀疑，因为我们本身的经历就不断提醒我们，人生不是黑白分明的。直到今时今日，女性还面对很多传统压力。比如多念两个学位，就被警告说会嫁不出去；不结婚，每逢亲戚聚会就成为他们说教的目标；结了婚不生小孩，就被责是“自私”。凡此种种，只算是小事，可也够烦的。更别说职场上被低贬，被占小便宜了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;书里此种叙述也可看出新旧观念与身份的模糊性：不同于朱安、陆小曼，江冬秀在丈夫的朋友圈里真正收获了尊重。你认为有哪些因素导致了这样的区别？在当时，文化圈层评价女性的标准也是复杂多样的吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;唐德刚说江冬秀幸运，我很同意，因为她的丈夫个性温和，对女性又带着西方的君子风度，让她能发挥自己的长处。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实文化圈也不是单一的，每个圈子都有内在运作的标准。比如朱安在周家新台门大家族时，不会被认为不够格；陆小曼早年进出交际场所，是大家艳羡的对象。只是在进入新的圈子之后，她们才被人用另一种标准来衡量。这样的情况，即使不是文化剧变时期，也有例子，比如普通人家跟豪门进行婚娶，双方也会面对新的衡量标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“说到女性经验，经济问题总要抬头”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;文中提到，林徽因被许多人视为中国20世纪新女性佼佼者，你的字里行间也透露出同样的欣赏。林徽因在事业、感情方面一以贯之的选择，除了见出她的理智、坚定，还有没有更深层的品质？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我最欣赏的是林徽音坦然的态度。像她自己说的，她是个理智和感情同样强烈的人，因此我相信她的决定不是纯粹由理智主导的，“爱”也占很大的比重。说到坦然，我想这可能正是她病危时想见张幼仪的原因——因为张幼仪被弃和她扯上了关系，她无法坦然。我们不可能知道她当时想说什么，假如我戴上小说家的帽子，给她编一句话，那会是“我佩服你”。不过，也许她真的不必说话：张幼仪愿意见她，一派成功女士的风范，而且儿孙绕膝，她可以坦然了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为何在初版中没有撰写江冬秀这个人物？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是个正中要害的问题。我写初版的时候觉得无法捉摸江冬秀，回想起来有点吊诡，因为事后才了解，最大的障碍可能就是麻将。这跟我小时候大家族聚会的情况有关，每逢喜庆，长辈聚头总要打麻将，我们小孩觉得很吵。但终于为我打破心理障碍的也是麻将：我一位姑婆病危住院，亲戚去看望，她迷糊中还说：“叫佣人给你们开台吧。”这让我终于明白麻将在那一代人中起的社交作用。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;许广平“经过自由恋爱和个人选择而建立的婚姻关系，竟然令她失去原来的独立地位”。在你的观察里，当代中国女性在职场、婚恋上的境遇，与新文化运动时期相比，有哪些比较显著的异同？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我对中国内地年轻一代的生活了解不多，很难做深入的对比。只能这样说：人性基本是相通的，这很大程度是女性苦恼的来源。比如大家都认为女性细心，善于照顾人，于是家中小的老的都是女的一肩挑起。即使是西方，妇女运动红红火火数十年，夫妇生了孩子，托儿的经济负担太重，要其中一人留在家里带孩子，那就总是女方辞职或者改为半职，男的负责带孩子百中无一，结果是到了退休时，女性的退休金远比男的低。说到女性经验，经济问题总要抬头。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于现在和五四不同的地方，最主要是社会结构不一样了，人口向大城市转移，而城市文化为女性提供比较多的机会。人口政策也让很多家庭只有独女，现在女孩的待遇好多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;经过近十年修订此书，你有哪些新的理解与思考？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一个领会，是看到自己的盲点，也就是上面说到的江冬秀和麻将。此外是体会到细节能起的作用，比如在许广平那一章，新版提供了不少数字，包括她在广州的薪金和1940年代的物价，叙述就比较开阔了。当然，追寻细节不能无休无止，最后还是得坦然面对不足的地方。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;途经沙士顿，是成书的契机。在写作这本书期间，你是否走访过其他与传主们有关的地点？可以分享其中一两段对你触动最大的游历吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;孔慧怡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;感受最深的是在绍兴看周家新台门，看博物馆里层层相扣的陪嫁大床，还有坐小船从鉴湖到岳王庙。关于朱安的文字材料，除了她晚年的书信，基本都要淘金似的从别人的记述过滤出来，要体会她早年生活的环境，就靠那一个星期的绍兴之行。此外，在北京鲁迅博物馆看朱安和许广平及海婴通信的原信，也让我很感动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外一件事，是我构思这本书之前好几年。一位上海学者陪我到鲁迅故居，站在门外时，他说：这也是许广平故居。我当时觉得很“安慰”，因为也有男性学者注意到这一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安机关公开通缉2名缅北电诈犯罪集团重要头目，最高奖励50万元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258471]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;当前，缅北涉我电信网络诈骗犯罪形势严峻，社会危害严重，人民群众反映强烈。经浙江省杭州市公安局、云南省昆明市公安局侦查发现，陈岩板（又名鲍岩板）、肖岩块（又名何春田）系缅北涉我电信网络诈骗犯罪集团重要头目，长期组织开设诈骗窝点，实施针对中国公民的电信网络诈骗犯罪活动，诈骗数额巨大、性质极其恶劣。现已查明，陈岩板、肖岩块犯罪事实清楚、证据确凿充分，浙江省杭州市公安局、云南省昆明市公安局决定对其进行公开悬赏通缉。公安机关敦促犯罪嫌疑人陈岩板、肖岩块认清形势，悬崖勒马，主动投案自首，争取宽大处理。同时，希望社会各界和广大人民群众积极举报，协助抓捕犯罪嫌疑人。对提供有效线索和协助抓捕的有功人员，公安机关将给予10万至50万元人民币奖励。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b66902f5091a00a278af19b7c2b64497.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;283&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b66902f5091a00a278af19b7c2b64497.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;犯罪嫌疑人陈岩板（鲍岩板）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ad5acecebd6294fb46481dca103a3d0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;358&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ad5acecebd6294fb46481dca103a3d0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;犯罪嫌疑人肖岩块（何春田）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>