<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《过往人生》：所有分手，皆是前世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3xhFWCTzZEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3 xhFWCTzZEO. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250685&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The English title of the movie &quot;Past Lives&quot; (&lt;em>;Past Lives&lt;/em>;) is a pun, which is both past life and plural. previous life. This shortlisted film for the main competition of the 2023 Berlin Film Festival has recently been praised by many audiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Nora reunited with Haisheng, a boy who had first fallen in love at the age of 12, after 24 years of separation, she had already changed her English name. On Nora&#39;s left hand side, her husband, American Jewish writer Arthur, sat, speaking English to him; on Nora&#39;s right hand side, Hae Sung, who had miraculously transformed from a child into a mature man, spoke Korean to him. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora and Haisheng discussed that the reason why they can sit here is because they were full of bonds in their previous lives. In those previous lives, they were either a princess secretly in love with her servant, or two people who did not love each other and betrayed each other due to family marriage, or they just happened to be seated next to each other on the train, or they were a bird and the person who carried it. Early morning tree branches. When they parted, they said that this moment might also be the past life. Because the past life is not only the talk of karma in Buddhism, but also a parallel time and space of imaginary, regretful, and missed possibilities. Since their relationship in this life is still full of shortcomings, then think of it as a vague past life, think of it as something that has happened and been written, rather than something that is being created, think of it as a dream and a bubble. Not vividly. What will be their afterlife? No one knows the answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Three past lives or parallel time and space&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the tetralogy of the Japanese writer Mishima Yukio&#39;s posthumous novel series &quot;The Sea of ​​Plenty&quot; , the reincarnation of past life, present life, and afterlife slowly unfolds in a bizarre and reasonable way. It is a completely different view of time from the West. All tragedies can always be soothed by the endless world of possibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the film, at the age of 12, Nora is still called Moon Na-young in Seoul. Her father is a director and her mother is an artist. She is a cultural elite and middle class in South Korea, and she decided to immigrate to Canada with her family. Hae Sung was Na Young&#39;s classmate in elementary school, because Na Young always came first in the exam. Once Hae Sung got the first place in the exam, Na Young became a crybaby. When her classmates asked her why she wanted to immigrate, she said it was because Koreans could not win the Nobel Prize for Literature. Naying drew a bird on Hae Sung&#39;s arm with a colored pen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 24, Nora accidentally found a post looking for her on her father&#39;s Facebook page. Haisheng had been looking for Naying online, but she had already changed her name to Nora Moon. The two communicated through text messages, made video calls, and crush each other again, their hearts pounding. For a while, their relationship was like an exotic online relationship. In order to adapt to Haesheng&#39;s time zone, Nora changed her schedule and got up early to talk to him. When Haesheng was riding the cable car in Namsan, he would also make video calls to Nora and show her Seoul from the air. landscape. But the signal in the air was unstable. After the connection was disconnected, Nora&#39;s expression seemed to be worried that something might happen to Hai Sheng. The network&#39;s Aladdin&#39;s lamp withdrew its promise to her, and Hai Sheng was imprisoned in the darkness of the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Haisheng said to Nora, your Korean is really bad. She said, I only speak Korean to my mother and you. Online dating will always come true one day. Nora hopes that Haisheng will come to New York, where she has dreams of drama and writing. But what she wants now is not the Nobel Prize for Literature, but the Pulitzer Prize. Haisheng is going to China for exchange. He has always wanted to learn Chinese because it will be useful in the future. Is the distance between the two just the vast Pacific Ocean? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 36, Haisheng came to New York under the pretext of traveling, but actually he made a special trip to visit Nora. Nora has been married to Arthur for seven years. Compared with Hai Sheng, Arthur looks ordinary and is used to wearing worn jeans and brown jackets. He is a writer. Of course, he will not take a yacht to see the postcard scenery like the Statue of Liberty like a tourist. But after learning that Nora is accompanying him on the sea Sheng had been to this travel project, but felt a little bit disappointed. He met Nora at a creative writing residency and got married for Nora&#39;s green card. Arthur asked Nora if our story was a little too plain. You only spoke Korean in the dream, which was a world I couldn&#39;t understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora finally sent Hai Sheng to the street where he was waiting for the bus. The two of them were silent for two minutes, one meter apart, as if this meter was the Pacific Ocean. For two minutes, they had no kiss, no lingering affection, no confession. They had never become true lovers. It was not until the car came that they had a hesitant courtesy hug. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why these two minutes of silence are touching? Perhaps no one said it better than the American writer Salinger: &quot;Some people think that love is sex, marriage, a kiss at six o&#39;clock in the morning. Pile of children, that may be true, Miss Leicester. But you know what I think? I think love wants to touch and then withdraws its hand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is no paradise, no paradise on earth&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Celine Song, the director of &quot;A Life in the Past,&quot; must be no stranger to Salinger. She is a writer of Korean descent in Canada. She came to New York to do theater in her twenties and wrote this story based on similar experiences. A few years ago, she was sitting with her American husband and her childhood friend at a bar in New York&#39;s East Village, and she kept translating for them. Song felt the eyes around him sizing up this strange trio, so he started talking about it in the voice-over at the beginning of the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song loves romantic dramas. She feels that what drives romantic dramas are often adults who act like children. She hopes that the characters will show what love is like when everyone reveals their feelings for each other. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Korean-American actress Greta Lee, who plays Nora, read the script, she couldn&#39;t help sobbing and had to continue reading with difficulty while crying. Although Greta Lee is a second-generation immigrant born in the United States, she can obviously understand the double dilemma of Asians in North America. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora told Arthur that in New York, she knew many Korean Americans, but Haisheng was not like them. He was an authentic Korean. However, when chatting with Hai Sheng, she also became more Korean. Nora asked Hai Sheng why he was not married yet. She seemed to have completely lost the New York artist&#39;s tolerance for multiculturalism and marital status, and asked her compatriots in a conservative way of thinking. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the difference in life choices between Hai Sheng and Nora is a metaphor for Korean society: Hai Sheng studied practical engineering and came to China, which has deep historical roots with South Korea and broad economic prospects. Exchange; Nora studies literature and drama and wants to pursue her ambitions in New York, a global cultural center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Nora said that the reason for immigration was that &quot;Koreans cannot win the Nobel Prize for Literature,&quot; this line with quite a comedic effect revealed a common anxiety among residents of the third world. : On the one hand, they are full of recognition and admiration for the literary achievements represented by the Nobel Prize in Literature; on the other hand, they unconsciously fall into the inevitable Western-centrism trap of the Nobel Prize selection mechanism. The self-hate contained in the negative sentence &quot;Koreans can&#39;t get...&quot; is behind the distrust of the social structure, cultural system, and overall creativity of backward areas. But when she broke away from Korea and wrote in English, when she was identified as a North American Asian, she was forever stuck in the middle state of being neither a Korean writer nor an American writer. She and Arthur moved in together because they could save money by renting together, and they got married early because of the immigration policy. Nora asked, is this really the life that their parents expected their daughter to live when they immigrated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douban netizen Toska said in a short comment: &quot;The thing that makes me feel most uncomfortable in &quot;A Past Life&quot; is the undercurrent of superiority. New York is better than Toronto, Toronto is better than Seoul, and she is better than or equal to the United States. Koreans, American Koreans are better than Koreans (a word used in the movie is Korean Koreans, the former word is Korean in the cultural sense, and the latter word is Korean in the ethnic sense), &quot;The scary thing is that I think The creator himself is not aware of it, but he feels wronged. He sings about his own barren experience and feelings without self-reflection.&quot; This may provide another angle to think about the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening film of this year&#39;s Busan International Film Festival &quot;I Hate Korea&quot; is adapted from the novel &quot;Out of Korea&quot;. The protagonist Guina is a person with average education, work and appearance. Everything in the future is doomed. No miracle happened, she said: &quot;Korea loves itself, not me. It only loves those who make it shine... and avoids those who shame it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the same theme of separation, the protagonist of &quot;Out of Korea&quot; wants to escape involution and class solidification, Nora of &quot;My Life&quot; is looking forward to being on the world stage, and Hae Sung, who stays in Korea, wants to To become a &quot;better&quot; person, even if the body is hard, the spirit is not willing to admit defeat. The real problem is that no matter which land we live in, we cannot expect a paradise on earth. There is no paradise once and for all, only eternal dilemmas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hai Sheng asked Nora, if you had not gone abroad when you were 12 years old, what would be the difference if I came to New York when I was 24? Perhaps, it is precisely because they have only had two glimpses in the past 24 years and have not fallen into the trivialities of life and magnified each other&#39;s shortcomings that this shortcoming is perfect and charming, worthy of Nora bursting into tears. On one side is the perfect first love of the imperfect motherland, and on the other It is the imperfect daily life of a perfect utopia. She wanders the streets of Manhattan and wanders in nowhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海一初中现投毒事件？警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:23:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 15:37 on September 12, 2023, the Pudong Public Security Bureau received an alarm saying that there was a police officer in a middle school on Xianan Road. Many students are unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After preliminary investigation, the school’s student Yang Moumou (&lt;span>;female, 13 years old&lt;/span>;) and his classmate Zheng Moumou (female, 13 years old) took advantage of the physical education class that morning. Returning to the classroom, he poured the cleaning and bleaching mixture into the water cups of his classmates, causing many students to become uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant students were sent to the hospital for treatment and were discharged that night and have now resumed normal classes. Currently, the police are working with the education department to conduct further investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;295&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250759&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当买不起LV包的年轻人入手了百元高奢包装袋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo/图）&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wearing the latest Chanel jacket, putting on a collector’s edition Cartier watch, picking up the Hermès “Dream Love Bag”, and feeling the refreshing fragrance of Guerlain perfume, it was officially Stepping out of the house - this is the &quot;luxury&lt;/span>;urban dream&quot; in the hearts of countless boys and girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, a post &quot;Zhejiang people spend 1.8 billion a year on Chanel&quot; sparked heated discussion. Sales of the Chanel store in Hangzhou Tower reached 1.8 billion yuan last year. Many luxury goods, including Chanel, are advertised as &quot;rich&quot;. Netizens joked: &quot;Poverty limits my imagination. There are so many rich people, why can&#39;t there be one more for me?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“There are not many people in ordinary shopping malls, but there are long queues in luxury stores.” Many netizens have this feeling about luxury stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking across the country, whether in Beijing, Shanghai, or other cities, the stores of luxury brands such as Hermès, Chanel, and Gucci are often overcrowded. When new products are released, they are comparable to large-scale &quot;ticket check-in&quot; scenes, which are different from ordinary stores. Compared with the twos and threes of customers in the brand store, it can be described as a world of ice and fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China’s luxury craze: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Thousand-layer tricks to attract attention and attract money&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Luxury goods are recognized internationally It is defined as &quot;a kind of consumer goods that are unique, scarce, rare and beyond the scope of people&#39;s survival and development needs&quot;, also known as non-living necessities. However, the sluggish consumption environment does not seem to affect the enthusiasm of &quot;die-hard fans&quot; for this &quot;non-necessities of life&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, a Louis Vuitton handbag&lt;/span>; sells for 17,000 yuan in France and 24,000 yuan in mainland China. Yuan. In addition to the long queues outside the store, a group of people silently opened the page of the overseas purchasing platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an important force in the world’s luxury consumption, the Chinese market is indispensable for brand expansion. The &quot;2022 China Luxury Goods Report&quot; shows that Chinese luxury goods market sales will reach 956 billion yuan in 2022, a slight decrease of 4% year-on-year, accounting for 38% of the global luxury goods market. Its importance can be imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only are they expensive, the prices of luxury goods are also soaring. In November last year, Chanel raised the prices of all products by 3% to 11%. According to statistics from the fashion website Purse&lt;span>;Bop, the average annual increase for low-end luxury goods is about 4%, and that for high-end luxury goods is between 15% and 18%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although prices are &quot;rising and rising&quot;, they cannot resist the enthusiasm of buyers, and snapping up luxury goods has become a highly sought-after fashion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250401 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Behind the &quot;pursuit of luxury&quot; is the multi-pronged strategy of &quot;attracting attention&quot; and &quot;attracting money&quot; created by luxury brands&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the popularity of the &quot;Metaverse&quot; concept, many brands have turned their attention to this new way of playing. Gucci once cooperated with the gaming platform Roblox to open a Gucci pop-up store and launched a digital version of the Gucci Bacchus bag, which was sold for US$4,100, US$700 higher than the physical bag. Balenciaga also makes virtual costumes for multiple characters in the game &quot;Fortnite&quot;, and players can wear &quot;genuine skins&quot; for $8. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“It’s not money that is wasted. If you can’t afford it in real life, just enjoy it in the game.” Ronaldinho, a senior gamer, talked about his views on buying “skins” mentioned at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Not only that, brands such as Prada, Louis Vuitton, and Burberry have all tested the &quot;Metaverse&quot;. This wave of operations inevitably led to ridicule from netizens: &quot;The leeks in reality&lt;/span>; are endless, and we have to cut the leeks in the &#39;metaverse&#39; again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Breaking the consumption dimension wall is not enough, &quot;it is economical&quot; Luxury goods are also indispensable for the hot trend. As the saying goes, &quot;pampering comes with the owner,&quot; many cats and dogs enjoy a luxurious cat/dog life under the &quot;absolute love&quot; of their owners. A traction rope worth 5,000 yuan, a pet carrying case worth 20,000 yuan, a pet bed worth 17,000 yuan... The pet products launched by Hermès focus on &quot;gold and preciousness&quot;, &quot;These days, dogs are richer than me.&quot; Pet. Zhu Xiaofang commented on social media, &quot;Why are even pets involved? I cried.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course, luxury brands will not let go of any potential consumers. In addition to traditional items such as bags, clothing, and jewelry, small items such as mobile phone cases, earphone cases, and keychains are also quietly emerging. A certain grassroots blogger wrote on Xiaohongshu: &quot;Can&#39;t afford a five-figure Louis Vuitton bag, and also can&#39;t afford peripherals? Go, go, go!&quot; I don&#39;t know how many buyers were attracted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking through the catalogs of luxury brands, you can also see many novel products: coffins, body bags... rich in styles and expensive. Netizens&#39; imaginations ran wild: &quot;Is this the &lt;span>;legendary &#39;die gracefully&#39;?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC pho&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to / picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people play high-end luxury: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Second-hand buying and selling , Big-name samples&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The level of luxury goods consumption is inseparable from the city&#39;s economic strength. The &quot;2019 Luxury Goods Industry Insight Report&quot; shows that Beijing and Shanghai ranked first and second respectively in the ranking of cities with luxury goods consumption levels in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 53 Hermès stores across the country, excluding a total of 20 stores in Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan, Beijing and Shanghai have 5 stores each, accounting for nearly 1/3 of the number of stores in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these buyers, high-net-worth groups (mainland Chinese with assets of tens of millions of yuan) are the &quot;top-tier&quot; consumers. They and &quot;luxury goods&quot; are like the best partners going both ways. However, nowadays, luxury consumers are not just traditional &quot;high-end buyers&quot;, but also a huge number of young people who can become buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report shows that the post-90s generation in China’s luxury goods market has become the main force in luxury goods consumption, accounting for 50% of the overall market consumer population. At the same time, Bain Luxury Research Report has predicted that by 2025, Millennials and consumers under the age of 25 will become the main force in the luxury consumer market, accounting for 65% to 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As young people with potential, luxury brands have made a lot of efforts in digital marketing to reach them - 68% of young people will be &quot;planted&quot; by content posted by celebrities or bloggers , and then generate purchasing behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250409&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, not all young people have amazing financial resources. Young buyers can also enjoy luxury goods by buying second-hand goods with &quot;exquisite poverty&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;China&#39;s Second-hand Luxury Goods Industry Overview 2021&quot; shows that more than half of second-hand luxury goods consumers are under 30 years old, and the reasons for more than half of consumers&lt;/span>;&#39;s purchases The price is lower than new products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buy and sell, sell and buy, &quot;out-of-print&quot; goods on the market can be found second-hand, and both parties enjoy the joy of luxury goods circulation in the transaction. According to statistics, more than half of the users in the market choose to &quot;buy and sell at the same time&quot;, and there is a significant trend of &quot;integration of buying and selling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 Circular Fashion Industry Trend Report&quot; shows that the domestic second-hand luxury goods market reached 17.3 billion yuan in 2020, and is expected to reach 38.4 billion yuan in 2025. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Buyers hunt for goods in a variety of categories, mainly in the fields of luggage and leather goods, clothing, shoes and hats, high-end watches and jewelry accessories. Due to the wide audience and high value retention, luggage Leather goods have become the first choice for second-hand luxury goods consumers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Facing high-end luxury cosmetics that are easy to wear, there is a more affordable &quot;big brand sample&quot; method. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“You can enjoy big-name brands at a two- or three-digit price, why not?” Xiaotian, a junior student, is a makeup novice and works with many beauty experts. Similarly, she has collected all kinds of big-name foundations, lipsticks, perfumes, and skin care products. The only difference is that hers are all &quot;samples&quot;: &quot;I don&#39;t wear makeup more than ten times a month. It&#39;s a waste to buy formal clothes. Worry about being cheap, big brands will feel more at ease.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by the huge consumer market, businesses have sensed business opportunities. Not only are &quot;samples&quot; sold individually, but repackaged versions of big-name cosmetics are also highly sought after. On the e-commerce platform, the official price of 100ml of Chanel Gabrielle Natural Perfume is about 1,690 yuan, and its 10ml &quot;sample&quot; only costs about 130 yuan. However, most of these products are sold by stores named &quot;XX Purchasing Agency&quot; or other stores whose legitimacy is difficult to judge. The products are mixed and it is difficult to distinguish between genuine and fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1074&quot; height=&quot;3659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250408&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, there is also the method of &quot;making the most of everything&lt;/span>;&quot; that was once popular. Platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu have launched a trend of packaging reform. Some bloggers have transformed packaging bags or packaging boxes with brand logos into tissue boxes, jewelry boxes, and take-out bags, which has quickly accelerated the purchasing trend of luxury packaging. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, there are still many people selling luxury goods packaging on Xianyu, ranging from tens of yuan to hundreds of yuan, and there is an endless stream of people coming to inquire. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250406 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC photo / picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;Luxury goods controversy:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The quality of genuine products is worrying, and the fake rate reaches 80%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;No&lt;/span>; However, luxury goods remain The public&#39;s impression is not only that it is expensive, but also a product that is deeply involved in controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, almost every year, the Internet takes turns to ridicule the &quot;legendary&quot; items launched by certain luxury goods. For example, the &quot;woven bag for moving&quot; that appeared in the fashion week, the sneakers covered with green grass, the same fake bangs of the &quot;Buried Love Family&quot;, and the hole-in-the-wall umbrella that &quot;shelters from rain and loneliness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the designer did it intentionally or not, the marketing effect is so good that even if the whole network complains, it cannot stop a group of people from secretly placing orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, luxury shopping has been described by various bloggers as a &quot;magical&quot; experience. &quot;Wearing cheap clothes and being looked down upon after entering the store&quot; &quot;The shopkeeper looks down on ordinary people&quot;...Such shopping reviews are flooded with short video platforms, and the amplification of the Internet has made many people fear luxury stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the quality of luxury goods has been criticized. In February this year, Ms. Zhang from Fujian spent 20,000 yuan to buy a Chanel handbag while traveling in Chengdu. However, the chain broke after just 15 minutes of carrying it. Such problems are common, and there are endless complaints about luxury goods on the Black Cat complaint platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is a widely circulated joke on the Internet: If&lt;/span>; the luxury bag you buy has problems such as fading, there is no doubt that it must be genuine. It is particularly strong and wear-resistant, so be careful as it may be a fake. &quot;Key customer data&quot; shows that in channels other than the brand&#39;s official channels, the rate of fake products is as high as over 80%. In the current Chinese market, the number of fake luxury goods is six times that of genuine goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4178&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250410&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is even more nerve-wracking&lt;/span>; is the frequent plagiarism of luxury goods in recent years. Last year, Dior launched a mid-length skirt that collided with the traditional Chinese dress &quot;horse face skirt&quot;, but the brand called it &quot;Dior&#39;s signature silhouette.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, with the aftermath of the &quot;Horse Face Skirt&quot; incident still lingering, Dior has launched a 2022 autumn and winter series of clothing, with the original Dior winter garden pattern once again colliding with the Chinese traditional painting &quot;Flowers and Birds&quot;. In the face of successive acts of plagiarism, the voice of resisting &quot;cultural appropriation&quot; has become increasingly louder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the world-class luxury goods that are currently highly sought after still mainly come from overseas. On the other hand, my country&#39;s local brands still have huge room for growth on the road to becoming the world&#39;s business card. We also look forward to the international success of local brands&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部启动首届全国大学生职业规划大赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the Ministry of Education issued a notice to launch the first National College Student Career Planning Competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first National College Student Career Planning Competition, with the theme of &quot;Building Dreams and Aiming for Youth in All Places, Planning to Start Careers and Lead the Future&quot;, was co-sponsored by the Ministry of Education and the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Government. By holding competitions, we strive to create a large classroom that strengthens career education, a large platform that promotes the connection between talent supply and demand, and a large market that serves graduates&#39; employment. We strengthen career education and employment guidance in colleges and universities, enhance college students&#39; awareness of career planning, and guide college students to prepare for employment as early as possible. Better promote high-quality and full employment of college graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition will be held from September 2023 to May 2024. It will adopt a three-level competition system of school competition, provincial competition, and national finals. It will set up a growth track, an employment track, and career development and employment guidance courses for college students. The teaching track is for teachers of career development and employment guidance courses for junior and middle school students, senior students and college students in colleges and universities. The school competition is organized by each university, and the provincial competition is organized by each locality. The national finals are hosted by the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission, Fudan University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai Normal University, and Shanghai Vocational College of Arts and Crafts. There are gold, silver, and bronze awards, as well as individual awards, local and university outstanding organizations. Award, Outstanding Instructor Award and other awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Registration for the competition will begin on September 20, 2023. At that time, participating students can register through the National College Student Career Planning Competition platform (website: zgs.chsi.com.cn) or designated channels. Registration deadline The time is determined by each locality according to the provincial competition arrangement. During the competition, universities across the country will also hold a series of activities such as employment guidance, campus recruitment, school-enterprise supply and demand matching, and career experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《校外培训行政处罚暂行办法》颁布：严管校外培训，能否压缩外力鸡娃的空间？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Education promulgated the &quot;Interim Measures for Administrative Penalties for Off-Campus Training&quot;, with 6 chapters and 44 articles, which will be implemented in 2023 It will come into effect on October 15, 2020. As soon as the regulations of this department were promulgated, they attracted concern from all parties, especially training institutions and their employees and even parents, who wanted to know where the legal and illegal boundaries of off-campus training were drawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common consensus among everyone is that in-service teachers should not engage in off-campus training. Article 16 of the above-mentioned measures stipulates that if the parties involved &quot;are in-service teachers in primary and secondary schools and the training content is subject-based off-campus training&quot;, they shall be severely punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been cases like this: a teacher did not teach well in class, and then mobilized students to participate in paid private training organized by him, and even put small shoes on students who did not participate. This is undoubtedly against professional ethics. Public school teachers, teaching is their main job, and they have to be worthy of the salary they receive. How can they charge students a second time for the content that should be taught in the classroom? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what are the core contents and provisions of this regulation? The following three points deserve attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, Article 2 of the Measures stipulates: If a natural person, legal person or other organization recruits preschool children, primary and secondary school students over 3 years old from the society, and illegally conducts off-campus training, and shall be given administrative penalties, these Measures shall apply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, if a natural person or institution enrolls infants and young children under 3 years old, it is almost equivalent to day care. It is okay for the children in day care to play educational games and recite Tang poetry. It will be considered as off-campus training or illegal off-campus training. Indeed, logically, only when a child goes to kindergarten or school can there be &quot;school&quot;, and only then can there be &quot;outside school&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for this article, the General Provisions do not define &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Among the various types of penalties, specific circumstances of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; should be punished. The basis for the document&#39;s definition of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; is: the 2021 &quot;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Training Burden of Students in Compulsory Education&quot; issued by the two offices in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;double reduction&quot; programmatic document defines the boundaries of off-campus training as follows: for training institutions, &quot;all localities will no longer approve new subject-based off-campus training institutions for students in compulsory education. All discipline-based training institutions are uniformly registered as non-profit institutions, and the original registered online discipline-based training institutions are changed to an approval system.&quot; For training content, &quot;Establish a training content filing and supervision system, and formulate and release training materials for off-campus training institutions. &quot;Management Measures&quot; &quot;It is strictly prohibited to exceed the standard and advance training, it is strictly prohibited to engage in subject-based training by non-disciplinary training institutions, and it is strictly prohibited to provide overseas education courses&quot;; for students and teachers, &quot;Online training must pay attention to protecting students&#39; vision, and each class period shall not exceed 30 minutes. The interval should be no less than 10 minutes, and the training end time should be no later than 21:00. &quot;The hiring of foreign personnel within the country must comply with relevant national regulations. It is strictly prohibited to hire foreign personnel abroad to carry out training activities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this measure stipulates that the &quot;off-campus training competent department&quot; shall enforce the law and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Article 6 stipulates that administrative penalties for off-campus training shall be implemented by the off-campus training authorities of governments at or above the county level, and the off-campus training authorities shall be determined by provincial governments in accordance with relevant national regulations. So, is the “off-campus training authority” the local education bureau or education committee? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This regulation is formulated and promulgated by the Ministry of Education, which also authorizes provincial governments to determine what is the competent authority for off-campus training. There is a trend in administrative law enforcement: instead of allowing each department to enforce the law on its own, a comprehensive law enforcement agency will be established to ensure that law enforcement is carried out within legitimate substantive matters and due procedures, and to reduce the number of departments that rely on the weak and the weak. Create space for rent-seeking to reduce nuisance to natural persons and enterprises and improve the business environment. Therefore, it remains to be seen who will enforce the law on &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this measure is very strict. It must control and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. The subjects include not only institutions, and the identification standards for institutions are strict, but also natural persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict standards for the identification of institutions. Article 17 of the Measures stipulates that if a natural person, legal person or other organization conducts off-campus training without approval and meets these three conditions, (1) there is a special training venue for offline training, and a specific website or application for online training, (2) Having more than 2 training practitioners, (3) having corresponding organizational structure and division of labor constitutes &quot;organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization&quot;, and will be ordered to stop organizing, refund the fees charged, and impose a fine of more than double the illegal income A fine of up to five times. This means that a mom-and-pop shop or a partnership shop between friends that handles training and operations, with as few as two people, may be recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution.&quot; Once recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution&quot; and without approval before opening, it may It constitutes organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict control over individuals engaged in subject training. Article 18 of the Measures stipulates that natural persons, legal persons or other organizations carry out off-campus training in subject areas in disguise, but do not meet the conditions stipulated in Article 17 of these Measures and commit any of the following acts: (1) Through instant messaging, online conferencing, live broadcast platforms, etc. (2) Using residential buildings, hotels, cafes and other places to organize paid off-campus training such as &quot;one-to-one&quot; and &quot;one-to-many&quot;; (3) Using consultation, cultural dissemination, quality development, For paid off-campus training in the name of competitions, thinking training, housekeeping services, family education guidance, live-in teachers, crowdfunding private tutors, study tours, study tours, winter and summer camps, trusteeship, etc., the punishment can range from an order to make corrections and a refund of fees to a fine. A fine of not less than 50,000 yuan but not more than 100,000 yuan is imposed. In theory, college students who serve as tutors will also be subject to supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Landlords or business premises that provide premises will also be subject to joint penalties. Article 19 of the Measures: If a natural person, legal person or other organization knows or should know that illegal off-campus training activities exist, but still provides a place for them to carry out off-campus training, the punishment can range from being ordered to make corrections within a time limit to being given a warning or a notice of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This measure began to solicit opinions in November last year. Now that it has finally been implemented, it will definitely have a profound impact on the form and pattern of off-campus subject training. If implemented to the letter, it will greatly reduce the space for parents to rely on external forces to help their children. Of course, it remains to be seen how much this will shake the parents’ determination and motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[仅仅多一项选择，外卖平台就显著减少了污染]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256558]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 8, 2023, the magazine &quot;Science&quot; published a report by the University of Hong Kong, Peking University, etc. The results of the research team, “Green Boosting Reduced Disposable Tableware Use: Evidence from China’s Takeaway Industry.” This paper studies the impact of the green promotion practice of changing the cutlery selection user interface of the Ele.me food delivery platform on the consumption of disposable tableware (SUC) and the reduction of plastic waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这项针对中国10个主要城市的新研究表明，在外卖应用程序下订单时默认选择“不使用餐具”，并奖励那些选择不使用塑料餐具的顾客，可以显著减少一次性餐具的浪费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;表面上看，一项涉及环保、商业、心理和经济方面的研究结果能登上世界一流期刊，足以表明这项研究的重要性。更重要的是，这项研究回答了一个重要问题，也提供了一个解决问题的思路和方法，即环保不仅需要绿色助推，也需要线上线下的共同努力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2017年9月，重庆市绿色志愿者联合会以造成资源浪费和环境污染为由，将美团、百度外卖以及饿了么告上法庭。志愿者认为，被告未向用户提供“是否使用一次性餐具”选项，致使系统默认配送一次性餐具造成巨大的资源浪费和生态破坏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这首先是线下的环保聚焦到线上的订餐。作为对绿色志愿者提告的回应，以及面临严峻的环境保护问题和巨大的责任，外卖行业巨头们纷纷作出积极回应。 2018年，美团、饿了么分别推出“青山计划”“蓝色星球计划”等环保方案，用户在订餐时，可以选择“无需餐具”，助力环保。除此之外，部分外卖平台鼓励商户用环保纸袋代替塑料袋的外卖包装，以减轻环境压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便当时这些外卖企业作出了回应，也有人怀疑，要解决由外卖衍生而出的污染问题并不容易，仅凭外卖平台方，作用有限，必须通过外卖商户、外卖平台、餐盒生产方以及消费者等多个相关方共同发力，才能让问题得到缓解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，科学研究的结果对这些问题和疑问有了一个初步的回答，只要去做和行动，哪怕是一个环节的努力，都有可能减少塑料污染，改善环境，而且结果显著，意义重大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据中外研究团队的研究结果，阿里巴巴的在线订餐平台饿了么（Eleme，类似于Uber Eats和DoorDash）利用绿色推动的概念，在应用程序中进行了调整：1.增加一个弹出窗口，要求顾客在订单中明确选择一次性餐具的数量；2.设置该弹出窗口的默认值为“无餐具”；3.为那些选择不使用餐具的人提供小额的非金钱奖励——一些“蚂蚁森林绿点”。这些绿色积分可以兑换成在中国种植真正的树木。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对2019年至2021年中国10个主要城市197062名随机选择的用户订餐历史的详细客户层面数据进行分析，发现这些绿色助推显著降低了一次性餐具的使用。无餐具订单的比例增加了648%。如果在全中国实施，这样的干预措施每年可以节省超过217.5亿套一次性餐具，减少326万吨塑料垃圾，节省544万棵树，并且不会影响阿里巴巴或个别餐厅的业务业绩或收入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个结果是多赢，但是也不只是多赢，而是提供了一个可以借鉴的减少塑料污染的可行措施，尤其是对于人口大国和使用塑料产品较多的国家有借鉴作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据经济合作与发展组织(OECD) 2022 年2月的一份报告，2000年至2019 年全球的塑料产量从234万吨增加到4.6亿吨。塑料垃圾的产生量增加了一倍多，2019年达到3.53 亿吨。根据联合国环境规划署的数据，塑料占海洋垃圾总量的至少85%。仅在2019年，就有2200万吨塑料被释放到环境中，其中600万吨流入河流、湖泊和海洋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，全球32%的塑料产自中国；一半以上的塑料来自亚洲。仅中国的产量就占全球产量的1/3 (32%)。中国又是世界上最大的一次性餐具的生产国和消费国，2022年有超过7.53亿用户是外卖服务的活跃用户，每天消耗五千多万套未被充分回收或处理的一次性餐具，包括塑料袋、塑料叉子、塑料勺子、木筷子和餐巾。因此，减少一次性餐具是一个迫在眉睫的重要使命。而且，中国也设定了到2025年将外卖食品配送中一次性餐具的使用减少30%的目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在看来，线上的订餐平台只要科学设置程序，就可以极大减少一次性餐具的使用，而且还不会减少订餐量和平台及餐馆的收入，这当然是线上和线下共同努力才能完成的。但是，在实施这种举措时，也获得了科学的依据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;饿了么订餐应用程序用户界面的变化体现了行为经济学和社会心理学中的“助推”概念，即改变选择环境(或选择架构)或提供间接信息以影响个人行为和决策的方法。助推的关键特征是它们不限制个人可用的选择，也不改变金钱激励，但是能起到某种推进或促进作用，如环保。而且助推已被用于许多社会领域，从这个理念看，也是线上和线下的行动可以极大减少一次性餐具的使用，从而保护环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，订餐平台的绿色助推并非完美，也存在不足，有待改进。一是，尽管顾客在点餐时选择了“无需餐具”，但一些商家仍然提供一次性餐具。原因在于，当商家太忙而无法逐一核对订单或担心消费者可能是错选“无需餐具”选项时，会发生这种情况；二是，顾客经常浪费他们的绿色能量，或者无法积累足够的绿色能量来种树；三是，绿色助推的影响在实施后的头几个月最明显，但会随着时间的推移而略有下降，这表明一些顾客后来决定更改默认的“无需餐具”选项。这与以往研究中关于默认选项的衰减效应是一致的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，解决这些问题，线下要下更多的功夫。当然，如果能在国内所有订餐平台，以及在其他国家的订餐平台，如DoorDash和Uber Eats等尝试和推广绿色助推，将大大减少全球塑料垃圾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼儿园教师，过剩还是不足？村小撤并与否，有更好的选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGKVGV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1116&quot; height=&quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGKVGV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年9月8日，郑州市中牟县某幼儿园。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前不久，21世纪教育研究院院长熊丙奇参加一场乡村小规模学校教师培训。有校长告诉他，当地政府一度愿意办乡村小规模学校，但现在几乎都不赞成了，认为应该撤并。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《中国教育统计年鉴》，中国乡村小学数量由2001年的416198所减至2018年的90603所，减少325595所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乡村小学数量减少的一个大背景是少子化。第七次全国人口普查结果显示，中国0至14岁人口比重为17.95%，低于狭义人口少子化概念所界定的少儿人口占总人口20%的标准。相对应的是，适龄入园幼儿人数也随之减少，给学前教育发展带来了挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在少子化持续的趋势下，学前教育如何应对？少子化叠加城镇化，乡村小规模学校又何去何从？ 2023年9月7日，由21世纪教育研究院主办的“新时代教育的转型”研讨会暨《中国教育观察（2022）》新书预告活动在北京举行，多位参会学者围绕这些教育问题展开讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“学生少于&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;56人时，幼儿园无法维持运转&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“如果要维持运作，幼儿园必须有一定规模。”东北师范大学中国农村教育发展研究院教授刘善槐对一家普惠幼儿园进行测算后，得出这样的结论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那家幼儿园的测算结果显示，每名学生每月保教费390元，一年收取9个月。政府按每名学生每月365元的标准，每年补助幼儿园12个月。当学生少于56人时，幼儿园无法维持运转。学生数量不少于115人，才能维持较好的运转水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;855&quot; height=&quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月7日，北京，东北师范大学中国农村教育发展研究院教授刘善槐（中）在研讨会上作分享。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;少子化的影响链条中，学前教育首当其冲。熊丙奇认为，政府要加大对学前教育的投入，“不应该按照现有的资源保障模式规划未来发展”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他进一步建议，应该按照义务教育的标准保障学前教育，即将义务教育向前延伸至12年，这有利于构建生育友好型社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在入园学生数量减少的同时，北京师范大学教育学部副教授冯婉桢注意到，2020年中国幼儿园教师数量却比2010年增长了近两倍，其中教职工增加了334.9万人，专任教师增加了176.9万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;增长数据背后，她发现，一些地区幼儿园教师已经富余，但在部分地区仍缺失严重。截至2020年，仍有广西、云南、四川等11个省份幼儿园在园幼儿总数与专任教师总数之比，未达到《幼儿园教职工配备标准（暂行）》中规定的大班配备最低标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冯婉桢看来，面对教师资源的不均衡，应该进行合理统筹，补充结构性缺编的幼儿园教师。在部分教师资源富余的地区，可以探索托幼一体化，把幼儿园教师引流到紧缺的托育教师队伍中。同时结合自身实际条件，扩大幼儿园的服务形式，发挥现有教师资源的效益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管教师数量大幅增长，但由于待遇较低、编制不足等原因，幼儿园教师存在流动性较大的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对上述问题，2023年8月已提请全国人大常委会初次审议的《学前教育法草案》，对幼儿园教师工资福利、人员配备等作出规定：民办幼儿园应当参照当地公办幼儿园同类教师工资收入水平合理确定教师薪酬标准，依法缴纳社会保险；幼儿园教师在职称评定、岗位聘任（用）等方面享有与中小学教师同等的待遇；地方各级编制部门依据幼儿园教职工基本编制标准和配备标准，核定公办幼儿园教职工编制并进行动态调整，地方教育部门会同人社部门及时补充公办幼儿园教师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;村小“小而优”难实现&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不同于学前教育近年开始面临少子化冲击，农村小规模学校还要面对城镇化的挑战，生存危机来得更早。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果农村教育有更高的质量，学龄人口就不必因选择优质教育流入城镇地区。”刘善槐认为，应该通过完善教育资源配置等方式，实现教育和人口的良性互动。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在东北一个县级市调研时了解到，该市2022年出生人口1200多人，6年后上小学时又将流失300至400人，一年级学龄人口只剩800至900人。这意味着，“假如不考虑学生的分布，（该市只要）一所小学就够了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在现实中，学生是分散的。而当学生从农村流向城市，教育资源的供给不一定会更加充分。但可以预见的是，农村学校的学生数量将越来越少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘善槐认为：“未来农村学校的小规模化是常态，并且越来越多的中心校会变成小规模学校，越来越多的教学点将会消失。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，一些学者对乡村小规模学校“小而优”的期待，按现有的资源配置很难实现，学科能否开设齐全也打上了一个问号。他举例说，按照师生比1比19的配置方式，某学校有分布在3个年级的12个学生，“配一个老师根本就不够”。这将导致小规模学校处于低质低效的运作状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受影响的不光是教学质量，刘善槐担心，如果学校学生数量过少，还将影响学生的社会性发展、心理健康和交往能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农村学校数量的确在持续减少。在提问交流环节，一名记者分享了她在河南某县采访的发现。该县2023年共关停70所乡村学校，根据方案，今年撤并学生数量50人以下的学校，明年将撤并100人以下的学校，后年将撤并200人以下的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在刘善槐看来，单纯以学校的学生数量作为撤并标准，过于单一且并不合理。学校数量减少，对管理者而言更加便利，但增加了学生上学距离，也给家长带来不便，“应该按照自然的人口分布，确定农村学校的分布”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学生减少的情况难以逆转，农村学校办学质量如何提高？刘善槐认为，基于学生数量的公用经费标准不能满足乡村学校的实际需求，应当完善经费结构，保证乡村教育发展的经济基础。同时通过乡村教师定向培养、特岗计划、退休支教等方式，巩固乡村教师多元的补充渠道。在信息时代，信息技术的应用也有助于提高乡村教育水平，应该进一步加强乡村学校硬件设施配置和数字资源建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2012年，针对农村义务教育学校大幅减少，导致部分学生上学路途变远、交通安全隐患增加，学生家庭经济负担加重，并带来农村寄宿制学校不足、一些城镇学校班额过大等问题，国务院办公厅出台了《关于规范农村义务教育学校布局调整的意见》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意见要求坚决制止盲目撤并农村义务教育学校，同时农村义务教育学校布局要保障学生就近上学需要，原则上人口相对集中的村寨要设置村小学或教学点，人口稀少、地处偏远、交通不便的地方应保留或设置教学点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述乡村小规模学校教师培训上，几位来自河南的校长，再次强烈呼吁叫停一刀切的撤点并校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘善槐在基层调研后发现，在实践中是否撤并小规模学校，面临多方冲突，“没有最好的选择”。教育部门工作人员对他反映，原先撤并学校，是出于整合教育资源的考虑。撤并后出现了批评的声音，认为学生的上学距离更远了，家庭的教育成本增加了。但如今保留了很多小规模学校，又有不同意见，认为学生不如在县城学校和乡镇中心校发展得好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘善槐说，面对这种冲突，目前缺少科学化的标准。他建议综合考虑学生的全面发展、教育成本和教育公平性等多种因素，在国家层面出台操作指南，给各地提供参考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广西通报“中学小卖部一年经营权卖224万元”：已中止合同，今后不再对外承包]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256607]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;针对网民关注的贺州第五高级中学发包小卖部经营权有关问题，平桂区联合调查组进行了深入调查，现将有关情况通报如下：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;经调查，贺州第五高级中学小卖部经营权对外发包程序不符合有关规定，双方已终止合同。今后，该校小卖部不再对外承包经营。我们将对有关责任单位及责任人依法依规严肃追责问责。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;感谢广大网民对我们工作的关心、监督和支持！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;贺州市平桂区人民政府办公室&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年9月13日&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刑事二审开庭难有望缓解：“两高两部” 专项促改]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256609]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;刑事案件二审开庭率低的局面有望改变。 2023年9月12日上午，北京尚权律师事务所律师毛立新注意到一则消息：最高法、最高检、公安部、司法部联合印发《关于开展促进提高刑事案件二审开庭率专项工作的通知》，这项工作已于9月1日起开展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照通知要求，要改善刑事案件二审开庭率总体偏低状况，推动建立提高刑事案件二审开庭率常态化机制，并充分发挥庭审在查明事实、认定证据等方面的重要作用。 “两高两部”将开展为期一年的促进提高刑事案件二审开庭率专项工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这对律师是一大利好。”毛立新感慨。 5个月前，他参加了一场关于二审开庭难的研讨会。会上，他表示，除自己在一审阶段就代理的案件外，自己基本不接刑事二审案件，“如果不开庭，律师能发挥的空间很小”。这一说法引起了现场律师们的共鸣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛立新计划，如果二审开庭难能得到缓解，自己也可以开始代理刑事二审案件，“至少工作有了抓手”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/NT944p2PXwAmylBUIwd2Dp1SLgMdA2liQC4Aqe5T.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/NT944p2PXwAmylBUIwd2Dp1SLgMdA2liQC4Aqe5T.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年5月19日，“吴谢宇弑母案”二审开庭，当日有市民从福州市中级人民法院电子公告牌旁经过。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;有地方开庭率已提高75%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刑事二审开庭率低，已成为律师们的普遍感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海交通大学凯原法学院讲席教授孙长永主编的《中国刑事诉讼法制40年》一书中为此提供了数据支撑：2013年，刑事二审开庭率超过40%，2014年至2016年基本保持在30%至40%之间。不过，2017年以来，这个数据已降到20%以下，总体呈逐年下降趋势。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠疫情，也在一定程度上影响了二审开庭率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年6月，河南省高院发布的一则对省政协委员提案的答复中提到，各地法院通常优先保证一审案件和死刑、死缓、抗诉二审案件的开庭需要，挤占了其他二审案件的庭审资源，个别地市的二审开庭率较疫情前下降了近10%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，南方周末记者注意到，2023年以来，上述通知发布前，地方法院已经开始探索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据公开报道，2023年2月14日，河南省高院刑四庭副庭长郝卓就刑事二审开庭情况到平顶山市中院调研；3月8日，郝卓等人又到濮阳市中院进行专项调研。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调研时，郝卓提到，提高二审开庭率这项工作是根据中央、最高人民法院关于刑事诉讼制度改革的要求作出的工作部署，要树立二审“开庭为原则，不开庭为例外”的原则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月25日，河南省许昌市中级法院发布一篇文章，其中提到，许昌中院与许昌检察院联合会签了一份《关于提高刑事二审案件开庭率的意见》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据最高法公布的数据，2023年以来，截至8月31日，河南、陕西、湖南法院刑事案件二审开庭率同比提高超过75%，福建、重庆、黑龙江法院同比提高超过50%，北京、江苏、浙江、甘肃、新疆生产建设兵团法院同比提高超过10%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“改发率”偏低，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;实际效果待观察&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;此次通知指出，要开展调查研究，剖析影响二审开庭率低的各方面原因，采取有效举措，消减影响二审开庭的不利因素，确保二审开庭率稳步提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年8月，金华市中级人民法院在答复一位人大代表建议时坦承，刑事二审开庭率下降的原因在于，近几年被告人案件数量明显增加，押解车辆、押解警力等难以满足开庭所需；检察官无法满足二审刑事开庭所需；员额法官开庭压力较重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天津大学法学院副教授田源在基层、中级及以上法院从事审判工作十余年。他也在调研中发现，面对日渐沉重的办案压力，二审法官容易作出不开庭的选择。开庭审理刑事二审案件应当组成合议庭，而二审法官数量相对有限，为组成合议庭，不得不经常去民庭、商庭或行政庭“搬救兵”，案件庭审及事后合议效果自然会大打折扣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央民族大学法学院院长韩轶此前也曾撰文呼吁刑事二审案件开庭审理。他看到四部门联合发布的通知后，认为其中说法相对原则，具体在实践中如何实施，仍需要出台具体细则。例如，韩轶认为，在法官名额调配上，需要有配套政策跟进。此外，在实践中，“哪些情形二审必须要开庭的、哪些情况可以不开庭，还需要进一步细化，也更利于基层法院执行”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有律师认为，在刑事案件改判发回重审率（简称“改发率”）偏低的情况下，二审开庭的实质效果如何，仍有待观察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按最高法发布数据，2023年上半年，全国法院刑事一审裁判改发率为1.65%，同比下降0.22个百分点。这意味着，在100件刑事案件中，一审后被改判的案件数量平均不足2件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月15日，《半月谈》刊发报道，指出长期以来，各地法院把案件的低改发率作为评价法院、法官审理案件质量的重要指标，促使二审法院慎重改判、严格发回，导致“该改发的不改发”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不提高改发率，二审的监督、把关的价值还是没法实现。”韩轶也认为，此次通知的发布值得点赞，同时，后续实践中也应当注意政策施行是否有效。除改发率偏低问题外，韩轶还提到，也需要注意避免一味注重提高二审开庭率，“这可能会导致二审法院选择开庭审理一些相对简单的案件，而对重大复杂的案件则选择不开庭”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从初代网红到二次出狱：郭美美曾说“不想以这种方式出名”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“慢慢理解世界，慢慢更新自己。”9月12日，沉寂将近三年的郭美美更新了个人社交账号，显示其或再次出狱。同日，郭美美向南都、N视频记者确认此事，并称自己现在一切都还好，想“先休息一段时间”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回归社交平台后，她解散了自己组建的粉丝群，其首次出狱后一手打造的百万粉丝账号如今仅剩6条微博可以查看。在此之前，郭美美最后一次露面停留在2021年8月的一次公开庭审。同年10月，她因销售有毒、有害食品罪获刑，这是她第二次因刑事案件获刑——她曾因犯开设赌场罪被判处有期徒刑五年，并于2019年7月获释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12年前，一次认证信息的修改，令郭美美成为初代网红，一时间名声大噪。当年，郭美美在接受南都记者采访时承认，自己有想红的欲望，但“不想要以这种方式出名”。然而，十多年来，“炫富”“坐牢”“赌博”“卖假药”等字眼，逐步与她的名字纠缠在一起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/116df681e74128d4a9bca29fbe552420.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/116df681e74128d4a9bca29fbe552420.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月12日，郭美美个人社交账号断更近三年后更新。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二次入狱&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月12日，已断更近三年的郭美美个人社交账号，发布了一条新消息——“慢慢理解世界，慢慢更新自己”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社交平台宣布回归后，郭美美的首个举动，便是解散了自己的粉丝群。曾经她在粉丝群中大方分享自己的动态，有粉丝称，“我们在群里面坚守了这些年，出来就解散群”。对此她解释，“有些自己的想法，所以解散了”。郭美美也告诉南都记者，自己现在一切都还好，想“先休息一段时间”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美上一条微博更新停留在2020年12月，而她的最后一次公开露面，则停留在两年前的一次公开庭审。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年8月13日，郭美美等涉嫌生产、销售有毒、有害食品罪一案，在上海铁路运输法院一审开庭。庭审画面显示，被告人郭美美、汪邹雅身穿防护服由法警带入法庭。陈述阶段，郭美美流泪供述，最后手擦眼泪由法警带离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/482c73cce6e1a98a05c40064770e39c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/482c73cce6e1a98a05c40064770e39c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;庭审现场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月18日，上海铁路运输法院对郭美美、汪邹雅销售有毒、有害食品一案依法进行公开宣判，以销售有毒、有害食品罪判处郭美美有期徒刑二年六个月，并处罚金人民币二十万元；判处汪邹雅有期徒刑七个月，并处罚金人民币一万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美此番“二进宫”，最早可追溯至2020年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时郭美美正经营着自己首次出狱后新开的社交账号“郭美May努力努力”，在短短一年多的时间内吸引了超百万粉丝的关注。她通过组建粉丝群、微博引流至微信等方式进行多渠道卖货，“瘦身”是常常出现在她微博的字眼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美的高调举动引发了关注。2020年12月，上海浦东公安分局经侦支队收到一条线索称，有人在网上销售假减肥药。该制售窝点通过在网上发布广告进行宣传，吸引爱美女性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据上海警方通报，2021年3月11日，浦东警方成功侦破一起生产、销售添加违禁成分（西布曲明）减肥类食品案件，抓获生产人员郭某某（女，30岁）等32名犯罪嫌疑人，均已被依法刑拘。南都记者从接近上海警方权威人士处证实，该起通报中涉案30岁的郭某某，正是郭美美。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公诉机关指控，郭美美、汪邹雅分别自2021年1月、2月起，在明知上家赵某（另案处理）处所销售的减肥糖可能非法添加西布曲明的情况下，仍各自以每盒699元等单价对外销售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至案发，郭美美销售减肥糖100余盒，收款人民币7万余元。期间，郭美美还帮助汪邹雅向赵某订货、付款，共同销售减肥糖4盒，收款人民币2796元。案发后，公安机关从查获的涉案减肥糖中检出西布曲明成分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一审开庭当日，一位公诉方相关人士曾向南都记者透露，在开庭前，郭美美已签署认罪认罚具结书。然而开庭时，郭美美对是否“主观明知”所售减肥药含西布曲明成分进行了辩解。“这种行为是否构成&#39;翻供&#39;，是否会作为量刑情节考虑，还需由法官裁定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;首次落网&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;郭美美被浦东警方依法刑拘时，距离她在长沙刑满出狱，仅过去607天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年7月，郭美美等人因涉嫌赌博罪被北京市公安局东城分局依法刑事拘留。经调查，郭美美供认了在世界杯足球赛期间参加赌球以及组织赌博的违法犯罪事实，并供认了长期参与赌博活动、为牟取暴利开设赌局的犯罪事实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期赌博始于2010年，远早于令其名声大噪的“郭美美事件”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方查明，2010年至2014年期间，郭美美先后60余次往返澳门、香港及周边国家进行赌博。2012年底，郭美美在澳门赌场认识了一名外籍职业德州扑克赌徒康某某，二人很快发展为情人关系并在北京同居。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，郭美美由参赌转变为设赌。同年２月，郭美美与康某某策划在北京开设赌场，由其生活助理吕某某出面，在朝阳区北京公馆西塔楼以月租1.9万元的价格租下一套房屋，用于设赌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布置完场地后，郭美美及康某某又购置了赌桌、筹码、POS机，并邀请发牌手。随后，郭美美亲自打电话邀请朋友来赌博。第一次，郭美美邀请了6个人，她从中牟利7万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美对此并不满足，她当时的助理吕某某曾透露，郭美美觉得少，说“还是得女人当家，下次我自己组牌局”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，郭美美每次都是自己聘请专业发牌手，找专人负责赌资结算，并打电话或发微信邀请“朋友”上门赌博，她本人抽取3%至5%的返点作为“水钱”。据北京警方核实，郭美美开设赌局的每场赌资金额都在百万元以上，她个人通过“抽水”非法牟利数十万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年6月，第20届世界杯开幕。7月9日，北京警方打掉一个在世界杯期间组织赌球的犯罪团伙，抓获团伙成员８名。该团伙在境外赌博网站开户，通过电话、微信等形式下注，进行赌球违法犯罪活动。郭美美正是其中的一员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5d97ac8fe5e01fc678810ad328c66a6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5d97ac8fe5e01fc678810ad328c66a6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;庭审现场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年9月10日，郭美美涉嫌开设赌场一案在北京东城法院公开开庭审理。该案刑事判决书显示，被告人郭美美（曾用名郭美玲）因犯开设赌场罪，赌资达二百余万元，被判处有期徒刑五年，并处罚金人民币五万元。其刑期自2014年7月14日起至2019年7月13日止。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;初代网红&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南都记者曾从多处交叉信源核实，郭美美一直在长沙女子监狱服刑，服刑期间未获减刑。服刑1825天后，2019年7月13日，郭美美出狱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，一张郭美美出狱后的近照曝光。照片中郭美美头戴鸭舌帽，妆容淡雅，但身形不复此前纤细，脸部也出现肿胀。她承认，出狱之后，发现和社会脱节了，自己也因为甲亢发胖了二十斤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但郭美美并未因此消沉，作为曾经的“网红”，郭美美熟稔运用网络的能力再次得到体现。出狱后不久，她便积极试水微博、直播、短视频等网络平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她将这归因于自己在狱中五年“被锻炼出的生存本能”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美曾在接受采访时说，自己出狱后两天两夜没合眼，一直在上网接收大量讯息，大概一个月就摸索出了时下最流行的软件是什么，如何使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沉寂仅2个多月，郭美美便开通微博账号“郭美May努力努力”，重回公众视野。2019年9月30日，她发布第一条微博称，“我正在努力蜕变，学更多的知识与才艺，再沉淀沉淀自己吧！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，她还晒出一张坐在车内的自拍照，头发已剪短并染了颜色，妆容精致，照片还加了标签“郭美美复出”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，奢侈品、豪车、星级酒店等彰显财富的“标配”又再次陆续出现在郭美美的微博中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年7月，她发布看车视频，称“打算订一辆敞篷宾利，年轻时就该花钱，钱攒着死了也带不走”；2020年11月，她又发布看房视频，称“来长沙演出不小心买了套新房子，下午看完就交款了”；2021年2月，她在微博晒出一辆粉色的劳斯莱斯，称是“送给自己一份新年礼物”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美曾在接受南都记者专访时表示，自己确实有些爱慕虚荣，喜欢炫耀昂贵的东西。但她坚称，其目标并不是全体老百姓，而是微博中的粉丝，“就像好姐妹一样，我只不过是在分享每天的生活”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年11月，复出仅两个月，她就在微博创建了粉丝群。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年2月，她在微博评论中回复网友称自己在做电商，卖“衣服和面膜”。在经历了直播账号被封、服装店网店运营不善关闭的“创业”坎坷后，郭美美找到了更为有效的“财富密码”，即通过微博引流至微信卖货。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在微博积极“营业”，发布大量自己的照片，并多次现身评论区让网友加她助理的微信，“我日常的穿搭都有卖的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美制造热门话题的能力，从复出伊始发布的第一张自拍照加上“郭美美复出”标签便可见一斑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那张照片下，被点赞最多的评论是“出狱火速整容，厉害”。随后，她也大方承认自己“做了鼻子”，因不满意效果，她又取出假体再调整，并在微博晒出接受“肋骨鼻手术”的经过和整形医院的牌子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，那家整形医院正式成为了她的“合作伙伴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博开通仅一年半的时间，“郭美May努力努力”账号的粉丝数已超百万。除了在简介中挂出自己的微信号，称“演出、瘦身+VX”外，她也多次发微博推介自己的微信号，宣称“想变美，找我”“想赚钱，找我”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2f0fae35a5347bb78c6658640367eafa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2f0fae35a5347bb78c6658640367eafa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郭美美多次在微博推介自己的微信号。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;渴望出名&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;上述微信账号名为“郭美美工作号”，朋友圈含有多条推介医美整形和售卖减肥糖的内容。其与“顾客”的聊天截图声称，吃完一盒“瘦了七八斤”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而上海警方披露的案件细节显示，郭美美所在的制售窝点正是通过在网上发布广告进行宣传，吸引爱美女性。该减肥药中里添加了违禁成分“西布曲明”，虽有减肥的效果，但会对身体会造成伤害。该案涉案金额超5000万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，账号“郭美May努力努力”仅剩6条微博可以查看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12年前，一次认证信息的改动，令微博账号“郭美美Baby”走进公众视野。2011年6月20日，认证信息为“中国红十字会商业总经理”的郭美美在微博上炫耀其奢华生活，自称“住大别墅，开玛莎拉蒂”，引起轩然大波。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国红十字会澄清并无“红十字商会”的机构，更无“郭美美”其人，但质疑仍层出不穷。受此影响，事发一个月后中国各地红十字会收到的慈善捐款锐减、信誉受到质疑，其他官方慈善机构也受到牵连，慈善组织6-8月接收的捐赠数额降幅达到86%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年8月4日，郭美美在电视节目中流泪道歉，称出于虚荣心和攀比心理认证了“中国红十字会商业总经理”，并强调一切与红会无关。但慈善信任风暴已经形成，一轮慈善体制改革的大讨论兴起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同年，郭美美在接受南都记者采访时表示，在事情发生之前，她“对慈善不了解”，只是在三四月份的一次饭局上，听到“干爸”王军提到过“中国红十字会商业总经理”这个名字。4月份的一个下午，郭美美看到关注好友们的微博，认证资料写着总裁、总经理，“但我知道有几个人并不是，其中一个我们班同学，只是拿了十万元去注册一个公司名字，就变成了CEO，我就干脆也改成了&#39;中国红十字会商业总经理&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭美美曾在表演学院进修，她说自己特别喜欢表演，曾对行业抱有梦想。她也向南都记者承认，自己有想出名的欲望。“学表演，学艺术的人，没有一个不想出名吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但“郭美美事件”发生后，她哭称，宁愿时光倒流，希望自己没有改那个认证、不要以这种方式出名，“我不喜欢这样的出名方式”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说，思考后能理解为什么会引起轩然大波，也特别害怕说错话，对红十字会、对老百姓也有歉意。在采访中，郭美美还向南都记者阐述过她对成功的定义：“我的理想是找个自己很爱，他又很爱我的人，踏踏实实做点生意。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，郭美美还大谈自己憧憬中的幸福生活——“开个饭店、首饰店什么的。过着开心幸福的日子就好了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一边，她却步步迈向赌博的深渊，不到三年后便锒铛入狱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被严重低估的流感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;每年一到秋天，随着气温降低，光照减少，人们在享受季节更迭的同时，身体对传染病的抵抗力也随之下降。流感，这一人们熟悉的“老朋友”也将如期而至。大多数人并不认为流感是种严重的疾病，喉咙痛、流鼻涕、肌肉酸痛——这些典型的症状往往与重感冒无异。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在新冠流行以前，流感是世界卫生组织（World Health Organization，WHO）第一个实行全球监测的传染性疾病。据世卫组织统计，季节性流感每年导致29万至65万人死亡。流感的破坏力之所以如此猛烈，部分原因在于这一病毒的变异速度快，过去感染过流感病毒的人们并不能对新病毒产生防御能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我国，流感是被严重低估的传染病，每年感染流感的群体庞大，其带来的健康风险和疾病负担远比想象的厉害。学者对我国不同年份不同城市所开展的流感流行病学调查研究结果的荟萃分析得出，2011-2019年中国每年流感发病人数约为8400万-14400万。 2010-2011至2014-2015流行季，我国平均每年有8.8万例流感相关呼吸系统疾病超额死亡，其中大于60岁的老人流感相关超额死亡数占全人群的80%。儿童发病风险约为成人的1.5-3倍；孕妇在妊娠期间感染流感增加重症和死产风险。一项系统综述分析了我国流感所致经济负担，其中全年龄组门诊病例768-1000元/人次、住院病例平均9832元/人次，5岁及以下儿童和60岁以上老年人住院病例的直接医疗费用远高于其他人群。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和很多新传染病不同，对于流感科学家们已经十分熟悉，世界卫生组织每年都会根据全球监测情况对流感疫苗抗原组分进行更新，并提供用于制备疫苗的候选毒株，供工业界研发最新的流感疫苗。尽管新毒株的变异让流感疫苗的有效性存在波动，但接种疫苗仍是预防流感及并发症最为经济有效的手段，世卫组织建议各国将老人等推荐疫苗接种人群的接种率目标设定为75%。在我国，流感疫苗接种率仅2%-4%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我国流感疫苗接种状况很不理想。”中国疾病预防控制中心传染病管理处副研究员彭质斌曾在2022年全国疫苗与健康大会上披露，2021~2022年流感季，疫苗接种率仅为2.46%，同比下降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为接种率太低，每年企业流感疫苗的报废率更是高达20%-40%。如何提高我国流感疫苗的接种率，保护大众的公共健康一直是长期困扰公共卫生研究者的难题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;三大因素&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;近日，中国医学科学院北京协和医学院群医学及公共卫生学院副院长冯录召教授团队对我国流感疫苗接种的现状及问题进行了归纳总结，并为促进我国流感疫苗接种提出了一系列策略建议，该文章作为昆山杜克大学“疫苗交付研究创新实验室”项目产出成果发表于2023年9月12日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;流感疫苗接种率这么低，究竟受哪些因素影响？冯录召教授的研究指出，三种因素影响了我国的流感接种率：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是对流感病毒和流感疫苗的认知误解带来的疫苗犹豫行为。调查显示，“认为自己身体好，不需要接种流感疫苗”“即使得流感也不会造成严重后果”是导致人们产生流感疫苗犹豫的主要原因；超过40%的公共卫生人员认为流感不会导致严重的疾病，18%的公共卫生人员和45%的医务人员表示自己对解答流感疫苗相关问题缺乏信心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是费用与流感疫苗接种率密切相关。在我国，流感疫苗属于非免疫规划疫苗，需要自费接种。近年来，一些省市将流感疫苗纳入地方免费范畴，大大提高了局部地区的疫苗接种率。中国疾控中心调查显示，免费接种流感疫苗的地区人群接种率可超过50%，享受医保报销政策也可以在一定程度上提高接种率，而自费人群的接种率仅有1.8%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是当前预防接种体系与实际需求不匹配。流行季节前接种流感疫苗是最佳时机，我国每年的接种工作集中在9-12月份。当前流感疫苗预防接种服务主要依托于儿童免疫规划预防接种门诊，多数接种点仅在工作日开设1-2个半天提供流感疫苗接种，这与每年集中释放的接种需求不相适应。从接种服务角度导致供不应求，接种服务预约困难，造成可及性和便利性差。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;他山之石&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1918年流感大流行袭击的强度和速度几乎是不可想象的——感染了地球人口的三分之一（约5亿人）。在这之后，各国都在积极建立防御流感的公共卫生体系，并探索行之有效的推进措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让人们主动接种疫苗，是各国公共健康行动的重中之重。截至2021年，世界卫生组织成员国有65%（128个国家和地区）将老年人、医务人员等高风险人群的流感疫苗接种纳入国家免疫规划或公共卫生项目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冯录召教授曾任WHO免疫专家咨询委员会（SAGE）流感疫苗工作组成员，现担任WHO新型流感疫苗全方位价值评估咨询组专家。他研究了多个国家的流感疫苗接种促进策略，发现许多国家在政策倡导、提升疫苗接种的可及性、激励疫苗接种服务提供方的积极性、监测流感疫苗接种行为与社会驱动因素等方面有丰富的成功经验，其干预措施有效提高了流感疫苗接种率。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究发现，不少国家将流感疫苗纳入国家免疫规划或出台强制接种策略。譬如，美国和加拿大卫生行政部门为减轻医务工作者及患者的感染风险，规定医务工作者和养老院工作人员强制接种流感疫苗。其次，大力提高接种服务点数量和便利性，在北美和欧洲各国，流感疫苗接种点已涵盖药店、超市、私人诊所、医院等多种场所。落实服务提供方的激励政策也是有效手段。美国、英国、澳大利亚等将重点人群的流感疫苗接种率作为医务人员的绩效考核指标。英国则通过向全科医生提供流感相关宣教材料，同时实施绩效激励策略，鼓励医务人员完成既定流感疫苗接种率目标后，给予经济或物质激励，促进医务人员接种和推荐流感疫苗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，一些创新性的激励措施也可提升医务人员的接种意愿，2017年，英国伯明翰儿童医院等机构实施一项接种行动，当一名医务人员完成流感疫苗接种后，医疗机构将通过联合国儿童基金会为发展中国家的儿童或母亲捐赠10支破伤风疫苗，该措施使这些机构的医务人员流感疫苗接种率达到95.7%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于流感疫苗需求的不确定性和毒株的多样性带来的采购挑战，“疫苗交付研究创新实验室”曾总结发达国家经验，发现在采购过程中通过数量承诺等方式将量与价挂钩往往有利于压低价格。例如，英国在招标过程中允许厂商根据不同的采购数量给出不同的报价（往往采购量越大价格越低），从而可以有效地利用规模经济，同时降低厂商风险。加拿大政府会在授予厂商合同之前要求各省或地区对其需求量进行估计，并要求各省或地区至少购买其估计量的75%，从而形成对厂商的数量保障。同时，政府采用长期合同降低厂商的风险，降低了疫苗采购的价格和增加疫苗供给的稳定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对大众而言，广泛的科教宣传也不可或缺。欧洲15个国家流感疫苗接种情况提示，政府部门对流感疫苗接种率的监测、发送免费接种疫苗的短信提醒是促进目标人群接种的重要影响因素。美国则通过媒体宣传，不仅将老年人流感疫苗接种率提高了8%，还将接种时间提前1.8-4.1天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些以国家为主导的措施效果显著，以老年人为例，巴西接种率高达89%；英国65岁以上老年人接种率自2004年以来一直维持在70%以上；美国多年维持在60%以上；加拿大、西班牙、新西兰约为60%-70%，法国、澳大利亚、日本约为50%-60%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;策略建议&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;接种流感疫苗可显著降低罹患流感及并发症的风险，有效减少流感相关疾病的门急诊、住院和死亡人数，成本效益十分明显。 2020年以来，科学家们监测发现，流感与新冠病毒呈交替流行趋势。已有多项研究证实，新冠病毒和流感病毒的合并感染会加重患者住院风险，并使患者的病情复杂化。多年来，科学家们不断强调流感疫苗的重要性，但提高接种率依旧困难。针对我国流感接种率偏低的现状，冯录召教授团队提出了如下策略建议供政策制定者参考：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;疫苗犹豫让不少本该接种流感疫苗的群体处于“裸奔”状态。 “健康教育应针对公众对流感及疫苗的认识误区，找准有效途径，特别是针对老年人、中小学生等免费项目覆盖的人群，研究接种的影响因素和有效干预措施，开展精准的宣传与科普。”在冯录召教授看来，各地应该积极提高公众对流感的认识，增强疫苗信心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于重点人群，研究则建议逐步推行老年人、中小学生、医务人员等流感疫苗免费接种，力争将流感疫苗接种纳入基本医疗保险支付范畴。他们还鼓励各级医疗机构设立成人预防接种门诊，通过继续教育、职业培训等不断强化医务人员的公共卫生和预防职责，探索医务人员开具疫苗的处方权，将预防接种工作纳入医疗机构考评体系，提高医务人员推荐接种流感疫苗的积极性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，针对每年流感疫苗报废率较高的现象，可借鉴国际经验，与企业签订流感疫苗长期（如不低于五年）的合同，带量采购、以量保供，不仅能分担市场风险，还能确保企业产能稳定增长。避免出现年年生产，大量报废的局面出现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们不知道何时会再遇到一场流感大流行，但流感大流行不排除会再发生。正如世卫组织所言：有效的大流行应对措施的核心是一个强大、资源充足的卫生系统。其中包括训练有素的卫生工作者；有效的水、环境卫生和个人卫生体系；优质的快速诊断实验室服务；获得包括疫苗在内的医疗产品；用于跟踪和报告疾病病例的可靠系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，美国免疫实施咨询委员会（ACIP）更新了2023-2024年流感疫苗成分变化和接种建议，提醒公众最好在9月或10月接种疫苗。在国内，目前2023-2024批次的流感疫苗各地已经到货开放预约了。根据中疾控监测数据，7月底开始南方个别省份流感病毒检测阳性率一直略有上升。对于个人而言，面对流感这一季节性流行病，主动防护，积极接种疫苗，让病毒的危害降至最低是可以身体力行的选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>