<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[佳木斯体育馆坍塌背后：建设单位多次中标市政工程，涉事广场系省级重点项目]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260102]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 11:21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/FL9ZJRTyvyLXtiDcUFkgyB4RAlS5XKsule9kZFXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; ​​height=&quot;338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/FL9ZJRTyvyLXtiDcUFkgyB4RAlS5XKsule9kZ FXn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yuecheng Plaza. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Huanan County People&#39;s Government Website/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than four months after the roof collapse of the gymnasium of No. 34 Middle School in Qiqihar, Heilongjiang Province, the tragedy happened again , the roof of Jiamusihua Nanyuecheng Stadium, 600 kilometers away, also collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a notice from the Huanan County Government, around 19:20 on November 6, 2023, a partial collapse occurred in the Yuecheng Gymnasium in Hunan County, Jiamusi City. It was initially confirmed at the scene that three people were trapped in the gymnasium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the time of the Qiqihar incident, there had been heavy rains for several days. In this incident, more than 15 mm of snow fell in Hunan County for 6 consecutive hours, and a red warning for heavy snowfall was issued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice showed that the Yuecheng Gymnasium where the incident occurred was a two-story frame structure with a construction area of ​​about 2,000 square meters. The collapse location was the basketball area on the second floor on the west side, with the collapsed area of ​​about 500 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three venues in this gymnasium. The collapsed basketball hall, a table tennis hall on the first floor, and a children&#39;s physical training hall on the second floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhicheng is the owner of this children&#39;s physical training gym. He told Southern Weekend reporters that it happened to be a rest day for the gym and was used for cleaning and cleaning. There was no one in the gym where he was when the incident occurred. The basketball court and table tennis hall on the first floor should be open for normal business. Under normal circumstances, they will not close until 9 p.m., but &quot;there should be no people on Monday.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Li Zhicheng received the news, he cooperated with the police and obtained the surveillance video of the incident on the entire second floor. At that time, the police also wanted to use his camera to confirm whether anyone was trapped. Surveillance video showed that around 19:20, the entire roof suddenly collapsed. He originally added a plaster wall on the second floor. The entire wall was washed down by the huge air wave, and the camera also fell down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhicheng borrowed 200,000 yuan from a friend to open this venue. &quot;Our family is still a poor household in the county. We originally thought that we could make back our money in the first two years, but we failed in the third and fourth years.&quot; I can make a profit, but now I have nothing. Fortunately among misfortunes, my store happened to be doing a general cleaning today. If there were casualties in my store, I would never be able to live with it for the rest of my life. My parents are quite heartwarming anyway, and they are all asking me if I have any problems. It’s okay”. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The incident had just been inspected two months ago&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Information Office of Huanan County Government of Heilongjiang Province issued a notice in the early morning: At 0:35 on November 7, Yuecheng, Huanan County Rescue completed at the scene of a partial collapse of a fitness gym. When the accident occurred, there were seven people at the scene, three of whom escaped on their own, one was slightly injured, and three were killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The venue where the accident occurred belongs to the New Sunshine Fitness Club in Huanan County, and the person in charge of the club has been controlled by the police. The cause of the accident is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found out that the legal representative of New Sunshine Fitness Club is Men Yanan. Around 22:52 on November 6, Southern Weekend reporters called Men Yanan several times, but the call was always busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Men Yanan opened the Yuecheng Sports and Fitness Club on April 8, 2021, but canceled it, and then re-registered the New Sunshine Construction Club at the original address on July 20, 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reports from the official Huanan County media &quot;Damei Huanan&quot; showed that two months before the incident, on the afternoon of September 5, 2023, Dong Lijuan, member of the Standing Committee of the Huanan County Party Committee, led a team to inspect the safety of the cultural and entertainment market. Production work, Yuecheng Sunshine Fitness and Yuecheng Good Voice KTV are among the inspection sites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/UfZ57TmF0Kxawz0rsT2wZfOXEqattzYkkFOiBRrB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;535&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/UfZ57TmF0Kxawz0rsT2wZfOXEqattzYkkFOiBRrB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 5, venues including Yuecheng Sunshine Fitness conducted safety production inspections. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Damei Huanan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local media reported that &quot;Dong Lijuan carefully checked the safety risks of each place wherever she went. Whether fire-fighting facilities and equipment comply with regulations, whether fire-fighting equipment is within the validity period, whether fire-fighting passages are clear, whether emergency lights can operate normally, and whether certificates and licenses are complete. For discovered safety hazards, rectification measures and time limits are clarified on the spot. If rectification measures cannot be clarified on-site, , make a list of problems, and instruct relevant departments and responsible persons to put forward rectification opinions and plans, and make rectifications in place within a deadline.&quot; Dong Lijuan said that we must pay close attention to the awareness of safety production risk prevention and control, &quot;keep an eye on outstanding problems and major hidden dangers, Grasping it to the end. Continue to build a strong awareness of safety red lines and the rule of law, promote the implementation of safety production responsibilities, ensure that the safety production situation continues to be stable, and the mass cultural undertakings advance steadily and orderly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local media reported that on July 24, Cheng Xianfeng, deputy secretary of the Huanan County Party Committee and county magistrate, also visited the Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym to inspect the implementation of safety work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Both construction units are major bidders&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found out that the stadium is part of the Yuecheng Plaza complex, and the developer of the project is Heilongjiang Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. Company (hereinafter referred to as Yuecheng Real Estate). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public bidding information shows that the project has two phases. The construction unit that won the bid for the first phase is Heilongjiang Haifeng Weiye Construction and Installation Engineering Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Haifeng Weiye). The construction start date is June 30, 2018, and the completion date is October 1, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The winning construction unit for the second phase is Heilongjiang Huayou Construction Engineering Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Huayou Construction). The construction start date is June 10, 2018, and the completion date is October 1, 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted Yue Chengqi, the legal representative of Haifeng Weiye. The other party said that he was aware of the stadium collapse incident, but was not sure whether it was a project built by him and &quot;needs to go back and check the information.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tendering information shows that Haifeng Weiye is a major tenderer of the Huanan County Government and participates in a wide variety of projects. In terms of municipal projects, we have undertaken the construction of public parking lots, roads, high-speed rail parking lots, etc., and medical projects include the county CDC, the infectious disease area of ​​the county hospital, and the 120 emergency center, as well as the construction of beautiful rural infrastructure in Huanan County and the county power supply bureau. The material reserve warehouse and the black soil transfer earthwork in the pig slaughtering plant area of ​​Huanan Economic Development Zone. In addition, we also won the bid for the county&#39;s affordable housing project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mou Yandong, the shareholder of Huayou Construction, the winning bidder for the second phase of Yuecheng Phase II, is the second shareholder of Yuecheng Real Estate. Similar to Haifeng Weiye, Huayou Construction is also a major tenderer for government projects. In addition to Yuecheng Plaza, it has received at least three government projects, namely the Jiamusi Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital’s medical housing renovation project, the Huachuan County Culture, Radio, Television, Press and Publication Bureau’s cultural facilities construction project, and the Huannan County village and town construction project. Management center’s dilapidated house renovation project in Hunan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A company was also registered at the address of the collapsed stadium, called Heilongjiang Yuecheng Sports Culture Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Yuecheng Sports). The legal representative of this company, Sun Yongjun, is Yue. Supervisor of City Real Estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is quite strange is that Yuecheng Real Estate and Yuecheng Sports have been canceled in 2021 and 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuecheng Real Estate was once a local star company. According to local media reports in Huanan, “After vigorous investment promotion by the county housing and construction department, Beijing Deyi Yintong Technology Co., Ltd. invested 380 million yuan in the former Olin in the county. Xincun Phase III shanty town construction urban complex project, and invested and registered Heilongjiang Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. The project started construction in May 2016 and was completed in October 2019.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report stated, “The Yuecheng Plaza project manager said that with the strong support of the Huanan County Party Committee, the county government and relevant departments, our project has now completed two relocation buildings with an area of 34,000 square meters, the commercial area of ​​the urban complex is 28,000 square meters, and the area of ​​the high-end residential area is 16,000 square meters. In 2017, our company plans to invest 170 million yuan, and all is now in place. All preparatory work for the construction is Arrangements are in place, and the commercial and residential area is now in the interior and exterior decoration stage, and is expected to be completed and put into use in August.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the Yuecheng Plaza complex project ranks as a provincial key project in Heilongjiang and appeared in the Huanan County Government Work Report in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, the official website of Huanan County Government still retains reports of the grand event that year. On January 22, 2018, Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza opened. The deputy magistrate of the county government delivered an opening speech and announced the opening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuecheng Plaza is introduced as “an urban comprehensive commercial complex integrating leisure, entertainment, shopping, experience and other functions. The project itself has business format advantages, functional advantages, taste advantages, characteristic advantages, The scale advantages, service advantages, brand advantages, etc. put the project in a very competitive leading position. It will surely become a well-known urban complex project in the county, improve the taste of the city, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of vitality, civilization, ecology, integrity, wisdom, The harmonious and happy beautiful Huanan adds luster.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many surrounding neighbors confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that the Yuecheng Stadium where the incident occurred has been sealed off, but the KTV located in the Yuecheng Plaza shopping mall was still open for business that night. On Dianping, a netizen commented that Yuecheng Plaza is the best place to have fun in this county. “I’ve been to this small county a few times, but I can’t remember other places. This mall is really good, and the gym uses all the equipment of big international brands.” , the same as the gym in Harbin with more than 10,000 yuan a year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (At the request of the interviewee, Li Zhi became a pseudonym in the article.) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江又有体育馆坍塌，天灾还是人祸？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260100]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 11:39:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of November 6, a gymnasium in Huanan County, Heilongjiang collapsed. In the early morning of the 7th, rescue was completed at the accident site. Three people escaped on their own, one was slightly injured, and three were killed. More than three months ago, the roof of the gymnasium of No. 34 Middle School in Qiqihar City, Heilongjiang Province collapsed, killing 11 teachers and students. The cause of the accident was illegal stacking of perlite on the roof, which caused increased water infiltration and increased roof load. This time the Huanan County Gymnasium collapsed, and there were also voices pointing to the heavy snow weather as the cause.</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原佳木斯一体育馆坍塌瞬间，3人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260097]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 10:51:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江又有体育馆坍塌：形式主义安全检查难辞其咎丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260093]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 10:07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At close to 11 o&#39;clock on the evening of November 6, 2023, the Huanan County Government Information Office announced through the official social media account , at 19:20 that day, the Huanan County Yuecheng Fitness Gym (full name Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym) partially collapsed. Currently, three people are trapped. The local government and fire department are doing their best to rescue them in the snow. Prior to this, this news had quickly become a hot topic across the Internet and attracted great public attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people were in the library at that time, how many students were among them, and what the casualties were are what the public is eager to know. According to the latest disclosure from the local government information office: at 0:35 on the 7th, the rescue at the accident site has been completed; when the accident occurred, there were 7 people on site, 3 of whom escaped on their own, 1 was slightly injured, and 3 were killed; the venue where the accident occurred It belongs to the New Sunshine Fitness Club in Huanan County, and the club leader has been controlled by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what caused the stadium to collapse? According to CCTV reports, the gymnasium is a two-story frame structure with a construction area of ​​about 2,000 square meters. The collapsed location was the basketball area on the second floor on the west side, with the collapsed area of ​​about 500 square meters. Video posted online showed that the roof of a building collapsed. The four walls were intact. The building was about two stories high. The scene was covered with snow and wall fragments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the gymnasium roof reminds people of the roof collapse of the No. 34 Middle School gymnasium in Qiqihar City in July this year. The accident killed 11 teachers and students of the school&#39;s women&#39;s volleyball team who were training in the gym. The cause of the collapse was that the construction unit illegally stacked perlite on the roof of the gymnasium. The perlite absorbed rainwater and gained weight, causing the roof load to increase and cause the collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the Huanan County Gymnasium this time was also a roof collapse, which is similar to the collapse of the Qiqihar Gymnasium. Therefore, there are also voices pointing to the heavy snow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the blizzard red warning signal issued by the Jiamusi Meteorological Observatory at 17:30 on November 6, the cumulative snowfall in the city in 6 hours has reached 15 mm. The snowfall is expected to continue until the morning of the 7th, with accumulated snowfall in the process. The amount can reach 25-35 mm. The Huanan County Meteorological Observatory issued a red snow warning signal at 16:47 earlier: The snowfall in our county has reached more than 15 mm within 6 hours and the snowfall is still continuing. Please pay attention to precautions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City was related to rainfall. It rained frequently in the area for a period of time before the incident. Perlite can gain three times its weight after absorbing water, and the water is not easy to dissipate. After repeated rains, the weight of perlite will increase a lot. Moreover, these perlite building materials are not laid flat on the roof, but gathered in one place, which increases the pressure on part of the roof structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The roof of the collapsed gymnasium in Huanan County was covered with snow. Judging from the video posted online, the snow on the ground is not too deep. Winter has just begun in the Northeast at this time, and there should be no snow before. The snow on the roof is mainly caused by this snowfall. Unlike rain, snow does not accumulate in one place, and the pressure is basically evenly distributed to the entire roof. Is 15 millimeters of snow enough to collapse the roof of a stadium? Converted into pressure, it is only 15 kilograms per square meter, or 147N/square meters. The standard live load value for roofs that are not accessible to people is 0.5kN/square meter (50 kilograms of force per square meter). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City, which is an old building with a history of more than 30 years, according to media reports citing eyewitness reports, the collapsed gymnasium in Huanan County was a newly built urban complex in recent years. If the entire roof cannot withstand a pressure of 15 kgf/m², does its construction quality pass the standard? How did it pass the inspection in the first place? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after the collapse of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City, Heilongjiang Province held an emergency video conference on production safety throughout the province that night and requested that the buildings of various schools and public welfare sports venues be quickly organized and inspected. Safety. According to the Hunan County Government website, on the afternoon of July 24, 2023, the day after the roof of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City collapsed, the Magistrate of Hunan County went to the Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym to inspect the implementation of safety work. . Just over three months later, a very similar roof collapse accident occurred in this gymnasium, indicating that Huanan County was probably just a formality at that time and did not conduct serious safety inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four months before the collapse of the No. 34 Middle School gymnasium in Qiqihar City, the Qiqihar City Education Bureau also conducted a school building safety inspection. This safety inspection also failed to discover the serious safety hazard of a large amount of perlite piled on the roof of the stadium, which ultimately led to the tragedy. Although the cause of the accident was rainfall, it was also a man-made disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real cause of the roof collapse of the Huanan County Gymnasium has yet to be identified. But in any case, the roof collapse shows that the building safety inspection 3 months ago was definitely not in place. How many more of these superficial inspections, official business matters, and formalistic inspections are there? How many more lives must be paid in exchange for a true emphasis on safety? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This stadium easily passed the safety inspection 3 months ago. How to explain it? More importantly, this stadium is part of the Yuecheng Plaza urban comprehensive commercial complex built in 2018 as a local investment attraction project. The total construction area of ​​this complex is more than 110,000 square meters, including commercial, residential and supporting public buildings. If the construction quality of the stadium is so poor, are there any quality problems or safety hazards in other parts of the entire complex? This is a much bigger issue than the quality and safety of gymnasiums. It should be clarified what responsibilities the construction unit, supervision unit, developer and local regulatory authorities should bear respectively; it should also be clarified whether the person in charge of the club has any responsibility in this construction process, and the operator should not be allowed to take the blame for the entire incident. Xia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public expects answers to these questions as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[史国威：打破摄影与绘画的边界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/xg0hnrzo0ZCiBuLzrU0BwZisyNWVwdgt8GSxiT6p.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xg0hnrzo0ZCiBuLzrU0BwZisyNWVwd gt8GSxiT6p. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256520&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several cats are patrolling on the two-meter-long glass table. One is black, one is white, one is completely brown from behind, and one is hiding. I don&#39;t want to see anyone on the second floor, it&#39;s gray. They have accompanied the artist and traveled around with respect as guests for more than ten years. The studio has been demolished again and again, and now it has retreated to the edge of the city and rents a flight attendant dormitory near the Capital Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The indoor space is getting smaller and smaller. When Shi Guowei is painting on the first floor, his cats stay on the second floor of the loft; sometimes even if he goes downstairs and jumps on the workbench, he still knows that he is always and at the same time. Keep a distance of one meter from the painting area. Looking at these aging pets is like witnessing an overly clear ending. After giving away several cats one after another, he no longer dared to raise new cats. Thinking of the scene of standing in front of the crematorium furnace again and again, he couldn&#39;t help showing a look of pain, &quot;My heart really couldn&#39;t bear it.&quot; He can only take things as they come. &quot;I don&#39;t dare to take them for a physical examination. They are all so old. If the problems are found, they must be treated. The energy, time, and expense are all beyond my reach.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Had he known that he would have to face this kind of torture again and again, he might have chosen to bypass it in the beginning. It was 2006, and he had just returned from studying photography at the Dortmund University of Technology in Germany. Like many young people who were excited and trying to become artists at that time, he built a large studio in Heiqiao and posed for photos in the studio. After completion, photos of people, real outdoor scenes and objects with Chinese elements were collaged and combined following famous Western paintings, washed into a huge black and white photo nearly two meters wide, and finally hand-colored into a colorful painting. His father, who was in the bonsai business, sometimes came to see Shi Guowei and brought a litter of newborn stray cats from Laitai Flower Market, which was once the largest in Beijing. He couldn&#39;t bear to banish them, so he had to accept these brothers and sisters with different colors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A soft-hearted bachelor with nearly ten kittens (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;after giving birth to two litters, the female cat disappeared. was able to give up&lt;/span>;) and began his fashionable and ambiguous artistic career. He hired an intermediary to search for Russian models for him. They should not be curvy or beautiful, but should focus on ugliness and conflict. Venus is no longer a symbol of peace and tenderness. The fat naked girl has her eyes closed and is sleeping soundly. There are many weird plastic dolls beside her, and the Old Summer Palace is on fire in the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/f9uPJOCXa1XpSg5L8Ld0W0Sh05Qv0tIp47Rq4sKA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/f9uPJOCXa1XpSg5L8Ld0W0Sh05Qv0tIp47Rq4sKA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256521&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Flowing Sunset&quot; 2023, laser silver salt on paper, liquid paint, 130cm×177cm, photo/courtesy of the artist and Magician Space&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hans· Holbein&#39;s &quot;Ambassadors&quot; has been transformed by Shi Guowei. The characters have changed from wool-clad nobles to blood-covered butchers. The astronomical observation equipment in the original work has been replaced with those from the 1960s and 1970s. Objects are thrown on a blood-red blanket, and a photographed Buddha head represents the skull at the bottom of the oil painting - neat irony and confrontation are ready to emerge in these works that combine photography and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By around 2010, this experienced boilermaker (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; had weak heating in his studio. In order to survive the long winter, The artists in Heiqiao wore black coats and shoveled coal constantly to prevent it from burning out. Their faces and hands were black every day. When the coal was weighed in their hands, they knew how much it cost per ton&lt;/span>;) They created nearly twenty visuals Powerful nude work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes a lot of time to color photos by hand. This method was first used in his master&#39;s degree graduation work. In order to graduate successfully in Germany, Shi Guowei thought for a long time and thought that he should make up for his lack of shooting hardware, The shortcomings in technology are highlighted while the strengths in art are highlighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in college, he studied photography in the Graphic Visual Arts Communication Department of Tsinghua Academy of Fine Arts, but the courses for the first three years had no direct connection with photography. He trained in sketching, color, sculpture and other skills every day. I took basic sketching courses for two years and developed the same painting skills as an art student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creative method of photography and painting was determined. In terms of content conception, he still focused on the comparison between Eastern and Western cultures that he was busy with in the following years. He invited foreign models to wear Mulan costumes, and then asked Chinese models to wear Robin Hood costumes. He may be dressed like a pope, but his face is painted with Peking Opera facial makeup. &quot;This one is easier to operate, and you can use a large landline phone. At least the materials are better than others. After the black and white photo is developed, I will use hand coloring to paint it into color. In this way, it will stand out immediately. You and I All students are different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ie6zEu59X0Q9LUBcLXmXPMFJFaUZngiHbtNqhDUy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;873&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ie6zEu59X0Q9LUBcLXmXPMFJFaUZngiHbtNqhDUy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256522&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Wool&quot; 2021, laser silver salt paper base, liquid paint, 180cm×198cm Image/Courtesy of the artist and Magician Space&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&quot;Why is there always meat in my paintings? Is there blood?&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he completed his graduation project, the one-meter-wide photo paper table could not fit on it, so he had to lie on the floor of the rental house and sketch with his hands. Holding two brushes, I used the fine brushwork and heavy color blending method I learned in technical secondary school, dipped a dab of dog tag paint sent from China, and immediately changed it to water to dye it evenly. I relied on these eight single photos to &quot;get ready for graduation.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Curator and critic Karen Smith once summed it up, &quot;He observed and recorded scenes, creating black-and-white photographs in the traditional photographic style, which he then painted by hand over a long period of time. This The process not only requires eye-hand coordination behind the camera lens, but also requires precise control of the way the brush is applied. After returning to China after studying at the Higher School of Photography in Dortmund, Germany, Shi Guowei gradually formed his own unchanging and compelling vision. The way of expression is a delicate and exquisite fusion between photography and painting. The combination of many materials and techniques also makes the work carry more connotations than the literal meaning of the label &#39;hand-colored photos&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the early days of his return to China, he recalled that the large amount of bloody violence and pornography in his works came from &quot;many years of repression in society. When he was studying in Germany, he spent most of his time working to make a living, and had no choice but to wash dishes in restaurants and go to restaurants. I worked the night shift in the factory carrying bags, doing the lowest level of work. Art and other things didn&#39;t matter to me. The first goal at that time was to have enough food to survive, and the second goal was to graduate as soon as possible so that I could have an explanation for my family. Yes. Only with this diploma can I make a living and do what I want to do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The works from those years appeared in a number of exhibitions, large and small, but received little recognition. &quot;At that time, I wanted to do something related to the West, thinking that everyone could understand it, but in fact, through several exhibitions, I found that people didn&#39;t know what I was going to do, and they didn&#39;t know the source. Now it looks like I was there at that time I shouted as loud as I could and yelled very strongly, but it had no effect, so I might as well be quieter. If the treatment was superficial in the past, now it is internal injuries. Even if the treatment is calm, the Qigong has actually penetrated the body. It&#39;s through your body.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Hxm6eYLC2cSPba4i9gtCjIUwz3t9kP9wVFjNhQ6A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;795&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Hxm6eYLC2cSPba4i9gtCjIUwz3t9kP9wVFjNhQ6A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256524&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Roshan&quot; 2021, laser silver salt paper base, liquid pigment, 184cm×154cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（ (Photo courtesy of the artist and Magician Space)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since about 10 years ago, the content of his creations has undergone tremendous changes. &quot;I slowly changed because I started walking in the mountains and taking some photos related to nature. I felt more and wanted to return to myself. The previous works were all about society and other people, and exported some of my understanding of the outside world. I know, it has nothing to do with myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Shi Guowei first turned to nature, what he pursued was still the similarity of shapes. He painted very finely and obscurely meticulously. The grass itself is green. The painting is still green, but the degree of greenness may be slightly different compared to the color photo. What he hoped to hear at that time was the audience&#39;s perception when they took a quick look and said, &quot;Hey, isn&#39;t this a color photo?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, he has turned more and more inward. When he goes to Lingshan Mountain, he may only take one or two touching photos. In the solo exhibition at Magician Gallery in September 2023, some of the paintings are from his travels in Xinjiang, the Daxinganling and other places. He became more and more strict when selecting, &quot;You will wonder whether this scene is related to me, and whether it is worth it.&quot; .&quot; The traces of coverage are getting heavier and heavier, making it almost difficult to see the original appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rocks are painted with the texture of raw meat in his paintings. No matter how magnificent the scenery is, through his eyes, it is often transformed into a cruel product. The deaths of pets and relatives lingered in his mind. When he saw the wool piled up like a huge yurt, waiting for wool traders to come and buy it, dark brown, light brown and yellow were intertwined in the wind. The herdsmen were used to it, and he only felt cruel. ; Seeing an Ewenki hunter kill a deer in 20 minutes, he recalled how he handled hares alone after hunting with his father when he was a teenager (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hook The scene of putting on the doorframe, lifting the knife, and peeling the skin&lt;/span>;), &quot;It was familiar and uncomfortable at the time, so why is there always meat in my paintings? Is there blood? This kind of atmosphere is throughout, but now it is used It is more stable and not as bloody as the large area more than ten years ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of my wife, who is also doing art work, this dyed image is not a restoration, but more subjective than reality. , is doubt and dissatisfaction with the realistic picture. Coloring the fictitious landscape in reality means putting aside the training of restoring color cards and extreme precision in past photography classes, and completing denial and rebellion in &quot;turning a blind eye&quot;. He once said, &quot;Over the years, I have been trying relentlessly to break the boundaries between photography and painting, just like breaking a decaying wall. To be more precise, I am trying to keep myself free from the edge, like an acrobat walking on a tightrope. Maintain balance and never fall to any side, no matter photography or painting. Only in this way can I face the things around me more clearly and calmly, so that I don&#39;t get lost. Just like the edge of the river, there are always weeds that are fatter than elsewhere. , where the nutrients are the most abundant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[平均降价58%，​第九批国家药品集采41种药品采购成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260089]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 6, the ninth batch of state-organized centralized bulk procurement of drugs produced results in Shanghai. 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase. The average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%, and it is expected to save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year. Pharmaceutical companies actively participated in this centralized procurement, with 382 products from 262 companies participating in the bidding. 266 products from 205 companies are eligible to be selected, including 260 products from 200 domestic pharmaceutical companies and 6 products from 5 international pharmaceutical companies (including 1 original research drug and 5 imported generic drugs). The winning rate is about 78%, with an average of 6.5 companies for each category planning to be selected. This centralized procurement has a high selection rate for enterprises, and has a good effect on reducing the burden on the masses, achieving a balance between the multiple goals of &quot;reducing burdens, promoting development, and ensuring supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This centralized purchase covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. Lenalidomide capsules for the treatment of multiple myeloma will be included in the centralized procurement in time after the patent expires in May 2023. The average price of each capsule (25 mg) has been reduced from about 200 yuan to 15 yuan, which can save about 3,880 yuan in monthly drug costs. Patients The burden is significantly reduced. The prices of three nationally focused drugs monitored for rational use, including rabeprazole oral sustained-release dosage form and esomeprazole magnesium enteric-coated dry suspension for the treatment of gastrointestinal diseases, have been significantly reduced. Five kinds of shortage drugs and emergency drugs, including amiodarone injection to treat arrhythmia, dopamine injection to rescue shock, and oxytocin injection to induce labor, have been used to stabilize corporate expectations through the &quot;volume-based&quot; procurement method to ensure supply and Balance of multiple objectives for reasonable price reduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, the National Medical Insurance Administration has organized and carried out nine batches of nationally organized drug procurement, including a total of 374 kinds of drugs, with an average reduction of more than 50%. In the next step, the National Medical Insurance Administration will work with relevant departments to guide various localities and selected companies to implement the winning results to ensure that patients across the country can use the selected products after the price reduction of this centralized purchase in March 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃不完剩下点很正常”？节约习惯还得从小塑成丨养儿育女]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260019]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As a working mother, I always believe that it is important to prepare a hearty, delicious and nutritious meal for my second-grade son every day. The rich and satisfying breakfast was indeed a &quot;big job&quot;. Recently, in the morning, I followed my child&#39;s request and packed breakfast for him at the bakery or community cafeteria downstairs. When I came home in the evening, I found that he always had more than half of a hamburger or rice ball left. I curiously asked him why he wasted some food every day, and he answered me nonchalantly: &quot;It&#39;s normal not to be able to finish the rest!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After listening to the child&#39;s words, I gave him a detailed calculation. An economic account: If he wastes 9 yuan a day, 63 yuan a week, and 252 yuan a month, he wastes more than 3,000 yuan a year. This money can buy a good mobile phone, a A branded washing machine can also cover the living expenses of a poor rural person for a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The child was extremely shocked by what he said. He sighed repeatedly, &quot;Mom, before you calculated this account for me, I never thought that if you waste a little bit every day, you would lose so much. I will ask you to buy less in the future, please remember it!&quot; Seeing the sincerity on his face, I couldn&#39;t help but sigh, modern children&#39;s awareness of thrift really needs to be cultivated from an early age! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that today’s favorable material living conditions can easily cause children to lack the concept of money. From childhood, when you open your mouth to eat or stretch out your hands when wearing clothes, if you open your mouth to ask for anything, parents will satisfy you without reservation. Some parents even feel that they suffered too much in childhood and have not experienced many fun in childhood, so they feel that they cannot be owed anything. child. Over time, mentally retarded children will no longer know where money comes from, let alone how difficult it is to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, wrong guidance from parents is also the main reason why children have no concept of money. With the development of modern technology, people tend to use mobile payment instead of cash payment. During e-commerce festivals such as &quot;6·18&quot; and &quot;Double 11&quot;, many parents &quot;buy, buy, buy&quot; regardless of whether it is useful or not. Behind the convenient and fast payment, children cannot feel what money is, and they will not ask &quot;how much money does my family have&quot; or &quot;how much money can my parents earn in a day&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the limitations of school education methods are also an important reason for children&#39;s lack of money concepts and awareness of saving. I believe that all schools will warn children to develop the habit of thrifting from an early age, but it is obviously difficult to exert their due effect by admonishing and urging children. Of course, it is also difficult to arouse children&#39;s empathy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all know that children are in a critical period of forming their outlook on life. Proper guidance from parents and schools is particularly important for them to develop correct values. Because of this, as parents, we must first guide our children to establish a correct concept of money. Use plain and easy language to calculate accounts for children, so that they can concretely understand the concept of money and truly feel that money is hard-won. You might as well prepare a piggy bank for your children, let them save money and use it by themselves, and warn them not to buy and spend randomly. Take your children to participate in some social labor, let them experience the hardship and fun of making money, and let them realize that making money is not easy during labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teaching by words and deeds is worse than words and deeds. Parents are role models for children to follow. Good examples inspire people to make progress, but bad examples can cause endless harm. As parents, we ourselves must develop a good habit of saving, teach our children why we need to save and how to develop a good habit of saving in every aspect of our lives, tell them that money should be spent wisely, and then create a culture of spending money when it is appropriate and being thrifty and thrifty. family atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that school education and social guidance are also extremely important for children to develop thrifty habits. In school education, we carry out themed study activities such as &quot;Spend January with 100 Yuan&quot;, organize children to go to rural poverty-stricken areas to experience life and feel poverty, so that they can truly understand that making money is not easy and life is difficult, and encourage them to develop thrift. virtue. At the same time, mass media such as radio and television should also promote the &quot;new trend of frugality on the dining table&quot; and encourage everyone to promote traditional virtues. We can also encourage children from developed areas in the east to pair up and help each other with children from poor areas in the central and western regions, so that the &quot;little princesses&quot; and &quot;little princes&quot; living in honey pots can use their own actions to help children in poor areas realize their &quot;dream of going to school&quot; and &quot;seeking knowledge&quot; &quot;Dream&quot; to promote common growth and let the &quot;little princesses&quot; and &quot;little princes&quot; truly realize the great role of saving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a civil servant in Quzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; As a parent and teacher, share the scenery you have experienced and the principles you have learned on the way your children grow up. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[​黑龙江佳木斯一体育馆发生坍塌，初步确认3人被困丨滚动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260091]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 22:02:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Beijing time November 6, 21 Hours 58 minutes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the relevant departments of Jiamusi City, Heilongjiang Province that at around 19:40 on November 6, 2023, the Yuecheng Gymnasium in Hunan County, Jiamusi City partially collapsed. The building was a two-story frame. The structure, with a construction area of ​​about 2,000 square meters, collapsed in the basketball area on the second floor on the west side. The collapsed area was about 500 square meters. It was initially confirmed on site that three people were trapped in the gymnasium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, fire protection, public security and other departments are working hard to rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(CCTV News)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;21:00, November 6, Beijing time&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;​A gymnasium collapsed in Jiamusi, Heilongjiang, and rescue operations are underway&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6 On the evening of the same day, a gymnasium collapsed in Huannan County, Jiamusi, Heilongjiang. Relevant departments have arrived at the scene for rescue. Videos taken by netizens showed thick white snow on the collapsed building. It is reported that the scene has been sealed off and local rescue has been launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Surrounding merchants told reporters that a gymnasium did collapse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/c7865ffe43bc9b27db8a41302fde4a36.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;595&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/c7865ffe43bc9b27db8a41302fde4a36.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257222 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/a1bd13d49c78172c78bcec02522df3c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/a1bd13d49c78172c78bcec02522df3c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257221&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Huanan County Meteorological Observatory upgraded and issued a blizzard red warning signal at 16:47 on November 6, 2023: The amount of snowfall in our county has reached more than 15 mm within 6 hours and the snowfall is still continuing, which is harmful to traffic. Or agriculture and animal husbandry may have a greater impact, please take precautions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（Southern+）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年轻人“断亲”怎么看？“陌生人社会”不是要消灭“熟人社会”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260048]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The topic of divorce for those born in the 90s and 2000s has been very popular in recent years. Recently, some media published a report describing a female monster born in 1991. One day in July 2022, she severed ties with her relatives by deleting WeChat and blocking her phone number: List Including 3 cousins, 1 cousin, aunt, and parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The article stated that in 2022, she was fired from an Internet company in Suzhou. She suffered a cerebral infarction and a stroke the next day after drinking the break-up drink. She will need to take care of herself for at least a year. In addition to not drinking alcohol or eating high-fat foods, In addition to salty food, you also need to go to the hospital regularly to prescribe medicine, which requires a medical fee. Her parents divorced when she was 8 years old and each formed a new family. She grew up under the care of her grandmother and aunt, so she asked her closest aunt, but her aunt said it was &quot;inconvenient to bear&quot;; she also asked her father for help, hoping that every month Borrowing two to three thousand yuan from himself, her father said that he could only pay for her hospitalization expenses; she asked her mother for help, but her mother had no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many such reports in the media. For example, there is a report about the separation of relatives, which describes the 37-year-old Ye Wen. When he was a child, he was a left-behind child. His parents were working in Dongguan. He did not go to college. , works as a photography apprentice, opens a photography studio, likes literature, and writes worker poetry, but &quot;is not understood by his family or even his parents.&quot; He believes that his relationship with his father is broken by the word money. In 2019, he wanted to open a photography studio and borrowed 10,000 yuan from his father. His father did not speak. In his words, he was &quot;playing dead.&quot; He continued to ask: &quot;Do you want to borrow it or not? Let&#39;s talk.&quot; The father replied: &quot;I can&#39;t take care of your business.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two cases of divorce are quite extreme. . There are two definitions or types of renunciation: one is (actively) severing contact with parents, family members and relatives, which is very clear; the other is the so-called &quot;lazy or negligent communication with relatives&quot;, which is also very clear. Vague, will be discussed further later. A common misunderstanding is to use extreme cases of the former to cover the latter, in order to exaggerate the breadth and severity of disconnection among young people. In fact, there are differences between the two situations and should be discussed separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First discuss the above two cases and the first type of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 32-year-old female Xiaoguai and the 37-year-old Ye Wen both had shortcomings in childhood: one was that her parents divorced and formed new families, and they did not raise her by their side; the other was a left-behind child when she was a child, and her parents It&#39;s pitiful that I can&#39;t be with you when I&#39;m busy working to make money. However, these two people have already grown up. As adults, how to view and deal with the relationship with their parents, family members and relatives should also be done in an adult way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no more than two ways for adults: one is the modern way, where one is independent, has personal rights and dignity, and can take responsibility for oneself vs. other individuals who are equally independent and have boundaries; In the traditional way, everyone belongs to a big family or family, and blood is thicker than water, and family ties are important. Big families or families are natural blood communities, and have mutual financial and insurance functions. You can only choose one. Each method is equal. You will get what you pay for. No one can take anything and ask for it blindly. It cannot be said that I want all the advantages and disadvantages of both methods. That is extremely refined egoism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Xiaoguai is 31 years old. Grandma and her aunt took care of and raised her after her parents divorced. This is not the aunt&#39;s duty, but a matter of affection. This is tradition and help from the extended family. After she became an adult, her aunt also had her own small family, and it was not unreasonable to &quot;not be able to bear&quot; her maintenance and medical expenses. Why did she have such high psychological expectations for her aunt? To have so much resentment and sever ties with my aunt after not meeting expectations? She must have been working for some years. Has she ever repaid her aunt for her kindness in raising her in the early years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An adult who follows modern ways and does not expect to receive any help from his parents or extended family and does not maintain relationships with his parents, family members and relatives on a daily basis should be held responsible for his actions, e.g. After earning money, you should save money to prepare for emergencies; choose a healthy lifestyle and take care of your physical and mental health, because you have made up your mind to only rely on yourself. You cannot talk about personal freedom and independence when you are active and active. When you encounter trouble, you will think of your parents and extended family. In fact, after she opened her mouth to her father, he was willing to pay her hospitalization expenses as an adult and was kind to her. He just didn&#39;t meet her request to &quot;lend herself two to three thousand yuan a month.&quot; Why did she have to sever ties with her father? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, in 2019, Ye Wen was 33 years old and borrowed 10,000 yuan from his father to open a photography studio. When his father refused to borrow the money, he severed the relationship with his father. This also caused a high psychological impact on his father. Expectations, and when expectations are not met, a lot of resentment arises. Speaking of modern methods, it is a matter of affection to be a father, but it is a duty not to be a father. In this sense, a father is the same as anyone else. If you borrow money from any friend, borrowing money from a friend is a matter of affection, but not borrowing money is a duty. Will you fall out because your friend refuses to borrow money? Doesn’t this confirm the correctness of not borrowing from friends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, for the second type of severance, some people believe that the reason is that some young people no longer value &quot;blood relations&quot; and hate family gatherings with male elders as the core in a patriarchal society; the significance of progress It&#39;s very big, &quot;You can&#39;t choose relatives, but you can choose friends&quot;, which reflects the change from &quot;acquaintance society&quot; to &quot;stranger society&quot;. These arguments are all debatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, the extended family or family is a natural blood community, which itself means that you are born with social capital (birthright). Why abandon it like worn out shoes? To a certain extent, trust based on blood and family ties is irreplaceable, and the maintenance cost of family ties is very low. If you are in the local area, you should visit regularly; if you are out of town, make a phone call or send a text message during the holidays to show yourself mind. In an era of peace and prosperity and when you are happy, these relationships may not be needed; but when facing difficulties and challenges, it is most reliable for family members to stay together and resist risks. Atomized individuals have poor ability to resist risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two possibilities for &quot;being lazy and neglecting to interact with relatives&quot;. One is that you have essentially broken off the relationship. The problem is: you just don’t have to interact with relatives who are weird or have bad character, but you don’t have to essentially cut off contact with all relatives. Confucianism says &quot;cultivate one&#39;s moral character and bring order to one&#39;s family.&quot; People who have bad relationships with all their relatives may have problems themselves. If you are driving on the highway and find that all the cars are going the wrong way, there is only one truth: it is not others who are going the wrong way, but you. The other is just that you think so in your heart, and your parents still come forward to maintain the relationship for you while you are away from home for a long time. This is a false breakup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can indeed choose friends, but close friends and life-and-death acquaintances are rare and require a high degree of spiritual and values ​​​​fit + deep trust established by long-term living and communication together. How many close friends, life and death friends, can a person have in a lifetime? What&#39;s more, there is no substitute for maintaining family relationships and making friends, and they can go hand in hand. Moreover, it may be difficult for those who have severed blood ties and family ties to establish deep connections and trust with people who are not even blood related, and it is also difficult for them to become trustworthy friends in the eyes of others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the so-called &quot;stranger society&quot; does not mean to eliminate the &quot;acquaintance society&quot;, but the &quot;acquaintance society&quot; is embedded in the &quot;stranger society&quot;. The world you face is still a world with Different concentric circles, the center of the circle is yourself, and the small family and the big family wrap you up in turn. As for the term &quot;patriarchal society&quot;, it is a deconstruction of fathers, marriage and family (one of the cornerstones of civilization). Civilization domesticates men, makes them assume family responsibilities, provides resources and protection, and improves the survival ability of children. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“爱”已成往事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260087]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 20:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;When a love affair turns into a marriage, a lawsuit will be filed. When love becomes a thing of the past, children become the focus of contention. Ai Fukuhara may face more than two years in prison due to the custody dispute. What will Jiang Hongjie win and lose?</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 20:55:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[只要改变，晚年也不算晚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260066]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/nvinpd6IpuIPaGpXr7eFQvWbMofoUvOrpkNW6dcG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1133&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/nvinpd6IpuIPaGpXr7eFQvWbMofoUvOr pkNW6dcG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insisting on exercise and a balanced diet...maintaining these good living habits can contribute to health. This concept has been widely recognized in the scientific community, but in real life Whether people can maintain a healthy lifestyle affects people&#39;s actual physical and mental state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, researchers from the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and other institutions have studied the impact of a healthy lifestyle on people&#39;s lifespan by analyzing the genes and living habits of a large number of elderly people. It was found that people with healthy lifestyle habits tended to have a lower risk of death and longer life expectancy, even in later life. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nature and nurture&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to data observed by the research institute, if elderly people with low genetic risk have relatively healthy lifestyle habits, they are expected to have The life expectancy may be 3.84 years longer than other people. If people with higher genetic risk have healthy living habits in their later years, the life expectancy can be 4.35 years longer. Relevant research will be published in &quot;The Lancet Healthy Longevity&quot; in October 2023. It can be seen that people with higher genetic risk benefit more by maintaining a healthy lifestyle, while those with high genetic risk but unhealthy lifestyle have the highest risk of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Innate genetic factors and acquired social environmental factors are two basic variables that affect human health. Research on long-lived elderly people shows that the death risk of elderly people over 110 years old is relatively stable, and there is no significant correlation with genetics, living habits, age, gender and other factors. But for most people under the age of 110, genetics, age and a healthy lifestyle are all important factors that affect lifespan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on twin studies, it is estimated that about 25% of the difference in life span between people can be attributed to genetics. But in 2018, Columbia University scientist Yaniv Erlich and others analyzed the lifespan patterns of more than 10 million people through family trees and believed that the impact of genetics on lifespan may not be that great. Explains 16% of the difference, which is less than one-fifth. This shows that factors such as living environment and lifestyle may have a greater impact on people&#39;s life span. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in order to comprehensively measure the impact of genetics, lifestyle and other factors on the life expectancy of the elderly, the latest research analyzed data from these two aspects at the same time. Relevant health data comes from the Chinese Health and Longevity Survey from 1998 to 2018, which recorded the conditions of more than 36,000 people over the age of 65. During the follow-up study period, a total of more than 27,000 people died. To compare the impact of life expectancy factors provide a reference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of researchers, a healthy lifestyle generally includes four aspects, not smoking, not drinking excessively, regularly participating in physical activities, and maintaining a healthy diet. It is worth mentioning that the scope of sports activities is also very wide, not only regular exercise is recognized, but also housework, gardening, raising animals, playing cards and other activities are included in the statistics. Considering that the elderly are prone to protein deficiency, only a diet that contains high-protein foods such as meat, eggs, and fish will be defined as a healthy lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When combined with the health habits of these older adults and their longevity, the findings actually emphasize the importance of developing a healthy lifestyle. Even in old age, these habits may help increase life expectancy. However, due to limitations of the research design, the latest research cannot provide a scientific explanation of the mechanism behind this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It does not happen overnight&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For the elderly, health and longevity are inseparable from a series of diseases. As aging intensifies, the incidence of many diseases, such as dementia, continues to increase. In 2022, a forecast study by the Global Burden of Disease Project estimates that the number of people suffering from dementia worldwide is likely to increase significantly from more than 57 million in 2019 to approximately 150 million in 2050, an increase of 166%. During this period, the number of sick people in China may increase from more than 15 million to more than 45 million, an increase of 197%, which is equivalent to a tripling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Alzheimer’s disease and other dementias are related to the cognitive ability and self-care ability of the elderly, they will not only affect the quality of life of the patients themselves and their families. Once they become lost or separated from care after the disease, It may also be life-threatening. In recent years, more and more studies have found that diseases such as dementia are also related to living habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, researchers from the Department of Biological Sciences at the University of Southern California used health data of nearly 50,000 elderly people to study the relationship between sedentary behavior and dementia, and found that the length of sitting is related to the onset of dementia. There is a clear link to risk, with longer periods of sitting associated with a higher risk of dementia. Compared with a median of 9.27 hours of sedentary behavior, those who sit for 12 hours a day have an increased risk of more than 60%, and if they sit for 15 hours a day, the risk more than triples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of these elderly people were diagnosed with dementia at the beginning of the study. The average age was over 65 years old. They carried monitoring devices on their wrists and accurately recorded their sedentary time in subsequent years. Here, some people are diagnosed with dementia. But that doesn’t mean dementia is caused solely by sitting for long periods of time in old age. Existing scientific observations show that education, smoking, obesity, high blood sugar and other conditions may affect the risk of dementia. Lifestyle factors associated with geriatric disease can be traced back to younger ages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, psychology researchers at the University of Sussex used an observational study lasting nearly thirty years to explore the long-term health effects of symptoms such as depression and found that if people accumulate If there are too many symptoms of depression, anxiety, etc., cognitive functions will be more damaged in middle-aged and elderly people, such as poorer memory and lower accuracy of information processing. This evidence means that the relationship between some diseases may be interlocking and can induce other diseases decades apart. Not only should early detection, early intervention and early treatment be required, but also the development of healthy lifestyles should be early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, for depression, scientists have discovered that there is a causal relationship between a healthy lifestyle and this type of disease. If you adhere to a healthy lifestyle, reduce sitting for long periods of time, increase social activities, exercise regularly, do not smoke, drink less alcohol, and maintain a healthy diet and sleep, it will help prevent depression. Research on older people has also found that developing even a hobby can help reduce people&#39;s symptoms of depression and improve their happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mental health diseases such as dementia and depression are just one case that affects people’s health and longevity. In reality, there are many diseases that affect people’s health. Although the pathogenic mechanisms of various diseases are mostly complex, existing Scientific evidence shows that lifestyle factors are at work behind a considerable number of diseases. In other words, by changing your lifestyle, it is possible to reduce the risk of disease and even death. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Brutal Truth&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The latest research released by the Global Cardiovascular Risk Alliance shows that more than 50% of cardiovascular disease cases and about 20% of all-cause The deaths can be attributed to five modifiable risk factors. The five risk factors are: body mass index (BMI), systolic blood pressure, non-HDL cholesterol, smoking and diabetes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, about 57% of cardiovascular disease cases and 22% of various death cases among women are affected by these five risk indicators, and about 53% of men are affected. % and 19%, relevant research was published in the &quot;New England Journal of Medicine&quot; (NEJM) in October 2023. Modifiable risk factors serve as weather vanes. Abnormalities in a single indicator will not suddenly cause disease or death, but they can give people time to identify disease risks early and make changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Body mass index (BMI), which can measure body fat and thinness, has been widely used in health management and disease risk prediction. Overweight and even obesity are obvious risk signals. Blood pressure and cholesterol are usually items that can be checked during a physical examination. Smoking is harmful to health, and quitting smoking as early as possible can greatly reduce the risk of disease. As for diabetes, as an important risk predictor of other cardiovascular diseases, it is a chronic disease in itself. Preventing and controlling blood sugar levels as early as possible requires developing many healthy lifestyles and persisting for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerning health and longevity, in recent years there have been some scientific opinions that do not seem serious enough, such as &quot;people with higher incomes live longer&quot;, &quot;people who love art live longer&quot;, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, behind They all point to the issue of lifestyle affecting life span. Although these economic, social, and cultural factors, such as diet, hobbies, etc., are simple, common, and even interesting, scientific proof shows that they can all be used as environmental factors that affect life span and affect human health together with genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, artistic hobbies affect lifespan, probably because these cultural and sports activities not only exercise the body, but also activate the brain. They also provide opportunities for social interaction, improve people&#39;s sense of happiness and belonging, and reduce It relieves loneliness, which is very rare for the elderly. An epidemiological study in Norway found that people who regularly participate in singing, dancing and other artistic activities will reduce the risk of death by more than 40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for those with higher incomes and longer lives, the relevant evidence is more abundant, and it also confirms the widespread influence of factors such as economic and social status. Public health studies in the United States, Norway and other places have found that the life expectancy of people in the top 1% of income levels is nearly 10 years longer than those in the bottom 1%. In societies with different welfare systems and varying degrees of inequality, economic factors play surprisingly similar roles. It is a cruel truth that people with high incomes can live longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Developing good habits as early as possible&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is actually related to a series of healthy lifestyles. From the perspective of basic material conditions such as diet and housing, healthy diet and high-quality living environment are often more expensive and require higher income support. Medical care, services closely related to health and lifespan, and physical exercise facilities also rely on economic basis. In addition, education, income, health awareness, etc. are often related. People with higher incomes may be more aware of the importance of health, understand more health knowledge, increase exercise, and smoke less, drink less, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When these healthy lifestyles are concentrated in cities, comparative data show that people living in big cities tend to live longer overall, including low-income groups living in big cities. . Although the income is not high, they may benefit from the overall public health services, policies and health culture of large cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the secret of longevity, the scientific community has never stopped exploring. In recent years, some preliminary findings in some animal experiments are actually related to lifestyle. Researchers at the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center observed hundreds of mice for nearly four years, the equivalent of a lifetime. In 2022, their nearly four-year study showed that dietary patterns can change the lifespan of mice, specifically reflected in the amount of food and the time of eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Restricting 30% of the caloric intake can extend the lifespan of mice by 10%. If the caloric intake time is further restricted and eating during normal activity times according to the circadian rhythm, the lifespan can even be extended by 35%. This provides a reference for humans to understand the mechanism of longevity, and also proves the importance of a healthy lifestyle to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that it is difficult to grasp all the information about a person’s daily life in various current studies on healthy life, especially when observing diseases and life span through the lifestyle of large-scale groups. There are many limitations, and more research is needed in the future to uncover the secrets of health and longevity. In view of the fact that some healthy behaviors also have a positive impact on people&#39;s current lives, such as regular exercise, healthy eating, and smoking and alcohol control, these recognized daily healthy behaviors are worth developing as early as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>