<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[儿童医院人满为患，国家卫健委回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261135]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In view of the recent increase in the number of outpatient and emergency visits in hospitals and the increase in the number of children infected with respiratory diseases in some places, the National Health Commission In an exclusive interview with Xinhua News Agency on November 23, the relevant responsible comrades of the Health Committee answered some questions that the public, especially families of children, are concerned about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Recently, many local children’s hospitals have been overcrowded, and the National Health Commission has taken measures What measures are in place to provide relief? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Recently, we have continued to pay attention to the diagnosis and treatment of vulnerable groups in children during the period of high incidence of infectious diseases, and guided all localities to strengthen overall planning and implement hierarchical diagnosis and treatment. system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some community hospitals have recently opened examinations for children services, but some parents are worried that community hospitals have insufficient diagnostic and treatment capabilities and may delay their children’s condition. What should they do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The National Health Commission has required all localities to play the role of medical consortiums to strengthen technical guidance to grassroots medical and health institutions and improve the prevention and control of general infections. Diagnosis and treatment capabilities and critical illness identification and referral efficiency. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which hospitals are qualified to accept children with respiratory tract infections? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The National Health Commission has guided all localities to publish information on medical institutions that can provide pediatric diagnosis and treatment services in the region to facilitate nearby medical treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What should I do if my child has a fever or cough? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Large hospitals are densely staffed, have long waiting times, and have a high risk of cross-infection. It is recommended that children with mild symptoms first go to primary care. Institutions, general hospital paediatrics, etc. After a diagnosis and treatment plan is determined at a children&#39;s specialized hospital, the patient can also be referred to a primary medical institution for follow-up treatment or home treatment through the medical consortium. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the conditions under which children must go to the hospital for medical treatment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;According to expert advice, if a child has a very high fever or a fever that lasts for more than three days, frequent coughs that affect normal life, poor mental status, or even symptoms of If you experience lethargy, increased respiratory rate or difficulty breathing, frequent vomiting, rash, headache or convulsions, etc., you should take your child to the doctor promptly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大学图书馆应该向公众开放]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261055]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Zhao Kui, a professor at Huazhong University of Science and Technology, said on Weibo recently: I didn’t understand before why so many Chinese scholars I want to go to Harvard to study China. After looking at the collection of the library, I couldn’t help but wonder, just for the Chinese local chronicles, which library in China has so many original local chronicles from the early Qing Dynasty, where you can read them by hand, take photos for free, and each set of rare books has been specially protected. Protected and carefully collected, this is just the tip of the iceberg of Harvard&#39;s many libraries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Zhao Kui said that some of Harvard University’s chronicles were purchased by Yenching University when it was running a school in China in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China, some were purchased from Japanese collectors after Japan’s defeat, and many were purchased by Chinese collectors. The income is directly donated by the family, which is the accumulated income of hundreds of years and generations of research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regardless of the amount of information, Harvard University’s openness is worth promoting in China. Foreigners who intend to visit the Harvard University Library can enter the library with valid documents after applying for a visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China&#39;s relevant laws and policies, public libraries must be open to the public free of charge. However, school libraries do not have this obligation. In 2017, the second draft of the Public Library Law was reviewed, and Article 47 stipulated: “The state encourages school libraries, libraries of scientific research institutions, and other types of libraries to be open to the public.” Article 48 of the Public Library Law that was finally implemented stipulates: &quot;The state supports school libraries, scientific research institution libraries and other types of libraries to be open to the public.&quot; From encouragement to support, opening school libraries to the public On the issue of openness, the attitude has become weaker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people believe that libraries in universities and scientific research institutions serve specific teachers and students, and students also pay fees to go to university. Therefore, libraries in universities and scientific research institutions should put the interests of teachers and students first. In the first place, there is no obligation to the public. From the perspective of resources and capabilities, school libraries have limited space. Now many university libraries are overcrowded and it is difficult to find a library. University libraries are unable to assume the responsibility of opening to the outside world. Opening up to the outside world will worsen the experience of teachers and students in schools. After it is opened to the outside world, even if there is access through ID cards, citizen cards, etc., it cannot be strictly managed like subway security inspections. There are great dangers and hidden dangers, which is not conducive to protecting students. In addition, there will be management issues, such as the problem of non-return after lending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, these reasons are not valid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, although students pay tuition fees, the running costs of the university cannot be covered by tuition fees. China&#39;s universities and scientific research institutions are all supported by state funding, including libraries, and state funding comes from taxes paid by each citizen. University libraries are also public libraries to some extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public&#39;s demand for the library is mainly for borrowing, which will not put too much pressure on the venue. In terms of management, the credit system is now very developed and can fully undertake the management of university libraries opening to the outside world. In addition to ID cards, citizen cards, and financial credit systems, social credit systems such as Zhima Fen are now very efficient. Not only can you borrow power banks and shared bicycles without a deposit, you can even rent a car without a deposit. These values ​​are more expensive than books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for security issues, borrowing itself is a screening demand. Those who have this demand are people with some education. Even if it is open, it will not be like a teahouse or bar, and the demand will not skyrocket and the pressure will not be Not big. Of course, there are always more risks when there are more people, but this risk is no higher than college students taking the subway or walking on the street, so the so-called safety issues are not valid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there is another very important reason why universities and research institutions do not open their libraries, that is, they can monopolize scarce information and academic resources, thereby gaining advantages in publishing papers and producing results. But obviously, academic libraries supported by public finance should not become exclusive academic resources. Someone said on Weibo that he went to the National Library and wanted to read the only copy of &quot;The Book of Fishing&quot; from the Ming Dynasty. He only saw it after asking for help. He was not allowed to take pictures. It took him three days to enter it on the computer and spent more than 500 yuan on the remaining part. Copying, and you also need to sign a &quot;no publication&quot; guarantee before you can read it. The original copies of the Ming Dynasty have long lost their copyright. The library should be responsible for disseminating knowledge, but it regards this as an exclusive resource. This phenomenon is more serious in universities and research institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The libraries of universities and research institutions are more professional than public libraries and have more comprehensive subject materials. If they are only used by one family, it will cause waste. If they are open to the public, they can exert greater value and make more people use it. Many people benefit, and it is also conducive to academic competition and innovation. On the other hand, university libraries are independent, which will lead to duplication of construction and is not conducive to the efficient use of resources. Opening up university libraries and sharing resources is conducive to the differentiation of university libraries into professional directions, which is also a good thing for universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Good Will Hunting&quot;, which was nominated for Best Picture at the 70th Academy Awards together with &quot;Titanic&quot;, tells the story of the growth of a talented boy. In the film, a Harvard college student laughs at the male protagonist, and the male protagonist counterattacks: &quot;The education you spent fifteen thousand dollars on, I can get in a public library for only one and a half dollars.&quot; Open libraries are conducive to education. Fairness and fair opportunities allow more people who have not entered universities or scientific research institutions to easily obtain academic materials and promote the development of China&#39;s science, technology, and cultural knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2017, the Ministry of Education and the General Administration of Sports jointly issued the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Promoting the Opening of School Sports Venues to the Society&quot;, which aims to effectively alleviate the growing sports and fitness needs of young people and the general public. The contradiction between sports venues and insufficient supply of resources promotes the prosperity and development of national fitness. Objectively speaking, the operation of sports venues is a zero-sum game with little flexibility and an either-or for users. But libraries are different. If they are just for borrowing, opening them to the public will have little impact on students and researchers. Therefore, since university stadiums can &quot;promote opening to the public&quot;, then there is no reason for university libraries to be closed and refused to be open to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The library is a public service with strong externalities. It can popularize knowledge, help innovation, and drive the country&#39;s technological and economic progress and social development. The more borrowings there are, the stronger the role of the library. It is a great thing for the country and individuals for libraries to operate at a higher intensity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the state should promote, encourage and even require libraries in universities and research institutions to be open to the public. Nowadays, libraries have a lot of electronic materials, which are open to the public. They do not occupy library space and do not put a lot of pressure on the network. Electronic materials in colleges and universities are open to the public, and this can be done immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这对错置的父女，治愈又温情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261059]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;There is a new movie recently. George, a 12-year-old hearing-impaired girl, lives alone after the death of her mother. Suddenly, her childish father Jason, whom she has never met, breaks into her life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It was shortlisted for the main competition unit of this year’s Beijing International Film Festival, and also won the Jury Prize in the world cinema feature film unit of this year’s Sundance Film Festival. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Occasionally Echoed&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/866afcc07801117a78c26caa6e83b215.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/866afcc07801117a78c26caa6e83b215.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a niche literary film, &quot;Occasionally Echoed&quot; 》Requires you to be completely immersed in it while watching the movie. Any external actions or sounds may break the continuity of the experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This does not mean that &quot;Oudehui&lt;/span>;ring&quot; has high threshold requirements for the audience. In fact, it does not have a dramatic plot, nor emotional ups and downs, and is even a bit straightforward and monotonous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is such a movie, but it has something that many current movies lack - truth in details, emotional intimacy, and the opposite of spring breeze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/10687a29fbb137cc8bf11f0a59aebb10.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/10687a29fbb137cc8bf11f0a59aebb10.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259120&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this kind of delicate emotional presentation also requires the audience to carefully understand the fleeting arrangements in the movie from the lens language and plot settings. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, the instant switching between day and night, documentary-style comments from friends around, and the protagonist’s loneliness when he tried to use bicycle parts to build the Tower of Babel leading to heaven. And the various interactions between her and her sudden appearance of her father all hint at the careful thoughts of director Charlotte Regan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8192125475f2b4e38c9f0ee66458f3a5.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8192125475f2b4e38c9f0ee66458f3a5.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259122 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Oudehui&lt;/span>;Hang&quot; uses the perspective of the little girl George to show her changes in the whole thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her eyes, all her actions such as stealing other people&#39;s bicycles and reselling them, beating up the little girl next door, etc., have a natural legitimacy; while the father who climbed over the wall is an idiot in life. He is the one who needs to be taken care of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This contrary narration method makes the film full of a childishness that pretends to be mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f150d9df5aa87d07e290d3bffcacb8f1.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f150d9df5aa87d07e290d3bffcacb8f1.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259125&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In our traditional understanding, fathers are often figures of silent giving. For example, in Zhu Ziqing&#39;s novel, the father left a deep shadow after turning over the track to buy oranges for his son; for example, the father played by Zhang Yi in the currently released &quot;Priceless Treasure&quot; is very willing to protect and pay for his adopted daughter, even if he faces jail, he still has to protect his daughter&#39;s safety. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A father from this perspective is always like a mountain, extending his hands when his children need them, and becoming a beacon when their children move forward. Likewise, as children, they should also go Understand their hardship and be grateful for their efforts. &lt;/span>;This is a profound expression of father&#39;s love, and also contains a spiritual expectation of parents for their children, hoping that they will be considerate and filial in return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, &quot;Occasional Echoes&quot; misplaced the maturity of the little girl and her father in an exaggerated way, causing the father to confess that he was not sensible and did not know how to take care of him as soon as he appeared. child. The daughter, on the other hand, cleans the house the way her mother did when she was alive, so that every place in the house always looks like it did when her mother was alive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this contrary misplacement, the movie&lt;/span>; rarely restores the world of a child. There is the joy that only belongs to children here. She dances cutely downstairs to please the neighbors, rolls around on the grass with her friends, thinks she can steal other people&#39;s bicycles seamlessly, and thinks she is confident in bargaining with unscrupulous car dealers. This is a child who forces himself to mature and begins to explore the grand world, full of vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the film generously acknowledges that our parents can also be outrageous. For example, he would join his daughter&#39;s theft, not only to help her look out, but also to start the operation. As a result, the bicycle was not stolen&lt;span>;, but instead the patrolling police were attracted...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/69d49ea63542fb2185386e93591beaa4.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/69d49ea63542fb2185386e93591beaa4.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This pair of parents Women, they use their own ways to understand life, but as a result, they are all inexperienced and at a loss, and they are unable to become better guardians and children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an atypical father-daughter relationship. The film not only captures the panic and anxiety of children trying to grow into adults, but also captures the panic and fear of men becoming fathers. They are limited to their first time. The father must learn to accompany and the daughter must learn to accept. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Towards the end of the movie, there is a plot that makes people laugh out loud - the little girl&lt;/span>; heard her mother leaving a &lt;span>;message&lt; to her father on the phone&lt; /span>; &quot;Take good care of your daughter&quot;, but in a blink of an eye she found that her father was not in the house. She searched in panic, and finally heard the boy playing football calling &quot;Jason&quot; next to a football field on the corner of the street. The little girl looked inside and found that the father she had been looking for for a long time was actually playing football with a group of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/26c512d2dd2451a0c5904c13152b6065.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/26c512d2dd2451a0c5904c13152b6065.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259123&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is the most gratifying part of the film. &lt;/span>;The 1994 director did not try to exploit the pain and ferocity of this subject, &lt;span>;but instead presented it tolerantly&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;. Let us see that adults can also be as fragile as children, and children can also appear mature and steady. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this misplaced line drawing, there is neither the mountain-like weight of father&#39;s love nor the pain of children&#39;s growth, but that they both want to play the good role in each other&#39;s life hard and clumsily. own role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[包子铺卖豆腐脑被罚一万五：对小本生意岂可如此“用重典”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261051]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a bun shop in Beijing was confiscated by the municipal supervision department for selling tofu noodles and was fined 15,000 yuan and more than 7,000 yuan. attracted public attention and strong doubts. Selling tofu buns in a bun shop may indeed violate the regulations, but it does not necessarily require a huge penalty. Is there a more humane way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the China Quality News Network, a subsidiary of China Quality Newspaper and Periodicals, which is in charge of the State Administration of Municipal Supervision, an administrative penalty published on the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau recently showed that the &quot;Beijing Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop&quot; will be closed in 2022. From April 23 to July 27, 2023, &quot;1,169 orders of tofu nao (salty) were sold on a food delivery platform, priced at 6 yuan/order, with a value of 7,014 yuan.&quot; The Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that the bun shop sells hot food beyond the scope of its licensed business items and violates Article 16, paragraph 1, of the Measures for the Investigation and Punishment of Illegal Activities on Online Food Safety and the Measures for the Supervision and Administration of Food Safety in Online Catering Services 》Article 4 stipulates that he shall be fined 15,000 yuan according to law; his illegal income of 7,014 yuan shall be confiscated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is undoubtedly surprising that the bun shop cannot sell tofu pudding. As a result, the penalty quickly attracted a lot of attention on social media. Many netizens made fun of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The clause quoted in the administrative penalty decision stipulates that food operators shall not operate beyond the scope of the food business license. But why is it beyond the business scope of a bun shop to sell tofu? This really leaves a lot of people scratching their heads. According to the Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau, selling tofu curd is exceeding the permitted scope of selling hot food, but aren’t steamed buns a hot food? Since you can sell steamed buns, it means you have a hot food business license, so why can&#39;t you sell tofu puffs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public administrative penalty information does not provide any further explanation. Then we can only look up more information. Judging from the industrial and commercial registration information, the business license of this bun shop was registered in 2018, and its business scope includes catering services and food sales. According to the Food Safety Law, food-related business activities require a food business license. Then I checked its food business license information and found that its licensed business item is &quot;manufacture and sales of hot food (limited to staple food products)&quot;. The &quot;restricted to staple food products&quot; in the brackets is probably the reason why this bun shop was fined. Although they are all hot foods, steamed buns are a staple food, so their production and sale are allowed, while tofu curd is not considered a staple food, so they cannot be sold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, the punishment imposed by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau cannot be said to be illegal. However, its rationality is still questionable. First of all, why is the scope of the food business license of this bun shop so narrow? According to the &quot;Food Business License Management Measures&quot; formulated by the former State Food and Drug Administration, the food business license items applied for by catering service operators are divided into hot food production and sales, cold food food production and sales, raw food food production and sales, and cakes. Production and sales of food, homemade drinks and other types of food. Except for the specific varieties approved by the Food and Drug Administration, which should be clearly marked for the production and sale of other types of food, other categories do not need to be specially labeled. So why is the food business license of this bun shop marked as limited to staple food products? If regulations do not stipulate that different business licenses apply to staple food and non-staple hot food, is the license originally issued by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau suspected of not being administered in accordance with the law and improperly restricting the business scope of the business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that information from the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau shows that the food business license of Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop was issued on October 17, 2023. The penalty decision for operating beyond the scope was made on November 13. The illegal facts in the penalty decision show that Baozipu has been selling tofu nao on the takeout website since April 2022. So, when this bun shop applied for a food business license in 2023, why did it only apply for the production and sale of &quot;staple food&quot; hot foods? Knowing that in addition to steamed buns, their store also sells tofu puffs, and that there is no need to apply separately for hot food business licenses for staple food and non-staple food, the store deliberately only applied for a manufacturing and sales license for &quot;staple food&quot; to limit its business scope and Excluding the tofu pudding that you are already selling, are you digging a hole for yourself? Were you misled when you applied for a food business license? Have the staff of the competent department fulfilled their duty of explanation? Is it even possible that when applying for a license, they deliberately misled them to only apply for a staple food license, and then investigated and punished them for selling non-staple food beyond the scope? Considering that he was investigated and fined less than a month after applying for the license, such a timing coincidence can easily lead to other suspicions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if there are no problems with the above process, imposing such a heavy penalty violates the basic principle of administrative punishment that the penalty should be commensurate with the offense. The Administrative Penalty Law clearly stipulates that if the violation is minor and corrected in a timely manner without causing harmful consequences, administrative penalties will not be imposed. Baozi and tofu are both hot foods, and regulations do not make any special distinction between the safety supervision of the two. The sale of tofu in the bun shop has not caused any food safety consequences. Even if there is any violation of law, the circumstances are very minor, and it can be given a warning and ordered to make corrections. At the beginning, more than 7,000 &quot;illegal gains&quot; were confiscated and fined 15,000 yuan. A total of more than 20,000 yuan. How long does it take for a bun shop to make money back? At a time when it is difficult to make a living in a small business, imposing such heavy penalties on small businessmen will of course arouse strong dissatisfaction among the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for small mistakes to be punished heavily. In 2021, a vegetable shop owner in Yulin, Shaanxi Province was fined 66,000 yuan by the market supervision department for selling 5 kilograms of substandard celery. After being exposed by the State Council Supervision Bureau, the deputy director of the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau admitted that the punishment was too severe and was not proportionate. A CCTV report found that among the more than 50 penalties imposed on small and micro market entities by the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau since 2021, 21 cases were fined more than 50,000 yuan, and the case value was only tens or hundreds of yuan. The Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau in Beijing imposed a heavy fine on Baozi Shop, which is comparable to the case in Yulin. Is this kind of supervision for supervision or for fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food safety supervision is of course very important, but supervision cannot be for the sake of supervision, let alone supervision for the sake of fines. Under the current economic situation, providing good services to small and micro market entities and creating a good market environment should be the primary responsibility of regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“阿根廷特朗普”米莱：他承诺去做的和他将会去做的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261100]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/VYQXzpdI0T4ZMuFEFaFT7g8Rc2qZzVWbsN7BPZzu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/VYQXzpdI0T4ZMuFEFaFT7g8Rc2qZzV WbsN7BPZzu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259316&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, the candidate of the Argentine far-right electoral alliance &quot;Freedom Forward Party&quot; Milai greeted the people at a polling station in the capital Buenos Aires &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local On October 22, the results of the second round of the Argentine presidential election were announced. Far-right candidate Javier Milei, known as &quot;Argentine Trump (Donald Trump)&quot;, defeated the candidate representing the ruling coalition and the current economic leader. Minister Sergio Massa was elected as the next president. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Argentina’s “Olympic Team Member”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Millais, 53, is an Argentinian of Italian descent. He holds two master’s degrees in economics. After graduation, he has held positions including Financial executive positions, including senior economist at HSBC, have shifted to focus on research and teaching of economic and financial theory and development strategies since 2012. He has served in many well-known economic and financial think tanks and forums, and has served as a domestic He serves as a lecturer or part-time teacher in many foreign universities, and has published 9 monographs and more than 50 papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is an ardent believer of the &quot;Austrian School&quot; who advocates &quot;abandoning all financial and national economic controls and implementing absolute economic liberalism&quot;, and later gradually evolved into a combination of Milton Friedman-style monetarism ( The &quot;alternative Austrian school&quot; of Monetarism advocates that &quot;the government should do nothing except regulate the currency issuance through the central bank to control inflation.&quot; After entering politics, he further advocated that even the central bank can be eliminated. Argentina can completely abandon its local currency and Switch to the U.S. dollar to achieve the goal of controlling inflation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This idea of ​​being &quot;more Austrian than Austrian and more Friedmanian than Friedmanian&quot; is called &quot;native Austrian school&quot; by many economists in Argentina. It might as well be called As &quot;Argentine Olympic Team&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/nsPZYDEKzQ9IMyPzFBHKJADkWEcvxdFED3QjrcUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/nsPZYDEKzQ9IMyPzFBHKJADkWEcvxdFED3QjrcUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259317&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, in Buenos Aires, Argentina, voters voted at a polling station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After turning to &quot;retreat&quot;, he opened his own radio magazine radio program &quot;Demoliendo mitos&quot; (Demoliendo mitos), which long-term, systematic and dedicated criticism of the Argentine left-wing party He accused the government of being responsible for a series of long-term ills in Argentina&#39;s economy, society and people&#39;s livelihood, and quickly gained popularity. Since 2017, he has become interested in politics. In 2021, he founded the far-right political party &quot;Avanza Libertad&quot; (Avanza Libertad) and was successfully elected to the House of Representatives as the party&#39;s candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, he announced his participation in the presidential election. Initially, because he was a &quot;rookie&quot; in politics and his political party was very weak, he was generally considered to be a &quot;student with the prince&quot;, and even got the nickname &quot;El Loco&quot; ) nickname. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the primary election on August 13 (a unique electoral stage in Argentina. Due to the large number of small parties in Congress, several larger party alliances must be formed, and each alliance recommends a single presidential candidate. The purpose of the primary election (the single candidate for the election of each coalition), Millais not only stood out from the &quot;Juntos por el Cambio&quot; coalition composed of 12 large and small right-wing parties, becoming the only candidate of the coalition, and after all 5 candidates passed Among the candidates in the primary election, he topped the list with 30% of the vote and became the most popular candidate in the election overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first round of voting on October 22, Milais received 29.99% of the votes, second only to Massa (36.78%). Due to Argentina’s election rules, the candidate to be elected president must obtain a majority. In the second round of voting on November 19, Millay won with an absolute advantage of 55.7% to 44.3%, and won 21 of Argentina&#39;s 24 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why was the &quot;madman&quot; elected?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Argentina&#39;s annual inflation rate has reached 140%, and may even exceed 200% by the end of the year. More than 40% of the population lives below the poverty line. In the past 20 years, It has defaulted on its international sovereign debt three times in the past few years, and the latest time it even caused neighboring Bolivia and Brazil to refuse to deliver the pineapples and bananas they ordered as part of the contract to avoid defaulting on their debts. Argentina, nicknamed &quot;the only developed country to develop into a developing country in modern times&quot;, ranked sixth in the world in terms of economic aggregate at the beginning of the 20th century, but has now fallen to 66th. Argentines have long complained about this. Not only that, massive public expenditures, deteriorating social security, and the prevalence of nepotism known as &quot;political casteization&quot; have become the targets of public outrage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was against this background that Milais, who appeared with an alternative image of &quot;wild hair and a big mouth&quot;, entered the political arena as an &quot;amateur Internet celebrity gunner&quot; and shouted out a series of seemingly shocking but in fact The alternative political platform of &quot;Directed Demolition&quot;: Abolish the central bank and the local currency and switch to the US dollar, which is intended to cater to the public&#39;s distrust of the local currency and central bank accumulated due to long-term inflation and local currency establishment, and the public&#39;s belief that &quot;strong medicine may be able to eradicate inflation and &quot;Wealth shrinkage&quot; is expected; the abolition of more than half of the ministries and commissions is intended to cater to public dissatisfaction with nepotism and bureaucracy; the withdrawal from the &quot;BRIC&quot;, freezing of large-scale engineering projects, and the privatization of public service enterprises and educational institutions such as schools, radio and television facilities, and electricity ization is intended to cater to the public’s strong desire to reduce public expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for other &quot;alternative propositions&quot;, they are mostly put forward to highlight their &quot;core values&quot; or attract core supporters, such as advocating anti-abortion and anti-contraception, opposing energy conservation and emission reduction, and drastically cutting social welfare and Medical privatization, etc., are all in line with its &quot;basic color&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At one point, he also proposed that &quot;everyone has a gun&quot; and even allowed his die-hard supporters to insult the current Pope Francis, who is also an Argentinian. This was also his &quot;true performance.&quot; As for the drug liberalization policy, which is very different from the &quot;Trump replicas&quot; of most other countries, it was &quot;condescendingly&quot; proposed to cater to the tastes of some low-level people in Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most analysts point out that although the majority of the Argentine public may not really believe that Millais can &quot;cure all diseases&quot;, given the negative impact of left-wing Peronism in the past Having won 10 out of 13 general elections, the left wing has already overdrafted the trust and patience of voters, while the traditional right wing has failed to reverse the situation in the last two elections. Therefore, &quot;since other methods don&#39;t work, we might as well try strong medicine.&quot; This kind of &quot;maybe it might work&quot; thinking quickly became popular, and allowed Millay, who had participated in a &quot;copycat&quot; Rolling Stones band and was familiar with the way of pop success, to win the presidency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts pointed out that after Milley suddenly emerged in the primary election, the government used a propaganda machine to &quot;demonize&quot; him in a panic, which was counterproductive. Some works intended to arouse public panic about Milley&#39;s administration (such as claiming that Milley&#39;s cuts in public spending will cause the Buenos Aires metro ticket to rise to 1,100 pesos, while the current price is only 56 pesos) have actually done the government a disservice because The public can easily associate this with the soaring prices, and be led away by Milley&#39;s propaganda that &quot;the government spends money indiscriminately like this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some local observers pointed out that Millais carefully created the image of a &quot;political outsider&quot; and successfully attracted a large number of grassroots votes under the banner of &quot;understanding the sufferings of the people&quot; and &quot;opposing nepotism&quot;, but his However, the image of &quot;grassroots spokesperson&quot; was carefully created by a group of the richest people in Argentina: billionaire Eduardo Eurnekian is one of Millay&#39;s most important supporters, and the media network &quot;A24&quot; he controls is Millay&#39;s The main shaper and promoter of successful political public relations images, and successfully &quot;killed&quot; the mediocre public media in a series of dazzling combinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The right-wing’s decisive choice after the first round is a tactical key: Patricia Bullrich, also a far-right but “relatively less right” candidate, won the primary election as “ The slogan &quot;Anti-high crime rate&quot; competed with Millais&#39;s snipe and clam, and won 23.81% of the votes in the first round, ranking third after Massa and Millais. After the first round, Milley decisively stopped his criticism of Burridge, who quickly announced his support for Milley after weighing the pros and cons. In fact, Milley&#39;s vote share in the second round (55.7%) was the same as in the first round. The combined votes of Millais and Burridge (53.90%) were about the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cdRisNIh3HwbGLwcb0IvcmMiztRxeqzryQU7RPLV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cdRisNIh3HwbGLwcb0IvcmMiztRxeqzryQU7RPLV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 19, 2023, Massa, candidate of Argentina&#39;s center-left ruling coalition Fatherland, gave a speech after voting at a polling station in Tigre, Buenos Aires Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Civil and military officials and the &quot;prime minister in black&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Because of the political party to which Milai belongs It is too small and the core team is not large. It is generally believed that he will widely absorb other larger right-wing parties that belong to the &quot;Common Change Alliance&quot;, especially political veterans who obey the orders of former President Mauricio Macri to join the cabinet or join the staff. However, core cabinet members will still try to arrange confidants and like-minded people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, the foreign minister has been identified as Diana Mondino, who co-founded the &quot;Free Progress Party&quot; with him. She and Milai were both &quot;Argentine Olympic team members&quot;; she was convicted of helping Argentina in 1996. Radoner&#39;s star lawyer and television commentator Mariano Cuno Libarona, a star -related lawsuit, will become the new judicial minister. The celebrities who are proficient in &quot;Internet celebrity economics&quot; will be in the election campaign. In the process, there were many wonderful counts for Miller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His Vice President partner Victoria Villarruel is a controversial person: she has a high popularity and has a considerable appeal in the right -wing camp, but because of the former military government, the former military government wants The family of members, and publicly advocated controversy for the &quot;rehabilitation&quot; of the military government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As for the public office, it may have a significant impact on the strategy and policy direction of the new government. Karina Milei, who is called &quot;My Moses&quot;, is also known as &quot;the biggest influence on Millet&quot; by the circle, is also a character that must not be ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The promise that will be fulfilled, will not be fulfilled, and may not be fulfilled &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;Stay away from &#39;BRICS&#39;&quot;, cut public expenses and frozen large projects. The campaign commitment that will be fulfilled later is because these commitments have a wide range of voters&#39; foundations, and they are intertwined (such as the former government actively strives to join the &quot;BRICS&quot;, in order to get more large project financing in the horse). The core political platform and the least popular policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Privatization of public media&quot; will also be launched as soon as possible, not only because excessive public officials are concentrated on social dissatisfaction (Miller once violently criticized &quot;6.2 million in private in the broadcast show Argentine employees who work in the company should support 20 million public officials &quot;and win a piece of applause), and because after the preliminary election, in Mirley&#39;s&quot; witch hunting frenzy &quot;and&quot; directional stains &quot;, I am afraid that Mirley will not guarantee that the rice bowl will be guaranteed after coming to power Public media employees performed very exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ve41ebvcsbeygl3aemeekyqzokhhhhh.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;640&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ve41ebvcsbeygl3aemeekyqzo3nokhhhh.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259315&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; On November 16, 2023, in Corolopa, Argentine, the rotary right-wing election alliance&quot; Free Metamorulet &quot;candidate Mila (middle) participated in the campaign rally &lt;span style =&quot; Color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some campaign commitments will be fulfilled, but most of them will&quot; discount &quot;: ministries and commissions will definitely be reduced, but it is estimated that this will not be claimed before the previous claims. After turning over half the ministries and the central bank, this is not only overkill. As a smaller ruling party, it is not conducive to discussing the personnel of the allies and arranging allies. Before the second round of voting, he had a low profile that he would &quot;keep the contract signed with Chinese companies&quot;, and many analysts pointed out that his &quot;national Olympic&quot; economic and financial strategy relies on overseas financing, but in the United States, regardless of the Democratic Party or the Republican Party, None of the interest in Argentina, who has long been reputable for Golden aid (Interestingly, the congratulations to his elected Trump, who admired him, publicly opposed to continue to provide financing for Argentina for convenient American politicians), messed up The relationship with China, China, China, China may not have any benefits for Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, he has publicly threatened to visit the United States, for the first time after being elected, and worship a number of Jewish leaders (he once claimed to convert to Jewish religion), but recently lowered the tone because the latest people have The tone shows that the mainstream public opinion in Argentina is very interested in the US dollar, but it is too close to the country to make the country too close to Israel, especially to make the president&#39;s &quot;Jewishization&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Almost destined commitments that will not be fulfilled include attacking the Pope (apologized before the second round of voting), &quot;everyone holding a gun&quot; (the first round of voting is discarded because of the reversal of the polls), the medical and private ownership Hua and large -scale reduction of public welfare (the polls have been sharply reduced after the strong reversal), and &quot;to give Malaysia Island to Britain&quot; -The campaign of most allies within the alliance to publicly oppose it. Several Malaysian war veterans reacted fiercely, and public opinion feedback was not ideal. He has rarely mentioned recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are also some promises to observe or be observed. The most prominent is &quot;abandoning the local currency to use the US dollar&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some analysts believe that, given that Argentina has long been cited at home and abroad at home and abroad, and Argentina companies and ordinary people have actually begun to use the US dollar, the &quot;currency dollar&quot; resistance is actually not as big as imagined as big as expected. In addition, the public&#39;s complaints about &quot;the government has made a rising and poverty through the money printing&quot;, and this move is also expected to gather popularity in a short period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But most analysts, such as the chief emerging market economist William Jackson and Zurich&#39;s investment group manager of Zuri Larose, chief emerging market economist, believes that the situation believes that the situation is that the situation It is not that simple: Argentina is the third largest economy in Latin America. The abandonment of the US dollar in the US dollar means giving up the control of independent fiscal and financial policies, the &quot;financial colonization&quot; of its country, and allowing the Federal Reserve to control Argentina&#39;s economy. For setbacks, the public emotions are easily reversed in the Latin American environment, which makes the initials of the policy that put forward this policy into a shortage situation. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Not only that, because of the poor credit reporting of Argentina&#39;s international credit, it is unknown whether the Fed that has become &quot;priority in the United States&quot; in recent years. They also pointed out that &quot;currency dollars&quot; may control the rise, but they cannot solve Argentina&#39;s fiscal predicament, and the latter is the foundation of Argentina&#39;s economic and financial predicament. In fact, in the speech, Miller did avoid the slogans that had repeatedly shouted before and again before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is unknown whether the privatization of the public service industry and the privatization of large state -owned enterprises, because refusal to fulfill the promise offending many voters and continue to bear heavy financial burdens, but it will definitely cause &quot;smashing&quot; but it will definitely cause it. The violent social turmoil, how to choose, is difficult to decide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are two recognitions that are not listed in the campaign commitment, but they must do: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One is to try the reorganization of international debt again. Therefore, the sound of not the same thing is because the left wing is also doing this when the left wing is in power; Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner is likely to be sent to court and even prison after steps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many analysts believe that, given that the party affiliated to Miller is only 10%of the seats in the Argentine Senate, only 5%in the House of Representatives, and the &quot;Common Reform Alliance&quot; is still a minority of parliament, and rice is also rice, and rice is also rice, and rice is also rice, and rice, and rice, and rice Laiben was also very unrealistic in the parliament (it is said that he only participated in the co -signs of a draft law during his time as a member of the parliament), and many of his too radical and highly controversial campaign commitments will face different degrees of &quot;discount dumping&quot; in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 09:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[融创完成900亿元债务重组，保交楼压力仍在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261096]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Sunac Beijing, a real estate in Beijing. Visual China/Picture&quot; SRC = &quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8707716b.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8707716b.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259327 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Sunac Beijing A real estate. Visual China/Picture &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After 18 months, Sunac China (01918.HK) overall resolution of about 90 billion yuan in debt risk, and all domestic and foreign debt reorganization was completed. The real estate industry ushered in the first large -scale real estate company to complete debt reorganization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 20, 2023, Sunac issued an announcement that the conditions for overseas debt reorganizations have been met and officially took effect that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the announcement, the existing debt of the creditors will be replaced with new bills, mandatory convertible bonds, convertible bonds, and Sunac Services (01516.HK) stocks, respectively. $ 100 million, US $ 275 billion, $ 1 billion, $ 775 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, three products: new bills, mandatory convertible bonds, and convertible bonds are expected to be listed on the New Stock Exchange on November 21; Sunac Services has been transferred to the planned creditor&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the second half of 2021, more than 50 listed real estate companies have launched debt reorganization. In May 2022, Sunac&#39;s debt defaults, and the domestic debt restructuring was completed by the end of the year. &quot;In the next stage, the company&#39;s focus is on the insurance delivery building.&quot; An insident of Sunac told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Sunac can also be saved&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The information provided by the above insiders shows that after the reorganization of Sunac&#39;s overseas debt, it reduced by about 4.5 billion US dollars (over 30 billion yuan) debt In the scale, the annual debt repayment pressure dropped by nearly 2.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the debt reorganization, the first bill after Sunac&#39;s first exhibition expired in September 2025. At the same time, the company has the right to extend it for one year. Pastening window for nearly 3 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, the company can choose physical interest in the previous two years. In the first year, it can fully capitalize interest. In the second year, you can choose to support only 2%of cash interest (the remaining part of the interest capitalization), which reduces it. The company&#39;s overseas cash payment pressure within two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned insiders introduced that the restructuring plan received more than 98%of the creditor&#39;s rights at the Credit Party Conference in September 2023 and high votes for more than 99%of the number of creditors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xie Yifeng, Dean of the Chinese Institute of Urban Real Estate, analyzed the reporter from the southern weekend that housing enterprises usually need third -party help, such as financial institutions, central state -owned enterprises, overseas capital, etc. , Guarantee the principal and interest income of the creditor. Only in this way can we get the exhibition period and avoid liquidation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the explanation of the overseas debt restructuring telephone number on March 29, 2023, Wang Mengde, Executive Director and CEO of Sunac&#39;s Executive Director, introduced that some loan exhibition projects are actively striving for financial institutions such as banks and other financial institutions. Asset management companies) and other third -party funds to solve the difficulty of financing such as trusts and other interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the WeChat official micro -news, Six banks led by SPD Bank, China Huarong (02799.HK), and CITIC Trust jointly injected capital to Sunac&#39;s Shanghai Dongjiadu project, with a scale of over 12 billion yuan, the first stroke, the first stroke The funds were put in January 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned insiders introduced that since 2022, Sunac has obtained a total of 19 billion insurance delivery funds, and has cooperated with AMC with AMC to get new financing over 20 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xie Yifeng believes that Sunac&#39;s successful debt reorganization reflects that the creditors and third -party institutions believe that &quot;Sunac can be saved&quot; after evaluating its assets and debt. Confidence in the real estate market. Compared with other thunderous real estate companies, Sunac&#39;s debt scale is relatively small and the quality of assets is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in his opinion, Sunac&#39;s debt restructuring is of limited significance for other housing companies. Due to the different assets and liabilities of each housing enterprise, the &quot;one room, one policy&quot; is required to evaluate. Such as Country Garden (02007.HK), Ocean Group (03377.HK), and Jindi Group (600383.SH), as well as housing companies that are also facing debt pressure, the application period is not successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The target of 300,000 sets of insurance buildings in the year &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that the completion of debt restructuring only means that Sunac lifts short -term debt risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after the window period is over, Sunac is still facing a test. &quot;As long as there is no recovery in the real estate market, the company does not sell the payment, and there may be debt defaults such as business tickets.&quot; Xie Yifeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He explained that Sunac is currently only on the exhibition period of domestic and foreign bank loans, bonds, etc., but the business tickets for the payment of the project funds are still not small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sunac&#39;s midterm of 2023 shows that as of June 30, 2023, the company&#39;s trade and other payments should be 274.1 billion yuan and contract liabilities were 292.6 billion yuan. This means that Sunac&#39;s owed suppliers and owners who did not accept houses were nearly 600 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xie Yifeng analyzed that in the environment of real estate downside and market cold, if you want to solve the debt risk at this level, companies can only adopt three types of exhibition period, housing, or introduce new shareholders to develop development to develop development. Way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The primary point of the next step is to speed up the sales repayment.&quot; Xie Yifeng said that once there is a problem with the sales repayment, it is easy to occur in arrears of engineering funds and business ticket defaults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On February 22, 2023, Sunac Released the Company was included in the announcement of the person who was incorporated into the dishonesty. The reasons for the fact that the business tickets that are not equal have not been paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xie Yifeng believes that after the debt reorganization, real estate companies still need to open source. While developing financing channels, deal with negative assets, reduce scale, reduce land acquisition, and reduce the pressure of capital chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above-mentioned insiders of Sunac introduced that the company&#39;s consideration is to invest more funds and manpower in the insurance delivery building during the 2-3 years after debt reorganization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;As of October, we paid 205,000 units, ranking second in the industry.&quot; He said that the company&#39;s goal of 2023 was to deliver 300,000 units, and the task in 2024 was equivalent to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This means that in the last two months of 2023, Sunac still has nearly 100,000 houses for delivery. The insider admits that &lt;Span>; the company is still facing the delivery pressure and is relieved the pressure on funds through multi -party financing channels. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直击人性底线，大逃杀王者回归]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261053]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 23:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p data-mpa-popered The game &quot;Trilogy (a total of four films) is popular all over the world, with a cumulative box office of nearly 3 billion. Jennifer Lawrence, the&quot; big cousin &quot;of the heroine Katenis, has also become a popular star. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Although the drama film of the current fugitive theme is endless, it is undoubtedly a new thing to watch a group of young people fighting each other in a reality show. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4826dc0358db1fb014754cae12a9.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4826dc0358db14754cae12a9. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259108 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;&quot; Hunger Games &quot;has established a complete worldview setting: Shi Huiguo consists of a capital city and thirteen border areas. Life. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Ducheng has founded a hungry game with a fierce fighting. &lt;/Span>; Each district must send two (also called tribute) to participate in each district, and Killing is a TV show chased by the superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It has been eight years since the end of the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7fd5250b4cb6c5a2adda60824aae5f6aa.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1634 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7FD5250B6C5A2ADDDA60824aa.jpeg &quot;data-k&quot; ey = &quot;259110&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the positive, the elderly version of the elderly version of Donald Susselan is not angry and deep, and is a ruthless ruler. In the end, it was unable to stop the revolutionary boom of the resistance. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/da6705ab7be9297cbb1a459e9a7a6.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 861 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/da6705ab7bbb1a459E9FC0A7A6. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259107 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;&quot; The Song of the Bird and Snake &quot;pulled the timeline back to 64 years ago, and said &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; The teenager Snow &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (Tom Bryce) &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; blackened history. &lt;/span>; &lt;Span>; As a mentor in the tenth hungry game, he had to be responsible for his tribute -Girl Lucy from the 12th district &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Become a community of destiny. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the game of &quot;a glorious and glorious, a damage&quot;, they have gradually produced love, but how far can young and fragile love go? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6Fa493FF4D2C11376E14D.JPEG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6FA493FF4D9BBE8F7C64D. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259106 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; After the Song of the Birds and Snakes is released, the beans &lt;/span>; The petal score is 7.1 points, but the reputation is uneven. Although the title of &quot;Hunger Games&quot; is the title, it is a movie about people, focusing on the digging of characters, and despising the design of the game. Therefore, it is a little less entertaining and critical than the positive passage. The thickness of a single character. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; ——The number of spoilers below, if you mind, please read carefully- &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;pan>; The place is to make up for the former history of President Snow, which shows the slightly facial villain. There is a saying: &quot;If you know me before, you may forgive me now.&quot; If you understand the teenager Snow, you may add a little understanding to the old Snow. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; There is no whitening of Snow, but it does catalyze the audience&#39;s pity for him, especially under Tom Bryce&#39;s interpretation, 18 -year -old Snow It looks handsome, arrogant and pleasing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/baf3f1717660A5EB3DFA2F5F3EEG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1035 &quot;height =&quot; 436 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/baf3f1717660A5EB3F5F5F3EE1907. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259109 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Snow is the son of the general of the capital, but as the father&#39;s death family fell into a dilemma, he was dependent on the cousin and grandmother in the empty Chinese house. The nobility of the rack -like aristocracy. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The opening of the movie is an important day for the school to issue scholarships. If he has excellent grades, he will be able to go to college as long as he gets this money. But he can usually wear school uniforms. Important days are not enough. He lacks a clothes that can get a hand. Fortunately, the cousin&#39;s heart was clever. First, he used the reagent of the bleached curtains to treat the yellowish shirt, and then made a new button with a small piece of tile tile. Snow, who went out of his head, was as confident and proud as Scarlett, as he used curtains in &quot;The Beauty of the Chaos&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/92320b533d447c7ddbe810700F.JPEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 451 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/92320b533d8c7ddbe8107007e0f.j.j peg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259111 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; He talked with the classmates of the noble school to explain that he was sweating all because the driver could not send him to the school gate. (Half of it), and classmates who also came from the old money class contempt for the noble classmates who moved from the second district to the capital city. In just a few minutes, an image of a proud hiding inferiority, being necessary to gain anything, and accustomed to bluntness jumps on the paper. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Unfortunately, things are not as smooth as Snow want, the scholarship rules have changed. scholarship. Due to the personal grievances of his father, Snow was divided into a poor tribute -Lucy, who looked completely impossible to win. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/472FB5140AD446FF377597216CF0.JPEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STYLE = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/23/11/22/472FB5140AD446759721516CF0. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259113 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Snow is good at accepting facts, observing the world, and insight into people&#39;s hearts. He soon formulated a combat plan: performed in front of the camera, and used public opinion to build as much as possible. We may still remember that in the &quot;Hunger Games&quot;, Katenis and Pitter were supported by couples to get the support of the people of the capital. The essence of reality shows has always been &quot;show&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Snow himself &lt;/span>; Go to the train station to pick up Lucy, give her roses, hold her hands with her in the zoo cage, give her food supply, supplies her Encourage her to sing in front of the camera. Lucy, who is born in a blooming singer, is also well versed in the law of performance and is good at expressing emotions and ridiculous rules with singing. They are a great partner in the real sense, so the illusion of losing love is also very natural under the effect of hanging the &lt;SPAN>; bridge effect. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/799EFCC36F7D301C4A587E68443F2F6.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; STYLE = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 950 &quot;height =&quot; 633 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/799EFCC36A587E6844443F2F6. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259114 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The Song of Narut Birds and Snakes is divided into three chapters. The first two chapters are focused on the hungry game itself, but when the Lucy game is over, the beginning of the Snow game He faced fate rulings for unscrupulous means in the game. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;Span>; &quot;Snow Always Lands on &amp; Nbsp; Top&quot; Fate is returned, so he will be briefly deviated from the track, but once he has the opportunity, he will find the way to turn over. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/45EB4EC796D3Bace886e02d02d02d02d02D0.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 451 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/45EC796D3Bace886ead45E02D0. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259112 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; It is not comprehensive to summarize the&quot; Song of the Bird and Snake &quot;as&quot; the history of Snow Black &quot;. The description of how much the price is paid is also worthy of scrutiny. Judging from the information explained by the film, Snowr is an ambitious, cruel, paranoid, sensitive and powerful self -reliance. In the betrayal of betraying friends and leaving his lover &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, he torn off the elegant and decent mask step by step, buried the hidden heart of the young man, and finally returned to his original face. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d84e8f7ed303a2dcec5795C8F77BD148.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 1036 &quot;Height =&quot; 432 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/Image/23/11/22/d84e8f7ed303a2dcec5795777777777777888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888888. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259115 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The success of the role of Snow is the biggest highlight of&quot; Song of the Bird and Snake &quot;. His characters in a movie even exceeded Cagnisia in four movies, The latter is already a character described in the business blockbuster. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; However, in addition, &quot;The Song of the Bird and Snake&quot; is lacking. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; First of all, the highly controversial heroine, the newcomer Rachel Cizler is good at singing. After the Golden Globe Awards, with the &quot;Western Story&quot;, it is also a new version. The heroine of &quot;Snow White&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; In &quot;The Song of Narut Birds and Snake&quot;, she sings well, and her acting skills can only be &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; barely to see &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; The gap between the actor&#39;s affection for the act of the scene &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; extremely &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Ming &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; show &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Not the audience &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; blame, but compared with Jennifer Lawrence, she does have a long way to go. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/23d52F9A95D02FA380C909cbac.gif&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 245 &quot;height =&quot; 130 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/223d52F9A95D02F7B0C909cbac. gif &quot;data-key =&quot; 259116 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/68fdf8e7c843b4f6df1bb52a55E95B42.gif &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; OP acity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 545 &quot;height =&quot; 243 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/68e7c843b4F652A52a52.gif &quot;Data- Key = &quot;259117&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span>; (the picture shows the comparison of the same action) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;spn>; about the game of the game Settings, obviously the first 74th hunger game depicted in the first part is the best. Regardless of preparation preparation or actual combat, it is full of ingenuity, allowing the audience to be full of visual wonders. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; and the 10th hunger game in &quot;Song of the Bird and Snake&quot; is quite simple, or the indoor game of the stadium, which makes the series of action scenes proud of There is no room for exhibition. After watching, I only remember that a group of tributes hurriedly finished the game, and offered to the head one by one without any high -light bridge. The audience who runs away from the fighting game may be disappointed, because the movie is quite restrained by the presentation of miracles such as killing and violence. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8656582524cc7acd95bc6.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 451 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/86582524CC7AC7ACD95BC6. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259118 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; On the other hand, the Triple Trilogy&#39;s reflection on the reality show and the discussion of the revolution have no trace in&quot; Song of the Birds and Snakes &quot;. This may be the strategy of avoiding repeated self -repetitive self -regeneration, but it also blocked the possibility of digging into the depths of the text. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/9A1B55556ed3df477425DA4c.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 449 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/9A1B55556ed3df4774259CC065DA4c. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259119 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Therefore, if you want to find the criticalness and gaming experience of the&quot; Hunger Games &quot;series in the movie, it may be disappointed. But if you are interested in the character story, you can still see it. In this regard, &quot;Song of the Bird and Snake&quot; is indeed a little bit of strokes, which makes people suddenly be moved by the foreshadowing of fate. &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;Span>; When the old President Snow saw the rebellious girl from the 12th district, Katenis sang &quot;The Tree on the Tree&quot;, would you think of the younger youth. The loved man Lucy also sang for him? &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 18 -year -old Snow shoots crazy shooting in the foggy radon forest and destroying the corpse destruction of love I wouldn&#39;t think of this belated bullet and hit his eyebrows after several years. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离世四年，崔雪莉生前纪录片公开：被装进偶像模具的孤独灵魂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261090]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;img alt = &quot; Cui Xueli&#39;s in -depth interview with the documentary, at the age of 25, she frankly shared her inner feelings in the last day of her life. 11/22/adda255b2f.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 453 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/Adda255B2F. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259322 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;&quot; To Truth &quot;is a documentary carried out in a deep interview with Cui Xueli, 25 years old. In the last days of her life, she frankly shared her inner feelings. (Data diagram) &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Let&#39;s briefly introduce yourself.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Permail a lightweight opening problem opposite. The answer to this question can be the &quot;F (X) group Shirley&quot; and &quot;actor Cui Xueli&quot;. In front of the camera, the senior artist Cui Xueli seemed to be unable to accept this problem. She was silent and hesitated about nine seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I am Cui Zhen.&quot; He heard it peacefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared to &quot;Cui Zhenshi&quot;, in the Korean stream cultural circle, Cui Shi has a more loud stage name &quot;Cui Xueli&quot;. Binding with &quot;Cui Xueli&quot; is a sweet and pure face. In 2005, Cui Shinshi became a signing trainee of the Korean entertainment company SM, and four years later he made his debut as a member of the women&#39;s group F (X). Because of her fair skin and laughing, the fans called her &quot;human peach&quot; and &quot;pocket sister&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In front of the public, Cui Xueli maintained a sweet image. But she said that she was not a &quot;cute&quot; person, and she was far from the public&#39;s imagination of her &quot;pocket sister&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At some moment, she was doubtful about everything. &quot;I do what others ask me to do, but I don&#39;t know what the reason for doing this.&quot; She started to talk about a relationship that was not recognized by fans and family members, and passed the sexy style on her personal social platform. Conservative Korea&#39;s Pioneer Pioneer. Everything was known later: the turbulent criticism brutally hit her. On October 14, 2019, she committed suicide at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 13, 2023, four years after Cui Xueli died, Netflix launched her legacy &quot;To Truth&quot;. In this documentary, the interviewer talked to her about the pain and weakness of her years, as well as doubt and reflection in the star -making industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Treating every problem, she has remained silent and thought for a long time. In &quot;To Truth&quot;, she expresses the restraint of the entertainment industry. &quot;Do you know&quot; Nikita &quot;? Just like that movie. It can be said that we are all puppets. Who cares about we are tired?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;It is the worst of Korean idols. &quot;During the interview of the documentary, she bluntly said that people don&#39;t seem to think that celebrities are also people. &quot;When I first entered the entertainment industry, others kept telling me one thing, you were a product. At that time, I didn&#39;t feel ridiculous. You must be the most exquisite and class before the public.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt; p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;After debut for a long time, Cui Xueli maintained the public image of sweet and laughing. 11/22/02bebfc189.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 967 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02Bebfc189. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259323 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; After a long debut, Cui Xueli maintained the public image of sweet love and laughter. (Visual China Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;The only thing I can control is self -blame and self -degrading&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Before becoming an artist Cui Xueli, Cui Shi was born in Busan, South Korea. Parents were divorced when she was 7 years old. Mother raised three children and had economic constraints and needed to make a living in the labor market. At the age of Cui Zhenli, my mother thought that &quot;instead of sending to kindergarten, it is better to get to the (acting) college.&quot; It was the starting point of Cui Shi&#39;s life and the entertainment circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cui Shi has only a blurred impression of his father -a man who is always half lying on TV, but his attachment to his mother is deep. When I was a child, my mother was often not at home. &quot;Waiting for my mother every day is my job. I want to be a doll that is exactly the same as my mother.&quot; She said that the relationship between mother and daughter is like &quot;twins or two.&quot; &quot;I don&#39;t like green, it&#39;s not my favorite color. One day I asked her (mother), what color do you like best? She said it is green. I tell everyone that I like green.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In the art film &quot;4: Clean Island&quot; created by Shirley&#39;s personal experience, her mother was a image that died very early. She wrote a &quot;4&quot; on her young daughter&#39;s face with blood. Big, live as a butcher who kills pigs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why am I so unconfident in everything. I really remembered that when I was young, I couldn&#39;t remember the injury when I couldn&#39;t remember it, and I had a lot of affected me in my heart for a long time. Love. I did nothing but left my dad. I am afraid that if I do something wrong, I will cause trouble, and even my mother will leave. So there is always no self, only in favor of the opinions of my mother. &quot; Such a bare inner thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cui Zhenzhi became Cui Xueli because of a report. At that time, she was watched by Li Bingxun, the director of &quot;Da Chang Ghen&quot;, and was picked up to play the role of Princess Xiaoshanhua in &quot;Potato Nursery Rhymes&quot; among more than a hundred actors. The reporter who came to interview felt that the name &quot;truth&quot; Christian meaning was too heavy, and discussing the name. Later, when the report was reported, Cui Zhenzhi became Cui Xueli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cui Xueli was noticed by SM Entertainment. In the fifth grade of elementary school, Cui Xueli left Busan and started a trainee life in SM Entertainment in Seoul. A new life began, and after excitement, she also felt worried: &quot;Do you really want to live separately from your family?&quot; &quot;Can I adapt here?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; During the dormitory life, she is actually very very very very very good It is difficult to take care of your life completely. The mother later learned from the staff that because she washing her hair was not clean, Shirley often had a flavor on her head. Cui Xueli said before her lifetime that at the time, &quot;often seeing people&#39;s eyes, in order to survive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Just signed SM company, the company&#39;s training target for Cui Xueli was not a Korean idol, but an actor. At that time, Shirley had emerged in film and television works such as &quot;Potato Nursery Rhymes&quot;. When she graduated at almost elementary school in Seoul, she grew more than one meter or more. For children&#39;s actors, this is an awkward height. The figure is no longer suitable for children&#39;s actors, playing young people, and can not keep up with mind and experience. SM, a company sent by an idol group, placed her to another track: she became a member of the women&#39;s group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2009, Cui Xueli debuted as a member of the Korean women&#39;s group F (X). She soon was favored by fans with its outstanding appearance. From an actor to the idol, she faces another complete, accurate, and processed idol star industry. The Korean entertainment industry has a set of unwritten potential ideas. The level of actors is higher than idols. The actors have more autonomy, and idols must be cautious in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As an idol, Cui Xueli has an attitude towards fame. &quot;I understand what it means to mean, but I am also very scared. I always think this is a bubble. Turn around. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Before the age of 20, Cui Xueli was endured everything that&quot; beautiful &quot;brought to her -the fans of the crowd and the love of fans. South Korea&#39;s entertainment reporters evaluate her appearance, and even if she leaves the team, she can suck fans by beauty.但她同时也感到被外貌困住，“每次别人夸我漂亮，我都很想知道，他们为什么要那么说……我感觉自己一定要漂亮下去。我甚至因为举止不够漂亮而被人数落过。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“真理，你好像是受到了严格的控制和约束。压力这么大，你是怎么应对的？”在纪录片《致真理》中，访谈者提出疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我唯一能控制的事，就是自责和自我贬低。”她回答道，“唯一能让我感到自己有控制权的时候，就是在我让自己痛苦时。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但那也太痛苦了，人忍受痛苦的能力有限制。也许问题在业界本身，不一定是你的问题。”访谈者说，“这也许不是你的错。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;镜头前，崔雪莉的眼眶一下子湿润了。她把头仰高，故作轻松地说：“没有。”随后面对镜头，露出标准的微笑，问：“我能笑吗？”她有些哽咽着说：“我没有这个选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说，自己一直戴着名为“逞强”的面具，常常“假装没事”，“我总是不愿表现出自己软弱，我感到难为情，我经常有这样的羞耻感。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在采访的间隙，她不止一遍说，自己把这个采访“搞砸了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;崔雪莉出演个人真人秀节目《真理商店》。（资料图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d9d7e03505.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/d9d7e03505.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259324&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;崔雪莉出演个人真人秀节目《真理商店》。 （资料图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“一个人被留在这世上的感觉”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;20岁那年，崔雪莉决定打破偶像的假面。她计划做两件事，第一件，给自己找个心理治疗师，第二件则是跟别人约会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在很多人看来，那个粉丝和大众买账的雪莉“人设”，就是从恋爱后开始崩塌的。以前，外界将她的形象固定在对邻家妹妹的想象。恋爱消息爆出，她的交往对象是嘻哈团体Dynamicduo的成员崔子，比她大14岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“第一次恋爱传闻，本身就很敏感，对于爱豆来说。第一次恋爱传闻对象是谁真的很重要。所有人都在关心雪莉的第一个恋爱对象。”TVDaily记者金智贤在MBC的一部纪录片中说，“问题就是年龄相差太多的崔子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;母亲金秀静坚决反对这段恋情，母女两人甚至因此决裂，不再往来。在金秀静看来，那是这个家庭不幸的起点。 “在爆发恋爱传闻之前，我们家人都是幸福的。一直都是。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;粉丝也对这段恋情不满。恋情爆出时，正值f(x)的发展黄金期，恋爱影响团队发展。一些粉丝在舞台现场的视频里发现，崔雪莉有时舞蹈动作没到位，怀疑她是在“划水”。金秀静透露，从那时起，女儿已经患上了忧郁症和恐慌障碍，“粉丝就在眼前欢呼，其中有好话，也有坏话。要边听这些，边在舞台上表演”。雪莉去世后，金秀静回到空荡荡的房子，发现了不计其数的、远超普通人消化能力的药物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管崔雪莉在这段恋爱中感受快乐，但两人交往期间，崔子因新歌《吃做睡》中较为露骨的歌词而引发争议。 2015年，崔雪莉正式退出了f(x)组合。 2017年，两人宣布分手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“（我）因他人受过伤，当时整个人就崩溃了。因为有这些人，我可以有所依靠。藏在他人身后，我也能感到正能量。但是跟我很亲近的人，周围的人逐渐离开我。因为他们也是懦弱的人，他们只顾照顾好自己。我也想过请求帮助，但当时他们，没有伸出手。”崔雪莉说，她有一种“一个人被留在这世上的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离世前的几年，崔雪莉在社交平台上发布的很多内容被指责“出格”。往嘴里喷奶油的视频被网友视为带有“性意味”；和朋友聚餐，醉酒时的窘态被认为是“疯了”；和密友聚会的照片中，一群男男女女快乐地拥抱着，引致“吸毒了”的怀疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的一举一动都被留意，媒体爱起一些吸睛的标题，每次一有新动向，辱骂性的恶评就涌进新闻链接。一次直播，友人读出围观者的一条评论：来直播间，就是为了看看崔雪莉又做了什么奇怪的事情。她被很多人称为“关种”，意思是：爱博出位吸人眼球的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于年轻的崔雪莉来说，这些汹涌的恶意、质疑不容易招架。在一段视频采访中，崔雪莉笑着，像在求饶地对着镜头说：“观众朋友也请疼爱我一些吧，记者们请疼爱我一些吧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我真的不是坏人。”她在很多场合下都这么说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;崔雪莉最初以童星身份拍摄影视作品而进入娱乐圈，后来被打造成偶像团体成员，她曾多次表示，自己更想成为演员。图为电影《Real》剧照。（资料图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/b8ebb939ad.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/b8ebb939ad.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259325&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;崔雪莉最初以童星身份拍摄影视作品而进入娱乐圈，后来被打造成偶像团体成员，她曾多次表示，自己更想成为演员。图为电影《Real》剧照。 （资料图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;可贵的叛逆者&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2019年，崔雪莉的状况看上去好了一些，沉寂了很长一段时间后，她参加了《真理商店》和《恶评之夜》等综艺，公开行程多了起来。同年，她发行了自己的第一张专辑《Goblin》。那年6月，在第一次个人专辑的发行纪念粉丝会上，她对台下的粉丝说：“我会认真活下去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4个月后，她在独居的家中结束了自己的生命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2019年的韩国综艺《恶评之夜》上，一头粉发的崔雪莉逐个回应这些年来，网友加诸她身上的恶评。她谈到一直围绕在她身上的“no bra”争议，很自然地和主持人谈起自己对内衣的理解，“内衣就像配饰”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当我第一次发布没有穿内衣的照片时，很多人都在谈论它。我很害怕，本来可以隐藏起来，但我没有隐藏。原因是我想改变人们对此的偏见。我还想说，这没有什么大不了的。”她说，“我认为这关乎个人自由。内衣对健康并不好，它们有钢圈，对消化器官不好，我的消化能力也有问题。不穿它们会更舒服，所以我就不穿它们了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雪莉去世后，有外媒评论，身处一个“鼓励表演者在台下保持沉默的行业”，她以一个可贵的叛逆者形象存在着。在韩国，偶像作为商品的另一个潜在共识在于：偶像不要谈论时政，不要对社会事件发表言论。但崔雪莉一次又一次选择打破它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在性别观念相对保守的韩国社会，她很多公共表达都显得先锋。她说要摆脱“月经羞耻”，在综艺里对男主持人说，如果你支持男女平等，那你就是女性主义者。 2019年4月11日，韩国废止堕胎罪，她是为数不多公开表示支持的女性公众人物。在当天的instagram上，她发帖称：“今天真是光荣的日子，还给所有女性选择权。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在社交媒体上做的那些事，都是因为想做才去做。我的行为和意识在根本上跟那些支持女权主义的人是一致的。女人不应该那么做、女人不应该大声说话或者意见鲜明，这种观念与我的为人相悖。我不喜欢他们说的话。男人可以公开谈论性、他们的欲望或者不满，会因为在这些方面直言不讳而得到称赞。但如果女人也这么做，就会被认为粗俗和自以为是，从而遭到斥责。”在纪录片《致真理》中，崔雪莉回应道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“事实上，雪莉一再做厌恶女性主义者不喜欢的事情，并且拒绝道歉，这才是她真正受关注的原因。”雪莉去世后，印第安纳大学韩国文化与社会专家CedarBough Saeji在接受CNN采访时说，“仅仅因为她以不完全符合韩国社会规范的方式展现个性，社会就如此严厉地批评她，这真是令人难以置信。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她去世前不久，有朋友接到她的电话。朋友回忆，雪莉的声音听起来比糟糕的状态还要更糟一些。她说，自己感到很孤独。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长久以来，崔雪莉对周边的归属感和安全感有需求。 “我从一开始，就不得不直接进入复杂的现实世界，结果很多事，我都不明白。导致我想找到一种归属感。还有伴随归属感而来的那种稳定状态。”纪录片里，访谈者问她最在乎的人是谁，她说是f(x)的成员们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一次视频采访中，f(x)成员luna说，自从雪莉退团后，她们有五年没有见过。雪莉曾有一次主动联系她，给她发来短信：“姐姐，我想姐姐了。”那是她们认识15年来，雪莉第一次用平辈之间的半语，而非敬语和她Speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以感觉是忍了又忍之后才发过来的短信。作为姐姐，我感到抱歉，我应该先走向她的。”luna在镜头前哭着说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在与母亲断绝往来、爱情告吹、脱离团队、被外部世界批评的“不稳定状态”里，崔雪莉待了不短的时间。有时候，她开直播，和粉丝交流，有时表现出近乎躁动的兴奋，有时又陷入恍惚，眼神几乎失去了神采。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;崔雪莉参与了专辑《Goblin》中所有的歌词创作，其中有一首名为《月亮上》，歌词里或许藏着她的真实心绪。歌词这样写道：“让我们一同/坐上银河铁道999/如今想要永远成为/ 的快乐女孩/你的快乐女孩/在我沉睡的梦乡中携着人偶/将我美梦中的恐惧赶跑/肩上的小人接过我的回忆/轻松带走抹上我的色彩的纷飞/深夜之中怀着对书中世界的迷恋/将这副冰冷躯体的自由带走/阻止住妈妈双手合十的祈祷/登上月亮”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，f(x)组合的五个人去新西兰拍综艺，在当地共同埋下了大家成年后的第一个时间胶囊。十年过去了，崔雪莉再也没有机会打开它。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;（主要参考资料：Netflix纪录片《致真理》；MBC纪录片《雪莉哪里让你觉得不舒服》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年少时的心灵创伤如何疗愈？愿大家都能被温柔以待]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261049]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;南方周末App上受到读者热议的《&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260544&quot;>;&lt;u>;孩子被欺负，该打回去吗？谈谈我对孩子的勇气教育&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;》一文，让我回想起我曾经的懦弱并再次思考，当我的孩子被欺负时我该怎么做。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前的一天，孩子回来告诉我，有一名同学总是会在排队的时候踩他的脚，户外活动时频繁推搡自己。我问他，告诉老师了吗？孩子说告诉了，但是对质的时候对方又说没有踩，然后就不了了之了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想了想，能想到的办法就是远离他。 I said to my son, if outdoor activities watching him approach you, you quickly stay away from him. The son laughed and said tired. Ask me if I did n’t defend it, I dumb, I wanted to say to him randomly.这句话的潜台词就是踩回去，我没说出口。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过了几天，我去接孩子放学，特意早早过去，排在第一位，接到孩子后我就在一旁等着。等到那位孩子的家长出现，我走过去给对方妈妈说了下情况，对方妈妈态度很客气，说自己孩子有时候会“人来疯”，喜欢黏糊别人，说回去再说说。过了些日子，我问孩子最近有被踩吗，孩子说成功躲了几次后最近没有，他去踩别人了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我最早的有关欺凌的记忆，是乡村小学校园的厕所里，几个孩子围堵着一个正在小便的同学，有人手中拿着小砖头，有人在活动着拳头，好似做好了随时挥出去的准备。那个时候，我常常是胆怯地上完厕所赶紧走出去，偶尔外面无人时，我会大声叫喊“老师来了”，然后赶紧跑走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候欺凌者或者受害者的家庭都没有明显的差异，唯一明显的是，受害者如果来自城镇会更可能有父母来学校为孩子抱不平，而来自农村家庭的受害者大都不会受父母的重视，一是他们忙于农务，二是他们觉得那种小打小闹属于正常，不值得一提，除非有严重性的身体受伤，他们才会来学校找老师反馈。当然反馈的结果的好坏取决于能否遇到一位公正严明的班主任，而不是和稀泥。至于心灵创伤，在二十年前的村镇学校，几乎没有人听过这样的词汇。这样的忽视，让受害者的记忆会变得刻骨，即使数十年后也会因为某个因素被唤醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么多年，我依然记得十年前看过的一部日剧《家政妇三田》，在异国的作品里，我找寻到了一些人性共通的情感懦弱。剧中一家人在吃饭时，观看了一则小学生被欺凌后选择轻生的新闻，引起了一家人的讨论。讨论之中小儿子被问及有没有被欺负，他选择了隐瞒否认。正在读幼儿园的小女儿问三田，为什么有人会欺负人呢，三田面无表情地回答，那是因为人类是脆弱的动物，欺软怕硬，回答得尖锐而刺耳。小儿子在经历了被同学威逼协作作弊，最终在被威逼偷窃的时候，他选择请求三田的帮助。三田的“暴力”帮助让男孩陷入了更严重的威胁和亲人老师误解的困境之中。面对更严峻的欺凌威逼时，小儿子再次寻求三田的“暴力”帮助。这次的帮助上升到死亡威胁，在与欺凌者的对抗中，小儿子完成了思想的蜕变和醒悟，他及时制止了三田，与对方进行了男孩之间的对决。那一声声控诉话语让人戳心，但这些血泪诉说并没有让欺凌者有所改变，让人唏嘘不已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回想我幼时遇到的欺凌，通常的解决办法是承受或躲避，大都是熬过分班或升学。所以，当我的孩子也遇到类似欺凌时，我的心里没有太多备选答案，抛出的解决方案老旧而迂腐。当我向有孩子的朋友询问，如果你的孩子被别人欺凌时，你希望得到什么，她说能够自由沟通不被外界因素裹挟，她说得含蓄隐晦，我知道她害怕的是遭遇不公。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实案例中欺凌者走向善良的太少，拿盛产校园欺凌剧的韩剧来看，那些剧的模式大抵会走向“爽剧”模式，即最后以暴制暴，受害者最终抑制住了暴，施暴者受到了法律的制裁，而现实的情况往往是双方都走向了悲剧的深渊，很少出现我们期盼中的正向结局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幼儿受欺凌的创伤能得到治愈，除了小概率的自愈，另一部分是受到了其他同学的温柔以待。孩子每天回来会分享自己在校园里的开心，除了偶尔诉说被谁欺负之外，更多的是分享得到谁的帮助，例如谁分享给自己一个驱蚊手环，户外活动时谁帮自己把忘拿的水壶拿回教室，等等。那些在很多大人眼里觉得微不足道的举动，恰恰从小建立了孩子们之间友爱互助的情感，每每此时我会顺势告诉他，当别人遇到类似问题恰好你也能提供帮助时要给予帮助，这样的举动无形之中会在对方的心里生根发芽开花。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年少时的伤害或者救赎的影响往往会是一生的，这在很多现实题材作品中得到了验证，很幸运我至今还留有一段温暖的记忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十五年前，我读高二，那年有一个小高考，提前考几门，需要从镇上坐车两个小时到市里。那之前我还没坐过长途车，一上车就开始晕车，直出汗，头晕目眩。那辆中巴车上有十几个座位，大部分人需要站着。当时我旁边的女同学很快发现我的异样，两位女生站起来让我躺卧在座位上，拿出清凉油给我涂抹。那样的温情至今想来都让我觉得暖心，她们的举动让我在很早的时候就开始学会并拥有了同理心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果要去比较我与上一辈父母在孩子遭遇欺凌上的进步，那大概是我的第一反应是问孩子哪里受了伤害，而不是质问孩子为什么对方欺负你而不是欺负别人。 However, my father and I have the same dilemma. In addition to letting children avoid bullying, there are not many routes and methods for us to choose calmly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系文化行业工作者）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多所高校督导学生坐前排：不提高“教风”先要求“学风”，属本末倒置丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261057]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期，多所高校开展“学风”建设，督促学生上课“坐前排”引发关注，有的学校规定前排未坐满记最后一排违规，令人咋舌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河南省新乡医学院从11月20日开始在全校范围内开展学风专项督查，督查不带教材、不做笔记、不提问题、不坐前排“四不” Phenomenon. Henan Institute of Technology requires the establishment of a &quot;supervision -development&quot; system, focusing on checking students&#39; classroom &quot;class rate, head -up rate, and seat entry rate in front row.&quot;长沙理工大学交通运输工程学院要求引导同学主动“坐到前排来、把头抬起来、带着教材来、提出问题来”……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这事儿给人的第一观感是，把大学生当小孩子对待。除了要求大学生带教材、坐前排、做笔记之外，不乏有高校要求学生上晚自习不能待在寝室，还有查寝、查卫生之类。 In fact, in addition to professional courses, students in the same class may not take the same lessons, and different classrooms used in different lessons are not the same. They do not have a fixed classroom and position like junior high school students. Why do college students be trained like children, and cannot respect the self -determination of adults? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本人二十几年前上大学的时候，犹记得大家占位置的方式有两种。对于老师学养好、讲得精彩、受欢迎的课程，前排会首先占满，后来的人只好坐后面；对于老师表现平平或不尽如人意、讲得比较干瘪、不太受欢迎的课程，先来的人会占后排，后来的人只好坐前排，忍受老师的直接注目，还不得不假装在认真听讲、做出积极回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前一种方式就是对好老师的勋章。后一种方式，往往是因为虽然这门课没有意思或讲得很差但也不想挂科，或者因为任课老师要点名考勤而不得不应个卯，但留得住学生的身留不住学生的心，学生会以消极的方式进行抵抗。所以有的老师往往在第一堂课就说：来去自便，不点名，但作业不做、考试不及格责任自负。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，对老师而言，其首要的使命是靠自己深厚的学识、精湛的讲课技巧把有价值的专业知识与技能转授给学生，是吸引学生而不是强迫学生接受自己的授课内容。 Good spiritual food is full of fragrance. Tao Li is not talking, and it is self -contained; the twisting melon is not sweet, and it is meaningless to stubbornly press the water. These principles are well known, this is also the basic way of teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，教师与学校只能反求诸己，自我要求有很好的“教风”，把学生折服；而不是首先要求学生具备某种理想的“学风”，对教师授课能力反而没有什么要求。这纯粹是本末倒置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;讲课明明是照本宣科，乏善可陈，还要学生像听受欢迎的课程一样坐在前排，强迫学生抬起头做出认真听讲的模样，装模作样地进行互动，剥夺学生消极应付烂课程的权利，这简直是让学生在精神上受刑。而且，强求烂课程、差老师享受好课程、好老师一样的待遇，好比想把烂苹果、酸涩的苹果卖与好苹果、甜美的苹果一个价，完全是在挑战市场规律，也是在挑战人性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从经济学的角度看，高等教育或曰打包的专业学科知识产品与其他商品、服务并无二致，老师与学校是提供方，学生是需求方，双方在权利与人格上是平等的，并不存在一方可以无限度规训另一方的道理。合理的课堂纪律要讲，例如任何一个学生不能破坏课堂的安宁与进程，因为这损害了老师的尊严与其他学生的权益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但反过来，不能把要求大学生认真听讲确立为规则与义务，因为大学生是成年人。从利害的角度看，他觉得内容重要自会认真听讲，甚至课后还会进一步钻研，但他要是觉得自己已经掌握，或者这部分内容不重要，或者他低估了所讲内容的重要性而神游天外，只要不破坏课堂的安宁与进程，不应该视为一个需要解决的问题。从权利的角度看，师生之间有合理的边界，学生消极应付是基本自由，学生积极认真是挣得的（Earned)，不是应得的，让学生抢前排、占好位以得到极致的心智与精神享受，是老师努力的目标甚至可以说是本分。在这一点上，对待大学生与对待中小学生就应该不一样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于督查大学生带不带教材、记不记笔记，乃是无视大学知识传授的特点。只要上档次一点的高校，只要对授课有些追求的老师，一门课程，教材往往只是提纲与总括性质的，肯定要涉及大量的相关书籍与论文的阅读与讨论，某些课程除非照本宣科，否则看不出为什么所有学生一定要带教材；当然，如果教材本身是经典，值得逐字逐句深度研读，那学生一般应该带教材，但若有学生偶尔忘了带，也不是个事儿，与邻座的同学课堂上合用就可以完美解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果老师是照本宣科，则学生完全没有记笔记的必要；如果老师讲得特别精彩，那学生就会全神贯注，全身心投入去听，去汲取，去吸收，把老师的东西变成自己的东西，没有必要当堂笔记，以免影响在场吸收效果，事后归纳整理就可以了，还能进一步加深理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好的教风与学风就是尊重学生作为成年人的主权，让学生发挥个人自主性，提升个人自治能力，培植个人责任感。大学学习与中小学最大的不同是，大学生需要更多地投入思考，磨砺个人的理解力与分析力，学习一门专业，就是有逻辑性地把一个完备的知识体系建立在自己大脑中，成为主体性的一部分，记忆部分是相对次要的。强迫与灌输是没有意义的，学生真正思考透彻的东西才会变成他自己的东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;某大专院校教风学风建设，树立“医学影像检验与康复学院典型案例”，立三条规矩：“坐前排”，要求学生优先坐前排座位；“双汇报”，若前排未坐满，则由学委将最后一排同学名单记录，汇报给任课老师和辅导员。狠抓落实，让大家不敢违规：第一次：匿名通报其行为，要求其他同学引以为戒；第二次：要其在晚点名上公开检讨，班级成立专门队伍，跟踪检查；第三次：告知家长，再犯则需要来校沟通，或将“陪读”。坦率讲，这是管小学生的方法，而且是很糟糕的管小学生的方法，用到大学生身上岂止是不合适。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿光“明星”果蔬交易所被查，揭开“电子盘”风云二十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261073]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;寿光是全国最大的蔬菜集散中心。视觉中国/图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;寿光是全国最大的蔬菜集散中心。视觉中国/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被公安传唤后，钱莫友信上了周易。 He asked the reporter from the southern weekend to ask for birth information, and found a hexagram &quot;Master Zhou Yi&quot;. He learned that he had a fate with the reporter, and then he chose to meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其办公室相见时，他正往一个高约半米的敞口玻璃瓶里插花，花是修剪过的兰花。空瓶预示着“亏空”，凡是空的花瓶都得插满。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他人生中最大一笔亏空，发生在“寿光果蔬电子盘”。从2012往后数的短短四年间，他亏了数百万元。家庭因此分崩离析，人生曲线只剩跌停。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电子盘是舶来品，最早是指芝加哥商品交易所撮合交易的电子竞价平台。 In China, the electronic disk refers to the electronic platform of the commodity spot trading electronic platform outside the official futures exchange. At the beginning of its establishment, it was to promote the circulation of commodities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寿光果蔬盘诞生于2009年，次年迁入天津，由山东寿光蔬菜产业集团（天津）商品交易市场有限公司（下称天津交易市场）运营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寿光，是潍坊市代管市，也是全国最大的蔬菜集散中心。凭借“中国蔬菜之乡”的响亮名号，寿光果蔬盘一度成为颇负盛名的电子盘，代理商遍布全国，交易商众多。 Until May 2020, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Suddenly announced the stop of opening an account and deposit. In November, the company&#39;s entity was canceled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;余波更加汹涌。 In April 2023, Public Security in Jixian County, Rizhao City, Shandong, was investigated in the Tianjin trading market with &quot;suspected illegal operation crimes&quot; and took criminal measures for operating management teams and some regional agents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为寿光果蔬盘区县级代理商，钱莫友也受到牵连。 9月，他从所在地公安口中得知自己上了追逃名单，需要去莒县公安局交代情况，并上缴违法所得。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一位代理商告诉南方周末记者，他已上缴了两百万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电子盘的后续发展，脱离了当初设想。大批涉嫌变相期货、非法经营的交易平台关停注销。 “又是攻坚战，又是回头看，又是清理整顿，没有哪个行业像现货交易市场能持续清理整顿十几年。”商品交易场所创新服务联盟秘书长王在伟对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还介绍，全国交易场所鼎盛时期有一千多家，今天只剩两百来家，且这两百多家都是由国资控股、省级政府批准设立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾野蛮生长的电子盘，是否行至终局？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;靠代理商延伸的生意&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“早把他们取缔了，也就没有后来那么多人入市。”钱莫友回忆，介绍他开户的人曾信誓旦旦地说，其它盘一查就死，唯有寿光果蔬盘安然无恙，可见其正规。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是2012年，历经二十余年创业，钱莫友手头攒下一些资金，但公司面临发展瓶颈，正巧一位朋友介绍他到寿光果蔬盘投资。出于商人的谨慎与对农产品行业的陌生，他起初犹豫不决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朋友见他迟迟拿不定主意，便找来一位熟知寿光果蔬盘操作的老师。老师实际则扮演“喊单”的角色，指导钱莫友买入卖出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终，钱莫友在寿光果蔬盘的网站上注册成为代理商（可以开若干账户），一起尝试的还有若干亲友，当中不乏公职人员以及金融行业人士。 “他们见我资金量大，建议我注册代理商能够节约点手续费。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，寿光果蔬盘吸纳的应为从事农业的交易商。 However, according to the Shouguang Fruit and Vegetables obtained by the Southern Weekend Weekend, the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Period Spot Trading&quot;, account opening only needs to provide ID cards and bank card numbers, and there is a background of the agricultural product industry without providing certification materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;交易使用的软件界面与一般的期货、炒股软件无异，能看到价格走势K线图和集中竞价交易信息。交足20%的保证金，即可买入或卖出农产品合约。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;交易采用“T+0”制度，同一方向同一品种的合约当天可频繁交易。品种有南瓜、冬瓜、胡萝卜、辣椒干等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前期在老师的引导下，钱莫友有所小盈，于是投入资金越来越多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱莫友打出当时用于操作的几张银行卡的流水，大量转出账户为他本人，资金划转至天津交易市场。但钱莫友不愿拉人头，流水上少数想不起来的名字，是他向当时客户返还的手续费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与钱莫友不同，大部分代理商除了入市交易获利外，手续费更是主要收入来源。只有源源不断的客户在自己名下开户，引导客户频繁交易，才能给代理商带来丰厚回报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电子盘正是依靠代理商发展壮大。 For county -level agents such as Qian Moyou, 75%of the transaction fee for Shouguang fruit and vegetable disks generally return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据2011年的一份判决书，代理商崔某与寿光果蔬盘签订协议，对方委托其发展客户并给予客户交易手续费75%返点金额。崔某的下线王某继续发展客户可获得返点70%，王某继续发展下线李某并返佣68%，一周一返。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者以开户名义联系了寿光果蔬盘原郑州代理商，他现为另一农产品现货交易市场盛通九龙提供线上开户，把客户推荐到他这开户可按照日结返佣，获得该客户交易手续费的75%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;杀完多方，杀空方&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;跟着老师操作一段时间后，钱莫友初步掌握买卖逻辑。以土豆为例，对比盘面与现货价格，若现货价格高，则买多；若现货价格低，则卖空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他将自有资金分至二十多个账户，带着公司员工共同操作，每天交易挣下几个点，一天的工资就有了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但老师教授的方法时而奏效时而失灵。钱莫友的朋友中，有人苦研K线技术知识，在寿光果蔬盘，却一样派不上用场。入市四年，钱莫友“割肉”三四次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最狠一次“翻车”是在2014年的南瓜合约上。钱莫友根据现货行情做了空单，一开始还能挣几个点，大资金进来后，盘面不动了，之后一连几天打开网站就是跌停，突然又开始往反方向拉涨停。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了保住仓位，钱莫友不得不继续追加保证金，甚至找朋友借了钱，尽数投到盘里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入交割月后，钱莫友依据规定日期补足保证金。已经押上重金的他坚信盘面回归现货，不至于亏损过大，但最终结果是盘面价格与现货价格严重背离，这也让他动念到线下找货交割平仓。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快，钱莫友就联系到盐城的南瓜经销商，一番打听后，交割的想法也破灭了。盐城瓜贩看到交割协议约定的产品质量、外形、颜色等标准后遗憾的表示，规定太细，就是调集全城瓜农手里的瓜让他任意挑，都凑不出协议规定的货。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱莫友这才清醒过来，果断退出市场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“像你这样的，亏几百万都算轻了。”董杭戈操着一口浓浊的冀鲁官话说，听到钱莫友的遭遇，作为朋友的他忍不住Ridicule.董杭戈作为寿光果蔬盘的市级代理商，如今也被公安调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;董杭戈投资电子盘的经历比钱莫友丰富得多，他参与过著名的龙鼎盘，摸清楚了电子盘的门道——得跟主力资金反着买才能挣到钱. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这就是个虚拟盘，你懂吗？”董杭戈忍不住说破，你是真金白银，“坐庄”的人是一串虚拟数字。假设主力资金都在做多，那盘面就会往反向拉，逼多方割肉。只有猜对了方向，才能跟着挣钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，干代理商挣的是手续费，但光挣手续费还不够，还得帮着自己的大客户挣钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了探听盘面上的资金流向，董杭戈曾找来个年轻的大学毕业生，潜伏进客户资金量最大的市级代理商那里打听方向，他再指挥自己的客户往反方向Do.在一次土豆合约上，他手下的一个大客户挣了足足八百万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;董杭戈建议大客户见好就收，可惜，客户不知足。不出董杭戈所料，盘面杀了个回马枪，客户吃了的又吐出一大半。 “人家（庄家）杀完了空方，肯定回过头杀你多方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;接盘“寿光大蒜盘”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;前往公安局之前，钱莫友花了十多天找资料，研究自己为什么会“非法经营”。这才发现，现货交易市场曾是地方搞活经济、创新改革的产物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国期货市场创始人、原国务院发展研究中心研究员常清告诉南方周末记者，农产品生产分散，农户们需要能够反映市场供求关系的价格信号，以合理配置资源。 “寿光蔬菜批发市场能解决蔬菜流通，却难以解决&#39;菜贱伤农&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1990年起，中国陆续成立五大期货交易所，但大部分农产品未能进入期货市场。常清解释，大部分农产品由于可供交割量小，容易被操作合约（逼仓），因此不适宜进入资金量大的期货市场，但这些品种可由地方性平台或销地批发市场进行交易创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，寿光开始探索蔬菜中远期交易，相当于提前为农户锁定农产品价格，是一种介于期货和现货之间的交易模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年2月，经山东省政府批准，中国蔬菜流通协会等四家单位共同出资成立山东寿光蔬菜电子交易市场有限公司（下称寿光电子盘），可实现“未种先卖”“未收先卖”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时任寿光电子盘经理吴俊介绍，寿光电子盘将公布未来10个月采购价格，由种植户或经纪人在种植前将订单卖出，到期交上符合质量的货物，避免价格下跌给农户带来的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王在伟于2007年开始在山东运营大宗商品交易所。他告诉南方周末记者，早期大蒜品种交易量不错，参与的多是冷库老板、大蒜经销商和经纪人。这些人本身是现货型客户，通过电子交易只需要预付款就能实现买卖，节约了仓储和运输成本。 “（地方交易场所）存在的意义就在于能支撑现货客户的实际需求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但电子盘没有按照最初的设想运行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寿光电子盘真正开始名声大噪是因为大蒜，并因此获得一个更响亮的名字“寿光大蒜盘”。大蒜，又叫“白老虎”，虎能吃人，蒜亦能吃人，投资者一朝不慎则赔光身家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大蒜价格的高波动性，成为蔬菜品类中最适合投机炒作的品种。寿光虽是蔬菜之乡，但不产大蒜，2005年，寿光电子盘进入“蒜乡”——山东济宁市金乡县。到了2010年，金乡县已聚集五六家电子交易市场，其中规模较大的两家，除了寿光电子盘，就是龙鼎电子盘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当年的电子盘被视作电子商务这类新兴产业，很多地方政府都作为重点项目积极引进。” 山东省作家协会原副主席赵德发对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵德发在其纪实文学作品《白老虎》中写道，“蒜神”董自刚曾帮助寿光建立大蒜电子盘。一位大蒜商会会长评价，自董自刚加入行业后，改变传统贸易，引进资本运作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;董自刚是山东莒南人，定居潍坊，发迹于寿光大蒜盘，先后操盘金乡南店子、恒利盘，任恒丰电子盘总裁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电子盘还造就了一个神话——养猪出身的农民傅海棠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2009年3月，傅海棠将在豆粕期货上挣到的几万元投入寿光电子盘做多。正逢罕见的“蒜你狠”行情，寿光电子盘出台“集中转让”制度，即连续出现三个涨停板或三个跌停板就会协议平仓。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;傅海棠在自述中写道，当时的空头主力与交易所打了招呼，大蒜翻30倍的行情，他只挣了70万就被集中转让，于是他转战龙鼎盘，挣了600万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也正是这波行情，让龙鼎盘的空头错估形势，更拖垮了龙鼎盘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年，日照市副市长万同向交易商公布了龙鼎电子盘事件调查结果：龙鼎盘在大蒜行情巨变后，未按照规定对空头强平，反而借给空头主力侯大伟3000万虚拟资金做空，亏损后挪用客户保证金继续大肆做空，与交易商对赌，导致盘面价格与现货价格严重背离，上亿保证金亏空，交易商无法正常出金。且部分合约进入交割期后，仍有巨量未平仓单无法顺利交割，引发交割违约纠纷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事很快引发一轮监管风暴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证监会牵头7部委组成国务院大宗商品交易市场调查组进入山东，首站到达潍坊。 《中国经营报》报道，时任证监会主席姜洋检查潍坊的大宗商品交易场所后，拍案怒斥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此轮监管整顿前，不少电子盘因虚拟资金交易、交割不畅、创始人卷款跑路等问题崩盘，高管被捕入狱，但电子盘聚集的庞大资金仍令一批又一批的“赌徒”趋之若鹜。倒一个平台，就火一个平台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王在伟曾撰文称，2007年—2010年，山东涌现大量交易场所，形成“全国大宗看山东，山东大宗看潍坊”的局面。 “没批文，没审批，没监管，没规则，那时完全是敞开了干。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使拿到批文，也是靠平台各显神通，审批部门五花八门，“有发改委、商务局，还有金融办”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，江苏省盐城市公安局经济开发区分局将恒丰电子盘定性为变相期货市场，董自刚因此锒铛入狱，刑期十年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但寿光电子盘却活了下来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2009年，寿光电子盘被民企寿光蔬菜产业控股集团有限公司（下称寿光蔬菜产业控股）收购，后者由山东省寿光蔬菜产业集团有限公司（下称寿光蔬菜产业集团）出资设立。同年6月17日，寿光蔬菜产业集团成立寿光果蔬盘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据官网，寿光蔬菜产业集团入选国家农业产业化重点龙头企业500强，是全国知名的蔬菜全产业链运营商。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;转战天津&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“要么走，要么关。”王在伟说，姜洋的检查给潍坊政府造成巨大压力，当地的几家交易所被迫做出选择。寿光果蔬盘正是在这一阶段迁往天津，天津也成为全国各类交易所新的聚集地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寿光蔬菜产业控股相关负责人在接受自媒体“高倍镜”采访时透露，寿光果蔬盘受天津市政府邀请于2010年12月迁往天津，作为农业金融创新重点项目，落户滨海新区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“每个地区对大宗商品交易的理解及认知有很大差异。”王在伟说，这一阶段交易场所能否做下去，当地监管部门的态度至关重要，或者说起决定性作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着清理整顿趋严，交易所由各省级人民政府制定监管规则，有的地方政府将监管职责划给商务局，有的划给金融局。 “全国监管政策差别依然很大。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《经济导报》报道，2010年至2013年4月，寿光果蔬盘的职业经理人是姬海荣、孟庆超（不持股）。总裁姬海荣是寿光果蔬盘的灵魂人物，他曾供职于多地大宗商品交易所，圈内人更熟悉他的QQ昵称“大亨”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年年底，寿光果蔬盘也爆出电子盘逃不开的交收不畅问题。 2013年4月，姬海荣和孟庆超双双失联。后经媒体确认，姬海荣等人已被寿光市公安局采取强制措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，寿光果蔬盘在两位负责人出事后仍正常运营。他们的辞职公告中，亦称两人在职期间经营业务均符合国家相关法律法规。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在寿光果蔬盘运营的这些年，其历史股东包括寿光蔬菜产业集团、寿光蔬菜产业控股等，大股东均为杨明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨明颇为神秘低调，当地人也对他知之甚少。目前，仅能从企业官网上看到他的模样：顶发稀疏、额头锃亮，挺着啤酒肚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位市级代理曾参与过几次寿光果蔬盘的会议，见到杨明及一众高管。参会嘉宾皆是政府官员、期货领域专家，宣讲的是平台的规范性。会后，专家也会跟着领导们赴宴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;杨明控股的寿光蔬菜产业集团和寿光蔬菜产业控股，办公地点均位于寿光蔬菜大厦。南方周末记者周小铃/图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;杨明控股的寿光蔬菜产业集团和寿光蔬菜产业控股，办公地点均位于寿光蔬菜大厦。南方周末记者周小铃/图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;期货还是现货？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;像寿光果蔬盘这样的电子盘，是以现货交易市场的身份成立的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但北京寻真律师事务所主任王德怡告诉南方周末记者，寿光果蔬盘中，大量客户从事无实物交付的电子交易，以集中交易方式买卖标准化合约，最高人民法院多例案件以此作为“非法期货”的核心特征。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大宗商品现货领域，王德怡律师团队曾获得多地首例案件胜诉裁决，代理过多起寿光果蔬盘投资人与交易平台间的合同纠纷案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家住江苏的游智辉，是受访者中少数有过交割经验的投资人。大部分投资人由于未曾真正参与交割，不清楚寿光果蔬盘的交割仓库所在地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年开始，游智辉在寿光果蔬盘操作过一年半，但亏损了120万元。真正让他对市场丧失信任的，是次年的一次交割。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;交割前夕，游智辉收到代理商发给他的辣椒干提货单，落款时间为2017年3月1日，要求他在3月2日办理提货手续。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提货单显示质量等级为标准品，计量单位为78吨，交收仓库为德州武城县马营乡银山冷库。企查查显示，该冷库确有存储辣椒干。提货联系人为单永宁，他是天津交易市场的法定代表人。南方周末记者根据提货单上的联系人电话拨打过去，号码已无法接通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游智辉前往山东德州少说有七百多公里，搭上运输费运回江苏意义不大。为此，游智辉联系到几家当地的辣椒收购商一同交割，收购商验货后算好价格即可拉走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，问题就出在验收环节。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仓库交接方要求游智辉在交割日派车拉货，却拒绝提供产品入库信息，导致游智辉无法核对该批商品是否为合约约定货物，亦拒绝游智辉带收购商进仓验goods.仓库交接方甚至想以极低的价格收购游智辉的辣椒干。游智辉向交易市场提出复检申请也于事无补，最终交收失败。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王德怡接触过的大多数电子盘，无法清楚介绍客户资金流向，无法真实呈现交易场所的总成交量和实物交割量数据，同样也无法告知实物交付的客户数量和投资炒作number of clients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，频繁变动的价格实际上并不鼓励交割，投资者无不是希望通过点差赚取差价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;买卖标准化合约，也是期货的特征之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证监会对标准化合约有详细定义：除价格、交货地点和交货时间等条款外，其他条款相对固定的合约。合约订立后，允许交易者不实际履行，通过反向操作，对冲平仓方式了结离场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其他条款，是指交易商品数量、交易保证金、报价单位、交割质量标准等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我曾经对比（寿光果蔬盘）和郑州商品交易所的强麦期货合约文本，二者无本质差别。”王德怡说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管寿光果蔬盘的交易模式及交易细节均指向“期货”，但官司依旧打得艰难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大量关于天津交易市场的生效判决中，天津的法院未将其判定为非法期货。依据是，天津交易市场自国务院下发2011年38号文和2012年37号文后，未因违法开展期货活动、从事期货类交易等问题，被关闭、取缔或暂停交易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天津第二中级人民法院曾受理董玉美与天津交易市场买卖合同纠纷案。在二审判决书中，天津交易市场提交证据显示，2012年后，天津市清理整顿各类交易场所工作领导小组组织开展交易场所监管年审工作，天津交易市场名列《通过监管年审的交易场所名单》第14位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者致电寿光蔬菜产业控股，希望约访相关负责人。接电话者自称综合办公室工作人员，表示无法传达采访诉求。其后南方周末记者前往公司位于豪源路上的办公地寿光蔬菜大厦，但遭到门卫的拦截。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了天津交易市场外，寿光蔬菜产业控股还在四川、山东等地设有同类型的大宗商品交易平台。其中，北川羌族自治县的交易所于2021年注销，青岛的两家运转至2023年，南方周末记者近日探访时，发现其团队均已撤走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;南方周末记者探访了青岛两个交易平台，从保安和前台人员口中获悉，青岛交易市场的工作人员5月被警方带走，青岛汇海于9月撤离青岛康大财富中心的办公室。南方周末记者周小铃/图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;南方周末记者走访了青岛两个交易平台，从保安和前台人员口中获悉，青岛交易市场的工作人员2023年5月被警方带走，青岛汇海于9月撤离青岛康大财富中心的办公室。南方周末记者周小铃/图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“种地的不炒盘，炒盘的不种地”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;农产品现货交易市场承载着期货专家的改革期待和地方政府的产业愿景，但这场长达十余年的产业创新究竟发挥了多大的作用？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者前往寿光最大农产品物流园——寿光地利物流园，询问了十多位农产品批发商，是否了解寿光果蔬盘，大多数人听完后便摆摆手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我看这个市场没人知道你说的这个东西。”甄玲是黑龙江人，生于1980年，在物流园从事南瓜批发二十多年，咧嘴一笑神似喜剧明星贾Ling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她坐在偌大的交易大厅里刷着剧，时不时回复客户消息。她的客源相对固定，中午12点左右，在她摊上询价的人并不多。她告诉南方周末记者，物流园最大的作用就是能够完成产品分级和转运，来自全国各地的蔬菜都会在此中转再发往全国各地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自认南瓜行家的甄玲，对南瓜市场的行情撑死能看二十多天，“看一个月顶天了”。农民都在赌，看天吃饭，可能哪天突发一场大水，降下一场霜冻，地里的东西就全毁了，没有人敢去预测半年后的事，也预测不来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但农产品的价格波动也会形成波动规律，这两年行情都很差，第三年差不多也该涨了。这也不用去预测，大家都能看明白。作为一级批发商，甄玲从不畏惧价格波动，“有涨有落我们才能挣钱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;甄玲也会跟南瓜农户直接打交道。对南瓜种植户而言，不管行情贵贱，该种还是会种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寿光各个县都有特色农产品，农户会把自家大棚的果菜拉去县里批发市场销售，批发商也会根据需要前往不同的县进行采购。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高明家住寿光西南部的孙家集镇，这里也是冬暖式蔬菜大棚的发祥地，寿光“菜王”王乐义就住在孙家集镇的三元朱村。孙家集镇以种植黄瓜、苦瓜为主，家家户户的大棚都是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于对农产品的了解，高明“囤菜”已有十多年，他曾多次到金乡囤大蒜、蒜薹，价优的时候再卖出，相当于“二道贩”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于寿光蔬果盘，高明有所耳闻。村里不少人都曾在大蒜盘上做过交易，但做电子盘的这拨人不一定是农户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“挣钱快，赔钱也快，行情跟现实有差距，农户也不会看这个。”现在“囤菜”行情也不好，高明也搞起了大棚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到被公安找上门后，钱莫友才跟过去做过寿光果蔬盘的人建立了联系，大多是像他这样没有农业背景的人，“种地的不炒盘，炒盘的不种地”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，钱莫友、董杭戈、游智辉、甄玲、高明为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>