<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[今年各级政府支持就业创业资金超2000亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height=&quot;1337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/06/ca3f8f60d0301d53d89777184b559ed5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257144&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters from the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security Learned&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year various types of funds from governments at all levels&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Direct support for employment and entrepreneurship has exceeded 200 billion yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adjustment and optimization of employment stabilization policies&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Continue to implement the return policy until employment is stabilized&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to expand from absorbing employment subsidies&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To promptly restart the one-time employment expansion subsidy&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accelerate the release of policy dividends&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Injecting strong impetus into employment growth&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10.22 million new jobs were created in urban areas across the country&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Complete the full-year target 85% of the target&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national urban surveyed unemployment rate at the end of September was 5%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lower than the same period in 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment situation has generally improved and remained basically stable&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《莫斯科行动》，没写进报道的那些事丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260011]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Is there anyone else you particularly want to interview now? I was asked this question. I tried to count them on my fingers, but there seemed to be only a few. Qiu Litao may be one. I&#39;m looking forward to it after watching &quot;The Bomb Disposer 2&quot; at the end of 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be able to create a huge allegory with big scenes of banging, banging and jingling bells, allowing the audience to take what they need and understand each other, is an amazing creative power. I wonder how this person recognizes his own expression. But Qiu Litao is obviously not someone who can talk about this. This may be a bit embarrassing for him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, when asked questions that are too serious and strict, he will usually say &quot;I didn&#39;t think so much&quot; and &quot;I can&#39;t make a movie if I think so.&quot; For example, when it comes to anarchism - which he corrects to anarchism - he says that the definition is too vague and he doesn&#39;t know what everyone is talking about when they say these words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao definitely does not &quot;think so little&quot;. This is my feeling when I watched the movie &quot;The Decameron of Sex Workers&quot; directed by him. Regarding the young lady&#39;s situation, the mockumentary had a lot of back and forth, flashes of swords and swords. They are not expressions of &quot;pretentiousness&quot;, but are full of market acumen, speculation and ridicule. It&#39;s quite clever, but also quite embarrassing, like someone has taken off your clothes. Qiu Litao doesn&#39;t like clear things. From a utilitarian point of view, he is of course more tolerant of gray and vagueness. You can call him rough, but there are so many things that help him enrich his semantics. Who can I ask to explain? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first watched &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, I liked the sense of relaxation - many things that others have to put effort into laying out - such as whether this character is convincing or not, whether he resembles that era or not, it is not Qiu Litao Something that can be confusing. His camera flicked by, and his lack of restraint even formed a style. But that’s it, sometimes it works sometimes... I want to explain to readers that I don’t think this is a very good movie, although it is not without its merits. For example, the audience can see people and people in the early 1990s in the cinema. society. One of my interviewees felt that Qiu Litao might need a good screenwriter to help him overcome the cultural barrier of making films outside of Hong Kong. This is a tolerant statement, and after completing the reporting and writing of the report, I am willing to give a tolerant understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/13SYS5YmyGVuj4bGxkvkIf2IOrSdDSHff9ePADsI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; uses many details to restore the social scene of the early 1990s. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Qiu Litao has leg problems and walks with a long stride, but he works hard enough to make People ignore this. People should be able to understand this feeling. When we were young and could not travel far away, the TV was a magical door at home, which could take us to different countries and distant starry skies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the interview, I wrote an email to Director Qiu Litao and asked him to introduce the interviewees. He felt that it would be a bit embarrassing for him to come forward and tell his partners, &quot;The media did an exclusive interview with me, and I would like to interview you to talk about my story and working methods.&quot; But he listed the right names and ways I could contact them. This is not his responsibility. I am grateful for his understanding and sympathy for media work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I interviewed the main creators behind &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, such as the producer, screenwriter, action director and assistant director. In addition to talking about Qiu Litao, I also talked about their own work. Some stories that couldn’t be written into the main manuscript, I wanted to record in my notes. I hope I live up to their expectations and time, and I hope this information is useful to readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When screenwriter Chen Daming received the invitation from Chinese Pictures, he heard that multiple versions of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; had been written. Chen Daming is familiar with that history. In the late 1980s, he stayed at the Beijing Film Academy to teach. During the period when &quot;trafficking&quot; was most popular, most of the people lining up in the hall of the film school and making phone calls were not talking about art, but reselling color TVs and jeeps. The most successful business was selling MiG fighter jets - this last detail was written into the film. The character played by Andy Lau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What he wanted to show in the script was animality. &quot;People don&#39;t care about anything when they are hungry.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain Miao Qingshan played by Huang Xuan is nicknamed Old D. He likes to listen to Shostakovich&#39;s music. There is not much metaphor in this setting. Originally, Chen Daming wanted to call him Lao Bei, referring to Beethoven, but it didn&#39;t seem to fit him, so he wanted to find a Russian composer. One day he met a neighbor in the courtyard, an Englishman who was a conductor in China, and recommended Shostakovich. Chen Daming feels that his works have &quot;black elements&quot; and &quot;seem to be fighting against black forces and evil forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/1UzsbDxuEWrLGNM0sdTAxlACAAWlPL6k3vCo1lXv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257131&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scene after the Shostakovich concert in the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, action director Li Zhongzhi was filming with Jackie Chan , there is no script for the scenes he is responsible for, just one word, play. Now the action scenes have to be integrated with the plot of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Gui Youming made great efforts to introduce me to the team of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The art designer Zhao Hai has worked on &quot;Ming Dynasty 1566&quot; and &quot;Toward the Republic&quot;, and one of the computer special effects production teams has worked on &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. With the help of a digital imaging technology referred to as DIT, Gui Youming can see the shooting scene from anywhere with his iPad. Because of this technology, producer Andy Lau was able to follow up on-site shooting every day in the quarantine hotel at the time. Gui Youming believes that this is a characteristic of the industrialization of the film industry. This technology is very helpful when shooting movies of a scale similar to &quot;The Wandering Earth 3&quot; and &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/xdO8Gm1cHBefBRYjvmfZYStXrnvVoBjj8g5yGJHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As the producer of the movie &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, Andy Lau (left) relied on high-tech communications to improve work efficiency during the filming of the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao was particularly impressed by the scene at the international train track-changing station interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deputy director Wen Zhenwei contacted the National Railway Administration and got back a lot of information. Qiu Litao was not concerned about the ins and outs and technical details of the train&#39;s track change at the Sino-Russian border. He only wanted to know where the people on the scene should be and how they reacted when the different carriages were raised. For example, that is when the flight attendants are most busy and when passengers are most curious. Few people have seen the train changing tracks at the border. At this time, the robbers rush in. &quot;It is a good timing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vasily, played by Andy Lau, has many fake passports. The fake name on one of them is Wen Zhenwei, which is the name of the assistant director. In order to avoid misunderstandings about the real names, the names of the staff will be used as much as possible when making movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Daming once saw some photos in National Geographic magazine, taking pictures of abandoned rocket bases around the world. He especially hopes to film a crime-related gunfight scene in such a place in the future. There is such a scene in &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. Gui Youming said to Zhao Hai, have you ever seen a movie called &quot;Oriental Condor&quot; (there is a similar scene in the film), I want to make it bigger than that. . So they referred to a lot of information about abandoned Russian rocket bases. &quot;I remember that day Uncle Zhi (Li Zhongzhi) came to the scene and said, &#39;What are you doing? Why is it so big?&#39;&quot; Gui Youming warned that we must make full use of this scene: &quot;Blow up here and there, run around, inside and outside Use everything, don’t waste it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Chen Daming, the earliest draft of the script ended with a courtroom scene. Vasily was sentenced to 5 years in prison, suspended for 2 years. Policeman Cui Zhenhai patted him on the shoulder and said, if you look back, Vasily saw his daughter. In the original script, the daughter was 15 years old and attending a technical school. The daughter looked at her father from a distance, nodded, and that was how it ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao made major changes to the ending. In addition to adding the scene of the rail-changing station, he also changed Vasily&#39;s ending to one in which he was blinded due to a gun accident. Chen Daming thinks that there is a bit of blank space in this ending, and many people are guessing whether the daughter Vasily met at the end is real or fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[流连菖蒲河的老人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpIRG4hA5NAwK4U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;781&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Y95SxHpqoVDODMKhW252L4T8FmpI RG4hA5NAwK4U. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256659&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The social stage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-October, the ancient trees along the Changpu River in Beijing are still lush, and pairs of wild ducks inhabit the dark green stream. Every Tuesday and Saturday, when the sun is at its strongest, the classical promenade in Changpu River Park is filled with elderly people looking for partners, and the golden light spots add romantic vitality to them. The red wall of Huangshichen blocks the busy traffic of Chang&#39;an Street, bringing the park a secluded space suitable for romance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t expect a successful match based on true love.&quot; This is the sincere warning to latecomers from an old man who often comes to parties in Changpu River Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman in her fifties, dressed in an emerald-colored Tang suit and with exquisitely braided hair, refused to communicate with any of them in depth after an afternoon of ballroom dancing with a few uncles, and stayed alone. The pillars of the gallery rest. Asked why she wasn&#39;t looking for a partner in Changpu River Park, she said she wasn&#39;t looking because &quot;the blind dates here come with various conditions, and people are sold like livestock.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A bald man in his sixties who always wears gold-framed sunglasses from Beijing has been here for 15 years. He can freely blend into any dating gossip and naturally bring together any interested couple. men and women. But when the other party&#39;s ambiguous signal reaches him, he always laughs at himself: &quot;I won&#39;t look for it. I have no money. If I don&#39;t have money, I can&#39;t find the right one.&quot; With a 14-square-meter bungalow and a retirement salary of more than 4,000 yuan, he always Can extinguish the other person&#39;s enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changpu River Park has been criticized by the elderly, but it always has the magic to tie them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During a conversation in the corridor, it was like a default etiquette to ask each other about houses, household registration, salary, and medical insurance information. No one wants to be dragged down, everyone is rushing to get better conditions. After a while of &quot;greetings&quot;, there is a more detailed matching of needs. As long as you stay here for a day, the old people will not help but tell you that there are only a handful of people who set marriage registration as their goal; there are not a majority of people who are sincerely looking for a long-term wife. Maybe what the other person wants is just an ambiguous opposite-sex friendship or an extramarital affair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is a common and decent ending to look down on each other. We can also become nodding friends - old acquaintances who say &quot;here we come&quot; to each other. And getting along emotionally involves the risk of paying for lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a week of official dating, his girlfriend asked Uncle Zhou to use his savings to buy her a gold ring worth 20,000 yuan. Uncle Zhou emphasized that &quot;that is pension money and cannot be touched.&quot; Afterwards, they broke up, and Uncle Zhou kept blaming himself for being a fool. Sister Qin met a man in his sixties in the park. During a video call at 9 o&#39;clock one night, other women vaguely appeared in the other party&#39;s kitchen. &quot;He didn&#39;t tell me at first that he had a relationship with more than one woman. I didn&#39;t like that he kept talking about sexual matters between men and women all day long.&quot; Sister Qin blocked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical temporary union occurred between a Northeastern woman in her fifties and a Beijing man in his seventies. One needs wealth and shelter, the other desires youth and care. After a period of time, there will always be a reason to bring an unhappy end to the relationship due to the ownership of the house, differences in consumption concepts, and the opposition of the man&#39;s children. After they broke up, the woman thought she was cheated of sex, and the man thought he was cheated of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changpu River Park, some people can adapt to this &quot;exchange&quot; rule, while others find it chilling. Uncle Chen, 63, has a monthly rent income of 30,000 yuan. After ending his romantic relationship with a woman in her forties, he always took the initiative to compensate her with something, whether it was a big meal or a red envelope: &quot;Why should I let you, an old man, take advantage of me?&quot; Uncle Zhou would say Lamenting under the street lights at night, &quot;This place is like a microcosm of society. There is true love, but too little. Everyone has lost faith and only has the word &#39;profit&#39; in their eyes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who complain, People who have been deceived, people who are ready to break up, and people who seem to be watching indifferently will eventually return to the Changpu River. They persuaded the elder sister who was eager to be a matchmaker and register information for the elderly: this place is too chaotic and not a serious place to find a partner. They themselves are willing to be trapped in chaos. They always come here on Tuesdays and Saturdays to chat, strike up conversations, dance, and play cards. An old man riding a bicycle claimed that he was not here to fall in love, but on the blind date day, he would shuttle back and forth between the east and west gates of the park to observe and inquire around. He pointed to the winding corridor and said: &quot;This is the big stage of society. (I am here) to see how these people perform here wearing masks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Late release&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>; Geng Tielin wears a peaked cap and a mask and often hangs out in gathering areas where Northeasterners gather. He is from Harbin. He is 1.76 meters tall, well-proportioned and lean, and his posture when climbing up the river is brisk and flexible. It seems hard to believe that he is already 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m not looking for a date, I&#39;m just here for a walk. Besides, as a tall guy like me, I don&#39;t have to worry about no one liking me.&quot; Geng Tielin is confident in his charm. When he comes to the park, he just needs to stand there and many women will come and add their WeChat messages. He will approve the application out of politeness, but the only people he is interested in are &quot;tall, good-looking, and under 60&quot;; the only people he agrees to get along with are people who don&#39;t covet his money and &quot;don&#39;t want this or that.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his chat history, there are three women in their fifties who he calls &quot;sisters&quot;. When chatting with other elderly people in the park, Geng Tielin referred to them more as &quot;friends&quot; - people who can meet up to eat, travel, and sleep in the same bed without binding each other to a fixed identity. The sisters came from a well-off family and never asked Geng Tielin to bear any expenses. He sent a wedding red envelope to the son of one of his sisters, but the other party politely returned it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since his divorce 35 years ago, Geng Tielin has never had a long-term girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When my wife left, my daughter was only 5 years old. In order to raise his daughter, Geng Tielin worked as a driver, a chef, and opened a breakfast shop to help her get admitted to a graduate school in a Beijing university. The daughter found a job in a bank in Beijing, and the old father moved to Beijing with her and cooked in a factory canteen in Daxing. Geng Tielin was very proud when talking about his daughter who bought a house with an area of ​​more than 80 square meters and a value of more than 6 million yuan in Chaoyang District with an annual salary of one million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Tielin said that he had not touched a woman for more than 20 years after his divorce. The biggest reason is that he doesn&#39;t want the shadow of his &quot;stepmother&quot; to hinder his daughter&#39;s growth. But he has desires - physiological desires that cannot be channeled and are born at the wrong time. In those days, having sex outside of marriage was considered hooliganism. Geng Tielin did not dare to tell anyone, so he could only hold back or solve it on his own. &quot;It&#39;s such a shame, I was so miserable during those twenty years.&quot; After the millennium, he gradually tried to date different women. Sometimes it’s a hotel clerk you meet while driving, sometimes it’s an acquaintance whose husband is crying to him about his loss of sexual function due to cerebral palsy. However, no romance has turned into a stable relationship. Geng Tielin believes that it is impossible for him to ask others to adapt to his &quot;bad habits.&quot; Worrying about his daughter and raising a family, he often stayed awake all night, pacing back and forth and scrolling through his cell phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, he suddenly took off his peaked cap and showed me that his almost smooth head had only short, gray and sparse hair, dotted around the ears. At this time, he became a 65-year-old man. &quot;Our family has good genes, and no one has ever lost their hair. My grandfather was lying in a coffin at the age of 90 with black hair. It was because of his insomnia in those years that my hair became like this. I also want to have a wife to love, and have My wife loves me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The frugal and chic single life is also what Geng Tielin enjoys. He refused to live under the same roof as his daughter and rented a house of more than 20 square meters in Yanjiao to live alone, paying only 400 yuan in rent per month. Sauce elbow is Geng Tielin’s specialty. The price of raw materials in Yanjiao is only half of that downstairs in my daughter&#39;s community. Geng Tielin feels that now is the best time in life. His daughter has a future and he does not have to worry about raising his granddaughter. He is in good health and lives a comfortable life. There is no new partner to divide one&#39;s salary, but there are tender greetings and the joy of traveling together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On National Day two years ago, while wandering around, Geng Tielin accidentally discovered Changpu River Park. Although the elderly people here &quot;have their own thoughts,&quot; the situation of single elderly people is very similar to his. Even if he can&#39;t find a satisfactory &quot;friend&quot;, Geng Tielin still likes to chat here. He said he was not lonely at all, and his life of walking in the park and recuperating at home was well arranged. He also said that after his daughter got married, she was too busy and made fewer phone calls than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I met Geng Tielin, a slender lady with wavy hair reaching her waist, wearing a silk scarf, took the initiative to sit next to him, and the two talked and laughed. When I met him for the second time two days later, he said he wanted to delete the other person. According to him, the two went on a date to visit Zhongshan Park, and the man paid for the trip. Naturally, the lady ordered an extra bun, and asked Geng Tielin to buy the &quot;Pulse&quot;. She also insisted on asking for a 50 yuan hat in the scenic spot. Three more days later, I saw him for the third time. While chatting, Geng Tielin suddenly held his chin in a daze and murmured to himself: If there is someone better than those sisters, he will fall in love with her, and he will live with her wholeheartedly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/e8cogyRmvajkybIRrQGv2uXKSw6k6uCbfIXVnKjA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Live life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compare calamus Among the other well-dressed ladies in He Park, Zhang Ming&#39;an&#39;s clothing is obviously pragmatic. Her short hair was dyed jet black but didn&#39;t appear to be trimmed carefully. The upper body is a warm but bloated dark blue fur coat, the lower body is black pants and black shoes, and a styleless cross-body bag hangs casually in front of the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In just one hour by bus, Zhang Mingan can go to the park from his home near Tiantongyuan. At 9:30 a.m. on Saturday, the elderly people who live further away have not yet arrived. The promenade of the park is a bit quiet. Most of the people here are local Beijingers like Zhang Mingan who live in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, Zhang Mingan also wanted to find a local who lived in the city to be her wife, but it was obvious that she had not met anyone she was satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Beijing gentleman communicated with her back to back for a while, then turned and left. She pouted and looked at the other person&#39;s back, and said to me during the interview: &quot;You have a wife, why are you here? Aren&#39;t you Huo Huo&#39;er (Note: Beijing dialect, spoiling, destroying things)? What have I become?&quot; &quot;The uncle&#39;s legally married wife has been living abroad for a long time, and he has participated in the Beijing senior dating program &quot;Choice&quot; three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Mingan’s words, these are all “fancy” relationships. At the age of 62, she has only one simple request, which is to find a wife who can &quot;live&quot; with her and spend the last twenty years of her life together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingan has no children. In her thirties, she underwent surgery to remove uterine lesions due to uterine lesions. After that, she divorced her first husband. At the age of 50, she found a partner with whom she could travel around the world, Lao Fang. Zhang Mingan told me with a smile that in the past 10 years, they had participated in affordable tour groups and visited the United States, Thailand, Japan and South Korea. When she was 60 years old, Lao Fang died of pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took more than a year to get out of depression, and Zhang Mingan figured out that he should live for himself. I danced and played ball with the retired sisters from my workplace, watched anti-Japanese dramas, and kept my house tidy. &quot;If you can&#39;t move, go to the nursing home. Just make sure someone collects the body for you. There is no need to find your wife.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Zhang Mingan realized the vulnerability of being alone. After she was infected with the new coronavirus, she lay alone on the sofa at home. The coffee table and water glass were very close to her, but she was too weak to reach the water. She was thirsty on the sofa all day. She really hoped that there was someone beside her who could give her some medicine and make some porridge. &quot;If I can&#39;t survive, you will take care of me. If you can&#39;t survive, I will take care of you. Be sincere and support each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I am a good helper in life.&quot; Zhang Mingan thinks so. Fried pancakes, baked pies, and steamed flower rolls are all here. Neighbors said she had a mysophobia, her home was always clean, and she would pick up even a trace of hair on the ground. Neighbors also said that Lao Fang was really lucky because he could not move after being ill. Zhang Mingan was always there to wash his feet and cut his nails every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Mingan can never find anyone with whom he can live a good life. When I went on a blind date at an agency, the other person kept talking about how he owned more than a dozen houses. Zhang Mingan pointed out that she didn&#39;t believe it and didn&#39;t want it. There were many outsiders at the sorority, which did not meet her expectations in choosing a mate. After coming to Changpu River Park, the people who came to ask her were either people with wives, or people who were just dancing or just having fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of offline dating platforms is also a problem. Zhang Mingan recalled that he needed to pay 1,000 yuan to register for an introduction at a wedding agency in Changping. In Dongcheng District, the price is more than 10,000. After the Changping family registered, a year passed between the first and second matches for her. Offline gatherings are more efficient, but she only knows the daily gathering locations at Changpu River Park on Tuesdays and Saturdays and Temple of Heaven Park on Sundays. Zhang Mingan also hopes that in offline activities, household registration, marriage, property and other status can be authenticated by real-name authentication to reduce unnecessary communication costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;679&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/EWM4alxMBNhzjWDtoUFM8tTX44Hr2o0HEsXGzgwN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Imazins/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Obsession&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In In the dating circle of Changpu River Park, the reputation among outsiders, especially women from outside the area, is not very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to some people, they left their hometown in their fifties and hoped to establish themselves in Beijing. They dragged their luggage to the park as soon as they got off the train and were willing to live with an old man if he gave him money and a house. The condition is to undertake all housework. An old man from Beijing told me that he once met a beautiful 39-year-old woman from other provinces. After the woman found out that he was from Beijing, she immediately expressed her intention to marry him - this was to obtain a Beijing household registration for her son. She said that it would be easier for her to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University for the Beijing College Entrance Examination. According to another uncle, a woman from another province always talked about the conditions for bride price, which made him feel a huge gap in concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the hearts of locals, even if not all foreign women who come here are like this, the four words &quot;ruthless and profit-seeking&quot; are secretly engraved behind this geographical name card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hongzhen, who comes from out of town, seems to be able to accept this label openly. Her friend Meng Shuying from Inner Mongolia hopes to find a long-term partner with a foundation of love in Changpu River. Wang Hongzhen hates that iron cannot be made into steel: &quot;Her idea is impossible to find here. While I am still in good health, I will make money when I can. It is impossible to find a long-term life here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The money she talks about is working as a nanny in the man&#39;s house with a salary of more than 3,000 yuan. Before August 2023, she lived in the home of an 88-year-old professor in Beijing until his daughter took him to the United States. In addition to doing housework, Wang Hongzhen accompanied him to buy groceries, exercise, go to the park, listen to him talk about history, and help him bathe and rub his back. They stayed alone under the same roof for two years, and Wang Hongzhen couldn&#39;t tell whether this was considered emotional or whether he was considered the other&#39;s wife. But she thinks this is no longer important. &quot;Making money is the main priority, and the objects are secondary.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15 years ago, Wang Hongzhen, like her friends, was eager to regain marriage and happiness through the platform of Changpu River Park. . This dream was later shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2000, 41-year-old divorced Wang Hongzhen came to Beijing with his two sons to work hard. She has opened a beauty shop and worked in an agency and a travel agency. In 2007, when Wang Hongzhen was still a flower in Changpu River Park, he met a widowed water plant manager here. The other person was about the same age as her, tall and handsome, and the two fell in love. But under the strong opposition of each other&#39;s children, they could not go on. Every year when Wang Hongzhen returns to Beijing from his hometown, he will bring a souvenir to his former lover to express his gratitude. During her most difficult time, he helped her rent a house and see a doctor. The relationship with the second partner was not as intense as the first, but the relationship also ended due to the fear of the other partner&#39;s daughter. The story that followed was not sweet. One year after Wang Hongzhen registered her marriage with a man, he dumped her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, in Wang Hongzhen&#39;s eyes, the men in Changpu River Park are all people who trick people into sleeping and then kick the woman off after having enough fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her obsession became having an independent residence in Beijing. With his own strength, Wang Hongzhen cannot buy a house in Beijing. Living with her eldest son in Dachang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hebei Dachang Hui Autonomous County&lt;/span>;), she had to take care of the housework for the family of five. &quot;They are too busy at work. I take care of the two children for walks, cooking, and laundry. I will get sick after living there for three months.&quot; Working as a nanny is actually a kind of rest. Another consideration of Wang Hongzhen is, &quot;Now that I am in good health, I don&#39;t want to trouble my sons by living in their house. If you have conflicts over time, how will you find someone to help you when you get older? How unjust.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;If he must form a male-female partner, Wang Hongzhen’s requirement is: first of all, he must have a place to live in Beijing. Second, either register the marriage and ask her to move her household registration to Beijing after two years; or do not register but give her a sum of money every month. She said that with a Beijing household registration, you can apply for affordable housing even if you get divorced, and you can reimburse medical expenses in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An uncle sent Wang Hongzhen a tender invitation to dinner. She always had a premonition that the other party was trying to cheat, so she threatened him back: &quot;You register your marriage with me now, write down my name in the house book, and I will marry you.&quot; Eat, or else you&#39;ll fall down.&quot; The uncle on the side blamed her for being too domineering: &quot;You have to have an emotional foundation before talking about these financial contributions, otherwise how can we call it love?&quot; Wang Hongzhen smiled and did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are always more people on Saturday night than on Tuesday, and the elderly don’t have to rush to pick up their grandchildren from school. After 6 o&#39;clock, the sky turned dark blue, the dance music at the end of the corridor was still playing, and the banquet had not yet come to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I met an interviewee who appeared on Chen Xiaonan&#39;s show &quot;Talk to Strangers&quot;. It was this program that unearthed the senior dating corner in Changpu River Park and exposed it to the media spotlight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This interviewee is not as high-spirited as in the show. He admitted that in the 6 years since the show was broadcast, he has been searching here and had several relationships, but he still has not found his ideal partner. He said, &quot;On Tuesdays and Saturdays, the Changpu River, on Thursdays, Zhongshan Park and Taoranting, and on Sundays, the Temple of Heaven Park. The same group of people go to every place.&quot; This has become a place where old people check in to work. Even if you can&#39;t find someone, it&#39;s better to spend time together than to be alone at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are all old people. Maybe one day, one of them will no longer be able to come.&quot; During the conversation, an old man suddenly tripped while going up the ladder. The interviewee and several younger people around him were relatively young. The elderly man hurriedly ran up to help him up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(To protect the privacy of the interviewees, the characters in the article are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《老友记》钱德勒一生对抗毒瘾：美国“鸦片危机”有多严重？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260017]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 28, 2023, the actor who plays Chandler in the famous American sitcom &quot;Friends&quot; Matthew Perry was 54 years old and died of suspected drowning in a hot tub at his home in Los Angeles. Local law enforcement said &quot;no drugs were found at the scene and there were no signs of foul play.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case is still under investigation, and no drugs have been found at the &quot;scene&quot; yet, but this does not mean that there is no drug abuse background in this case. In fact, Matthew has been addicted to alcohol and drugs since the first season of Friends in the mid-1990s. In his memoir &quot;Friends, Lovers and the Big Terrible Thing,&quot; he said: He has been fighting drug addiction his whole life, during which he was near death twice, costing him as much as $9 million (equivalent to 65.85 million yuan). But he was still defeated in the end. At the worst point, he swallowed 55 pills of Vicodin (opioid analgesic) every day and drank 1 liter of vodka. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Very similar to this incident, on February 11, 2012, the 48-year-old American singer Whitney Houston suffered a heart attack due to a drug overdose at the Hilton Hotel in Beverly Hills, Los Angeles. After losing consciousness, he slipped into the bathtub and drowned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier, on June 25, 2009, American rock star Michael Jackson suffered a heart attack after his personal doctor Conrad Murray injected him with a fatal dose of propofol (a short-acting intravenous anesthetic). die. Prior to this, Jackson also used a large number of painkillers and anesthetics for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the banner of these big-name celebrities taking drugs, Americans are taking drugs and abusing addictive drugs extremely seriously. According to the classification standards of the National Center on Drug Abuse Statistics, there are eight main types of drugs: alcohol, marijuana, cocaine, heroin, fentanyl, methamphetamine (methamphetamine), opioids (controlled psychotropic substances), and prescription stimulants agent. The United States accounts for less than 5% of the world&#39;s population, but uses 80% of the world&#39;s opioids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC): Among the approximately 280 million Americans aged 12 and above, there are approximately 31.9 million drug users. On average, 1 in 12 people takes drugs, accounting for 12% of the total number of drug addicts worldwide. On average, about 300 people die from drugs every day, and drug abuse kills 100,000 people every year, of which about 71,000 die from fentanyl abuse. The number of deaths caused by drugs is eight times that of Americans who die from gun accidents, far exceeding the number of Americans who die from AIDS, car accidents, and gun accidents. Of the total number of deaths, 70% were men between the ages of 25 and 54. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2022 report of the &quot;Joint Economic Committee of the U.S. Congress&quot; pointed out that the abuse of opioids caused nearly 1.5 trillion US dollars in losses to the United States, accounting for about 7% of the GDP that year. In 2022, compared with before the outbreak of the &quot;new crown epidemic&quot;, the United States will lose about 6.3 million labor force, about 20% of which are caused by drug abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regardless of the loss of life, economic losses, social security, moral corruption... the United States has fallen into a large-scale, long-term nationwide &quot;opium crisis.&quot; Unlike the disaster in the late Qing Dynasty from 1840 to 1842, the Americans&#39; &quot;opium crisis&quot; did not involve external force invasion. It was completely directed and acted by them: the youth group is the age group with the fastest growing number of drug addicts and the fastest growing number of deaths in the United States. 18 -The drug abuse rate among people aged 25 years old is 39%; among people aged 26-29 years old, it is 34%; and 70% people who have tried illegal drugs before the age of 13 have a clear trend of drug use at younger ages.这一趋势显示出：传统的美国价值观正在崩溃，正如李光耀在《中国与世界》中谈到的“美国精神”的消散。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国“卫生与公众服务部”前副部长表示：当前美国毒品和药物滥用是最具破坏性的公共卫生灾难之一。这场危机是美政府多系统监管失败的反映，急需紧急、统一、全面的应对措施。美国“全国公共广播电台”（NPR）痛陈“美式自由主义”酿成了美国的悲剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导致毒品泛滥的“新自由主义”（New Liberalism），又称进步主义，乃是极左意识形态。其与古典自由主义是截然对立的，后者所主张的自由是在不妨碍他人权利前提下按自我意志行为的权利，没有法律就没有自由，私有财产不可侵犯，每个人为自己的行为负责。其主张的自由是：不受任何限制、不承担任何后果的行为，即“想做啥就做啥、想咋做就咋做”，最好还由政府或社会来埋单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美式自由主义，从1960年代开始通过性解放、性放纵、吸食毒品、颓废文艺等手段，在西方掀起诸多“进步主义”社会运动。持续几十年至今，导致了婚姻和家庭逐渐土崩瓦解、毒品泛滥、犯罪横行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国“鸦片危机”的祸根却难以根治，美警方曾谈到：如果按东方社会的严厉禁毒措施，那就得处决超过百万毒贩，把美国监狱全部腾空再扩容十倍，用于强制戒毒。但这在美国和西方社会，是根本不可想象的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国民主党政府搞“理念创新”：把吸毒合法化，不算犯罪，那么涉毒犯罪率不就下降了吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是把毒品区分为“硬毒品”和“软毒品”，对成瘾性、危害性稍微低些的，如大麻，在美国的31个州被允许合法使用（医用）、10个州允许合法使用娱乐大麻。然后，俄勒冈州通过了“110法案”，成为美国首个将持有海洛因、冰毒、可卡因等“硬毒品”非罪化的州：持有少于1克的海洛因、摇头丸，少于2克的可卡因、冰毒，少于12克的裸盖菇素，少于40剂的致幻剂、羟考酮等情况，将不再被视为犯罪，取而代之的是100美元罚款或健康评估。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一理念创新“成果显著”，美国《国会山报》2022年8月28日报道：盖洛普民调显示，吸食大麻的美国人数创下历史新高，首次超过了吸烟人数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了“硬毒品”和“软毒品”分阶段走的策略之外，美国制药产业还推出了“阿片（鸦片）类处方药”策略。俄亥俄州“罗伯戒毒中心”负责人Hill认为：相比其他国家，美国人更倾向于选择通过药物来缓解疼痛，释放压力。促成这一社会文化形成的主要动力，是1990年代中期，美国大型医药企业投入重金展开的“制药史上最慷慨营销活动”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中最典型的是1995年，美国“普渡制药公司”推广其研发的Oxycontin（奥施康定），率先打响了“阿片类药物无害论”宣传攻势，其上市后6年内，普渡公司赞助了2万个宣教项目。阿片类药物制造商和经销商在10年内花费了8.8亿美元，用于营销广告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿片类药物将阿片衍生物含量大大降低，服药者就采取增加服药量的对策。譬如前文的Matthew就曾每天吞服55粒阿片类镇痛药，采取医嘱处方的合法方式，“曲线”服用毒品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毒品导致的深层次社会问题，包括：毒品对吸食者脑内神经造成破坏，引发心理变态和认知障碍、诱发精神疾病、加剧情绪激化，导致家庭危机、暴力犯罪、儿童心理创伤等问题；贩毒所导致的黑社会犯罪、凶杀等暴力灾难，影响社会稳定，产生洗钱等上下游犯罪。在社会层面，毒品泛滥削减了美国社会劳动力基数，影响美国人口平均寿命；在精神层面，毒品及其诱发的犯罪摧垮传统价值观、泯灭正义良知、毁灭道德、释放人性中的至恶，是具有击垮社会、动摇国本、摧毁后代精神与意识形态基础的毁灭性犯罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国的“鸦片危机”已积重难返，仍将长期继续，毒品泛滥成为美国社会中传统群体所深恶痛绝，但却难以真正铲除的痼疾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被诬偷拍的人，不可逆转的伤害]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260001]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 23:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;11月3日，“成都地铁被诬陷偷拍案”开庭审理。近年来，“偷拍乌龙”事件频出，面对被当众指责偷拍、变态的窘况，被冤枉者只能忍气吞声吗？应该如何理性维权？</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走，去大自然丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 22:00:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;5月23日，2023年珠峰科考登顶队员在冲顶&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/259430&quot; title=&quot;冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年&quot;>;冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两年，我时常怀念一个或许并不存在的昨日世界。就好像茨威格形容他的父辈，被理想主义蒙蔽的一代人抱着乐观主义的幻想，坚信宽容和友好是不可缺少的约束力，真诚地认为各个国家及各个教派之间的界限和信仰的分歧，将会在人们的友善中逐渐化解，整个人类将享有最宝贵的财富：和平与安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;种种原因，我的工作和生活都在面对各种各样的人群，了解各式各样的思想，在沟通、靠近、了解、解释。而就像我的同事M所形容的，时常会想“即时退出人类社会”。每当此时，我就会做一些和人类无关的选题，动物或植物，大河或高山。无论大象出走还是洪水泛滥，无论冰川消融还是山林火灾，这些都折射出人类的渺小和愚蠢，人类的退让与自救。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这便是我想报道珠峰科考、冰川消融的最初动机。简单地说，连珠峰都能测出DDT（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有机氯类杀虫剂&lt;/span>;）了，连东绒布冰川都在节节败退了，对于喜马拉雅这座横跨五国的年轻山脉，人类难道不该搁置偏见与分歧，互相信任合作么？也确实，在采访中，冰川研究者普遍把世界视为一体，面对自然，面对宇宙，争端与冲突都失去了意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管，全球变暖不仅关乎环境，也关乎公平。最脆弱人群和生态系统遭受的损失和损害尤为严重，也正在承受与自身责任不相称的气候变化的不利影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如同对上世纪八九十年代主张“重写文学史”和人文精神大讨论，意图在文学中剥离立场本就是一种立场，意图超越意识偏见去记录科学工作，或许本身就是一种意识的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰州和西藏的采访，在我面前展开的是开阔的世界，是造物者之无尽藏也。这些在中国西部从事冰川研究的科学家热爱野外科考，部分原因就是热爱自由，追求潇洒的生活，他们能够忍受在珠峰脚下驻扎十年的艰苦，也是他们不吝啬时间，有能感知到地球脉动和珠峰壮阔的幸运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有回晚上采访，我们坐在兰州大学的操场上，受访者跟我说，有时候还挺同情你们大城市人，那么多压力，永远走不出钢筋水泥的城市森林。我突然想到印象派的诞生：经历了工业革命的都市人，开始厌弃弥漫着工业雾霾的伦敦，向往田园与大自然。而后脱胎于印象派，又诞生了更为自由的野兽主义、立体主义、表现主义。中国也已经完成了工业革命。今天的国人，是否也向往自然与田园？向往离开小环境或大环境里的冲突与争斗？这是否会催生新的文化形态？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说回对全球变暖、冰川消融的关注。我心里过不去的愧疚是，记录一些研究冰川、感知地球脉动的人以科学证实人类活动剧烈地伤害了环境，好像谈不上是关注环境变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最近，我读到了一段金国威的创作阐述，感到有所安慰甚至自洽。他是以拍摄《徒手攀岩》、《泰国洞穴救援》享誉全球的纪录片导演，他说：“我喜欢拍摄人性积极的那一面，那些能激励我们变得更好的品质。我有很多朋友拍摄人性的另一面，战争、冲突、争议。很显然，我还没有拍过这种主题的作品。世界上已经发生了这么多灰心的事，让人悲伤，让人愤怒，我希望试着制作能与之抗衡的作品，我想这是我能为世界做出的贡献。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[自家院子聚餐要办证？行政执法别乱来丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260013]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of a law enforcement officer in Hua County, Henan Province saying that a certificate is required to set up a fire party in rural areas has attracted great attention. The Huaxian Municipal Supervision Bureau issued a situation report on November 1, saying that law enforcement officers did not interpret the policy in a standardized manner, causing misunderstandings, and suspended them. However, this report was vague about the nature of the incident, which aroused greater doubts among netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to netizens, they were preparing to have a dinner in their yard when several law enforcement officers suddenly arrived. In the video, a uniformed staff member said, &quot;As long as you set up a fire, it is considered a business. If you have a group dinner, you must apply for a food safety license and a food business license. If you do not apply, you will be fined.&quot; Faced with doubts from netizens, law enforcement officers Take out a copy of the Food Safety Law and indicate that there is a legal basis for requesting a certificate. This aroused great doubts among netizens. Many people commented under the video: &quot;Do I need a permit to cook at home?&quot; &quot;I invited some relatives to my house for dinner a few days ago and didn&#39;t apply for a permit. Is it illegal?&quot; &quot; I plan to invite a few friends to my home for dinner in the next few days. Where can I apply for a certificate?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming a hot spot on the Internet, the Huaxian Municipal Supervision Bureau reported that on October 17, the bureau received a report that a certain village There was a dinner party in a courtyard. After the law enforcement officers arrived at the scene, they &quot;found that this was not a normal wedding and wedding gathering in rural areas. Five people were preparing dishes and cleaning tableware on the scene. The processing environment was simple and open-air. There were no &#39;three prevention&#39; facilities. The operators did not hold valid health certificates. There were Serious safety hazards can easily lead to food safety incidents and endanger people&#39;s health. Law enforcement officers explained relevant laws and regulations to the above-mentioned personnel and persuaded them to stop processing behaviors.&quot; &quot;During the law enforcement process, law enforcement officers did not interpret the policy in a standardized manner, which caused The masses misunderstood. The comrade was ordered to make an in-depth inspection and be suspended from duty.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, this announcement is confusing. The previous paragraph seems to say that law enforcement is no problem. It’s just that law enforcement officers’ interpretation of the policy is not standardized enough. If that&#39;s the case, it&#39;s just a small mistake and doesn&#39;t warrant suspension, right? Just criticize and educate, and then learn standardized policy interpretations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if I read the first paragraph carefully, the more I read, the more confused I become. The scene was &quot;not a normal wedding and wedding gathering.&quot; What kind of dinner was that? Is it normal to gather for weddings and weddings, but is it abnormal to gather for other gatherings? Do we need a certificate for “normal” weddings and weddings? Or is it only needed for “abnormal” dinner parties? What kind of dinner party is this? How many people are at the dinner party? Are the five people preparing food on site also part of the party, or are they the chefs they hired? The answers to these questions are different, and the nature of the events may be completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this is just a dinner party between family and friends, and the person preparing the food is also part of the dinner party, then there is absolutely no reason for the so-called law enforcement. If you have a dinner party with relatives and friends and cook and eat by yourself, do you need to apply for a food safety certificate or food business license? Of course not. There is no such provision in any law. The so-called &quot;simple processing environment, open-air operation, no &#39;three prevention&#39; facilities, and operators without valid health certificates&quot; and so on do not violate any laws. Rural gatherings, no matter whether they are weddings, weddings or other reasons, if there are many people, it is common for the host to cook in the open air in his own yard. The host is too busy, so relatives and friends help out. Do we still need relatives and friends to provide health certificates? As long as your relatives don&#39;t dislike it, the regulatory authorities have no reason to intervene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also possible that the person preparing the food is a chef specially hired by the host. For events with large gatherings of people, it is very common in some rural areas to hire professional chefs to serve at your doorstep. These chefs generally have a fixed team and provide mobile services in neighboring villages and charge service fees. This is indeed a commercial catering service, and it seems that the relevant personnel are required to apply for health certificates, food business licenses, etc. There are laws to follow. But the problem is that the food business licensing regulations formulated by the former State Administration of Food and Drug Administration require &quot;one license for one place&quot;, which means that to conduct food business in one place, you must obtain a license. For mobile catering services, this requirement is difficult to achieve. It is impossible to go to the regulatory authorities in advance to apply for a license every time you serve a place. Not to mention that it is difficult for these temporary venues to meet the conditions stipulated in licensing regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that it may be managed as a food vendor. The Food Safety Law has relatively loose provisions on small food production and processing workshops and food vendors, and authorizes provincial governments to formulate specific management measures. However, in the &quot;Henan Provincial Small Food Workshops, Small Business Stores and Small Stalls Management Regulations&quot; passed by the Henan Provincial People&#39;s Congress in 2017, small food workshops and small business stores are required to have fixed production and business premises. Although small food stalls do not have fixed stores, they Stalls must also be set up at approved locations and within the specified time. Therefore, this regulation does not apply to mobile door-to-door catering services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What should we do if there are no clear regulations to follow? Based on the abstract provision in the Food Safety Law that &quot;people engaged in food production, food sales, and catering services must obtain a license in accordance with the law,&quot; teams that provide mobile catering services are forced to apply for a license, and then they are refused and banned on the grounds that they do not meet the license conditions. , or should we follow the principle of modesty in administrative law enforcement and intervene as little as possible when there is no clear legal basis to rely on? The right choice should be self-evident. After all, rural areas are not full of restaurants like cities. Some places may be more than ten miles away from restaurants in towns, and transportation is not that convenient. It is unrealistic to travel across mountains and rivers to eat after finishing errands. Ignoring the actual needs of the rural public and using mechanical enforcement will only drive this market underground. Regulatory authorities should provide more services and less &quot;enforcement&quot;, and especially should not threaten fines at every turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深秋川西：最美季节，斑斓画卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259992]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨葛剑雄：不要指望通过玩来学历史]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260009]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 18:30:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/05/kEzg0k24CbQPfWdjHliBiwF8uZki3OYbTjMcSGYG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/kEzg0k24CbQPfWdjHliBiwF8u Zki3OYbTjMcSGYG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Ge Jianxiong was in a bookstore on Daxue Road, Shanghai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Wei Cuicui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong , the first doctor of history in New China (tied with Zhou Zhenhe). &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;On December 15, 1945, he was born in Nanxun Town, Wuxing County, Zhejiang Province (now Nanxun District, Huzhou City). &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;September 1957-July 1960, studied in junior high school at Chang&#39;an Middle School in Shanghai. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From September 1960 to July 1964, he attended high school at Shibei Middle School in Shanghai, during which he took a year and a half of sick leave. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;September 1964-July 1965, teacher training class of Shanghai Institute of Education, internship at Shibei Middle School. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From August 1965 to September 1978, he served as a teacher and secretary of the Youth League Committee of Gutian Middle School in Shanghai. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From October 1978 to November 1981, he was a graduate student in the History Department of Fudan University, studying under Mr. Tan Qixiang, and received his master&#39;s degree. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In December 1981, he stayed at the school to work. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In March 1982, he was an on-the-job doctoral candidate at the Institute of Chinese History and Geography at Fudan University, tutored by Professor Tan Qixiang. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In June 1983, he graduated early with the approval of the Ministry of Education. In October, he was awarded a doctorate in history from Fudan University. Together with Zhou Zhenhe, he was among the first batch of liberal arts graduates in the country. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In 1985, he was appointed associate professor; in 1991, he was appointed professor; in 1993, he was appointed doctoral supervisor. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From 1996 to 2007, he served as the director of the Chinese Institute of Historical Geography. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From 1999 to 2007, he concurrently served as the director of the Historical Geography Research Center, a key research base of the Ministry of Education. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From 2007 to 2014, he served as the Director of the Library of Fudan University. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From 2008 to 2018, he served as a member of the Standing Committee of the 11th and 12th National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In 2014, he was appointed as a senior professor of liberal arts at Fudan University. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In 2016, he was hired as a librarian of the Central Research Institute of Literature and History and a librarian of the Shanghai Research Institute of Literature and History. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Retired in January 2020. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 1978, green crops and soybeans were planted on the lawn of Fudan University. 32-year-old Ge Jianxiong entered the school and became a graduate student in historical geography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two months later, there were more lectures, and &quot;ballroom dancing&quot; became popular on campus. Ge Jianxiong, who was among them, also felt the vigorous vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to college is not easy. In December 1945, Ge Jianxiong was born in Nanxun Town, Wuxing, Zhejiang. He hoped to apply for the classical literature major at Peking University, but he was diagnosed with lung disease during a physical examination in his sophomore year of high school, and his studies were forced to interrupt. After losing the chance to take the college entrance examination twice in a row, he followed the teacher&#39;s advice and began training for teaching qualifications while preparing to take the college entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 1965, Ge Jianxiong officially became an English teacher at Shanghai Gutian Middle School. He thought he would be able to enter college after his health recovered, but instead he received news that the university had suspended admissions. Ge Jianxiong has spent more than ten years teaching at Gutian Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The college entrance examination was resumed in 1977, and the age limit for taking the exam was 30 years old. The 31-year-old Ge Jianxiong was not eligible to take the exam. In 1978, graduate student enrollment was resumed and the age limit was relaxed to 40 years old, allowing Ge Jianxiong to quietly sign up. With a high school education, he was admitted to the History Department of Fudan University with the first score in the preliminary examination, and studied historical geography under Mr. Tan Qixiang. A few years later, by chance, Ge Jianxiong and his fellow student Zhou Zhenhe became the first two PhDs in history independently trained by China after the reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ge Jianxiong often mentioned Mr. Tan Qixiang’s ingenious metaphor about historical geography: If history is a drama, then geography is the stage, and history cannot work without this stage. Mentioning the relevance of this subject to ordinary people, Ge Jianxiong said that historical geography is omnipresent. &quot;Whether it is the changes in the natural environment or the development of human geography, such as today&#39;s folk customs and intangible cultural heritage, they are all products of the historical geographical environment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the reason why he entered historical geography, Ge Jianxiong explained that even if he liked history since childhood, it was just a manifestation of blind curiosity in his youth until he became a graduate student at Fudan University in October 1978 and stayed at the school to work three years later. , only then decided to take historical geography as a lifelong career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ge Jianxiong is also a scholar with quite a personality. He often said, &quot;Don&#39;t be a nerd, don&#39;t be a hypocrite.&quot; Whether as a scholar or a member of the CPPCC, he always expressed his views outspokenly. In addition, he has traveled to Antarctica as a member of China&#39;s 17th Antarctic Expedition, climbed Mount Kilimanjaro, the &quot;King of Africa&quot;, and visited Ali, Tibet, the &quot;Roof of the World&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the last day of the National Day holiday in 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter met Ge Jianxiong in a bookstore on University Road in Shanghai. The 77-year-old man is white-haired and slightly stooped. He is wearing a dark blue cotton and linen shirt and dark gray trousers. He is carrying a white canvas bag filled with documents and books. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Missed the college entrance examination&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;You once mentioned that you were unable to take the college entrance examination due to physical reasons in high school. What was the situation like at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My goal in high school was to major in classical literature at Peking University, but I was diagnosed with lung disease in May of my second semester of high school. Due to widespread malnutrition, three people in our class were diagnosed with lung disease. My condition was the most serious and I had to suspend school. I originally thought that I would be able to start my senior year of high school in time after taking a three-month break, but after an examination, I found that the lesions were not completely absorbed, so I ended up taking a year and a half out of school and studying with the next class in my senior year of high school. In May 1964, I still failed the physical examination for the college entrance examination and was unable to register. Under such circumstances, I could only work as a social youth, but my teacher suggested that I join the workforce. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What work have you done and what do you hope for the future? Planning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Shanghai Institute of Education was running a teaching qualification training course at that time, which was equivalent to a one-year college. We were sent to various key schools to receive training, and after one year we were officially assigned as teachers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I planned to become a teacher first, and wait until I recovered before taking the college entrance examination. I trained at my alma mater, Shibei Middle School. I like literature and history, and I wanted to teach Chinese. But the teacher in charge of my class was the Chinese teacher. He said that the Chinese teacher had to correct the compositions of two classes and the burden was too heavy. He knew that I planned to enter college and suggested that I teach English so that I could have more spare time for self-study. After one year of internship, on August 5, 1965, I reported to Gutian Middle School and officially became a teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What other preparations have you made for the college entrance examination? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Not long after I started working, in September 1965, the night school department of Shanghai International Studies University enrolled students, and I applied. Starting from October of that year, we had English classes two nights a week. I thought I would have the opportunity to enter university after working for two years, but when the Cultural Revolution began in 1966 and the university closed down, my hope was dashed. The university resumed enrollment in 1977, but the age requirement was 30 years old. I was over the age and had no chance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Applying for graduate school with a high school degree, similar exceptions are available for admission Was it common at the time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When the country resumed postgraduate enrollment, the &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; published an article proposing to reduce talents in any way. Many regulations have been broken. For example, a high school diploma is required to enter college, but nothing is required to enter graduate school. The age is also relaxed to 40 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was reported in the news at that time that some people graduated from elementary school and were admitted to graduate school. There was also a Shandong student who had studied with his father since he was a child and had never set foot on campus and was admitted to graduate school. The oldest among the first batch of graduate students was Qian Liqun, who was born in 1939, and the youngest recruited by Fudan was born in 1957. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You originally wanted to study classical philology, but why did you apply for Fudan University? Historical geography? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I got married in March 1978 and registered for the exam in May or June. My wife wanted me to stay in Shanghai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I really wanted to study classical philology when I was in high school, but later I found that history was more practical and safer. I didn’t know what historical geography was at first, but I liked both history and geography, so I applied for this subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did the application process go smoothly? What was your mentality at the time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I prepared quietly for the first test and did not dare to tell the employer. I don&#39;t place any hope on the exam. If I can pass it, I will take it. If I fail, I won&#39;t be ashamed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The examination room was at Shanghai Institute of Technology, which is now the Yanchang Road campus of Shanghai University, two or three kilometers away from Gutian Middle School. At eight o&#39;clock in the morning, I organized the flag-raising on the school radio and lectured the students. It took about a quarter of an hour to complete these tasks, and then I rode a bicycle for ten minutes to take the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the preliminary test results came out, I ranked first. Only after I was able to take the re-examination did I start preparing seriously. I went to the public reading room of the Shanghai Library to borrow professional reference books, such as &quot;Selected Readings of Ancient Chinese Geography Classics&quot;. At that time, there was only one copy. It had been borrowed when I went there on the first day. I went to borrow it very early the next day to get it. , and it was also at this time that I met the classmates who later re-examined together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in fact, middle school has known it for a long time. After I enrolled in the school, the old branch secretary of the school accidentally told me that after seeing the preliminary test scores, Fudan University suspected that I had falsified my high school diploma and had sent someone to Gutian Middle School to learn about the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You had been working at Gutian Middle School for more than ten years when you were admitted to graduate school. Did you Are you still worried that the school won’t let you go? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. I was responsible for student affairs at the school and also served as the full-time Youth League Committee Secretary. I introduced the first batch of League members in the school. In 1977, I was selected as an advanced worker in education in Shanghai, and later became a deputy to the Shanghai Municipal People’s Congress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the leaders of the Zhabei District Education Bureau specifically called the school to express their attitude - if I am admitted to graduate school, it means that the country needs me to go to graduate school more, and the school must release me unconditionally. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/8CTAl7WVPMKw6hkp1USDjvszLxnrwA6urOi61djs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;614&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/8CTAl7WVPMKw6hkp1USDjvszLxnrwA6urOi61djs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 1983, President Xie Xide of Fudan University (left) awarded Ge Jianxiong a doctorate degree. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exceptional award of doctorate degree&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;October 1978 was the time you entered school. Was there any change in the atmosphere at the school at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Not long after we entered school, the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee was held, and the school ushered in earth-shaking changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first entered Fudan, green crops were still growing on the school lawn, and bright red big-character posters were posted on the main road, Nanjing Road. After the plenary session, the big-character posters were removed, scar literature caused heated debates among students, and more and more lectures were given. Some students proposed improving the treatment of intellectuals. While the views they put forward were not necessarily mainstream, they were passionate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deng Xiaoping’s speech proposed that it must be ensured that scientific and technological personnel must spend at least five-sixths of their time in business work a week. Our political study time has been significantly reduced, to half a day a week. In the past, we would have meetings and study all day long, and individuals had to attend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the course arrangements after enrollment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;During the master’s period, the school offers public courses, including politics and foreign languages. I chose English, German and Japanese. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Tan offers professional courses. When he enrolled, Mr. Tan was still hospitalized. He gave us the first class in the foyer of Shanghai Longhua Hospital. After two lectures, I thought the foyer was too noisy. Mr. Tan happened to have a student working at the Shanghai Dictionary Publishing House, so he asked someone to find a house for the publishing house near Longhua Hospital. In this way, Mr. Tan gave us a semester of professional courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school does not offer other professional courses and requires tutors and departments to resolve the issues themselves. Most of the courses are offered by tutors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have geography internships starting from this year. In 1979, two teachers took five of us graduate students to Yangzhou, Zhenjiang and Nanjing to conduct formal &quot;academic mountain climbing&quot; and observe geological structures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You chose to stay in school after graduation and started working and studying at the same time Bo, what&#39;s the opportunity in this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After I graduated with my master&#39;s degree, I was assigned a job. My family is in Shanghai, so I stayed in school smoothly, serving as Mr. Tan&#39;s assistant and undertaking scientific research tasks. In the spring of 1982, the country began to officially recruit doctoral students. At that time, doctoral supervisors had to go to Beijing for evaluation. It was not until 1992 that Peking University, Tsinghua, Fudan and other universities could evaluate at their own school, and they had to report to the Ministry of Education for registration. After Mr. Tan was named a doctoral supervisor in 1981, he recruited Zhou Zhenhe and me in 1982. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the whole, the number of doctoral students recruited in the first batch is very small, with only a dozen or so in the Liberal Arts Department of Fudan University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the first batch of Ph.D.s, what is your training method? Is there a relatively clear training plan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no standardized training method, and I don’t know what the above requirements are. After discussing with us, Mr. Tan decided to study on his own first and ask him for advice if he had any questions. Since I am his assistant and follow him all day long, I can ask for advice at any time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the number of doctoral students is small, the school does not offer courses specifically for doctoral students, so we don’t know what courses are available. However, considering that there is a thesis requirement for doctoral graduation, we began to prepare the doctoral thesis shortly after the semester started in 1982. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 1983, after more than a year of doctoral studies, you and Zhou Zhenhe was specially approved by the Ministry of Education to graduate early, which seems incredible today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In May 1983, the first batch of Ph.D.s in science appeared in China. The evaluation is based on the master&#39;s thesis, and if it reaches the doctoral level, it can be recognized as a doctorate. At that time, 18 people from across the country passed, and 4 from Fudan, namely Hong Jiaxing, Zhang Yinnan, Tong Yusun and Li Shaokuan. At the meeting of the school’s academic degree committee, Mr. Tan asked whether Zhou Zhenhe’s and I’s papers could also be recognized as doctoral thesis because they were also of high quality. However, Principal Su Buqing objected. He believed that the expressions of science subjects such as mathematics and physics have international standards, while liberal arts are Chinese subjects and have no international standards. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the school already had the first batch of science Ph.D.s, but no liberal arts Ph.D.s. If you wanted to strengthen your strength, this was an entry point. Jiang Yihua, the then department chair, learned that Tsinghua University and Peking University did not yet have liberal arts PhDs, so he asked whether Fudan could strive to cultivate the first batch of liberal arts PhDs in China. They specifically approached the Vice Minister of Education Huang Xinbai, and the result was that exceptions could be made, but all courses must meet the standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you meet the standards required by the Ministry of Education? No twists and turns? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Zhou Zhenhe and I completed the closed-book politics exam. For professional courses, Mr. Tan prepared test papers based on our situation. In addition, foreign language scores are also required. Zhou Zhenhe and I both took English and Japanese during our master&#39;s degrees, and our Japanese scores were over 80 points. We proposed that the first foreign language test be English, and the second foreign language should be replaced by the Japanese scores during the master&#39;s degree. The Ministry of Education agreed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the thesis defense in August 1983, we invited Hou Renzhi and Shi Nianhai. However, after the defense date was set, the written approval from the Ministry of Education for our early graduation has not yet been issued. When the school learned that Huang Xinbai was having a meeting in Harbin, it sent someone to Harbin to find him to sign. The night before the defense, they made a long-distance call and said that our defense was &quot;legal&quot; only after Huang Xinbai approved it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The degree awarding ceremony will be held in September. At that time, the doctoral certificates were numbered nationwide. The first 18 numbers were for science. Zhou Zhenhe was numbered 19th and I was numbered 20th. With a clear conscience, although we graduated early as an exception, we did not take things lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another episode. We were supposed to have professional titles after graduation, but due to the rectification of professional titles, it was not until 1985 that the assessment of professional titles was resumed, and Zhou Zhenhe and I were promoted to associate professors. I was named a professor in 1991 and became a doctoral supervisor in 1993. From the time I was studying for a Ph.D. to becoming a professor, I was able to continue doing academic work. If not for the reform and opening up, I would never have had these opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/5gv0PjMm2R0vUVItxmyHEVQp06V6hOrmR2hxAVs3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/5gv0PjMm2R0vUVItxmyHEVQp06V6hOrmR2hxAVs3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 1981, Ge Jianxiong (3rd from left) and his mentor Tan Qixiang (2nd from left), Zhou Youguang (1st from right) and Zhang Yunhe (1st from left). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How come toys must make you lose your mind? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You often mentioned Mr. Tan’s opinions on acting and The metaphor of a stage, so what is the value and significance behind studying the stage where history takes place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Historical geography is the study of geographical conditions in historical periods, including natural topography such as mountains, rivers, and humanities, Such as politics, economy and culture. The stage is an abstract metaphor, which actually refers to all geographical conditions, geographical elements and geographical distribution in the past. The value behind it lies in how we apply it. It is a science in itself and an objective law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For the discipline of historical geography, What did it mean for you to receive your PhD in 1983? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Everyone agrees that historical geography was basically formed in the 1980s. But for a subject to become a knowledge, at least there must be people studying the basic fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the Fudan University Library held its centenary exhibition, it asked me for a topic, and it was finally decided to be &quot;The Legend of the End of the Fire&quot;. I took out a few exhibits. The first one is Mr. Tan&#39;s university graduation thesis - &quot;History of Chinese Immigration&quot;. His instructor was Mr. Pan Guangdan. This manuscript also contains Pan Guangdan&#39;s comments. The second item is a six-volume history of Chinese immigration that I edited. The third thing is the books published by my students on the history of Chinese population and Chinese immigration. There are about six kinds of books. There are also many doctoral theses written by their students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our four generations have focused on the topic of Chinese immigration history, from unpublished university thesis manuscripts, to compiled six volumes, to so many papers, and we have truly passed it down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Combined with your own experience and feelings, the development of historical geography and What is the connection between reform and opening up? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In general, historical geography used to be a very small subject. Later, thanks to Mr. Tan&#39;s &quot;Atlas of Chinese History&quot; and everyone&#39;s continuous efforts after the reform and opening up, the social visibility of the subject was improved. If he could not seek truth from facts when studying historical geography, Mr. Tan would be very painful. However, the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee restored the line of seeking truth from facts. On such a major issue as historical maps, Mr. Tan received support from the central government. Mr. Tan was very moved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After so many years of research, what is your understanding of historical geography? What deeper understanding has there been of the subject? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After entering this discipline, I feel that the development of the discipline is inseparable from the line of seeking truth from facts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Marx’s historical materialism fully affirms the role of material foundation in history, and historical geography studies the stage and material foundation of history. If Marxist materialism can be used as technical guidance, historical and geographical research can naturally serve reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some major issues can be explained from the perspective of historical geography, while exploring the positive and negative roles played by geographical conditions in the process of historical development. For example, Mr. Tan proposed in 1962 that the fundamental reason for the long-term steady flow of the Yellow River after the Eastern Han Dynasty was the change in land use patterns in the middle reaches, which greatly reduced soil erosion. The good degree of vegetation maintenance in the middle reaches of the Yellow River determines the severity of soil erosion. Therefore, farming or animal husbandry in the middle reaches directly affects the safety of the lower reaches of the Yellow River. He proposed that the middle reaches of the Yellow River cannot be all engaged in agriculture, and should be adapted to local conditions. Farming should be done if it is suitable for agriculture, pastoral should be used for grazing, and forest should be used for forestry. It needs to be comprehensively developed and utilized comprehensively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this view has been criticized, its advanced accuracy has been fully proven after the reform and opening up. This is now the case in the middle reaches of the Yellow River, with some returning farmland to forests and some returning farmland to grassland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After becoming a doctoral supervisor in 1993, based on your past life experiences, you What are the differences in admissions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am an eclectic person, and several students were recruited with the approval of the school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like my student Ma Menglong, he failed the doctoral entrance examination, but after talking with him, I found that he has great potential, has strong logical thinking, and is very good at using his brain. I encouraged him to go back and review before taking the exam. Later, I felt that it was not enough to let him review by himself, so I decided to recruit him specially. The school stipulates that academicians and tutors who have produced hundreds of outstanding doctoral theses across the country can be specially recruited. I took advantage of this right and came up with the questions myself. After he answered the questions, I graded the results and handed the papers to the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year of recruitment, Ma Menglong couldn’t understand the class and was very anxious. I advised him not to worry, I believe you can follow me. Later, he slowly came to his senses, and his graduation thesis was of a very high standard, and even won the top 100 in the country. If I were not given autonomy, this kind of student would never be able to get in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Fudan has this tradition, which stipulates that academicians and doctoral supervisors who have produced top 100 papers have the right to recruit special talents. Then we should make full use of this right to discover special talents. As Mr. Tan advocates, on the one hand, we must abide by the system, but on the other hand, we must leave room for special circumstances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to academic research, Notice You is also a mobile game Academic consultants participate in the construction of the historical values ​​​​of the game. What is your original intention for doing this, and how do you understand the relationship between play and learning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ge Jianxiong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We need to correct a misconception. In ancient times, it was said that playing with things makes you lose your morale. How come playing with things must make you lose your morale? Can you keep your ambition without playing? Modern society is all about production, material rather than spiritual, but people have the right to play, and citizens&#39; right to play should be protected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But don’t expect to learn history by playing, that’s ridiculous. A nation that does not pay attention to history is pathetic, and a nation that can only learn history through games is even more pathetic. History is very serious and must be studied seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I serve as an academic advisor for mobile games, just to make sure that the values ​​of the game are okay. As long as the game is harmless, it is fine, but the values ​​​​must be correct. I once suggested to them to avoid causing harm to young people, and later strengthened supervision through secondary certification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“小姐姐报警称被同行人抛弃”：做旅游搭子应摒弃巨婴心态丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, an incident in which &quot;a young lady called the police and claimed that she was abandoned by a travel partner&quot; has attracted public attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, a woman posted a video on social media, saying in tears that &quot;she was abandoned by her travel partner&quot; and that she had already called the police. According to her description, there were five people in this &quot;travel group&quot;, including a couple and two men besides her. The group started traveling by car from Chengdu, and Daocheng Yading was the last stop. We originally agreed to drive back to Chengdu in the evening after climbing the mountain on the 27th. The woman involved said that when she came back at seven o&#39;clock that night, she found that the other four people had abandoned her and gone back first, and had stored her luggage in the hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 29, events took a turn. Another woman who was traveling with her posted a clarification, pointing out several facts. First, the pick-up group had repeatedly emphasized to the woman in advance that they would meet at the foot of the mountain at 16:30 that day and then drive back to Chengdu, but the woman ultimately ignored this; second, everyone urged her many times to no avail and could not contact her. at 18:30, she finally gave up and left, but stored her luggage at the hotel and shared her experience on the return route; third, after the woman involved called the police, the police also confirmed that they were not responsible for the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the entire incident, it can be seen that the woman involved completely ignored the agreement between the &quot;travel partners&quot; and acted arbitrarily in the AA-style escort group, and always asked others to &quot;help her&quot; in the process. &quot;Leave her alone&quot;, claiming that it is not your prerogative. The most critical thing is that she failed to fulfill the punctual obligation of &quot;meeting at 16:30&quot; that the group had repeatedly confirmed, and she couldn&#39;t be contacted in the middle of the trip, so the other partners had no choice but to leave early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, after all, travel groups are very different from travel agency group tours. It is completely possible to &quot;discuss everything&quot; on specific matters, as long as it wins the consent of the majority of people or does not hinder other members rights and interests. Taking this incident as an example, the woman involved could have disagreed with the meeting time in advance and tried to persuade others to postpone the meeting. Of course, the woman involved could also offer to give others a certain amount of financial compensation and wait until she came back before setting off; that was really not possible. , you can also declare to &quot;leave the group&quot; without interfering with each other, eliminating the need for subsequent disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, problems similar to &quot;tourists not arriving at the meeting point at the specified time&quot; will also occur in group tours of travel agencies, which has also caused many disputes. Whenever a similar situation occurs, there are always two directions. The first is that &quot;a group of people are waiting for one person&quot; but they dare not speak out and allow tourists who do not abide by the contract to damage the rights and interests of others; the second is that the travel agency &quot;does not tolerate him&quot; after seeking the consent of the tourists present and gathers them to leave first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, during a dispute over the &quot;One-day trip to Beijing Olympic Park&quot; involving a tour group from Tianjin, the tour guide asked to gather at 15:00, but tourist Song and four other people did not arrive until 15:30 because of their children. At the meeting point, the tour guide car has left at this time, and tourists have to return to Tianjin on their own. Song and others requested the travel agency to refund a total of 8,490 yuan including all travel expenses, liquidated damages, self-return expenses, and mental damages. After the trial, the court held that Song and others had breached the contract and the travel agency had no liability for compensation, and dismissed the plaintiff&#39;s lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If travel agencies have obligations to abide by contracts and need to bear liability for breach of contract, then the same is true for tourists. Put it in the scenario of &quot;travel hook-ups&quot;, that is, every hook-up has an obligation to keep the contract, and they also need to bear the same liability for breach of contract. Of course, partners can also reach different proportions of rights and obligations distribution plans, and women can also receive some care, such as &quot;help her and let her&quot; in this incident, but this does not mean that the woman involved can Regardless of breach of contract, unless she really treats other partners as personal tour guides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Details of this case show that the five-person group that set off this time did not reach any form of written contract, so there is no way to talk about their respective rights and obligations stipulated in black and white. The travel agreement between the group members was reached in the form of a verbal contract, and the only written form was nothing more than &quot;WeChat group chat records.&quot; After the woman in question withdrew from the group, the chat records became incomplete, which once affected the determination of facts and gave the woman in question room to gain a head start and &quot;preemptively draw pictures&quot; on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, although &quot;travel partners&quot; are much more flexible than travel agency group tours, they still have to abide by the contract reached between each other so that the entire team can successfully complete the journey. &quot;Travel partner&quot; can be regarded as a tiny autonomous group. The success of the journey depends on the contractual spirit, organizational ability, communication and coordination ability of each team member. To put it bluntly, it is how to adjust the relationship between &quot;individual&quot; and &quot;team&quot; The relationship of rights and obligations between each other, so that each partner has &quot;equal rights and responsibilities&quot; in the itinerary, only in this way can the situation of everyone be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the standard contracts and team formats of travel agencies and group tours, the travel format of &quot;travel partners&quot; is full of more flexibility and uncertainty, which also tests the comprehensive skills of team members. Qualities include but are not limited to physical fitness, interpersonal skills, self-rescue ability, adaptability, etc. This case also shows that in addition to safety issues, contract issues have arisen in the emerging business of travel hookups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Freedom is not free, it also means responsibility. Even if it is a &quot;go as you please&quot; and &quot;flexible&quot; travel group, this kind of freedom does not mean that you can do whatever you want, and it cannot evolve into the behavior of letting others foot the bill at any time. Since the tour group has delegated the freedom of travel to each partner, it also requires each partner to fulfill their own responsibilities, abide by the contracts reached with other partners, and be responsible for their own choices at any time and bear the costs. , you can enjoy the joy of traveling with strangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都地铁被疑偷拍案开庭，涉事女子“差一个道歉”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;He Jun described the incident on Weibo, with diagrams of each scene . On November 3, 2023, he appeared in court wearing the shoes on the day of the incident. Internet screenshot&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/14932cc6aa.jpeg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/14932cc6aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257123&quot; >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shoes suspected of containing secret camera equipment. On November 3, 2023, He Jun appeared in court wearing this pair of shoes. Internet screenshots&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The incident of a man being suspected of being secretly photographed on the subway in Chengdu originated on June 1, 2023. The person involved, He Jun (pseudonym), wrote in a long post on Weibo that he was secretly photographed on the subway by a small camera hidden in his shoes. He was then carried to the platform by a subway security guard and stood with one foot off his shoes and socks. span>;&lt;span>;The crowd&lt;/span>; watches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun believes that this process is like a shadow in life. For this reason, he went through many twists and turns and brought the two women involved and the Chengdu Metro to the court, demanding a public apology and financial compensation. The incident occurred a week after a Sichuan University girl falsely accused migrant workers of filming secretly, and thus attracted much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly half a year after the incident, on November 3, 2023, He Jun sued two women for a general personality rights dispute in the Chengdu Railway Transportation First Court. . The trial lasted for two and a half hours that day, and no verdict was announced in court. He Jun said on Weibo that when he recalled the entire process during the trial, he still felt very uncomfortable and had to constantly restrain his emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan, He Jun’s attorney, mentioned, “Leave aside the issue of men and women, any person can defend themselves when their rights and interests are threatened. own rights.&quot; Liu Dan said that he understood the behavior of the woman involved in standing up bravely when she suspected that she was being secretly photographed; but with such rights, she should also bear corresponding obligations. After discovering that it was a misunderstanding, the woman involved&lt;span >;The child&lt;/span>; should apologize proactively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/83324ca659.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/83324ca659.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;He Jun described the incident on Weibo, accompanied by diagrams of each scene. Internet screenshots&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unacceptable apology&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun has told the story of the incident many times on different occasions. For the first time, He Jun wrote a long article on Weibo based on his own memories, and always kept this article at the top of Weibo. After the case entered the investigation and evidence collection stage, He Jun made additional corrections to some details based on the contents of surveillance videos and law enforcement recorders, and gradually updated them on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On June 11, 2023, He &lt;span>;Jun&lt;/span>; took the subway home from Xipu, Chengdu. When he arrived at the South Railway Station, there was Two girls said they saw the green light flashing on his shoes and suspected that he was filming secretly. According to the video provided by passengers in the same carriage, two girls pointed at his shoes and said, &quot;It&#39;s shining, it&#39;s not reflecting light, it&#39;s shining.&quot; &quot;When we were filming, he put it on closed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the train safety officer of the car arrived, He Jun took off his shoes in public according to the girl&#39;s request. After the train safety officer and the two girls checked, no camera was found. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun recalled to Southern Weekend reporters before the court session that during this process, everyone on the train suddenly focused their attention on him, and some people deliberately looked out. When he looked up, he saw someone was taking pictures with a mobile phone, which already made him feel uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another place that made him feel uncomfortable was when he arrived at the station. The security officer and the station attendant arranged for him to stand against the wall and take off his right shoe. He Jun said that the environment he was in at that time was a public place connected to the platform. Passengers coming and going could see him taking off his right shoe and socks and standing next to the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I think this matter is not final. I was just a suspect at the time, so we should consider reducing some of the impact, such as taking me to a In a place with few people, maybe use something to block me, that’s what I thought.” He Jun believed that this was something Chengdu Metro did improperly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan, He Jun&#39;s attorney, told Southern Weekend reporters that they added Chengdu Metro as a defendant precisely because Chengdu Metro had problems with expanding the damage. It is true that the subway security officer did not force He Jun to take off his shoes or search him, but after a preliminary check that he was not secretly photographed, he could consider finding an office where the two parties could sit down and negotiate and wait for the police to arrive. Liu Dan said that in the case, He Jun also took the initiative to call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the police took off He Jun&#39;s shoes for inspection, they confirmed that there was no camera. The police also showed a restored video taken at the same location on the subway, and speculated that the advertising plates on both sides were reflected on the shiny surface of the shoes, reflecting green light. After mediation by the police, the two &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; apologized to He Jun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun is not satisfied with this apology. He said that according to the video content of the law enforcement recorder reviewed afterwards, the older female student said &quot;I&#39;m sorry, handsome man&quot;, and the younger female student said immediately &quot;We I have wronged you.&quot; &quot;The entire sentence did not take more than two seconds,&quot; He Jun said. They were &lt;span>;wearing&lt;/span>; masks and could not hear clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the long article recorded by He Jun afterwards, the police mediation was still continuing, and the girl &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; emphasized that she was speaking for the public. , to prevent other people&#39;s privacy from being infringed, and He Jun emphasized that the two &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; had a &quot;meal-eating&quot; mentality to share their experiences with their friends. &lt;p>; &quot;After they apologized, I think they may have made up their minds (to defend their rights),&quot; He Jun said. The next day, he took the initiative to post the experience online with the subject &quot;I was falsely accused of being secretly filmed by wearing a shoe-covered camera on the Chengdu subway.&quot; &quot;, hoping to record the progress of his rights protection, and also hope to find &lt;span>;eyewitnesses&lt;/span>; in the same carriage through the Internet. The post quickly attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;He Junfa&#39;s diagram on Weibo. Internet screenshot&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d3a352aff2. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d3a352aff2.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;257125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A diagram posted by He Jun on Weibo. Internet screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Do not support using violence to fight violence&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun&#39;s rights protection process was not smooth. At first, He Jun could not find any evidence such as video of the scene to prove the place of occurrence, which made it impossible to file a case in court for investigation and evidence collection. After many twists and turns, a man in the same carriage provided a signed certificate stating that the incident had occurred on Chengdu Metro Line 1, and the case was officially filed on August 15. During subsequent evidence collection, Chengdu Metro informed the platform that the monitoring equipment was damaged and the video was missing. On September 27, after communicating with his lawyer, He Jun added Chengdu Metro as a defendant in the prosecution case. The main reason was that Chengdu Metro was suspected of breach of contract and infringement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although some netizens demanded &quot;severe punishment&quot;, He Jun has not disclosed the two &lt;span>;names&lt;/span online in the six months since he posted this experience >;&lt;span>;Girls&lt;/span>; appearance, name and other private information. He does not support the method of &quot;responding to violence with violence.&quot; &quot;I have never had such an idea, and I have been calling on the media and netizens not to (defame or bully the other party online).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ding Yaqing, a lawyer at Guangdong Zhiheng (Guangzhou) Law Firm, has represented cases involving sexual harassment liability disputes. She believes that the two women involved suspected that someone was filming secretly and found the subway security officer to intervene in the verification. There was no problem in itself. In some situations where sexual harassment is alleged, finding a third party to intervene can help resolve the dispute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The key is that after the facts were clarified, this man spent time and energy to cooperate with the investigation and was scrutinized in public. &quot;He felt bad.&quot; Therefore, it is necessary and reasonable to demand an apology and explanation. &quot;The core problem for the girls in this case is that the process of &lt;span>; and &lt;/span>; apologizing was not explained in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, Ding Yaqing believes that Chengdu The train safety officers of the subway do not have the power to enforce the law, and their actions may not be appropriate in this regard. &quot;I noticed that the person involved said that the security officer carried him away,&quot; Ding Yaqing said. This &lt;span>;suggested&lt;/span>; whether the security officer exceeded his authority to conduct a search. She suggested that in places such as subways where sexual harassment accusations are prone to occur, staff should be trained, such as how to respond when such accusations occur, what are the staff&#39;s scope of authority, how to appease both parties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She believes that the response to sexual harassment accusations in public places can be compared to passengers encountering theft on the subway or bus - find a third party, The police, who have law enforcement powers, do not need to raise the issue of differences between men and women and gender antagonism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ding Yaqing analyzed that in general personality rights infringement cases, the responsibilities stipulated by law include stopping the infringement, eliminating the impact, making an apology, etc. He Jun&#39;s current demands One is to publicly apologize, but whether the scope of disclosure refers to the place where the incident occurred or on social media such as Weibo, and to whom the incident will be made public, etc., will also depend on the circumstances of the court trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan said that since the case is not open for trial, the form of a public apology cannot be revealed. &quot;But it must be public, because the infringement is also public, and the apology It should also be made public.” After the court hearing that day, Liu Dan said in an interview that there was a fierce debate in the court and the other party also provided tenable arguments. He did not have high expectations for the verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>