<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[贩卖假出生医学证明：“洗白”被拐儿童是黑产重要一环丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, anti-trafficking volunteer Shangguan Zhengyi reported that the director of Jianqiao Hospital in Xiangyang, Hubei Province was selling birth certificates, which caused great concern . In response, the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission reported that the obstetrics and gynecology department of the hospital involved has been suspended for rectification, and the hospital director has been subject to criminal coercive measures and is under investigation. According to the latest news, the Xiangyang Municipal Public Security Bureau has upgraded the investigation of this case, and has initially verified the criminal facts of 5 cases of buying and selling birth certificates, and is further digging into other accusations such as baby trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A medical birth certificate is a certificate issued by a medical institution for a newborn, including the newborn’s name, gender, date of birth, parents’ information, etc. This birth certificate, known as the &quot;first certificate in life&quot;, can play a role in proving the parent-child relationship during the subsequent settlement process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, fake medical birth certificates have become a very important link in the entire child trafficking industry chain. Using the information of the briber as the parents and creating a fake birth medical certificate, the abducted children can openly register as the briber&#39;s biological children at the police station and &quot;cleanse&quot; them. As a long-term anti-trafficking volunteer, Shangguan Zhengyi has encountered the other party many times during anti-trafficking operations to produce a &quot;medical birth certificate&quot; to prove that the child is his own. It was precisely because of this that he began to pay attention to and report the issue of falsification of medical birth certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Shangguan Zhengyi attracted widespread attention was when he reported that nearly 5,000 stolen medical birth certificates from Shangqiu Maternal and Child Health Hospital in Henan were used for child trafficking. In 2016, during his anti-trafficking investigation, he discovered that someone in Fujian purchased a child and then registered it with an illegally obtained birth certificate. Some of the birth medical certificates came from Shangqiu Maternal and Child Health Hospital. Shangqiu Maternal and Child Health Hospital stated that as early as 2011, it discovered that a large number of medical birth certificates had been stolen. At that time, it reported to the police and published a newspaper statement stating that they were invalid. In 2012, it was discovered that a batch of birth certificates had been stolen twice, totaling 4,885 copies. The Shangqiu police stepped up their investigation and eventually found out that the theft was committed by insiders. The then section chief and deputy section chief of Shangqiu Maternal and Child Health Hospital who were responsible for managing birth medical certificates were all captured and sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shangqiu Maternal and Child Health Hospital is not the only place where medical birth certificates have been stolen and used for illegal activities. This case is only more interesting because of the sheer number of stolen items. It is worth noting that these stolen medical birth certificates were declared invalid in newspapers. Therefore, strictly speaking, the certificates produced from these stolen certificates are invalid and false. However, because the database of the medical system is not connected with the public security department, it is difficult for the police station to verify the authenticity of the medical birth certificate when registering a newborn baby (in fact, the medical birth certificate does not use any high-end anti-counterfeiting technology). In addition, some police stations do not conduct strict inspections, so some completely forged birth certificates can be used to register for household registration, not to mention these &quot;fake certificates&quot; made from stolen &quot;real certificates&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of selling medical birth certificates at Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital goes a step further. The fake certificate they forged was not just a fake certificate, but a complete record in the health department&#39;s system. From the time of pregnancy to the hospital filing, all the way to the subsequent prenatal check-up and delivery, everything is recorded in the health system. The birth medical certificate and vaccination certificate are also available in the system. In other words, if you only look at the superficial documents, then this is so true that it cannot be truly “true proof”. Even if the police station gets the certificate from the health system to check its authenticity, it can only conclude that it is a genuine certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital and its director Ye Youzhi are undoubtedly accomplices of child trafficking and have committed serious crimes. At present, some of the facts of his illegal sale of birth medical certificates have been verified, which has violated the crime of buying and selling official documents and documents of state agencies. But this is only a misdemeanor. The more serious charge is that if Ye Youzhi knew that the baby was abducted and issued a false birth medical certificate for him, he might be found to be an accomplice in child abduction. The minimum penalty for child abduction and trafficking is 5 years in prison, and in serious cases, the death penalty. Ye Youzhi once claimed that she &quot;committed a capital crime&quot;, which shows that it is very likely that she knew that the fake birth certificates issued were used on abducted children. How many fake birth certificates did she sell, and how many abducted children were &quot;laundered&quot; among them? It remains for the police to further investigate and follow the clues to uncover more criminals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital and Ye Youzhi are not the only ones who forged medical birth certificates. As early as 2019, CCTV reported a case of forging medical birth certificates at a private hospital in Shehong, Sichuan. The method was exactly the same as that of Jianqiao Hospital. This time, Shangguan Zhengyi also reported hospitals in Nanning, Guangxi and other places. There are also more agents selling fake birth certificates active on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This black industrial chain that operates as a harbinger of evil must be severely cracked down on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[襄阳健桥医院“贩卖出生证明”事件：7人已被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260305]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A hospital in Xiangyang City, Hubei Province was recently reported to have &quot;colluded with intermediary gangs in many places to sell birth medical certificates&quot;, causing social concern focus on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The birth medical certificate is a statutory medical certification document stipulated in the &quot;Maternal and Infant Health Care Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and is an important basis for birth registration by the household registration authority. The national health authorities have repeatedly emphasized the need to strengthen the management of medical birth certificates. Under strict regulations, why is the birth certificate &quot;lost&quot; here? &quot;Xinhua Viewpoint&quot; reporters conducted an investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The obstetrics and gynecology department of the hospital involved has been closed for rectification&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 7, the reporter came to the hospital involved - located in Xiangcheng District, Xiangyang City, Hubei Province Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital. Walking into the lobby, the reporter saw that the hospital was operating normally, with banners hanging in conspicuous positions. Looking at the floor signs, in addition to the various departments of the hospital, there is also a confinement center in the building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/c1c67129f5796f6a5ad65ea78a6a2f03.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/c1c67129f5796f6a5ad65ea78a6a2f03.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257765&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows the lobby on the first floor of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital taken on November 7. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Hou Wenkun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, anti-trafficking volunteer Shangguan Zhengyi (screen name) posted on social platforms that after more than a year of unannounced visits, he discovered that Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital Dean Ye Moumou colluded with intermediary gangs in many places, used social platforms to publicly publish birth certificate information, scouted for customers, and sold birth medical certificates and vaccination books. According to Shangguan Zhengyi&#39;s understanding, the medical birth certificates sold are &quot;authentic and verifiable&quot;, and some are for abducted children, some for surrogate children, and some for abandoned babies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the interview that the Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital involved was formerly known as Xiangyang 102 Hospital. In 2011, the hospital was transformed into a private hospital and changed to its current name in 2017. In 2020, Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital (East District) was officially opened. The introduction at the hospital gate shows that Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital (East District) is an integrated medical and nursing hospital in Xiangyang City featuring maternal and infant care. It provides pregnancy examinations, prenatal diagnosis, nutritional guidance, psychological consultation, childbirth, confinement care, Integrated services such as baby care and early education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission on the 8th that the Obstetrics and Gynecology Department of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital has been closed for rectification, and the hospital’s authority to issue medical birth certificates has been suspended. At the same time, a professional team has been arranged to provide consultation and care for pregnant women in the hospital involved, and make every effort to ensure the health and safety of pregnant women in the hospital. So far, reporters have searched online for the hospital involved and found that the link to its official website has been unable to be found. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Seven suspects have been subject to criminal compulsory measures&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission told reporters that Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital did have a child born in Qualifications for issuing medical certificates. Relevant departments will regularly inspect the issuance of medical birth certificates. However, maternal delivery and hospitalization involve multiple departments within the hospital, and usual supervision is often focused on a specific link. We did not expect that the hospital would falsify delivery and hospitalization records and other materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/8755ed5ba6f8db390e73093ebb8752eb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/8755ed5ba6f8db390e73093ebb8752eb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257764&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows the internal environment of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital taken on November 7. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Hou Wenkun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from an interview with the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission that Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital has been experiencing constant disputes between doctors and patients, and the health department has punished it more frequently. However, it mainly focuses on medical services and medical safety, and does not involve the issuance of medical birth certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Xiangcheng District Branch of the Xiangyang Municipal Public Security Bureau told reporters on the 8th that starting from the evening of November 6, the public security department has been involved in the work and has completed relevant information inspection and personnel control in stages. The current focus of the work is to carry out investigation and evidence collection and verification one by one around the reporting clues, which is now being carried out in full swing. In order to improve the efficiency of investigation, the public security agencies at the two urban levels have established multi-type task forces to fully promote relevant work. Criminal coercive measures have been taken against seven suspects, including the director of the hospital involved and relevant staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Fill the loopholes and strengthen the &quot;gateway&quot; for issuance and registration of birth certificates&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As early as 2009, the health department issued a notice requiring further strengthening of medical birth certificates. For standardized management, the issuing agency must implement the requirement of having dedicated personnel manage the birth medical certificate and seal respectively, and strictly enforce the issuance process. In December 2020, the national health department held a national work conference on the management of medical birth certificates, emphasizing the need to strictly manage issuance and ensure the implementation of the system. Relevant departments have issued repeated orders to strengthen education and training, and alarm bells are ringing at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Trafficking medical birth certificates of newborns can launder the identities of trafficked people.” A grassroots policeman who has been engaged in “anti-trafficking” work for a long time told reporters that when investigating human trafficking cases, DNA comparison results, birth certificates, etc. Medical certificates and household registration information form the basic chain of evidence. If a trafficked person obtains a legal medical certificate of birth, he or she can legally apply for household registration. It is difficult to form sufficient evidence based on DNA comparison results alone, which will bring serious challenges to case investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pan Yu, a partner at Hubei Yingchu Law Firm, pointed out that the birth medical certificate is a legal medical certificate used to prove the identity of the baby. It is a national agency document uniformly printed by relevant national departments and issued by the hospital. The behavior of the hospital director involved is suspected of forging and buying and selling state agency documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, some interviewees said that loopholes must be filled, relevant management systems must be improved, and the &quot;gateway&quot; for the issuance and registration of birth medical certificates must be tightened as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police handling the case from the Xiangcheng District Branch of the Xiangyang Public Security Bureau said that the task force is currently using reported clues as an entry point to speed up the investigation. If new clues or new crimes are discovered during the process, they will never let them go. , we must investigate thoroughly and never tolerate it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[进博会偶遇中国驻伊朗大使常华：寻找共建“一带一路”的新方式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;November 7, 2023 is the second day of the official launch of the 6th CIIE, Southern Weekend reporter I ran into Chang Hua at the booth of an Iranian brand. He was admiring a bottle of &quot;Damascus Rose&quot; essential oil. Chang Hua currently serves as China’s Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Islamic Republic of Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How was the sales at the CIIE this year?&quot; &quot;Are all the raw materials from Iran?&quot; &quot;How many times has this been to the CIIE?&quot;... Chang Hua had only one entourage around him. From time to time, he asked the person in charge of the booth about his participation in the exhibition, but most people around him were unaware of his identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Hua shared his thoughts on participating in the CIIE with Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;For more than ten years, China has been Iran&#39;s largest trading partner. Although it is currently encountering some difficulties, the reasons It is mainly a matter of US sanctions and not a bilateral issue between China and Iran. But we can still see that Chinese and Iranian businessmen are overcoming various difficulties and actively developing economic and trade cooperation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, China and Iran signed a 25-year comprehensive cooperation agreement plan. According to media reports, the agreement stipulates that within 25 years, Iran will steadily provide oil to China in exchange for Chinese investment in areas such as 5G communications, infrastructure, and energy facilities, which is expected to total approximately US$400 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Information from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs shows that as of 2022, China will continue to remain Iran’s largest trading partner, largest export destination, and second largest import source. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The “Belt and Road” features of the Sixth China International Import Expo have become increasingly obvious. According to Sun Chenghai, deputy director of the China International Import Expo Bureau, a total of 72 countries and international organizations participated in the national exhibition this year, including 64 countries co-building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Iran has historically been an important country in the &#39;Belt and Road Initiative&#39;. After my country proposed the &#39;Belt and Road Initiative&#39;, Iran has also been actively expressing its support for this policy.&quot; Chang Hua told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;I hope Entrepreneurs can use their subjective initiative to break through or open up a new situation in the face of the US blockade obstacles and find new cooperation highlights (between the two countries).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Chinese businessmen return to the &quot;Silk Road&quot; ”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Guicai did not know in advance that Ambassador Chang Hua would come. “(Ambassador) only knew about the existence of an enterprise like ours after seeing the TV station’s report on us yesterday.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a corner of the Iran exhibition, a booth of less than 20 square meters had many people stopping, most of them women. This is the Iranian plant essential oil brand &quot;Barij&quot; founded by Zhang Guicai. )&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Balize is a Chinese company, but its production partners and raw material importers are all from Iran. &quot;The production and refining are completed by Iran, and China is responsible for packaging and branding.&quot; Zhang Guicai told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, China and Iran announced the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership, and Iran joined the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. This year, Zhang Gui began his entrepreneurial journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Guicai graduated from Tsinghua University. “I first worked on mining equipment, and later transferred to the field of aromatic plants.” He said that Iran is extremely rich in natural resources. In addition to the well-known minerals, crude oil, and natural gas etc. Agricultural and sideline products are also quite famous. &quot;More than 90% of the saffron familiar to Chinese people in the world is produced in Iran. There is also the &#39;Damascus Rose&#39;, the national flower of Iran, which was famous during the Persian Empire and is mainly produced in Iran.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhang Guicai first entered the field of fragrances and fragrances, his main product was saffron, and then expanded to plant essential oils and hydrosols. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the first year we participated in the CIIE (2019), we only brought 100 bottles of samples, and they were sold out in less than half a day. This year we have made sufficient preparations, but they are still not enough.&quot; Another A brand manager pointed to a row of new products on the wall and said that these are samples that the factory worked overtime to produce. Baliji’s sales volume of hydrosol products this year has exceeded 10 million bottles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Without a platform like the CIIE, it would be impossible for Chinese people to understand Iran’s superior specialties, let alone a niche brand like ours.” Zhang Guicai said that in 2023, Balizhe would be The Iranian Consulate in Shanghai selected it as a special souvenir for the National Day reception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Balij’s current largest supplier is an Iranian factory called Dorrin Golab. The factory is responsible for the entire process from planting, picking, refining to production. Because of the purchasing power of the Chinese market, the factory has grown from 60 The number has expanded to nearly 200 this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dorrin Golab is a medicinal plant production company established in 1998 and belongs to the Medicinal Plants and Food Exporters Union under the Iranian Chamber of Commerce, Industry, Mining and Agriculture (ICCIMA). One detail is that in addition to Farsi and English, the official website of the above-mentioned alliance also has Chinese pages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ICCIMA is the largest private business alliance in Iran. A message on the website on September 27 showed that Hussein Serawaz, chairman of the chamber of commerce, met with Chang Hua that day and said that it had been established. A task force on developing trade relations with China was established to further activate private sector trade through the chambers of commerce platform of both countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2023, at the &quot;Iran-BRICS: Partnership and Cooperation Prospects&quot; seminar, Ambassador to Iran Chang Hua spoke. Image source: Ministry of Foreign Affairs website&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e696052863.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e696052863.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;In August 2023, at the &quot;Iran-BRICS: Partnership and Cooperation Prospects&quot; seminar, Ambassador to Iran Chang Hua spoke. Image source: Ministry of Foreign Affairs website&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An important window for global export trade&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to a report by Iran&#39;s &quot;Tehran Times&quot; on November 5, led by Iran&#39;s First Vice President Mohammad Mukhbel Team, more than 50 Iranian companies and more than 250 Iranian businessmen participated in the CIIE. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iran’s Deputy Foreign Minister Safari told the Iranian media, “One of our main export target countries is China...China, with a population of 1.4 billion, can provide Iran with important export space. This visit is very important. Important, indicating that the government attaches special importance to exports.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many problems are slowly being solved, such as visas, foreign exchange transactions, etc. Under the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; system, the trade between China and Iran will definitely become more and more important. The more convenient it is,&quot; Zhang Guicai pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, it is not surprising that customs clearance took several weeks in the past, but now it only takes one week for imported Iranian goods to be cleared domestically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Report on the Export Potential of Developing Countries Along the Belt and Road to China&quot; released by the United Nations International Trade Center (ITC) at this CIIE, before the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative in 2013, developing countries along the Belt and Road The country&#39;s total exports to China are approximately US$445 billion, and have reached US$798 billion in 2023, an increase of approximately 79%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sylvie Betang Kexin, the center’s Asia-Pacific Affairs Director, pointed out in a sub-forum at the CIIE that during the same period, the trade between developing countries along the “Belt and Road” and other parts of the world increased. Only 12%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ke Xin told Southern Weekend reporters after the meeting that the export growth of the “Belt and Road” countries to China in the past ten years was mainly concentrated in the primary industry, that is, chemical industry, ore and other raw material fields, “We We also look forward to further growth in the manufacturing industry in the future, from primary products to some high value-added processed products, which will further help the economic development of these countries.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Hua is also thinking about how China-Iran trade can further develop in the context of US economic sanctions against Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;First of all, the U.S. sanctions are unreasonable. Our government is firmly opposed to it, but we must also protect the interests of our own companies, taking into account the risk of being sanctioned (jointly and severally), Iran&#39;s funds and industrial chains, etc. It is still relatively fragile.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his observation, some Chinese business groups have successively participated in Iranian exhibitions this year. The local commerce department or local trade promotion association has organized a large-scale visiting group. The Iranian market is very important to Chinese companies. increasingly attractive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June this year, a 45-member trade delegation from Jilin Province visited Tehran to participate in the &quot;Iran-China Trade Forum&quot; held on June 18. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 15th BRICS leaders’ meeting in August, six countries including Iran officially became members of the BRICS family, and their membership will take effect on January 1, 2024. This is the second time Iran has joined an important multilateral mechanism after joining the Shanghai Cooperation Organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胸中剩有丘陵在，好听昭时鸣玉珂：怀念刘操南先生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260206]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/dByCLHe1G44YYJZ7YDW3EecCWQxtmxYOlNILYcho.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;497&quot; height=&quot;693&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/dByCLHe1G44YYJZ7YDW3EecCWQxtmxYOlNILY cho. png&quot; data-key=&quot;257547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Caonan (1917-1998), professor of the Institute of Ancient Books of Hangzhou University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our 78-level course on the history of Chinese literature, Mr. Liu Caonan has taught several lectures on the pre-Qin and Han Dynasties. He sang as soon as he opened his mouth and asked everyone to sing along. The scene was very lively. He also asked everyone to recite it in this way after class. This is my first contact with singing, and it feels very fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three articles that impressed me the most. The first is &quot;The Book of Songs·Binfeng·Dongshan&quot;: &quot;I went to Dongshan, melancholy and did not return. &lt;span>;I&lt;/span>; came from the east, and there was zero rain. &lt;span>;I&lt;/span>; said east and returned, &lt; span>;I&lt;/span>; am heartbroken.&quot; At that time, I was reading the Book of Songs, and my favorite poems were love poems, but this one was about the scene of returning from an expedition, which was very sad. The second is &quot;Li Sao&quot;, &quot;Tsuen is not aware of what is going on in the world&quot;, full of depression and complaints. The third is Cao Zhi&#39;s &quot;Ode to the Goddess of Luo&quot;. I still remember the way Mr. Liu recited &quot;In the third year of Huang Chu&#39;s reign, the capital of Yu Dynasty returned to Luochuan...&quot;. The chapters he recited all contained his life experiences and emotional resonance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu is from Wuxi, Jiangsu. Reciting was originally his &quot;teaching lesson&quot; when he was in private school. He regarded us as innocent children and diligently dedicated his treasures to us. In his later years, he enthusiastically advocated and promoted the art of classical poetry recitation. He once recorded and released &quot;Song Poetry Recitation&quot;, which can still be heard on the Himalayas website. Therefore, when students from different classes recall Mr. Liu’s classes or lectures, the first thing they mention is singing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Poetry recitation is now on CCTV and is very fashionable, but at that time we felt it was fresh and had doubts: we should teach new knowledge in the classroom and spend such precious time teaching recitation. ,is this necessary? But Mr. Liu completely ignored the questioning glances from the audience and was immersed in his own world. He explained &quot;Li Sao&quot; and began to recite it as he spoke. He recited it so deeply that he was speechless and choked with tears. In addition, when he was happy in class, he would write his own old-style poems on the blackboard and sing them proudly - not wanting this to be a class on ancient literature - which some students complained about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the old gentleman in the Chinese Department, who was over 70 years old, no longer taught classes for undergraduates. Still in the first online basic class is an old man who is over sixty but not yet seventy years old. Because of this chant, Mr. Liu became the one who impressed the students the most. But among the students, there were some who admired it and some who took it as a joke. ——Everyone doesn’t respect him as much as they do other old gentlemen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was young and ignorant at that time. I neither understood the significance of reciting poetry or comprehending its charm, nor could I understand his knowledge. Before I graduated from my undergraduate degree, I applied for graduate school. My tutors in the literature major of Yuan, Ming and Qing Dynasties were Liu Caonan and Xu Shuofang, who were applying for novels and drama respectively. Although I had put a lot of effort into novels before, I still chose Quanwu in the end. Basic drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I listened to Mr. Liu’s class again when I was a graduate student. Each of the five tutors gave three lectures, which constituted one semester of graduate courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu mentioned in class the &quot;Almanac&quot; and &quot;Tianguan Shu&quot; of &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Lü Li Zhi&quot;, &quot;Astronomical Records&quot; and &quot;Nine Chapters of Arithmetic&quot; in &quot;Han Shu&quot;. He said that when it came to calibrating astronomy, calendar and arithmetic, &quot;we&quot; were different from our predecessors in that we did not calibrate based on the version, but used modern mathematical methods to calculate and then make corrections (at that time, we could not say &quot;I&quot; more, we had to say &quot; us” to avoid the suspicion of individualism). I was in awe when I heard it. Because this is a real &quot;unique skill&quot;, it requires a strong foundation in modern mathematics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I heard that he had won the first prize in the school’s teachers’ mathematics competition (non-mathematics major group). Now Zhejiang University Press is editing and publishing &quot;The Complete Works of Liu Caonan&quot;, which is compiled into 22 volumes and has more than 6 million words. Among them, works related to calendars include &quot;Ancient Books and Science&quot;, &quot;A Search for Calendar Calculations&quot;, &quot;General Introduction to Ancient Calculations&quot;, &quot;Celestial Calendar Theory Collection&quot;, &quot;Interpretation of Ancient Calendar Data&quot;, etc., and &quot;Explanation of Ancient Astronomical Calendar&quot; (2009). Single line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ny7mraO7Y5GFFm1gNHSi8vPSCMafhQDxWcHj0nBw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ny7mraO7Y5GFFm1gNHSi8vPSCMafhQDxWcHj0nBw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Caonan has two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of his single papers on calendar calculation were published or broadcast during the period when he was teaching at the old Zhejiang University (1942-1952), such as &quot;New Interpretation of &quot;Haidao Arithmetic Classic&quot;, &quot;Nine Chapters of Arithmetic Annotation and Correction of Zu Chong&#39;s Kaili Yuan Shu&quot;, &quot;Annotations and Readings of &quot;Zhou Bi Arithmetic Classic&quot; Pythagorean Square Diagram&quot;, &quot;Nine Number Interpretations of &quot;Zhou Li&quot;, etc. The impact is considerable. But when we were graduate students, the above works were not published. Because this kind of work is an alternative in the Chinese Department, and no one can do it in the History Department, and there is even no journal to publish it. It can be said that there is no way out. Therefore, Mr. Liu is lonely as a master and has no one to understand and understand, so he has no choice but to enjoy himself in the classroom. He often said that I had written an article on this matter and that I had solved that problem, but the impression given to the listeners seemed to be self-promotion, because what he said was really a &quot;book from heaven&quot; that we did not understand at all and had no way to verify, let alone No one responded to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, he was qualified to recruit graduate students in multiple directions: pre-Qin and Han literature, ancient science and technology history, and Yuan, Ming and Qing literature and novels. However, it was difficult to recruit students from the pre-Qin and Han Dynasties, and it was impossible for anyone to study the history of science and technology in the Chinese Department, so he decided on the direction of novels. The first class he recruited was Li Mengsheng, and our current class recruited Chen Fei. After studying for three years, under the guidance of Mr. Liu, Chen Fei published a series of papers on Ming and Qing novels, making his debut in the academic world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In class, Mr. Liu also talked about novel research, but as he talked, he began to talk about his unique ideas and methods: rewriting classic novels into popular readers. At that time, he had already co-published a book &quot;The Romance of Wu Song&quot; with Mao Saiyun, with 250,000 words. It was based on the famous &quot;Ten Chapters of Wu&quot; in &quot;Water Margin&quot; and adapted from Hangzhou Pinghua. This book was published by Donghai Literature and Art Publishing House in 1959, with an initial printing of 60,000 copies; in 1980, Zhejiang People&#39;s Publishing House published a revised edition, with an initial printing of 150,000 copies; in 1983, Zhejiang Literature and Art Publishing House republished it, with an initial printing of 300,000 copies. No wonder Mr. Liu believes that this is a new path, and he should follow this path, one by one, and write it into a series, which not only promotes the classics, but also eliminates its dross. In his view, literary creation is the prerequisite for literary research. If you don’t understand creation, you will not be able to do research well. He lamented that he was old and encouraged everyone to attend in class. His words were full of expectations, but no one responded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/maxWYg8ePtn6BMpfBKdxeP0xXPCpgAH4PFnbehcw.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/maxWYg8ePtn6BMpfBKdxeP0xXPCpgAH4PFnbehcw.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Different versions of &quot;The Romance of Wu Song&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I actually didn&#39;t think so, thinking that rewriting ancient vernacular novels had no &quot;academic content&quot;. There must be many people who have the same idea as me. It seems that Chen Fei has not followed suit. Therefore, Mr. Liu can only walk alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I looked at the catalog of the volumes of &quot;The Complete Works of Liu Caonan&quot; and found that &quot;The Romance of Wu Song&quot;, &quot;Shui Bo Liangshan&quot;, &quot;The Green-Faced Beast Yang Zhi&quot; and &quot;Zhuge Liang Comes Out of the Mountain&quot; have been published, and they are all based on classic novels. It was written. In fact, he also had a considerable number of rough works that were not included in the collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the new century, I visited Japan and found that they had systematically rewritten classic classics. Only then did I truly understand the value and significance of the work advocated by Mr. Liu. It&#39;s a pity that he passed away at the end of the last century, so I can&#39;t apologize to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu not only studies ancient times, but also pays attention to modern and contemporary folk arts. This &quot;going down&quot; approach is currently considered a &quot;new vision&quot; and a &quot;growth point&quot; for future academics. However, there was a &quot;chain of contempt&quot; in &quot;university academics&quot; at that time, and folk literature and rap Literature is at the bottom. However, Mr. Liu was not only engaged in astronomy and calendar, &quot;Confucian classics&quot; and popular literature, so he was unaware of this. He has always maintained a close relationship with storytellers. When we were graduate students, he invited Mr. Tang Gengliang, a famous storyteller, to give a lecture. Unexpectedly, he discovered that I was also in the photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/n4Yl1LKt0ys3vdGzu7zzQkkVT1kK8VVfReOttdSv.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;472&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/n4Yl1LKt0ys3vdGzu7zzQkkVT1kK8VVfReOttdSv.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Front row, from left, Liu Caonan, Tang Gengliang, Ping Huishan; back row, from left, Li Jianliang, Zhu Hongda, Huang Shizhong, Chen Fei. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Liu also has unique insights into the research of &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot;. He discovered the value of Chen Qitai&#39;s Tonghuafengge Commentary on &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, wrote a series of essays to introduce it, and compiled the &quot;Collection of Tonghuafengge&#39;s Commentary on &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot;&quot; (1981). He also extensively collected Tanci literature and compiled it into &quot;The Opening Collection of Tanci in A Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, which was only published after his death (2003), many of which are unique copies. However, these works have not entered the mainstream of research on &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot;. He has been involved in novels, operas, and folk arts throughout his life. He can be a family, but he is not outstanding enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/np6fLPOwejqvrR74YxGTVeGjh556GOhL2D1UbgcJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/np6fLPOwejqvrR74YxGTVeGjh556GOhL2D1UbgcJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;These two books bring together Mr. Liu’s research on novels and operas, but they will not be published until 2021. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The literature and history of Pre-Qin and Han Dynasties that Mr. Liu devoted the most to. Looking at the list of &quot;Complete Works&quot;, the first volume is &quot;Exploration of &quot;The Book of Songs&quot;&quot;, the second volume is &quot;Textual Interpretation of Chu Ci&quot; and &quot;Collection of Poems&quot;, the third volume is &quot;Collection of Historical Events of the Twelve Princes in the Spring and Autumn Period in &quot;Historical Records&quot;&quot;, and the fourth volume Volumes &quot;Notes on &quot;Gongsun Longzi&quot;&quot; and &quot;Compilation and Research of Chen Hanzhang&#39;s Posthumous Works&quot; and the fifth volume &quot;Literature and History Series&quot;. These works are truly remarkable. However, most of them were not published during his lifetime, and only three volumes have been published so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Mr. Liu loved poetry and ancient prose since he was a child, and he kept reciting it until his death. He said that he wrote no less than ten thousand poems in his life, but &quot;Poems of Yi Caoxuan&quot; (Xiling Seal Society, 2002) contains only a thousand poems. &quot;Yicaoxuan Wencun&quot; has not yet been published. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His energy is so strong and his research fields are so broad, which really amazed me. The Zhejiang University Press introduced his life when it published the &quot;Complete Works&quot;, saying that he &quot;learned about Chinese and Western liberal arts, comprehensively comprehended hundreds of schools of classics and history, was good at poetry and articles, wrote prolifically, made outstanding achievements, and was famous at home and abroad.&quot; These words are not an exaggeration. . But in fact, even a graduate of this department like me lacks due respect for Mr. Liu. Not long after our graduate students enrolled, Mr. Liu was transferred to the Institute of Ancient Books, and then he recruited graduate students collectively. The previous students had all attended Mr. Liu&#39;s classes, but Fu Jie was the only one who chose Liu Caonan as his second tutor because of his work on the Book of Songs (the first tutors were all Mr. Jiang Liangfu). After graduation, he stayed at the school as Mr. Jiang&#39;s assistant. Fu Jie said that he was actually more influenced by teacher Guo Zaiyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mawpbCB7XRZsV5UvSBTLkbmEeNurqKZeah5mldvG.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mawpbCB7XRZsV5UvSBTLkbmEeNurqKZeah5mldvG.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Teachers and students of the Institute of Ancient Books of Hangzhou University in 1986. Mr. Liu is in the front row, second from the right. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1987, the school directly went through the retirement procedures for him without informing him, and Mr. Liu left the teaching profession he loved deeply. post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was seventy years old and in good health. At that time, most senior liberal arts scholars of this age were still at the forefront of teaching and scientific research, but he probably had no choice but to retire because he was not qualified to be a doctoral supervisor. It seems that Hangzhou University, which has many famous scholars, did not realize his value. Chen Fei gave up the opportunity to stay at Hangzhou University when he graduated. Fu Jie left for Fudan shortly after staying at the university, so Mr. Liu did not leave any academic connections at Hangzhou University. Just before Hangzhou University was merged into Zhejiang University, Mr. Liu passed away due to illness at the age of 82. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In retrospect, in class, he likes to wear a black double-breasted Tang suit or a navy blue Chinese tunic suit, with formal buttons fastened tightly. He has a dark complexion and a pair of black-rimmed glasses on his big nose. , there is always a hint of melancholy in his eyes. He sang &quot;Li Sao&quot; and lamented that Qu Zi was not understood, which was not a personal feeling. At the last moment of his life, he wrote &quot;Two Laws of Writing Tests in the Wuyin Dynasty during the Illness&quot;, the second part goes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Eighty years of stone and fire have passed, and I am deeply ashamed that my book and sword have been wasted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The past events in the ancestral hall are forgotten in books, and there are many new things in the school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Who said that Tianguan is not Chinese culture, but he ended up teaching Ye Shituo&#39;s tragedy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are hills left in the chest, and it is nice to hear the sound of jade ke in Zhaoshi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who said that Tianguan is not Chinese learning?&quot; is like &quot;a question from heaven&quot;, but no one can answer it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I checked the resume of Mr. Liu Caonan. His nickname was Zhaoxun, his nickname was Bingxian, and his later nickname was Liangxi Kuangsou. Liu Yuanchang was born on December 13, 1917 in Nanmen, Wuxi, Jiangsu. His family was well off. He entered a private school at the age of six and recited &quot;Four Books&quot;, &quot;Mao Shi&quot;, &quot;Shang Shu&quot;, &quot;Zuo Shi Chun Qiu&quot;, etc. After leaving school, he was admitted directly to middle school. He was good at both arts and sciences, and was especially good at mathematics. When he was in the third year of junior high school, he wrote a long paper &quot;Research on Quadrilaterals&quot;, which was published in the graduation commemorative journal of the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1937, he was admitted to the Department of History and Geography of Zhejiang University, but went to Shanghai for some reason. It happened that Zhijiang College of Arts and Sciences was recruiting students in Shanghai, so he applied and was admitted to the Department of Civil Engineering, where he studied. In November, the Songhu War broke out, and soon Shanghai was occupied by the Japanese army. The following year, he returned to Zhejiang University and joined the Department of History and Geography. He moved westward with the school and spent three years in Jiande, Zhejiang Province, Ji&#39;an, Jiangxi Province, Yishan, Guangxi Province, and Zunyi, Guizhou Province. When he was in Yishan, he applied to transfer to the newly restored Department of Chinese Literature, but he still studied literature and science concurrently, including earth science, physics, calculus, three biographies of the Spring and Autumn Period, &quot;History&quot;, &quot;Han&quot;, Tang and Song poetry, Courses and books on text exegesis are also included in the elective exposition. He studied astronomy and calculus from Qian Baocong, poetry, literature and history from Miao Yue. He took elective courses such as He Zenglu&#39;s optics, Zhu Tinghu&#39;s earth science, Zhang Yinlin&#39;s history, etc. He studied political science with Fei Gong as his tutor, and he was fluent in both China and the West. The paper &quot;The Moon Has Slowness and the Sun Has Waxing and Shrinking, Also Discussing Chinese and Western Calendar&quot; written when he was in college was praised by Qian Baocong. He graduated from Zunyi in 1942 and stayed at the school to teach. He was the only teaching assistant in the department until 1947. In 1950, he concurrently served as secretary of the Academy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BpzJL1MrXfs621UY9ycsgV0WPey3cFZdk4jRjgqd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BpzJL1MrXfs621UY9ycsgV0WPey3cFZdk4jRjgqd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Letter of appointment from Mr. Liu Caonan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, the Chinese Academy of Sciences was preparing to compile the &quot;Chinese Science History Data Series&quot;, and Zhu Kezhen, then vice president, wanted to transfer him to Beijing. , the school refused to allow it and the trip failed to take place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years after he stayed in school, the old Zhejiang University’s liberal arts, science and engineering environment made him feel at home. Although wars were frequent, he himself wrote quite a lot, such as &quot;An Examination of the Origin and Origin of &quot;Island Arithmetic Scripture&quot;&quot;, which discussed many differences. Qian Baocong, Li Yan, and Qiu Chongman praised his skills and methods for determining the distance between the sun and the sun. Qiu said: &quot;This is the unfinished work of Yang Hui, Dai Zhen, and Li Huang. How can I compare it with others who play gong?&quot; The happiest period of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1952, the departments were adjusted and transferred to Zhejiang Normal University (renamed Hangzhou University in 1958). The old astronomical and calendar research was no longer sustainable. Due to work needs, he &quot;switched&quot; to the study of ancient literature, mainly teaching pre-Qin and Han literature. At this time, the teaching and research of ancient literature has required combining Marxist thought to extract the essence and eliminate the dross, and oppose cumbersome textual research. This is a new test for scholars from the old era, and I think Mr. Liu also No exception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, Mr. Liu passed the evaluation of the associate professor title and reported it to the Ministry of Education, but it was suspended due to the &quot;Four Clean-ups&quot; and the &quot;Cultural Revolution.&quot; The associate professor certification was restored in 1978. Promoted to professor in 1983. Retired in 1987. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a story in the middle. On October 27, 1964, &quot;A classmate submitted a written opinion to the classical literature teaching and research group, criticizing Mr. Liu Caonan&#39;s teaching of ancient mythology.&quot; The reason was that on September 16, Liu Caonan lectured on the myth of &quot;Gun and Yu&#39;s control of floods&quot;. The new counselor came to listen to the lecture. Under the background of &quot;never forget class struggle&quot;, the matter was upgraded to &quot;class struggle&quot;. the height of. On November 3, &quot;Mr. Liu Caonan examined the &#39;erroneous&#39; views in ancient myths previously discussed.&quot; After that, teacher Xu Shuofang came to the end on behalf of the teaching and research team. Teacher Xu gave a 25-minute speech, which not only affirmed the political sensitivity of the critics, but also supplemented the imperfections of the criticized lectures. The matter was settled. (The above is based on the article &quot;Remembering Xu Gong in Fragments&quot; by He Shengmo, a 1962 student in the Chinese Department) Mr. Liu&#39;s lectures seem to have failed to keep pace with the times, which is evident from this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s terms, Mr. Liu Caonan is actually a &quot;science and engineering man&quot; who has crossed over to the Chinese Department. He is good at mathematics, but fails to gauge people&#39;s hearts; he pays attention to precise details in his work, but is too realistic and does not know how to &quot;fuzzy processing&quot;, which makes him out of place; he has little interest in people, is full of enthusiasm for things, and is often immersed in his own emotions. Among them, I don’t know what night it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He summarized himself in his later years, saying: &quot;After listening to the teachings of Principal Oufang (Zhu Kezhen), Zhuoru (Qian Baocong), and Yanwei (Miao Yue), I knew that in order to learn, I must learn from Bo Huiyue. . The intersection of Chinese and Western elements, the infiltration of liberal arts and science, and the consideration of textual research, theory, and lyrics. Scholars are not only erudition, interrogation, careful thinking, discernment, and sincere practice; they must also study the laws of natural science and social science in depth, develop things and accomplish things, and enrich the country. Minye.&quot; (&quot;Preface&quot; to the first volume of &quot;Ancient Books and Science&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is indeed a heart-breaking argument. But how can &quot;the intersection of China and the West, the infiltration of liberal arts and sciences&quot; and &quot;the in-depth study of the laws of natural science and social science&quot; be easily achieved by people who are engaged in literature, history and philosophy? With the tone set so high, listeners may think that he only tailors it for themselves to promote themselves and suppress others, so most of them will sneer in response, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All the sages in ancient times were lonely. But are Mount Tai decadent, beams broken, and philosophers withered? Fortunately, the hills are still left, and all the relics are there. &quot;It sounds good to hear the sound of jade ke in the Zhao Dynasty.&quot; Let future generations comment on it! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[未知终点的旅程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/EaRWMUN5AGUC2ypEysvTSFIS8MlEbOKbtYzI0WYd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/EaRWMUN5AGUC2ypEysvTSFIS8MlEbOKbtYzI 0WYd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artist Ding Yi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Li Xiaoliang/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For abstract artists, there is an ultimate proposition that may run through the entire career, that is: after having formed their own iconic illustrations, how to &quot;effectively Repeat yourself”? In other words, how to use similar icons again and again but always give them new meaning, creating ever-changing combinations based on the language that you form? The answer varies from person to person. On this path, many abstract masters have left their own answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same problem also poses to curators. For those prolific artists who hold large-scale solo exhibitions every year, how to find new context and angles in their curatorial ideas? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l3qk2aavAUz7VlNfWCywRgzAGscaxX7VjL7yPpi9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l3qk2aavAUz7VlNfWCywRgzAGscaxX7VjL7yPpi9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Yi’s solo exhibition &quot;Hometown and Journey&quot; attempts to answer these propositions. This is also the first time that Ding Yi has returned to his hometown to hold a large-scale solo exhibition in his more than 30-year artistic career. The first stop of the exhibition is the Ningbo Art Museum. The art museum is located at the dockside of Ningbo’s Old Bund, and is where this port city opened hundreds of years ago. years of testimony. Ding Yi was born in Shanghai, but when he was a child, he often returned to his ancestral home, Ningbo. The Western-style Shanghai points to a rich external world, while Ningbo, which is also a port, points to the depths of history and culture. This is the inclusiveness of Shanghai-style civilization. The etiquette and customs of his hometown such as New Year celebrations, social operas, weddings and funerals, etc., still impress him to this day. What was particularly unforgettable was that he took a night boat from Shanghai back to Ningbo every week and sailed on the water all night. In addition to the fishing fires, the starlight in the sky was refracted on the sparkling water - he later saw this mapping relationship countless times, whether in Looking up at the stars in the sky from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, or looking down at the city lights on the ground while flying, the world and the sky share the same abstract and bright patterns, all of which enter into his paintings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xwMZCcL9MXVq4fDdtWbe7zHkfaIBbrZxuSh17RGI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;485&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xwMZCcL9MXVq4fDdtWbe7zHkfaIBbrZxuSh17RGI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Yi, &quot;Signs of Crosses 2023-B3&quot;, 2023, mineral pigment, toner, charcoal, pencil, acrylic on rice paper, 350cm×720cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ding Yi Studio/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The exhibition itself is like a journey. Besides Ningbo Art Museum, Huamao Art Education Museum serves as the second stop of the exhibition. Echoing this kind of artistic context combing with travel as a clue. Because of his work, Ding Yi often travels around the world and maintains the habit of painting along the way. &quot;In recent years, I have traveled to many countries and regions, and I feel that they are the birthplaces of ancient human civilization, such as Egypt and Greece. , India, Arabia, Africa, etc., have all experienced glorious and powerful periods and are part of the world as a whole, so I incorporate these travels into my creative thinking.&quot; - These small works on paper are like graphic versions of Diary: Barcelona is the mottled brown, red and black colors on the vellum paper, Athens is the solemn temple columns on the golden coast, Istanbul is the shadowy acupuncture geometric patterns in the pure white, Cairo is the pyramids under the blazing sun, Alxa is There are layers of gold-plated Gobi yellow sand, and Osaka is filled with various shades of green... Ding Yi still uses his usual cross pattern, but his obsession with &quot;fighting against painterliness&quot; has long since disappeared. In fact, when facing Ding Yi&#39;s original works, what one feels is the richness of painting. Different media and techniques make this exploration more and more in-depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xKUsWPz6S5sEifm8nIBYV3wGdFFGaxuInMMuIPdB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;528&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xKUsWPz6S5sEifm8nIBYV3wGdFFGaxuInMMuIPdB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256539&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Exhibition view of Huamao Art Education Museum&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The migration and flow of people may be one of the biggest changes in the times in the past 30 years. This can be seen everywhere in the exhibition hall The traces of movement reflect the small history of individuals and the big history of social change: in addition to the departure and return from hometown and the relocation of studios, the footprints left by artists around the world, and even the paintings themselves have become the subject of movement. In many Below the paintings, the places where they have been exhibited around the world are recorded, as if they are also traveling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qyqHZ8NjmCYCmM1TARXdzBqQLyrBZSPoZx8OpE2D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;685&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qyqHZ8NjmCYCmM1TARXdzBqQLyrBZSPoZx8OpE2D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Yi, &quot;Travel Notes&quot;, Varadero, Cuba, 2017, water-soluble colored pencils on sketchbook, 21cm×30cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Ding Yi Studio/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A work created in 1988 marks the beginning of the &quot;Cross&quot; series and is also the starting point of this journey. Five years later, Ding Yi&#39;s works participated in the 45th Venice Biennale, the First Asia-Pacific Art Triennial and the Chinese Avant-Garde Art Exhibition, officially beginning the internationalization of Chinese contemporary artists. After that, &quot;Cross&quot;&#39;s footprints spread all over the world. These works traveled across the ocean, were displayed and seen, and became a carrier of cultural and memory exchanges. Ding Yi&#39;s important early works are densely marked: Berlin, Birmingham, Bilbao, Bologna, Rotterdam... It seems that this painting has acquired a deeper personality due to frequent travels. Those marked His wandering is like a medal: a veteran who has seen a lot and made great achievements in battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Pc95Jx9xMhvB6Mh1YKl7hr64oqqASDLICt2waIYd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;727&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Pc95Jx9xMhvB6Mh1YKl7hr64oqqASDLICt2waIYd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Yi, &quot;Travel Notes&quot;, Ningbo, China, 2023, water-soluble colored pencils on sketchbook, 19.5cm×27cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Ding Yi Studio/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A time journey that aims to look back on the past has gained a spatial dimension, but the end of the journey is unknown, and the future has not yet been closed. Everything is still there. The openness continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[双十一前“底价”之争：头部主播陷罗生门，地方指引有待观望]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260286]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Double Eleven shopping carnival is coming. In the past few days, the &quot;low-price agreement&quot; controversy in the live broadcast room has arisen again and again. From the lead anchor Li Jiaqi being accused of &quot;choosing one of the two&quot;, to Brother Yang angrily criticizing Li Jiaqi for &quot;price monopoly&quot;, and then Brother Dayang&#39;s company was revealed to have a price guarantee agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a time, the &quot;minimum price agreement&quot; hidden behind the leading anchors was put on the table, and a storm of public opinion about price and law began. An industry insider told reporters from Nandu and N Video, &quot;In the past few years, anchors would clarify the content of the &#39;minimum price agreement&#39;, but now they may find ways to avoid this expression, such as &#39;This price must be the maximum discount given by the brand.&#39;&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, on October 30, Hangzhou issued the &quot;Livestreaming E-commerce Industry Compliance Guidelines (Draft for Comments)&quot; which clarified that livestreaming e-commerce practitioners must not require merchants to sign a &quot;minimum price agreement.&quot; . Zheng Ning, director of the Law Department of the School of Cultural Industry Management of Communication University of China, told Nandu reporters that this is a &quot;Guideline&quot; issued at the local level and has no mandatory legal effect. It may not be applicable to other regions, but it can serve as a leading example for the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Reduced Price Controversy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of October, a salesperson posted on WeChat Moments that Li Jiaqi was suspected of &quot;choosing one of the two.&quot; It stated that it received a lawyer&#39;s letter from the brand owner Hai&#39;s. The brand complained that because the price of a certain Hai&#39;s oven on the platform was lower than the price of Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast, it violated the &quot;reservoir price agreement&quot; signed between them and Li Jiaqi and required huge liquidated damages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Hai&#39;s issued a statement stating that it had not signed any &quot;reserve price agreement&quot; with the channel mentioned by the sales staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Nandu reporters asked the relevant person in charge of Li Jiaqi’s operator Meizhi (Shanghai) Network Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Meizhi Company&quot;), the other party did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company’s official website competition and compliance announcement states that “Meijia strictly adheres to the principles of equality, voluntariness, fairness, honesty and credit, and fully respects the independent business rights of merchants.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And that’s it. Not long ago, a &quot;post-90s&quot; investment specialist of Meizhi Company took advantage of his position to provide merchants with help in product selection and live broadcast scheduling, and collected over one million yuan in benefits. He was found guilty of bribery by non-state personnel and position-related crimes. Crime of embezzlement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 4, Meishi Company issued a statement stating that the labor contract had been terminated and that there was no green channel for the investment and product selection process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noticed that on the same day that the sales staff shouted to Li Jiaqi, e-commerce anchor Dayang Ge angrily criticized Li Jiaqi for price control in the &quot;Crazy Little Yang Ge&quot; live broadcast room, &quot;How much lower are we than Li Jiaqi?&quot; , then nothing can be sold, he can build a platform by himself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09 /a7abe56dd7eedceb164fef353547f911.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;609&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /09/a7abe56dd7eedceb164fef353547f911.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257719&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brother Yang said Li Jiaqi controls prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is intriguing is that not long after Brother Yang angrily criticized Li Jiaqi, it was revealed that the live broadcast room of &quot;Crazy Little Brother Yang&quot; had an insured contract, and &quot;the amount of compensation stipulated in the event of breach of contract is 1 million yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Supply Chain&quot; column of the official website of Hefei Sanguangyang Network Technology Co., Ltd., the company to which &quot;Crazy Little Yang&quot; belongs, points out the requirement for &quot;price control&quot;, that is, &quot;the whole network has the same price&quot; We control the price of each product to ensure that the live broadcast room is truly cost-effective.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One wave has not subsided, but another wave has arisen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, netizens discovered that Simba’s Douyin account had been banned. According to people familiar with the matter, &quot;Simba has repeatedly published false information on Douyin, insulted and abused, and provoked wars.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noticed that in a previous live broadcast on Douyin, Simba once said &quot;I don&#39;t care about your platform, nor your traffic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/7720cb332ccc203bee21691c08866cd6 .jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;518&quot; height=&quot;839&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09 /7720cb332ccc203bee21691c08866cd6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257718&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Simba’s Douyin account has been banned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that Simba sold a Mousse mattress originally priced at more than 20,000 yuan for 4,980 yuan in a previous live broadcast, bringing more than 1 billion in goods to Mousse live broadcast. This caused dissatisfaction among many offline dealers of Mousse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The day before his account was banned, Simba angrily shouted in the Douyin live broadcast room, &quot;Can you please stop messing with me? I, Xin Youzhi, don&#39;t have the ability to monopolize an industry.&quot; &quot;No matter how much I sell, It doesn’t matter to you, my customers are not your users, and Mousse mattresses are not allowed to be taken off the shelves before the 31st.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a time, a storm of public opinion surrounding the live broadcast e-commerce industry was unfolding. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Monopoly suspicion&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The floor price agreement definitely exists.” On November 4, Mr. Li, a brand manager in the cosmetics industry, told Nandu reporters &quot;In the past few years, it would have been written very clearly. Now anchors may find ways to avoid this expression. For example, &#39;this price must be the maximum discount given by the brand&#39;, which means the same thing as &#39;minimum price agreement&#39;, but The way of expression is different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the brand violates the &#39;minimum price agreement&#39;, the anchor may not necessarily file a lawsuit with the brand, but he may not help the brand bring goods, or may not do so in the future. Cooperation.&quot; Mr. Li believes that this kind of loss is unbearable for the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the day after the sales staff shouted out Li Jiaqi, the person in charge of home appliances and furniture of an e-commerce platform posted in Moments, &quot;Some top anchors deprive consumers of their enjoyment for their own selfish interests. It’s really a chaos of low-price rights, and we must resist the overbearing clauses of ‘low-price agreements’ across the entire network.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Does the “low-price agreement” signed between the anchor and the brand involve a violation of the “Anti-Monopoly Law” Behavior? Ding Maozhong, director of the Competition Law Research Center of Shanghai University of Political Science and Law, told Nandu reporters that this requires standardized analysis. Judging from the identification standards of the Anti-Monopoly Law, a clear conclusion cannot yet be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Monopoly agreements are divided into horizontal monopoly agreements and vertical monopoly agreements. The prerequisite for a horizontal monopoly agreement is that there is a competitive relationship between operators, and there is no competitive relationship between the anchor and the brand.&quot; Ding Maozhong explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the vertical monopoly agreement mainly depends on whether it has a dominant market position and whether there is abuse of market dominance. &quot;This requires a series of normative analyses. For example, the prerequisite for abusing a dominant market position is that the operator must have a dominant market position. Judging from the current situation, it cannot be concluded whether the anchor violates the Anti-Monopoly Law.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;So, what is &quot;choose one&quot; behavior? Ding Maozhong explained that this is an abuse of market dominance to restrict transactions. &quot;First of all, the operator must have a dominant market position. Secondly, the operator, without legitimate reasons, restricts the transaction counterparty to only trade with it or only with its designated operator, which constitutes the so-called &#39;choose one of the two&#39;. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether Li Jiaqi is involved in &quot;choosing one of the two,&quot; Ding Maozhong said that this also requires a standardized analysis based on specific factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Development Prospects&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether it is a &quot;lower price agreement&quot; or a &quot;choose one&quot;, it is actually a battle between anchors about the &quot;lowest price&quot; scramble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/84b59e1f2611a479a79830ddb24b44af.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;384&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/84b59e1f2611a479a79830ddb24b44af.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257720&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The lead anchor Li Jiaqi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Li, the brand manager of the cosmetics industry, believes that excessive pursuit of “minimizing” prices is not a good thing for brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The anchor keeps the brand&#39;s price to the lowest, and the brand may think about how to reduce production costs simultaneously, and the quality will also decrease relatively. And this is a fatal blow to the innovation of the company.&quot; He said, Enterprises no longer aim at product upgrades, but are forced to find cheaper production methods, which is actually a step back for the development of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, the anchor is seeking benefits for consumers by requiring merchants to sign a &quot;lower price agreement.&quot; In fact, the &quot;lowest price on the entire network&quot; serves as a trump card for anchors to attract consumers and promotes the popularity of live broadcast rooms. It not only increases the influence of anchors, but can even further increase their live broadcast commissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The increase in the profits of anchors selling goods also eats up the development space of brands. In the long run, the industry cannot sustain healthy development, low-priced products will eventually disappear, and consumers will have to pay for new high-priced products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the “lowest prices” that can be seen everywhere in the live broadcast room, who sets the price of the product? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Maozhong introduced that live broadcast pricing does not deviate from the legal framework. The Price Law divides pricing into two categories: one is market independent pricing, and the other is regulated by the government. Among the products promoted and sold by anchors, products that do not fall within the scope of government guidance or pricing are all market-regulated prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Price Law&quot; stipulates that in principle, sales at a loss, price gouging and other behaviors that seriously disrupt the market order cannot be carried out. The &quot;Consumer Rights and Interests Protection Law&quot; also stipulates that consumers&#39; rights to fair transactions must be ensured. Buying and selling must be fair and reasonable, and prices must be clearly marked. Prices must not be increased first and then reduced through promotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Standardize order&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments have also issued relevant &quot;Guidelines&quot; regarding the pricing of e-commerce live broadcasts to regulate market development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, Hangzhou released the &quot;Livestreaming E-commerce Industry Compliance Guidelines (Draft for Comments)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guidelines&quot;), soliciting opinions and suggestions from all walks of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is mentioned that live broadcast e-commerce practitioners shall not require merchants to sign a &quot;minimum price agreement&quot; or adopt other agreements, decisions or coordinated actions that exclude or restrict competition, except for those that do not constitute a monopoly agreement according to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding the legal content of prices, live broadcast e-commerce practitioners are reminded not to abuse their independent pricing rights through low-price dumping, price collusion, price gouging, price fraud, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The “Guidelines” released this time have national demonstration significance.” Zheng Ning, director of the Law Department of the School of Cultural Industry Management of Communication University of China, told Nandu reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Ning said, &quot;The &quot;Guidelines&quot; are an integration of existing regulations for live broadcast e-commerce. They provide a certain degree of operability for how live broadcast e-commerce can establish compliance systems before, during and after the event. &quot;Guidance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Of course, we must also see that this &quot;Guideline&quot; does not have mandatory legal effect after all.&quot; Zheng Ning believes that this is a &quot;Guideline&quot; issued at the local level and may not directly apply to other region, but it can serve as a leading example for the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effectiveness of the &quot;Guidelines&quot; remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She suggested that from the regulatory perspective, inspections and law enforcement should be stepped up, and strict enforcement of laws and regulations should be carried out. At the same time, consumers should also be encouraged to actively supervise and report and safeguard their rights legitimately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the platform itself, live broadcast e-commerce platforms must strengthen personnel and system construction and improve compliance management levels. From an industry perspective, the most important thing is to give full play to the role of industry self-discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Maozhong told Nandu reporters that in the supervision of the live broadcast e-commerce industry, platforms have the responsibility to manage product promotion. &quot;For typical violations of laws and regulations, the platform can make requirements and some advocacy suggestions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260307]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73362&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70174&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/8fc5b440c4.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3197.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hong Huanhuan teaches her sister-in-law to make paper flowers using toilet paper .Photo courtesy of interviewee&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/8fc5b440c4.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;257770&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan taught her sister-in-law to make paper flowers using toilet paper. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until October 25, 2023, Hong Huanhuan’s relatives and friends came to the community and held up placards asking the residents here to provide information about her life in the past year or so. , the details of the work, residents of Building 14 of Yintai Yuhuayuan in Wuhan, Hubei Province realized that an ambulance had pulled a female domestic worker away from the building three days ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since September 2022, Hong Huanhuan, as a live-in nanny, has been taking care of the children of her employer Xiong, a pair of twins who have just turned two years old. On the morning of October 22, 2023, the 38-year-old fell to the ground at Xiong’s home. A few hours later, relatives and friends rushed to the hospital after hearing the news and saw her body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;What impressed me most was my sister&#39;s eyes that she never closed until she died, and the tears in the corners of her eyes.&quot; On October 31, Hong Huanhuan&#39;s brother Hong Mingxuan told Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The last time Hong Huanhuan saw her family was during the May Day holiday in 2023. She and her husband returned to their hometown in Hanchuan, Hubei Province to visit their children and the elderly at home. Over the next five months, whenever someone wanted to ask her out, she always said she was too busy at her employer&#39;s house. In early October, Xiong informed the housekeeping company by phone that Dabao accidentally injured his leg when Hong Huanhuan took her child to play on the slide on October 2. The housekeeping company immediately offered to visit her, but Xiong refused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When we meet again, we will be separated forever. The family found a wound on her head and multiple bruises on her body and immediately called the police. The doctor told Hong Mingxuan that Hong Huanhuan had no heartbeat at Xiong&#39;s home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73361&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70173&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/50a4245fe2.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3196.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wuhan, Hubei, Yintai Yuhuayuan Community, the building where Xiong Lan lives. Southern Weekend reporter Photo by Wang Xuqiulin&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/50a4245fe2.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;257771&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wuhan, Hubei, Yintai Yuhuayuan Community, the building where the employer Xiong lives Building. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;First time moving into the home&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It has been nearly 10 years since Yintai Yuhuayuan was built. Lianjia APP shows that this community’s historical transaction volume and listing price of nearly 25,000 yuan per square meter are the highest in Wuhan’s Baibuting area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Several neighbors recalled that in 2020 or even earlier, Xiong bought the four-bedroom, two-bedroom apartment in Yintai Yuhuayuan from the previous resident. Wei&#39;s house has an area of ​​about 160 square meters. Wang Yifei, a neighbor across the door, told Southern Weekend reporters that he visited Xiong&#39;s house when it was being renovated. It was &quot;Chinese style, all made of mahogany, very luxurious. It is said to have been left behind by the previous owner.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Yifei said that he likes to chat with people, but does not like to deal with Xiong, because the other party often talks about issues such as community hygiene, neighbor decoration, and exercise noise downstairs. In the building group, they criticized others and used fierce language. Sometimes when he meets Hong Huanhuan in the elevator, Wang Yifei will chat with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, a Southern Weekend reporter called Xiong’s contact number and it showed that the machine was down. According to the content recorded on Xiong’s short video account, she is born in the 1970s. She previously worked in the female body care business in Zaozhuang, Shandong, Xuzhou, Jiangsu and other places. She returned to Hubei in 2020 and opened a shop on the second floor of Yintai Yuhuayuan in the second half of the year. opened a beauty salon. Currently, the beauty salon is closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A merchant surnamed Yuan downstairs of the beauty salon recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Xiong&#39;s hometown is in Huangpi, Wuhan, and he bought the second-floor store from himself in 2020. , the lease term was agreed to be three years. Less than a year later, due to pregnancy, he planned to sell the store, and there was &quot;a little dispute&quot; when he quit the lease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The husband did not appear in the short video taken by Xiong. After returning to Wuhan, most of the content she posted was related to emotions, and sometimes she revealed her depressed side. At the end of August 2021, the twins, a boy and a girl, were born. From the moment the baby could raise his head, to babbling, to taking the baby for a walk, she liked to share everything online. She said that she wanted to be a happy mother for the sake of her children, but she also said that whether her temper was good or not depended on &quot;how you treat me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 6, after the child was injured while playing on the slide, Xiong asked among his neighbors if there were any hourly workers he knew well, and asked him to cook lunch once a day and clean the house. Home Hygiene. Many neighbors recalled that they had never met Xiong&#39;s husband. Before that, Xiong&#39;s father occasionally came over to help with the child, but he returned to his home two months before the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73364&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70176&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/e6c72907f9.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3200.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 31, 2023, the door of Xiong Lan&#39;s house was closed, and no one answered the knock on the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e6c72907f9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257772&quot; style =&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 28, 2023, the door of Xiong’s house was closed, and no one answered the knock on the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan was an employee of Wuhan Auntie Lai Housekeeping Service Co., Ltd. during his lifetime. Carrying twins for Xiong was Hong Huanhuan&#39;s first job since she was transferred to a new job as a nanny, with a monthly salary of 6,500 yuan. In the opinion of a colleague named Hu, the salary of this job is not high. According to the market price in Wuhan, it costs 6,000-8,000 yuan for a nanny to take care of a child who is not in kindergarten. &quot;Generally, two aunts take care of twins.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the job transfer, Hong Huanhuan&#39;s position was as a domestic agent. Former colleague Gao Xuemei explained to a reporter from Southern Weekend that in a housekeeping company, an agent&#39;s income mainly depends on personal performance. &quot;The more orders you sign, the more you get.&quot; In the past few years due to the epidemic, some domestic workers have had a heavy financial burden and have chosen to change careers. The wages of domestic agents have also dropped from seven to eight thousand yuan per month to at most four to five thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan’s husband Wu Qiang works on the assembly line of an electronics factory in Wuhan, and his father-in-law has a pension. My father-in-law passed away due to illness in 2021. My 70-year-old mother-in-law has underlying diseases and has to take care of their two children who are in school in their hometown in Hanchuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I didn&#39;t make much money in the past few years, so my sister said I needed a stable job.&quot; Hong Mingxuan explained the reason why Hong Huanhuan became a nanny. His wife is the general manager of Wuhan Auntie Housekeeping Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan and Hong Huanhuan grew up together. He recalled that after graduating from junior high school, his sister first went to work in Guangdong and then went to Zhangjiakou to set up a stall. In 2018, she returned to Wuhan to work as a housekeeper to be closer to the children and to take care of the elderly. During this period, she took the nanny qualification certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Xuemei recalled that the two met in October 2022 after Hong Huanhuan moved into the household. Hong Huanhuan said that she and Xiong took care of the baby together. She took the baby to bed at night, and the child&#39;s grandfather was responsible for doing housework. Hong Huanhuan mentioned that her clients like to keep their homes clean. Although she does not need to do most of the hygiene, she will help with cleaning and washing baby clothes as long as she has time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时洪欢欢告诉高雪梅，“宝妈（熊某）有时候可能情绪不太好，有时候会骂人”，有时候会冲她发脾气，对她好的时候又很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我把客户家孩子摔骨折了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;孩子玩滑梯的事故发生后，熊某的短视频账号十几天都没有更新。 10月16日，她在新视频里唱“我羡慕的幸福总是得不到，爱我我爱的人也没有照顾好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上述商户回忆，此前，熊某和洪欢欢常带着两个孩子在小区花园和周边遛弯。 10月初的一天，她曾见到熊某满脸通红，仿佛喝了酒，边走边骂身后的洪欢欢“太狠心了”。接下来几天，洪欢欢来她店里取快递，她发现对方“神情不太好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据流传的说法，熊某在孩子玩滑梯受伤后，要求洪欢欢赔偿10万元。洪明轩向南方周末记者确认了这一数额。洪明轩、高雪梅、吴强的二姐称，事情发生后，洪欢欢在微信上找他们或身边人借过钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月，高雪梅老家的冬枣成熟，她给洪欢欢发微信：“欢欢，你把家里的地址给我，寄枣子给你。”10月12日晚11点多，洪欢欢回：“不要寄，没有心情吃，我把客户家孩子的腿给摔骨折了。”高雪梅追问，洪欢欢没有回复。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月20日，高雪梅收到洪欢欢的文字消息：“亲爱的，你手里有钱吗？能不能借我一万块钱？”她回复：“欢欢，不好意思，我妈妈在前两个月查出来癌症，这个月在放化疗，可能还要做个手术。我确实手里没有多钱给你。”洪欢欢告诉她：“没事没事，我这边也处理得差不多了，给你们添麻烦了。”这是她们最后的联系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴强二姐说，事发前几天，洪欢欢也找吴强的大姐借过钱。大姐没说什么就把钱打了过去。事后大姐与她谈起这次匆忙的视频通话，回想起当时洪欢欢在熊某家里全程戴着口罩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴强二姐后来计算，10月以来，吴强及亲戚朋友一共给了洪欢欢6.1万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩也借了钱给姐姐，他说当时没多问，毕竟孩子受伤，姐姐需要赔钱也可以理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩称，2022年上户前，洪欢欢检出有胆结石，其他指标都正常，但他没有提供对应的体检报告。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们并不知晓洪欢欢为何突然离世。多位受访邻居表示，没有留意这家人的动静，只有王逸飞安装在走廊里的摄像头记录了10月21、22日两天里，这家人部分出入情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;21日上午8点35分、10点26分和17点32分，熊某、洪欢欢以及一位短发中年女性带着两个孩子分别出入家门三次。其中短发女性一直带着女孩，熊某推着坐有男孩的车，洪欢欢穿着灰色短袖和灰色长裤。两次出门时，洪欢欢都戴着口罩，出现在镜头前时，她没有带孩子，总是拎着手提袋、菜或者垃圾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73363&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70175&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e26d751080.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3199.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;监控录像中，2023年10月21日，熊蓝（左）和洪欢欢（右）走出电梯口。视频截图&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e26d751080.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257773&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;监控录像中，2023年10月21日，熊某（左）和洪欢欢（右）走出电梯口。视频截图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;摄像头未记录21日晚上他们五人何时回到家中。直到22日上午9点2分，监控录像显示，4名急救人员分别带着医用氧气袋、急救包、担架等设备敲开了熊某家的门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9分钟后，急救人员将洪欢欢抬出熊某家。此时，熊某跟着担架一起出门，又站在门外看向屋内，屋内还站着一名男子。这位男子此前没在视频里出现过，邻居和洪欢欢的亲戚均表示不认识这名男子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10秒后的监控录像显示，熊某家的门关上了，所有急救人员都站在电梯间。熊某左手多出一件绿色外套，右手提着3个塑料袋，也从走廊挤进电梯间。一个男声问：“她之前有一点混沌（音）？”女声回答：“对对对。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据洪明轩讲述，22日送医院后，家政公司曾接到熊某的电话，说洪欢欢在家“晕倒了”。家政公司立刻通知洪欢欢的家人，同时派人赶往医院。洪明轩说当时自己离医院比较近，最先赶到，家政公司、洪欢欢的父母、丈夫和其他亲友随后陆续赶来，“结果得知我姐姐已经不在了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩赶到时已接近中午，此前，洪欢欢已在医院接受了一个半小时左右的抢救措施，“雇主坚持要送医抢救”。他未向南方周末记者提供洪欢欢的死亡证明，上面一般会注明死亡时间。他解释，由于警方已立案侦查，目前医院未给家属开具死亡证明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;监控录像显示，熊某在洪欢欢送医当天的10点58分和13点30分各回了一趟家。当天15点21分，数名警察来到熊某的家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴强二姐在22日下午赶到派出所。她回忆，在派出所看见了熊某，因情绪激动二人发生推搡，最后她被民警拉开；旁边还有一名男子，“听说是她（熊某）老公”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来洪明轩从家政公司了解到，熊某的丈夫平时在广东做生意，事发头一天回到武汉；熊某在武汉没有正式工作，日常在家带娃。洪明轩说，除了22日在派出所见过熊某一面，再未见过，“情况说明没有，道歉也没有”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月25日，武汉市公安局江岸区分局后湖派出所工作人员对媒体称，警方已经立案，嫌疑人已被控制，案件具体原委还在调查中。 11月7日，后湖派出所工作人员告诉南方周末记者，案件情况暂不对外回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;五个月未见家人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢的同事张立佳说，家政公司给每个上户的阿姨买了保险，如果阿姨上户时出现意外，如受伤、损坏雇主财物等，24小时内告知家政和保险公司，可以启动理赔流程，“每个阿姨都会经过这方面的培训”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢从2018年开始做家政经纪人，熟悉家政工上户遇到意外时的处理方式。 “我想不通，为什么几天后，才由宝妈通知公司孩子出了事。”张立佳说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当经纪人时，洪欢欢和张立佳在办公室的阁楼上一起住了一年多。她们经常一起做饭，一起唱歌，夏天下班后，还会在门店门口支一张桌子，一起喝酒吃宵夜。但洪欢欢上户后，两人见面的机会少了很多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月24日，张立佳给洪欢欢发微信，问她在做什么，洪欢欢没有回复。张立佳以为她只是忙。 “小龙虾下来那会（夏天），我问她要不要一起出来吃，她说估计最近没空，等大闸蟹出来（秋冬）再一起吃吧。”张立佳2023年夏天联系洪欢欢时，对方曾这样和她约定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢很喜欢拍短视频，记录和家人聚会、与同事去海边、带孩子出去玩的日常。这些内容经常更新，一个月总有好几条。转岗上户后，尽管频率有所下降，她还是发过照片，记录感染新冠、过年聚会、出门散步时的一些片段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;4月30日，她和女儿合拍了一条一起唱歌的短视频，配文：“新买的亲子睡衣，这娃非得要拍个视频。”此后，这个账号再没发过新内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那次正值洪欢欢和吴强一起回汉川。二人的老家都在一个镇上，相隔两公里左右。这也是多位亲人回忆他们最后一次见到洪欢欢的时候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;老家亲人说，“五一”洪欢欢看上去还好好的。吴强的母亲回忆，儿子儿媳结婚15年来，她就没见两人拌过一句嘴，即便自己有时候脾气急，洪欢欢也没与她发生过争执。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73360&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70172&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/9c383803f7.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3195.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;湖北汉川，洪欢欢老家村口。南方周末记者汪徐秋林摄&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/9c383803f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257774&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;湖北汉川，洪欢欢老家村口。南方周末记者汪徐秋林摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢同事介绍，育儿嫂每个月有4天假期，有事也可以和客户请假。吴强此前在武汉的工作地附近租了一间房，离银泰御华园不算近，但洪欢欢每次休假都会过去，如果有空，二人再一起回老家看孩子。每次休假找吴强前，洪欢欢还会先去洪明轩家看父母。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但2023年五一假期过后，洪欢欢没有休过假。洪明轩见姐姐好几个月不来，向母亲询问姐姐的近况，“我总让妈妈劝姐姐，钱是赚不完的，可每次我们让她休假，她总说宝妈家的孩子离不开她”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩“五一”没回汉川，错过了与姐姐最后团聚的机会，现在回想起来，他很后悔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢有两个手机，做家政经纪人时基本24小时在线，但做了家政阿姨后，她往往不会及时回复信息。高雪梅解释，家政阿姨在带宝宝时不看手机被视为一种职业操守，除非查看时间或遇到紧急事情，否则她们要等到晚上宝宝睡觉才联系家人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩说，上户带两个孩子后，家里知道洪欢欢工作忙，没有急事也不会多找她。母亲平时与洪欢欢联系得多，她“不会长时间不回信息”，但“五一”过后，洪欢欢在家族群里很少发言，有时好几天才回复信息，其中有一段时间，母亲有过一个多星期没联系上女儿，很着急。他们通过家政公司找到熊某，与洪欢欢通了电话，得到的说法是“她的手机坏了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪明轩说，后来从姐姐的朋友那里了解到，“雇主没收过她的手机”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;多位亲友表示，洪欢欢曾私下说觉得这份工作“很累”，不想续约了，等熊某找到合适的育儿嫂就下户。但2023年9月，做满一年时，她还是与对方新签了一份合同。高雪梅当时问洪欢欢为何续签，洪欢欢告诉她，“做生不如做熟嘛，跟客户、宝贝都比较熟悉了，那就继续做”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此时，洪欢欢和自己的孩子已近5个月没见面。得知洪欢欢国庆假期无法休假回家后，家里人曾与她约好，在做工的小区楼下和孩子见一面。但10月1日当天，吴强开车带两个孩子从汉川来到武汉，在银泰御华园门口等洪欢欢出来时，她的手机又联系不上了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“住家没有下班”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高雪梅记得，一年前见面时洪欢欢说过：“宝妈（熊某）不容易，要带孩子，（还要）跟我一起做事情，她也教了我很多东西，还有就是不愿意给经纪人找麻烦。我尽量把这个单子做完，把这个合同（期）做满。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;第一次上户，洪欢欢平常的求助总是与熊某的孩子有关。 2023年6、7月，她微信问高雪梅：“宝宝总红屁屁是怎么回事？给宝宝穿尿不湿的时候总是会侧漏怎么回事？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张立佳说自己不是洪欢欢的经纪人，无法对洪欢欢作为家政阿姨的业务能力做出评价，但她认为，“阿姨总是有缺点的”，“给她一点耐心和包容，人才会慢慢成长”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在高雪梅眼里，家政工作面对的是人，不可能不投入感情，“尤其是对孩子，要是没有爱心、没有耐心的话，做不了这件事情”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张立佳一直想让“家政工”这份工作更专业化。她刻意保持着一些习惯，比如与客户交流前先出示名片、展示印有自己穿职业装的海报、上班前化妆。办公室的墙上也贴着家政阿姨在公司接受培训后可以掌握的十几种技能。 “客户在家庭以外为社会作贡献，我们也在家庭里让客户没有后顾之忧。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但她也承认，家政阿姨这个群体，学历一般不高，经济也不宽裕，上户面对不同客户的要求，焦虑也是常态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;做家政经纪人之前，张立佳也做过住家的育儿嫂。 “住家就像24小时服务，没有下班。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;做经纪人后，张立佳需要在家政阿姨上户需要帮助时安抚对方的情绪，比如有阿姨会与她反映，被雇主指责吃得太多、做饭不好吃……“很多时候她们没法和家人说委屈。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“追悔莫及。”另一位与洪欢欢关系较好的同事说，家政阿姨一天24小时都在户上，她担心与洪欢欢聊天会影响其工作和休息，因此没有与洪欢欢语音或视频过，“没有更早发现一些异样”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢曾经的办公室藏在武汉一个高端小区的一楼商铺里。这个60平方米左右的办公室有厨房、卫生间和宿舍。张立佳说，有时一些阿姨休假，离家远没法回家，就会来这住两天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;现在这里还留着洪欢欢生前置办的置物架、小黑板、绿植、药品、挂钩。洪欢欢上户后，张立佳就坐在她曾经的工位上，“哪里都是欢欢的痕迹”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;处理洪欢欢留在门店的旧物时，张立佳留下了她们俩一起唱歌的话筒。她说原来两人住在阁楼里时，一个人睡红蚊帐，一个人睡白蚊帐，自封“红莲教主”和“白莲教主”。 “她就像我的妹妹，曾经给我们的生活带来了这么多欢乐。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;洪欢欢离世后，不少家政阿姨在她的社交账号下表达哀思。也有一些阿姨给张立佳发消息表示担忧。 “大家思念她，也有一部分是想到了自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中洪明轩、王逸飞、高雪梅、吴强、张立佳为化名，姚智丽、南方周末实习生杜逢对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融稳定法立法提速：“治未病”与“治已病”如何更有效？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;酝酿多年之后，金融稳定法有望在第十四届人大任期内完成立法程序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日，受国务院委托，中国人民银行行长潘功胜在第十四届全国人民代表大会常务委员会第六次会议上作国务院关于金融工作情况的报告时称，加快推进金融稳定法立法工作。此前的9月7日，十四届全国人大常委会发布立法规划，金融稳定法被列为一类项目，即&lt;span>;“条件比较成熟、任期内拟提请审议的法律草案”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融稳定法（草案）（下称《草案》）如何吸收和吸取过往国内金融风险案件处置经验和教训？不同监管机构如何协同？如何让地方政府不干扰但不躺平？金融稳定保障基金来源如何解决？它与金融稳定保障基金、存款保险基金、行业保障基金之间有何关联？公开征求意见的人民银行版和全国人大版草案有何实质不同？它如何借鉴国际相关法律规定和国际通用做法？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员就上述问题对比研究两个版本差异之处，并横向研究多国金融稳定基金的操作路径，更与业内专家进行探讨交流。草案核心纲领旨在从跨行业和跨部门的角度对金融稳定制度作出统筹安排，侧重于应对重大金融风险；立法要点上，草案从事前防范、事中化解和事后处置三阶段明确金融风险的工作要点，同时界定金融机构、地方政府和监管部门等相关主体的职责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，金融稳定法不仅立足于预防金融风险即“治未病”，还着眼于有效处置金融风险，即“治已病”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;全球金融风险频次增加&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;纵观世界金融史，从18世纪的阿姆斯特丹到2008年的纽约，系统性金融危机一直伴随金融业的潮起潮落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具有讽刺意味的是，2008年金融危机爆发前夕，花旗集团CEO Chuck Prince于2007年的一句话成为名言：“当名为&#39;流动性&#39;的音乐戛然而止（金融危机到来），事情就棘手了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融稳定法立法提速之际，全球局部金融风险频次提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，全球局部金融风险时有发生。继美国3月初的银行挤兑和硅谷银行(SVB) 崩盘之后，签名银行(Signature Bank) 随之倒闭。市场恐慌迅速蔓延至欧洲，全球系统重要性银行瑞士信贷集团倒闭。旦夕之间，瑞士差点面临全面银行挤兑。欧元区银行普遍承压，德意志银行因投资者集体抛售股票而面临压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，针对欧元区银行在快速上升利率下的敞口，欧洲央行展开了全行业调查，试图了解风险可能如何扩散到其他行业，并进行压力测试。国际货币基金组织2023年曾出面就全球快速扩张的非银金融机构可能出现的全球金融危机发出警告。这些机构包括保险公司、养老基金、共同基金和高风险对冲基金。影子银行和复杂的金融工具使风险通过相互关联的金融机构得以滋生和蔓延。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未雨绸缪，“治未病”与“治已病”如何有效结合&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;成为各国首要之务。金融稳定法可以更好地将“治已病”和“治未病”相结合，建立健全金融风险预防、预警、处置和问责制度体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;强调&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;被处置机构的自救责任&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;金融稳定法为何被列为一类项目？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员发现，近年来，我国金融立法工作稳步推进，已形成以中国人民银行法、商业银行法、证券法和保险法等金融基础法律为统领，以金融行政法规、部门规章和规范性文件为重要内容、地方性法规为补充的多层次金融法律体系。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但涉及金融稳定的法律制度缺乏整体设计和跨行业跨部门的统筹安排，相关条款分散，规定过于原则，一些重要问题缺乏制度规范。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，作为中国金融监管体系的重要法律基石，金融稳定法旨在确保金融系统稳定，提高金融机构的适应能力和应对风险的能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，这部法律对于金融稳定工作有两重重大意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是明确规定建立国家金融稳定发展统筹协调机制和成员组成，提出宏观审慎政策框架、治理机制和基本制度，覆盖主要金融机构、金融市场、金融基础设施和金融活动。草案不仅明确了各级政府、金融管理部门、金融机构和行业保障基金的职责，还强调了各部门之间的合作和信息共享，尤其在处理金融风险时要加强反腐，协调监察、审计和司法。此外，草案还提出设立金融稳定保障基金。这为金融稳定创造了有力的制度支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是强调了金融机构的主体责任，特别强调了股东责任。草案第十一条增加了“金融机构应当严格遵守资本和风险管理、公司治理、关联交易、客户权益保护等制度，有效监测、识别和防范金融风险。金融机构应当建立权责明确、有效制衡的公司治理结构和内部控制机制，防范主要股东、实际控制人以及董事、监事、高级管理人员等相关人员违反规定干预控制金融机构”，更细化了对于主体责任的要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;草案还厘清了在处理重大金融风险时各部门的职责、处置措施和程序，尤其强调了被处置金融机构的自救责任和采取市场化处置方法的原则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;稳定基金&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;风险处置后备资金&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与央行版征求意见稿相比，全国人大版的草案有何相同与差异之处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心对比两个版本研究发现，人民银行版为8147字、48条，全国人大版为8433字、49条；虽然从字数和条数上看变化不大，但实则删改内容不少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是更加健全金融管理部门、发展改革部门和财政部门等成员单位间的协调机制，明确国家金融稳定发展统筹协调机制的性质和职能，防止工作冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是明确金融稳定保障基金作为国家重大金融风险处置后备资金的定位。草案对金融稳定保障基金的用途、资金来源和偿还措施等内容进行了具体说明。其中，金融稳定保障基金由向金融机构、金融基础设施运营机构等主体筹集的资金以及国务院规定的其他资金组成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是加强存保基金风险防范职能与风险化解权利，明确行业保障基金范围，厘清监管与保障基金之间的分工。 &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四是首次提出金融管理部门、地方人民政府应当依法公开金融风险防范、化解和处置有关信息，并及时澄清虚假信息或者误导性信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五是人民银行版中关于处置资金来源的条款被删除，同时也删除了地方政府对于非金融企业引发的金融风险的处置责任。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，这应是考虑地方政府在处置金融风险时可调动的资源和工具，同时防止过度下放责任，确保金融稳定与发展的整体协调。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六是国家金融基础数据库的相关信息要向省、自治区、直辖市人民政府，存款保险基金管理机构和行业保障基金管理机构等提供有关信息，国务院金融管理部门和省、自治区、直辖市人民政府应当及时互相通报发现的金融风险隐患，增强协调机制的信息共享。 &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;事前事中事后&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;各方责任明确&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;草案还明确了一系列针对金融风险的事前、事中和事后防范和处理措施：事前防范强调通过审慎性准入条件、规范公司内控机制、明确禁止性行为等手段，有效控制金融风险的源头。监管部门、政府、保险保障基金管理机构等各部门应形成监管合力，共享数据和信息，以提前识别和防范潜在风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事中化解方面，草案强调在金融风险的早期积极应对和化解。监管部门应承担监管纠正的责任，尤其注重早期纠正措施的作用。同时，金融机构应作为主体承担风险化解的责任，根据实际情况采取多种方式来降低资产负债规模、暂停相关业务、清盘存量资产等措施。地方政府在其职责范围内应提供支持和帮助，并依法打击违法违纪行为，确保风险能够及早得到化解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事后处置方面，草案要求金融风险处置的分工与各主体承担的责任相对应。除被处置金融机构及其主要股东和实际控制人应承担主体责任外，还需要存款保险基金、行业保障基金、省级政府、央行和财政部门等提供相应支持，确保风险得以有效处置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，草案明确了各主体的责任分工。这将更加有效地预防、化解和处置金融风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;金融稳定基金&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;与&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;存保基金&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;如何协同&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;草案中的金融稳定保障基金备受关注。它与目前运行的存款保险基金及行业保障基金如何互动和互补？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年5月，原银保监会在《求是》杂志发表《持之以恒防范化解重大金融风险》，其中指出金融稳定保障基金基础框架已初步建立，首批646亿元资金已经筹集到位，存款保险制度得到加强，保险保障基金和信托业保障基金管理办法将进一步修订完善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;草案为金融稳定保障基金构建了一个协同体系。它与存款保险基金和行业保障基金形成了明确分工的合作模式。这一协同体系旨在维护金融系统的稳定性，为应对金融风险提供多层次的保障。央行《2022年第四季度货币政策执行报告》中提到，金融稳定保障基金基础框架初步建立，已有一定资金积累，并且已在两个风险处置案例中得到实际运用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;存款保险基金在该协同体系中起到关键作用。 2015年5月1日，《存款保险条例》施行，我国存款保险制度正式建立。它根据金融机构风险级别进行差别费率设定，及时识别和通报风险，以推动风险的早期化解。中国人民银行披露，截至2022年末，全国3998家吸收存款的银行业金融机构按规定办理了投保手续，2022年共归集保费487.27亿元，实现基金利息收入9.88亿元，资金支持到期转回2.76亿元，存款保险基金存款余额达549.4亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保险保障基金的规模也不断扩大，制度持续优化。保险保障基金是根据保险法和《保险保障基金管理办法》的规定缴纳形成的行业风险救助基金，用于救助保单持有人、保单受让公司或者处置保险业风险。 2008年9月，中国保险保障基金有限责任公司设立，依法负责保障基金的筹集、管理和使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;信托业保障基金/流动性互助基金也已建立，由信托公司缴纳资金，用于处置信托公司系统性风险、具有较大外溢性风险以及监管部门认定的其他重大风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;草案强调金融稳定保障基金的慎用原则：只有在可能引发系统性风险的情况下才能动用。国际货币基金组织（IMF）、国际清算银行（BIS）和金融稳定理事会（FSB）对于系统性金融风险的定义为：金融体系的全部或部分功能受到破坏引发的大规模金融服务中断，以及由此对实体经济造成严重负面冲击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这有助于确保金融稳定保障基金的有效使用，同时促进金融市场的健康竞争和优胜劣汰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;海外&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;金融稳定基金&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;先自救纾困&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;后外部救助&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;欧美预防和化解金融危机有哪些经验？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴塞尔银行监管委员会(BCBS)与国际存款保险协会(IADI)联合发布的《有效存款保险制度核心原则》指出，存款保险制度与中央银行最后贷款人职能、审慎监管共同构成金融安全网三大支柱。存款保险制度至少在146个国家和地区建立，是国际普遍实施的基础性制度安排。比如美国的联邦储蓄保险公司（FDIC）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是仅仅有银行储蓄的兜底保障基金是不够的。 2008年金融危机的风暴眼恰恰是美国最大的保险公司——美国国际集团（AIG）。如果当时AIG破产，除风险蔓延传导至银行与非银金融机构外，它所承保的飞机和汽车将不能承运。这将给社会带来超出经济活动之外的巨大混乱。因此，需要有专门针对系统性金融风险的兜底保障机制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国的有序清算基金（以下简称“OLF”）和欧洲的金融稳定基金（EFSF）和欧洲稳定机制（ESM）即是针对系统性金融风险和危机而设立的重要兜底性保障机构。它们的成立和运作兼具独特性和共性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;OLF是针对复杂大型金融机构的破产清算问题而建。它成立的背景是2008年金融危机。当时政府认识到大型金融机构的破产可能引发系统性风险。其后，2010年美国出台《多德·弗兰克华尔街改革和消费者保护法案》，其中提出建立有序清算制度，并设立OLF为此提供流动性支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;OLF的资金来源主要是联邦存款保险公司（FDIC）和在有序清算过程中获得赔偿的债权人。在清算问题机构后，FDIC可先向财政部借款。但如果清算成本不足以被资产清算覆盖，则需向其他金融机构收取费用以补充资金。这一机制降低了处理大型金融机构破产的系统性风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲也设有金融稳定基金(EFSF) 和欧洲稳定机制(ESM)。 EFSF最初为了提供临时贷款以维护欧元区成员国的稳定。 EFSF的主要资金来源来自欧元区成员国提供的贷款担保，还在国际资本市场上发行债券。欧洲稳定机制（ESM）是EFSF的继任者，具有更强的救助能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲还建立了单一处置机制（SRM）及单一处置基金（SRF）。这些机制用于处理重大金融风险和危机，特别是跨国金融机构的问题。这些机制在应对主权债务危机和维护欧元稳定和促进欧洲一体化进程方面发挥了重要作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述兜底性保障基金都旨在维护金融系统的稳定，应对系统性风险，并强调金融行业内部承担主要责任和国家财政作为后备支持的原则。它们都坚持“先自救纾困，后外部救助”的核心原则，鼓励金融机构在危机中优先自救，减少外部资金的介入。这些机制为我国金融稳定体系建设提供了经验和参考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;央地协调机制&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;亟须改进&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;金融监管涉及中央政府和地方政府的关系。从中央与地方的金融事权来看，中央的垂直监管模式与地方的属地监管模式之间存在一定冲突。中央政府通常更注重全国性的风险防范和金融体系的稳定，而地方政府可能更关注地方经济的发展和地方金融市场的繁荣。为获得机构的资金支持或更多的信贷投入，地方金融监管部门往往选择效益先行。这种不同的关注点可能导致监管的协调问题，央地协调机制亟须进一步改进。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在风险处置上，地方政府有可能出现借助存款保险等制度推诿责任的情况，也存在群众错误理解存款保险制度的可能，从而导致金融风险转嫁给其他监管部门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为更好地协调央地之间的金融监管，应建立更完善的中央-地方协调机制，确保在风险防范和金融监管方面的政策目标一致，正如草案强调了央地之间的信息共享。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国人大版《草案》删去了人民银行版中关于处置资金使用顺序的第三十八条，或考虑到可能存在地方政府与金融监管部门事权冲突。客观上讲，地方政府背负了多重任务，地方政府对于系统性金融风险的把控可能超出了目前的能力和人力及财力范围。仍有可能出现风险处置仍需中央财政兜底的情况，因此需给予一事一议的灵活操作空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在金融稳定方面，地方金融监管部门基于金融风险全覆盖的总体目标，致力于地方金融风险防控责任的具体化，实现对中央金融监管的必要补充，避免地方金融活动出现监管真空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综合来看，加强中央和地方之间的金融监管协调是确保金融体系稳定性和经济可持续发展的关键。这需要谨慎的政策设计、明晰的法律制度和有效的执行，以确保各级政府之间的共识和协调，共同维护金融市场的健康和稳定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;金融稳定法&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;将影响深远&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;倘若金融稳定法正式实施，其影响将非常深远。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，该法案将有五个方面的深远影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是将加强对金融机构的监管力度，更加注重风险防范，从而减少金融危机和系统性风险的潜在风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是有助于确保市场公平、透明和有序运行。这将提高投资者的信心，吸引更多的资本流入市场，促进市场繁荣；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是金融创新将在监管框架内得到推动，以确保创新与监管的适应性。这将有助于金融体系更好地满足不断发展的经济和社会需求，从而推动中国金融领域的优化和升级；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四是该法案将加强中国与国际金融监管机构和其他国家监管当局的合作。这有助于中国更好地融入国际金融体系，并与其他国家共同应对全球性金融挑战；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五是该法案还强调金融风险的预防和处置，确立了“先自救纾困，后外部救助”的核心原则。这将有助于提前应对金融风险，降低金融系统的脆弱性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体而言，这一法案的出台体现了中国政府在金融领域的积极角色，并将为中国未来经济的健康和可持续发展，以及国际金融体系的稳定和安全作出积极贡献。这标志着中国在金融监管和改革方面取得了长足的进展，对于全球金融市场和经济体系都具有广泛的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赵郁飞丨移家作个画中人：我印象深刻的六部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;县城青年观影史历历可扪：仪式感由部队礼堂和工人文化宫教会，欣赏趣味在正大剧场的译制腔中奠定。横空出世的《泰坦尼克号》曾搅动每条街巷的空气，碟片出租屋的老板手握通往纳尼亚世界的钥匙。那年代“电驴”还不是代步工具，它需要配搭射手的外挂字幕方可簸行。连锁影院和视频网站来了，分占朝野，旧疆底定。时间的古怪之处，在于你并不知道它会带走什么，留下什么。好在电影搭建起永无生灭的Neverland，让你轻易遁入出离现实的两三小时。况蕙风《双调望江南》句云：“见说画中花不落，移家作个画中人”，其境何似。因在记忆河流中稍为打捞，将印象深刻的电影胪列如次：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7jnTKEiYQoezSHAm6gGbi0rn5Z2tBXDsiA0jOnBd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;499&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7jnTKEiYQoezSHAm6gGbi0rn5Z2tBXDsiA0jOnBd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《城南旧事》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;那一代渡海女作家似有种共同气质，潮水和砂砾濯磨后，文字遂如贝母散发淡淡光泽。如余光中谓之“敏感而温柔”的林文月，再如林海音。庆幸在合适的时间窗口（青春期前）就翻熟了《城南旧事》，又偶然获得观看同名电影的机缘。 “我没看过海，分不清海和天，也分不清好人跟坏人”，那个浑璞世界，究竟是什么时候在我们眼前破碎的呢？当父亲的墓碑渐渐在秋山消隐，最后小于一枚红叶，马车上的英子驶离了童年。今夏祖母辞世后，我忽然想起这个长长的镜头。尽管多年客居，早就和故乡达成了事实层面的交割，但我知道生命中有关过去的一小块，从此永远地失掉了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《城南旧事》我看来即是中国版的《爱的教育》，其中流动、微细的情感有赖电影一一具象化。如再合以关维兴为此书所绘水彩插图，庶几可达“苞含名相，网罗视听”的全方位互文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/a1kmmF8DYauAMKeZov9aOH8JG6dyqtwoszpFblQP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;537&quot; height=&quot;716&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/a1kmmF8DYauAMKeZov9aOH8JG6dyqtwoszpFblQP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257530&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《铁西区·艳粉街》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《木帮》《光棍》《跳大神》里是恒纪元的东北，导演于广义正是一副我从小看熟的、典型的通古斯面相。 《铁西区》不同。它太贴近，几乎是从我的经验世界完整挖走的一块。新雪、污水和烧柴的混合气味顶开了记忆的随意门，不用佩戴VR眼镜，我就能在艳粉街自由穿行。撤走高山密林的幕布，连残酷都无法舒展成悲剧，没有魔幻，只有现实。孩子嘴里咀嚼着脏话，少年的求爱过程犹如一场恫吓，艳粉街上空的话题渐渐向动迁聚拢。 “早晚得走啊，大气候谁也挡不了”，跨坐在梁上的中年人说得如此轻描淡写，好像手底下砸的不是自家房子。我无法向你明确言说这种苦涩的乐观究竟是如何习得，尽管我和他一样，早已习惯面对大雪封山的命运。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/25LMKLctd96yJ54Vb3QSisblSMkmMHEq1LiKCw8R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; height=&quot;724&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/25LMKLctd96yJ54Vb3QSisblSMkmMHEq1LiKCw8R.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257529&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《窃听风暴》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;柳宗元有篇很有意思的《骂尸虫文》，描绘了一种寄生在人腹中的尸虫。它专门伺听人言，暗自记录，每逢庚申日，一五一十汇报给天帝，“以是人多谪过、疾疠、夭死”。柳氏于是痛骂曰：“来，尸虫！汝曷不自形其形？阴幽诡仄而寓乎人，以贼厥灵。膏肓是处兮，不择秽卑；潜觑默听兮，导人为非。冥持札牍兮，摇动祸机；卑陬拳缩兮，宅体险微。以曲为形，以邪为质。以仁为凶，以僭为吉……谮下谩上，恒其心术，妒人之能，幸人之失。”其芒刺尖利，尤在《蝜蝂传》上。其实蝜蝂贪婪短视，却不一定害人；尸虫之患，更不知伊于胡底。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我说的是《窃听风暴》。片子看完，我和朋友陷入长久的沉默。它的好不言自明，它的好也让我们难过。故事有一个温暖的结局，可惜现实永远是虫豸们“已微于蠢蠢，仍害及仁人”。据说洁版删掉了维斯勒在窃听后被唤起某种生命力的片段，何必呢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7soD4BNiaDLDWmfcIEvG5x8pokSDhYPmBp4Y519v.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;566&quot; height=&quot;802&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7soD4BNiaDLDWmfcIEvG5x8pokSDhYPmBp4Y519v.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;兄弟出头天》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阿尔·帕西诺、克里斯托弗·沃肯、艾伦·阿金，三人各携大几十年的履历和哀乐，凑到一部非典型黑帮片里。两位老友分别从监狱和养老院放归市井，线头很快由道克收束完毕，接下来是遗愿清单式的铺陈。瓦尔在酒吧邀请陌生女孩共赴舞池——这显然是有意安排的一舞。昏昧灯光下，瓦尔与史法兰上校的面孔不断交叠，甚至站在时光两端的两个舞伴都有几分相似。赫希靠两口氧气凝聚起全部生命精华，倾力一搏，气贯长虹。每忆及他被佳人轮流狂吻，就忍不住大笑出声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片最后一个镜头，是瓦尔和道克各着西装墨镜，执双枪，从容走向仇家一整幢楼的武装，最后的战斗无比华丽决绝。 Johnny Cash的吟唱适时响起：I&amp;nbsp;hurt&amp;nbsp;myself&amp;nbsp;today,&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;see&amp;nbsp;if&amp;nbsp;I&amp;nbsp;still&amp;nbsp;feel.I&amp;nbsp;focus&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;pain,&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;only&amp;nbsp;thing&amp;nbsp;that&#39;s&amp;nbsp;real.&amp;nbsp;永忆江湖归白发，固是别种境界，但人生尽多无法放下的心情，和不甘走进的良夜。三位的演技已是无往不利，观看体验如一块奶油太妃糖在口中缓缓化开，真是赏心乐事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/I2RE2UGpgzmbb42GN3GDdlYXGZODhOMNmY864uGX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;502&quot; height=&quot;782&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/I2RE2UGpgzmbb42GN3GDdlYXGZODhOMNmY864uGX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257532&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《降临》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《降临》较《星际穿越》轻捷——这当然是相对后者的硬科幻属性而言。作为方法论的语言学像一把匕首，撬开了宇宙的果壳。露易丝·班克在外星语言的学习中参悟了迥异于人类的非线性思维：万事之运转，不是顺次推倒的多米诺骨牌，而是无终无始的循环。一张名叫命运的巨大穹顶上，过去、现在和未来同时在她眼中铺展（Ted Chiang原著即名《你一生的故事》）。这是比永生更悲哀的超能力。她超拔出时间，却仍难挣脱因果。露易丝选择走进婚姻，生下女儿——即使早已预知她数年后的死亡。她为女儿取名Hannah，一个“萦环宛转无断绝”的回文词。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日前为诸生授晚清词话，至谢枚如《赌棋山庄词话》中一则云：“词之回文体……虽极巧思，终鲜美制。魏善伯祥曰：诗之有回文，犹梅之有腊梅，种类不入品格。”此语我深韪之。不过《降临》运用入妙，大概有赖越界所带来的审美惊奇，和那一点恰到好处的匠心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NlY4JnKnOJUi8kCuntOSzjhSUDNJ2C7ztSeYk64r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;506&quot; height=&quot;760&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NlY4JnKnOJUi8kCuntOSzjhSUDNJ2C7ztSeYk64r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257531&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;《三块广告牌》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对罪案题材的偏爱要追溯到上世纪九十年代，我在童年看了太多粗粝生猛的国产刑侦剧。 《三块广告牌》刚好填上我在三季《冰血暴》后的心灵空虚，然后发觉它非仅代餐而已。两把火，三封信，前者将故事切分成自然段，后者负责改变人物的轨迹，而信的作者Willoughby警长，自是那枚舍身撞击他者的白球。如果要评选“电影中的经典书信”，本片可与《海角七号》《绿皮书》等一同入选。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人性是何等渊深光怪，以致创作者争相取一瓢饮，只是人巧欲胜天公，实在太难。编剧或导演的自我过剩是个通病，“两个聪明脑壳打架”式影片即为我最不喜一类。从这个角度说，原创剧本的《三块广告牌》允称范式，或者直接引用Willoughby&amp;nbsp;留给Mildred的遗言：“Like a chess move.” 当这一段旁白响起时，逆光特写对准了Mildred枯瘦手背上的青筋。 Frances McDormand这样的女演员真乃“不可无一，不能有二”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[人类请回答：科幻能否跟上现实的魔幻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260297]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VHmTK17O6xJf358f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VH mTK17O6xJf358f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, the main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention-Chengdu Science Fiction Museum, people walk in the &quot;time and space tunnel&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A problem that has never occurred in 5 million years&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy for Mr. Bryant, an 80-year-old science fiction fan, to travel to Chengdu from Hampshire. He first took a flight from the UK to the Netherlands, transferred in Beijing, and finally arrived in Chengdu. Pidu District, Chengdu City is the venue for the 81st World Science Fiction Convention. The local area is famous for Pixian Doubanjiang. Two years ago, Mr. Bryant voted for Chengdu, China, at the World Science Fiction Convention. In mid-October 2023, he arrived at the appointment and came to mainland China for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Mr. Bryant has not read the most popular science fiction work in China - Liu Cixin&#39;s &quot;Three-Body&quot; series, nor has he read any Chinese science fiction works, after a few days with Chinese science fiction Face-to-face communication with fans, his interest in this place has gone beyond science fiction. As a lover of cooking, he plans to bring several jars of bean paste and a local cookbook in English when he returns home to study Sichuan cuisine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chengdu Science Museum, which looks like a giant spacecraft and covers an area of ​​nearly 60,000 square meters, people often excitedly share their encounters with him in the WeChat group of science fiction fans on site. At the age of 80, he still has a strong curiosity about the world, which gives young science fiction fans a lot of encouragement. However, the language barrier has become Mr. Bryant&#39;s biggest challenge in participating in this conference. He has participated in 14 World Science Fiction Conventions before, and only 4 of the previous 80 conferences were held in non-English speaking countries. The venue in Chengdu had elements from science fiction movies and TV shows like &quot;Star Trek&quot; and &quot;Doctor Who&quot; that he was familiar with, but the most popular ones were Panda and &quot;The Three-Body Problem.&quot; People often take photos with the &quot;Three-body&quot; stone pillars outside the venue. One of them is engraved with the warning issued by the Three-body monitor about the risk of the destruction of human civilization, &quot;Don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In November 2014, Liu Cixin and Liu Yukun (middle left) were in the same frame at the 5th Chinese Science Fiction Nebula Award Ceremony held in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Yibo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Chengdu, Ethan, a software engineer from New York, USA, was about to finish reading &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; The first one, for which he temporarily put aside a collection of short African science fiction novels he was reading. At nearly 40 years old, the only Chinese science fiction work he had read before was &quot;The Story of Your Life&quot; by Ted Chiang (the original work of the movie &quot;Arrival&quot;). This time, the Chengdu Organizing Committee provided benefits such as travel assistants, transportation, Hugo Awards, and opening ceremony viewing quotas for science fiction fans who came from 3,000 kilometers away. However, Ethan believes that many European and American science fiction fans have given up on attending the conference remotely. Obviously, &quot;there are language barriers, there are few direct flights, air tickets are expensive, and you need to transfer in other countries.&quot; He said that science fiction fans in Europe and the United States are mainly middle-aged and elderly, and traveling for more than ten hours will be very hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, the 79th World Science Fiction Convention was held in Washington, USA. The Ethan family witnessed the success of Chengdu Science Fiction. This process was full of twists and turns. “At that time, there were many discussions about whether the conference should be held in China, such as whether it could comply with conference traditions, voting formats, cultural differences, etc. Of course, the current political situation is also very complicated,” he said. In the travel warning to China issued by the U.S. State Department at the end of June 2023, mainland China was listed as a &quot;third-level&quot; travel destination, calling on U.S. citizens to &quot;reconsider whether to go.&quot; After hesitating for a month or two, Ethan finally decided to come to mainland China to take a look. When he said this, we were sitting around a table eating butter hotpot. Several other sci-fi fans attending the meeting were from Russia, Canada and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2880&quot; height= &quot;1958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257751&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 26, 1999, Liu Cixin attended the &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; PEN Conference in Chengdu. At this time, he was participating in a PEN discussion with his new work &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The organizing committee has previously announced a set of data as of August 31: In addition to members of the World Science Fiction Association who enjoy offline participation rights, non-Chinese participants who purchased offline participation packages There were 51 people, accounting for 1% of the total number of people who purchased offline package tickets. There were 3,908 Chinese citizens who purchased offline package tickets, most of whom were attending the conference for the first time - including Xiami. Xiami, who is in his early 30s, is a physics teacher at a university in Xiamen, Fujian. In 2003, Xiami, who was in the second grade of junior high school, read novels by Wang Jinkang, Liu Cixin and others in a borrowed magazine &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;, and &quot;officially entered the pit of science fiction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, let Xiami prepare What makes him feel disappointed is that although the venue is large, the area and number of science fiction fan exhibition areas are far less than he expected. Afterwards, Xiami was very sorry to hear that Ethan brought the board game with him but could not find a suitable venue or playmate. After college, he mainly devoted his energy to theoretical research. &quot;This conference is like going back to the pit to take a look.&quot; There is a long &quot;tail&quot; on Xiami&#39;s participation card - if you participate in the booth activities, you will have the opportunity to obtain a booth. Homemade creative ribbons, this is a traditional peripheral for science fiction conventions. During the second half of the conference, Xiami turned to the salon of new generation writers. His notebook was filled with notes about the creation of science fiction novels, and his suitcase also contained more than a dozen novels by new generation writers. He is ready to restart the dream he had in high school - to write science fiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the rapid changes in reality, can science fiction still provide people with enough strangeness and surprise, and can science fiction creation keep up with the magic of reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height= &quot;558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Hague, Netherlands, August 1990, Yang Xiao (second from left) with famous American science fiction writer Harry Harrison (first from left) and British science fiction master Brian Aldis The couple attended the WFS annual meeting together. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now, reality and science fiction do have a competitive relationship.&quot; Science fiction writer Han Song said. Sometimes he serves as a judge for science fiction awards and finds that some science fiction works are not as surprising and strange as reality. &quot;Reality is more like an alien world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 58-year-old Han Song is the leader of the external editorial department of Xinhua News Agency , is also a science fiction writer. Before arriving at the venue, he had already published a rather optimistic report on Xinhua News Agency, &quot;Embracing Science Fiction, Creating Tomorrow.&quot; For more than thirty years, he spent the day writing, editing and distributing news reports for the world at the Xinhua News Agency building on Xuanwumen West Street in Beijing. He got up at three or four in the morning to write science fiction before going to work. In 2018, he finished writing the science fiction novel &quot;Hospital&quot; trilogy. A few years later, when the COVID-19 pandemic hit the world, many people turned to his novels to contrast the visions of reality. Han Song continued to compile and publish reports on the COVID-19 epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1939, the first World Science Fiction Convention was held in New York, USA, reflecting that in the 20th century when the theory of relativity and quantum mechanics appeared, the evolution of human civilization entered a new stage, &quot;another turning point has been reached.&quot; Han Song He said, &quot;Quantum mechanics and the theory of relativity have appeared in the past 100 years. All the material foundations we have today are laid by these two theories. In these 100 years, humans have created weapons that can destroy themselves and other life on the earth. This is 500 years of human evolution.&quot; A phenomenon that has never happened in ten thousand years. Now we have nuclear weapons, artificial intelligence, nanotechnology, and life technology.&quot; One of the meanings of the existence of science fiction is to face these problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many salons at this science fiction conference talked about artificial intelligence, controllable nuclear fusion, quantum computing and communications. More than 80 years after the birth of nuclear weapons, some countries have used controllable nuclear fusion technology to solve the earth&#39;s energy problems. During the conference, science fiction writers were invited to the Southwest Institute of Physics of the CNNC Nuclear Industry to visit the nuclear fusion device known as the &quot;artificial sun&quot; - China Gyre 3, a new generation of artificial sun - which was selected for the &quot;Annual Science Fiction Plan&quot;. 74-year-old science fiction writer Wang Jinkang stood in front of the &quot;artificial sun&quot; and observed. As a senior engineer specializing in internal combustion engines, he once used nuclear energy to build a new path from the earth to outer space in science fiction novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Song, who also came to visit, immediately conducted an interview and wrote a report &quot;Science Fiction Writer Approaches &quot;Artificial Sun&quot;&quot;. The two-story ring-shaped device is covered with colorful pipelines and surrounded by instruments and computers. The nuclear fusion device looks like a giant monster. Most of the scientists explaining it on site are women. Han Song immediately thought of &quot;Frankenstein&quot; written by the British writer Mary Shelley in 1818, which was the first modern science fiction novel in human history. &quot;Science fiction was created by women.&quot; He was also thinking about his own science fiction. If controllable nuclear fusion solves the energy crisis of the entire earth, and if everyone on the earth has equal access to so much energy, will families and marriages disappear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Han Song’s view, science fiction is a species literature. &quot;Sometimes literature is the spiritual history of a nation, but science fiction is literature that describes the human species as an object.&quot; He feels that this is the meaning of every science fiction conference, &quot;So you will always be curious and want to know the same things as us What do these people think when faced with the same technology and the same proposition?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8ENsufAnh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8EN sufAnh .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 18, 2023, at the theme exhibition of the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, Audiences are choosing sci-fi IP peripheral products &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Science Fiction Literature of the World&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1990, In order to save money, Ms. Yang Xiao took an 8-day and 8-night train across Eurasia to attend the annual meeting of the International Science Fiction Association (WSF) in The Hague, Netherlands. She was accompanied by the then Director of the Press and Publication Division of the Sichuan Provincial Foreign Affairs Office. Zaiwang, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; art editor Xiang Jichun. They dragged a large box of the achievements of Sichuan science fiction literature and gifts with panda elements, and once again fought for the right to host the 1991 WSF Annual Conference in Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May of the previous year, as the editor-in-chief of &quot;Science and Literature&quot;, Yang Xiao went to the WSF Annual Conference held in San Marino alone. Twenty or thirty people sat in a small conference room to discuss the most popular science fiction topics in the world. &quot;We are talking about atmospheric pollution, human beings&#39; position in space, low-temperature life support, flying into space...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chinese science fiction is taking off, and Chinese teenagers like science fiction very much.&quot; She said at the meeting Said repeatedly. Her English was not very good. During the defense, she held two small volumes of &quot;A Concise Chinese-English Dictionary&quot; and &quot;A Concise English-Chinese Dictionary&quot; and wrote down the translations from English to Chinese and then from Chinese to English. However, she finally won the 1991 award for Chengdu. The right to host the WSF annual meeting. Others present said she &quot;With a little English and lots of determination to do a lot of things (with a little English and lots of determination to do a lot of things)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this decision was later overturned, and the host country for the 1991 meeting would be re-voted at the 1990 WSF Annual Meeting. This time, Yang Xiao and his team were well prepared, answered various questions and doubts, and showed off the achievements of Chinese science fiction and the cute appearance of pandas. At the end of the discussion at the meeting, Brian Aldiss, the leader of the British New Wave Science Fiction Movement and one of the founders of WSF, stood up. His words always meant what he said, and he, who was always gentle, said seriously and solemnly: &quot;Political disputes are just temporary. Yes, the dialogue and understanding between East and West are long-term, and the friendship between people is eternal. We should not follow political trends.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, Aldis and Chinese science fiction writers Zheng Wenguang has correspondence. Zheng Wenguang was born in 1929 and was a researcher at the Beijing Observatory of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. In 1957, Zheng Wenguang&#39;s novel &quot;The Builders of Mars&quot; won the award at the World Youth Festival in Moscow. This was the first Chinese science fiction work to win an award abroad. Once, after receiving a letter from Zheng Wenguang and his new book &quot;Selected Works of Zheng Wenguang&quot;, Aldis expressed surprise at the title of the book in his reply. Is it really called that? This kind of name won&#39;t sell to us. For this collection, we have to pick the most interesting novel in it as the title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 1991, in Chengdu, China, at the annual meeting of the International Science Fiction Professional Association, 66-year-old Aldis and 62-year-old Zheng Wenguang reunited. At that time, Zheng Wenguang was already in a wheelchair, and Ordis Dees helped push his wheelchair on every occasion. Also present that year were American science fiction writer Frederic Bohr and others. This annual meeting also invited Wu Yan, a scholar who teaches science fiction creation courses in colleges and universities, and others, and was full of encouragement for young creators. In order to invite Han Song, a student of Wuhan University, to join, Tan Kai, the editor-in-chief of &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; wrote a letter To the stranger Qi Minyou, the president of Wuhan University and mathematician, Qi quickly approved and funded 400 yuan for room and board expenses. At the meeting, Han Song showed the &quot;Cosmic Tombstone&quot; that had been rejected earlier to the Taiwanese scholar Lu Yingzhong who was present. Lu Yingzhong took it to Taiwan and gave it to the writers Zhang Xiguo and Zhang Dachun. In the end, this novel won the World Chinese Science Fiction and Literature Award in 1991. prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 18, 2023, at the theme exhibition of the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, visitors watched the robot &quot;Silence&quot; playing drums&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this annual science fiction conference that connected many people, Chinese science fiction is back on track. &quot;Science and Literature&quot;, founded in 1979, was renamed &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; in the same year, and later successively published science fiction novels by new authors Wang Jinkang, Han Song, He Xi, and Liu Cixin - now they have become the &quot;Four Kings&quot; of Chinese science fiction. . During a collective visit to Dujiangyan at the annual meeting, 23-year-old Han Song asked an old foreigner how to write about political themes in world science fiction? He later learned that this man was Aldis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He has been here twice and always talks very enthusiastically about the people he knows and what is happening in the science fiction world. He also very much hopes that Chinese science fiction works can get more recognition, which is also the case for him. The reason why he is keen to hold that science fiction annual conference. There is always a photo of him and Yang Xiao in his study, which is very important to him.&quot; At the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, Aldis&#39;s daughter Wen Di Aldis told me that this afternoon she completed two salon conversations with Yang Xiao. Mr. Aldis has been dead for six years now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Chengdu in 1991, Aldis was upset that a piece of luggage was lost when he transferred before arriving in Chengdu. It was a small box of science fiction books given to the editorial department of &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;. Wendy brought a large pile of her father&#39;s books with her this time and placed them on the salon table during the event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the things in Aldis&#39;s book have become reality. Aldis&#39;s most famous work is &quot;Jungle Greenhouse&quot;, which has been serialized in the British &quot;Fantasy and Science Fiction&quot; since 1961. He constructed a &quot;post-Earth era&quot; in which intelligent plants dominate the earth. At that time, the earth was already a The huge greenhouse that stopped rotating formed a stable system with the moon. The plants reaching the sky extended their branches and leaves to the moon where flying people lived. The movie &quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot; directed by Steven Spielberg is adapted from Aldous&#39;s &quot;Super Toys That Lasted All Summer.&quot; The novel is poetic and melancholy, about a robot with human emotions who doesn&#39;t want the humans who raised him to discover that he already knows he is a robot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aldis’s works are full of reflections on modern civilization. In fact, British science fiction literature, which was born in 1818, is a product of the technological revolution and the industrial revolution. This literary genre, which appeared very late compared to other literary genres, originally had two visions for creating modern society: one is Utopia, a true and false travelogue that originated in the Age of Discovery; the other is the idea that human beings will continue to progress. , a narrative that gradually took shape with the Enlightenment and the French Revolution, and has had a profound impact on human thought around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese science fiction literature was born along with enlightenment modernity. At the beginning of the 20th century, Lu Xun translated science fiction novels (called &quot;science novels&quot; at the time) such as &quot;Travel to the Moon&quot;, &quot;Travel to the Underground&quot; and &quot;The Art of Creation&quot;. At the same time, more and more famous writers have joined in the translation or creation of science fiction literature. At that time, most participants in science fiction literature longed for the changes in the times brought about by technological progress, and explored various possibilities for the future of mankind and the world. After the founding of New China, the first batch of science fiction writers in New China such as Zheng Wenguang appeared. Their science fiction novels assumed part of the responsibility of popularizing science. The positive attitude towards modernity in Chinese science fiction at the beginning of the last century was continued to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 17, 2023, a drone performance next to the main venue of the Chengdu Science Fiction Conference&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the West, where the modernization process was earlier, there has always been no shortage of science fiction works that are wary of modern civilization. Even in the first modern science fiction novel &quot;Frankenstein&quot;, there is already a Scientific doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When humans can develop weapons to destroy the earth and launch wars to exterminate species, mature works that reflect on modernity also appear outside Western countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, the year Japan hosted the Olympic Games, Japanese science fiction writer Sakyo Komatsu began writing &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. This novel, which took nine years to be written, caused a sensation in Japanese society after it was published. The novel describes the Japanese archipelago being destroyed by the earth&#39;s crust. Big changes and sinking to the bottom of the sea. Japan&#39;s postwar economic miracle made Komatsu Sakyo deeply worried. He was worried about people&#39;s consumption of large amounts of resources and energy, and their tense and conflicting relationship with nature and society. He also showed great compassion and sympathy for the fate of mankind. &quot;Japanese science fiction has a great influence on me. As for &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; specifically, it was actually greatly influenced by &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. I was shocked after watching &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. A science fiction work can actually reveal the deepest depths of a nation. The sensitive and fragile fear of the future is reflected.&quot; Liu Cixin once said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hoshi Shinichi, a Japanese science fiction writer who was active in the second half of the 20th century like Sakyo Komatsu, wrote his short story &quot;Hey! &quot;Come Out&quot; was included in Chinese language textbooks in the early 21st century. Many domestic middle school students read this type of story in their textbooks for the first time. In the novel, a bottomless pit suddenly appeared on the earth. Human beings discovered that the hole was endless, so they dumped all the garbage and pollutants they produced into it without any scruples. Later, when all the endless destruction and desires of mankind were sprayed back to the ground and returned to mankind, what served as a harbinger was the innocent and ignorant cry of mankind when they discovered this hole, &quot;Hey - come out!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In 2007, the World Science Fiction Convention came to Asia for the first time. In Yokohama, Japan, at the opening ceremony of the 65th World Science Fiction Conference, 76-year-old Sakyo Komatsu appeared in a wheelchair. He was the first person to introduce Japanese and even Asian science fiction to the world. &quot;More than half a century ago, he was like a prophet, predicting that scientific progress does not necessarily make people happy. He expressed human pain, revealed the barbarism of human nature, and at the same time placed hope and light.&quot; Han Song likes Sakyo Komatsu very much, That year, he went to Yokohama to attend a science fiction conference with writer and scholar Wu Yan, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; president Qin Li, and editor-in-chief Yao Haijun. Komatsu Sakyo was very happy to see them. He held Han Song&#39;s hand and said repeatedly in Chinese, &quot;Thank you, thank you so much.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The times have caught up”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the World Science Fiction Convention will come to Asia for the second time. At the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention, whenever Liu Cixin is present, he always attracts the cheers and attention of the audience like a magnet. Even if he is not a guest on the spot, his name and &quot;Three-Body Problem&quot; are unavoidable topics in the salon for guests from all over the world. As China&#39;s most famous science fiction writer, Liu Cixin&#39;s autograph session was specially arranged by the organizing committee for three hours, starting at 2:30 p.m. However, just after 11 a.m. that day, there was already a long queue in the autograph hall. In the past, Liu Cixin insisted on signing the last reader in line every time he signed. This time he signed for three hours. His hands were shaking when he signed, and he wanted to persist, but was stopped by the organizer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 21, 2023, in Chengdu, Sichuan, &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot; created by Chinese writer Hai Ming (middle) won the Hugo Award for Best Short Novella&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; won the 73rd Hugo Award for Best Novel, and Liu Cixin became the first Asian writers who have won this award. Today, 60-year-old Liu Cixin has become one of China&#39;s most famous writers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this science fiction conference venue, there is a white sculpture about 9 meters high in the most conspicuous position in the atrium. The prototype is the lunar robot mechanical dog &quot;Benben&quot; in &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. There are many people taking pictures around Benben. It is the most representative product image in the &quot;Wandering Earth&quot; IP licensing business. &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, adapted from Liu Cixin&#39;s novel of the same name, has a cumulative box office of 4.029 billion yuan in mainland China and a global box office of US$598 million. It will also represent mainland China in the competition for Best International Film at the 96th Academy Awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before becoming a famous writer, Liu Cixin worked as an engineer at a power plant in a small town called &quot;Niangziguan&quot; in Yangquan City, Shanxi Province. After he became famous, the town was visited by many news reporters. In a series of activities at this science fiction conference, Liu Cixin showed rare relaxation and enjoyment in a salon with the theme of &quot;Engineer Science Fiction&quot;. &quot;No matter how difficult things are in reality, they can be solved in novels without any effort.&quot; The difficulty lies in the tortuous technical construction, how to write the craziest imagination and the most ethereal super technology in the most realistic details, so that readers can feel as real as reading news reports and historical records.&quot; He loves engineer science fiction. I long to be able to do it myself, and also long to read it in other people’s works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;With the depletion of resources on each continent and the deterioration of the environment, the world has turned its attention to Antarctica... But human reason has won on the other hand, and the final process of the complete elimination of nuclear weapons around the world has begun. With the realization of global denuclearization, mankind&#39;s fight for the Antarctic continent has become safer.&quot; Liu Cixin&#39;s short story &quot;Earth Cannon&quot; published in &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; in 2003 is Xiami&#39;s entry into the trap. There is a sense of calmness and perseverance throughout the novel: the government built a tunnel from Mohe through the center of the earth to the Antarctic. The mega-project was closed due to a catastrophic accident. Since then, the global environment has further deteriorated. In order to find a way out, mankind has decided to transfer the industries on the earth to space. The tunnel was reactivated, and humans added magnet coils to it, using gravity and Ampere force to turn the earth into an &quot;earth cannon&quot;, which allowed them to launch surface objects into low-Earth orbit at low cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I read this ambitious story for the first time, Xiami, who was still in the second grade of junior high school, felt the excitement and surprise that was very different from other literary works. &quot;I was immediately attracted by the novel setting and... The grand epic hit me.&quot; Since then, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; has become Xiami&#39;s monthly must-read publication. In 2006, Xiami read the newly serialized &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; in &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;. When science fiction fans were eager to analyze the physical settings in &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, no one could foresee that this novel would What kind of future will Chinese science fiction lead to? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the break of a salon at the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention, Mr. Bryant showed our reporter his self-made laminated card, which contained his certificates from the past 14 World Science Fiction Conventions he had participated in. Highlights. The 80-year-old said that after he returns home, he will share his thoughts and suggestions from the conference with the organizer via email. &quot;If China holds the World Science Fiction Convention again in ten years, I hope I can still attend&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Chen Yang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Liu Cixin was writing the third part of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, he participated in a pen meeting for science fiction writers in Hangzhou. Everyone was talking about &quot;What method should be used if Hangzhou is to be completely destroyed?&quot; He got excited and said that he could first make the city two-dimensional, into an ink landscape, and then one-dimensionally into a thin thread. Everyone was very excited after hearing this. After sobering up, Liu Cixin was very nervous. Fortunately, no one appropriated this science fiction idea. The two-way foil is one of the most amazing cosmic law weapons in &quot;Three-Body III: Death Eternal Life&quot; published in 2010. Its ability is a dimensionality reduction attack, which collapses three dimensions into two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, when &quot;Three Body III&quot; was published, with the popularization of smartphones and 4G networks, China entered the mobile Internet era from the PC Internet era. Xiaomi and Meituan were established that year, and WeChat was launched the following year. Xiaomi founder Lei Jun recommended it to other entrepreneurs after watching &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; in 2010, and has publicly talked about the &quot;dimensionality reduction attack&quot; and &quot;dark forest&quot; of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; on many occasions as an inspiration for Internet strategy. The &quot;Three-Body&quot; series has been highly praised by the science fiction circle, and the discussions among these Internet upstarts have allowed this work to break through the circle and truly enter the public eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of science fiction in a region requires realistic soil, which has long been verified in other countries. In the 19th century, British and French science fiction literature benefited from the industrial revolution and developed, represented by Verne and Wells. After World War II, Western science fiction literature represented by the United States entered its heyday. The period of rapid development of Japanese science fiction was from the 1970s to the 1980s. In the 1970s, Japan created the &quot;Japanese Miracle&quot; with rapid economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being translated by Chinese-American writer Liu Yukun, the English version of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; began to spread in 2014. Facebook founder Zuckerberg said that &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; &quot;liberated me from the economic, social, and scientific books I have read recently, and made me feel relaxed and happy.&quot; After watching &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, then-U.S. President Obama &quot;felt that being a U.S. president was too small compared to the vast universe. After all, all he dealt with every day were trivial matters arguing with Congress, and there was no need to worry about alien invasion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the English copyright renewal fee for &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; reached as high as US$1.25 million, setting a record for the overseas copyright export of Chinese literary works. The &quot;Three-Body&quot; series produced by American streaming subscription platform Netflix will hit the screen in 2024. &quot;Chinese science fiction is a very successful example of international communication. It does not matter how much money is spent, nor does it have to be promoted to the world. I think Chinese science fiction learns from the world and combines the good things of world science fiction with China&#39;s traditional culture and modern culture. Integration, with a strong Chinese imprint, allows the world to experience Chinese science fiction. Chinese science fiction faces universal problems in the world, such as the environment, space, war, etc., and puts forward Chinese-style answers, allowing the world to experience This solution is valuable and unique, and can bring unexpected gains and surprises to the world,&quot; Han Song said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Song in the office&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various things Chance and necessity make the &quot;Three-Body&quot; series a miracle that is difficult to recreate. At every public event, people ask Liu Cixin when he will release a new work that will surpass &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This science fiction writer is racing against technology. Liu Cixin has always maintained the habit of reading cutting-edge scientific and technological articles. He is accustomed to &quot;writing it out in one go&quot; after accurately modeling it in his brain. In 2015, in an interview with Sanlian Life Weekly, he mentioned a &quot;good idea&quot; that he had conceived for two years. This subject had high hopes for him. Not only did the setting leave a lot of room for development, but he also His experience working in power systems can also help him portray full-bodied characters. Until one day, he saw an article published by researchers at Waseda University in Japan. The other party not only proposed the same idea, but also &quot;calculated the total power generation&quot; and proposed &quot;building a relay station at the Lagrange point to send the microwave back&quot; and so on. After reading this article, Liu Cixin completely gave up the idea, and the 300,000-word manuscript was shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Cixin set the threshold for releasing new works as &quot;something that can excite myself&quot; and emphasized that she &quot;has been working hard&quot;, but the resistance has also been unprecedented. &quot;I often feel shocked when I first start writing, but halfway through writing I find that the times have caught up and I feel bored, so I start writing again, and time is wasted.&quot; Liu Cixin told me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The rapid development of science and technology has weakened the sense of magic of science and people&#39;s expectations for the future that science can create. This has a great impact on the traditional type of science fiction.&quot; He believes that this is like him A common problem for hard science fiction writers who &quot;rely on creativity and world construction&quot; is that &quot;colleagues in the East and the West are working hard, hoping to use more expression techniques to restore the vitality of science fiction creation. But frankly speaking, the current effect is not good.&quot; He even regretted it, feeling that the more than 30 short stories and short stories he published in his early years were an excessive waste of subject matter and exhausted his passion. In the future, as the expression vehicle of science fiction stories shifts from novels to the screen, he is also worried about whether he can adapt to the changes in roles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The time I can write is about 10 years at most.” Liu Cixin feels that artificial intelligence is accelerating this countdown. “The science fiction novels written by ChatGPT are getting better and better. I don’t think so. Knowing that artificial intelligence will leave us at least as much time as possible.&quot; He believes that this is a natural law and cannot be considered pessimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Guo Fan on the set of &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New crisis and science fiction The vitality of , a fleeting excitement arose in the dying heart.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Song read in a low voice &quot;Cold War and the Courier&quot; he wrote 30 years ago, which is the only one at this science fiction conference reading activities. He thinks this is a love story, &quot;two generations, politics, war, men&#39;s rights, women&#39;s rights. The humbleness of people in time and space.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This novel was insistently chosen by the science fiction writer Sugar Bandit. She I think it is very suitable for the current situation where local conflicts occur in many places. An American science fiction fan who came to China to attend a conference was banned from bringing a computer by his company before departure. Uri Aviv, the founder of the Tel Aviv International Science Fiction Film Festival, comes from the war-torn areas of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.等大会结束，他又要回到屡遭空袭的以色列特拉维夫。特拉维夫国际科幻电影节将于12月开幕。一些工作人员被征召入伍，许多工作面临调整。 “我们肩头的责任比以往任何时候都更重，科幻作品能为人们提供平静和治愈的力量，帮助他们在对当下和时代的忧虑重压下喘一口气，得以思考、构想和期待更美好的未来。”一个小时的读书中，活动现场挤满了人，竟有人听得落下泪来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类不得不直面这充满不确定的现实。韩松原本想在读书会上展开读糖匪的新书《后来的人类》，甚至准备了三段内容，分别对应着设定架构、机器、关系。小说构建了一种未来的新型公寓，人工智能“家庭主脑”控制着公寓的一切，以无所不用其极的方式来照顾人类，实际却是一个监视者，甚至成了统治者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管新生代的科幻作家对外部世界的描写更加多元和令人兴奋，也更广阔，但韩松觉得科幻文学目前还需要更大的想象力。此外，他觉得女性作家写得更细致，有时候写得更深刻，“不仅体现在对情感的了解，还有对历史和社会的认知。”他觉得反映社会问题最好的作品之一就是郝景芳的《北京折叠》（获雨果奖），慕明和双翅目的作品也有很强的社会风格，技术后面有很强的历史和社会认知。 “但有些男作家写现实就显得有点着急，我觉得比较粗线条。不一定写到这样的主题，就算写到了，小说到他技术惊奇的画面那里就截止了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场科幻大会的几天之前，韩松赶去浙江绍兴参加了一场中日作家的交流会，与会者有多位芥川奖得主和鲁迅文学奖得主。会议特意选在了鲁迅的出生地举办，鲁迅是最早把科幻小说译介到中国的人之一。这一场交流会谈论的问题，成为世界科幻大会探讨的许多内容的预演。这些东亚作家首次一起深入讨论人工智能时代的文学到底是什么、人类在新技术条件下生活的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一场科技革命都会引起欢呼和惊恐，人工智能的发展也不例外。但全球对人工智能产生全面的紧张感是从2022年底ChatGPT的发布开始的。有观点认为，随着以AI为代表的智能化生产方式的出现和普及，第五次工业革命正在发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《三体》剧照(2023) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人类以前只是感觉到危机。更早以前大机器出现，感觉到要失业，然后核武器出现，感觉到人类会被灭绝。但是这次不一样。前面几次工业革命创造的都是物质，这次人工智能的科技革命，创造的是精神。”韩松说，“而且这个精神，看上去比人类思考得还要厉害，而且人类也不知道这个人工智能是怎么想的。”这是人类物种（被更替）的危机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“反倒是科幻小说，对未来人工智能做了方方面面的预测性描述。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年写人工智能和元宇宙的科幻小说变得非常多，而且将未来建模得相当详细。最近，韩松读到墨熊的新小说就是写后人类时代，全球人工智能挽救人类，让人类能在整个宇宙演化的灾难中继续生存，最后的办法是人与机器融合的怪物更替了人类这一物种。科幻作家江波近几年也写了很多人工智能。 “他还是很悲观地认为人和机器的战争是很难避免的。写共生的也有，人机耦合也写过，但我还是觉得不可预测。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;653&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松的“医院三部曲”在2018年全部出版，这个系列由《医院》《驱魔》《亡灵》组成，也想象了人工智能：“药时代”里，医药成了新的神；“药战争”接替了全球“核战争”；在医药战争中，整个宇宙也像病人一样走向死亡，而不得已遭遇所有故事的，不过是一个因为喝了坏水而被送进医院的可怜上班族。书中的忧思最初只在学界传播，哈佛大学教授王德威在参加北京大学纪念“五四”运动百年活动演讲时，指出韩松的“医院三部曲”重启了早期鲁迅对科学与文学的批判性思考。到2020年全球暴发新冠疫情时，一些人找到韩松的这套《医院》，来对照眼前惊人的生活。 “在社会发展、生活逐渐繁荣的同时，每个人内心深处都有一层伤口。生活凭靠运气，下一步怎么活下去没有把握。许多担忧与无力交织在人心里，内化成心底的巨大惧怕。”2017年，刚写完《驱魔》的韩松对我说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;662&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;694&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文学发展到现在，韩松认为其处理的核心问题没有根本性的变化，科幻对现代性的继承、发展和反思与主流文学是一致的，“最早的&#39;鲁郭茅巴老曹&#39;本质上就是在写现代性的问题。 ”在他的观察里，这些年主流文学在应对现代性方面有些弱化，“我不知道是什么原因，它跟现实好像有点脱节。有些纯文学好像要把现实描写得很精确，也在写现实，但好像不是我们真正的现实。但是科幻某种程度上弥补了这种现代性，尤其是揭示了科技和经济又一次巨大变革后，民族也好、人类也好，危机的存在。虽然不能完全做比较，但我觉得科幻文学像鲁迅《呐喊》一样地喊大家。文学还是要直面现实问题，而不仅仅是语言的技巧。我觉得中国科幻崛起的一个根本原因，是它反映了现代性。 ”11月2日，韩松在电话里平静地说。他正在福建厦门的金鸡百花电影节担任创投大会“科幻片单元”的特邀嘉宾，在这通采访电话结束后便要去参加讨论会。科幻片单元入围作品《星际信使》就改编自他的《冷战与信使》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，我在新华社对外部实习时，想做一篇北京地铁的报道，我的实习老师建议我采访部门领导韩松，并读一读他的短篇小说《地铁惊变》。韩松每天上班来得很早，总是拍下1号线首班地铁中乘客的样子。我还记得自己在韩松楼下办公室读完《地铁惊变》后因惊栗而久久无法动弹的状态，那是我第一次看见熟悉的现实在科幻中的扭曲和变形。他又写了《高铁》《轨道》，和《地铁》组成“轨道三部曲”。他写那些在新闻中总以进步和繁荣之姿出现的技术，“新闻成为世界的镜子就很不容易了，讽刺小说是一面哈哈镜，科幻像个万花筒。 ”韩松拿这个万花筒看高铁，看科技、经济、政治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松编发过很多灾难报道。2008年汶川地震发生时，新华社第一个向世界报道了震级，“整个晚上，我们特别难过的，是不断地编发了一所一所学校倒塌的新闻，大批的学生被埋在下面。学校，还是学校……”在那个书山一样的办公室，韩松依然写新闻或科幻，又过了两年，他交了科幻小说《再生砖》：大地震后，建筑师用废墟瓦砾、麦秸和死尸制造了新型建筑材料。在艺术展斩获国际大奖后，再生砖被大规模生产并在灾区和全国推广，再生砖风靡世界，带动灾区振兴，人类聆听和赞美砖头里亡灵的哭声。人类如此迷恋再生砖，以致记不住任何教训，甚至去外星球播撒人造微生物来制造新灾难，最后发现，宇宙本身就是一块由废墟和生命建成的再生砖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对韩松来说，是科幻作家叶永烈带来了科幻的火种。叶永烈的《小灵通漫游未来》在1978年出版后很轰动，“中国人之前沉浸在人与人的斗争中，很久没有想象未来时空了。 ”他觉得叶永烈最了不起的科幻小说，自己至今也无法超越的，还是那篇《巴金的梦》，发表在1980年代的《科幻世界》。“他写中国未来一定会建这么一个牢记历史的博物馆，而且是与国际合建，他详细描写了这个馆怎么建，有什么馆藏。这个小说光是能发表就很了不起了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，叶永烈对未来是乐观的。他是《十万个为什么》的主要作者，又写了《小灵通漫游未来》。他在20世纪60年代写了21世纪的中国，有生产粮食的工厂，有给学生上课的机器人，有电脑的普及，有人造肉、人工控制天气，还有会飞行的汽车等等，向那个年代的小读者描绘出一个充满希望与光明的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014年11月，刘慈欣（中右）与刘宇昆（中左）在北京举办的第5届华语科幻星云奖颁奖礼上&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（李一博提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年世界科幻协会年会在成都举办期间，主办方组织作家采风，韩松（左）与科幻作家张劲松（中）、舒明武在四川彭州银厂沟合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;金字塔的地基&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日，1990年出生的作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得雨果奖“最佳短中篇小说”奖，成为继刘慈欣、郝景芳后第三位获雨果奖作品奖的中国科幻作家。雨果奖评选委员会负责人戴夫·麦卡蒂在颁奖晚会后对《南方周末》说，《时空画师》“创造了一个无英文译本、完全由中文作品获奖的历史”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这届世界科幻大会上，多项科幻产业发展相关的计划公布，甚至有科幻产业项目的集中签约仪式。与科幻素有渊源的成都提出“科幻全产业链生态圈”“IP打造”“强化科幻之都形象”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熙熙攘攘的会场、沙龙和展厅，都在彰显科幻的“热”。但作为文化产业的一部分，国内科幻产业的发展仍在起步期。据“IT桔子”的数据，2022年国内文娱行业有投融资事件88起，涉及投资金额46.36亿元，数量和金额创近5年新低。据《证券日报》不完全统计，截至2023年9月14日，该年国内文娱行业（含传媒、游戏、元宇宙、社交、体育）共发生13起投融资事件。而2022年国内文娱领域投融资事件为96起，2019年该数据为2158起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文化品牌“未来事务管理局”（以下简称“未来局”）创始人姬少亭是第三次参与世界科幻大会，此前两次分别在英国伦敦和芬兰赫尔辛基。许多西方参会者向她提起他们的惊讶发现——中国科幻迷群体的年轻化和较高的女性占比。海外科幻的发展历程较长，科幻迷大多是中老年。收获同行惊羡的同时，姬少亭心里思考的却是另一个问题，从青年到白头，这些西方读者为何能数十年保持对科幻的热爱？答案很明确。 “他们一定是被持续投喂了大量优秀的作品，这意味着有创作热情的人才在源源不断地涌入科幻行业。归根结底是因为这个行业体量足够大，足够提供就业和发展的强大支撑。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2015年8月23日，美国宇航员凯尔．林格伦在地球之外350 公里的国空间站通过视频连线向全球宣布:中国作家刘慈欣凭借科幻小说《三体》（第一部）获得第73 届雨果奖最佳长篇故事奖，从而成为该奖自1953 年创立以来首位获此殊荣的亚洲人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，成都世界科幻大会会场的巨型雕塑，原型是《流浪地球2》中的月面机器人机械狗“笨笨” &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，姬少亭离开工作10年的新华社，创立未来局，开始深度参与到科幻产业发展。七年来，未来局已成为国内主要的科幻IP开发方之一，参与了众多图书、影视、游戏、玩具等行业科幻IP项目的开发和策划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年1月，未来局举办了《流浪地球》的第一个观影会，导演郭帆和刘慈欣第一次在电影院完整地看成片。映后，姬少亭十分坚定地对我说，这部电影肯定会火的。这部电影被认为“开启了中国科幻电影元年”，票房和效应超出预期，并给电影行业带来巨大的启示。 《流浪地球》在中国大陆票房累计达46.88亿元，全球票房7.39亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，影视行业对科幻题材的理解整体还处于初级阶段。同时，受累于羸弱的投资环境，科幻影视的市场化步履蹒跚。据阿里影业总裁李捷2023年4月在一场创投大会上介绍，阿里影业的科幻电影创投，10到15个项目中，进入成片阶段的只有1到2部。在同一场活动中，《流浪地球》《宇宙探索编辑部》的监制王红卫则勉励科幻创作者“咬住牙”，“我希望以后一年起码有一部高质量的科幻作品，能够再撑住我们这个类型。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《流浪地球》系列的成功反映出国内对优秀科幻作品需求惊人，需求和供给之间的巨大沟壑就是行业的机遇所在。对于具体的公司、事和人，机遇是肯定存在的，就看谁能把握住。好的作品是一切。”姬少亭说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年，由于发表渠道和推广资源收紧，姬少亭明显感觉推进一件事的阻力要比过去大得多。 “经济面临下行压力，各个环节都缺钱，变得保守，不愿试错，资金和资源会向顶级作者和作品集中。当然，这更有利于实现单点突破，弊端则在于新人出头和成长的机会在缩减。”未来局在成立那年就启动了科幻写作培训，致力于持续培养并帮助新兴科幻作者成长。姬少亭常被问道，什么时候才会出现下一个刘慈欣，“我真正希望看到的局面是大量中等以上作品的出现。如果我们连金字塔的地基都不扎实，没有足够庞大的基数，要如何期待下一个刘慈欣呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;淡蓝的小点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;吴文琛重返科幻的世界，是因为《流浪地球》。 2019年上映时，他和妻子、儿子一起去影院看了这部电影。现在，他11岁的儿子在写一个科幻小说。吴文琛小时候也看《科幻世界》，写科幻小说的念头倒是从来没有过。当年《科幻世界》每页的最下边是读者栏目，刊登读者的一句话想象和地址，来稿的多是中学生。吴文琛在中学时也投过稿，还在《科幻世界》发表了一句对世界的好奇和想象，那像是人在少年时对宇宙的呐喊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次从成都市中心来郫都参加科幻大会，就是儿子拉他过来的。上高中后，他再也没读过科幻，后来工作、开公司，生活工作连轴转。看到台上坐着创办《科幻世界》的编辑们，他一下被刺激到，在互动环节举手，几乎不停歇地说了几分钟：“我从一个理想主义者变成了何夕老师口中的现实主义者，但我也没有办法……现在小孩的教育压力真的太大了，我非常忧愁这样的教育会影响孩子的想象力发挥，但我也不知道怎么办。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨潇有一个写着很多中外科幻作家名字的本子，上面有郑文光，有奥尔迪斯，像一本中外科幻交流的合集。这次大会结束后，杨潇的本子上又多了一个名字，是吴文琛的儿子吴嘉麒。杨潇和谭楷把这个11岁的孩子请到台上，鼓励他的写作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年代，《中国少年报》编辑找到郑文光，请他为孩子们写一篇科幻小说。这是天文学家郑文光成为新中国成立后第一位科幻作家的契机。他在故事里虚构了三个偷偷开走火箭船的小孩，他们一路飞到火星的上空，看见了这颗星球上的红色沙漠和蓝绿色植物，这么绕着火星转了一大圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年5月，出席成都世界科幻协会年会的日本作家柴野拓美在卧龙点燃了象征友谊的籍火，随后大家围着籍火跳起了锅庄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在2023成都世界科幻大会主题展览上，一名小科幻迷在VR设备上观赏太空景象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个天真烂漫的故事发表在在1954年的《中国少年报》上，引发了意想不到的热烈反响，《从地球到火星》成为新中国第一篇有影响力的科幻小说：北京掀起了“火星热”，那时候，北京天文馆还没有成立。为了满足孩子们的好奇心，《中国少年报》编辑部在建国门上的古观象台架起一座天文望远镜。孩子们吃了晚饭，就到古观象台排队看火星，为此可以一直排到深夜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都的这场大会同样热闹，有非常多的新闻报道，“但科幻还是一个小众的东西，甚至读它的人还没有读奇幻和魔幻的多。科幻不是一切，不要以为它代表一切、能拯救万物，好像科幻才能让科技发展，不是那么回事，我觉得就一个平常心来看待它。科幻大会是一个粉丝的文化，大家喜欢在一起。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种平常心更接近韩松刚写科幻时的心境。在他的少年时代，1980年代，人们总想把什么送上太空去看一看。韩松的第一篇小说是中学时写的，他首先写陨石在地球砸了一个洞，人们往洞里看，什么也没有。老师说不行，他就写了一篇小说送一只熊猫上太空。 “没有写科幻的话，很可能我就是一个整天泡在酒局饭局里、吃完大家胡扯一通、然后打牌睡觉又开始第二天的人，一辈子就过去了，甚至更糟糕的是，加入到争名夺利的战争里去。”这么多年写科幻，与其说带来什么变化，不如说是不变，“科幻让一个人保持了少年时候那种好奇、纯粹、探究的心，甚至包括那时候那种莫名的惆怅、恐惧，那种本能的跟宇宙、自然的天然的联系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在科幻大会落幕的傍晚，成都科学馆像日落中停泊的一艘飞船。我和吴嘉麒在馆里聊他的小说。他之后要回家赶作业，有点担心接下来的功课过多，不知什么时候才能完成那写了一半的科幻小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也是一个有关太空漫游的故事。 11岁的作者在小说里，给两年前过世的曾祖母造了一座宇宙飞船，她离开了地球，在浩瀚广阔的星际，见到了那些人类无法想象的风景。故事里，她已经找到了一颗移居的星球。当她回头望地球，那颗所有人类出生和死亡的星球，那颗众多文明诞生又毁灭的星球，凝成了宇宙中一颗淡蓝色的小点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢吴岩、杨枫、科幻光年、糖匪、西夏、刘悠翔、北落师门等对采访提供的帮助，感谢八光分文化提供历史图片支持。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被控受贿2.1亿，招商银行原党委书记、行长田惠宇案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月9日，湖南省常德市中级人民法院一审公开开庭审理了招商银行股份有限公司原党委书记、行长田惠宇受贿、国有公司人员滥用职权、利用未公开信息交易、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息一案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常德市人民检察院起诉指控：1997年至2022年，田惠宇利用担任中国信达信托投资公司副总裁，上海银行股份有限公司党委委员、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司上海市分行党委副书记、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司深圳市分行党委书记、行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司北京市分行党委书记、行长，招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长等职务便利以及职权、地位形成的便利条件，为有关单位和个人在贷款审批、业务承揽、工作调动等事项上提供帮助，非法收受他人给予的财物，折合人民币共计2.1亿余元；田惠宇在担任招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长期间，为徇个人私利，违反规定，滥用职权，干预招商银行股份有限公司附属机构正常经营决策活动，致使国家利益遭受特别重大损失；利用因职务便利获取的内幕信息以外的其他未公开信息，违反规定，从事与上述信息相关的证券交易活动，情节特别严重；身为证券内幕信息知情人员，在对证券交易价格有重大影响的信息尚未公开前，买入该证券，或者泄露相关信息，或者明示、暗示他人从事上述交易活动，情节特别严重。检察机关提请以受贿罪、国有公司人员滥用职权罪、利用未公开信息交易罪、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息罪追究田惠宇的刑事责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审中，检察机关出示了相关证据，被告人田惠宇及其辩护人进行了质证，控辩双方在法庭的主持下充分发表了意见，田惠宇进行了最后陈述并当庭表示认罪悔罪。庭审最后，法庭宣布休庭，择期宣判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人大代表、政协委员及各界群众三十余人旁听了庭审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>