<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260307]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73362&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70174&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/8fc5b440c4.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3197.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hong Huanhuan teaches her sister-in-law to make paper flowers using toilet paper .Photo courtesy of interviewee&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/8fc5b440c4.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;257770&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan taught her sister-in-law to make paper flowers using toilet paper. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Until October 25, 2023, Hong Huanhuan’s relatives and friends came to the community and held up placards asking the residents here to provide information about her life over the past year. , the details of the work, residents of Building 14 of Yintai Yuhuayuan in Wuhan, Hubei Province realized that an ambulance had pulled a female domestic worker away from the building in the morning three days ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since September 2022, Hong Huanhuan, as a live-in nanny, has been taking care of the children of her employer Xiong, a pair of twins who have just turned two years old. On the morning of October 22, 2023, the 38-year-old fell to the ground at Xiong’s home. A few hours later, relatives and friends rushed to the hospital after hearing the news and saw her body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;What impressed me most was my sister&#39;s eyes that she never closed until she died, and the tears in the corners of her eyes.&quot; On October 31, Hong Huanhuan&#39;s brother Hong Mingxuan told Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The last time Hong Huanhuan saw her family was during the May Day holiday in 2023. She and her husband returned to their hometown in Hanchuan, Hubei Province to visit their children and the elderly at home. Over the next five months, whenever someone wanted to ask her out, she always said she was too busy at her employer&#39;s house. In early October, Xiong called the housekeeping company and told the housekeeping company that Dabao accidentally injured his leg when Hong Huanhuan took her child to play on the slide on October 2. The housekeeping company immediately offered to visit her, but Xiong refused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When we meet again, we will be separated forever. The family found a wound on her head and multiple bruises on her body and immediately called the police. The doctor told Hong Mingxuan that Hong Huanhuan had no heartbeat at Xiong&#39;s home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73361&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70173&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/50a4245fe2.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3196.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Wuhan, Hubei, Yintai Yuhuayuan Community, the building where Xiong Lan lives. Southern Weekend reporter Photo by Wang Xuqiulin&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/50a4245fe2.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;257771&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wuhan, Hubei, Yintai Yuhuayuan Community, the building where the employer Xiong lives Building. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;First time moving into the home&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It has been nearly 10 years since Yintai Yuhuayuan was built. Lianjia APP shows that this community’s historical transaction volume and listing price of nearly 25,000 yuan per square meter are the highest in Wuhan’s Baibuting area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Several neighbors recalled that in 2020 or even earlier, Xiong bought the four-bedroom, two-bedroom apartment in Yintai Yuhuayuan from the previous resident. Wei&#39;s house has an area of ​​about 160 square meters. Wang Yifei, a neighbor across the door, told Southern Weekend reporters that he visited Xiong&#39;s house when it was being renovated. It was &quot;Chinese style, all made of mahogany, very luxurious. It is said to have been left behind by the previous owner.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Yifei said that he likes to chat with people, but does not like to deal with Xiong, because the other party often talks about issues such as community hygiene, neighbor decoration, and exercise noise downstairs. In the building group, they criticized others and used fierce language. Sometimes when he meets Hong Huanhuan in the elevator, Wang Yifei will chat with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, a Southern Weekend reporter called Xiong’s contact number and it showed that the machine was down. According to the content recorded on Xiong’s short video account, she is born in the 1970s. She previously worked in the female body care business in Zaozhuang, Shandong, Xuzhou, Jiangsu and other places. She returned to Hubei in 2020 and opened a shop on the second floor of Yintai Yuhuayuan in the second half of the year. opened a beauty salon. Currently, the beauty salon is closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A merchant surnamed Yuan downstairs of the beauty salon recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Xiong&#39;s hometown is in Huangpi, Wuhan, and he bought the second-floor store from himself in 2020. , the lease term was agreed to be three years. Less than a year later, due to pregnancy, he planned to sell the store, and there was &quot;a little dispute&quot; when he quit the lease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The husband did not appear in the short video taken by Xiong. After returning to Wuhan, most of the content she posted was related to emotions, and sometimes she revealed her depressed side. At the end of August 2021, the twins, a boy and a girl, were born. From the moment the baby could raise his head, to babbling, to taking the baby for a walk, she liked to share everything online. She said that she wanted to be a happy mother for the sake of her children, but she also said that whether her temper was good or not depended on &quot;how you treat me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 6, after the child was injured while playing on the slide, Xiong asked among his neighbors if there were any hourly workers he knew well, and requested that he cook lunch once a day and clean the house. Home Hygiene. Many neighbors recalled that they had never met Xiong&#39;s husband. Before that, Xiong&#39;s father occasionally came over to help with the child, but he returned to his home two months before the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73364&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70176&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/e6c72907f9.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3200.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 31, 2023, the door of Xiong Lan&#39;s house was closed, and no one answered the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e6c72907f9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257772&quot; style =&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 28, 2023, the door of Xiong’s house was closed, and no one answered the knock on the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan was an employee of Wuhan Auntie Lai Housekeeping Service Co., Ltd. during his lifetime. Carrying twins for Xiong was Hong Huanhuan&#39;s first job since she was transferred to a new job as a nanny, with a monthly salary of 6,500 yuan. In the opinion of a colleague named Hu, the salary of this job is not high. According to the market price in Wuhan, it costs 6,000-8,000 yuan for a nanny to take care of a child who is not in kindergarten. &quot;Generally, two aunts take care of twins.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the job transfer, Hong Huanhuan&#39;s position was as a domestic agent. Former colleague Gao Xuemei explained to a reporter from Southern Weekend that in a housekeeping company, an agent&#39;s income mainly depends on personal performance. &quot;The more orders you sign, the more you get.&quot; In the past few years due to the epidemic, some domestic workers have had a heavy financial burden and have chosen to change careers. The wages of domestic agents have also dropped from seven to eight thousand yuan per month to at most four to five thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan’s husband Wu Qiang works on the assembly line of an electronics factory in Wuhan, and his father-in-law has a pension. My father-in-law passed away due to illness in 2021. My 70-year-old mother-in-law has underlying diseases and has to take care of their two children who are in school in their hometown in Hanchuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I didn&#39;t make much money in the past few years, so my sister said I needed a stable job.&quot; Hong Mingxuan explained the reason why Hong Huanhuan became a childcare nanny. His wife is the general manager of Wuhan Auntie Housekeeping Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan and Hong Huanhuan grew up together. He recalled that after graduating from junior high school, his sister first went to work in Guangdong and then went to Zhangjiakou to set up a stall. In 2018, she returned to Wuhan to work as a housekeeper to be closer to the children and to take care of the elderly. During this period, she took the nanny qualification certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Xuemei recalled that the two met in October 2022 after Hong Huanhuan moved into the household. Hong Huanhuan said that she and Xiong took care of the baby together. She took the baby to bed at night, and the child&#39;s grandfather was responsible for doing housework. Hong Huanhuan mentioned that her clients love to keep their homes clean. Although she does not need to do most of the hygiene, she will help with cleaning and washing baby clothes as long as she has time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan told Gao Xuemei at that time, &quot;Bao&#39;s mother (Xiong) may not be in a good mood sometimes, and sometimes she will curse&quot; and sometimes lose her temper at her , and when he is good to her, he is very nice. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I broke my client’s child’s bone after falling”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the child’s accident on the slide, Xiong’s short video account had more than a dozen There has been no update for days. On October 16, she sang in a new video, &quot;The happiness I envy is always not available, and the people I love who love me are not taken care of.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above-mentioned merchant recalled that previously, Xiong and Hong Huanhuan often took their two children for walks in and around the community garden. One day in early October, she once saw Xiong with a red face, as if he had drunk alcohol. As he walked, he scolded Hong Huanhuan behind him for being &quot;too cruel.&quot; In the next few days, Hong Huanhuan came to her store to pick up the express delivery, and she found that he &quot;was not looking very well.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to rumors, Xiong asked Hong Huanhuan to compensate Hong Huanhuan 100,000 yuan after his child was injured while playing on the slide. Hong Mingxuan confirmed this amount to Southern Weekend reporters. The second sisters of Hong Mingxuan, Gao Xuemei and Wu Qiang said that after the incident, Hong Huanhuan borrowed money from them or people around her on WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In October, the winter jujubes in Gao Xuemei&#39;s hometown were ripe. She sent Hong Huanhuan a WeChat message: &quot;Huanhuan, give me your home address and send the jujubes to you.&quot; At around 11 o&#39;clock in the evening on October 12, Hong Huanhuan replied: &quot;Don&#39;t send it, I&#39;m not in the mood to eat it. I broke the customer&#39;s child&#39;s leg.&quot; Gao Xuemei asked, but Hong Huanhuan did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 20, Gao Xuemei received a text message from Hong Huanhuan: &quot;Dear, do you have any money? Can you lend me 10,000 yuan?&quot; She replied: &quot;Huanhuan, I&#39;m sorry, my mother was diagnosed with cancer two months ago. She is undergoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy this month, and may need an operation. I really don&#39;t have much money to give you.&quot; Hong Huanhuan told her: &quot;It&#39;s okay, it&#39;s okay. I&#39;ve pretty much taken care of it here. I caused you trouble.&quot; This was their last contact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Qiang’s second sister said that a few days before the incident, Hong Huanhuan also borrowed money from Wu Qiang’s eldest sister. The eldest sister handed over the money without saying anything. Afterwards, the eldest sister talked to her about the hurried video call and recalled that Hong Huanhuan wore a mask the whole time at Xiong&#39;s house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Qiang’s second sister later calculated that since October, Wu Qiang and his relatives and friends had given Hong Huanhuan a total of 61,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan also lent money to his sister. He said he didn&#39;t ask much at the time. After all, the child was injured and it was understandable that his sister needed to compensate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan said that before joining the household in 2022, Hong Huanhuan was diagnosed with gallstones and other indicators were normal, but he did not provide the corresponding physical examination report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They don’t know why Hong Huanhuan died suddenly. Many neighbors interviewed said that they did not pay attention to the family&#39;s movements. Only the camera installed by Wang Yifei in the corridor recorded some of the family&#39;s comings and goings on October 21 and 22. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 8:35, 10:26 and 17:32 on the 21st, Xiong, Hong Huanhuan and a middle-aged woman with short hair took two The children came in and out of the house three times. Among them, the short-haired woman was always carrying a girl, Xiong was pushing a car with a boy in it, and Hong Huanhuan was wearing gray short-sleeves and gray trousers. Hong Huanhuan wore a mask when she went out twice. When she appeared in front of the camera, she did not take her children with her. She always carried handbags, vegetables or garbage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73363&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70175&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/e26d751080.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3199.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;In surveillance video, Xiong Lan (left) and Hong Huanhuan (right) walked out of the elevator entrance on October 21, 2023. Video screenshot&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e26d751080.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257773&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the surveillance video, on October 21, 2023, Xiong (left) and Hong Huanhuan (right) walked out of the elevator mouth. Video screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The camera did not record when the five of them returned home on the evening of the 21st. Until 9:02 a.m. on the 22nd, surveillance video showed that four first responders knocked on Xiong&#39;s door with medical oxygen bags, first aid kits, stretchers and other equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9 minutes later, emergency personnel carried Hong Huanhuan out of Xiong&#39;s home. At this time, Xiong went out with the stretcher, then stood outside the door and looked into the house. There was also a man standing in the house. This man had not appeared in the video before, and neighbors and Hong Huanhuan&#39;s relatives said they did not recognize the man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The surveillance video 10 seconds later showed that the door of Xiong’s home was closed and all the emergency personnel were standing in the elevator. Xiong had an extra green coat on his left hand, and holding three plastic bags in his right hand, he also squeezed into the elevator from the corridor. A male voice asked: &quot;She was a little confused before?&quot; The female voice replied: &quot;Yes, yes, yes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Hong Mingxuan, after being sent to the hospital on the 22nd , the housekeeping company received a call from Xiong, saying that Hong Huanhuan &quot;fainted&quot; at home. The housekeeping company immediately notified Hong Huanhuan&#39;s family and sent people to the hospital. Hong Mingxuan said that he was relatively close to the hospital at the time and was the first to arrive. The housekeeping company, Hong Huanhuan&#39;s parents, husband and other relatives and friends arrived one after another. &quot;It turned out that my sister was no longer here.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was close to noon when Hong Mingxuan arrived. Hong Huanhuan had already received rescue measures in the hospital for about an hour and a half. &quot;The employer insisted on sending her to the hospital for rescue.&quot; He did not provide Hong Huanhuan&#39;s death certificate to Southern Weekend reporters, which usually indicates the time of death. He explained that since the police have opened a case for investigation, the hospital has not issued a death certificate to the family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Surveillance video shows that Xiong returned home at 10:58 and 13:30 on the day Hong Huanhuan was sent to the hospital. At 15:21 that day, several police officers came to Xiong’s home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sister Wu Qiang rushed to the police station on the afternoon of the 22nd. She recalled that she saw Xiong at the police station, and the two of them pushed and pushed because of their excitement. In the end, she was pulled away by the police; there was a man next to her, &quot;I heard that he was her (Xiong&#39;s) husband.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, Hong Mingxuan learned from the housekeeping company that Xiong’s husband usually did business in Guangdong and returned to Wuhan the day before the incident; Xiong did not have a formal job in Wuhan , taking care of the baby at home every day. Hong Mingxuan said that except for the meeting with Xiong at the police station on the 22nd, he had never seen him again. &quot;There was no explanation of the situation and no apology.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 25, staff from the Houhu Police Station of the Jiangan District Branch of the Wuhan Municipal Public Security Bureau told the media that the police had filed a case and the suspect had been controlled. The details of the case The whole story is still under investigation. On November 7, staff from Houhu Police Station told Southern Weekend reporters that they would not comment on the case for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I haven’t seen my family for five months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan’s colleague Zhang Lijia said that the housekeeping company bought insurance for every aunt who came to the household. If an aunt encounters an accident when she comes to work, such as being injured or damaging the employer&#39;s property, she should inform the housekeeper and the insurance company within 24 hours, and the claim settlement process can be started. &quot;Every aunt will undergo training in this area.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan has been working as a housekeeping agent since 2018, and is familiar with how to deal with accidents when domestic workers come to the household. &quot;I can&#39;t figure out why it was only a few days later that Bao&#39;s mother notified the company that something happened to her child,&quot; Zhang Lijia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When they were agents, Hong Huanhuan and Zhang Lijia lived together in the attic of the office for more than a year. They often cook and sing together. In the summer after get off work, they would set up a table in front of the store to drink and have late-night snacks together. But after Hong Huanhuan moved into the household, the two of them had fewer opportunities to meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 24, Zhang Lijia sent Hong Huanhuan a WeChat message and asked her what she was doing, but Hong Huanhuan did not reply. Zhang Lijia thought she was just busy. &quot;When the crayfish came out (in summer), I asked her if she wanted to go out to eat together. She said that she probably didn&#39;t have time recently. Let&#39;s eat together when the hairy crabs come out (in autumn and winter).&quot; When Zhang Lijia contacted Hong Huanhuan in the summer of 2023, the other party said this She agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan likes to shoot short videos, recording her daily life with family gatherings, going to the beach with colleagues, and taking her children out to play. These contents are updated frequently, and there are always several items a month. After transferring to a household, although the frequency has decreased, she still posted photos, recording some moments when she was infected with the new crown, New Year gatherings, and going for walks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On April 30, she and her daughter co-produced a short video of singing together, with the text: &quot;The newly bought parent-child pajamas, this baby has to take a photo Video.&quot; Since then, this account has not posted any new content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That time coincided with Hong Huanhuan and Wu Qiang returning to Hanchuan. Their hometowns are both in the same town, about two kilometers apart. This was also the time when many relatives recalled the last time they saw Hong Huanhuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Relatives in my hometown said that Hong Huanhuan looked fine on May Day. Wu Qiang&#39;s mother recalled that in the 15 years since their marriage, she had never seen her son and daughter-in-law have a word with each other. Even though she was sometimes short-tempered, Hong Huanhuan never had a dispute with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73360&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70172&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/9c383803f7.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3195.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanchuan, Hubei, the entrance to Hong Huanhuan&#39;s hometown. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/9c383803f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257774&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The entrance to Hong Huanhuan’s hometown village in Hanchuan, Hubei. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan&#39;s colleague said that nanny&#39;s have four days of leave every month, and they can ask for leave from clients if they have something to do. Wu Qiang previously rented a room near his workplace in Wuhan, which was not close to Yintai Yuhuayuan, but Hong Huanhuan would go there every time he was on vacation. If they were free, the two would go back to their hometown to look after their children. Before every vacation to see Wu Qiang, Hong Huanhuan would go to Hong Mingxuan&#39;s house to see her parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But after the May Day holiday in 2023, Hong Huanhuan did not take any vacation. When Hong Mingxuan saw that his sister had not been here for several months, he asked his mother about her current situation, &quot;I always ask my mother to persuade my sister that there is endless money to be made, but every time we let her take a vacation, she always said that Bao&#39;s mother&#39;s children can&#39;t live without her. she&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan did not return to Hanchuan on May Day and missed the opportunity to finally reunite with his sister. Looking back now, he regrets it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan has two mobile phones. When she was a housekeeping agent, she was basically online 24 hours a day. However, after becoming a housekeeping aunt, she often did not reply to messages in time. Gao Xuemei explained that it is considered a professional ethics for housekeeping aunts not to look at their mobile phones when taking care of the baby. Unless they check the time or encounter an emergency, they have to wait until the baby goes to bed at night before contacting the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan said that after taking care of her two children, her family knew that Hong Huanhuan was busy with work and would not call on her if there was no urgent matter. My mother usually had a lot of contact with Hong Huanhuan, and she &quot;would never go without replying to messages for a long time.&quot; However, after May Day, Hong Huanhuan rarely spoke in the family group, and sometimes it took several days to reply to messages. During one of these times, her mother had a I haven&#39;t contacted my daughter for many weeks and I am very anxious. They found Xiong through the housekeeping company and talked to Hong Huanhuan on the phone. They were told that &quot;her mobile phone was broken.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Mingxuan said that he later learned from his sister’s friends that “the employer had confiscated her mobile phone.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many relatives and friends said that Hong Huanhuan once said privately that he found this job &quot;very tiring&quot; and did not want to renew the contract. He would wait until Xiong found a suitable childcare nanny. household. But in September 2023, after one year, she signed a new contract with the other party. Gao Xuemei asked Hong Huanhuan why she renewed her contract, and Hong Huanhuan told her, &quot;It&#39;s better to be experienced than to do it for a living. Once you are familiar with the customers and the baby, then just keep doing it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At this time, Hong Huanhuan and her children had not seen each other for nearly 5 months. After learning that Hong Huanhuan could not go home during the National Day holiday, her family made an appointment with her to meet her children downstairs in the community where she worked. But on October 1, Wu Qiang drove his two children from Hanchuan to Wuhan. When they were waiting for Hong Huanhuan to come out at the gate of Yintai Yuhuayuan, her mobile phone could not be contacted again. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“No work at home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Xuemei remembered that Hong Huanhuan said when they met a year ago: &quot;Bao&#39;s mother (Xiong) is not easy. , she has to take care of her children and do things with me. She has also taught me a lot, and she is not willing to cause trouble to the agent. I will try my best to complete this list and complete this contract (period). .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first time she went to the household, Hong Huanhuan’s usual requests for help were always related to Xiong’s children. In June and July 2023, she asked Gao Xuemei on WeChat: &quot;Why is the baby&#39;s butt always red? Why does the baby always leak when wearing diapers?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Lijia said that she was not Hong Huanhuan&#39;s agent and could not comment on Hong Huanhuan&#39;s professional ability as a housekeeping aunt, but she believed that &quot;aunties always have shortcomings&quot; and &quot;give her some patience and tolerance.&quot; , talents will grow slowly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Gao Xuemei’s eyes, domestic work deals with people, and it is impossible not to be emotionally involved, “especially for children, if you don’t have love and patience, Can&#39;t do this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Lijia has always wanted to make the job of &quot;domestic worker&quot; more professional. She deliberately maintains some habits, such as showing her business card before communicating with clients, displaying posters showing herself in professional attire, and putting on makeup before going to work. There are also more than a dozen skills that housekeeping aunts can master after receiving training in the company. &quot;Customers contribute to society outside the family, and we also provide customers with no worries at home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also admitted that the group of housekeeping aunts has average academic qualifications. It is not high and the economy is not well-off. Faced with the requirements of different customers, anxiety is normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before becoming a domestic agent, Zhang Lijia also worked as a live-in nanny. &quot;Living at home is like a 24-hour service, without getting off work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After becoming an agent, Zhang Lijia needs to appease the housekeeping aunt when she comes to the house and needs help, such as Some aunts will report to her that they are accused by their employers of eating too much and cooking poorly... &quot;Many times they cannot tell their family members about their grievances.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; &quot;It&#39;s too late to regret it.&quot; Another colleague who has a good relationship with Hong Huanhuan said that the housekeeping aunt is at the door 24 hours a day. She is worried that chatting with Hong Huanhuan will affect her work and rest, so she has not had any voice or video chat with Hong Huanhuan. &quot;I didn&#39;t find any abnormalities earlier.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Huanhuan’s former office was hidden in a first-floor shop in a high-end community in Wuhan. This office of about 60 square meters has a kitchen, bathroom and dormitory. Zhang Lijia said that sometimes some aunts would come here to stay for two days when they were on vacation and could not go home far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are still shelves, small blackboards, green plants, medicines, and hooks purchased by Hong Huanhuan during his lifetime. After Hong Huanhuan came to the house, Zhang Lijia sat at her former workstation. &quot;There are traces of Huanhuan everywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When dealing with Hong Huanhuan’s old things left in the store, Zhang Lijia left behind the microphone they used to sing together. She said that when they lived in the attic, one slept under a red mosquito net and the other slept under a white mosquito net. They called themselves the &quot;Red Lotus Leader&quot; and the &quot;White Lotus Leader.&quot; &quot;She is like my sister, who once brought so much joy to our lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After Hong Huanhuan passed away, many housekeeping aunts expressed their concern on her social media Express your condolences under the account. Some aunts also sent messages to Zhang Lijia expressing concern. &quot;Everyone misses her, and part of them thinks of themselves.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Hong Mingxuan, Wang Yifei, Gao Xuemei, Wu Qiang, and Zhang Lijia are pseudonyms in the article. Yao Zhili and Southern Weekend intern Du Feng also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 12:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融稳定法立法提速：“治未病”与“治已病”如何更有效？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After many years of preparation, the Financial Stability Law is expected to complete the legislative process during the term of the 14th National People’s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, 2023, entrusted by the State Council, Pan Gongsheng, Governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, made a report on the financial work of the State Council at the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress. , Accelerate the legislative work of financial stability law. Previously, on September 7, the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress issued a legislative plan, and the Financial Stability Law was listed as a first-category item, that is, &quot;draft laws with relatively mature conditions and to be submitted for review during the term of office.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does the Financial Stability Law (Draft) (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Draft&quot;) absorb and learn from the experience and lessons learned from the handling of past domestic financial risk cases? How do different regulatory agencies collaborate? How to prevent local government from interfering but not lying down? How to solve the source of financial stability guarantee fund? How is it related to the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund, Deposit Insurance Fund, and Industry Guarantee Fund? What are the substantive differences between the People&#39;s Bank of China version and the National People&#39;s Congress version of the draft that are open for public comment? How does it draw on relevant international legal provisions and common international practices? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center compared and studied the differences between the two versions on the above issues, conducted horizontal studies on the operation paths of multinational financial stability funds, and even discussed and exchanged ideas with industry experts. The core outline of the draft aims to make overall arrangements for the financial stability system from a cross-industry and cross-department perspective, focusing on responding to major financial risks; in terms of legislative key points, the draft clarifies financial risks in three stages: pre-prevention, mid-event resolution and post-event disposal. Key points, while defining the responsibilities of relevant entities such as financial institutions, local governments and regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from Southern Weekend’s New Financial Research Center believe that the Financial Stability Law is not only based on preventing financial risks, that is, “treating the disease before it occurs,” but also focuses on effectively handling financial risks, that is, “treating the disease before it occurs.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The frequency of global financial risks is increasing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Throughout the history of world finance, from Amsterdam in the 18th century to New York in 2008, systemic financial crises have always been accompanied by financial crises. The ebb and flow of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ironically, on the eve of the 2008 financial crisis, Citigroup CEO Chuck Prince&#39;s words in 2007 became famous: &quot;When the music called &#39;liquidity&#39; stops abruptly (financial crisis (arrive), things will get tricky.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the legislation of financial stability laws accelerates, the frequency of local financial risks around the world increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, local financial risks will occur from time to time around the world. The collapse of Signature Bank follows a U.S. bank run in early March and the collapse of Silicon Valley Bank (SVB). Market panic quickly spread to Europe, and global systemically important bank Credit Suisse collapsed. Suddenly, Switzerland almost faced a full-scale bank run. Euro zone banks were under widespread pressure, with Deutsche Bank under pressure as investors sold shares en masse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, the European Central Bank launched an industry-wide investigation into the exposure of euro area banks to rapidly rising interest rates, trying to understand how risks may spread to other industries and conduct stress tests. The International Monetary Fund came out in 2023 to warn of a possible global financial crisis in the world&#39;s rapidly expanding non-bank financial institutions. These institutions include insurance companies, pension funds, mutual funds and high-risk hedge funds. Shadow banking and complex financial instruments allow risk to breed and spread through interconnected financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To prepare for a rainy day, how to effectively combine &quot;preventive treatment&quot; and &quot;treating existing diseases&quot; has become a top priority for all countries. The Financial Stability Law can better combine &quot;treating the disease&quot; with &quot;treating the disease before it occurs&quot;, and establish and improve the financial risk prevention, early warning, disposal and accountability system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Emphasize&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;the self-rescue responsibility of the disposed institution&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why is the Financial Stability Law listed as a Category I project? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that in recent years, my country&#39;s financial legislation has been steadily advancing, and has been guided by basic financial laws such as the People&#39;s Bank of China Law, the Commercial Bank Law, the Securities Law and the Insurance Law. It is a multi-layered financial legal system in which financial administrative regulations, departmental rules and normative documents are important contents, and local regulations are supplementary. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the legal system involving financial stability lacks overall design and cross-industry and cross-department overall arrangements. Relevant provisions are scattered and overly principled, and some important issues lack institutional norms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, as an important legal cornerstone of China&#39;s financial regulatory system, the Financial Stability Law aims to ensure the stability of the financial system and improve the adaptability and risk response capabilities of financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that this law has two major significances for financial stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it clearly stipulates the establishment of a national financial stability and development overall coordination mechanism and member composition, and proposes a macro-prudential policy framework, governance mechanism and basic system, covering major financial institutions, financial markets, financial infrastructure and financial activities. The draft not only clarifies the responsibilities of governments at all levels, financial management departments, financial institutions and industry security funds, but also emphasizes cooperation and information sharing among various departments, especially when dealing with financial risks, it is necessary to strengthen anti-corruption and coordinate supervision, auditing and judicial . In addition, the draft also proposes the establishment of a financial stability guarantee fund. This creates strong institutional support for financial stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to emphasize the main responsibility of financial institutions, especially the responsibility of shareholders. Article 11 of the draft adds &quot;Financial institutions should strictly abide by systems such as capital and risk management, corporate governance, related transactions, and customer rights protection, and effectively monitor, identify and prevent financial risks. Financial institutions should establish a system with clear rights and responsibilities and effective checks and balances.&quot; Corporate governance structure and internal control mechanism to prevent major shareholders, actual controllers, directors, supervisors, senior managers and other relevant personnel from violating regulations and intervening in the control of financial institutions,&quot; which further refines the requirements for subject responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The draft also clarifies the responsibilities, disposal measures and procedures of various departments when dealing with major financial risks, especially emphasizing the self-rescue responsibilities of the financial institutions being disposed of and the principle of adopting market-oriented disposal methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Stabilization Fund&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Risk Disposal Reserve Fund&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the central bank’s version of the consultation draft , what are the similarities and differences between the National People&#39;s Congress version of the draft? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center compared the two versions and found that the People&#39;s Bank of China version has 8147 words and 48 items, and the National People&#39;s Congress version has 8433 words and 49 items; although the number of words and items has not changed much It&#39;s big, but actually a lot of content has been deleted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is to further improve the coordination mechanism among member units such as financial management departments, development and reform departments, and finance departments, clarify the nature and functions of the national financial stability and development coordination mechanism, and prevent work conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to clarify the positioning of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund as a reserve fund for the country&#39;s major financial risk disposal. The draft specifically explains the purpose, sources of funds and repayment measures of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund. Among them, the financial stability guarantee fund consists of funds raised from financial institutions, financial infrastructure operating institutions and other entities, as well as other funds specified by the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to strengthen the risk prevention functions and risk resolution rights of deposit insurance funds, clarify the scope of industry protection funds, and clarify the division of labor between supervision and protection funds. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, it is proposed for the first time that financial management departments and local people&#39;s governments should disclose relevant information on financial risk prevention, resolution and disposal in accordance with the law. And promptly clarify false or misleading information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, the provisions on the source of funds for disposal have been deleted from the People&#39;s Bank of China version, and the responsibility of local governments for the disposal of financial risks caused by non-financial enterprises has also been deleted. A researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that this should consider the resources and tools that local governments can mobilize when dealing with financial risks, while preventing excessive delegation of responsibilities and ensuring overall coordination of financial stability and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sixth, the relevant information of the national financial basic database must be provided to the people&#39;s governments of provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, deposit insurance fund management agencies, and industry security fund management agencies. The financial management department of the State Council and provinces and autonomous regions , The people&#39;s governments of municipalities directly under the Central Government should promptly notify each other of discovered financial risks and hidden dangers, and strengthen information sharing in the coordination mechanism. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Before, during and after the event&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Parties Responsibilities are clear&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The draft also clarifies a series of pre-, in- and post-prevention and handling measures for financial risks: pre-prevention emphasizes prudent access conditions, standardizing the company’s internal control mechanism, clarifying Prohibiting sexual behavior and other means to effectively control the source of financial risks. Regulatory authorities, governments, insurance protection fund management agencies and other departments should form a joint regulatory force and share data and information to identify and prevent potential risks in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of resolving issues, the draft emphasizes actively responding to and resolving financial risks in their early stages. Regulatory authorities should assume the responsibility for regulatory correction, paying particular attention to the role of early corrective measures. At the same time, financial institutions should assume the responsibility of risk resolution as the main body, and adopt various methods according to the actual situation to reduce the scale of assets and liabilities, suspend related businesses, liquidate existing assets and other measures. Local governments should provide support and assistance within the scope of their responsibilities, and crack down on violations of laws and disciplines in accordance with the law to ensure that risks can be resolved as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of post-event disposal, the draft requires that the division of labor in financial risk disposal correspond to the responsibilities of each entity. In addition to the main responsibilities of the disposed financial institution and its major shareholders and actual controllers, corresponding support is also required from the deposit insurance fund, industry security funds, provincial governments, central banks, and financial departments to ensure that risks can be effectively resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the draft clarifies the division of responsibilities among various entities. This will prevent, resolve and deal with financial risks more effectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How do the Financial Stability Fund&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; and the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Deposit Insurance Fund&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; collaborate&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The financial stability guarantee fund in the draft has attracted much attention. How does it interact and complement the currently operating deposit insurance fund and industry protection fund? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission published &quot;Perseverance in Preventing and Resolving Major Financial Risks&quot; in &quot;Qiushi&quot; magazine, which pointed out that the basic framework of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund has been initially established, and the first batch of 64.6 billion yuan of funds has been Once the funds are raised in place, the deposit insurance system will be strengthened, and the management regulations for insurance protection funds and trust industry protection funds will be further revised and improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The draft establishes a collaborative system for the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund. It has formed a cooperation model with a clear division of labor with the deposit insurance fund and industry guarantee fund. This collaborative system aims to maintain the stability of the financial system and provide multi-level protection against financial risks. The central bank&#39;s &quot;Monetary Policy Implementation Report for the Fourth Quarter of 2022&quot; mentioned that the basic framework of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund has been initially established, a certain amount of funds have been accumulated, and it has been actually used in two risk disposal cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The deposit insurance fund plays a key role in this collaborative system. On May 1, 2015, the &quot;Deposit Insurance Regulations&quot; came into effect, and my country&#39;s deposit insurance system was officially established. It sets differential rates based on the risk levels of financial institutions and promptly identifies and reports risks to promote early resolution of risks. The People&#39;s Bank of China disclosed that as of the end of 2022, 3,998 deposit-taking banking financial institutions across the country had gone through insurance procedures in accordance with regulations. In 2022, a total of 48.727 billion yuan in premiums had been collected, and fund interest income of 988 million yuan had been realized. Fund support was transferred back upon maturity. 276 million yuan, and the deposit insurance fund balance reached 54.94 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scale of insurance protection funds has also continued to expand, and the system has continued to be optimized. The insurance security fund is an industry risk relief fund formed by contributions in accordance with the provisions of the Insurance Law and the &quot;Insurance Security Fund Management Measures&quot; and is used to rescue policy holders, policy transferee companies or deal with insurance industry risks. In September 2008, China Insurance Security Fund Co., Ltd. was established to be responsible for the raising, management and use of security funds in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trust industry protection fund/liquidity mutual aid fund has also been established, with funds paid by trust companies to deal with systemic risks of trust companies, large spillover risks and other major risks identified by regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The draft emphasizes the principle of caution in the use of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund: it can only be used when it may cause systemic risks. The International Monetary Fund (IMF), the Bank for International Settlements (BIS) and the Financial Stability Board (FSB) define systemic financial risks as: large-scale disruptions in financial services caused by the destruction of all or part of the functions of the financial system, and This has had a serious negative impact on the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This helps ensure the effective use of the Financial Stability Guarantee Fund, while promoting healthy competition and survival of the fittest in the financial market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Overseas&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Financial Stability Fund&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Self-rescue first&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Post-external bailout&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What experience do Europe and the United States have in preventing and resolving financial crises? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Core Principles for an Effective Deposit Insurance System&quot; jointly issued by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (BCBS) and the International Association of Deposit Insurance (IADI) pointed out that the deposit insurance system is consistent with the central bank&#39;s lender of last resort function and prudential supervision. constitute the three pillars of the financial safety net. The deposit insurance system has been established in at least 146 countries and regions and is a basic institutional arrangement that is universally implemented internationally. For example, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it is not enough to have a safety net of bank savings. The eye of the financial crisis in 2008 was American International Group (AIG), the largest insurance company in the United States. If AIG went bankrupt at that time, in addition to the risk spreading to banks and non-bank financial institutions, the aircraft and cars it insured would not be able to be transported. This will bring huge chaos to society beyond economic activities. Therefore, there is a need for a protective mechanism specifically targeting systemic financial risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States&#39; Orderly Liquidation Fund (hereinafter referred to as &quot;OLF&quot;) and Europe&#39;s Financial Stability Facility (EFSF) and European Stability Mechanism (ESM) are important safeguards established to address systemic financial risks and crises. Sexual security agency. Their establishment and operation are both unique and common. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;OLF was built to address the bankruptcy and liquidation issues of complex large financial institutions. The background to its establishment was the 2008 financial crisis. At that time, the government recognized that the bankruptcy of large financial institutions could trigger systemic risks. Subsequently, in 2010, the United States introduced the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, which proposed the establishment of an orderly liquidation system and the establishment of an OLF to provide liquidity support for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;OLF&#39;s funding sources are mainly the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) and creditors who receive compensation in the orderly liquidation process. After liquidating a problem institution, the FDIC can first borrow money from the Treasury Department. However, if the liquidation costs are not covered by the asset liquidation, fees will be charged to other financial institutions to replenish funds. This mechanism reduces the systemic risk of dealing with the bankruptcy of large financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Europe also has the Financial Stability Facility (EFSF) and the European Stability Mechanism (ESM). The EFSF was originally intended to provide temporary loans to maintain the stability of euro area member states. The main source of funding for the EFSF comes from loan guarantees provided by Eurozone member states, and it also issues bonds in international capital markets. The European Stability Mechanism (ESM) is the successor to the EFSF and has stronger rescue capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Europe has also established a Single Resolution Mechanism (SRM) and a Single Resolution Fund (SRF). These mechanisms are used to deal with major financial risks and crises, especially those of multinational financial institutions. These mechanisms have played an important role in responding to the sovereign debt crisis, maintaining the stability of the euro, and promoting the European integration process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned basic protection funds are designed to maintain the stability of the financial system and respond to systemic risks, and emphasize the principle that the financial industry assumes the main responsibility and the national finance serves as backup support. They all adhere to the core principle of &quot;self-rescue first, external assistance second&quot;, encouraging financial institutions to prioritize self-rescue in crises and reduce the involvement of external funds. These mechanisms provide experience and reference for the construction of my country&#39;s financial stability system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The central-local coordination mechanism&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;needs urgent improvement&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Financial supervision involves the relationship between the central government and local governments. From the perspective of the financial powers of the central and local governments, there is a certain conflict between the central vertical supervision model and the local territorial supervision model. The central government usually pays more attention to national risk prevention and the stability of the financial system, while local governments may pay more attention to the development of local economies and the prosperity of local financial markets. In order to obtain financial support from institutions or more credit input, local financial regulatory authorities often choose to put benefits first. This different focus may lead to regulatory coordination problems, and the central and local coordination mechanisms urgently need to be further improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of risk management, local governments may use deposit insurance and other systems to shirk their responsibilities, and the public may misunderstand the deposit insurance system, resulting in the transfer of financial risks to other regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to better coordinate financial supervision between the central and local governments, a more complete central-local coordination mechanism should be established to ensure consistent policy objectives in risk prevention and financial supervision. As the draft emphasizes information sharing between. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National People&#39;s Congress version of the &quot;Draft&quot; deleted Article 38 of the People&#39;s Bank of China version regarding the order of use of disposal funds, or taking into account the possible conflict of powers between local governments and financial regulatory authorities. Objectively speaking, local governments are burdened with multiple tasks, and their ability to control systemic financial risks may exceed their current capabilities and human and financial resources. There may still be a situation where the central government still needs to handle risks, so there needs to be room for flexible operation on a case-by-case basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of financial stability, local financial regulatory authorities, based on the overall goal of full coverage of financial risks, are committed to specifying local financial risk prevention and control responsibilities, achieving necessary complements to central financial supervision, and avoiding local financial activities There is a regulatory vacuum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taken together, strengthening financial regulatory coordination between the central and local governments is the key to ensuring the stability of the financial system and sustainable economic development. This requires prudent policy design, clear legal systems and effective implementation to ensure consensus and coordination among governments at all levels to jointly maintain the health and stability of the financial market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Financial Stability Law&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;will have far-reaching impact&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If the Financial Stability Law is formally implemented, its impact will be far-reaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the bill will have far-reaching impacts in five aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, we will strengthen the supervision of financial institutions and pay more attention to risk prevention, thereby reducing the potential risks of financial crises and systemic risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to help ensure fair, transparent and orderly operation of the market. This will increase investor confidence, attract more capital to flow into the market, and promote market prosperity;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, financial innovation will be promoted within the regulatory framework to ensure the adaptability of innovation and regulation. This will help the financial system better meet the evolving economic and social needs, thereby promoting the optimization and upgrading of China&#39;s financial sector;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourthly, the bill will strengthen China&#39;s cooperation with international financial regulatory agencies and other Cooperation with national regulatory authorities. This will help China better integrate into the international financial system and work with other countries to respond to global financial challenges;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, the bill also emphasizes the prevention and disposal of financial risks and establishes the principle of &quot;rescue yourself first&quot; The core principle of &quot;after poverty, external bailout&quot;. This will help to respond to financial risks in advance and reduce the vulnerability of the financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the introduction of this bill reflects the Chinese government’s active role in the financial field and will make positive contributions to the healthy and sustainable development of China’s future economy and the stability and security of the international financial system. contribute. This marks that China has made great progress in financial supervision and reform, and has broad significance for the global financial market and economic system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赵郁飞丨移家作个画中人：我印象深刻的六部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The history of movie watching for young people in the county is evident: the sense of ritual is taught in the Army Auditorium and the Workers’ Cultural Palace, and the enjoyment is in the Main Theater The translation accent is established. The sudden release of &quot;Titanic&quot; stirred the air in every street and alley, and the owner of the disc rental house held the key to the world of Narnia. At that time, the &quot;eMule&quot; was not yet a means of transportation. It needed to be paired with the shooter&#39;s plug-in subtitles to travel. Cinema chains and video websites have arrived, occupying both the government and the opposition, and the old territory has been determined. The weird thing about time is that you don’t know what it will take away and what it will leave behind. Fortunately, the movie sets up an eternal Neverland, allowing you to easily escape into two or three hours of reality. Kuang Huifeng&#39;s &quot;Double Tune Looking at the South of the Yangtze River&quot; says: &quot;Seeing that the flowers in the painting never fall, I moved home and became the person in the painting.&quot; How similar is the situation. Due to a little salvage in the river of memory, the most impressive movies are listed as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 08/7jnTKEiYQoezSHAm6gGbi0rn5Z2tBXDsiA0jOnBd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;499&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7jnTKEiYQoezSHAm6gGbi0rn5Z2tBXDsiA0jOnB d. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Old Things in the South of the City&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;That generation of female writers who crossed the sea seemed to have a unique temperament, the tide and the gravel After polishing, the text will exude a light luster like a mother-of-pearl. Such as Lin Wenyue, who Yu Guangzhong calls &quot;sensitive and gentle&quot;, and another example is Lin Haiyin. Fortunately, I became familiar with &quot;Old Stories in the South&quot; at the right time window (before puberty) and got the chance to watch the movie of the same name. &quot;I have never seen the sea, I can&#39;t tell the difference between the sea and the sky, and I can&#39;t tell the good guys from the bad guys.&quot; When did that pure world shatter before our eyes? When her father&#39;s tombstone gradually disappeared in the autumn mountains, and finally became smaller than a red leaf, Eiko on the carriage drove away from her childhood. After my grandmother passed away this summer, I suddenly remembered this long scene. Although I have lived as a sojourner for many years and have already reached a de facto relationship with my hometown, I know that a small piece of my past related to my life has been lost forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, &quot;Old Things in the South of the City&quot; is the Chinese version of &quot;Education of Love&quot;. The flowing and subtle emotions in it rely on the movie to materialize them one by one. If combined with the watercolor illustrations painted by Guan Weixing for this book, we can almost achieve an all-round intertextuality that &quot;contains names and images, and encompasses audio and visual content.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/a1kmmF8DYauAMKeZov9aOH8JG6dyqtwoszpFblQP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;537&quot; height= &quot;716&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/a1kmmF8DYauAMKeZov9aOH8JG6dyqtwoszpFblQP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257530&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Tiexi District Yanfen Street&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mu Gang&quot;, &quot;Singles&quot; and &quot;Dance Master&quot; are about the Northeast of the Era. Director Yu Guangyi is exactly what I have seen since childhood. , typical Tunguska physiognomy. &quot;Tiexi District&quot; is different. It&#39;s so close that it&#39;s almost a complete piece of my world of experience. The mixed smell of fresh snow, sewage and burning firewood opened the random door of memory. I could walk freely through Yanfen Street without wearing VR glasses. When the curtain of mountains and dense forests is removed, even cruelty cannot be transformed into tragedy. There is no magic, only reality. The child chewed dirty words, the boy&#39;s courtship process was like a threat, and the topic on Yanfen Street gradually focused on relocation. &quot;Sooner or later, we have to leave. No one can stop the weather.&quot; The middle-aged man sitting on the beam said it so lightly, as if what he was smashing was not his own house. I can&#39;t tell you exactly how I acquired this bitter optimism, even though I, like him, have long been accustomed to facing the fate of snow-capped mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/25LMKLctd96yJ54Vb3QSisblSMkmMHEq1LiKCw8R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; height= &quot;724&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/25LMKLctd96yJ54Vb3QSisblSMkmMHEq1LiKCw8R.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257529&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;&quot;Eavesdropping Storm&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Zongyuan has an interesting &quot;Essay on Corpse Insects&quot;, which describes a kind of corpse insect that lives in the human belly. It specializes in listening to people&#39;s words, recording them secretly, and reporting them to the Emperor of Heaven on every Gengshen Day: &quot;Because of this, many people have been banished, suffered from illness, and died young.&quot; Mrs. Liu then cursed bitterly: &quot;Come on, corpse insect! Don&#39;t you recognize your own shape? It&#39;s dark and treacherous, and it contains people, and it&#39;s like a thief. The old man is in this place, and he doesn&#39;t choose to be filthy and humble. He quietly listens in silence. , leading people to wrongdoing. Holding the slips secretly shakes the opportunity for disaster; the humble fists are shrinking, and the house is dangerous. Use bends as form, evil as quality. Use benevolence as evil, use blasphemy as good... , He keeps his ingenuity, is jealous of others&#39; abilities, and is lucky to lose others.&quot; His awns are sharp and sharp, especially in &quot;The Legend of the Grasshopper&quot;. In fact, locusts are greedy and short-sighted, but they do not necessarily harm people; the plague of corpse insects is even more unknown to Yiyu Hudi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, I am talking about &quot;The Overheard Storm&quot;. After watching the film, my friend and I fell into a long silence. Its goodness is self-evident, and its goodness also makes us sad. The story has a heart-warming ending, but the reality is that insects are &quot;less stupid than stupid, but they still harm benevolent people.&quot; It is said that the clean version deleted the scene where Wiesler was awakened to some kind of life force after the wiretapping. Why bother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7soD4BNiaDLDWmfcIEvG5x8pokSDhYPmBp4Y519v.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;566&quot; height= &quot;802&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7soD4BNiaDLDWmfcIEvG5x8pokSDhYPmBp4Y519v.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Brothers in their early days&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Al Pacino, Christopher Walken, and Alan Arkin, each of them has been together for decades His experiences, sorrows and joys are combined into an atypical gangster film. The two old friends were released from prison and nursing home respectively into the market. Doc quickly tied up the thread, and what followed was a bucket list-style unfolding. Val invites a strange girl to join him on the dance floor at a bar - an apparently staged dance. Under the dim light, the faces of Val and Colonel Sfarlan kept overlapping each other, and even the two dance partners standing at opposite ends of time were somewhat similar. Hirsch relied on two mouthfuls of oxygen to condense all the essence of life, and with all his strength, his energy penetrated the rainbow. Every time he recalled that he was kissed wildly by beauties in turn, he couldn&#39;t help laughing out loud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last shot of the film shows Val and Doc, each wearing a suit and sunglasses, holding two guns, calmly walking towards the enemy&#39;s armed forces in a building. The final battle is extremely gorgeous and decisive. Johnny Cash&#39;s chant sounded at the right time: I&amp;nbsp;hurt&amp;nbsp;myself&amp;nbsp;today,&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;see&amp;nbsp;if&amp;nbsp;I&amp;nbsp;still&amp;nbsp;feel.I&amp;nbsp;focus&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;pain,&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;only&amp;nbsp;thing&amp;nbsp;that&#39;s &amp;nbsp;real .&amp;nbsp;Remembering the rivers and lakes forever and returning to gray hair is indeed a different state, but there are many emotions in life that cannot be let go, and good nights that you are unwilling to walk into. The acting skills of the three actors are flawless, and the viewing experience is like a piece of butter toffee slowly melting in your mouth, which is really enjoyable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/I2RE2UGpgzmbb42GN3GDdlYXGZODhOMNmY864uGX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;502&quot; height= &quot;782&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/I2RE2UGpgzmbb42GN3GDdlYXGZODhOMNmY864uGX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257532&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Arrival&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Arrival&quot; is lighter than &quot;Interstellar&quot; - this is of course compared to the latter&#39;s hard science fiction nature. Linguistics as a methodology is like a dagger, prying open the nut shell of the universe. In her study of alien languages, Louise Bank realized the non-linear thinking that is very different from human beings: the movement of everything is not a sequence of dominoes toppling over, but a cycle with no end and no beginning. On a huge dome called destiny, the past, present and future are spread out in her eyes at the same time (the original work by Ted Chiang is called &quot;The Story of Your Life&quot;). This is a sadder superpower than eternal life. She transcended time, but she still couldn&#39;t escape the cause and effect. Louise chose to get married and give birth to a daughter - even though her death was predicted years later. She named her daughter Hannah, a palindrome that means &quot;wandering around without interruption&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, I taught students about late Qing poetry. Xie Meiru said in &quot;The Poems of Gambling Villa&quot;: &quot;The style of poetry... although it is extremely clever, it is ultimately beautiful.&quot; Wei Shanboxiang said: Poetry It has a palindrome, just like plum blossoms have wax plum blossoms, but the type does not meet the character.&quot; I deeply understand this statement. However, the wonderful use of &quot;Arrival&quot; probably depends on the aesthetic surprise brought by crossing the boundary and the right amount of ingenuity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NlY4JnKnOJUi8kCuntOSzjhSUDNJ2C7ztSeYk64r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;506&quot; height= &quot;760&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NlY4JnKnOJUi8kCuntOSzjhSUDNJ2C7ztSeYk64r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257531&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;&quot;Three Billboards&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;My preference for crime themes can be traced back to the 1990s. When I was a child, I watched too many rough and fierce domestic criminal investigation dramas. &quot;Three Billboards&quot; just filled the void I felt after three seasons of &quot;Fargo,&quot; and I realized that it was more than just a meal replacement. Two fires and three letters, the former cuts the story into natural segments, the latter is responsible for changing the trajectory of the characters, and the author of the letter, Sheriff Willoughby, is the white ball that sacrifices his life to hit others. If you want to select &quot;classic letters in movies&quot;, this film can be selected together with &quot;Cape 7&quot;, &quot;Green Book&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human nature is so profound and strange that creators are scrambling to take a cup of it. However, it is too difficult for man to defeat God by his cleverness. It&#39;s a common problem for screenwriters or directors to have too much ego. &quot;Two smart heads fighting&quot; movies are the type I dislike the most. From this perspective, the original script of &quot;Three Billboards&quot; can be called a paradigm, or it may directly quote Willoughby&#39;s last words to Mildred: &quot;Like a chess move.&quot; When this narration sounded, the backlight close-up focused on Mildred&#39;s skinny appearance. Veins on the back of the hand. Actresses like Frances McDormand are truly &quot;indispensable&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[人类请回答：科幻能否跟上现实的魔幻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260297]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VHmTK17O6xJf358f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VH mTK17O6xJf358f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, the main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention-Chengdu Science Fiction Museum, people walk in the &quot;time and space tunnel&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A problem that has never occurred in 5 million years&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy for Mr. Bryant, an 80-year-old science fiction fan, to travel to Chengdu from Hampshire. He first took a flight from the UK to the Netherlands, transferred in Beijing, and finally arrived in Chengdu. Pidu District, Chengdu City is the venue for the 81st World Science Fiction Convention. The local area is famous for Pixian Doubanjiang. Two years ago, Mr. Bryant voted for Chengdu, China, at the World Science Fiction Convention. In mid-October 2023, he arrived at the appointment and came to mainland China for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Mr. Bryant has not read the most popular science fiction work in China - Liu Cixin&#39;s &quot;Three-Body&quot; series, nor has he read any Chinese science fiction works, after a few days with Chinese science fiction Face-to-face communication with fans, his interest in this place has gone beyond science fiction. As a lover of cooking, he plans to bring several jars of bean paste and a local cookbook in English when he returns home to study Sichuan cuisine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chengdu Science Museum, which looks like a giant spacecraft and covers an area of ​​nearly 60,000 square meters, people often excitedly share their encounters with him in the WeChat group of science fiction fans on site. At the age of 80, he still has a strong curiosity about the world, which gives young science fiction fans a lot of encouragement. However, the language barrier has become Mr. Bryant&#39;s biggest challenge in participating in this conference. He has participated in 14 World Science Fiction Conventions before, and only 4 of the previous 80 conferences were held in non-English speaking countries. The venue in Chengdu had elements from science fiction movies and TV shows like &quot;Star Trek&quot; and &quot;Doctor Who&quot; that he was familiar with, but the most popular ones were Panda and &quot;The Three-Body Problem.&quot; People often take photos with the &quot;Three-body&quot; stone pillars outside the venue. One of them is engraved with the warning issued by the Three-body monitor about the risk of the destruction of human civilization, &quot;Don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In November 2014, Liu Cixin and Liu Yukun (middle left) were in the same frame at the 5th Chinese Science Fiction Nebula Award Ceremony held in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Yibo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Chengdu, Ethan, a software engineer from New York, USA, was about to finish reading &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; The first one, for which he temporarily put aside a collection of short African science fiction novels he was reading. At nearly 40 years old, the only Chinese science fiction work he had read before was &quot;The Story of Your Life&quot; by Ted Chiang (the original work of the movie &quot;Arrival&quot;). This time, the Chengdu Organizing Committee provided benefits such as travel assistants, transportation, Hugo Awards, and opening ceremony viewing quotas for science fiction fans who came from 3,000 kilometers away. However, Ethan believes that many European and American science fiction fans have given up on attending the conference remotely. Obviously, &quot;there are language barriers, there are few direct flights, air tickets are expensive, and you need to transfer in other countries.&quot; He said that science fiction fans in Europe and the United States are mainly middle-aged and elderly, and traveling for more than ten hours will be very hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, the 79th World Science Fiction Convention was held in Washington, USA. The Ethan family witnessed the success of Chengdu Science Fiction. This process was full of twists and turns. “At that time, there were many discussions about whether the conference should be held in China, such as whether it could comply with conference traditions, voting formats, cultural differences, etc. Of course, the current political situation is also very complicated,” he said. In the travel warning to China issued by the U.S. State Department at the end of June 2023, mainland China was listed as a &quot;third-level&quot; travel destination, calling on U.S. citizens to &quot;reconsider whether to go.&quot; After hesitating for a month or two, Ethan finally decided to come to mainland China to take a look. When he said this, we were sitting around a table eating butter hotpot. Several other sci-fi fans attending the meeting were from Russia, Canada and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2880&quot; height= &quot;1958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257751&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 26, 1999, Liu Cixin attended the &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; PEN Conference in Chengdu. At this time, he was participating in a PEN discussion with his new work &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The organizing committee has previously announced a set of data as of August 31: In addition to members of the World Science Fiction Association who enjoy offline participation rights, non-Chinese participants who purchased offline participation packages There were 51 people, accounting for 1% of the total number of people who purchased offline package tickets. There were 3,908 Chinese citizens who purchased offline package tickets, most of whom were attending the conference for the first time - including Xiami. Xiami, who is in his early 30s, is a physics teacher at a university in Xiamen, Fujian. In 2003, Xiami, who was in the second grade of junior high school, read novels by Wang Jinkang, Liu Cixin and others in a borrowed magazine &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;, and &quot;officially entered the pit of science fiction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, let Xiami prepare What makes him feel disappointed is that although the venue is large, the area and number of science fiction fan exhibition areas are far less than he expected. Afterwards, Xiami was very sorry to hear that Ethan brought the board game with him but could not find a suitable venue or playmate. After college, he mainly devoted his energy to theoretical research. &quot;This conference is like going back to the pit to take a look.&quot; There is a long &quot;tail&quot; on Xiami&#39;s participation card - if you participate in the booth activities, you will have the opportunity to obtain a booth. Homemade creative ribbons, which are traditional peripherals at science fiction conventions. During the second half of the conference, Xiami turned to the salon of new generation writers. His notebook was filled with notes about the creation of science fiction novels, and his suitcase also contained more than a dozen novels by new generation writers. He is ready to restart the dream he had in high school - to write science fiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the rapid changes in reality, can science fiction still provide people with enough strangeness and surprise, and can science fiction creation keep up with the magic of reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height= &quot;558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Hague, Netherlands, August 1990, Yang Xiao (second from left) with famous American science fiction writer Harry Harrison (first from left) and British science fiction master Brian Aldis The couple attended the WFS annual meeting together. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now, reality and science fiction do have a competitive relationship.&quot; Science fiction writer Han Song said. Sometimes he serves as a judge for science fiction awards and finds that some science fiction works are not as surprising and strange as reality. &quot;Reality is more like an alien world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 58-year-old Han Song is the leader of the external editorial department of Xinhua News Agency , is also a science fiction writer. Before arriving at the venue, he had already published a rather optimistic report on Xinhua News Agency, &quot;Embracing Science Fiction, Creating Tomorrow.&quot; For more than thirty years, he spent the day writing, editing and distributing news reports for the world at the Xinhua News Agency building on Xuanwumen West Street in Beijing. He got up at three or four in the morning to write science fiction before going to work. In 2018, he finished writing the science fiction novel &quot;Hospital&quot; trilogy. A few years later, when the COVID-19 pandemic hit the world, many people turned to his novels to contrast the visions of reality. Han Song continued to compile and publish reports on the COVID-19 epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1939, the first World Science Fiction Convention was held in New York, USA, reflecting that in the 20th century when the theory of relativity and quantum mechanics appeared, the evolution of human civilization entered a new stage, &quot;another turning point has been reached.&quot; Han Song He said, &quot;Quantum mechanics and the theory of relativity have appeared in the past 100 years. All the material foundations we have today are laid by these two theories. In these 100 years, humans have created weapons that can destroy themselves and other life on the earth. This is 500 years of human evolution.&quot; A phenomenon that has never happened in ten thousand years. Now we have nuclear weapons, artificial intelligence, nanotechnology, and life technology.&quot; One of the meanings of the existence of science fiction is to face these problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many salons at this science fiction conference talked about artificial intelligence, controllable nuclear fusion, quantum computing and communications. More than 80 years after the birth of nuclear weapons, some countries have used controllable nuclear fusion technology to solve the earth&#39;s energy problems. During the conference, science fiction writers were invited to the Southwest Institute of Physics of the CNNC Nuclear Industry to visit the nuclear fusion device known as the &quot;artificial sun&quot; - China Gyre 3, a new generation of artificial sun - which was selected for the &quot;Annual Science Fiction Plan&quot;. 74-year-old science fiction writer Wang Jinkang stood in front of the &quot;artificial sun&quot; and observed. As a senior engineer specializing in internal combustion engines, he once used nuclear energy to build a new path from the earth to outer space in science fiction novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Song, who also came to visit, immediately conducted an interview and wrote a report &quot;Science Fiction Writer Approaches &quot;Artificial Sun&quot;&quot;. The two-story ring-shaped device is covered with colorful pipelines and surrounded by instruments and computers. The nuclear fusion device looks like a giant monster. Most of the scientists explaining it on site are women. Han Song immediately thought of &quot;Frankenstein&quot; written by the British writer Mary Shelley in 1818, which was the first modern science fiction novel in human history. &quot;Science fiction was created by women.&quot; He was also thinking about his own science fiction. If controllable nuclear fusion solves the energy crisis of the entire earth, and if everyone on the earth has equal access to so much energy, will families and marriages disappear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Han Song’s view, science fiction is a species literature. “有时候文学是一个民族的心灵史，但科幻是把人类物种作为一个对象来描写的文学。”他觉得这就是每一次科幻大会的意义，“所以你总是会好奇，想了解跟我们一样的这些人，面对同一种技术、同样一个命题，他们是怎么想的？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8ENsufAnh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8ENsufAnh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在2023成都世界科幻大会主题展览上，观众在挑选科幻IP周边产品&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;世界的科幻文学&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1990年，为了节省开支，杨潇女士乘坐8天8夜的火车，横跨欧亚大陆，去荷兰海牙参加国际科幻专业协会（WSF）年会，同行的还有时任四川省外事办公室新闻出版处处长申再望、《科幻世界》美术编辑向际纯。他们拖着一大箱四川科幻文学的成果和熊猫元素的礼物，再次争取1991年WSF年会的成都举办权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前一年5月，作为《科学文艺》主编的杨潇只身奔赴在圣马力诺举办的WSF年会，二三十人坐在一间小会议室里，讨论全球科幻最关注的问题，“在讲大气污染、人类在太空中的位置、低温生命维持、飞向太空……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国科幻正在起步，中国的青少年很喜欢科幻。”她在会上反复说。她的英语不太好，答辩时全程拿着两小本《汉英简明辞典》《英汉简明辞典》，记在纸上英译中、再中译英，但最终为成都拿下了1991年的WSF年会举办权。在场的其他人说她“With a little English and lots of determination to do a lot of things（用一点英语和很多决心去做很多事）”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而这一决定在之后被推翻，要在1990年的WSF年会重新投票选定1991年的会议举办国。这次杨潇一行三人准备充分，回答各种问题和质疑，展示中国科幻的成果和熊猫的可爱模样。会议讨论尾声，英国科幻新浪潮运动主将、WSF发起人之一的布莱恩·奥尔迪斯站了起来，他的话向来一言九鼎，一向温和的他严肃、郑重地说：“政治争执只是一时的，东西方之间的对话和了解是长期的，人们之间的友好是永恒的。我们不要跟着政治风云走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在1980年代，奥尔迪斯与中国科幻作家郑文光就有通信。郑文光生于1929年，曾是中国科学院北京天文台研究员。 1957年，郑文光的小说《火星建设者》在莫斯科世界青年联欢节获奖，这是第一篇在国外获奖的中国科幻作品。有一次，收到郑文光寄来的信和新书《郑文光新作选》，奥尔迪斯在回信中对书名表达了惊讶，难道你们那真的叫这种名字吗？这种名字在我们这是卖不出去的，我们这出合集，得摘里头最好看的小说来当书名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991年5月，中国成都，国际科幻专业协会年会的现场，66岁的奥尔迪斯与62岁的郑文光重逢，那时的郑文光已经坐上了轮椅，奥尔迪斯在各个场合都帮忙推着他的轮椅。那年到场的还有美国科幻作家弗雷德里克·波尔等。这场年会还请了在高校开设科幻创作课的学者吴岩等人，对年轻的创作者也充满鼓励——为了让武汉大学学生韩松加入，《科幻世界》的总编谭楷写信给不相识的武汉大学校长、数学家齐民友，齐很快批准并资助了400元作为食宿费用。会上，韩松把早前被退稿的《宇宙墓碑》给在场的台湾学者吕应钟看，吕应钟带到台湾交给了作家张系国、张大春，最后这篇小说在1991年获得世界华人科幻文艺奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在2023成都世界科幻大会主题展览上，参观者在欣赏机器人“寂静”打架子鼓&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这场连接了许多人的科幻年会后，中国科幻重新走上了轨道。创刊于1979年的《科学文艺》在同年更名为《科幻世界》，后来接连发表新作者王晋康、韩松、何夕、刘慈欣的科幻小说——如今他们成为了中国科幻界的“四大天王”。年会上集体参观都江堰时，23岁的韩松问一位外国老头，在世界科幻中，关于政治的主题怎么写？他后来才知道这人就是奥尔迪斯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他来过这里两次，总是非常热情地谈论他所认识的人以及科幻界正在发生的事，并非常希望中国的科幻作品能得到更多认可，这也是他如此热衷于举办那次科幻年会的原因。他的书房里总是有一张他和杨潇的照片，这对他来说非常重要。”在2023年成都世界科幻大会，奥尔迪斯的女儿温迪·奥尔迪斯对我说，这天下午她完成了两场与杨潇对话的沙龙。如今，奥尔迪斯先生已经去世六年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991年到成都时，奥尔迪斯曾为到成都前转机被弄丢一件行李而懊恼不已，那是一小箱送给《科幻世界》编辑部的科幻书籍。温迪这次带了一大摞父亲的书，活动时就放在沙龙的桌子上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥尔迪斯书里的一些事已经变成现实。奥尔迪斯最著名的作品是从1961年开始在英国《幻想与科幻》上连载的《丛林温室》，他构建了一个智能植物称霸地球的“后地球时代”，那时的地球已是一个停止了自转的巨大温室，与月球形成了一个稳定的系统，通天的植物将枝叶蔓伸到了有飞人居住的月球。史蒂文·斯皮尔伯格导演的电影《人工智能》则改编自奥尔迪斯的《玩转整个夏天的超级玩具》。小说诗意而忧伤，这是关于拥有人类情感的机器人的故事，机器人不想让养育他的人类发现，他已经知道了自己是机器人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥尔迪斯的作品充满对现代文明的反思。实际上，诞生于1818年的英国科幻文学，本就是科技革命和工业革命的产物。这种相比其他文学类型很晚才出现的文类，最初有着两种创造现代社会的愿景：一是乌托邦，起源于大航海时代的亦真亦假的游记；二是人类会持续进步的思想，这是随着启蒙运动和法国大革命而逐渐成型的叙事，并在世界范围内对人类的思想产生深远影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国的科幻文学就伴随着启蒙现代性而生。 20世纪初，鲁迅翻译了《月界旅行》《地底旅行》《造人术》等科幻小说（当时叫“科学小说”）。同时期，越来越多名家加入到科幻文学的译介或创作中。那时科幻文学的参与者大多向往科技进步带来的时代变化，并探讨人类及世界未来的种种可能。新中国成立后，郑文光等新中国第一批科幻作家出现，他们的科幻小说承担了一部分科普责任，中国科幻上世纪初对现代性的积极态度得到了一定程度的延续。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月17日，成都科幻大会主场馆旁的无人机表演&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在现代化进程更早的西方，始终不乏对现代文明有所警惕的科幻作品，甚至在第一篇现代科幻小说《弗兰肯斯坦》中，就已经有对科学的怀疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当人类可以研制出毁灭地球的武器、发动灭绝物种的战争时，西方国家以外也出现了成熟的反思现代性的作品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1964年，日本举办奥运会那年，日本科幻作家小松左京开始写《日本沉没》，这部写了九年的小说在出版后轰动了日本社会，小说描写日本列岛因地壳大变动而沉入海底。日本战后的经济奇迹反而让小松左京深感忧虑，他为人们消耗大量资源和能源、与自然界和社会形成紧张冲突的关系而担忧，也流露出对人类命运的巨大悲悯和同情。 “日本科幻对我的影响很大，具体到《三体》，其实受了《日本沉没》巨大的影响。我看《日本沉没》后很震惊。一部科幻作品竟然能把一个民族深处最敏感、脆弱的对未来的恐惧感体现出来。”刘慈欣曾说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和小松左京一样活跃于20世纪下半叶的日本科幻作家星新一，其短篇小说《喂！出来》曾在21世纪初被收入中国语文课本。很多国内的中学生第一次在教科书读到这一类型的故事。小说里，地球上突然出现一个无底洞，人类发现这个洞无穷无尽，便毫无顾忌地将自己制造的所有垃圾和污染物倒了进去。后来，当人类无休止倾倒的破坏和欲望全部被喷回地面返还给人类时，作为预兆的恰是人类发现这个洞时那句天真无知的呐喊，“喂——出来！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，世界科幻大会第一次走进亚洲。日本横滨，第65届世界科幻大会开幕式上，76岁的小松左京坐在轮椅上出场，他是把日本乃至亚洲科幻推向世界的第一人。 “半个多世纪前，他就如先知一般，预言科学进步并不必定使人幸福，他表达了人类的痛苦，揭示了人性的野蛮，同时寄予期望和光明。”韩松非常喜欢小松左京，那年他和作家、学者吴岩，《科幻世界》社长秦莉、总编姚海军一起到横滨参加科幻大会。小松左京看到他们非常开心，握着韩松的手，用中文反复说，多谢，多谢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“时代已经追上来了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年，世界科幻大会第二次来到亚洲。在成都世界科幻大会现场，只要有刘慈欣出席的场合，他总像磁石般吸引着全场的欢呼和注目。即便不是当场嘉宾，他的名字和《三体》也是沙龙里各国嘉宾绕不开的话题。作为中国最著名的科幻作家，刘慈欣的签售会被组委会特意安排了三个小时，从下午两点半开始，然而当天上午11点刚过，签售大厅便已排起了长队。以往刘慈欣每次签售都坚持签完最后一位排队的读者，这次他签了三个小时，签到手抖，还想坚持，但被主办方拦住了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月21日，四川成都，中国作家海漄（中） 创作的《时空画师》 获雨果奖最佳短中篇小说奖&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年，《三体》获得了第73届雨果奖最佳长篇小说奖，刘慈欣成为首个获此殊荣的亚洲作家。如今，60岁的刘慈欣已经成为中国最著名的作家之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次的科幻大会会场，中庭最显眼的位置有一座约9米高的白色雕塑，原型是《流浪地球2》中的月面机器人机械狗“笨笨”，总是有很多人围着笨笨拍照，它是“流浪地球”IP授权业务中最具代表性的产品形象。改编自刘慈欣同名小说的《流浪地球2》在中国大陆票房累计40.29亿元，全球票房5.98亿美元，还将代表中国大陆角逐第96届奥斯卡奖最佳国际影片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成为著名作家之前，刘慈欣的工作是工程师，在山西省阳泉市一个名叫“娘子关”的小镇的电厂工作。在他成名后，那个小镇被很多新闻记者探访。本届科幻大会的一系列活动中，刘慈欣在一场主题为“工程师科幻”的沙龙中展现出难得的放松和尽兴，“现实中再困难的事情，在小说中都能解决，不费吹灰之力。难就难在曲折的技术建构，如何把最疯狂的想象、最缥缈的超级技术用最有实感的细节写出来，让读者就像在看新闻报道和历史记录那般真实。”他钟爱工程师科幻的独特美学，渴望自己能做到，也渴望在别人的作品中读到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随着各大陆资源的枯竭和环境的恶化，世界把目光投向南极洲……但人类的理智在另一方面取得了胜利，全球彻底销毁核武器的最后进程开始了，随着全球无核化的实现，人类对南极大陆的争夺变得安全了一些。”刘慈欣于2003年发表在《科幻世界》的短篇小说《地球大炮》是虾米的入坑之作。小说贯穿着一种镇定和坚毅：政府建造了一条从漠河穿过地心直达南极的隧道。这项超级工程因灾难性事故而被封闭。此后全球环境进一步恶化，人类为寻找出路，决意把地球上的工业转移到太空。隧道被重新启用，人类在其中加上磁铁线圈，利用地心引力和安培力把地球变成了“地球大炮”，得以低成本地把地表物品抛送到近地轨道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次读到这个构想恢弘的故事时，还在读初二的虾米便感受到了与其他文学作品迥异的刺激和惊喜，“我一下就被那种新奇的设定和宏大的史诗感击中。”从此《科幻世界》成了虾米的每月必读刊物。到了2006年，虾米在《科幻世界》读到刚开始连载的《三体》，当科幻迷们津津乐道地分析《三体》中的物理设定时，没有人能预见这部小说将把中国科幻引向什么样的未来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;成都世界科幻大会的一场沙龙间隙，布莱恩特先生向本刊记者展示他自制的塑封卡片，里面是他参加的过往14届世界科幻大会证件的集锦。 80岁的他表示自己回家后，会将本次的参会感想和建议通过邮件分享给主办方。 “十年后如果中国再次举办世界科幻大会，我希望自己还能来参加”&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者陈洋/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘慈欣写《三体》第三部期间，曾在杭州参加了一次科幻作家笔会。大家聊“如果要把杭州彻底毁灭，应该用什么方法”，他一激动，说可以先把城市二维化，变成一幅水墨山水，再一维化，成为一根细细的丝线。大家听了都很兴奋。酒醒之后，刘慈欣很紧张。还好没有人挪用这个科幻构想。二向箔正是于2010年出版的《三体III:死神永生》中最令人惊艳的宇宙规律武器之一。它的能力是降维攻击，将三维坍缩成二维。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《三体III》出版的2010年，随着智能手机和4G网络的普及，中国从PC互联网时代跨入移动互联网时代。小米和美团在这一年成立，微信在次年推出。小米创始人雷军在2010年看完《三体》后又推荐给其他企业家，并多次公开谈及《三体》的“降维攻击”“黑暗森林”对互联网战略的启发。 《三体》系列收获了科幻圈的推崇，而这些互联网新贵们的讨论则令这部作品打破圈层，真正进入大众视野。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻在一个地区的发展需要现实土壤，这在其他国家早已得到验证。 19世纪，英法科幻文学受益于工业革命而发展，以凡尔纳、威尔斯为代表。二战后，以美国为代表的西方科幻文学进入鼎盛期。而日本科幻的高速发展时期是1970-80 年代，1970 年代的日本缔造了经济快速发展的“日本奇迹”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过美籍华裔作家刘宇昆翻译，英文版《三体》在2014年开始传播。 Facebook创始人扎克伯格称《三体》“把我从最近所读过的经济、社会、科学书籍中解脱出来，令我感到轻松愉悦”。时任美国总统奥巴马看完《三体》后，“觉得当个美国总统和浩瀚的宇宙相比实在太渺小了。毕竟每天处理的都是和国会争论的琐事，不用担心外星人入侵。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，《三体》英文版权续约金高达125万美元，创下中国文学作品海外版权输出的最高纪录。美国流媒体订阅平台奈飞制作的《三体》剧集将于2024年登上荧幕。 “中国科幻就是国际传播非常成功的例子，不是说花了多少钱，不是一定要生硬地往世界推广。我觉得中国科幻是向世界学习，把世界科幻好的东西跟中国的传统文化和现代文化融合，打上了很强的中国烙印，再让世界去感受中国人的科幻。中国科幻面对世界的普遍性问题，比如环境、太空、战争等等问题，提出了中国式的解答，让世界感受到这个解答是有价值的、独一无二的，能够给世界带来意想不到的收获和惊喜。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;韩松在办公室&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;种种偶然与必然让《三体》系列成为难以再创的奇迹。每次公开活动，都有人问刘慈欣何时出新作，超越《三体》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位科幻作家在与科技竞赛。刘慈欣一直保持着阅读前沿科技文章的习惯。他习惯于在大脑精准建模之后，再“一鼓作气写出来”。 2015年，他在接受《三联生活周刊》采访时提到自己之前构思了整整两年的一个“好点子”，这个题材曾被他寄予厚望，不仅设定留有很大的发挥空间，他在电力系统工作的经历也可以帮助他刻画丰满的人物形象。直到有一天，他看到一篇由日本早稻田大学的研究者发表的文章。对方不仅提出了同样的想法，还“算出了总的发电功率”，并提出“在拉格朗日点建立中继站把微波送回来”等等。看完这篇文章，刘慈欣彻底放弃了这个构想，已经写好的30万字手稿就此尘封。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘慈欣将新作品发布的门槛设定为“能让自己兴奋起来”，并强调自己“一直在努力”，但阻力也前所未有。 “经常是刚开始写时觉得很震撼，写到一半却发现时代已经追上来了，连自己都觉得很无聊了，于是重新开始写，时间就这么浪费过去了。”刘慈欣对我说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“科技的飞速发展削弱了科学的神奇感以及人对科学可能创造的未来的期冀，这对传统类型的科幻小说的打击很大。”他认为这是像他一样“依托于创意和世界建构”的硬科幻作家的共同难题，“东西方的同行都在努力，希望用更多的表现手法来恢复科幻创作的活力。但坦率说，目前效果并不好。”他甚至有些后悔，觉得自己早年间发表的三十多个中短篇小说是对题材的过度挥霍，耗完了激情。而未来，随着科幻故事的表达载体从小说转向荧幕，他也担忧自己是否能适应角色变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我能写作的时间，最多也就是10年左右了。”刘慈欣觉得让这场倒计时加速的还有人工智能，“ChatGPT写出的科幻小说越来越好，我不知道人工智能给我们，至少给我还留下多少时间。”他认为这是自然规律，不能算悲观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;导演郭帆在《流浪地球2》 片场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;新的危机与科幻的生命力&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“铁鸟知道自己将不久于世，于是，他开始努力回忆往事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那时候所有的行星都还在冷战呢，他回忆到，将死的心中荡起一丝转瞬即逝的兴奋。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松低低的声音念着自己在30年前写的《冷战与信使》，这是本届科幻大会唯一的读书活动。他觉得这是一个爱情小说，“两代人，政治，战争，男权，女权。人在时空中的卑微。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这篇小说是科幻作家糖匪坚持选的，她觉得很适合多地发生局部冲突的当下。一位来中国参会的美国科幻迷在出发前被公司禁止携带电脑。特拉维夫国际科幻电影节的创办人乌里·阿维夫来自巴以冲突的战乱地区。等大会结束，他又要回到屡遭空袭的以色列特拉维夫。特拉维夫国际科幻电影节将于12月开幕。一些工作人员被征召入伍，许多工作面临调整。 “我们肩头的责任比以往任何时候都更重，科幻作品能为人们提供平静和治愈的力量，帮助他们在对当下和时代的忧虑重压下喘一口气，得以思考、构想和期待更美好的未来。”一个小时的读书中，活动现场挤满了人，竟有人听得落下泪来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类不得不直面这充满不确定的现实。韩松原本想在读书会上展开读糖匪的新书《后来的人类》，甚至准备了三段内容，分别对应着设定架构、机器、关系。小说构建了一种未来的新型公寓，人工智能“家庭主脑”控制着公寓的一切，以无所不用其极的方式来照顾人类，实际却是一个监视者，甚至成了统治者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管新生代的科幻作家对外部世界的描写更加多元和令人兴奋，也更广阔，但韩松觉得科幻文学目前还需要更大的想象力。此外，他觉得女性作家写得更细致，有时候写得更深刻，“不仅体现在对情感的了解，还有对历史和社会的认知。”他觉得反映社会问题最好的作品之一就是郝景芳的《北京折叠》（获雨果奖），慕明和双翅目的作品也有很强的社会风格，技术后面有很强的历史和社会认知。 “但有些男作家写现实就显得有点着急，我觉得比较粗线条。不一定写到这样的主题，就算写到了，小说到他技术惊奇的画面那里就截止了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场科幻大会的几天之前，韩松赶去浙江绍兴参加了一场中日作家的交流会，与会者有多位芥川奖得主和鲁迅文学奖得主。会议特意选在了鲁迅的出生地举办，鲁迅是最早把科幻小说译介到中国的人之一。这一场交流会谈论的问题，成为世界科幻大会探讨的许多内容的预演。这些东亚作家首次一起深入讨论人工智能时代的文学到底是什么、人类在新技术条件下生活的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一场科技革命都会引起欢呼和惊恐，人工智能的发展也不例外。但全球对人工智能产生全面的紧张感是从2022年底ChatGPT的发布开始的。有观点认为，随着以AI为代表的智能化生产方式的出现和普及，第五次工业革命正在发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《三体》剧照(2023) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人类以前只是感觉到危机。更早以前大机器出现，感觉到要失业，然后核武器出现，感觉到人类会被灭绝。但是这次不一样。前面几次工业革命创造的都是物质，这次人工智能的科技革命，创造的是精神。”韩松说，“而且这个精神，看上去比人类思考得还要厉害，而且人类也不知道这个人工智能是怎么想的。”这是人类物种（被更替）的危机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“反倒是科幻小说，对未来人工智能做了方方面面的预测性描述。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年写人工智能和元宇宙的科幻小说变得非常多，而且将未来建模得相当详细。最近，韩松读到墨熊的新小说就是写后人类时代，全球人工智能挽救人类，让人类能在整个宇宙演化的灾难中继续生存，最后的办法是人与机器融合的怪物更替了人类这一物种。科幻作家江波近几年也写了很多人工智能。 “他还是很悲观地认为人和机器的战争是很难避免的。写共生的也有，人机耦合也写过，但我还是觉得不可预测。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;653&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松的“医院三部曲”在2018年全部出版，这个系列由《医院》《驱魔》《亡灵》组成，也想象了人工智能：“药时代”里，医药成了新的神；“药战争”接替了全球“核战争”；在医药战争中，整个宇宙也像病人一样走向死亡，而不得已遭遇所有故事的，不过是一个因为喝了坏水而被送进医院的可怜上班族。书中的忧思最初只在学界传播，哈佛大学教授王德威在参加北京大学纪念“五四”运动百年活动演讲时，指出韩松的“医院三部曲”重启了早期鲁迅对科学与文学的批判性思考。到2020年全球暴发新冠疫情时，一些人找到韩松的这套《医院》，来对照眼前惊人的生活。 “在社会发展、生活逐渐繁荣的同时，每个人内心深处都有一层伤口。生活凭靠运气，下一步怎么活下去没有把握。许多担忧与无力交织在人心里，内化成心底的巨大惧怕。”2017年，刚写完《驱魔》的韩松对我说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;662&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;694&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文学发展到现在，韩松认为其处理的核心问题没有根本性的变化，科幻对现代性的继承、发展和反思与主流文学是一致的，“最早的&#39;鲁郭茅巴老曹&#39;本质上就是在写现代性的问题。 ”在他的观察里，这些年主流文学在应对现代性方面有些弱化，“我不知道是什么原因，它跟现实好像有点脱节。有些纯文学好像要把现实描写得很精确，也在写现实，但好像不是我们真正的现实。但是科幻某种程度上弥补了这种现代性，尤其是揭示了科技和经济又一次巨大变革后，民族也好、人类也好，危机的存在。虽然不能完全做比较，但我觉得科幻文学像鲁迅《呐喊》一样地喊大家。文学还是要直面现实问题，而不仅仅是语言的技巧。我觉得中国科幻崛起的一个根本原因，是它反映了现代性。 ”11月2日，韩松在电话里平静地说。他正在福建厦门的金鸡百花电影节担任创投大会“科幻片单元”的特邀嘉宾，在这通采访电话结束后便要去参加讨论会。科幻片单元入围作品《星际信使》就改编自他的《冷战与信使》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，我在新华社对外部实习时，想做一篇北京地铁的报道，我的实习老师建议我采访部门领导韩松，并读一读他的短篇小说《地铁惊变》。韩松每天上班来得很早，总是拍下1号线首班地铁中乘客的样子。我还记得自己在韩松楼下办公室读完《地铁惊变》后因惊栗而久久无法动弹的状态，那是我第一次看见熟悉的现实在科幻中的扭曲和变形。他又写了《高铁》《轨道》，和《地铁》组成“轨道三部曲”。他写那些在新闻中总以进步和繁荣之姿出现的技术，“新闻成为世界的镜子就很不容易了，讽刺小说是一面哈哈镜，科幻像个万花筒。 ”韩松拿这个万花筒看高铁，看科技、经济、政治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松编发过很多灾难报道。2008年汶川地震发生时，新华社第一个向世界报道了震级，“整个晚上，我们特别难过的，是不断地编发了一所一所学校倒塌的新闻，大批的学生被埋在下面。学校，还是学校……”在那个书山一样的办公室，韩松依然写新闻或科幻，又过了两年，他交了科幻小说《再生砖》：大地震后，建筑师用废墟瓦砾、麦秸和死尸制造了新型建筑材料。在艺术展斩获国际大奖后，再生砖被大规模生产并在灾区和全国推广，再生砖风靡世界，带动灾区振兴，人类聆听和赞美砖头里亡灵的哭声。人类如此迷恋再生砖，以致记不住任何教训，甚至去外星球播撒人造微生物来制造新灾难，最后发现，宇宙本身就是一块由废墟和生命建成的再生砖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对韩松来说，是科幻作家叶永烈带来了科幻的火种。叶永烈的《小灵通漫游未来》在1978年出版后很轰动，“中国人之前沉浸在人与人的斗争中，很久没有想象未来时空了。 ”他觉得叶永烈最了不起的科幻小说，自己至今也无法超越的，还是那篇《巴金的梦》，发表在1980年代的《科幻世界》。“他写中国未来一定会建这么一个牢记历史的博物馆，而且是与国际合建，他详细描写了这个馆怎么建，有什么馆藏。这个小说光是能发表就很了不起了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，叶永烈对未来是乐观的。他是《十万个为什么》的主要作者，又写了《小灵通漫游未来》。他在20世纪60年代写了21世纪的中国，有生产粮食的工厂，有给学生上课的机器人，有电脑的普及，有人造肉、人工控制天气，还有会飞行的汽车等等，向那个年代的小读者描绘出一个充满希望与光明的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014年11月，刘慈欣（中右）与刘宇昆（中左）在北京举办的第5届华语科幻星云奖颁奖礼上&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（李一博提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年世界科幻协会年会在成都举办期间，主办方组织作家采风，韩松（左）与科幻作家张劲松（中）、舒明武在四川彭州银厂沟合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;金字塔的地基&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日，1990年出生的作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得雨果奖“最佳短中篇小说”奖，成为继刘慈欣、郝景芳后第三位获雨果奖作品奖的中国科幻作家。雨果奖评选委员会负责人戴夫·麦卡蒂在颁奖晚会后对《南方周末》说，《时空画师》“创造了一个无英文译本、完全由中文作品获奖的历史”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这届世界科幻大会上，多项科幻产业发展相关的计划公布，甚至有科幻产业项目的集中签约仪式。与科幻素有渊源的成都提出“科幻全产业链生态圈”“IP打造”“强化科幻之都形象”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熙熙攘攘的会场、沙龙和展厅，都在彰显科幻的“热”。但作为文化产业的一部分，国内科幻产业的发展仍在起步期。据“IT桔子”的数据，2022年国内文娱行业有投融资事件88起，涉及投资金额46.36亿元，数量和金额创近5年新低。据《证券日报》不完全统计，截至2023年9月14日，该年国内文娱行业（含传媒、游戏、元宇宙、社交、体育）共发生13起投融资事件。而2022年国内文娱领域投融资事件为96起，2019年该数据为2158起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文化品牌“未来事务管理局”（以下简称“未来局”）创始人姬少亭是第三次参与世界科幻大会，此前两次分别在英国伦敦和芬兰赫尔辛基。许多西方参会者向她提起他们的惊讶发现——中国科幻迷群体的年轻化和较高的女性占比。海外科幻的发展历程较长，科幻迷大多是中老年。收获同行惊羡的同时，姬少亭心里思考的却是另一个问题，从青年到白头，这些西方读者为何能数十年保持对科幻的热爱？答案很明确。 “他们一定是被持续投喂了大量优秀的作品，这意味着有创作热情的人才在源源不断地涌入科幻行业。归根结底是因为这个行业体量足够大，足够提供就业和发展的强大支撑。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2015年8月23日，美国宇航员凯尔．林格伦在地球之外350 公里的国空间站通过视频连线向全球宣布:中国作家刘慈欣凭借科幻小说《三体》（第一部）获得第73 届雨果奖最佳长篇故事奖，从而成为该奖自1953 年创立以来首位获此殊荣的亚洲人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，成都世界科幻大会会场的巨型雕塑，原型是《流浪地球2》中的月面机器人机械狗“笨笨” &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，姬少亭离开工作10年的新华社，创立未来局，开始深度参与到科幻产业发展。七年来，未来局已成为国内主要的科幻IP开发方之一，参与了众多图书、影视、游戏、玩具等行业科幻IP项目的开发和策划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年1月，未来局举办了《流浪地球》的第一个观影会，导演郭帆和刘慈欣第一次在电影院完整地看成片。映后，姬少亭十分坚定地对我说，这部电影肯定会火的。这部电影被认为“开启了中国科幻电影元年”，票房和效应超出预期，并给电影行业带来巨大的启示。 《流浪地球》在中国大陆票房累计达46.88亿元，全球票房7.39亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，影视行业对科幻题材的理解整体还处于初级阶段。同时，受累于羸弱的投资环境，科幻影视的市场化步履蹒跚。据阿里影业总裁李捷2023年4月在一场创投大会上介绍，阿里影业的科幻电影创投，10到15个项目中，进入成片阶段的只有1到2部。在同一场活动中，《流浪地球》《宇宙探索编辑部》的监制王红卫则勉励科幻创作者“咬住牙”，“我希望以后一年起码有一部高质量的科幻作品，能够再撑住我们这个类型。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《流浪地球》系列的成功反映出国内对优秀科幻作品需求惊人，需求和供给之间的巨大沟壑就是行业的机遇所在。对于具体的公司、事和人，机遇是肯定存在的，就看谁能把握住。好的作品是一切。”姬少亭说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年，由于发表渠道和推广资源收紧，姬少亭明显感觉推进一件事的阻力要比过去大得多。 “经济面临下行压力，各个环节都缺钱，变得保守，不愿试错，资金和资源会向顶级作者和作品集中。当然，这更有利于实现单点突破，弊端则在于新人出头和成长的机会在缩减。”未来局在成立那年就启动了科幻写作培训，致力于持续培养并帮助新兴科幻作者成长。姬少亭常被问道，什么时候才会出现下一个刘慈欣，“我真正希望看到的局面是大量中等以上作品的出现。如果我们连金字塔的地基都不扎实，没有足够庞大的基数，要如何期待下一个刘慈欣呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;淡蓝的小点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;吴文琛重返科幻的世界，是因为《流浪地球》。 2019年上映时，他和妻子、儿子一起去影院看了这部电影。现在，他11岁的儿子在写一个科幻小说。吴文琛小时候也看《科幻世界》，写科幻小说的念头倒是从来没有过。当年《科幻世界》每页的最下边是读者栏目，刊登读者的一句话想象和地址，来稿的多是中学生。吴文琛在中学时也投过稿，还在《科幻世界》发表了一句对世界的好奇和想象，那像是人在少年时对宇宙的呐喊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次从成都市中心来郫都参加科幻大会，就是儿子拉他过来的。上高中后，他再也没读过科幻，后来工作、开公司，生活工作连轴转。看到台上坐着创办《科幻世界》的编辑们，他一下被刺激到，在互动环节举手，几乎不停歇地说了几分钟：“我从一个理想主义者变成了何夕老师口中的现实主义者，但我也没有办法……现在小孩的教育压力真的太大了，我非常忧愁这样的教育会影响孩子的想象力发挥，但我也不知道怎么办。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨潇有一个写着很多中外科幻作家名字的本子，上面有郑文光，有奥尔迪斯，像一本中外科幻交流的合集。这次大会结束后，杨潇的本子上又多了一个名字，是吴文琛的儿子吴嘉麒。杨潇和谭楷把这个11岁的孩子请到台上，鼓励他的写作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年代，《中国少年报》编辑找到郑文光，请他为孩子们写一篇科幻小说。这是天文学家郑文光成为新中国成立后第一位科幻作家的契机。他在故事里虚构了三个偷偷开走火箭船的小孩，他们一路飞到火星的上空，看见了这颗星球上的红色沙漠和蓝绿色植物，这么绕着火星转了一大圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年5月，出席成都世界科幻协会年会的日本作家柴野拓美在卧龙点燃了象征友谊的籍火，随后大家围着籍火跳起了锅庄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在2023成都世界科幻大会主题展览上，一名小科幻迷在VR设备上观赏太空景象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个天真烂漫的故事发表在在1954年的《中国少年报》上，引发了意想不到的热烈反响，《从地球到火星》成为新中国第一篇有影响力的科幻小说：北京掀起了“火星热”，那时候，北京天文馆还没有成立。为了满足孩子们的好奇心，《中国少年报》编辑部在建国门上的古观象台架起一座天文望远镜。孩子们吃了晚饭，就到古观象台排队看火星，为此可以一直排到深夜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都的这场大会同样热闹，有非常多的新闻报道，“但科幻还是一个小众的东西，甚至读它的人还没有读奇幻和魔幻的多。科幻不是一切，不要以为它代表一切、能拯救万物，好像科幻才能让科技发展，不是那么回事，我觉得就一个平常心来看待它。科幻大会是一个粉丝的文化，大家喜欢在一起。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种平常心更接近韩松刚写科幻时的心境。在他的少年时代，1980年代，人们总想把什么送上太空去看一看。韩松的第一篇小说是中学时写的，他首先写陨石在地球砸了一个洞，人们往洞里看，什么也没有。老师说不行，他就写了一篇小说送一只熊猫上太空。 “没有写科幻的话，很可能我就是一个整天泡在酒局饭局里、吃完大家胡扯一通、然后打牌睡觉又开始第二天的人，一辈子就过去了，甚至更糟糕的是，加入到争名夺利的战争里去。”这么多年写科幻，与其说带来什么变化，不如说是不变，“科幻让一个人保持了少年时候那种好奇、纯粹、探究的心，甚至包括那时候那种莫名的惆怅、恐惧，那种本能的跟宇宙、自然的天然的联系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在科幻大会落幕的傍晚，成都科学馆像日落中停泊的一艘飞船。我和吴嘉麒在馆里聊他的小说。他之后要回家赶作业，有点担心接下来的功课过多，不知什么时候才能完成那写了一半的科幻小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也是一个有关太空漫游的故事。 11岁的作者在小说里，给两年前过世的曾祖母造了一座宇宙飞船，她离开了地球，在浩瀚广阔的星际，见到了那些人类无法想象的风景。故事里，她已经找到了一颗移居的星球。当她回头望地球，那颗所有人类出生和死亡的星球，那颗众多文明诞生又毁灭的星球，凝成了宇宙中一颗淡蓝色的小点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢吴岩、杨枫、科幻光年、糖匪、西夏、刘悠翔、北落师门等对采访提供的帮助，感谢八光分文化提供历史图片支持。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被控受贿2.1亿，招商银行原党委书记、行长田惠宇案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月9日，湖南省常德市中级人民法院一审公开开庭审理了招商银行股份有限公司原党委书记、行长田惠宇受贿、国有公司人员滥用职权、利用未公开信息交易、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息一案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常德市人民检察院起诉指控：1997年至2022年，田惠宇利用担任中国信达信托投资公司副总裁，上海银行股份有限公司党委委员、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司上海市分行党委副书记、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司深圳市分行党委书记、行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司北京市分行党委书记、行长，招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长等职务便利以及职权、地位形成的便利条件，为有关单位和个人在贷款审批、业务承揽、工作调动等事项上提供帮助，非法收受他人给予的财物，折合人民币共计2.1亿余元；田惠宇在担任招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长期间，为徇个人私利，违反规定，滥用职权，干预招商银行股份有限公司附属机构正常经营决策活动，致使国家利益遭受特别重大损失；利用因职务便利获取的内幕信息以外的其他未公开信息，违反规定，从事与上述信息相关的证券交易活动，情节特别严重；身为证券内幕信息知情人员，在对证券交易价格有重大影响的信息尚未公开前，买入该证券，或者泄露相关信息，或者明示、暗示他人从事上述交易活动，情节特别严重。检察机关提请以受贿罪、国有公司人员滥用职权罪、利用未公开信息交易罪、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息罪追究田惠宇的刑事责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审中，检察机关出示了相关证据，被告人田惠宇及其辩护人进行了质证，控辩双方在法庭的主持下充分发表了意见，田惠宇进行了最后陈述并当庭表示认罪悔罪。庭审最后，法庭宣布休庭，择期宣判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人大代表、政协委员及各界群众三十余人旁听了庭审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电诈和战乱，热搜不断的缅北]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年10月27日，缅北多地的政府军据点遭武装袭击并爆发交火，战事激烈，胶着至今。战乱之外，近几年的缅北深陷电信诈骗漩涡。战乱加上电诈让缅北成为舆论焦点。&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[历时9月，金融机构“标杆”呼之欲出]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260291]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;标杆是商业竞争的至佳境界和核心考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央金融工作会议强调，金融是国民经济的血脉，是国家核心竞争力的重要组成部分。牵一发而动全身的金融业，它的标杆又应有何特异之处？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为彰显金融标杆的共性，南方周末新金融研究中心研究团队历时9个月，已相继完成“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”的指标体系优化、测评对象调整、数据更新、深调研和外部专家评审团打分等各项工作。榜单名次呼之欲出。“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”和“2023年中国新金融发展趋势报告”将于2023年12月8日在北京举办的“新金融大会”上正式发布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何确定测评对象？测评制作榜单为何耗时如此之久？外部专家评审团成员是谁？较之市场上的各类金融业榜单，“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”有何特异之处？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心为此进行部分揭秘。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;聚焦“主力军”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”将分为八个子榜单和总榜。本次榜单测评对象锁定中国金融业的主力军。哪些金融机构是主力军？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心认为，商业银行、商业保险公司和公募基金领域的头部机构即为中国金融业主力军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;较之7—9月发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，此次榜单有何调整？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时移事易。针对商业银行领域，南方周末新金融研究中心根据2023年9月中国人民银行发布的国内系统性重要银行名单，将6大国有银行、9家股份制银行和5家城市商业银行共计20家商业银行纳入测评范围。因此，较之7月发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，测评名单增加了一家商业银行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对商业保险领域，南方周末新金融研究中心将业务规模排名前八的寿险公司纳入测评之中。较之此前发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，测评名单增加了一家未上市大型寿险公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在公募基金和基金销售领域，南方周末新金融研究中心重点测评了资产管理规模排名前32名的公募基金机构和18家第三方基金销售机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综上所述，榜单测评覆盖金融机构总数量达79家，极具代表性。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;覆盖&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;八&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大领域&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;金融机构哪些业务领域是榜单测评核心考量范畴？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据商业银行、寿险公司、基金公司及基金销售公司的战略业务板块和与公众密切相关的业务领域，南方周末新金融研究中心将财富管理、绿色金融、数字金融、数据安全、寿险效能提升、信用卡质效、风控合规和投教品质等八个领域作为榜单的核心考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，为更客观反映金融行业动态发展，南方周末新金融研究中心进一步全面优化财富管理榜、绿色金融榜、数字金融榜、数据安全榜、寿险效能提升榜和信用卡质效榜六个子榜单的指标体系及各指标的相应权重，以期指标体系及相关权重更合理更科学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时移数也易。南方周末新金融研究中心以2023年各金融机构中报所披露内容为基准，并辅以其它相关数据，对榜单数据进行大面积更新。而此前发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”以各金融机构2022年年报数据及相关数据信息为评测基准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，南方周末新金融研究中心对于大多数金融机构披露而个别金融机构没有披露的数据，对其实施降权处理，以体现对充分披露相关信息金融机构的鼓励。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心还将基于南方周末自研的“牧羊犬—金融合规云平台”发布2023年“金融合规榜”。其中，“牧羊犬—金融合规云平台”已完整收录中国人民银行、国家金融监督管理总局、国家外汇管理局公开发布的行政处罚大数据，并成功实现数据库的标准化运作。因智能和人工双校验，该平台已是金融领域数据最完整最精准且功能最强大的合规数据库。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为激励新秀和倡导创新，南方周末新金融研究中心还特设新金融人物和新金融创新案例等三个年度奖项，并公开接受报名&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;三维&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”内外兼&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;评&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如何为各金融机构定座次呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;定量定性的指标测评体系，依然是此次榜单的核心权重，但非全部权重。其中定量定性合计权重占比70%。因此，在各项科学权威的指标里，真实透明的各项数据在为各金融机构的分值“说话”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心对上述各金融机构的深调研将构成另外一个权重。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员持续一个多月以问卷调研、电话调研、线上会议调研和实地调研等形式调研了解各金融机构最新最深的发展情况。此调研结果将占测评权重的15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心还特邀了7名在金融领域的重磅专家。他们以自身长期研究结果对测评对象实名打分，权重为榜单的15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数研结合、内外兼评，“三维”测评法将提升榜单的权威和含金量。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;谁是专家&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;评&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;审团成员&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为进一步凸显本次榜单的客观、权威和公正，并充分考虑上述榜单涉及细分领域的专业性，南方周末新金融研究中心特邀对应行业的7位权威专家和学者组成外部评审团。他们将独立实名行使测评权，测评权重占榜单权重15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外部专家评审团成员究竟是谁？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们分别是郭田勇、郝演苏、尹振涛、张伟、郑尊信、李秀兰和姚泽宇。（排名不分先后）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;尹振涛&lt;/strong>;现任社科院金融研究所金融科技研究室主任、国家金融与发展实验室金融法律与金融监管研究基地秘书长。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/Ljkoo5AF6AdWcCYYKu5ugPYyLMXX2TxM2tPo6ikN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;389&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/Ljkoo5AF6AdWcCYYKu5ugPYyLMXX2TxM2tPo6ikN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;张伟&lt;/strong>;现任清华大学国家金融研究院副院长、国家顶尖金融智库专家，多次受邀为决策层授课、建言。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/U5Eo4SfqJPGfdDOURjR96fRHX21QwuoHppfYPnl1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;407&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/U5Eo4SfqJPGfdDOURjR96fRHX21QwuoHppfYPnl1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郭田勇&lt;/strong>;现为中央财经大学金融学院教授、博士生导师并兼任中国银行业研究中心主任，还担任亚洲开发银行高级顾问、中国人民银行货币政策委员会咨询专家。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/AFZJT4YjmzTfqqBhbGS7u4jCCvMFTmLIWm8Vef1M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;431&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/AFZJT4YjmzTfqqBhbGS7u4jCCvMFTmLIWm8Vef1M.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郝演苏&lt;/strong>;现为中央财经大学风险管理与保险系教授、博士研究生导师，曾任中央财政金融学院（现中央财经大学）保险系主任、保险学院院长，兼任全国保险专业研究生教育指导委员会副主任委员、《保险研究》杂志编委。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ZroMrjYguLPOsX0gaIDstE7qw5D5lcB31fHW2Yt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;553&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ZroMrjYguLPOsX0gaIDstE7qw5D5lcB31fHW2Yt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257733&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郑尊信&lt;/strong>;现任深圳大学经济学院院长，是我国数量经济学领域的顶尖学者，在金融工程、资产定价、货币金融等领域拥有深厚造诣。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/QE9YvQjZ0VgylQ3URknpHyAtNl8RX704MTWzNuAr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/QE9YvQjZ0VgylQ3URknpHyAtNl8RX704MTWzNuAr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李秀兰&lt;/strong>;现任英国标准协会（BSI）可持续发展总监，绿色金融、ESG管理方面的资深研究者，连续多年参加联合国气候峰会并就气候变化、绿色金融、可持续发展等话题发表主旨演讲。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/zBgaabVyS6eFVJjV9KAcnHGWpN8OlWnzIpdQ7agz.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;499&quot; height=&quot;696&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/zBgaabVyS6eFVJjV9KAcnHGWpN8OlWnzIpdQ7agz.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;姚泽宇&lt;/strong>;现任中金公司研究部执行总经理、非银金融及金融科技行业首席分析师，在科技金融、数据安全等方面在海内外资本市场具备广泛影响力。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/666BeD7AR3IME1pUQTI48FA5Whs5Lueoken2Aegb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;637&quot; height=&quot;568&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/666BeD7AR3IME1pUQTI48FA5Whs5Lueoken2Aegb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（榜单研制：南方周末新金融研究中心研究员李鹤鸣、廖浩伦、张文景&amp;nbsp;蒋昭昆；助理研究员杨超群、邹欢、梁承昊、张金湖、许颖、白雨彤、杜城仪、李晓宛、张琦、陈淑怡、余瑶、李璐、彭君婷、丘子颖、陈祖旭、李金宇、杨相龙、陈乐瑶、刘伟钊、洪新、陈森荣、李书曼、曾子桓和廖剑豪对此榜单亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;数据库技术支持工程师：陈晓龙&amp;nbsp;叶伟豪&amp;nbsp;肖杰&amp;nbsp;唐伟斌&amp;nbsp;甄楚霏&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的《立冬》，竟是冒牌诗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260295]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月8日，立冬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在当天的微博等网络平台上，各式各样的立冬海报宣传图占据着各大官方账号的首页。这些海报上不乏古诗词文案。其中，《立冬》一诗出现频率颇高：“冻笔新诗懒写，寒炉美酒时温。醉看墨花月白，恍疑雪满前村。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看起来，这首诗描绘的情境确实契合立冬。各大官方账号在转发诗句文案的同时，也不忘加上诗人的鼎鼎大名：李白。或许是因为这些缘故，近几年来，每逢立冬日，这首诗总能在一众诗词中“脱颖而出”，成为立冬节气宣传的常客。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，早在2016年，有微博网友便发布帖子，揭示《立冬》这首诗并非李白所写，而是伪作。2018年11月7日，该网友发布微博写道：“连续三年辟谣，也经不住官方大V如此彪悍……成为&#39;李白《立冬》&#39;假诗的最有力官方传播者。”直至2023年立冬，该网友发布帖子时，依然会带上“立冬李白伪诗”的辟谣词条。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，南京师范大学文学院教授、李白研究专家郁贤皓在接受《扬子晚报》采访时，也称《立冬》一诗是伪作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，该李白伪诗并非孤例。2020年，复旦大学中文系教授陈尚君在接受《南方人物周刊》采访时，便曾举例，唐诗中最有名的伪诗是传为杜牧所作的《清明》，他认为，此诗并非出自杜牧，而是写于宋代。在采访中，他还引用日本学者平冈武夫的统计结果，称清编《全唐诗》虽收诗49403首，但里面的伪诗很多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月，北京，李白人形机器人亮相2023世界机器人大会。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，《立冬》一诗究竟来源于哪里？这类伪诗又是怎么被制造出来的？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“它就突然出现了，这是非常可疑的”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为一名中文系毕业的古诗词爱好者，许容与早在四五年前就一直在关注伪诗现象，而她注意到《立冬》这首诗的时间实际上还要更早。不过那时候，因为早已对李白多伪诗的情况习以为常，她也没有想过要专门去考证它。直至2022年，不少读者粉丝询问她一些伪诗的相关问题，她才专门写了篇考证文章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她看来，要查证一首诗是否为伪作，最直接的方法就是考察这首诗的流传过程——它最早出现在哪本书里？流传过程中有没有经过后人的篡改？今天看到的文字，是最初的面貌吗？这些都是很重要的问题。“古人的作品能流传，它一定是有一个载体的。”许容与对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现有的古籍数据库提供了极大的便利。许容与先是在《全唐诗》以及现存的各种李白诗集里去搜索《立冬》一诗，都没有结果。她转而将目光投向了现代出版物的数据库，她发现，一些比较严谨的书籍，会附上诗句来源，其中有的书籍便提到，《立冬》这首诗出自《唐诗画谱》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《唐诗画谱》是明代万历年间由黄凤池编辑刊行的诗、书、画合一的版画图谱。在《唐诗画谱》里，所谓《立冬》一诗，实际上诗名为《冬景》，第三句诗的内容也略有不同。《冬景》版本为“醉看梅花月白”，《立冬》版则为“醉看墨花月白”——许容与觉得，后者表面上看起来虽然也很雅致，但细究“墨花月白”的意象，会发现解释不通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在《唐诗画谱》里，除了《冬景》，还有《春景》《夏景》《秋景》，这四首六言诗均伪托在李白名下。经过更细致地研究，许容与发现，《夏景》里存在押韵押错的现象，而《秋景》则存在典故“穿越”的情况，即诗中所用典故比李白在世时还要晚几十年，这便从侧面证明这些诗并非李白所作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“（而且）这首诗从李白生活的唐朝，一直到明代万历年间，中间没有任何载体或者记载，没有出现过这首诗的身影。然后在《唐诗画谱》里面，它就突然出现了，这是非常可疑的。”许容与告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2018年接受媒体采访时，郁贤皓也提过，李白诗集在明朝以前有过不少刻本，宋时宋敏求已务求其尽，其编成的《李太白文集》收录有998首李白诗，此后流传下来的诸多选集和刻本，没有一本收录有六言诗。1908年，法国人伯希和在敦煌发现唐人写本，其中唐人选唐诗收录多首李白诗，无一首是六言诗。过了八百多年，突然出现那么多首六言诗，很有可能是书商为了卖书造假。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《唐诗画谱》里其实很多作品都是伪作，包括杜牧等很多知名唐代诗人的伪作，可能是（书商）请一些人做的，其实是为了赚钱，因为那些诗人知名度高、流量高。（这个书商）就有点像今天的枪手。”许容与说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她介绍，明朝商业经济相对发达一点，刻书业也很发达，刻书印刷是当时伪作的一个重灾区。“我们现在看到的很多（伪作）都是那个时候那些书商为了谋利，为了蹭流量而造出来的，（那些名人）是大IP。”许容与告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“古人一直喜欢伪托别人写东西”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;陈尚君曾在一次媒体采访中介绍，目前大众可以见到的大约一千首李白的诗歌，最主要的来源是李白本人的文集、唐宋时期的各种诗文选本以及各种史书、笔记、诗话、类书、方志等。“有的诗100%是李白的，有的诗只有1%的可能性是李白的，李白名下的伪诗至少就有几十首，而且情况各自不同。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他举了一首李白名下的《傀儡诗》为例：“刻木牵丝作老翁，鸡皮鹤发与真同。须臾弄罢浑无事，还似人生一梦中。”在《全唐诗》中，这首诗同时出现在李白、唐玄宗和梁锽三人名下，其中，梁锽名下的这首诗题目为“咏木老人”。现在普遍认为，他才是这首诗的作者。这首诗确实是唐诗，但不是李白所写。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而除了李白，如苏轼、辛弃疾等著名词人名下同样存在不少伪作。80后的林杉也是古诗词爱好者，在这一领域进行创作大概已有十年。自2022年起，他陆续对网络上流传比较广的三十篇伪诗进行考证，其中便包括辛弃疾这种著名词人的作品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在林杉看来，伪作在文学史上是有一个基础的：“古人一直喜欢伪托别人写东西，原因各种各样，有些是不想自己留名，还有一些是有自己的想法，但是在当时不敢说，所以假托古人来写。至于伪诗，像伪造李白，可能就是为了求名了——虽然自己没出名，但是被别人误以为真是李白的作品，心里也会很爽。还有像明朝这种故意伪造（来赚钱）的情况也是有的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于伪造的手段，许容与向南方周末记者介绍，一种比较普遍的情况就是东拼西凑，比如将对联的句子拆开，再与其他句子拼凑成诗。还有一种就是直接伪造，比如某人可能想刻一本李白的伪作书，那么他可能会直接找秀才创作，伪托在李白名下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两者也是导致许多伪作出现的较为典型的手段。至于一些张冠李戴的情况，比如抄写时看错诗人名，写错之后一直流传下来；或者在某些电影里实际上是由编剧创作的诗句，在传播过程中却被误认为真是由某位诗人所作，也有可能导致伪作出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于不太了解古诗词相关知识的普通读者来说，要进行伪作的识别和考证，其实很困难。“普通读者基本上是辨别不出来的，除非你还有一点格律知识，但是古人编的，你有格律知识也没用，因为古人都是会写诗的，所以他想伪造的话就很容易。”林杉告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，他觉得，如果在义务教育阶段，能向学生普及一些格律方面的知识，比如平仄不能互押之类的，也会有一些帮助，至少对一些“特别离谱”的伪作，大部分人就是能够辨别出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许容与也认为，要辨别伪作很困难，“其实伪作能够流行，最大的原因还是传播链路上（存在问题）。影响力非常大的人，专业的鉴别能力未必那么过关；但是像我们这种能够去鉴别一些东西，写一些科普文章的人，又没有那么大的影响力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但她觉得，有质疑精神还是很重要的，至少有可能离真相更进一步。“我觉得主要是有一个质疑的意识：觉得它有点不对劲，就去查一下它。你在网上搜，可能就会搜到一些人的质疑，你就可以接近真相。主要还是得有这种&#39;多问一句，多想一下&#39;的意识。”许容与告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，林杉为笔名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[CEO被传失联，斗鱼“内忧外患”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260293]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 21:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月6日，斗鱼证实CEO陈少杰失联的词条冲上微博热搜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，已有传言称陈少杰被查，失联三周。这位39岁的CEO一贯低调，鲜少出现在聚光灯下，上次出现在公众视野是8月14日举办的斗鱼2023年第二季度业绩电话会上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诞生于2014年的斗鱼（DOYU.&amp;nbsp;Nasdaq）熬过了中国游戏直播行业初期的野蛮厮杀，曾以凶猛的打法和早于其入局的虎牙位列行业双雄。 2019年，斗鱼迎来高光时刻，紧随虎牙成为美股上市企业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但近两年来，B站、快手、抖音等大型综合性中短视频平台加速出击，游戏直播赛道越来越卷。斗鱼内部亦经历主播流失、业绩乏力、丑闻频发等状况，前景并不乐观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月25日，斗鱼收到纳斯达克上市资格部发出的合规警告，称其收盘价已连续30个交易日低于1美元/股，不符合纳斯达克的最低股价要求。斗鱼需在180天内，或2024年4月22日之前，维持股票收盘价至少连续十个交易日不低于1美元/股，才能恢复合规。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和斗鱼莫测的前景相呼应的，还有CEO陈少杰的行踪。斗鱼方面向南方周末记者表示，对此消息斗鱼暂无官方回应，公司目前运转正常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月8日，斗鱼以0.82美元/股收盘，跌幅1.19%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“喜欢冒险、刀口舔血的人”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1984年，陈少杰出生于山东济南。观其人生经历：沉迷游戏、选计算机专业、大学辍学、连续创业，陈少杰集齐了互联网时代弄潮儿们身上的诸多特征，并成功将爱好做成事业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈少杰本人曾在一次斗鱼直播中直言，自己算是高中学历，大学上了一年就辍学了。他认为耗费四年读书也不一定对互联网有多深的了解，并对标三国，表示出身不是最重要的，“刘备原来是卖草席的，关羽卖枣子，张飞杀猪，随着各自的成长，他们都成了最牛的将领”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2009年底，陈少杰与其合伙人张文明将第一个创业项目“掌门人”对战游戏平台出售给盛大游戏，陈因此成为盛大边锋武汉公司的总经理。掌门人的功能是实现单机游戏的联机对战。极客公园曾报道，掌门人是一款成功的产品，上线一年，累计注册45万人，日活用户20多万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年，挖到第一桶金的陈少杰以400万元左右的价格收购了二次元视频网站AcFun（简称A站），并上线“生放送”直播频道。 2014年1月，陈少杰将“生放送”独立为带有弹幕功能的游戏直播平台——“斗鱼TV”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后几年，中国游戏直播行业进入爆发期。 2014年5月，背靠国有控股企业浙数文化（600633.SH）的战旗直播上线。当年11月，YY分拆出游戏直播业务成立虎牙直播。 2015年，龙珠直播以及王思聪的熊猫TV成立。 2016年，网易和腾讯先后上线CC直播和企鹅电竞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斗鱼一出场便是资本的宠儿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企查查显示，2014年刚成立，奥飞娱乐（002292.SZ）就对斗鱼进行了2000万人民币天使轮投资。同年在A轮融资中，红杉资本又投了2000万美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年3月斗鱼B轮融资，腾讯领投4亿元人民币，南山资本和天娱数科（002354.SZ）跟投，投资总规模达1亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5个月后的C轮融资中，由凤凰资本、腾讯领投，多家机构跟投，斗鱼最终募得15亿元人民币。在2019年上市前，斗鱼每年都拿到了融资。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有融资做底气的斗鱼打法凶猛，这和陈少杰的个人性格也不无关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾有媒体报道，斗鱼内部人士将陈少杰评价为“喜欢冒险、刀口舔血的人”。斗鱼曾在一个月内从业界连续挖了六名主播，总费用超过6000万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;YY游戏直播创始人古丰曾撰文分析斗鱼初期为何能反超虎牙。 “斗鱼的起来，很大原因是一开始就砸了巨资把YY里和行业里的头部主播签了下来。”在斗鱼之前，YY游戏直播可通过控制流量和收入分配就相对控制住主播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，游戏主播不同于娱乐主播，前者有外部效应，不依赖直播平台，且有其他变成网红的机会（比如电竞赛事、优酷游戏频道、微博等），具备自带粉能力，还可以带粉迁移，所以YY游戏直播并未和头部主播签约。这却给了斗鱼可乘之机，直接用签约费代替分成来获得头部主播，成了斗鱼能反超虎牙的核心原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，游戏直播行业经历了大浪淘沙后的整合期，在第一梯队形成“鱼牙对峙”的格局，斗鱼和虎牙分食游戏直播大部分市场份额。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;盈利问题难解&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2019年7月17日，斗鱼以11.5美元/股的发行价在纳斯达克上市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但它的股价只在疫情期间经历了短暂的持续性增长。 2021年2月16日，斗鱼盘中一度冲至20.54美元/股的最高价，之后便一路狂泻到现在的不到1美元/股。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入2021年后，斗鱼季度营收，除了当年第四季度之外，均为负增长。其2022年财报介绍，斗鱼收入增长严重依赖于付费用户和每名付费用户的收入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但斗鱼的用户正处于流失状态。 Wind数据显示，2023年第二季度，斗鱼季度付费用户数为400万，较上年同比减少39.39%。月度活跃用户数为5030万人，较上年同比减少9.69%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斗鱼目前的营收仍主要来自直播和广告，且其对广告商的吸引力也在持续下滑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年到2022年，斗鱼直播收入为88.522亿元、85.966亿元和67.973亿元人民币，分别占同期总收入的92.2%、93.8%和95.6%。斗鱼广告销售收入为6.452亿元、4.649亿元和1.903亿元人民币，分别占同期总收入的6.7%、5.1%和2.7%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然营收持续下降，但其在2023年连续两季度实现盈利。 2023年第二季度，斗鱼净利润为680万元，2022年同期净亏损3880万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“斗鱼扭亏为赢是其降本增效的成果。”互联网资深观察人士丁道师对南方周末记者表示，他并不认为这是一种健康的盈利方式，但表示理解，“这也是非常时期的一种无奈策略”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年第二季度，斗鱼费用为1.96亿元，较上年同期的3.4亿元下降42%。其中，销售和营销费用较上年同期下降48%，研发开支下降30.2%，总务及行政开支下降48.2%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斗鱼的疲怠表现，一方面归因于短视频平台对传统直播平台的冲击，另一方面，也在于B站、抖音、快手等头部视频平台对于游戏领域的强势抢占。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年底，B站斥资8亿元，力压快手、斗鱼、虎牙等国内直播平台，拿下英雄联盟（LOL）全球总决赛（S赛）中国地区三年独家直播版权。同年7月，快手推出了“百万游戏创作者扶持计划”，并频繁举办各类赛事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对不利局面，2020年7月，腾讯试图主导斗鱼与虎牙的合并，后被监管机构依法以反垄断为由叫停。截至2023年3月31日，腾讯对虎牙持股46.7%，对斗鱼持股37.7%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游戏产业分析师张书乐对南方周末记者表示，虽然斗鱼和虎牙是游戏直播大混战的幸存者，但合并失败意味着两者都失去了一次资源整合的机会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，斗鱼和虎牙也在持续经历人才流失。 2023年8月，在斗鱼直播了5年的头部主播旭旭宝宝宣布转战抖音。此前3月，虎牙户外大主播沐莹莹也入驻抖音。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“主播如同候鸟，哪里暖和去哪里。”张书乐说，主播对平台没有忠诚度，现在都眼红带货。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在丁道师看来，斗鱼和虎牙少有护城河，他们早年依靠腾讯系及相关的热门电竞直播崛起。近些年，B站、抖音、快手、甚至视频号也可以做游戏直播。 “分蛋糕的有那么多，但蛋糕的增长幅度显然并不同步。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为，在这样的背景下，以斗鱼和虎牙为代表的传统电竞直播平台在这些年的下滑不可避免，且下滑趋势仍会持续。他们都在寻找游戏之外新的增长路径，如体育直播，但效果还需要时间来验证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张书乐直言，斗鱼游戏直播、短视频整体营收场景单一，面对其他泛娱乐平台的进击，斗鱼除了背靠腾讯，缺乏更有效的制衡手段，“最大的痛点仍是盈利难题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为，斗鱼唯一的护城河只有作为国内游戏公司三巨头之一的腾讯（其余两个是网易和米哈游）。腾讯在电竞领域控场盘面极大，可以用IP授权和电竞赛事授权为斗鱼保留一些自留地。但对手依然可在腾讯系以外寻找游戏和电竞赛事合作，因此护城河并不宽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张书乐表示，斗鱼和虎牙的困境几乎一样，只是现在两家在腾讯的安排下，不能合并就错峰试错，想要探出一条活路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，斗鱼身上游戏属性太强，户外、颜值、二次元等区的用户画像和游戏区的高度重叠。斗鱼真正可能的脱困方向，或是在同样盈利困难的电竞赛事上组合出新的盈利模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“万人聚赌”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为头部游戏直播平台，斗鱼近年来频频传来色情、低俗、涉嫌赌博的负面消息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年9月，共青团中央官博发文称，斗鱼主播“彡彡九户外”（下文简称339）直播间涉嫌万人聚赌，日流水能达几百万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年1月，中国青年网短视频官博发文称，斗鱼主播“长沙乡村敢死队”才是“斗鱼最大赌场”，每晚10点开启涉嫌聚赌的抽奖活动，因此形成公开暗号“十点经济课”。 2020年其流水高达1.77亿元，日流水最高1300万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，“彡彡九户外”受到赌博定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据四川法制报，339成员付某龙等3人在2017年3月至2020年9月间，通过“一个办卡五万带回家”“搏一搏单车变摩托”等大量煽动性语言鼓动直播间观众参与抽奖，并通过平台、微信群等方式向其他未参与直播观看的人员推送抽奖时间及金额等信息，导致大量人员在直播抽奖时段进入直播间采用付费“办卡”、刷虚拟礼物等方式参与抽奖。抽奖结束后，向中奖人员发放中奖现金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至被抓获时，付某龙等人共计组织抽奖4267场（次），442万余人次参与，参赌资金近1.2亿元。都江堰法院经审理认为，3人行为构成开设赌场罪，分别判处六年至三年有期徒刑不等，并处罚金。此案件也是由公安部督导办理的全国首例直播平台涉赌案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年1月，前斗鱼户外主播一哥钱小佳在采访中透露，339等直播间的涉赌活动，虽然不是斗鱼官方举办，但平台并非毫不知情，甚至会进行内部引导。 2019年下半年，钱小佳因违规遭到斗鱼封杀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月30日，国家网信办微信公众号“网信中国”发布2023年一季度全国网信行政执法与监督情况，表示将持续推进“清朗”系列专项行动，坚决依法查处网上各类违法违规行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中提到，针对百度、新浪微博、斗鱼、豆瓣等网络平台履行主体责任不力，对其用户发布的信息未尽管理义务，造成淫秽色情、封建迷信、招嫖卖淫、赌博引流、高利借贷等有害信息在网上传播的问题，国家网信办指导属地网信办分别依法约谈、责令整改并开展处罚措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5月8日，“网信中国”再发文称，针对斗鱼平台存在的色情、低俗等严重生态问题，国家网信办指导湖北省网信办派出工作组，进驻斗鱼平台开展为期1个月的集中整改督导。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张书乐看来，中国的直播热潮，起源于游戏直播，但游戏直播没能打破消费场景的壁垒，也没能成为风口上的领跑者，直到直播带货的出现才打开了新局面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在的游戏直播平台也在找属于自己的&#39;直播带货&#39;，只是疯狂试错下，出现了很多问题。”张书乐说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[100万？300万？想不上班到底要存多少钱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260278]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen in Jiangxi shared his story. She and her husband spent 7 years saving 1 million yuan. After part of it was used to buy a house, the remaining 500,000 yuan was deposited in the bank. Now the monthly living costs can be covered by interest alone. She also shared a series of ways to save money, such as cooking at home for many years, not drinking coffee outside, only buying discounted clothes, taking her children to sunbathe instead of taking interest classes, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the authenticity of this experience has not been verified, in February this year, a Shanghai couple did decide to &quot;retire&quot; with a deposit of 3 million yuan. This news sparked widespread discussion at the time. Just recently, Professor Chen Bingzheng from the Department of Finance at the School of Economics and Management at Tsinghua University was interviewed by CCTV Finance. He mentioned that “a survey found that over 70% of those born after 90 start to think about pension issues.” He said that it is too late to start thinking about pension issues at the age of 35. From work After receiving your first month’s salary, you should start saving for retirement in a planned way. It can be seen that young people’s anxiety about saving money for retirement is not an idle complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much savings do you think you need to retire from the workplace with peace of mind? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[董明珠称孟羽童兼职接广告不合规：非工作时间能否干副业？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260289]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In May this year, Dong Mingzhu’s secretary Meng Yutong resigned, triggering various speculations and discussions. Recently, in an interview with Guangdong Satellite TV&#39;s &quot;Financial Eyes&quot;, Dong Mingzhu responded publicly to the matter for the first time: Internet celebrities do not judge people&#39;s quality, and it is illegal for people to advertise outside Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Dong Mingzhu said Meng Yutong’s part-time job accepting advertisements was illegal” was once a hot search topic. According to a report by the Shanghai Securities News on May 16, the reason for Meng Yutong&#39;s resignation was that he &quot;often missed work to participate in business activities and take on private work&quot; during his time at the company. After the company talked to him, he still carried out related activities without improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure, Meng Yutong did receive advertisements on social media platforms. In the short videos on his Xiaohongshu account, he appeared many times selling clothing, beauty products, electronic products and household goods. In the &quot;Good Things Pocket&quot; column, there are 65 notes included, none of which have anything to do with Gree Electric products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I originally thought that the rights and wrongs of this incident were very clear. However, many netizens believe that the contract Meng Yutong signed with Gree is a labor contract, not an endorsement contract. The time outside the eight hours is her own. Of course, she has the right to control how much she earns through endorsements and part-time advertising. Money is a reflection of her ability. This has also led to some discussions: Is it appropriate for the company to restrict employees from doing side jobs? If the income from your main job is not as good as your side job, will you leave your job? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this point of view and these discussions? First of all, it must be said unequivocally that it is not appropriate to use Meng Yutong&#39;s case to demonstrate the rationality of employees taking part-time jobs or doing side jobs outside of their own jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Yutong did graduate from a prestigious university, has a sweet appearance, and has good looks, but these qualities are not sufficient or necessary conditions to become an Internet celebrity. There are a lot of people with these qualities, but only a few lucky ones are successful. The track for Internet celebrities is very crowded and very winding. If someone says that Meng Yutong’s ability to become an Internet celebrity depends entirely or mainly on his personal abilities, that is undoubtedly not objective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that Meng Yutong became an Internet celebrity mainly due to Dong Mingzhu’s efforts on top of his buildable personal qualities. Dong Mingzhu made her his secretary, and announced that he would train her to be his successor and take her to various occasions. Through the event, many hot searches and topics were created, bringing her countless traffic. Dong Mingzhu is working hard to make her the first person to bring goods to Gree live broadcast. In this sense, Meng Yutong, who has become an Internet celebrity, is an asset of Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Dong Mingzhu and Gree are obviously old-school, hoping that gentlemen&#39;s agreement and personal consciousness will have sufficient behavioral constraints on Meng Yutong, rather than &quot;first Before the company invests resources in an individual, it ensures and locks in potential future earnings, and limits and eliminates the risk of breach of trust of a sparrow that turns into a phoenix and then soars into the sky and escapes control. That is, the contract stipulates the rights and obligations of both parties and improves the The cost of breach of trust should be taken into account before you can safely invest in betting and package marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, when it was discovered that Meng Yutong was using the Internet celebrity identity created by the company to do private work, Dong Mingzhu and Gree did not immediately send a clear and strong signal saying &quot;this is not acceptable&quot;, but The reason is that there was no timely intervention or the intensity of the intervention was not enough. The mentality may be that the matter can be solved quietly internally, through reasoning and persuasion, so as to prevent the matter from turning into a negative incident or scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if Meng Yutong had been given a clear choice the first time he did private work, either to stop and hand over the proceeds from his private work, or to leave, the problem might have been solved long ago. When Meng Yutong took on more and more private jobs and his income outside of work became higher and higher, it became difficult for him to stop. At a certain stage, Dong Mingzhu could no longer tolerate it and had to resolve it through a final showdown, which brought us to the scene in May this year. Therefore, if there is something wrong with Dong Mingzhu and Gree, it is that they made the above two mistakes one after another. But this does not disprove that it is in line with professional ethics for Meng Yutong to use the Internet celebrity status created by the company to do private work and make big money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is no simple answer to whether employees can work part-time or do side jobs outside of their regular jobs, and it needs to be analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it depends on whether there are express provisions on this in the labor contract or other types of contracts signed with the company or organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, units within the system generally have some clear restrictions on employees&#39; part-time work, and will regularly conduct inspections on employees in this regard, allowing employees to declare on their own. Of course you can lie or conceal the situation, but if your employer finds out, you will inevitably be punished or even lose your job. In addition, well-regulated companies generally prohibit employees from receiving remuneration from competitors, suppliers or customers. This not only potentially harms the company&#39;s interests, but may also lead to criminal investigation in serious cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it depends on the nature of your part-time job or side job, and whether there is any conflict of interest with your work in the unit and the business of the unit. You are a salesperson and have accumulated a lot of customer resources. At a certain stage, if you set up a business and go it alone, the company may not be able to do anything to you. However, if you secretly set up a business with a similar nature to the company while receiving a salary from the company, A company that imports customer resources into its own company is undoubtedly against professional ethics, and the company may not let it go if it finds out. Or if you are a technical R&amp;D person and sell the code you wrote in the company to a competing company or other companies, or take work from a competing company, this will also damage the company&#39;s rights and interests and seriously violate professional ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, &quot;Besides the eight-hour working time, it is all your own time, you can do whatever you want.&quot; This statement must be at least restricted by the above two rules. In the final analysis, it means respecting the contract and Observe professional ethics. As long as it does not violate the contract and company regulations, does not harm the company&#39;s rights and interests, has no conflict of interest with the company, and does not affect the main job, generally speaking, the company has no objection to individuals doing side jobs and part-time jobs to increase their income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>