<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[被质疑的苹果，难表达的“碳中和”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/nHIDfd2bNTsJ64eVDpNfavQc80QVApMfkzXL2MOn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/nHIDfd2bNTsJ64eVDpNfavQc80QVA pMfkzXL2MOn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 17, 2021, on the eve of Earth Day, Chengdu Taikoo Li Apple Experience Store The small leaves of the Apple logo turned green, and the employees’ work clothes also turned green. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The professional vocabulary &quot;carbon neutrality&quot; is increasingly out of the circle, but it is labeled as &quot;carbon neutrality&quot; It is not easy, and if you are not careful, you will attract doubts, even Apple, which is at the forefront of carbon management, is no exception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023 local time, Apple launched the first batch of carbon-neutral products, Apple Watch, in California, USA. However, on September 22, the environmental organization Institute for the Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE) released &quot;Suspicious Clouds about the Carbon Neutrality of Apple Products&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Suspicious Clouds&quot;), questioning Apple&#39;s lack of information on the use of clean electricity and carbon offsets for carbon-neutral products. Adequate disclosure and explanation, and failure to push suppliers to disclose factory-level carbon data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, Apple responded to Southern Weekend reporters, promising to share strategies and progress, and responded to some details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;carbon neutral&quot; label has been controversial for a long time. Carbon neutrality simply means that greenhouse gas emissions can be offset. After companies save energy and reduce emissions themselves, they often offset carbon emissions by purchasing “carbon credits” (such as forest carbon sinks). However, recently Nestlé, Gucci, easyJet and other companies have announced their withdrawal from the carbon offset market, and the third-party consulting company Carbon Trust will no longer provide carbon neutral label certification from September 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the controversy is the increasingly common practice of &quot;greenwashing&quot; - companies exaggerating their environmental protection behavior and misleading consumers into believing it is true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To prevent greenwashing, many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that the key is &quot;openness.&quot; However, there is currently no consensus on the granularity of carbon neutral product information disclosure, and standards need to be unified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Europe has taken the lead. France has put forward mandatory information disclosure requirements for “carbon neutrality”-related publicity. The EU reached a provisional political agreement on September 19, 2023. If it cannot provide proof, &quot;climate neutral&quot;, &quot;nature&#39;s friend&quot;, &quot;biodegradable&quot; and &quot;ecological&quot; Eco)&quot; and other labels will be prohibited. If passed, this agreement will take effect in 2026. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The six industry insiders interviewed by Southern Weekend reporters had relatively consistent views. They both affirmed that Apple’s information disclosure on its first carbon-neutral product is remarkable, and at the same time believed that there is room for improvement. Regarding IPE’s doubts, half of the respondents agreed that Apple needs to further disclose information on clean electricity use and carbon offsets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Apple’s level of data management and disclosure of suppliers leads the world, but it still needs to fully prove whether it has gone all out to achieve product carbon neutrality.” Founder of Climate Futures, &quot;Carbon Neutral&quot; &quot;Times&quot; author Wang Jun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/jM1wpQhW07Op9WGsVGUG1fvHbtcFiggO5v2c38y6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/jM1wpQhW07Op9WGsVGUG1fvHbtcFiggO5v2c38y6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 12, 2023 local time, the new Apple Watch was on display in California, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What the first carbon neutral product disclosed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;How does Apple Watch become carbon neutral? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year of announcing that its products were carbon neutral, Apple played a creative advertisement called &quot;Mother Nature&quot; at the press conference and on social platforms - Apple CEO Cook and others paid tribute to &quot;Mother Nature&quot; &quot;Mother&quot; reported on environmental protection work. The environmental report of the latest product was also published on the official website, disclosing the carbon footprint of the carbon-neutral Apple Watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the carbon-neutral model of Apple Watch Ultra 2 as an example: the baseline carbon emission is 63.2kg, and after the carbon emission is reduced by 81%, it is reduced to 12kg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;81% of carbon reduction starts from materials, electricity, transportation and other aspects: the weight of recycled materials accounts for more than 30%; 100% clean electricity is used; 50% and above product logistics are transported by non-air transport. The remaining 12kg of emissions are offset using carbon credits from the Restore Fund project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/hPC956MeD0XOs6ChYcF3UQgWM84eRnMypDAreBcP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;928&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/hPC956MeD0XOs6ChYcF3UQgWM84eRnMypDAreBcP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Carbon emission data of Apple Watch Ultra 2 carbon neutral model. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Apple official website, IPE compilation/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter learned from Apple that after drastically reducing product emissions, Apple has to deal with the current situation. High-quality carbon credits based on nature projects will only be used where solutions cannot yet avoid or reduce emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Han, director of the ESG Center at the China Business School of the University of Hong Kong, told Southern Weekend reporters that Apple has adopted a clear and strict product carbon reduction method, giving priority to reducing the three largest emission sources in the product life cycle - electricity, Materials and Shipping. But he also suggested that Apple could refer to the Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi) requirements for setting corporate net-zero standards, carry out the product carbon neutrality process, and strive to achieve a carbon reduction of no less than 90%. emissions, and then look for ways to offset carbon emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among various global initiatives related to combating climate change, SBTi is known for its strictness and is consistent with the Paris Agreement&#39;s efforts to achieve a temperature control path of 1.5°C&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258230&quot;>;&quot;More than 100 companies have been &quot;publicly delisted&quot;. How difficult is it to scientifically reduce carbon emissions? ?》&lt;/a>;)&lt;/span>;. Southern Weekend reporters found out that Apple has also joined SBTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;81% mentioned that 90% is not without space. Wang Jun told Southern Weekend reporters that although Apple explained its progress in reducing emissions in materials, electricity, and transportation, it lacked comparison with its peers and failed to demonstrate whether it had reached its own emission reduction limits, such as 50% non-air transport. Logistics and 30% recycled materials, why can’t the ratio be higher? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to prove&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;100%&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;use of clean electricity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Apple’s carbon emission reduction path, Clean electricity contributes the most. How to confirm that 100% clean electricity is used in the production process of Apple products is the first question of &quot;Suspicious Cloud&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data collected by IPE through different channels show that some of Apple’s suppliers’ carbon emissions have only declined slightly, while some are even still growing. &quot;Suspicion&quot; raised concerns that the proportion of clean electricity actually used by these suppliers is very limited, resulting in double-counting - claiming to allocate clean electricity to Apple, but actually allocating it to other brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xun, chief sustainability expert of Quantis, an environmental sustainability consulting company, also believes that the supply chain of electronic products involves multiple layers of suppliers, and it is relatively easy to require first-tier suppliers, but second- to fourth-tier suppliers Suppliers are difficult to control. Without disclosing the proportion of renewable energy, it is difficult to prove that suppliers at all levels use 100% clean electricity to produce Apple products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Southern Weekend reporters learned from Apple that Apple closely monitors, reviews and verifies the data submitted by suppliers every year, and hires a third party to conduct independent reviews of suppliers’ clean energy plan methods to track and verify suppliers’ clean energy contributions and provide assurance on reported data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to interview questions such as double counting, SCS Global Services (hereinafter referred to as SCS), a third-party company that provides carbon neutrality certification for Apple, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;We will not provide non-public information about our customers to the media. information&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Suspicious Cloud&quot; also believes that according to data disclosed by Apple, 24% of the more than 250 suppliers that have committed to using renewable electricity to produce Apple products are unable to purchase through on-site renewable electricity or renewable energy. To achieve clean electricity substitution, you need to purchase renewable energy certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun, founder of the Institute of Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE), said that the use and procurement of clean electricity in foundries is quite complicated. Many of them are not directly connected to renewable energy, but through the purchase of green power or green certificates. Achieve carbon emission reductions. In this case, how to distribute the limited green power among its different product lines becomes the key. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple responded to a Southern Weekend reporter saying that newly committed suppliers will need some time to obtain clean energy solutions, so some of the clean energy already committed in the Apple Watch supply chain has not yet been put into operation. In the interim, Apple has used its own renewable energy projects to close the gap, reducing the electricity footprint of manufacturing the Apple Watch to zero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/oPvV6ckNV7gVCA15OIB0hUt2r2x56wnMeiu6J5MY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/oPvV6ckNV7gVCA15OIB0hUt2r2x56wnMeiu6J5MY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, local time, Denmark, Apple CEO Tim Cook (right) and Apple&#39;s head of sustainability Lisa Jackson (middle), CEO of European Energy Company Erik Anderse, behind the solar panels that power Apple&#39;s data centers in Europe. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Concentrate resources on one product line&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Suppliers often serve multiple customers. Even if the supplier allocates clean power to Apple, another layer of doubt in &quot;Suspicion&quot; is &quot;cherry picking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;Suspicion&quot; pointed out that comparing Apple&#39;s public data, the overall carbon footprint of the newly launched 128GB version of iPhone 15 Pro is about 1 kilogram of carbon dioxide equivalent higher than that of iPhone 14 Pro, while the production process is about 2 kg higher. Kilogram carbon dioxide equivalent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/NcT0AMj0oNtPP11kFxaplOhnTHvnaaPAoJNVGWMz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/NcT0AMj0oNtPP11kFxaplOhnTHvnaaPAoJNVGWMz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 128GB version of the iPhone 15 Pro has a higher carbon footprint than the iPhone 14 Pro. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture of the IPE report &quot;Suspicions on Carbon Neutrality of Apple Products&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The carbon footprint of the new generation of Apple&#39;s mainstream products is smaller than that of the previous generation. The reduction instead of increase made Ma Jun suspicious: &quot;Theoretically, by concentrating indicators and resources such as clean electricity on one product line, it is possible for niche products to achieve carbon neutrality faster.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Apple emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that there is no pinching problem and that the power allocated to iPhone or other products is not used for Apple Watch. iPhone 15 Pro reduces emissions by 28% compared to the baseline, with most of the reduction coming from renewable energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Apple did not clearly respond to why the carbon footprint of iPhone 15 Pro is larger than that of iPhone 14 Pro. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from industry insiders that it takes time for renewable energy projects to be put into operation, which may be reflected in the ups and downs of the carbon footprint of individual links. Apple&#39;s &quot;2023 Environmental Progress Report&quot; shows that total emissions in fiscal year 2022 decreased by 2.6 million tons compared with the previous fiscal year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun believes that in order to avoid &quot;digital transport&quot; carbon neutrality, Apple needs to disclose more information for verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Details of the carbon offset project are to be announced&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Suspicious Cloud&quot; mentioned that Apple&#39;s information disclosure on carbon offsets is not transparent enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Apple stated in the Apple Watch Ultra 2 carbon neutral product environmental report that the remaining 12kg after emission reductions were offset using high-quality carbon credits from the Restore Fund project. However, no details were given on the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple&#39;s &quot;2023 Environmental Progress Report&quot; released in April 2023 shows that the Restore Fund will be jointly launched by Apple, Conservation International and Goldman Sachs in 2021. The focus of the first phase is Cultivate sustainably managed forests and generate high-quality carbon emissions rights. Key projects include the restoration and protection of high-quality production forests and native ecosystems in Paraguay and Brazil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going to a distant place to buy the carbon sequestration of a forest, how to ensure that the forest will not be cut down, burned by wildfires or double counted? Carbon offset projects are suffering from controversy&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(For details, see Southern Weekend&#39;s report&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/257762&quot;>;&quot;Many companies have given up, why are forest carbon sinks no longer fragrant?&quot; 》&lt;/a>;)&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many industry insiders expressed similar views to Southern Weekend reporters. Shi Han believes that Apple’s first carbon-neutral product report did not disclose the specific details of the carbon offset projects it used, such as project type, location, quantity and price. This makes it difficult for outsiders to assess the quality and effectiveness of its carbon offsets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, Southern Weekend reporters obtained six carbon neutrality certificates for Apple Watch straps and watches from SCS. The certificates show the carbon emissions, carbon offset quantity, and reference of each product. The internationally recognized SCS-108 and ISO14067 carbon neutral certification standards, but do not include specific information on carbon offsets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; SCS Vice President of Marketing Karen Righthand and Apple confirmed to Southern Weekend that the above certificates can be made public, and the public can check them later on Apple’s official website and in Apple’s annual environmental progress report the year after the product is released. On October 6, the SCS green certification product platform launched certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5kGm4JJ1bSIjPJm0bfUoKqIF4f7p3fWviLERgMgJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/5kGm4JJ1bSIjPJm0bfUoKqIF4f7p3fWviLERgMgJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Carbon Neutral Certificate of Apple Watch Ultra2 (with Alpine Loop Style). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(SCS/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that specific information on carbon credits is usually made public after the project is completed. At present, the Restore Fund carbon credit project corresponding to Apple Watch carbon-neutral products may not have ended yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the appendix page of Apple&#39;s &quot;2023 Environmental Progress Report&quot;, you can find information on two carbon offset projects used to offset Apple&#39;s 2022 corporate operational emissions footprint, namely Alto in the Peruvian Amazon. The Mayo Forest Conservation Project and the REDD+ project in the Kaiuru Mountains region in southeastern Kenya include a basic description of the project, year, repayment amount, and the project&#39;s registration link with Verra, a third-party carbon credit verification agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the Restore Fund, you can currently check the location, planning, start time and other specific information of a completed project - Forestal Apepu on the Verra official website. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that Apple’s response to demands and disclosure of carbon neutrality certificates to the public is a step worthy of recognition. However, the current carbon neutral certificates still lack specific information on carbon credits. Now that carbon neutral products have been promoted and marketed, more detailed information on carbon offset projects should be disclosed to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Suspicious Cloud&quot; cited the PAS2060 carbon neutrality standard issued by the British Standards Institute (BSI). When companies submit applications for carbon neutrality verification to verification agencies, they should submit the amount, type, and issuance time of carbon offsets. , validity period, cancellation date, etc. Although the PAS2060 standard does not require companies to disclose the above information to the public, Ma Jun believes that there is currently a lot of controversy over carbon-neutral products internationally, and it is necessary to review and improve the current standards, improve data disclosure requirements, and build a publicly verifiable chain of evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Data Disclosure&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Granularity&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Dispute&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun believes that the best way to resolve disputes is The way is to fully disclose carbon data to society. However, &quot;Suspicion&quot; pointed out that Apple &quot;has regressed in its position on environmental information disclosure.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2014, IPE has successively launched the &quot;Green Supply Chain CITI Index&quot; and &quot;Corporate Climate Action CATI Index&quot; to evaluate the environmental management performance of brands in China&#39;s supply chain. Apple has ranked among the best for many years in a row, becoming a CITI &quot;Outstanding Brand&quot; &quot;one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the IPE carbon disclosure platform will be officially launched. Companies need to change the way they submit carbon data. IPE has repeatedly confirmed with Apple about changes in its disclosure policy, hoping that Apple will push suppliers to fill in the disclosure form, and Apple told IPE that “suppliers will not be required to disclose factory-level carbon data to the public.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this, IPE suspects that Apple has &quot;regressed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple has had several rounds of communication with IPE. &quot;Suspicion&quot; published Apple&#39;s email in response to IPE. Apple stated that &quot;there has been no regression in the requirement for suppliers to report carbon emissions to Apple&quot; and &quot;we continue to encourage suppliers. Publicly disclose its Scope 1 and Scope 2 emissions, participate in IPE’s initiatives, and advocate for transparency.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from various sources that both IPE and Apple support the disclosure of carbon data by suppliers. The difference lies in the granularity of disclosure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPE encourages companies to disclose factory-level data. &quot;Some supplier groups have many factories, and some are even distributed around the world. If we only publish data at the supplier group level, it cannot be mapped to specific factories, and we cannot clearly judge the emission reduction progress of actual OEM factories.&quot; Ma Jun explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple encourages suppliers to disclose carbon data at the company level rather than at the factory level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple responded to a Southern Weekend reporter saying that the most impactful action suppliers can take to combat climate change is to transition to renewable energy. Because this positive impact (of supplier access to renewable energy) spans regions and potentially many plant sites, it is best measured at the company level, with renewable projects additive and localized to the same grid where manufacturing operations occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;factory level&quot; data also involves disputes over whether it is a trade secret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Weijia, general manager of Guangzhou Jie Carbon Technology Co., Ltd., a comprehensive dual-carbon service provider, told Southern Weekend reporters that carbon data is associated with many core confidential data, and companies have the right to disclose and share such data. There are also trade-offs necessary, and gaps in some data are understandable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If only third-party organizations can obtain and verify corporate carbon-neutral product data, it will be difficult for other relevant parties to verify it. Ma Jun believes that in the process of promoting carbon-neutral products, Apple should not &quot;outsource&quot; its disclosure responsibilities to third-party organizations that do not have the right to disclose. Unless a third-party organization is authorized to disclose on its behalf, &quot;pollution and carbon emission data should not be Classified as commercial secrets, disclosure is the principle and non-disclosure should only be the exception. The starting point to curb climate greenwashing must be, and can only be, comprehensive and complete information disclosure. At a time when the concept of carbon neutrality is widely controversial, we hope Seeing publicly proven carbon neutral products emerge on the market.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What needs to be acknowledged is that the current basis and standards for accurate inventory of carbon emission data in the manufacturing industry are still not rigorous and complete enough. It is normal to be questioned, and doubts will also help promote the development and progress of the entire carbon industry. Guan Weijia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Should we first create a carbon-neutral product? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is also controversial whether to first create a carbon-neutral product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Han believes that choosing a product to achieve carbon neutrality throughout the life cycle is a key start for companies to gradually achieve carbon neutrality for all products. But he also pointed out that when consumers buy Apple Watch, they may not know which combinations are carbon neutral - because only when they choose a specific watch and strap combination can they meet the requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun also holds a similar view. Through the carbon neutrality pilot demonstration of Apple Watch, Apple can run through the process and help achieve the goal of carbon neutrality for all products in 2030. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xun opposed it. He believes that there is nothing wrong with running through the internal process, but it is not appropriate to market the concept of &quot;product carbon neutrality&quot; at this stage. Carbon neutrality practices by companies are completely different from promoting carbon neutrality in products. The former is an action taken by companies out of social responsibility, while the latter is a market behavior directly facing consumers. “When carbon neutrality standards have not yet been perfected, companies Self-declared carbon neutrality has no practical significance and will face the risk of &#39;greenwashing&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that the carbon neutral label is controversial internationally, and some stakeholders have begun to formulate more stringent requirements. Under the condition that relevant standards need to be improved, companies that label their products with carbon-neutral labels have the responsibility to support green marketing through comprehensive information disclosure to avoid misleading consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Apple’s carbon neutral green logo is five eye-catching green leaves, but some companies have indicated that they will abandon the carbon neutral label. For example, in May 2023, Evian posted on its website that Evian was proud of the Carbon Trust certification it had obtained, but would not seek re-certification on a global scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, the Carbon Trust also announced that it would no longer provide carbon neutral label certification. The Carbon Trust is headquartered in the UK and has more than 20 years of consulting and certification experience. In 2007, it released the world&#39;s first carbon label based on product carbon footprint certification. Zhao Lijian, president of Carbon Trust China, told Southern Weekend reporters that &quot;carbon neutral labels are still in high demand around the world. The cancellation of carbon neutral labels is not because Evian or other companies will no longer continue to use them,&quot; but because &quot;the market is constantly changing.&quot; To support local development, more ambitious carbon labels need to be provided.” The updated label was well thought out and not a hasty cancellation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Lijian said that consumers hope that companies will take more active and transparent climate actions. The Carbon Trust’s updated carbon label no longer emphasizes carbon neutrality to avoid consumers mistakenly thinking that products have no carbon emissions or zero emissions. Instead, the focus is on carbon reduction and product carbon footprint comparisons. For example, the carbon reduction label will show how much the product&#39;s carbon footprint has been reduced through emission reduction measures compared with before; the low-carbon label will list: the carbon emissions of this product are lower than similar products of the same company; or the carbon emissions of this product are lower than similar products on the market Products are lower. Labels also display more comprehensive information via URL/QR code. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We should face the issue of carbon neutrality with more humility, recognize the complexity behind successfully achieving carbon neutrality, and face up to the difficulties.” Ma Jun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[钱伟长 最厉害的偏科生丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[把家庭财产、公司财产洗为个人财产？拆解三种洗钱类型]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258204]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 23:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Beijing TV station&#39;s &quot;Rule of Law in Progress&quot; column reported such a case, from free to high fees, over the New Year Ms. Chen, who was in her sixties, couldn&#39;t help being &quot;fooled&quot; again and again in a medical beauty institution in Haidian District, Beijing. She made 370 transfers in just 10 months, spending a total of 5.44 million yuan on beauty care, and even some The consumption in a single day reached 790,000 yuan, which consumed all the family’s savings and the life-saving money of my wife and children. The news triggered heated discussions, with some netizens asking, &quot;Is such an abnormal move suspected of transferring family assets?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the report, on the one hand, the medical beauty institution first claimed that it was free, and then gradually Ms. Chen introduced a fee-based item, and the sales consultant even said that he could &quot;help advance payment&quot; of part of the expenses and was unable to provide relevant medical records. This was indeed a violation of regulations. However, on the other hand, Ms. Chen knew that her husband was suffering from cancer, so she actually transferred the medical expenses and the entire family&#39;s expenses. He invested all his savings into it, but his behavior is also strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The money at home cannot be used by either spouse as they wish. In 2022, the People&#39;s Court of Fangshan District, Beijing heard a divorce case. My wife loves beauty and other high-end purchases, and has squandered all the family savings of 600,000 yuan. After trial, the court held that the 600,000 yuan deposit involved in the case was the husband and wife&#39;s business income and was the joint property of the husband and wife. Both spouses have equal rights to dispose of common property, but when exercising the right to dispose of common property, one spouse should adhere to the principles of moderation, rationality and prudence, use it reasonably and standardizedly, and must not be squandered or damage the property rights of the spouse. In this case, the court protected the part where the wife exercised her right of reasonable disposal. The part where excessive consumption was done without the consent of the spouse, was not for the purpose of daily household expenses, and was squandering, which infringed upon the property rights of the spouse. In the end, the court ruled that the woman should pay her ex-husband 200,000 yuan in compensation for her deposit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this reasoning, Ms. Chen spent more than 5 million yuan in family savings and her husband’s medical expenses on “exorbitantly expensive beauty treatments”, which is also suspected of harming her husband’s property rights. It is worth noting that the above report also mentioned a detail, &quot;The medical beauty institution gave a consumption details. Among them, there are many discrepancies between the total consumption amount, consumption records and the transfer details transferred by the bank.&quot; The actual expenditure It is inconsistent with the accounts. Are the relevant funds used for beauty expenses, or are they transferring family assets in the name of beauty? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As relevant departments intensify their publicity on &quot;anti-money laundering&quot;, the public has become aware of its concept. Money laundering is essentially the act of disguising, concealing, and transforming illegal assets or other assets that do not belong to individuals in various ways to make them legal in form. It can be roughly divided into three types: laundering family assets into personal assets, Criminal gangs or corrupt officials use their money to launder and turn company assets into their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above-mentioned &quot;sky-high price beauty&quot; case, the onlookers lamented the greed and foolishness of the person involved in &quot;spending thousands of dollars for beauty&quot;. Perhaps some people&#39;s abnormal behavior is just in response to the old saying &quot;Others laugh at me for being crazy, but I laugh at others because they can&#39;t see through it.&quot; In the name of large consumption, they convert family property into personal property. Once the subsequent marriage relationship changes, , and preparations are made for property cutting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many ways to &quot;launder&quot; family assets into personal assets. For example, use the joint funds of the couple to buy valuable jewelry and put it in their own names; regularly give a large amount of &quot;red envelopes&quot; to their parents, and then ask their parents to transfer the money into their own accounts; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whitewashing of funds with unknown future is common among corrupt officials, criminal gangs, etc. Corrupt officials clean up their corruption gains by investing in companies, purchasing art, and even regularly giving their children huge amounts of living expenses. Public officials use overseas companies to inflate the import price when importing equipment and raw materials, then receive huge kickbacks from them, and then keep the illegal gains abroad. This not only makes public funds their own, but also realizes the transfer of assets overseas. . Public officials can also use &quot;white gloves&quot; to set up shell companies to invest overseas, that is, first set up shell companies abroad, then use their powers to provide various conveniences, and finally remit domestic income abroad in the form of overseas investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Criminal gangs launder illegal gains into legitimate gains through investments in film and television dramas, virtual currency transactions, etc. There are criminal gangs that are linked to casinos, convert cash into tokens in casinos, and then deliver the tokens directly to the beneficiaries of the money laundering. Then he will exchange the tokens back into cash (usually requiring a handling fee of about 5%), and he can claim to have won the money by gambling in the casino. This avoids directly tracing the beneficiary of money laundering through the serial number on the banknote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the above two methods of money laundering, rich people complete the transfer of company assets to personal assets by purchasing overseas bonds issued by their own companies abroad and then using their authority to pay them first. For example, a company may be in debt due to poor business operations and face bankruptcy. As the actual controller of the company, the rich people let the company issue US dollar bonds with annual interest rates as high as ten percent or even higher, and then the rich people subscribed in large quantities. In this way, the rich man, as the actual controller of the company, theoretically only has limited liability within the scope of equity. It is the company&#39;s business to pay off its debts. In this way, through &quot;due process&quot;, the company was hollowed out, Jin Chan escaped from the shell, converted the company&#39;s assets into personal assets, and then took his family and children to enjoy the rest of his life abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子持刀列车上杀人，广铁集团通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258276]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After review by judicial authorities, it was found that on the evening of May 4, passenger He used a black folding knife (blade) About 10.5 cm long) was hidden behind a belt buckle. At Hengshan Station, he avoided the security check and entered the station, boarded the K435 train, and suddenly committed a murder with a knife at 21:50. He was later arrested for intentional homicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, Guangzhou Railway Group, based on the review conclusions of the judicial organs and relevant regulations, punished Hengshan Station Director Hong, Deputy Station Director Qin, and security inspectors for failing to perform their duties due to poor performance of their duties. Kuang Mou and other relevant responsible persons were investigated for responsibility such as dismissal and removal from office. At the same time, all units are mobilized to carry out case education, learn lessons deeply, comprehensively strengthen the training and management of security personnel, continuously strengthen security inspections at stations, and make every effort to prevent similar incidents from happening and ensure the safety of passengers&#39; lives and property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列突遭强袭：当地华人“感觉一天打的炮弹比以往一整年都多”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258269]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 22:51:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/Pj6tPDxRrzd6saqBbkQYslHO50FGTzFGere6eAyA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Pj6tPDxRrzd6saqBbkQYslHO50FGTz FGere6eAyA. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From the apartment window, Zhang Feng could clearly see the white trajectory of the artillery shells streaking through the air. . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, 2023, local time, dense rockets suddenly pierced Israel Air defense alerts were sounded in the southern and central parts of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Israeli city of Rehovot, after hearing the siren, Chinese chef Zhang Feng (pseudonym) squeezed into the small bullet shelter at the stairs of the apartment with five Chinese colleagues and local neighbors. From the apartment windows, the white trails of shells streaking through the air could be clearly seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The shelling lasted from 6 o’clock to 9 o’clock. It felt like the amount of shells fired in one day was more than in the previous year.” Zhang Feng has been in Israel for more than two years and has experienced many attacks, but “it feels like Not as powerful as this time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces declared on the 7th that the attack was carried out by the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement (Hamas) and that the country &quot;has entered a state of war.&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said that the Israeli military&#39;s response must make Hamas &quot;pay a huge price.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2007, Israel has imposed a strict land, sea and air blockade on the Hamas-controlled Gaza Strip, strictly prohibiting the import of military weapons. Hamas, on the other hand, has secretly broken through numerous blockades and frequently attacked Israel through small-scale attacks, attracting international attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She Gangzheng, director of the Overseas Security Research Center at Tsinghua University, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that although Palestinian-Israeli conflicts have occurred from time to time in recent years, large-scale attacks that attack the Israeli mainland and cause triple-digit deaths are rare. It broke the previous relatively stable and balanced situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the Israeli side is likely to take this as an opportunity to launch large-scale retaliation against Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“This time is different from before”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Feng is from Hengyang, Hunan, and currently works as a chef in an Asian restaurant in Rehovot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhang Feng first came to work here two years ago, he received a kind reminder from the restaurant manager - &quot;When the alarm sounds, run to the air-raid shelter immediately, and put down the pot when cooking.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhang Feng, many houses in Israel are equipped with bulletproof rooms or underground air-raid shelters to deal with emergencies. In April 2021, Zhang Feng encountered the first air defense alert. At that time, he was resting alone in the dormitory and was about to run outside in panic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he ran to the stairwell, a local man in his thirties caught him. &quot;He spoke English, which I couldn&#39;t understand. Then he pulled me into the bulletproof room.&quot; Zhang Feng sighed, &quot;He has indeed been trained.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a long-term conflict situation, The Israeli people responded to emergencies &quot;in an orderly manner&quot;. Even so, the attack on October 7 took many people by surprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I started hearing the sound of artillery shells being fired around 6 a.m. on the 7th, and it lasted for several hours.” Zhang Feng said, “This time the sound was particularly dense. It was like boom, boom, boom. The sound was different. It was like setting off firecrackers during the New Year, dozens of them were fired at once.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack, the three-story apartment building where he and his colleagues lived was &quot;almost empty,&quot; and many Local people drove their families to the air raid shelters for safety. Compared with bullet shelters in apartments, air raid shelters are stronger and safer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the attack on the morning of the 7th, Zhang Feng and his colleagues were still discussing how to go to work in the restaurant. Looking out the window, the usually crowded lanes are becoming deserted. However, they soon received a holiday notice from the restaurant headquarters, &quot;No need to go to work, no need to go out.&quot; In order to explain the situation clearly, the headquarters specially arranged a translator who knew Chinese to explain it word for word during the voice call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This time is really amazing, different from before.&quot; Zhang Feng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;big battle&quot; Zhang Feng felt was a &quot;rare&quot; moment experienced by this region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israeli military claimed that on the morning of the 7th, Hamas fired about 2,200 rockets from the Gaza Strip to attack Israel, and armed gunmen also crossed the border and launched ground attacks in southern Israel. For a time, air defense sirens continued to sound in the southern and central areas of Tel Aviv, the former capital of Israel, and explosions were heard over multiple Israeli towns close to the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the Israel Defense Forces issued a statement declaring a state of war and recruiting tens of thousands of reservists to launch attacks on multiple Hamas targets in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sudden escalation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict shocked the world. On the 7th, many Western countries, led by the United States, condemned Hamas for launching a &quot;terrorist attack&quot; on Israel, while many Arab countries called for an immediate ceasefire between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, when answering a reporter’s question on the escalation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated that China is deeply concerned about the current intensification of tensions and violence between Palestine and Israel, and calls on all parties concerned to remain calm and restrained. , cease fire immediately to protect civilians and prevent the situation from deteriorating further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/GTkhYNgPyEqsEAmhI6hxnZzeInzbQ1goeFtlhDLa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;533&quot; height= &quot;877&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/GTkhYNgPyEqsEAmhI6hxnZzeInzbQ1goeFtlhDLa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the explosion, the ground was in a mess. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Israel was unprepared”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After a day of fighting between Palestine and Israel, the number of casualties has exceeded 3,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Palestinian health department on the 7th, the Israeli air strikes on the Gaza Strip have killed 232 local people and injured about 1,700 people. According to a statement from the Israeli Ministry of Defense on the evening of the 7th, various attacks that day killed more than 200 people and injured more than 1,000 people in Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this raid, Israel, known for its intelligence and military strength, acted passively, triggering a lot of speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is difficult to describe how unprecedented today’s situation is.” The BBC reported on October 7 that this may be Israel’s “most serious intelligence failure” since the 1973 Yom Kippur War. It has the most powerful intelligence agency in the Middle East, but there was no early warning of the attack that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the US &quot;Capitol Hill&quot; news on October 7, former US Secretary of Defense Mark Esper bluntly stated in an interview with US media that Hamas&#39;s attack was &quot;surprising and made Israel &quot;There was no preparedness on the part of the Israeli side,&quot; he said, adding that this was an intelligence error on the part of Israel. He also believes that Israel’s mistakes will trigger chain reactions in many aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, in the first round of attacks by Hamas, Israel has been quite &quot;slow&quot; in its response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to rocket attacks, videos released by Hamas showed that Hamas armed personnel were heavily armed and used homemade simple gliders to infiltrate into Israel. Videos and pictures that appeared on social media showed Hamas militants also entering Israeli-controlled areas in pickup trucks and motorcycles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 7, local time, the Qassam Brigades, an armed faction affiliated with Hamas, issued a statement saying that dozens of Israeli officers and soldiers were captured during military operations that day. The men are currently being housed in a &quot;safe location.&quot; This news was also confirmed by the Times of Israel report. The media quoted Israeli military sources as saying that &quot;soldiers and civilians were indeed captured by Hamas and kidnapped to the Gaza Strip.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Israel&#39;s &quot;Jewish Chronicle&quot;, photos released by Hamas show that its armed men captured Israeli Major General Nimrod Aloni and many other Israeli soldiers. It is reported that Aloni served as the commander of the Israeli Army&#39;s &quot;Gaza Division&quot; and the commander of the &quot;Depth&quot; force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She Gangzheng believes that Israel has been in a state of guarding against surprise attacks for a long time, and the relative stability in recent years can easily lead to laziness and paralysis. This sudden large-scale attack by Hamas caught Israel by surprise. In addition, Israel has fallen into political chaos in recent years and has long lacked leading power. The judicial reform led by the Netanyahu government has further paralyzed the original political consensus, and all parties are busy fighting among themselves. This is also one of the factors behind Israel’s slow intelligence and military response this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 7th local time, the Israeli Political and Security Cabinet held a meeting. Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu stated in a statement that Israel’s goal is to “eliminate Hamas’ threat to and harm to Israel for many years to come. the capabilities and desires of citizens”. He also added, &quot;The decisions taken by the cabinet include stopping the supply of electricity, fuel and commodities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We have started offensive mode and will continue without reservation and without breath until the goal is achieved .&quot; Netanyahu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;16 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;open-air prison&quot; under blockade&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;According to CNN, Hamas military commander Mohammed Dave said on October 7 that the operation was in response to Israel’s “attacks on women, the desecration of the Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem, and the The ongoing siege of Gaza.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The so-called &#39;reasons for action&#39; put forward by Hamas, although relevant incidents did occur, are more of a rhetoric to defend the legitimacy of its actions. However, Israel&#39;s blockade and siege of Gaza This has been one of the deep-seated conflicts between Hamas and the Israeli authorities for a long time,&quot; She Gangzheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the unilateral withdrawal of Israeli troops in 2005, Gaza has become the Palestinian sphere of influence. Since 2007, Israel has regarded Hamas, which controls the area, as a major security threat, and has begun to implement a comprehensive sea, land and air blockade of the Gaza Strip, with strict restrictions on the entry and exit of goods and personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, incoming and outgoing goods are subject to security inspections, personnel need to hold a permit to enter and exit, and fishing areas accurate to kilometers are set up in coastal areas. In order to prevent the construction of military facilities, Israel once banned any steel bars, cement and other materials from entering Gaza. It was not until 2010 that Israel narrowed the list of prohibited items to &quot;weapons and materials for military use.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since the implementation of the blockade, Israel has claimed that it will not let Hamas obtain any weapons. But judging from the results, despite spending a lot of manpower and material resources, Hamas still has various channels to import weapons .&quot; She Gangzheng believes that since Israel&#39;s unilateral withdrawal in 2005, the Gaza area has been basically blocked by Israel, showing a stable and continuous state. On the one hand, Israel provides corresponding support to the Gaza Strip, such as electricity supply, allowing some Palestinians to enter the country to work, and releasing humanitarian relief supplies. On the other hand, millions of Palestinians are confined to this small area, where people&#39;s lives are restricted and often subject to humanitarian criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, the current population of the Gaza Strip exceeds 2 million, which is approximately one-fifth of Israel’s total population, but the area is less than one percent of Israel’s land. The Gaza Strip is small and densely populated. The blockade has hindered the development of the Gaza region. People&#39;s daily life, health system, and infrastructure have gradually deteriorated. A large number of residents rely on relief from international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s comprehensive blockade, the Gaza Strip has become an isolated &quot;enclave.&quot; Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas once described the Gaza Strip as a giant &quot;prison.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 7, local time, Israeli Energy Minister Katz announced that in response to the conflict, he had signed an order requiring the Israeli Electric Power Company to cut off power supply to the Gaza Strip. It is understood that about two-thirds of the electricity in the Gaza Strip depends on Israeli supply. Israel&#39;s announcement of &quot;cutting off supply&quot; is likely to further exacerbate the energy dilemma in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Fan Hongda from the Institute of Middle East Studies at Shanghai International Studies University believes that as long as the Palestinian issue cannot be properly resolved and as long as Israel&#39;s current position on this issue does not change, conflict between the two sides will be inevitable. Hamas may launch similar operations at any time it sees fit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Hongda also pointed out that this conflict is significantly different from the past conflicts. The Gaza armed forces have entered Israel and captured some Israeli hostages, including soldiers, which will bring consequences to the Israeli people. A real sense of fear. Next, Israel will intensify its attacks on the Gaza armed forces, and it will be a heavier blow than before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is foreseeable that the situation of the people in the Gaza Strip will be even more difficult in the future.&quot; Fan Hongda said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突升级 当地华人亲历“一波一波地炸”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258273]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 23:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[走不一样的路，刘清漪成为了亚运冠军]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258265]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/z1fLaqhsT7kZRweauhtytjsffUhiVXSTIKZ8LQv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;616&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/z1fLaqhsT7kZRweauhtytjsffUhiVXSTIK Z8LQv2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Liu Qingyi competed&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, the final day of the first break dance event of the Asian Games, after several rounds of dance battles between contestants , the Chinese national breakdancing team won two &quot;first&quot; medals: Qi Xiangyu won the third place in the men&#39;s category, the first medal in the breakdancing event in the history of the Asian Games; Henan girl Liu Qingyi won the championship in the women&#39;s category, the first women&#39;s breakdancing event in the history of the Asian Games gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four national team members who participated this time all performed very well. Qi Xiangyu and Shang Xiaoyu won the first and fourth place respectively in the individual qualifying competition. Unfortunately, Shang Xiaoyu stopped in the top eight. Liu Qingyi and Zeng Yingying successfully advanced to the semi-finals. Zeng Yingying lost to Japanese player Ayumi Fukushima (2023 World Breakdancing Championship Champion) in the bronze medal match and finished fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through this gold medal, Liu Qingyi qualified to participate in the break dance event of the Paris Olympics. At the post-match press conference, she said she was very happy, &quot;Thanks to my coaching team and my motherland for giving me this opportunity, and to myself for persevering.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the first batch of national teams such as Liu Qingyi and Qi Xiangyu For the team members, they have witnessed the transformation of break dancing from folk subculture to the highest sporting event. Their original intention of practicing break dancing may not be for honor, but their efforts will eventually be lived up to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/ppzyBbipfV265K5IZiwt4E3xCSbROxKcltM4nQSf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;649&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/ppzyBbipfV265K5IZiwt4E3xCSbROxKcltM4nQSf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Qi Xiangyu was in the bronze medal match. He defeated Japanese player Isshin Hisikawa 2-1 and won the third place &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From civilian to palace&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before being included in sporting events, breakdancing, a dance that originated in the New York neighborhoods of the 1970s, had always been popular among young people. It not only requires a certain degree of skill, but also integrates many action elements from Brazilian war dance, gymnastics and Chinese martial arts. It can also strongly express personal style and is highly musical and ornamental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The International Olympic Organizing Committee has taken a fancy to the influence of break dancing. The ratings on the first day of the official events of the Rio Olympics in 2016 dropped by about 28% compared with the London Olympics. The continued sluggish ratings forced the International Olympic Organizing Committee to turn its attention to the broad group of young people and pay attention to their popular preferences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 7, 2020, the Executive Committee of the International Olympic Committee held a meeting and agreed to add four major events including breakdancing, skateboarding, surfing, and rock climbing to the 2024 Paris Olympics. The breakdancing event falls under the &quot; sport dancing&quot;. Nine days later, the Olympic Council of Asia announced that breakdancing would become an official competition event at the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movements of break dancing can be divided into 4 parts, rock steps, leg movements, air freezes and overall movement. Compared with other hip-hop forms, the advantage of break dancing as a sporting event is that a large number of moves can be measured and scored using standards. However, according to the rules customized by the World DanceSport Federation, judges will not only pay attention to the skill and diversity of the movements, but also the integrity, musicality and even personality of the performance as the judging criteria. Movements that only have difficulty and technique will not receive high scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the four members of the Chinese team participating in the Asian Games, the only one with martial arts skills is 18-year-old Qi Xiangyu. He started practicing martial arts with his father when he was 5 and a half years old, and officially started hip-hop dancing at the age of 8 and a half. In terms of movements, Qi Xiangyu will repeatedly practice difficult movements, such as the Thomas Pivot - this movement requires supporting the ground with both hands, and using waist strength and inertia to drive the legs to swing. The 9-year-old Qi Xiangyu practices 200 times a day, which is a full exercise It takes half a year to become proficient. In terms of music, Qi Xiangyu will also understand it repeatedly. His father Qi Liying said, &quot;I can&#39;t teach him music. He will listen to a song until he understands the melody and emotion thoroughly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Qi Xiangyu first came into contact with break dancing, Chinese street dance was still a folk subculture. In 2018, two variety shows &quot;This!&quot; &quot;It&#39;s Street Dance&quot; and &quot;Hot Blood Street Dance Company&quot; brought street dance into the public eye. When break dancing entered the Olympics and Asia, the project moved from the folk to the palace and was recognized by mainstream culture. Learners, practitioners and training institutions sprung up like mushrooms after rain. The &quot;China Hip-Hop Industry Research and Development Report&quot; released in 2023 shows that there are currently nearly 3 million hip-hop practitioners nationwide, there are over 10,000 hip-hop training institutions, and more than 10 million people across the country choose to learn hip-hop every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese National Breakdancing Team was born through a selection competition on January 8, 2023. There are 4 male and female players each. The 17-year-old girl Liu Qingyi was selected with her rich, diverse and explosive dance. During her teenage years, dance practice was lonely and full of controversy. There were few female hip-hop dancers in China, and she was the only girl in the club. She was once considered by her friends and relatives as not doing her job properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Qingyi&#39;s attitude is &quot;less talk, more action&quot; and &quot;prove everything with strength.&quot; The gold medal in breakdancing&#39;s Asian Games debut is the best response to all the praise and criticism in the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BzTpgRXjGw6zyQaHnXD2JJgseJvx5hTRoM5P4LuW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BzTpgRXjGw6zyQaHnXD2JJgseJvx5hTRoM5P4LuW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese player Zeng Yingying competed in the bronze medal match of the women&#39;s break dance event. She lost to Japanese player Ayumi Fukushima 0-3 and finished fourth &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;The stage is my life&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have just finished competing in the World Championships and preparing for the Asian Games, which is a physical and psychological challenge for me.&quot; Recently, two major international competitions in break dancing Held in succession: From September 23 to 24, Liu Qingyi participated in the 2023 World Breakdancing Championships in Leuven, Belgium, and immediately started preparations for the Asian Games after returning to China. The intense preparation experience made her feel the limits of her body and mind, but she persevered. Liu Qingyi unfortunately stopped in the quarterfinals at the World Championships. Half a month later, she reached the top of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to break dancing, the young Liu Qingyi never thought of giving up, &quot;I am the kind of person who will &#39;die&#39; when encountering problems. Since it is my choice, You have to do it to the end and do it well, and don’t give up when you encounter some problems. This is a ‘slap in the face’.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, 10-year-old Liu Qingyi saw a street dance performance on the street, which was so cool Her movements gave her a visual shock and &quot;felt very handsome&quot;, so she joined the hip-hop club. Liu Qingyi showed athletic talent in her early days, and just two months later she won the runner-up in a hip-hop competition. At that time, not only were there few female dancers, but due to physical conditions, they were generally weaker in terms of strength and technical difficulty. Liu Qingyi prefers more energetic movements, such as Thomas pirouettes, 360-degree spins, etc., &quot;I want to be different from others, and I like to meet challenges.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wanting to be different&quot; also made Liu Qingyi decide From amateur to professional athlete. In 2019, in order to prepare for the break dance competition of the National Games two years later, Liu Qingyi was selected as an alternate member of the Henan hip-hop team. Should you join the provincial team and say goodbye to your ordinary school career, or should you give up break dancing and apply for college normally? Liu Qingyi made a choice: &quot;In the end, I still feel that taking a professional path in hip-hop dance is an opportunity for me. I think there are many paths to take in life, and not everyone is the same.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/XGTNiGD3bCG6uHZ9t7GFvPXMUYyF3ClJyW9CMoZ5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;697&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/XGTNiGD3bCG6uHZ9t7GFvPXMUYyF3ClJyW9CMoZ5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Chinese player Shang Xiaoyu (right) and Kazakhstan&#39;s Dolet Analbekuly competed in the men&#39;s round-robin group match&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the Henan Provincial Team, Liu Qingyi received more professional training and grew rapidly through large-scale events. The first international competition she participated in was the 2021 World Championships in Paris. She failed to advance to the quarterfinals, but she refused to admit defeat. &quot;Go back and practice hard and come again.&quot; In 2022, she began to make a name for herself around the world: breaking into the World Games He reached the semi-finals, won the championship in Outbreak and World Battle, two top events, became the first Chinese player to win the international break dance competition championship, and won the runner-up in the World Championship that year. Liu Qingyi used her strength to show the world the level of Chinese break dancing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My stage is my life.” Liu Qingyi believes that the most attractive thing about break dancing is that when she dances, no one can restrain her, “I can do what I want. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Independence and individuality, perhaps this is the reason why emerging sports such as break dancing have become popular. They represent the pursuit of a new generation of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[回顾近13年国庆档票房成绩单，2023年仅为2019年六成丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258267]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“雅思组合”蝉联亚运金牌，剑指巴黎奥运欲补遗憾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258242]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy32xlLgoLs1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy3 2xlLgoLs1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong (right) Group photo at the award ceremony&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which event is the most stable for the Chinese badminton team? The list includes men’s singles before Lin Dan retired, Ge Fei/Gu Jun, Gao Ling/Huang Sui, Yang Wei/Zhang Jiewen, Du Jing/Yu Yang, Zhao Yunlei/Tian Qing, Chen Qingchen/Jia Yifan’s women’s doubles, Zhang Ning , the women&#39;s singles during the Xie Xingfang period...and the Chinese mixed doubles before the 2018 to 2021 Tokyo Olympics and the 2022 to 2023 World Championships: a pair of Chinese pairs once dominated the world and became the absolute king among many mixed doubles pairs. The Badminton World Federation ranking points have exceeded an unprecedented 110,000. They are Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong, known as the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2017, the Chinese badminton team made adjustments and split the top two mixed doubles players Zheng Siwei/Chen Qingchen and Lu Kai/Huang Yaqiong into a new combination of Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong. The two formed a team to compete in November 2017. In the first half of 2018, they broke into the top ten in the world and reached the top of the world in August of the same year. In the 2018 season, he won 9 mixed doubles championships, broke 4 world records in 5 months, and ranked first in the world with a huge points advantage. In 67 games in 2019, they were 59-8. In the past two years, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; has won the World Championships championship, successively won the All England Open, Asian Games championship, year-end finals and other championships. With an undefeated record, it helped the Chinese team win the International Badminton Team Championship Su Diman Cup, becoming the most dominant mixed doubles combination in the Tokyo Olympic cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (top) and Huang Yaqiong (bottom) defeated the Japanese combination Watanabe 2-0 Yongda and Higashino Arisa won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2022, Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong will be paired up After regrouping, they won 7 consecutive season championships within 5 months, including the third world championship. After that, they won three championships in the second half of the year, including the Badminton World Tour Finals, and were awarded the &quot;Best Group of 2022&quot; award by the Badminton World Federation. The two set a record of 38 consecutive unbeaten games, with a winning rate of 96%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the 2023 season, the old rivals of the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;, the Korean combination Seo Chenjae/Cai Yujing, have made rapid progress. When the two sides meet, it usually takes three games to determine the winner. In the last two matches (the 2023 World Badminton Championship final on August 27 and the 8-4 match at the China Badminton Open on September 8), they defeated the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; consecutively and became the latter&#39;s current extremely important opponent. In the badminton mixed doubles semi-finals of the 2023 Hangzhou Asian Games, the two pairs met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past month, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; encountered some controversy due to two consecutive losses. In the comments on the game video, you can often see fans questioning the two&#39;s decline in form. For the third time in two months, the result was particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (first from left) and Huang Yaqiong (second from right) and the runner-up Japanese combination Yuta Watanabe (Second from left) and Arisa Higashino (first from right) shake hands and greet each other after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in 2021 From 2022 to 2022, the IELTS combination has experienced a more severe &quot;dark moment&quot;. The period before and after the Tokyo Olympics is also considered by the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; to be the most difficult stage in their mixed doubles career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year, Zheng Siwei is 24 years old and Huang Yaqiong is 27 years old. For athletes, their bodies are at their peak. During the Tokyo Olympics cycle, they won the championship in almost all mixed doubles competitions except the Olympic Games. They were high-spirited and pointed at the championship podium in Musashino Forest. However, it backfired as they lost to teammates Huang Dongping/Wang Yilu in the Olympic final and won the silver medal. After returning to China, they lost to the opponent again in the National Games final. The two took a break in the next Sudirman Cup, but after getting ready, they ushered in the second round of the 2021 World Championships (a first-round bye) and lost to the little-known Hong Kong combination Zhang Dezheng/Ng Yongrong, and were upset. For a while, the fans were talking a lot, unable to accept such a gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong said that she felt two different pressures before and after the Tokyo Olympics: before the game, she was anxious about not being able to train normally due to injuries to her partner, but she wanted to get good results in the Olympics; after the game, It&#39;s the loss of the game that leads to a sluggish state, and the confusion of not knowing where to start. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After research, the national team coaching staff decided to split the &quot;IELTS&quot; first. Huang Yaqiong recalled that before the split, her coach had a long talk with her and asked her to think carefully, &quot;You will be 30 years old in the next Olympics. Do you have the courage to persist until then?&quot; She replied firmly: &quot;I think Fight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles semi-finals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, South Korean combination Seo Seung-jae and Chae Yoo-jung (right) competed&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two entered winter training with Zhang Shuxian and Ou Xuanyi respectively. Before the start of the new season, Zheng Siwei/Zhang Shuxian won the first place in the team&#39;s round-robin competition, but they were eliminated in the first round of the German Open. Huang Yaqiong and Ou Xuanyi, who performed averagely in the round-robin competition, entered the finals and finished second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the low ranking of the new combination and the ineligibility to register for high-level tours, the IELTS combination was briefly reorganized at the All England Open in March 2022. Facing the not-so-strong French player in the first round, the two fought hard for three games and won. After the game, Yaqiong said to Si Si: &quot;Why is the game a bit tight?&quot; Si Si answered frankly: &quot;I feel a little lack of confidence.&quot; After several efforts, they broke into the semi-finals and reunited with Wang Yilu/Huang Dongping, but Still failed to achieve a breakthrough, lost 1:2 and missed the finals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong believes that she can clearly feel that her old partner is always short of breath and has no confidence. &quot;It&#39;s rare to see his mind in this state on the court. He used to be positive and dominate the game on the court. In the first game, I noticed that he was not as determined as before, and he couldn&#39;t handle the ball easily. No. Like his usual style.&quot; Zheng Siwei felt the change in Huang Yaqiong: &quot;My confidence was very low at the time, but Yaqiong was very different from before. She took the initiative to encourage me and was able to completely stabilize the situation on the court.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;After the All England Championships, Zheng Siwei&#39;s injury relapsed and it was difficult to walk. &quot;My style of play is very taxing on the body and ability. Now that my legs are not good, how can I still play? If I want to continue playing, I must improve (condition), maintain (strength), and practice more. However, practicing more will conflict with injuries. , it felt like the sky was falling.&quot; He recalled the dilemma he faced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coach asked them for their opinions on registration for the Asian Championship pairing. Zheng Siwei said: &quot;I still choose Yaqiong. From that time, we have already confirmed the pairing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After that, it was the familiar 30-game winning streak script. Before the 2022 World Championships, the two were worried about whether they would waste all their good luck in the previous open competitions, fearing that they would be worse in the big competition. Because I had been on a &quot;round trip&quot; before, I felt a little bit confused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They had a bye in the first round of the World Championships. When they debuted, they encountered a fierce blockage from the young Thai combination Supac/Supisara and lost the second game 19-21. The decisive game was once trailing 13-17. Huang Yaqiong said in an interview after the game: &quot;When we were behind 13-17, we got a point and caught up to 14-17. It was my turn to serve and I felt that my heart had settled down. After the game, my thinking also told me, That&#39;s when he felt very stable and we had no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, they made it all the way and won their third World Championship title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;596&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles semifinals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (left) and Huang Yaqiong (right) defeated the South Korean combination Seo Seungjae 2-1 , Cai Youjing, advanced to the finals &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of coach Yang Ming, the reorganized &quot;IELTS&quot; has reached another level : &quot;It was a good thing for them to be separated for a while. The two of them joined forces again and both have grown more than before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong recalled that the two would argue endlessly when they had differences before, but in the end there was no result. Now Zheng Siwei will listen to her opinions and try together to see whose method is more effective. Zheng Siwei believes that Huang Yaqiong is &quot;better able to handle it.&quot; &quot;The main feature and score of our combination lies in me. In the past, she would be affected by my poor condition, make mistakes together, and have a series of negative reactions. But now, no matter what I do, Yaqiong can handle it. I&#39;m good, She is better; I am worse, she can stand up... Maybe it is because since we cooperated, we have always been better in good times than in bad times, and we have not had much deliberation on how to solve problems in adversity. If we had not separated in those three months, we would still have been together. Continuing to hold it together and work together may have negative effects. It seems that we can&#39;t solve this kind of thing together. Once we get over this emotion in a new environment and new partners, we may not need to solve it in particular when we come back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With such a process from the bottom to the top, fans still have full confidence in them despite their anxiety about the two losing streak. Therefore, whether Seo Seung Jae/Chae Yoo Jung will win or lose in the semifinals of this Asian Games has become an important battle for whether the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; can overcome the psychological barrier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the game, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; failed to find a rhythm and had no effective scoring methods, and lost the first game 13-21. In the second game, &quot;Yasi&quot; actively adjusted and entered the defense by taking the initiative to pick the ball, looking for counterattack opportunities in the multi-shot stalemate, and regained the game 21-15. In the deciding game, &quot;IELTS&quot; fell behind 2-6 at first, but took the lead before 11 points. After that, &quot;Yasi&quot; played more resolutely and put all the pressure on his opponent. The opponent became tighter and tighter, making consecutive mistakes such as serving the ball and hitting the ball out of bounds. 21-16, they finally got what they wanted. After scoring the winning point, Zheng Siwei couldn&#39;t help but roar. During the game, Zheng Siwei no longer just attacked hard, but added changes in offense; Huang Yaqiong improved her marking and follow-up speed in front of the net. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253361&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 30, 2021, in the 2020 Tokyo Olympics badminton mixed doubles final, the Chinese combination Wang Yilu and Huang Dongping defeated their teammates Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong 2-1&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the game, Zheng Siwei said: &quot;We just shouldered them, played multiple shots with them, and took the initiative to play offense and defense with them. , In fact, the probability that our opponent will attack us is not very high.&quot; During the game, every time a point was scored, &quot;YELTS&quot; would be shouted three times. Zheng Siwei said that the fight to the end was no longer a purely technical and tactical contest, but more of a psychological contest. If you only shout once every time you score a point, your opponent will not feel the pressure and have to shout twice more. &quot;In the end, they will indeed be frightened and the serve will go into the net.&quot; Huang Yaqiong said: &quot;Actually, I There were times when I was not determined. After the 11-minute interval in the deciding game, my energy dropped a little, but my thinking kept encouraging me, and I also mobilized myself by shouting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this victory, IELTS The combination is as powerful as a rainbow. In the Asian Games badminton mixed doubles final on October 7, 2023, they defeated Japanese combination Higashino Arisa/Watanabe Yuta 2:0 (21-15/21-14) and retained the Asian Games mixed doubles championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the fight continues, my goal is the Olympics and Paris.&quot; Huang Yaqiong said after that conversation. Now, this goal is less than 10 months away. Can the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; that has returned to the top make up for the regrets of the Tokyo Olympics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新的中东战争爆发？以色列的猝不及防和犹太社区的自发秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 6:30 in the morning on October 7, 2023, the 50th anniversary of the &quot;Fourth Middle East War&quot; , Hamas launched a surprise attack on Israel. The Israeli intelligence system, which was once considered the most sophisticated, was completely unaware of the opponent&#39;s large-scale war preparations; the Israel Defense Forces, known for its elite, was completely unprepared and was caught off guard; and the once effective social &quot;militia&quot; The &quot;system&quot; (employing troops among the people) also failed to give full play to the rapid response effect in the previous &quot;Middle East wars&quot;, resulting in a large number of civilian casualties. Throughout the day, the two sides fought inextricably, and another powder keg started to smoke. Human society is really in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During dinner, I received a message from a friend in Canada: Due to this conflict, his Jewish community will raise more than 13.6 million Canadian dollars to aid Jewish compatriots, and his family will spread it to Nearly 550,000 Canadian dollars (approximately equivalent to 2.9 million yuan). very scary! Why do you want so much money? After some communication, I learned some little secrets of today’s Jewish community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This friend married a Jewish woman, gave birth to three children, was accepted as a Jew, and moved into a Jewish community in Canada consisting of 98 Jewish households. Jewish social rules are very special: they are based on matrilineal descent, and children born from the marriage of a foreign man to a Jewish woman are accepted as Jews. Children born from marriage between foreign women and Jewish men are not considered Jews, but only foreigners with Jewish genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New families entering the Jewish community, including foreign men who marry them, can enjoy the benefits of the community and must also assume the community&#39;s covenant obligations, including: infrastructure maintenance, cleaning, night shift duty, and security Services, school children&#39;s education, scholarships, religious services, psychological help, poverty relief, etc. A friend said: His children receive tens of thousands of Canadian dollars in scholarships and various benefits from the community every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the wool comes from the sheep. These benefits are not provided by the Canadian government, but are raised by their small Jewish community. Specifically: each family in the community has to pay a share of 165,000 Canadian dollars (approximately equivalent to 875,000 yuan) per year, and 1,600 per year. More than 10,000 Canadian dollars are the community&#39;s common fund to provide community survival operations, repairs and updates, security services, and mutual assistance. Equivalent to owner-operated properties, cleaning, security, social security, churches, teaching assistants and many other institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This community mutual fund is managed and paid by the rabbi. All accounts are open to all families and every member of the community. Decisions are made at community meetings, so there is no corruption or waste. This is a tradition and skill developed by the Jewish people who are good at financial management for thousands of years. Only by shrewdly watching their own money and not being misappropriated by power can each individual ensure that the wealth of the entire group and society is protected from theft and corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jewish Community Mutual Fund also has a high-value internal resource: teaching assistants. It is not a supplementary lesson, but a thinking course outside of school teaching. There are Jewish &quot;wise men&quot; who preside over the cultivation of children&#39;s values, ways of thinking, and methodology training... among which &quot;Tanach&quot; and &quot;Talmud&quot; are very important. The result is that Jewish children have great advantages in academics and business, Indians are good at being professional managers, and Jewish young people are better at cutting-edge high-tech, financial elites and startup company bosses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jewish households in this community all have high incomes and live in single-family houses with large yards and swimming pools. But even so, not every household can pay the full amount of 165,000 Canadian dollars every year. The community&#39;s approach is: those with money contribute money, those with power contribute, and those with talents contribute people, which is converted into a certain workload to undertake the above-mentioned community services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That friend’s father-in-law and brother-in-law are expanding a new Jewish community in Perth, Western Australia. In this emergency, there was no contribution or help, so friends contributed three contributions of about 550,000 Canadian dollars. From now on, how they settle their own accounts is their family matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to cultural genes and historical reasons, Jews advocate autonomy based on identification with Jewish religious and cultural traditions. Therefore, this small community with only 98 households and less than 500 people actually has its own self-defense force. Most young people in their teens to early twenties like to dance with guns and sticks. In Canada, where gun control is lax, they are equipped with real guns and live ammunition. In addition to the guns provided by each household, part of the community&#39;s common fund has a security fund every year that is used to purchase long guns and ammunition. In the photos my friend showed me, there is even a 12.7mm &quot;Barrett&quot; heavy weapon. spy. The community organizes military training for young people every year, but these powerful spears are usually locked in the arsenal to prevent accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This small Jewish community has less than 500 people, but it has more than 400 guns, short guns, long guns, shotguns... nearly every person has one, and the number is increasing every year. They joked: Who can use it again? Dare to slaughter the Jews? Come and try? Having said that, my friend said that at community meetings, the most controversial topic is still the cost of security. Many families think that some self-defense capabilities are enough. After all, this is not a war period, and Canada is not a war zone. There is no need for every household to pay for it every year. It&#39;s a waste of money to allow dozens of stupid boys and crazy girls to fire tens of thousands of bullets every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, these spontaneous martial arts training among civilians are not completely useless. After the early morning raid on October 7, many young people from Jewish communities in the United States, Canada, Australia and other places took flights to Israel that night to prepare to join the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jews are a very small ethnic group, with only 25 million people including those of mixed race, accounting for only 3‰ of the global population today. Due to their cultural and traditional characteristics, they like the financial industry and academic industry. This ethnic group is too rich, and it is not that they are &quot;rich no more than three generations&quot;. Instead, the generations of children they have raised have been too successful in academics and business, occupying the There are too many high-level jobs, high salaries, and high profits, and such a small population cannot build a large empire or form a million-strong army to protect itself. Therefore, the survival wisdom and organizational order that the Jewish community today has explored, which is what Hayek calls &quot;spontaneous order&quot;, are the adaptive choices of groups and individuals in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[决赛直落三局，中国女排击败日本队第九次登上亚运冠军领奖台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258263]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team captain Yuan Xinyue hit the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253420&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Yuan Xinyue, captain of the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team, hit the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games women&#39;s volleyball final was held at the gymnasium of the Cangqian Campus of Hangzhou Normal University. The Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team swept the Japanese women&#39;s volleyball team in three straight games, winning all six games during the entire Asian Games. Lost one game and successfully defended the women&#39;s volleyball championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Wang Yuanyuan hit the ball in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Wang Yuanyuan competed Hit the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the beginning of the first game of the final, the Japanese team led by 3 points, but then the Chinese team scored 10 points in a row and relied on effective blocking and high speed in the second half. The high-quality serve reversed the situation on the court and won the first game at 25:15 through consecutive points. In the second game, the Japanese team adjusted their status and clenched the score, once narrowing the point difference to 2 points. The rhythm of the game was intense and fierce. The Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team has been Maintaining the lead in the score and securing the victory at 25:21; in the third game, the Japanese team strengthened their blocking and played extremely tenaciously. The two teams fought all the way to 9:9. In the end, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball player Wu Mengjie won the third game Locked in at 25:21, the game ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team members blocked the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team Players block during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players hit the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, China Women&#39;s volleyball players hit the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players celebrated scoring during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, China Women&#39;s volleyball players celebrate scoring during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since its first participation in 1974, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team has occupied an absolute dominance in the Asian Games. The team has won a total of 9 gold medals and 3 silver medals in the 13 Asian Games. 1 bronze, the team with the most championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball girls celebrated winning the final.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team The girls celebrate winning the final. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, after the final, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team waved to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023 On the same day, after the final, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team waved to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Bin, the head coach of the Chinese team, believes that the efforts of the players have been rewarded: &quot;From the first game to the last game of this Asian Games, the players&#39; hard work has paid off.&quot; The ups and downs of mentality are actually very small. Keep your mentality calmer and do every process well, and the result will be natural.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On October 7, 2020, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players displayed the five-star red flag and gold medal on the medal podium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253427&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players displayed the five-star red flag and gold medal on the medal podium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>