<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[生态环境部答南周：对碳排放数据弄虚作假“零容忍”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 27, 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment held a regular press conference. Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, said that the theme of this conference is to actively respond to climate change, promote green, low-carbon and high-quality development, and release the &quot;2023 Annual Report on China&#39;s Policies and Actions to Address Climate Change&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the launch of the national carbon market in July 2021, the quality of carbon emission data has attracted much attention. Xia Yingxian, director of the Department of Climate Change, made his debut after taking up his new post. When answering questions from Southern Weekend reporters, he said that overall, companies&#39; awareness of emission reduction has significantly improved, their regulatory capabilities have been significantly improved, and the quality of carbon emission data has been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the measures taken by the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism for carbon emission data quality plays an important role. After enterprises submit data and certification materials through the management platform every month, national departments are responsible for big data screening and regular spot checks, provincial government departments are responsible for technical review, and prefecture-level government departments are responsible for on-site spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian introduced that the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism follows the management idea of ​​&quot;using the day to protect the month, using the month to protect the year&quot; to ensure that every day , monthly, and annual data are stable and reliable, &quot;reflecting our cautious and cautious attitude towards data quality.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian, Director of the Department of Climate Change Response of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Do a good job in daily supervision of data quality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has always attached great importance to carbon emission data quality management. There is &quot;zero tolerance&quot; for illegal and illegal activities such as data falsification. Especially since 2022, a series of measures have been taken to ensure that carbon emission data is accurate and reliable, focusing on comprehensively improving data quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, in terms of the construction of the legal system, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has actively cooperated with the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate to revise and issue judicial interpretations to criminalize the falsification of carbon emission data. Sanction scope. The accounting and verification guidelines were revised and introduced, reducing the formulas involved in carbon emission report verification from 27 to 12, optimizing the accounting methods, and effectively improving the pertinence, scientificity and operability of the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of supervision and law enforcement, since 2021, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has organized supervision and assistance, guided by problem clues, guided enterprises to standardize emission accounting reporting behaviors, and severely cracked down on Engage in deceptive behavior. Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment will severely punish and reduce carbon emission quotas for emission-controlled companies that have verified data to be falsified in accordance with the law; it has exposed a number of third-party verification agencies that violate laws and regulations, which has a great deterrent effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of carbon emission management capabilities, Xia Yingxian introduced that the national carbon emissions trading management platform will be launched online in 2023, realizing inventory management, emission management, and data quality supervision. , verification management, and quota management are intelligent and digital, and big data means are used to enrich data quality management technical means. Since 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has held 5 special training courses on carbon emission data quality management and supervision and law enforcement, with more than 5,000 trainees, and supervision capabilities have been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian also said that in the next step, we will continue to do a good job in daily supervision of data quality and make full use of the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review working mechanism. Conduct spot checks and reports on data quality management work in various regions, establish and improve daily supervision and technical review systems for greenhouse gas emission data, clarify technical review standards and procedures, and consolidate the main responsibilities of key emission units. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Carbon price is in line with China’s current reality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the press conference , Xia Yingxian also mentioned the progress of the national carbon market construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 2,257 key emission units in the power generation industry have been included in the second compliance cycle (2021 and 2022) of the national carbon market, covering annual carbon dioxide emissions of more than 5 billion tons. . The quotas for 2021 and 2022 have been distributed in August 2023, and payment and compliance are currently underway. Xia Yingxian revealed that the current contract fulfillment rate has exceeded 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian believes that the national carbon market has achieved the expected construction goals. &quot;After more than two years of construction and operation, the overall operation of the national carbon market is stable, the price discovery mechanism has initially appeared, and corporate emission reduction awareness and capabilities have been significantly enhanced, playing a positive role in promoting the goal of achieving carbon peak and carbon neutrality.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the national carbon market has initially established an institutional framework system, breaking through the blocking points in key links such as reporting verification, quota allocation, market transactions, settlement and compliance, etc. Difficulties, and realize full-service intelligence through the national carbon market management platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Regarding the topic of carbon market expansion, Xia Yingxian stated that it is urgent to include more qualified industries into the national carbon emissions trading market to reduce the cost of emission reduction for the whole society. We will insist on making progress while maintaining stability, and prioritize the inclusion of industries that contribute significantly to achieving the goal of carbon peak and carbon neutrality, have serious overcapacity, have great synergy potential for pollution reduction and carbon reduction, and have good data quality foundations, and include each mature industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The expansion of the carbon market requires a good data foundation. Xia Yingxian introduced that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment conducts annual carbon emission accounting report verification work nationwide every year for petrochemical, chemical, building materials, steel, non-ferrous metals, papermaking, civil aviation and other industries, and collects data from more than 6,000 companies. The above-mentioned 7 industries The total direct emissions from the power generation and power generation industries account for more than 70% of the country&#39;s total. In addition, special studies were organized on quota allocation methods, accounting and reporting methods, verification points, and expansion implementation paths for seven industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of October 25, 2023, the cumulative transaction volume of carbon emission quotas is 365 million tons, and the cumulative transaction volume is 19.437 billion yuan. The carbon price after the launch of the national carbon market Maintained at around 50-80 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recently, the quota price has shown an overall upward trend, maintaining at around 80 yuan/ton. The moderate increase in carbon price reflects the market nature of carbon price.&quot; Xia Yingxian believes that the carbon price is in line with China&#39;s current reality and basically reflects my country’s emission reduction costs. In the next step, we will study the establishment of a market adjustment mechanism and take measures such as early warning of contract performance risks to adjust market supply and demand, enhance market vitality, and ensure the healthy, stable and orderly operation of the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“三吠举报”到“恶犬法案”：美国人怎么养狗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is well known that many people in the United States love dogs. However, these Americans love and raise dogs to achieve a certain balance under the support of their specific natural conditions, social conditions and legal environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, in my opinion, the most important and overlooked point is that the United States is not a rabies epidemic area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 202 human rabies cases were reported in 143 districts and counties in China in 2020. Dogs in the United States hardly carry the rabies virus, and the few rabies cases are caused by wild animals (mainly bats). A total of five people died of rabies in the United States in 2021, the highest number of rabies deaths in the country in 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Differences in natural conditions will cause huge differences in social adaptation. When there are no worries about rabies, the intimacy between humans and cats and dogs will greatly increase, and dogs will not be too taboo about what they eat or lick. Even strange stray dogs don’t have to worry about rabies. This creates a close human-dog relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the living area and living pattern of Americans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the per capita housing area in the United States is 67 square meters, ranking first in the world. In addition to the large average area, there are also structural differences in urbanization rates. The overall average urbanization rate in the United States currently reaches 83%, and the urbanization rate in some metropolitan areas is close to 100%. China&#39;s urbanization rate in 2022 will be 65.22%. The problem of dog ownership is largely an urban problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calculated in terms of per capita housing area in domestic cities, especially large and medium-sized cities, it is about half that of the United States. This is just the living area, not the living pattern. Chinese people mostly live in high-rise buildings and share the green environment of the community, while Americans mostly live in suburban villas. Americans have far more outdoor space per household. Therefore, Chinese people use half of their living area and much less public outdoor area to raise dogs, which naturally creates more conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States also has another characteristic, that is, it is more diverse, has a large place, has many choices, and does not interfere with each other. It not only protects the rights of dog lovers, but also protects the rights of people who do not love dogs. There are many communities in the United States that prohibit pets. Not only are dogs not allowed in these communities, but dogs from outside are not even allowed to &quot;visit&quot;. Have a peaceful time together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Americans love dogs, and although the living area is large, the density is low, and there are many green spaces, it does not mean that American dogs do not bite people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the U.S. National Library of Medicine, approximately 1,000 people in the United States require emergency care treatment for serious dog bites every day, and more than 4.5 million people are bitten by dogs each year, with 30 to 50 People are killed by dogs. Injuries caused by dog ​​bites and attacks result in the need for 30,000 surgeries in the United States each year, including sutures and staples. In 2020, U.S. insurance companies paid $854 million for dog bites and attacks, with the average dog bite insurance claim amount being $50,245. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Humane Society of the United States estimates that 51% of dog bite victims are children, which means more than 2 million children are bitten by dogs in the United States each year. Among dog bite deaths, the highest proportion is among those aged 0-4 years. Since children under 1 year old are often unable to walk and are often looked after by adults, the rate of bites is the lowest. After the age of 4, as children get older, the likelihood of being bitten decreases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, although Americans love dogs, they also strictly manage dog ownership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For general harassment, take New York City as an example. If you are reported for not picking up dog poop while walking your dog, the police will issue a $250 (1,800 RMB) fine and may also require you to appear in court. The law also prohibits the harassment of pet dogs in all public and private places. If the dog is not kept on a leash, a fine of 200-400 US dollars will be imposed. For dog nuisance, follow the &quot;three barking report&quot; principle: if a dog of any family barks more than three times in a residential area, it will be considered a nuisance, and neighbors can report it. Under strict regulations, most dog walkers in the United States are self-conscious, and leash-free dog walking is rare. If a dog poops, most dog owners use plastic bags to collect the poop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the law stipulates that people who keep high-risk ferocious dogs must erect signs in conspicuous places in their yards to remind passersby to pay attention. In public places, high-risk ferocious dogs must wear a restraint leash and an anti-bite muzzle at all times. Otherwise, law enforcement agencies have the right to impound or execute the dog. Depending on the severity of the case, the dog owner may be held criminally responsible and may even be sentenced to 90 days in jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For higher levels of physical risk, some states have enacted so-called &quot;vicious dog laws.&quot; A dog is considered a &quot;vicious dog&quot; if it attacks or injures a human or their pet within a two-year period, or exhibits aggressive behavior that requires the police or animal control agencies to stop or drive away. Such dogs must be isolated, prohibited from contact with humans, and undergo mandatory training. If the owner refuses to cooperate, the dog may be euthanized. The Vicious Dog Act requires dog owners to take full responsibility for their dogs. If a dog attacks a person and the owner fails to take strict precautions and deal with it promptly, resulting in casualties, the dog owner must be responsible for all injuries and may even be subject to criminal penalties. If a dog attacks a human after escaping, the owner is still responsible for the dog&#39;s behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are very sound pet shelters and rescue stations across the United States, funded by the government and private organizations, to take in and rescue stray cats and dogs. In shelters, sheltered dogs and other animals are treated well. Americans love dogs, and there are always enough volunteers at shelters. Stray dogs in shelters generally have a 1-2 week deadline for adoption. Non-governmental animal protection organizations also try their best to allow dogs in shelters to be adopted. After that, if no one comes to adopt them, they will be euthanized. Statistics show that of the 8.5 million stray dogs sheltered in the United States in 2010, 82% were adopted and taken away by new owners, while the remaining 1.53 million old, sick, and unadopted dogs were euthanized. Although many civil organizations are trying to change euthanasia and replace it with sterilization, raising funds is still an unavoidable obstacle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All public issues are like this. Rights and obligations cannot be neglected or mentioned only on one side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年度佳作，没有人经得起剖析审视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 22:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;There are many movies about marriage. You can easily pull up a long movie list. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this topic is never out of date, and has different interpretations in the eyes of different people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;No, this year Cannes presents us with another blockbuster work - &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1060&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255204&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier is a female director. Her first two works were &quot;Victoria&quot; and &quot;Sibyl&quot;, both of which were self-written and directed, focusing on female expression. At the same time, Justine Trier is also the third female director in the history of Cannes to win the Palme d&#39;Or for this film. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255201 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The starring role is German actress Sandra Wheeler. In 2006&lt;span>;, at the age of 28, she won the Berlin Film Festival for her performance in &quot;Requiem&quot; Film Festival Silver Bear Award for Best Actress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255200 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talented female director teamed up with powerful actresses to present this masterpiece that cannot be missed this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The heroine Sandra is a well-known writer with strong creative power and very high productivity. Coupled with her androgynous temperament, she has accumulated many readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this day, while Sandra was being interviewed by a young female student majoring in literature, loud music suddenly came from upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reckless and rude interruption announced the existence of another person: Sandra&#39;s husband Samuel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255202&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Samuel was originally a university professor and also wanted to write. However, unlike his wife, who was full of literary ideas, he seemed to always get stuck halfway and find it difficult to write. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The two have an 11-year-old son named Daniel, who is visually impaired. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, this disability is not congenital, but is caused to some extent by Samuel: One day a few years ago, Samuel was supposed to pick up Daniel from school. But he suddenly got inspiration for writing and hired someone to pick up his son. During this period, Daniel had a car accident and damaged his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255205 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The accident not only interrupted their careers, but also put this middle-class family into financial difficulties due to medical expenses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to reduce debt pressure, Samuel suggested moving his family from London, England to his hometown in the suburbs of France. For Sandra, she lost her stable life in London and entered an unfamiliar environment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255203 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra has no one here, and her interview with the female student can only end hastily after being interrupted by Samuel. Soon, Daniel, who was returning from walking his dog, found his father&#39;s bloody body in the snow. He shouted for his mother, and Sandra, who came in a hurry, quickly called the police. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255207 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After identification, the fatal injury to the deceased Samuel was a heavy blow to the head. Although it appears that he fell to his death, he was most likely murdered. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255208 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But their family’s residence was nowhere to be found, and there were no other outsiders present when the incident occurred. Samuel usually had no enemies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thus, the common conclusion in crime movies&lt;/span>; is readily apparent: the murderer is the wife Sandra, and she must be resentful of her husband. Is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was controlled as the first suspect, and Daniel was on the scene The only witness. To prove her innocence, Sandra must convince the judge that there is love but not hatred between her and her husband, and that she has no motive for killing. At this point,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a death case has become a trial of a marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; also enters into the detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;analysis of marriage relationships: When a person &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; dies In this case, how can the other party prove itself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255210 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, except for Sandra, everyone else was basically in the same blind&lt;span>; situation as Daniel. After all, except for the two parties involved, everyone is an outsider in this relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255206 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So neither the psychiatrist’s testimony, which was heavily psychoanalytic, nor the defense provided by lawyers on both sides, could touch the real Samuel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is no way to reach the core of a living person or a love through words. But this trial has to find the truth through language. This is the contradiction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255209 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because she was in France, Sandra had to use her unskilled language to defend herself. Love&lt;/span>; is not like this: stumbling communication, but in the end it is inaccurate words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255211&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Words always have a certain performance quality, and &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; also presents this through a perfect recording. The film also completely enters the climax after the opening 80 minutes. . Samuel carried Sandra on his back and recorded the heated argument that broke out between the two on the day before her death. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the recording, Samuel accused Sandra of only caring about her career and ignoring her family, saying that she was always aloof, saying that she clearly blamed herself for causing Daniel&#39;s tragedy but refused to admit it. She plagiarized her own ideas and cheated on her physically...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/ 9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 24/9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was not to be outdone. From the beginning, she calmly advised Samuel not to complain and not to be self-motivated, but later she became unbearable. Gave him a slap...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif &quot; data-key=&quot;255213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a quarrel must have been experienced by most couples and couples who have passed the passionate love stage. It is difficult for outsiders to say that the public is justified and the mother-in-law is justified. Determine right or wrong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But the problem is that this quarrel and physical conflict happened the day before Samuel&#39;s death, which undoubtedly pushed Sandra towards the angry wife who murdered her husband. image. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The troubled media are still chewing on Sandra’s book at this time, believing that her murder of her husband was premeditated. But is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255212&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; is a work that analyzes marriage as delicately as a scalpel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a middle-aged female director, Justine Trier has not only gotten rid of the male perspective, but also has passed the stage of young women&#39;s blind longing for marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is very creative in placing the marriage relationship in the court scene to analyze, on the other hand, she still has the unique tenderness and pioneering spirit of women. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, in the setting of the heroine Sandra, she has a strong androgynous temperament, which is different from common female images. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255215 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compared to common settings, the situations and personalities of Sandra and Samuel are also reversed: Sandra has a successful career, a peaceful personality, and is close to her children; while Samuel Not only did I encounter a career development bottleneck, but I also became more emotional and exhausted my creativity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This image and gender setting itself break through the stereotype of male narrative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the film uses calm and restrained lens language and narrative expression, trying to go deeper into the truth of the death case and give the audience a sense of clarity beyond the case itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two recordings in the movie, one is the interview of the female student that day, and the other is the quarrel privately recorded by Samuel. These two daily conversations were analyzed and interpreted word for word in public in court, and were even used as evidence of crimes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When the second quarrel started by Samuel appears in court, the gender balance begins to tilt, and Sandra needs to explain all of Samuel&#39;s dilemmas : Why does he have to choose between work and family? Why does he never have time to write novels? Why is his creativity exhausted while she publishes novels frequently? Why is he frigid and she cheats on her physically? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, the intimate relationship must be put on the table to experience the scrutiny of others, and then others will give the final conclusion. Sandra was extremely embarrassed. What she encountered was not only a discussion about gender, but also a trial of marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the age of only 11, their son Daniel has already experienced major events such as car accidents, disability, the death of his father and defending his mother. He is actually the avatar of the audience. After listening to the trial half-blindly, he finally chose his mother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255214 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this choice itself, even Sandra&#39;s innocence itself, cannot achieve complete emotional catharsis, because when feelings need to be judged, it means that there will be no survivors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film&#39;s use of telephoto lenses, soft light, and close-up lenses makes the images presented in the film more cold and distant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255216 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the exquisite narrative of &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot;, the most commendable thing is the performance of the heroine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is a talented and famous writer, and on the other hand, she is a wife and mother who is troubled by intimate relationships. The emotions and gestures she expresses directly support her. Played the role itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255218 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the movie, Sandra is well aware of the complexity of language. She refutes others&#39; attempts to define Samuel again and again, and always uses negative statements to retain Samuel. beautiful image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;That&#39;s not him.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This denial itself is an expression of private love, but love cannot be declared to Mouth proves that love is so absurd. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So in the court that tried to convict her, she was the only one who loved the real Samuel. She did not kill him, but she did kill him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[色乡，一段关于救赎的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJInW9oBtSKF5N8j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJ InW9oBtSKF5N8j. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lodro Wolong Temple is built along the cliff, and the huts on the cliff are used for monks&#39; practice. The cave &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tawny and bare, this was my first impression of Luozha County. Luozha County is located in a mountain valley, and the county seat winds along the only mountain road in the middle. I chose to come to Luozha, Shannan City, to visit the Sakagutuo Temple with a history of more than 900 years in the Border Se Township. This is a pilgrimage road often walked by Buddhists. It has a long history and a mysterious place. As for the scenery, although I am not a Buddhist, I am also full of yearning for the beautiful scenery on the border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9 o&#39;clock in the morning, I set off from the bus station in the northern suburbs of Lhasa and passed through the beautiful Yanghu Lake and rows of snow-capped mountains. When I arrived in Lozha County, it was about 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon. I immediately bought the only daily ticket at the station. A ticket to Sexiang. It still takes nearly two hours to drive to Sexiang. The road begins to narrow and there are more gravels. But I was still attracted by the barren and spectacular scenery outside the window. One side of the car is close to the exposed rocks, and the other side is close to the rushing river. The river is rushing forward happily, as if it is racing with the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Loza County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were only five or six people on the bus An old Tibetan man, a young Tibetan man and me. The young Tibetan man comes from the Garze region and has been traveling to Tibet for more than half a year. This time he went specifically to Lapu Hot Spring in Sexiang. He wore a down jacket and carried a small plastic bag with him, but no other luggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already 7:30 when I arrived in Sexiang. I quickly found a place to stay before it got dark. The entire township is located on a flat land in the mountains. There are dozens of buildings built along the road. They are all occupied by local people. In order to welcome guests, some have been converted into hotels and some into restaurants. Hotels are either closed or full, and the owner is rarely there, leaving only a phone number. Finally, I finally found a bed at the Sakaguto Temple Hotel. There was a public bathroom, but I couldn&#39;t take a shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Saika Gutuo Temple in Sexiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;sai Kagutuo Monastery was originally a monastery of the Kagyu sect of Tibetan Buddhism, but later converted to the Gelug sect. It is a must-visit place for Tibetan pilgrims. The main building of Sakagutuo Temple, which has a history of more than 900 years, has been relatively completely preserved. The temple is located in the middle of Se Township, next to the cliff, and the sound of rushing river water comes from the bottom of the mountain, which is quiet and distant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a legendary and touching story of redemption behind the nine-story tower of Sakagutuo Temple. According to legend, in the 11th century, Marpa, the founder of the Kagyu sect, who was known as &quot;one of the seven great translators of ancient Tibet&quot;, had a disciple named Milarepa. He lost his father when he was young, his wealth was seized by relatives, and his family was enslaved. When he grew up, he learned magic and killed 35 people in revenge. Later, in order to atone for his sins, Milarepa came to Sexiang to become a disciple of Marpa. Marpa ordered Milarepa to build Sakagutuo Temple alone (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Means &quot;Nine-story Gongzi Castle&quot;&lt;/span>;). Day after day, year after year, every time he built it, Marpa asked him to overthrow and rebuild it, until it was finally completed the sixth time. The current Sakagutuo Temple was built at that time (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;later repaired and expanded&lt;/span>;). Ancient prayer wheels hang on the outside of the predominantly yellow temple, and murals from hundreds of years ago can still be faintly seen on the mottled walls inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green space by the Sexiang River and a released calf&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There is a small suspended plank road on the top of the 9-story watchtower tower for people to pray for blessings. When I climbed to the ninth floor, a lama said that since I had come up, I should go around the tower. It is said that turning once can wash away all the bad luck in the past life; turning twice can pray for the health and happiness of parents; turning three times will prevent you from falling into hell in the next life. However, except for the steel poles that can be grasped by hand, there are no protective fences around the top of the tower. I was afraid of heights and dared not go up. Finally, I walked around in a circle under the leadership of the lama. The young lama chanted sutras while walking. He walked many times every day and it became a daily routine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sakagutuo Temple is very small and can be completed in less than half an hour. On the top of the mountain south of Sexiang, there is also Lodro Wolong Monastery, which is the birthplace of the Kagyu Sect of Tibetan Buddhism and was built by Master Marpa when he was 29 years old. According to the official website of Luozha County Government, &quot;Luo&quot; means &quot;south&quot;, &quot;Zhuowo&quot; means &quot;beginning of auspiciousness&quot;, and &quot;Long&quot; means &quot;prophecy&quot;. Luozhawolong Temple is where the master predicted and prophesied. place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes several hours to walk to the Luozhuo Wolong Temple on the top of the mountain, and there is no public transportation. I found a ride on the road and met a Tibetan family who drove up the mountain and picked me up. The family came from neighboring Cona County and came to Luozha County for pilgrimage for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sexiang is dozens of kilometers away from Bhutan. Opposite the Sekhar Guto Temple is the Bhutanese commodity store, and the back of the mountain where Lodro Wolong Temple is located is In Bhutan, our ID cards were held at the checkpoint on the way up the mountain. The dusty gravel road was winding and difficult to walk. A couple from Guangdong decided to give up after driving for a short distance, but this Tibetan family did not. After half an hour, we successfully reached the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only temples on the mountain, and the landscape is extremely open. Several huge crows are circling overhead, and the shadows of clouds are cast on the mountain. Lodzo Wolong Temple is built along the stone wall on the top of the mountain. In addition to the main temple, there are also many small hermitages scattered under the cliff. A lama who has been practicing for many years has long hair reaching his waist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lamas in Lodro Wolong Monastery are the most enthusiastic lamas I have ever encountered. They explained the story behind the temple to everyone who went up the mountain. Although I was the only Han tourist, after they finished telling a long list of Tibetan words, they would tell it to me again in Chinese. According to them, the old Lodro Wolong Temple was destroyed and was rebuilt in 1992. There is a sky burial platform at the top of the mountain. A lama in his twenties said that it was built based on a stone that Marpa carried back from India where he studied scriptures for 12 years. On the hillside at the foot of the temple, there is a flat area surrounded by prayer flags. The place where stones are piled is Shunyuantian. According to legend, this is the place where Marpa and Milarepa met for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We stayed on the mountain for more than half a day, during which time the temple held a Dharma ceremony and witnessed the Tibetan Buddhist Dharma ceremony. Finally, I went down the mountain with the Tibetan family, and the car went around the zigzag road back to Sexiang. We separated and continued our journeys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[好心多修120米路要拆除？公共资金不能这么造丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A long-awaited road has been built an extra 120 meters, becoming an illegal land occupation and will be demolished , wait until the procedures are completed before re-doing it. Why is it so fussy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Hunan Radio and Television Urban Channel, a new road in Changsha City that nearby residents have long awaited will be opened soon. However, a section of this road was suddenly surrounded again recently, and excavators were excavating the paved asphalt road. Street lights, street trees and other facilities on the roadside were also dismantled and removed, and garbage trucks were also brought in from other places. The loess was transported and poured on the road. What happened? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that the main part of this road is in Changsha Economic Development Zone, but it extends 120 meters to Furong District. When the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company was building the road, it built an extra 120 meters along the way without going through the construction application procedures with the relevant departments of Furong District. The Furong District Natural Resources and Planning Department determined that this was “illegal land occupation.” As a result, the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company responsible for the construction began to demolish the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, staff from the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company said that they agreed that the land was indeed being used illegally, but they were &quot;purely out of good intentions.&quot; Also, if we don&#39;t build more of these 120 meters, there may be no way to connect it with other roads, and there will be a section of &quot;intestinal obstruction&quot; in the middle, so it won&#39;t make much sense to build this road, so we &quot;kindly&quot; help and provide money and efforts to complete it. The more than 100 meters of road should be repaired. So when they were deemed illegal by the relevant departments of Furong District, they felt a little aggrieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Furong District, the extra 120 meters of road construction is within my jurisdiction. According to regulations, road construction should follow procedures and be submitted for approval in advance. It is of course illegal to build roads without approval. The competent department requires that the illegal status be eliminated and the construction be restored to its original state. The construction application procedures will be completed before re-repairing, which is completely &quot;in accordance with the law and regulations and in compliance with the procedures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There seems to be nothing wrong with both sides. However, after construction and demolition, demolition and construction again, a lot of money was wasted. What went wrong? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jingkai District Urban Construction Company that built the road built it without approval. Of course, there were violations of laws and regulations. However, the road has been repaired, and it is indeed a road that has been long-awaited by the nearby people and is necessary to be repaired. However, if it is forced to be demolished, the problem may be even greater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all this is a huge waste of public funds. Although the 120-meter road is not long, it costs a lot. The entire road is about 1 kilometer long and costs 60 million yuan. Calculating the cost of 120 meters is 6 to 7 million yuan, and dismantling it will also cost a lot of money. Once it was built or demolished, millions would disappear. This is a municipal road, and the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company responsible for its construction is also a state-owned enterprise. The source of its construction funds must be public funds of the local government, that is, public money. For Furong District, it is a good thing that the Economic Development Zone is willing to spend the money to build its own roads. If it is forced to be demolished and then rebuilt by oneself, although the cost of demolition will be borne by the Economic Development District Urban Construction Company, the cost of reconstruction will still be borne by Furong District. It is also incomprehensible to abandon existing roads that have been built with help from others and to dig up and spend money to rebuild them yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, a section of the repaired road is dug out, and the rest becomes a dead end road. It took three years to build this road, and the nearby people had been waiting for it for three years. It was finally opened, but a section was demolished, and its effectiveness was greatly reduced. If we have to go through the formalities and rebuild it again, I am afraid we will have to wait at least another year and a half. This will bring great inconvenience to the public&#39;s travel and will also damage the image of the local government in the public mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Requiring the Economic Development Zone to demolish the roads and then rebuild them themselves can be said to be harmful to Furong District and not beneficial to itself. So why do the relevant departments in Furong District do this? From the perspective of organizational behavior, perhaps one or two explanations can be given. For some departments, they must make the decision on their own territory. It is absolutely unacceptable for others to interfere with their boundaries without telling them. Even if you spend more money, you must maintain your authority. After all, if you want to spend money, it is also a financial expense, rather than having to pay out of your own pocket. Only consider issues from the perspective of one place and one department, from the perspective of maintaining the authority of the local area and this department, only consider legal compliance from the perspective of this department, and show your sense of existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether the decision made is reasonable from a higher level, whether it will waste financial resources and state-owned assets, waste local taxpayers&#39; money and public interests and perceptions, and consume administrative credibility, it is not considered. scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident shows the fragmentation and lack of coordination among relevant government departments, the lack of appreciation for the use of fiscal funds, and the lack of care for the waste of state-owned assets. Such things are not uncommon. In the past few years, roads in some cities have been dug up frequently. Today they are laying water pipes, tomorrow they are burying wires, and the day after tomorrow they have to repair sewers. Frequently digging and repairing, repairing and digging again not only wastes construction funds, but also doubles the construction period and brings great inconvenience to citizens&#39; travel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, after the media reports this time, the relevant departments of Changsha Furong District have urgently stopped the behavior of damaging the road surface, and have speeded up the relevant procedures to legalize the 120-meter road as soon as possible. This case has been solved. I hope there will be fewer such absurd things in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“软实力之父”约瑟夫·奈：“中美间的交流应该是面向所有人的”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Is there destined to be a war between China and the United States? My answer Yes, no.&quot; Joseph Nye, a professor at Harvard Kennedy School, gave a negative answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye is a representative figure of the neoliberal school of international relations. Before and after the Cold War, Joseph Nye was famous for proposing the concept of &quot;soft power&quot;. Soft power refers to a country&#39;s strength other than economic and military strength, and mainly refers to influence such as culture, values, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He served successively as Assistant Secretary of State in the Carter administration, Chairman of the National Intelligence Council and Assistant Secretary of Defense in the Clinton administration. He is also a leading figure in American politics. But he reminded that the history of mankind is full of situations where wars &quot;accidentally&quot; entered. As long as China and the United States strengthen cooperation and act cautiously, wars can be avoided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China-US relations are one of the most important bilateral relations in the world today. On October 27, 2023, U.S. President Biden met at the White House with visiting member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since October 23, Joseph Nye has embarked on his first visit to China after the COVID-19 epidemic. Judging from the public schedule in just one week, the &quot;Father of Soft Power&quot; has successively attended speeches at many think tanks and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 25, in the Qiulin Lecture Hall of the School of International Relations at Peking University, Joseph Nye spoke with the topic &quot;Are China and the United States destined to have a war?&quot; Hundreds of teachers and students discussed &quot;The History and Future of Sino-US Relations.&quot; The conference was jointly hosted by the School of International Relations at Peking University and the Institute of International Strategic Studies at Peking University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye once proposed the &quot;20-year cycle theory of Sino-US relations&quot;, that is, since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States, the ups and downs of the relationship between the two countries have been based on a 20-year cycle. And change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the long run, China and the United States will have better relations. But in the short term, China and the United States still have differences to resolve.&quot; Joseph Nye told the South Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye believes that after 2017, Sino-US relations entered a cycle of great power competition. &quot;China-U.S. relations have gotten worse in the past. In a sense, I think we have seen the deterioration of Sino-U.S. relations, but I hope things will get better.&quot; Joseph Nye told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, discussions about the &quot;new cold war&quot; between China and the United States have been rampant in European and American public opinion circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Joseph Nye&#39;s view, the Cold War between China and the United States is completely incommensurable with the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union. “During the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union, although there was military and political competition between the two countries, their economic and social ties were very sparse. But now China and the United States are highly interdependent in many fields such as economy, society, and ecology. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, Joseph Nye wrote an article in the &quot;Wall Street Journal&quot; that the Cold War between China and the United States is completely avoidable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye supports China and the United States in strengthening cooperation in public health, climate change and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Exchanges between China and the United States should be open to everyone. Exchanges at the cultural and scientific levels are equally important.&quot; Joseph Nye told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes The public&#39;s attention should not only focus on high-level people, but also exert soft power. Low-level contacts are also very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The following is an interview with Joseph Nye:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Sino-US relations have gotten worse in the past. In a sense, we have seen a deterioration in Sino-US relations, but I hope things will get better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unfortunately, during the COVID-19 epidemic, communication between China and the United States has not been sufficient. However, communication between China and the United States has begun to change. The United States sent important cabinet members to visit China, and Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi also arrived in Washington for a visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I think Sino-US relations are making progress. Two years ago, Sino-US relations were worse than they are now. What we&#39;re seeing today is some pickup, and I hope it continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among China and the United States, China not only has strong economic performance, but also has the attraction of traditional culture. I believe that a country’s soft power comes not only from government actions but also from civil society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The U.S. government often does some unpopular things, but despite this, America&#39;s civil society remains attractive to others because it is relatively free. Therefore, the soft power of the United States comes more from universities, non-profit organizations, and foundations, such as the Bill Gates Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is undeniable that people&#39;s views of the United States have gone up and down in recent years. In my opinion, the soft power of the United States has gone up and down. During the Vietnam War and when U.S. troops invaded Iraq, U.S. soft power was declining. The soft power of the United States returned again with the election of Obama as President of the United States in 2008, and fell together with Trump (who became President of the United States) in 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soft power does not decline linearly or rise linearly. It is often cyclical. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, the soft power of the United States is weakening due to internal divisions within the United States. On the other hand, if you look at the hard power of the United States, you will see that the U.S. economy is booming. The United States is a wellspring of innovation, leading in technological fields such as biotechnology and artificial intelligence. Looking at the situation in the Middle East today, (U.S.) military power is still very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Biden administration has been in power for three years and has a more balanced view (compared to the Trump administration). They still believe there are still benefits to working with China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In May this year, the G7 summit changed its focus on decoupling from China to de-risking on China. This expression means Countries outside the G7 will adopt partial decoupling from China, mostly in the security field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In other words, de-risking does not mean completely cutting off economic ties, but there are limits. U.S. national security adviser Jake Sullivan called it &quot;building a high wall around a small yard.&quot; We should not let this small yard grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To prevent deterioration, Sino-US relations should start with high-level contacts. Next, look for areas of cooperation between China and the United States, which can convey to the public of both countries that cooperation with another country is beneficial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I think this is an area where China and the United States can strengthen cooperation (position on the Russia-Ukraine conflict). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China and the United States can also strengthen cooperation in other areas, such as climate change and working with the WHO to respond to epidemics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Exchanges between China and the United States should be open to everyone. Obviously, people always focus on the president or the cabinet. Exchange on cultural and scientific levels is equally important. If we need to build trust and cooperation (with each other) and exert soft power, low-level engagement is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(Sino-US relations) have become increasingly complex and difficult to resolve in the short term. I tend to use &quot;short-term pessimists&quot; and &quot;long-term optimists&quot; to describe China and the United States as not posing a threat to each other. In the long run, China and the United States will have better relations. But in the short term, China and the United States still have differences to resolve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一斤力气9分钱，重庆最后的女棒棒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259500]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;July 2021, Chongqing Mountain City Trail, sculptures representing Chongqing sticks and traditional stilted buildings . (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fa9ff8783c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fa9ff8783c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;July 2021, Chongqing Mountain City Trail, sculptures representing Chongqing sticks and traditional stilted buildings. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;How can a girl become a stickman? How can she afford the work? Go and do something lighter. You&#39;re still alive.&quot; This is the advice that 51-year-old Huang Xiuli often encounters when carrying goods at Chongqing&#39;s Chaotianmen Comprehensive Wholesale Market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Standing on the heights of Chaotianmen, you can see the intersection of the Jialing River and the Yangtze River. This is the largest water pier in Chongqing. South of the Jialing River and on the north bank of the Yangtze River is the Yangtze River Binjiang Road. On this modern street, there is the Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trading Market, the largest wholesale market gathering place in Chongqing. It is like a streamer, flowing with people buying goods from all over the country. Chongqing’s economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The mountainous city of Chongqing has steep roads and few flat areas, and its unique topography provides Bangbang with a living space. &quot;Bangbang&quot; is a Chongqing dialect that originally means &quot;stick&quot;. It is a local name for farmers who carry a bamboo stick and engage in heavy physical labor. In the Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trading Market, Bangbangs are responsible for the last link in this economic chain: transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you look carefully, you can find a few female figures among the sticks passing through the shops in the market. With their hair cut short or in buns, they look sophisticated and sophisticated, just like the men who dominate the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some of them work alone, and some open &quot;couple teams&quot;. In industries where they sell their physical strength to make a living, they often have to deal with employers questioning their &quot;business capabilities.&quot; But even so, they don&#39;t want to give up the stick. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Moving things uphill is the most annoying thing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At Chaotianmen at 6 o&#39;clock in the morning, the freighter on the riverside sounded its whistle, and the truck and asphalt The sound of the road rubbing against each other was more lively than the Chongqing night market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Huang Xiuli opened the window, and the noise and sunlight penetrated into the room. On the floor were corrugated boxes of pickles and corrugated boxes that Huang Xiuli had collected from various places. Drink bottles and leftovers were scattered on the table... Huang Xiuli picked out this house filled with musty smell one pound at a time. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli has been a &quot;professional player&quot; for 24 years. A stick, a three-meter-long red nylon rope, and a 232 yuan trolley are all her assistants in her work. Every morning at 6:45, Huang Xiuli goes to work in Dazheng Shopping Mall on time. While waiting for orders to come to her door, she and other Bang Bangs set up a gantry formation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In September 2023, Huang Xiuli was transporting goods. (Zheng Cailin/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/28/630028f496.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/630028f496 .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In September 2023, Huang Xiuli was transporting goods. (Zheng Cailin/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The employer that Huang Xiuli works with the most is Liu Chunsheng, nicknamed &quot;Liu Youtou&quot;. He has been selling men&#39;s clothing in Dazheng Shopping Mall for 25 years , with a bulging beer belly and a conspicuous bald head. Every morning when Liu Youtou was sorting out the cargo list, Huang Xiuli came over to help him load and carry the goods bag by bag according to the delivery location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Youtou agreed to pay 30 yuan per bag, which was the better price Huang Xiuli could get at Chaotianmen Market. One bag weighs 309.6 kilograms, and the straight-line distance is 324 meters - in 2023, Huang Xiuli&#39;s effort is worth an average of 9 cents per kilogram. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s affordable, usually more than ten yuan.&quot; Most of the goods she carries are clothing, which are light in weight and correspondingly priced lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Huang Xiuli’s experience, you need to use your brain to carry goods and not be reckless. In order to reduce air resistance, she lowered her head when pulling goods; she wore gloves on her hands to increase friction with the cart. &quot;The most annoying thing is carrying things uphill. Carrying it alone makes my head hurt.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In her early years at Chaotianmen, on the way home, Huang Xiuli’s inventory list Her bag was robbed by a motorcycle. &quot;How can I bear it? It&#39;s my hard-earned money.&quot; In order to keep the money, Huang Xiuli competed with the motorcycle, causing the bones of her upper arm to shift. &quot;I spent thousands, but the doctor didn&#39;t give me any money.&quot; Cure”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Later, for unknown reasons, the soles of Huang Xiuli’s feet swelled up. When she woke up, she started to feel pain when she stepped on the ground early in the morning. She thought about inserting acupuncture and applying medicinal wine on her own, but the more treatment she got, the more &quot;irritated&quot; she became. Therefore, Huang Xiuli likes to roll up half of her trouser legs to &quot;air out&quot; her calves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to physical pain, Huang Xiuli would move sideways slowly when lifting large heavy objects uphill or downhill. For a large box over one meter high, Huang Xiuli will first unfold the rope and move it under the heavy object, lift the two ends, cross-tie them and put them on bamboo sticks, and support the goods with both hands while walking. For Huang Xiuli, the body is not only a tool, but also her partner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 4 p.m., every merchant in the Chaotianmen Wholesale Market pulled down their rolling shutters. Huang Xiuli hid her sticks and trucks in the mall and went home to cook. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;When going uphill and downhill, Huang Xiuli cannot use a cart and needs to carry the goods manually. (Zheng Cailin/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/28/971d4f6708.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/28/971d4f6708.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli cannot use it when going uphill or downhill. Push carts require pure manpower to move goods. (Zheng Cailin/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Feng Shui Treasure Land&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli comes from Dianjiang, 120 kilometers away from the main urban area of ​​Chongqing. She is the youngest in her family and has four sisters. When she was in the countryside, Huang Xiuli often dragged her sister&#39;s large clothes to the fields to break buds, harvest wheat, and thresh millet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if she works from dawn to dusk in the village, Huang Xiuli earns only enough money to feed herself. She decided to visit the city. The night before leaving Dianjiang, she went to the bamboo forest in the mountains and cut two bamboos, thinking that she would make money from this stick in the future. That night, Huang Xiuli slept with Bangbang in her arms. The next day, she closed the doors and windows and went straight to the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli came to Chaotianmen in 1997. She was 26 years old that year. She had no crow&#39;s feet in her eyes, slightly curly black hair, tied with a black rubber band, and was energetic. Capable. The reason why I came to Chaotianmen is because this is the Feng Shui treasure land for Bangbang people to make a fortune. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1991, Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trading Market officially opened. By 1997, the market business area had grown from the initial 6,000 square meters to 270,000 square meters, and the number of operating households had grown from more than 500 to more than 10,000. In 1996, the annual transaction volume of the market here reached 3 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, on Chaodong Road where Bangbang lived, Peng Li, who was in charge of Chongqing Bishan Logistics, opened a freight order of more than 20,000 yuan a day. &quot;My joints hurt so much when I started to write,&quot; Peng Li said in pain and happiness. Liu You&#39;s first day&#39;s trade volume can reach more than 30,000 yuan. He describes his orders as being like a train pulling coal with no end in sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi also caught up with this wave of &quot;dividends&quot;. In the late 1990s, Gao Zongqi and Lao Zhao, who were from Qijiang, grew corn in their hometown. In the first year, they took their products to the city to sell them, but half of them were robbed before they even entered the city. They lost money. The next year, I took it to the city to sell it and made another loss. I heard that you can make money by helping people carry things in the city, so the couple picked up the stick and went to Chaotianmen. &quot;I can&#39;t read, so it&#39;s safer to be with my husband.&quot; This has been followed in Chaotianmen for 19 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of each year, the couple will receive a package fee of 10,000 yuan from their boss. Zhao laughed and said that he also gets a &quot;year-end bonus&quot; like white-collar workers. They relied on this &quot;year-end bonus&quot; to cover the expenses of returning home for the New Year. Gao Zongqi&#39;s parents praised their son-in-law for his promise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Dongqiu came to Chaotianmen for his son&#39;s wife Ben. Thirty years ago, Zhao Dongqiu and her husband opened a retail store in Anyue County, Sichuan. Although they made more money than farming, the couple was still worried about when they would be able to buy a house for their son and marry him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After chatting with someone, I learned that being a stick can make money quickly. The couple cut two sections of bamboo in their own mountain, scraped off the bamboo skin with a sickle, and wrapped the bamboo around them. We put on tape and nylon rope, bought tickets overnight, and arrived at Chaotianmen in the early morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he first came to Chaotianmen, Zhao Dongqiu&#39;s income was only two yuan a day. But she was not in a hurry and wandered around with the rope (rope) on her back. For four months, Zhao Dongqiu wandered around Chaotianmen and found out about her own &quot;human society&quot;: which family had girls who were many years old, and which family&#39;s mother-in-law had a hard life. It’s up to you, otherwise I can only work on a blank slate (not earning a penny).” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Slowly, 5 yuan, 10 yuan... more and more consignment notes entered Zhao Dongqiu&#39;s pocket. In 2003, the &quot;starting price&quot; of Bangbang was 15 yuan, and Zhao Dongqiu and her husband could get orders of more than 10,000 yuan in a month at most. When carrying goods, Zhao Dongqiu often wears jeans, a yellow shirt worth more than 30 yuan, and a thin gold necklace around his neck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The cakes in Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trade Market are getting bigger and bigger, and there are more and more sticks. Chongqing University&#39;s 2010 &quot;Survey on the Living Conditions of Shancheng Bangbang Army&quot; showed that during the most prosperous period, there were approximately 400,000 Bangbangs in Chongqing, of which 3% were women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chongqing Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trading Market is the first stop for most people looking for work. (Zheng Cailin/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fd0d13ae52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/28/fd0d13ae52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255843&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chongqing Chaotianmen Comprehensive Trading Market is a large The first stop for most people looking for work. (Zheng Cailin/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Poet Fu Wei once described it this way: In Chongqing, when your friends are drunk, you can ask a stick to carry them back; for your girlfriend’s birthday, You can ask a group of Bangbangs to send flowers and sing a &quot;Happy Birthday&quot; song; if your pet encounters misfortune, you can ask Bangbangs to help cry...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Although they can make money, Bangbang people live frugally. Ms. Liu and her husband have run the only clinic on Chaodong Road for more than 30 years. In Liu’s impression, it was rare for Bangbang to come to see a doctor. Even if he did come, he would always prescribe some medicine for headaches and fever. “They were reluctant to pay for it. I prescribed a pack of Acafol powder for 10 cents, and he asked me if it could be cheaper. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The boss likes to find male bangbangs”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Female bangbangs are not popular in Chaotianmen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi said that Huang Xiuli has a graceful appearance and does not look like a physical worker. There is no market for such a girl in Chaotianmen Bangbang. Once a boss thought she was a girl and couldn&#39;t afford the work, so Huang Xiuli would talk back: &quot;I can&#39;t afford it without paying!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I can afford it.&quot; So what if you get up? You will be Bangbang for the rest of your life, and I will be the boss for the rest of your life.&quot; The sharp-tongued Huang Xiuli shut up when she heard this. Bangbang, who sells his strength, is inseparable from the boss&#39;s choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The boss likes to find men to bang.&quot; In this industry, physical strength means money. In the Chaotianmen Wholesale Market, bulk goods shopping malls prefer men with physical strength. &quot;They can earn more than 50 per cart, and I earn 30 per order, which is very little.&quot; Hard work can make up for weakness, so Huang Xiuli only has to make a few more trips. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi was very envious of men who could carry toys. &quot;With a lot of money, he could carry my shoes three times in one trip.&quot; She came to Chaotian in 1998. Gate, the new Chongqing Chaotianmen International Shoe Center opposite Huang Xiuli carries goods. Gao Zongqi also discussed it with his boss, but the boss still asked Nan Bangbang next time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi was not discouraged and packed his shoes honestly, &quot;Their men are too stupid to do such a delicate job.&quot; Every time he learned the amount to be packed, Gao Zongqi began to think about how to put the shoe boxes into the box as much as possible horizontally and vertically. If the stuffing is tight, it will affect the presentation; if the stuffing is wide, the top of the box cannot be sealed with glue, and another box may be wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The steps of Gao Zongqi&#39;s packing are like putting on makeup: first apply a base layer horizontally, then change the angle of the second layer to apply it over a large area, and finally apply it like filling acne pits , insert a few small shoe boxes into every slot, and finally seal them with glue and tie them. Gao Zongqi raised his &quot;knife&quot; and cut the packing rope in two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Hands are easier to use than knives, but the speed must be fast, otherwise there will be blood.&quot; Gao Zongqi, who has been a &quot;bat player&quot; for 25 years, can always find the rope quickly The bifurcation point, quickly pull it off. After years of repeated movements, a groove appeared on the joint of Gao Zongqi&#39;s index finger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the last step of packaging is completed, Gao Zongqi is also responsible for &quot;after-sales&quot;, placing the remaining shoes of the shop owner, picking up the garbage, and then pulling the goods to Opposite the inn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gao Zongqi and her husband pack shoes together. (Zheng Cailin/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ 004772f5a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/004772f5a4.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;255844&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi packs shoes with her husband. (Zheng Cailin/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Female Bangbang will encounter sexual harassment. When they first came to Chaotianmen, Huang Xiuli and Lao Gao rented a house. On the first day they moved in, Bangbang, a man who lived across the street, saw Huang Xiuli and blurted out: &quot;What a good girl!&quot; and wanted to slap her butt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Bah! Even if I&#39;m not married, I won&#39;t be friends with you. If you don&#39;t know the door, just roll the ball.&quot; Huang Xiuli thinks she is a straight person, Don&#39;t hide your grievances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The man was so persistent that at 9 o&#39;clock one night, he asked Huang Xiuli out under the pretext of transporting goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I believe you, who wants to transport goods in the middle of the night? If you try to trick me later, I will trick you first.&quot; Huang Xiuli usually has a quiet voice. It&#39;s big, but sharp and harsh. If it&#39;s a little higher, it can scare a table of men. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The biggest fear is not being able to deliver the goods&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No matter how difficult it is , Huang Xiuli never thought about quitting Bangbang, but it could not stop the industry from declining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She remembers clearly that after the Wenchuan earthquake in 2008, the Chaotianmen business was abandoned. “Many people were from Sichuan and Chongqing and went home. Everyone has no intention of making money anymore, their lives are at stake.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;aftershocks&quot; were delayed until 2010. Chaotianmen Wholesale Market was facing upgrading and comprehensive renovation, and many merchants had the idea of ​​​​moving out of Chaotianmen. &quot;Outside business has been abandoned, and fewer people are coming to buy goods.&quot; Liu Youtou recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the rise of logistics companies, the competition in the door-to-door express delivery service industry is intensifying. In addition, Chongqing’s rail transit is accessible in all directions and private cars are booming. It seems that everyone is competing for the &quot;Bang Bang&quot; rice bowl&quot;. There are fewer and fewer sticks carrying bamboo sticks on their shoulders and wandering the streets asking for work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2021, a survey on the living conditions of Bangbang in Chongqing released by the School of Journalism and Communication of Northwest University for Nationalities estimated that the number of Bangbangs in Chongqing has been less than 2,000, and most of them are elderly. Most people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gao Zongqi and her husband worked together to carry goods. When they encountered a slope on the way, passers-by helped. (Zheng Cailin/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/28/330feb0e5c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/28/330feb0e5c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gao Zongqi and her husband worked together to carry goods, and met a Pokan, passers-by came together to help. (Zheng Cailin/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Gao Zongqi never thought about changing careers. &quot;I don&#39;t know anything, I can only contribute.&quot; Gao Zongqi is illiterate. She feels that she will be bullied by the maids in the restaurant, and it also depends on the boss&#39;s face, which Gao Zongqi doesn&#39;t like. She adapted to not having to &quot;punch in&quot; to work. &quot;Bangbang is free and has no one to care about. If you can afford it, take it. If you don&#39;t want to do it, rest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli doesn&#39;t want to go home either. &quot;It&#39;s hard to talk to a female Bangbang when she sees someone she knows.&quot; Relatives think that Huang Xiuli would be insulted if she worked as a Bangbang in the city. &quot;I don&#39;t feel embarrassed, but they always feel like something is wrong with you. How do they know I made a lot of money?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli thought, can As long as you make money, the rest doesn&#39;t matter. &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter whether it&#39;s hard or not, the worst thing is that I won&#39;t be able to deliver the goods. I&#39;ll have to pay hundreds of dollars a day. Every time the money disappears before it&#39;s warm in my pocket.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli did some calculations: the monthly mortgage of 4,000 yuan needs to be paid on time; her son is studying, and the living expenses of 800 yuan a month cannot be less; her daughter has given birth to a grandson, and neither husband nor wife has a job. , Huang Xiuli and Lao Gao provide 2,000 yuan per month. In order to occupy a place in the mall, Huang Xiuli also needs to pay 2,000 yuan &quot;land fee&quot; to the mall every year - occupying a 7-square-meter plot of 15 tiles, where Huang Xiuli&#39;s son sits and waits for his mother in his free time. Playing with mobile phones. Including water, electricity, property and food expenses, Huang Xiuli feels that it takes about 8,000 yuan per month to open her home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;September, October, and November every year are the replacement seasons of Chaotianmen Clothing Market. In previous years, it was also the golden period for Bangbang people to make money. But this year, there were no cargo loads after two or three days. According to Lao Zhao, you can’t even pay for water now. Liu Youtou also made up his mind to return to his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Peng Li is still sitting on the small bench by the roadside, but now she can only issue freight orders of more than 2,000 yuan a day. Huang Xiuli often secretly picks up corrugated cardboard when she gets off work. Gao Zongqi still sits at Chaotianmen International Shoes Co., Ltd. waiting for goods at 6 o&#39;clock every day, and his breakfast has changed from two buds to one. &quot;If you don&#39;t have money to earn, don&#39;t eat in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are fewer sticks, and there are even fewer female sticks. Southern Weekend visited and found that there are currently 8 female baseball players in Chaotianmen, 4 of whom are responsible for shoes in the new Chongqing Chaotianmen International Shoe Store, 1 is moving clothes in the third trading area of ​​the shopping mall, and 3 are mobile On Chaodong Road, it mainly transports foreign goods. There are four women in Sanxia Square, two of whom often wait for goods at the entrance of Chongqing New Century Supermarket, and two of whom follow their husbands everywhere to buy goods. There is a female stick worker at the Caiyuanba Bus Station. She closes her stall in the afternoon during the peak season and returns in the morning during the off-season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When asked where the more female fans went and how many female fans there are in the area now, their answers were all &quot;I don&#39;t know.&quot; &quot;&quot;not sure&quot;. In other Bangbang gathering places such as Guanyinqiao, Baiyakou Street, Shibati, etc., Southern Weekend did not find any female Bangbangs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Dongqiu has already saved enough money for her son&#39;s daughter-in-law, but she still doesn&#39;t want to leave Chaotianmen. Someone once took a fancy to Zhao Dongqiu&#39;s cleverness and asked her to settle accounts, but Zhao Dongqiu declined, &quot;It&#39;s easier to have fun here, and you can blow everyone off (chat)&quot;. Zhao Dongqiu&#39;s goal now is to &quot;get off work&quot; after earning 100 yuan a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Xiuli still insists on going out every day to find work. Before going out in the morning, she would put homemade medicinal wine on her feet, believing that her home remedies would be more effective than seeing a doctor. &quot;Life is difficult, but I still hope that life will get better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except for Zhao Dongqiu, all names in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陷入“以貌取人”困境的普通人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Weight, height, skin color, appearance... not only celebrities in the entertainment industry, but also ordinary people are increasingly falling into In anxiety about appearance. Some people invest a lot of money and energy in medical beauty, and some even suffer from &quot;eating disorders&quot; because of dieting. The reasons include not only the scrutiny of people around you, but also the evaluation standards of society. How to combat such an anxiety?</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张艺谋都没拍成的犯罪片，被他拍出来了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259238]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Watching &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; for the first time , still in Cannes. It was raining lightly in the early morning. Director Wei Shujun thanked everyone for coming to watch the movie before the movie started. He said that it was also raining in the first scene of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/92420c0a65a420316ddf9fdfdb6c6732.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;923&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/92420c0a65a420316ddf9fdfdb6c6732.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255188&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The opening rain scene of the film takes us back to the southern town in the 1990s. The cold weather, dilapidated buildings, dim light, and cramped alleys, the space presented in the film The texture is distant yet familiar. A series of bizarre murder cases lead the pursuers of the truth into the abyss of madness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a shortlisted film in this year&#39;s Cannes &quot;Un Certain Regard&quot; section, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; scored a high score of 3.5 points in the Cannes program&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;. As the opening film of the just-concluded Pingyao International Film Festival, this film once again received high praise from many film critics. &lt;span>;Since the short film &quot;Yanbian Boy&quot; debuted in Cannes in 2018, in just 5 years, every feature film directed by Wei Shujun has been favored by Cannes. Such excellent results are rare among the post-90s generation of directors. Its right. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wei Shujun’s first two works, &quot;The Parting of the Wild Horse&#39;s Mane&quot; and &quot;Stories of Yong&#39;an Town&quot;, have a very obvious personal color, not only in terms of plot, they are the same. This kind of personal experience narration also includes a preference for meta-film narrative. Cannes&#39; favor is undoubtedly a recognition of Wei Shujun&#39;s creative talent and potential, but these two previous works are still young and immature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/076b56ce199a61d4ff049d4328a9f286.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;725&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/076b56ce199a61d4ff049d4328a9f286.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255186 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;Mistake by the River&quot; shows a self-contained temperament, marking Wei Shujun&#39;s maturity in creation. Of course, on the one hand, this is due to the original novels with more humanistic value and interpretation space provided by Yu Hua. On the other hand, it is also the more professional and skilled performance of the creative team under the control of industrialization and commerciality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bdd362b284cc8f585bda60da8f8bef25.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bdd362b284cc8f585bda60da8f8bef25.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255185 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is a pioneering experimental novella, published in 1988, and is Yu Hua&#39;s early work. Yu Hua mentioned in the interview that Lu Xiaoya and Zhang Yimou both wanted to adapt this work, but neither of them came to fruition, which proves the difficulty of adapting this novel into a movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When describing the creative process of &quot;Alive&quot;, Wang Bin mentioned that the first thing he recommended to Zhang Yimou was &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; by Yu Hua. At that time, &quot;Alive&quot; Not fully published yet. After reading it, Zhang Yimou worried that the characters in &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; were too symbolic. In the process of continuous discussion, Zhang Yimou also constructed an almost brand-new story, with more realistic characters and plots, and obviously more Zhang Yimou&#39;s style - this story has a female as the protagonist. It&#39;s just that this idea went nowhere. Zhang Yimou was later completely attracted by &quot;Alive&quot;, thus creating a classic in Chinese film history. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than thirty years, in the hands of a younger generation of creators, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; has taken on a new glory. Wei Shujun and screenwriter Kang Chunlei&#39;s adaptation has no concerns of the times or historical considerations. Baggage is a bold addition, deletion, disassembly and reconstruction based on the original work. It not only grasps the absurd nature of the original work, but also injects it with an expression that is closer to the current mental state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5fe8b80026b408a31f2ac5ae24f08669.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5fe8b80026b408a31f2ac5ae24f08669.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255190&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The pursuit of the truth in Yu Hua&#39;s original work is the author&#39;s analysis of madness and civilization during the cultural renaissance wave in the late 1980s. The protagonist Ma Zhe was eventually diagnosed as a &quot;madman&quot;. It is an ironic social naming. In the movie version, as Ma Zhe gradually becomes a madman, he encounters individuals being crushed by authority, the uncertainty of memory, and black humorous coincidences in the process of solving crimes. Near the end of the movie, a change of viewpoint in one shot shows that Ma Zhe has finally become a madman, and is even more proactive than Ma Zhe in the novel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In that era in my memory, lunatics were common. Some liked to sing in the yard late at night, and some liked to tease others on the street. In today&#39;s era, we almost no longer see lunatics in public places, but more and more people entertain themselves as &quot;mentally ill.&quot; The different understandings of the symptoms of &quot;madman&quot; in the two eras may correspond to the different spiritual cores displayed by the two generations of creators in their treatment of novels and film texts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9d3a92c4251420384063fe14d67f7c51.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9d3a92c4251420384063fe14d67f7c51.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255189 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Hua said, &quot;Only fools are loyal to the original work.&quot; The movie &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is a smart and successful adaptation. The realistic texture created by Wei Shujun visually highlights the absurdity and the eerie atmosphere that makes people think deeply. The 16mm film shooting gives the film a retro tone, presenting the sense of small town space of that era, with occasional out-of-focus lenses, and even provides a stylistic expression for the theme of uncertainty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film&#39;s representation of the people and events in the unit of that era, as well as scenes such as the poetry meeting, is by no means a realistic reproduction. The director uses a slightly exaggerated satire, but more subtly conveys the reality of the times that makes people laugh. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ma Zhe, played by Zhu Yilong, also provides a wonderful screen image for this retro realistic texture. In order to interpret this role more accurately, Zhu Yilong went to Nanfeng, the filming location, to experience life in advance. He found inspiration for his appearance from an old photo of Yu Hua, and first gained weight and then lost weight for this role. His experiential performance created an amazing character. A convincing image of Ma Zhe. So far, this role is the biggest screen breakthrough for Zhu Yilong, who is still labeled as a traffic star, and will lay the foundation for his future as a big screen actor. In other words, we see one thing from him: acting skills are more important than traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4d2519bd4e8e9a251834b9bc08856dba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4d2519bd4e8e9a251834b9bc08856dba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255187&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Wei Shujun, who prefers meta-movies, said that &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is no longer a meta-movie. &lt;/span>;However, in the film, a movie theater that is about to be demolished is used as the working space for handling the case. The gaze and being gazed created by the camera&#39;s perspective, as well as the presentation of the chaos of dreams and reality, all demonstrate the director&#39;s meta-cinematic interest. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Similar to the original work, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; has a detective-themed genre shell, but the direction of the plot and the author&#39;s stylized treatment broke the expectations of genre suspense. . Moreover, it also abandons the avant-garde nature of the original work and uses a linear narrative as the main line, but it is by no means in line with the public&#39;s imagination. Therefore, we need to look at the market performance of this movie with caution. But regardless of whether it&#39;s good or bad at the box office, this is a work with a unique temperament. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙一钿：即将到来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259484]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/lAsQWMSOeodnf7QCdK12dexC0WyrUcK0OvPbqZTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lAsQWMSOeodnf7QCdK12dexC0WyrUcK0OvP bqZTe. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Andrea Rossetti/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the &quot;post-90s&quot; who are active in the contemporary art circle, Sun Yidian is undoubtedly the lucky one who has a good hand. She is the kind of international artist favored by galleries and academic institutions. The creator is also the darling of fashion brands and the collection market. Her works involve painting, installation, performance, and fashion cross-border... In her twenties, not long after leaving the Central American School, she was named &quot;Outstanding Youth Under 30&quot; by Forbes Asia &quot;, and in the past two years, he has won the &quot;Young Artist of the Year&quot; from The Best of Best in 2022 and the &quot;Outstanding Creator of the Year&quot; from the Chinese version of the Wall Street Journal in 2022-2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 will be an intense year for Sun Yidian. She returned to school and studied for a doctorate in literature and art at Tsinghua University. She has continued domestic group exhibitions and overseas exhibitions. In April, she held a solo exhibition in Berlin. Portrait&quot; opens, followed by the solo exhibition &quot;Once Upon a Time&quot; in Paris on October 17th (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Once Upon a Time&quot;&lt;/span>; ). Her iconic plastic dolls come from Western pop culture, but also contain Eastern codes. They have formed a unique accent in the old building of the landmark Place Fontaine in Paris: foreign viewers will smell the familiarity of the illustrations. A subtle touch of exoticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ph.D. supervisor Wang Minan once suggested that she complete her doctoral studies in a dual-thread approach: painting during the day and studying at night. But in fact, it is difficult to operate. &quot;Painting is still very brain-burning. After painting for a whole day, it is really difficult to read academic works at night.&quot; So she divided the time into different intervals: before the exhibition, she would retreat and paint intensively. , and then start the academic mode after all the paintings have been shipped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/IPytwWYqQQjX4FS4Yis8WejWuPCzF83Bh8eRStto.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/IPytwWYqQQjX4FS4Yis8WejWuPCzF83Bh8eRStto.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018, &quot;A twinkle&quot;, Shanghai, BANK Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Wu Ren Studio in Beijing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September, Wu Hongce In the &quot;Crossing Boundaries - Possibilities and Echoes&quot; exhibition at the Yuz Museum, Sun Yizhen met again with her previous work &quot;Pink Dinosaur with Blue Wings&quot;, which was her work around 2017. The entire &quot;man-made object&quot; &quot;The representative work shortly after the series started, &quot;I have never seen it again after the exhibition.&quot; When I met face to face in the exhibition hall five years later, &quot;it was exactly the same as seeing a long-lost friend or child. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You will recall the scene when you painted it, and even recall every stroke you drew. That moment was 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, and when you drew that stroke, the sun happened to shine. The place where you put down the pen, yes, suddenly, that memory was retrieved from your subconscious...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The memories all came back in an instant, and a painting opened the door to the past for her. A wormhole, not only about that painting, but also a whole set of life wrapped up in that painting: At that time, she was still in graduate school, and she shared a studio in Feijia Village with her friends at the time. There was an artificial pond there. In summer, the pond is crowded with lotus leaves and lotus flowers, and people living around it are all engaged in art. The next door neighbor is a dancer and a photographer. They visit each other all day long, go fishing in the pond, and eat big pot rice: stewed turtle, spicy crayfish... …spent many lively nights, like a utopia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is an elegy for collective life, which died out almost simultaneously with the student days. &quot;Now I have no collective life, only work is left.&quot; On the wall of the studio with small sketches, you can see the work Traces of madness: The exhibition schedule is accurate to every day, and is made into a list and posted in a conspicuous place; in an inconspicuous place, a whole row of &quot;45&quot; is densely written in pencil, and many of the &quot;45&quot; have been crossed out. ——This is the way good student Sun Yidian forces herself to focus on painting. She believes that every 45 minutes is a period of concentration. This is how the school&#39;s classes are set up. After every 45 minutes of serious painting, she will She crossed it out and allowed herself a small recess: she once liked using highly saturated fluorescent colors, which overloaded her eyes after long hours of homework and staring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BaVQHStk7Nt3jSUleSOHrwNw0XOXUbTuUiNWbfRY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BaVQHStk7Nt3jSUleSOHrwNw0XOXUbTuUiNWbfRY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255434&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Crossing Boundaries: Possibilities and Echoes&quot; exhibition view, Yuz Museum, Shanghai, 2023&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Alessandro Wang, Yuz Museum/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Sun Yidian’s fifth studio in Beijing, and it is also the one she considers “the most luxurious”. The so-called luxury means that it has heating and air conditioning, and has a high roof, ceiling windows, which bring in stable natural light, and large-open doors to facilitate the transportation of large-scale works. The second and third floors are storage rooms and bedrooms. There is a shelf large enough to store her past works, and a bed where she can lie down when she stays up late to paint - this is all an easel artist desires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other studios before can only be described as crude and homeless. She would count them on her fingers: the first studio was in Ark Court, a residential building next to Central Academy of Fine Arts. The space and light were cramped, and it was impossible to display large paintings. The size of the painting was slightly larger, and the relationship between colors was inconsistent. The depth is just not right. The second one was in Feijia Village. It was a happy time, but it was demolished and a group of artists were driven away as if they were being expelled. The third studio was near the turkey factory. One summer there was a sudden flood and most of her paintings were soaked. So she fled there and moved to the mainland. The fourth studio has no heating in winter and no air conditioning in summer. She spent three winters in this ice cave, painting with her feet on a small electric carpet. Her hands became cold and stiff after a while, so she could only put them under her buttocks to warm them up before continuing to paint. Her mother came to see her from Wenzhou and felt the extremely cold weather that had never been seen in the south. At night, the surroundings of the studio were pitch black and there were no street lights. She couldn&#39;t help shouting: Daughter! What kind of sin have you suffered here? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/XgzliM17Uhji4QMm2nlJC71KUgC9DGMrnP5WQ8VH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;738&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/XgzliM17Uhji4QMm2nlJC71KUgC9DGMrnP5WQ8VH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Once upon a time&quot; Acrylic on canvas, 205cmx158cm, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A painting can be painted this way, or it can be painted that way&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mother He was probably the first person to provide artistic support to Sun Yidian. When she was a child, her parents enrolled her in many interest classes. She was the child who cried when she saw she was about to play the piano, but she was very active in painting. She started studying painting at the age of 4. When she was in elementary school, her parents let her attend Wenzhou Youth Art School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other provinces in China, this kind of professional art school for primary school students is extremely rare, which corresponds to the strong demand for folk art education in the southeastern coast. These primary school students are cultivated by an almost omnipotent art concept. They have to learn Chinese painting as well as Western painting. Sketching, coloring, and sketching are all necessary basic skills. They have to go to the countryside to sketch, and they have to hand in calligraphy homework every week. &quot;Our primary school has actually trained many people. For example, the Asian Games torch was designed by our seniors, including architects and artists currently active in Zhejiang. If you ask, many of them came from this primary school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the art circle, it is very strange to praise a person with &quot;top student&quot;, but Sun Yidian has indeed been a top student all the way. Her elementary school does not relax its requirements for cultural courses just because it majors in art. Many students will later go to ordinary middle schools and comprehensive universities, and not all of them may be bent on becoming art students. Sun Yidian was admitted to Wenzhou Middle School, the best local high school, but at the same time, she also received admission notices from the National High School Affiliated to the National Academy of Arts and the Central American High School Affiliated to the Art Examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tlKnhoKUFJ4monMgkf7h5D6BTlFtFh8FzkurTiM0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tlKnhoKUFJ4monMgkf7h5D6BTlFtFh8FzkurTiM0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Simple Shed&quot; watercolor on paper, 25.3cmx19.1cm, 2009&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She chose the High School Affiliated to Central Academy of Fine Arts because she could go to Beijing and legitimately &quot;leave&quot; Parents stay away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Sun Yidian, the High School Affiliated to Central Academy of Fine Arts is a free and magical place. She seemed to be suddenly opened up to a whole new world and new senses to match it. She is still amazed that she watched so many niche movies and so many esoteric books that were inappropriate for her age when she was in the attached middle school. &quot;There are many big boring movies that I can&#39;t stand now, but I actually watched them wholeheartedly at that time. Many of them In fact, I only know a little about philosophy books, so I just read them hard to pretend to be cool. People around me don’t listen to pop music. They all listen to very literary and niche things to show that they are different.” In the attached middle school, not being mainstream is a kind of mainstream. These hard-to-eat nutrients have unknowingly become part of her background. “The biggest inspiration for my art is that I am willing to try anything and be interested in everything. After a person is suddenly opened up at that age, he realizes , It turns out that a painting can be done this way or that way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She still keeps a collection of sketches from when she was in the attached middle school. At that time, she had to submit a large number of sketches every week, and the teacher would write on the handed-in homework. The stamp indicates that it has been read, preventing students from submitting previous works for submission. In order to catch up on the huge amount of homework, they would go to Beijing Railway Station to stay up all night and paint the passengers who stayed at the station overnight. Foreigners from all over the world come in all shapes and sizes, and they don&#39;t move even after falling asleep due to fatigue. They are ready-made models at your fingertips. When she returned home during the summer vacation, while her mother was taking a bath, she was doing sketches of human figures. Her mother calmly let her do the painting without any hesitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from the High School Affiliated to the Central Academy of Fine Arts, she was recommended to the Central Academy of Fine Arts. Her college entrance examination scores in cultural subjects were surprisingly high among art students. After graduating from Central America, he was directly recommended to graduate school at Central America. Sun Yidian said that she is the kind of person with strong self-motivation, and her academic career is just &quot;going with the flow&quot;. It was also out of self-consciousness that after working as an artist for several years, she went to Tsinghua University to study for a Ph.D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BGK6BCcuRR8Ks5wz3wSVfM4ulvO5VlLwx2jScva5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BGK6BCcuRR8Ks5wz3wSVfM4ulvO5VlLwx2jScva5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ken&quot; acrylic on wood, 45.5cmx38cm, 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Natural objects and man-made objects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian is well-known and has the best market performance The series is &quot;artificial objects&quot;, and most of the pictures are inflatable or plastic toys, but she also has a secret &quot;natural objects&quot; series, which she started to create when she was 16 years old, a series oriented &quot;from the deep&quot;, including flowers and fruits. , mountains, rivers, and trees have all become the objects of her gaze and representation. But the &quot;natural objects&quot; have never been exhibited. Sun Yidian hangs them on the wall of his studio, like a private archive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Man-made objects&quot; are dazzling floats above the water, and &quot;natural objects&quot; are like anchors underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people came to my studio and liked the &#39;Natural Objects&#39; series. Last time a sister came over and said that this group of small paintings made her cry.&quot; She incorporated a lot of elements into this series. For media experiments, I like to use some children’s handmade materials, such as a kind of baby foam beads called “pearl mud”, which can be used for shaping and is also a common raw material in toy factories. Later, I discovered a Japanese paper pulp clay that has excellent modeling power and durability, and can create a spatial effect similar to a bas-relief on the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/RSyN0FWPkp9junVXBGZKFsIqxs7A2MxJSf78DO2v.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/RSyN0FWPkp9junVXBGZKFsIqxs7A2MxJSf78DO2v.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Let Me Hug&quot; Acrylic on canvas, 200cmx133cm, 2015&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Artificial Objects&quot; series made her famous in one fell swoop. The smooth, plump, grotesque and falsely sweet toys she draws have won her a steady stream of attention and collectors, and their prices have skyrocketed. As a child in Wenzhou, her childhood memories are all kinds of man-made objects. &quot;When I was a kid, when we said we were going to play at a classmate&#39;s house, what we actually meant was: go play in your family&#39;s factory.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost every household has a factory, including a shoe factory. , glasses factory, plastic products factory, lighter factory... Occasionally there are toy factories. There are not many toy factories, but the visual impact on a child is huge. These small commodity factories all retain a simple production layout. The factory building often has several bedrooms attached. The home is also the same as the factory. After the reform and opening up, materials, and the production brought about by materials, sprouted up everywhere in Wenzhou like bamboo shoots after a rain. What’s interesting is that her international collectors are also very sympathetic to these things she painted. They told Sun Yidian: The era when the artificial objects you painted suddenly exploded in abundance, maybe the 1990s in China. But in Europe and the United States, it was our 1960s. It is precisely because of this that they feel the same complex flavor of nostalgia and reflection in Sun Yidian&#39;s paintings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of commonality is not uncommon in Sun Yidian’s paintings, like a hidden cultural code. She paints huge idols. Their appearance and facial features are common in Western pop culture. However, the curved eyebrows and single eyelids come from traditional Chinese painting. The angle of the lips, which seems to be smiling but not smiling, is her classic image based on Buddhist sculptures. drawn. This image appears on the exhibition wall, facing the viewer in a overlooking manner. Regardless of whether the viewer is an Easterner or a Westerner, they will be slightly stunned and realize that something seems wrong in a sense of déjà vu. The &quot;Porcelain Mother&quot; she painted is a small white porcelain statue with hands clasped together, standing silently among the roots of the trees. This is a common porcelain Madonna ornament in Western families, but strangely, it also Much like the Dehua white porcelain Guanyin worshiped in Chinese homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian said that in her hometown, the belief system is complex. When she was a child, her family worshiped Buddha and worshiped Guanyin all year round. However, when she came to her uncle&#39;s house, he believed in Catholicism and kept a statue of the Virgin Mary in his home. As a child, she often felt confused. In her eyes, there was no essential difference between the kind and compassionate female faces. The localization of handicrafts has deepened this aesthetic mutual reference. A priest often came and went from her uncle&#39;s house. Apart from his detached and indifferent expression, she could not see any difference between the priest and ordinary neighbors. The same goes for the local church, which is European in form but with a strong Chinese decoration style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is keen to examine these common clues in different cultures out of curiosity about images. She painted Medusa and looked through Caravaggio and other classic paintings in the album. The snakes on Medusa&#39;s head were all live snakes. The artist had to focus on painting the twisting and entangled violence, lifelike, that is culture. Classic output to her symbols. In her private memory, Medusa only saw the logo on her mother&#39;s Versace bag when she was a child. She was surprised at that time. Why use the head of a strange woman as a label? In order to draw her own Medusa, she bought a bunch of rubber and plastic coiled snakes online as a reference. Their ferocity and beauty were just a bluff - &quot;I just wanted to draw them all as fake snakes, realistic fake ones.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her workbench is filled with these artificial toys, which have also become the prototypes in her paintings: original Barbie, pirated Barbie, Ken with his head ripped off, naked Ken... The first time she drew Ken with only a head, she shocked everyone and triggered a big discussion including hot words such as &quot;feminism&quot;, &quot;female revenge&quot;, &quot;consumer men&quot;, and &quot;female reverse gaze&quot;, but she Frankly speaking, I painted my friend as Ken just for visual reasons, which is like playing house on the canvas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/88ewe2kyK2hNwTUJjLor3sygbg00B5xHTLl3i9k8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;956&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/88ewe2kyK2hNwTUJjLor3sygbg00B5xHTLl3i9k8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Evening&quot; wood board composite material, 20cmx20cm, 2016&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The world is seven centimeters shorter&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian has always been interested in gender issues All are there. When she was in college, she asked acquaintances in her hometown to let her go to the obstetrics and gynecology hospital to observe women giving birth. It was the largest obstetrics and gynecology hospital in Wenzhou and the place where she was born. She saw groups of women rolling and moaning on the delivery bed. Their faces were blurred, and all their female characteristics were hidden. What mattered was the huge bulge in the middle of the body and the birth canal that was about to burst, as if that was their only thing at the moment. Biological attributes, their common identity and destiny. She turned this feeling into a series of works, titled &quot;Coming Soon.&quot; That year, she was 22 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;coming&quot; may be new life, or the adult life she is about to enter. But for Sun Yidian, &quot;coming soon&quot; is more like a moment in nature, &quot;In my hometown, there are many thunderstorms in the south, the kind of heavy rainstorms that suddenly fall, and the sky is so dark that the day seems like night, The raindrops were huge, pouring, and then there was lightning and thunder. I have many such memories when I was a child. I stood under the window of my house and looked at the heavy rain outside. The sky suddenly lightened up, and then there was a burst of thunder from the distance. . My &#39;coming soon&#39; is the moment when the lightning has flashed and the thunder has not yet come. I am nervous and scared, but I am also looking forward to that moment coming.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She did not explain her scene, no matter how It’s up to the viewers to draw their own interpretations, whether it’s gender issues, pop culture issues, material issues, consumerism issues... She is at ease with everything. Just like her painting &quot;Porcelain Mother&quot;, those who believe in Guanyin see Guanyin and the Mother of God. What the viewer sees is the Virgin. She believes that any viewing will first reflect the viewer’s cultural memory and information reserve, rather than the creator’s intention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As her doctoral thesis was about to be started, Wang Minan suggested that she write about consumerism. The implication was that it was related to the topic she drew, and it would be easier for her to gain insights when writing. She also thought it was reasonable. She is just worried that her logical ability is not strong - the academic construction of writing a paper and the picture composition that she is so familiar with are completely different things. Teacher Wang sometimes asks her from the perspective of &quot;consumption&quot;: I heard that one of your paintings has sold for millions? She was so frightened that she only waved her hands: Teacher, teacher, let’s never talk about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UfQY7vrtFQzxgrxEuiFVap805CGeMwvUOhSpJIQB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UfQY7vrtFQzxgrxEuiFVap805CGeMwvUOhSpJIQB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《瓷母》木板丙烯，54cm x 45cm，2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张爱玲说，成名要趁早。孙一钿举双手赞成，但她的理由跟张爱玲并不一样。她担心的并不是成功来得太晚，导致滋味不够甜美，而是她相信，年少成名可以让人获得一种可贵的松弛感，可以更加从容舒展地去做艺术。那些被命运折磨得太久、百般挣扎都难以胜出的艺术家，有时不免被成功的渴望和生存压力扭曲，导致动作变形，做出匪夷所思的选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我只有第一次展览卖画的所得对我是有意义的，因为那意味着我可以自己养活自己，成为一名独立艺术家。在那之前，我一直都在跟父母打预防针，要他们做好我可能毕业后没工作、不得不回家啃老的心理准备，那笔钱给了我极大的自由。来自金钱的快乐就到此为止了。那之后卖出的任何高价，对我来说都只是一个数字而已。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她天然地意识到，她这一代的女性艺术家，但凡在事业上取得一点进步，就必然要替全体女性发声。 “女性艺术家加上年少成名，别人很容易就会说：是不是因为你的容貌？是不是你背后有什么人在帮你抬价格？”女性不可能仅凭实力就取得成功吗？承认女性优秀很难吗？孙一钿的回击之道，就是用更全面的自我强大令他们闭嘴，这是从小到大一路当优等生建立起来的自信，也是她重返校园读博的动力之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她工作室墙上钉着的诸多草稿中，有几幅充满力量感的高跟鞋小稿，猩红色高跟鞋的鞋头并在一起，跟分立两侧的鞋跟拼成一副女性骨盆的形状。孙一钿一直记得少女时代读过的某个台湾男诗人的诗，写的是女孩子脚蹬高跟鞋时的感受——“世界矮了七厘米”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙一钿身高1米72，踩上7厘米的人造高跟鞋，比很多男性都高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一个矮了七厘米的世界里，她继续向前走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（图片致谢艺术家、BANK画廊和施博尔画廊柏林/巴黎/首尔、余德耀美术馆）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“潇湘”作为地名传进日本，竟然是因为一位禅宗大画家的加持？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Not long ago, I had a gathering with two old friends. During the dinner, I accidentally talked about the misfortune of Nie Er, the composer of &quot;March of the Volunteers&quot; The place of drowning - the coast of Shonan in Fujisawa Prefecture, Japan. Wang Zhongyi, the editor-in-chief of &quot;People&#39;s China&quot; magazine, asked me about the relationship between Shonan and Naito Hunan and Hunan Province. I knew what was going on but didn&#39;t know why. I was questioned on the spot. So, after returning home and doing some homework, I came up with this fake &quot;place name test&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iAnaBLpu5DQSiWI3mbKe9wYDfzszNsGMp2b7u9wI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;891&quot; height= &quot;1185&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iAnaBLpu5DQSiWI3mbKe9wYDfzszNsGMp2b7u9wI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese Sinologist Naito Konan (1866-1934). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about the latter first. The relationship between Naito Hunan and Hunan Province is simple, so simple that there is no half-cent relationship. Naito&#39;s halo as a sinologist is so dazzling that when Chinese people talk about this legendary figure, they often make associations: the &quot;Hunan&quot; in Naito&#39;s name must have been &quot;taken&quot; from Hunan Province, and is intentionally or unintentionally reminiscent of When it comes to the &quot;theory of cultural center movement&quot; and the &quot;theory of changes in the Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;, it seems that if you don&#39;t even &quot;roll&quot; your name, you can&#39;t be called a great scholar. However, Japanese intellectuals are mostly limited by the concept of regionalism and take it for granted. Since he is a leader of the Kyoto School, the name &quot;Hunan&quot; must come from Hunan City in Shiga Prefecture adjacent to Kyoto Prefecture, but this lake is not Dongting Lake, but Lake Biwa. In fact, neither of these two arguments is correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Naito Hunan&#39;s name is Tiger Jiro, whose courtesy name is Bingqing and whose nickname is Hunan. In 1866, he was born in Mamauchi Village, Mutsu Province (now Mamauchi, Towada, Shikaku City, Akita Prefecture). Shikaku is located at the northernmost tip of Akita Prefecture, separated from Aomori Prefecture by the boundary lake &quot;Lake Towada&quot;. &quot;Hunan&quot; means the south of Lake Towada. Lake Towada is a double volcanic lake formed by the eruption of the Towada volcano. It has beautiful scenery and is a famous lake in the Tohoku region. It is listed as a &quot;National Cultural Property&quot; as a special scenic spot. In the National Diet Building in the center of Tokyo, huge oil paintings depicting the four seasons of the Japanese archipelago hang on the walls surrounding the central hall. Among them, the summer work is &quot;Lake Towada and Oirase&quot; painted by Tanaka Giichi. In this way, due to the influence of Naito&#39;s Hunan and Kyoto schools, Hunan Province, which was originally out of reach, was forced to be disconnected. Even Hunan City, Shiga Prefecture, which had nothing to do with it, was attached to some kind of connection with Naito, and Naito Lake Towada, my hometown where I grew up, is not mentioned by the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Wvjin72u69Lnqd8pGj5ChHbXG2N2MlN21dU2dMKS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height= &quot;403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Wvjin72u69Lnqd8pGj5ChHbXG2N2MlN21dU2dMKS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The oil painting &quot;Lake Towada and Oirase&quot; hanging in the central hall of the Japanese Diet Building. Oirase is a river flowing from Lake Towada. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about the former. There is actually no definite conclusion about the connection between Shonan and Hunan Province. Although the interpretation of &quot;Southern Hunan&quot; in &quot;Guangciyuan&quot; (fifth edition) refers to it, it is not clear: ① The name of the scenic spot south of the Xiangjiang River that flows into Dongting Lake in Hunan Province, China. ② The &quot;Sōnan&quot; in the southern part of the ancient Sagami Kingdom was appended to ① and written as &quot;Shonan&quot; as the name for the coastal area of ​​Sagami Bay. That area includes Hayama, Zushi, Kamakura, Chigasaki and other areas. There are many bathing beaches in the summer, making it a summer resort for Keihin. The winter is relatively warm. It is widely developed as residential land. For example, &quot;Shonan Electric Railway&quot; is the general name of the old national railways that connect Tokyo and Numazu (Shizuoka Prefecture) over a medium distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through this explanation, we understand that without Hunan in China, there would be no Shonan in Japan. The next question is: when and how did this spatial &quot;link&quot; occur? In Japan, the expression &quot;Shonan&quot; was first seen in the dictionary &quot;Wa Ming Le Ju Chao&quot; (referred to as &quot;Wa Ming Chao&quot; or &quot;Wa Ming Chao&quot;) in the middle of the Heian period. The etymology is Shonan County, Changsha State. According to the explanation of &quot;Zizhi Tongjian Dictionary&quot; (Jilin People&#39;s Publishing House, 1994): Xiangnan County was &quot;established in the Western Han Dynasty, and its administrative location is southwest of Xiangtan City, Hunan Province. It was changed to the Marquis of Xiangnan in the Eastern Han Dynasty. In the Three Kingdoms, Wu restored it to Xiangnan County. The Southern Dynasties Waste all.&quot; However, &quot;Shonan&quot; in &quot;Japanese Names&quot; is still a simple ancient Chinese place name and is not equivalent to &quot;Shonan&quot; in Japan today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various evidence shows that the real &quot;crossing of the border&quot; in southern Hunan is related to Zen Buddhism. Mr. Ge Zhaoguang mentioned in &quot;The History of Chinese Zen Thought&quot; that Southern Zen is divided into two branches geographically, and the second branch is the &quot;Zen master group centered on Jingzhou and Hengyue&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, Fa Nao and Fa Ren of Jingzhou Emperor Temple, Fa Jing and Zhiyuan of Changsha Temple, Fa Cong of Xiangyang Jingkong Temple, Lushan Fa Chong wait. Of course, the most important thing is Huisi (515-577) who first went to Daesu Mountain in Gwangju and then to Hengyue, and opened the later Tiantai line. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tiantai Sect is the sect that has had a decisive influence on Japanese Buddhism and Zen Buddhism. In 804 AD, Zen Master Saicho went to the Tang Dynasty to study Dharma as an envoy to the Tang Dynasty. After returning to China the following year, he taught Dharma at the Enryaku Temple on Mount Hiei (also known as Mount Tiantai), and then founded the Tendai Sect of Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Muxi Fachang, a painting monk from the late Song Dynasty to the early Yuan Dynasty (Fachang is the Buddhist name, his birth and death dates are unknown), practiced Zen under the famous monk Wu Zhun when he was young, and later became the founder of Liutong Temple in West Lake. At the end of the Kamakura period (14th century), his paintings flowed into Japan in batches following the exchanges between Chinese and Japanese Zen masters, and they were immediately enthusiastically sought after by the upper class. The technique of using ink halos and a large amount of white space to express the beauty of the universe is superb and sophisticated. It is the &quot;symbol of the literati&#39;s longing for an utopia of natural mountains and rivers&quot; in the eyes of the Japanese (Japanese scholar Yuji Yamashita said), and it has also profoundly influenced Japan. of southern painting. The great Japanese painting masters of the Momoyama period, Hasegawa Tōhoku, Omotaya Sotatsu and others, all sought the foundation of ink painting techniques from Makiki&#39;s paintings; there are also many works that imitated Makiki in the Kano School of art. Muxi&#39;s paintings are the objects of collection by Japanese ministers, daimyo and wealthy businessmen. They are national treasures among national treasures. For example, in the &quot;Catalog of Imperial Paintings&quot;, a record of the painting treasures collected by the Ashikaga family of the Muromachi shogunate, of the total 280 pieces in the collection, Makixi&#39;s works accounted for 30%, as many as 103 pieces. In Japanese documents from the mid-14th century, if only &quot;monk&quot; is written, it is an honorific title for Muxi. Muxi&#39;s paintings are almost extinct in China (only the National Palace Museum and the National Palace Museum in Taipei hold one each). It is said that 134 paintings exist in Japan, all of which are stored in the treasure collections of the Cabinet Office for Culture and the country&#39;s first-class art museums. The &quot;ceiling&quot; of Mu Xi&#39;s work is generally recognized as &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot;. Seven of the eight volumes are in Japan. The location of the remaining volume, &quot;Yamaichi Seiran&quot;, is still unknown and a copy is preserved in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Cpej7mByBiUAd7Aqq2Ejiw6c3nmf2eEu7a3P27DL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;3197&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Cpej7mByBiUAd7Aqq2Ejiw6c3nmf2eEu7a3P27DL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fishing Village Sunset&quot; from Muxi Fachang&#39;s &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;Xiaoxiang&quot;, the definition of &quot;Cihai&quot; is: ①Another name for the Xiangjiang River, because the water of the Xiangjiang River is clear Well-earned reputation. &quot;The Book of Mountains and Seas·Zhongshan Jing&quot;: &quot;The abyss of the Xiaoxiang River.&quot; &quot;The Book of Xiangzhong&quot;: &quot;The clear light of the Xiangchuan River is five or six feet long, which is the name of Xiaoxiang.&quot; Or it may specifically refer to the section after the middle reaches of the Xiangjiang River meets the Xiaoshui River. That is one of the &quot;Three Hunans&quot;. ②Refers generally to the Hunan region. Zheng Gu&#39;s poem &quot;Farewell to Friends on Huaishang&quot;: &quot;Several bagpipes left the pavilion at night, you went to Xiaoxiang and I went to Qin.&quot; ③The name of the ancient town. It was placed in the Five Dynasties in the northwest of Yongzhou City, Hunan Province. It is named because it is the confluence of Xiaoxiang River and Xiangkou Pass; it is also called Xiaoxiang Pass or Xiangkou Pass. Accordingly, as the name suggests, the &quot;Eight Scenic Spots of Xiaoxiang&quot; refer to the eight scenic spots from the north along the Xiangjiang River to Dongting Lake after the Xiangjiang River merges into the Xiaoshui River. Since the Northern Song Dynasty, some painters have used it as a theme to create works, expressing their feelings for the landscape. The &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot; has almost become an artistic paradigm. Famous ones include the scroll of the same name by Song Di, which was later written down by Shen Kuo in &quot;Mengxi Bi Tan&quot;, including Fan Return from Yuanpu, Falling Geese on Pingsha, Evening Bell of Yansi Temple, Qinglan in Mountain City, Dusk Snow in River Sky, Autumn Moon in Dongting, Sunset in Fishing Village, Xiaoxiang Night Talk - the name of &quot;Eight Scenes&quot;, has since &quot;out of the circle&quot;. However, compared with the works of Song Di and others, the Japanese clearly prefer Mu Xi. As for the reason, the philosopher Han Bingzhe believes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mu Xi&#39;s &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot; inspired by Zen Buddhism is also &quot; The picture of &quot;empty&quot;, the pen and ink are simple and subtle, there is nothingness, the artistic conception is mysterious, a few scenes are hidden in the infinite white space, the careful brushwork makes the objects float between reality and virtuality, black and white, and there is no way to express it. meaning. Objects and images are integrated and dependent on each other, reflecting each other instead of driving away or dividing each other. Sora seems to have become a friendly intermediary. Water lives, mountains flow, heaven and earth unite. The emptiness and silence do not obliterate the still life in the painting, but reflect the elegance of the still life. (&quot;Zen Philosophy&quot;, page 35)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, from the Kamakura period to the Edo period, from the Ashikaga Shogun family (Ashikaga Yoshimitsu, Yoshimasa) to Oda Nobunaga, Toyotomi Hideyoshi, from the Tokugawa Shogun family (Tokugawa Ieyasu, Yoshimune) to Matsudaira Fumo and Murata Shuguang, Muxi&#39;s &quot;Eight Views of Xiaoxiang&quot; has been circulated among these figures, and its value can no longer be evaluated in terms of money. The Japanese really love the &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot; so much that they can&#39;t wait to move them to Japan. Sure enough, later the Japanese &quot;discovered&quot; the &quot;Eight Views of Kanazawa&quot; in the area of ​​Rokuura Village in Musashi Kunakurajo County (today&#39;s Kanazawa Eight Views Station of the Keihin Express Railway) - the whole is a &quot;Hako Garden&quot; version of the &quot;Eight Views of Xiaoxiang&quot; . The wonderful thing is that every scenic spot corresponds to the original scenery of Xiaoxiang, and it was adapted into Ukiyo-e paintings by Utagawa Hiroshige, including &quot;The Return of the Sailing Ship&quot;, &quot;The Falling Geese&quot;, &quot;The Evening Bell&quot;, &quot;Susaki Haru&quot; &quot;Arashi&quot;, &quot;Twilight Snow on Uchigawa&quot;, &quot;Seto Autumn Moon&quot;, &quot;Sunset on Noshima&quot; and &quot;Koizumi&#39;s Night Voice&quot;, a total of eight paintings. In the 7th year of Yuanlu (1694), Zen Master Donggao Xinyue, who fled to Japan from the Ming Dynasty, wrote a Chinese poem for each of the &quot;Eight Scenes of Kanze&quot;. With the endorsement of the seven-character quatrains of the Chinese great scholar, Kanze was like Xiaoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that in the early Edo period, the monk Sawuan began to call the Enoshima area &quot;Shonan&quot;. During the same period, Chongxue, a descendant of the Chinese who immigrated to Japan from China during the Muromachi period and an expectorant medicine merchant in Odawara, built a stone tablet at the Oiso nunnery, on which he engraved the seven words &quot;The end of the Qing Dynasty in southern Hunan&quot;. This monument still exists today and is regarded as the beginning of place names in southern Hunan. Before modern times, Sinology was always a prominent school in Japan. Therefore, whether it was due to a certain literary taste or arty elegance, there were many Zen monks and poets who used &quot;Shonan&quot; as their nickname, such as the Zen monk Shonan Tong, the poet Okubo Shonan, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the opening of the Shonan Electric Railway, the area known as &quot;Shonan&quot; further expanded, and even the Miura Peninsula was included in its division. In May of the 29th year of Meiji (1896), Tokutomi Soho bought a villa on the Zushi Seaside for his parents, and then handed over the task of taking care of the two elders to his younger brother Tokutomi Akasha, and he embarked on a journey around the world. At that time, Luhua was physically and mentally exhausted and tired of the dissolute life. She decided to temporarily go to her parents&#39; villa to live in seclusion while thinking about her future. He wrote in a letter to his brother: &quot;The air in Tokyo is too cold for me. I want to live in Shonan for some time.&quot; At that time, Shonan had become a residential area for the upper class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also at about the same time, Natsume Soseki and Suzuki Daijo each practiced Zen under Enkaku-ji Temple in Kita-Kamakura with the Zen master Shaksumi. Soseki practiced Zen for self-healing, while Dachu practiced Zen for the purpose of learning the Dharma. Time and space intersect, the two have neither the same purpose nor have they met. Since the Kamakura shogunate era, the shogunate rulers have been protected by the clan, and Zen Buddhism has been able to live and develop here. After five centuries of development, by the time Soseki and Daijo practiced Zen, it had become a grand sight. Kamakura, an ancient temple, was lined with many The ancient city, which is full of Zen, has also become a true &quot;Mecca&quot; of Zen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, from the &quot;Eight Scenes of Xiaoxiang&quot; by Muxi Fachang to the &quot;Eight Scenes of Kanze&quot;, from monk Ze&#39;an to the Chinese Zen master who fled eastward, it can be said that it is precisely because of the blessing of Zen Buddhism that This long and narrow coastal area, centered on Enoshima and extending east and west along Sagami Bay, has changed from the ancient place name &quot;Sōnan&quot; to the &quot;Shonan&quot; in the eyes of the world today. It has a unique atmosphere that is completely different from other regions. Romantic style. For example, if people living in the metropolitan area drive a car with a &quot;Shonan&quot; license plate on National Highway 134 on weekends, even if it is just an ordinary light motor vehicle, it is still a cool thing. Its &quot;gold content&quot; even surpasses the high-end residential area &quot;Shinagawa&quot; in Tokyo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Original title &quot;Where is Southern Hunan&quot;, the current title was proposed by the editor)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>