<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[借转融通“绕道减持”的不只高瓴，沪深交易所紧急打补丁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 8 and November 10, 2023, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued multiple Guidelines for self-regulation. Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/426cfe432f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/426cfe432f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 8 and November 10, 2023, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued a number of self-regulatory guidelines. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The well-known investment institution Hillhouse Capital staged &quot;disappearing shares&quot; in A-shares, citing the China Securities Regulatory Commission to initiate an investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, 2023, LONGi Green Energy (601012.SH) announced that it was suspected of violating restrictive regulations by transferring LONGi Green Energy shares. In accordance with the Penalty Law and other laws and regulations, the China Securities Regulatory Commission decided to file a case against HHLR Management Co., Ltd., a shareholder of Longi Green Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;HHLR Management Co., Ltd.-China Value Fund (hereinafter referred to as HHLR) is an investment management company under Hillhouse Capital focusing on the secondary market. It was formerly known as Hillhouse Capital Management Co., Ltd.-China Value Fund Trading (hereinafter referred to as Hillhouse Asset Management). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March, HHLR, the major shareholder holding 5.85% of Longi Green Energy, lent 1% of its shares through two refinancings. However, after the maturity and return, HHLR’s shareholding dropped by 0.87% compared with before the loan. gap. The market suspects that HHLR reduced its holdings during the refinancing period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not only HHLR, but also many shareholders of listed companies have quietly reduced their shareholdings to less than 5% after refinancing. It’s just that Hillhouse Capital, as a star investment institution, has attracted a lot of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regulatory response was rapid. On November 8 and 10, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges issued a number of self-regulatory guidelines aimed at patching the above vulnerabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Disappeared Shares&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;HHLR&#39;s shares were originally transferred from LONGi Green Energy&#39;s major shareholders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 19, 2020, Li Chunan, the major shareholder of Longi Green Energy, transferred 6% of his shares to Hillhouse Asset Management at a price of 70 yuan per share. The total transaction consideration was approximately 15.84 billion yuan. . Li Chunan is the concerted person acting in concert with the actual controllers of LONGi Co., Ltd. Li Zhenguo and Li Xiyan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the alumni news of Lanzhou University, LONGi Green Energy was co-founded by three classmates from the physics department of Lanzhou University in 1986 - Li Zhenguo, Zhong Baoshen, and Li Chunan. It was named after the old president Jiang Longji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the first trading day after the transfer announcement, LONGi Green Energy opened sharply and closed at the daily limit. Subsequently, LONGi redeemed its convertible bonds, the total share capital increased, and Hillhouse Asset Management&#39;s shareholding was diluted to 5.85%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 21, 2023, Longi Green Energy issued the &quot;Informative Announcement Regarding Shareholders&#39; Participation in the Refinancing Securities Lending Business and Equity Changes&quot;, stating that the renamed Hillhouse Asset Management, or HHLR, participated in the refinancing. Rongtong Securities Lending Business lends 0.85% of its shares with a term of 182 days. It plans to continue lending no more than 0.15% of its shares in the next 90 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Margin financing is when investors ask brokers to borrow money to buy stocks or borrow stocks to sell. However, brokers’ own funds and securities sources are limited, so refinancing has emerged, including refinancing and refinancing. Vouchers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The refinancing business in mainland China began in 2013. China Securities Finance Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as CSI Financial), as the counterparty to securities lending transactions, is the only domestic financial institution engaged in refinancing business. Its shareholders include the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, refinancing business means that CSI Financial lends its own funds or funds raised through the issuance of bonds to securities companies, and then the securities companies lend it to customers for them to buy and list. Company stock. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Securities refinancing business means that CSI Financial borrows securities from &quot;lenders&quot; such as shareholders of listed companies, and then refinances them to securities companies, which provide them to customers for sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the securities refinancing business that Hillhouse Asset Management participates in, CSI Financial first borrows circulating securities from the shareholders of Longi Green Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Longi Green Energy did not disclose the specific time for lending 0.15% of HHLR shares. However, its first quarter report for 2023 shows that HHLR’s shareholding has dropped to 4.85%, which means that HHLR participated in two refinancings within 10 days at the end of March. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also not disclosed when the shares loaned by HHLR will expire. Based on the time of its participation in refinancing and the 182-day lending period, it can be inferred that the 1% of shares lent by HHLR should be returned no later than September 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, LONGi Green Energy’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that HHLR’s shareholding is only 4.98%, which is 0.87% lower than the 5.89% shareholding before participating in refinancing. HHLR also did not disclose the reasons why its holdings decreased during the period when the shares were loaned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Disclosure of Listed Companies&quot; and other relevant regulations, when shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares change, they should proactively inform the board of directors of the listed company and cooperate with the listed company in fulfilling its information disclosure obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, LONGi Green Energy stated in the relevant announcement of HHLR refinancing in March that the shares were not registered under the name of the information disclosure obligor (HHLR) during the loan period, and “after the completion of this equity change, information disclosure The obligor shall no longer be a shareholder holding more than 5% of the shares of the listed company.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market generally believes that HHLR has circumvented the letter disclosure requirements for shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares through refinancing, thus achieving a &quot;detour reduction&quot;. Based on LONGi Green Energy’s current stock price of 23 yuan per share, HHLR has a floating loss of approximately 5.6 billion yuan compared with the time of purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter sent an interview letter to Hillhouse’s official email, asking whether he had reduced his shareholding during the refinancing period, and under which regulations he was determined to no longer hold more than 5% of the shares of Longi Green Energy. Shareholders have not received a reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not an isolated case&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For a long time, the securities lending business developed slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report of the Shanghai Securities Fund Evaluation and Research Center shows that as of April 30, 2020, the balance of margin financing and securities lending was 1.0431 billion yuan, accounting for 2.16% of the circulating market value of A-shares, of which the financing balance was 1.0216 billion yuan. Accounting for 97.9% of the total, insufficient securities sources are one of the main obstacles limiting the development of the securities lending market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to expand the source of securities, in 2019 and 2020, the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges successively included qualified institutional investors such as public funds, social security funds, and insurance funds, as well as strategic investors participating in the issuer’s initial public offering. Include lenders and participate in securities lending on the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued relevant systems for the full implementation of the registration system, and extended the optimization measures for refinancing securities on the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM to the main board, further liberalizing the refinancing business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no express provision, during the period of participation in refinancing, the relevant shares are generally not registered in the name of the lender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of CSI Financial, the refinancing securities lending business does not constitute a substantive securities transfer. If equity distribution occurs during the securities lending period, CSI Financial will compensate the lender in accordance with the business rules. However, CSI Financial Finance does not provide lenders with compensation for voting rights. During the period of securities lending, the number of shares held in the shareholder register will temporarily change and will be restored after the securities lending expires and is withdrawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hillhouse is not an isolated case. This phenomenon frequently occurs in A-shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 5, 2022, Huayi Brothers (300027.SZ) issued an announcement stating that Shenzhen Tencent Computer Systems Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tencent Computer), a shareholder holding 7.942441% of the shares, reduced its holdings through block transactions. 1.942447%, and participated in refinancing lending of 0.999998%. After that, Tencent Computer&#39;s shareholding dropped to 4.999997%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of Huayi Brothers&#39; shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huayi Brothers’ 2022 annual report shows that Tencent Computer’s shareholding has dropped to 1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 11, 2022, Changliang Technology (300348.SZ) announced that the shareholder Shenzhen Tencent Information Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tencent Information) reduced its holdings by 0.78670% through block transactions and transferred Rongtong lent the same share, and its shareholding dropped from 6.57339% to 4.99999%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of Changliang Technology.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changliang Technology’s first quarter report for 2023 shows that Tencent Information’s shareholding dropped to 1.14%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 17, 2023, Guomai Culture (301052.SZ) announced that Zhejiang Bona Film and Television Production Co., Ltd., which holds 6.8756% of the company’s shares, participated in the refinancing and lent 0.8755% of the shares, and passed Large trades reduced holdings by 1.0001%. After the equity change, Bona Film and Television holds 4.9999% of the shares and &quot;is no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of the company&#39;s shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guomai Culture’s 2023 interim report showed that Bona Film and Television’s shareholding was reduced to 4.15%, and by the third quarter report, it was reduced to 3.15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 31, 2023, Yuncong Technology (688327.SH) announced that its shareholder Jiadu Technology (600728.SH), which holds 6.63157% of the shares, reduced its holdings by 0.81579% through block transactions. During the refinancing process, the same share was lent, which reduced its shareholding to 4.99999%, &quot;no longer a shareholder holding more than 5% of the company&#39;s shares.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuncong Technology’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that Jiadu Technology’s shareholding ratio has been reduced to 3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shareholders of the above four companies all &quot;coincidentally&quot; reduced their shareholdings below the 5% letter disclosure red line through refinancing, and then reduced their shareholdings without letter disclosure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Just because there is a precedent does not mean it is right.” According to Wang Jiyue, a senior investment banker, supervision has clear requirements for shareholders to reduce their holdings of more than 5%, and Hillhouse’s approach took advantage of loopholes in the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Emergency patching&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Special treatment can be given to the disclosure rules of equity changes and shareholding reductions involved in securities lending.” Peng Bing, professor of Peking University Law School and securities law expert, told the South A reporter over the weekend explained that lending shares cannot be regarded as a true reduction of holdings because the lent shares will still be returned, so changes in equity should not be regarded as a reduction in equity and can be specifically disclosed as a temporary suspension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the words were spoken, supervision had already patched the loopholes in the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8th and 10th, the Shanghai Stock Exchange, Shenzhen Stock Exchange, Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM all updated the self-regulatory guidelines, mainly revising the information disclosure content of relevant entities participating in refinancing business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the Shanghai Stock Exchange as an example. It issued the &quot;Shanghai Stock Exchange Self-Regulatory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 2 - Business Processing (Revised in November 2023)&quot;, which requires shareholders holding more than 5% of the shares to Clear requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the guidelines, when investors and their concerted parties participate in margin trading, securities lending and refinancing business, the number of shares of the same listed company held by their ordinary securities accounts and customer credit securities accounts shall be the same as the number of shares that have not been lent through refinancing. If the total number of shares of the company returned exceeds 5% of the company&#39;s total share capital, the reduction of the company&#39;s shares shall be subject to the Exchange&#39;s &quot;Detailed Implementation Rules for Share Reductions by Shareholders and Directors, Supervisors and Senior Management Personnel of Listed Companies&quot; and other rules regarding major shareholders. Regulations on reduction of holdings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the number of shares lent by investors through refinancing should also be included in the number of shares when investors reduce their holdings, fundamentally eliminating &quot;detour reduction&quot;. At the same time, the revised rules also prohibit relevant shareholders from participating in short-term trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above guidelines show that shareholders who hold more than 5% of the shares of a listed company, do not directly or indirectly increase or decrease the number of shares they hold, and only participate in the refinancing business to lend and withdraw securities within 6 months, shall not Relevant regulations on short-term trading apply. If the company&#39;s shareholding is less than 5% of the total share capital due to participation in refinancing and lending shares, the relevant regulations on short-term trading shall apply to the purchase and sale of stocks and other equity securities during the lending period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 44 of the Securities Law stipulates that if specific entities such as major shareholders, directors, supervisors and senior management of listed companies and companies listed on the New OTC Market engage in short-term trading activities, the proceeds shall belong to the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above guidelines, the specific situation of shareholders holding 5% of the shares participating in the financing and refinancing business during the reporting period must also be disclosed in the regular report on share changes and shareholder status.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;The specific information includes the name of the shareholder, the number and proportion of shares held at the beginning of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares lent through refinancing at the beginning of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares held at the end of the reporting period, the number and proportion of shares lent through refinancing at the end of the reporting period, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[肺炎支原体感染潜伏期可达4周 专家：不建议自行给孩子吃阿奇霉素]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260514]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission held a press conference today (November 13) and invited relevant experts to introduce my country’s winter respiratory tract Information on disease prevention and control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0fda3637dda984ac42d2e05636fa7ab6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3642&quot; height=&quot;2049&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0fda3637dda984ac42d2e05636fa7ab6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258094&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Respiratory diseases in our country have entered the season of high incidence, and multiple diseases are intertwined&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, said that as winter begins in various places, respiratory diseases have entered the season of high incidence, and many diseases are intertwined. Respiratory diseases are intertwined and superimposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All localities must adhere to the common prevention and treatment of multiple diseases, follow up on key groups such as the elderly, patients with basic diseases, and children, and optimize vaccination services; they must coordinate medical resources, optimize diagnosis and treatment processes, and strengthen outpatient and emergency care, Pediatrics, respiratory departments and other forces are responsible for various medical treatment work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The incubation period of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can be up to 4 weeks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Quan, chief physician of Beijing Children’s Hospital, said that children are a high-risk population for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. Why are children infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae at a higher rate: &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;① Children’s immune systems are underdeveloped, and their specific and non-specific immune functions are not very mature; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;② Mycoplasma pneumoniae itself is highly transmissible and can be transmitted through respiratory droplets or close contact The incubation period of mycoplasma pneumonia infection is relatively long, usually 1 to 4 weeks, with an average of about 3 weeks. The carriage of pathogens Patients and sick people have certain transmissibility, and there are many opportunities for cross-infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is not advisable to give children azithromycin and other drugs by themselves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Quan, chief physician of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said that overall, viruses are still the most common pathogens of children&#39;s respiratory tract infections, and Azithromycin is ineffective and unreasonable against viral infections. In addition, children are young and have underdeveloped organ functions, and drug abuse may cause adverse reactions in children. We would like to remind all parents that children are not smaller versions of adults and should not use medicine at will. They must pay attention to its safety and effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What is the difference between mycoplasma pneumonia and influenza? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui, director of the Beijing Institute of Respiratory Diseases, said that the main clinical manifestations of mycoplasma pneumonia are fever and cough. At the onset of the disease, it manifests as severe paroxysmal irritating dry cough, which may be accompanied by Headache, runny nose, sore throat, earache. Compared with previous years, mycoplasma pneumonia has shown a trend of younger patients this year, but the condition has not been significantly aggravated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Influenza is more common in winter and spring. It starts with fever and upper respiratory tract infection, followed by worsening cough, dyspnea and some signs of the lungs, and even more severe systemic symptoms, including high fever, rapid disease progression, and fatigue. , headache, muscle soreness and other symptoms are more obvious. There are some similarities between the two in imaging. Respiratory specimen testing such as detection of type A or type B epidemiological antigens and nucleic acids can be distinguished. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have respiratory infectious diseases increased this year? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tong Zhaohui, director of the Beijing Institute of Respiratory Diseases, said that in fact, every winter is the season of high incidence of respiratory infections. Common mycoplasma pneumoniae, respiratory viruses, especially influenza viruses are more active than in summer and spring, leading to an obvious increase in the number of infected people. Increase. Current monitoring data shows that my country has entered the influenza season this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the COVID-19 epidemic, due to strict respiratory prevention and control measures, the incidence of acute respiratory diseases such as mycoplasma and influenza has indeed declined. With the normalization of prevention and control, these diseases have returned to their pre-epidemic behavior this year. is normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, combined with the fact that Mycoplasma pneumoniae itself has its own epidemic pattern (cyclical epidemics occur every 3-7 years), mycoplasma pneumonia in children is trending this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;ul>;&lt;/ul>; &lt;h4>;The epidemic situation of new coronavirus infection in my country has shown a fluctuating downward trend recently&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The epidemic situation of new coronavirus infection in my country has recently shown a fluctuating downward trend. Since late August this year, the number of reported cases of new coronavirus infection across the country has been declining for 10 consecutive weeks, and the positive rate of new coronavirus nucleic acid tests in fever clinics and sentinel hospitals across the country has continued to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to scientifically prevent respiratory diseases in daily life? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Dayan, director of the National Influenza Center of the Institute of Viral Diseases of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, said that the most effective and economical way to prevent infectious diseases is vaccination. In addition, we should pay attention to the following points:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Develop a healthy lifestyle, maintain adequate sleep and adequate nutrition , moderate physical exercise. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Develop good personal hygiene habits. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pay attention to keeping the home and workplace environment clean. Open windows regularly indoors for ventilation, and keep warm during the ventilation period. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;High-risk groups such as the elderly, children, and patients with underlying diseases should try to avoid going to crowded public places. &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once respiratory infection symptoms such as fever and cough occur, the patient should rest at home to avoid transmitting the pathogen to other people. &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网络暴力，难以消散的漩涡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260510]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;As of June 2023, the number of Internet users in China has reached 1.079 billion. A survey in early 2022 showed that 38.6% of people in China have suffered varying degrees of online violence on social media. In recent years, many victims of online violence have committed suicide. How to control online violence is a difficult problem that needs to be solved urgently.</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为了快乐挖土，一个考古学家决定去当美食博主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260512]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;What happens when an archaeologist becomes a &quot;foodie&quot;? Zhang Liangren, professor of history at Nanjing University, gave an example. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A meal of soup dumplings in a roadside fly shop can reveal 7,000 years of history: from the pottery age and the Bronze Age kitchen utensils &quot;retort&quot;, From the ancient &quot;steamer&quot; on the kitchen murals of the Eastern Han Dynasty tombs in Henan, to the plum blossom buns in the caves of the Song Dynasty...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A bowl of small wontons can help him interpret the weather of the universe. : &quot;&quot;The Chronicles of Yanjing&quot; says: The shape of husband&#39;s wonton is like a chicken egg, which is quite similar to the chaos of heaven and earth, so it occurs during the winter solstice solar eclipse.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; ​​height=&quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dumplings from the Tang Dynasty&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eating hot pot today? Then it&#39;s time to show real technology - &quot;tell the history of whatever you see&quot;. The professor is not afraid. There was originally a legend of &quot;fried Qin Hui&quot; behind fried dough sticks, and tofu was called &quot;Plough Qi&quot; in Lu You&#39;s poem; &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; not only made Liu Genghong famous, but also recorded the method of making yuba; instant noodles are not a patent of the Japanese , but was &quot;invented&quot; by Yi Bingzhuo, a calligrapher from the Qing Dynasty in my country, who accidentally poured noodles into the oil pan at his mother&#39;s birthday party...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The temptation of delicious food hangs on the taste buds, and these historical knowledge and anecdotes remain in the audience&#39;s memory through Zhang Liangren&#39;s eloquent narration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258067 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Netizens commented that Zhang Liangren looks like the Chinese version of a lonely gourmet&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >; With this &quot;unique skill&quot;, Zhang Liangren gained 38,000 fans and 300,000 likes in just over two months after joining Douyin. He was called &quot;The Lonely Gourmet&quot; that is more suitable for Chinese babies&#39; physiques. This expressed the wish he expressed in the first video: &quot;Break the dimensional wall, take off the cold and mysterious mask of archeology, and let everyone see the lovely and warm inner nature of this subject.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;What people don’t know is that this archaeologist decided to become a food blogger because he could “dig in the soil” happily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. An archaeologist who only loves food&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Graduated from Peking University undergraduate and social studies A postgraduate student of the Academy of Science and Technology went to the University of California, Los Angeles to get a doctorate. He worked as a researcher for many years and later became a professor at Nanjing University. Zhang Liangren devoted his life to archeology: &quot;he can go to the field and write articles.&quot; He not only does Chinese archeology, Also doing world archeology. In his own words: &quot;The total number of countries he has visited and explored could circle the earth.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also Zhang Liangren&#39;s habit to eat wherever he goes. Iranian mutton stew and saffron rice, Russian kebabs, and Siberian grilled fish... all impressed him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258068 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren visited Tajikistan in 2011&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, Zhang Liangren admitted frankly that he is far from being a qualified &quot;foodie&quot;: he enjoys delicious food, but he has not yet reached the point of searching for delicious food. What really guided him to become a food blogger was his love for archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Last year, Zhang Liangren accidentally opened a monograph &quot;Diet in Chinese Culture&quot; from the 1970s. The editor-in-chief of the book, Zhang Guangzhi, is a famous Chinese archaeologist, anthropologist, and Zhang Liangren’s mentor. The whole book provides a panoramic display and interpretation of China&#39;s food culture. From the pre-Qin Dynasty to the Han, Tang, Yuan, Ming and Qing dynasties, how did the characteristics of agricultural society affect the evolution of food on this land? How did Confucian moral concepts and social organization methods determine the Chinese people? cooking and dining habits...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren read more than 400 pages in one breath, as if he saw a new door: he has been doing archaeology for a lifetime, and he has been eating for a lifetime. , but never realized that there was such a close connection between the two. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From then on, eating was no longer just about eating. He could not help but think about it while eating: Why must there be food and rice on the Chinese dining table? &quot;Dual diet&quot;, but Westerners are accustomed to &quot;one plate&quot;? What makes the Chinese form a shared meal system, while Westerners form a divided meal system? When were wheat and tomatoes introduced to China, and how did the stir-fry cooking method come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, food archeology is not a brand-new research topic. It is only because food is perishable and cannot be preserved in the long history, and it is too difficult to excavate that it leads to There are very few people doing relevant research in the global archaeological community, and even fewer in China. But Zhang Liangren decided that he would face the difficulties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Just do it. This year, Zhang Liangren recruited two students to specialize in dietary archeology, hoping to unearth more dietary cultural relics and fill the gaps in archaeological research. Zhang Liangren has always had an academic ideal: to let the world hear the voice of the Chinese archaeological community. &quot;The first is to publish Chinese archeology abroad, and the second is to participate more in international archeology and contribute to world archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For this reason, he has Single-handedly initiated archaeological projects of Sino-Russian and Sino-Iranian cooperation. The Iranian team adopted the European excavation method, digging straight down like a deep well. Zhang Liangren felt that this area was too small and too inefficient, so he persuaded the other party to use the Chinese trench excavation method. The results were remarkable and were not only published in international journals. The paper attracted the attention of academic circles and was visited by members of the Iranian Congress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;How to make cold knowledge more pyrotechnic? Letting more people realize the value of archaeological history is something Zhang Liangren and his friends around him often discuss. In July this year, with the help of several friends, Zhang Liangren opened his own Douyin account and started to explore food stores. Zhang Liangren is responsible for the appearance, and friends are responsible for filming and production. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He made no secret that the reason why he came up with the idea of ​​making short videos was to spread knowledge to the public, and the other original intention was to &quot;expand awareness&quot; and let more people People know the value of archeology and support archaeological research in more ways. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Pour some cold water on young people who want to study archeology&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren The video is full of the fireworks of life and has a sense of history. He picked up a mouthful of duck blood vermicelli soup and said that this vermicelli soup has only a few decades of history, but from a can of duck eggs unearthed from a mound tomb in Jurong, Jiangsu, it can be seen that the tradition of eating waterfowl in Jiangsu dates back to 2,500 years ago. It started years ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also interesting to examine the origin of imitation meat vegetarian food. Emperor Liang Wu of the Han Dynasty issued an &quot;administrative order&quot; requiring monks to stop drinking and eating. The need to be both vegetarian and satisfy one&#39;s cravings led later generations to use their brains and develop meat-like vegetarian food that can mimic meat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the image in the video is humorous and friendly, Zhang Liangren waved his hands and laughed at himself, saying that he is an &quot;old scholar&quot; who spends all day burying his head in old papers and not listening to what is going on outside the window. He is good at academic research, digging soil, and giving lectures; reviewing video scripts and embedding historical knowledge can also be regarded as an extension of his professional skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Only appearing on camera is a big problem: &quot;I am a person who is not good at words, and I cannot speak Mandarin well.&quot; In the first few videos, his eyes were habitually Avoid the camera and look away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But what can stump a true &quot;old scholar&quot;? He began to use his scholarly spirit to make short videos, and specially hired an announcer to train himself to correct his pronunciation, improve his intonation and language rhythm, and practice facing the camera. Now, although he is still a little green and awkward, he can already look directly into the camera, clearly tell the history behind the food, and even make some funny expressions and movements to interact with the imaginary audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The contrast between &quot;old scholar&quot; and various current buzzwords, the fresh combination of historical knowledge and gourmet temptations, and the high-frequency output of updates every two days make the book more interesting. Zhang Liangren became a &quot;top leader&quot; in the archaeological community in just over two months. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But compared with the increased traffic figures, what makes him even more happy is that many ordinary people will leave messages or private messages asking questions related to archeology and history. &quot;More people are interested in We are interested in archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many young students also left messages: Can they take the postgraduate entrance examination for professors? Zhang Liangren will be more cautious towards this type of fans. On the one hand, he is pleased that more young people want to join the archaeological industry; on the other hand, he has to remind them that doing research and popular science are not the same thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258066 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The history of fried dough sticks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren has long noticed , in recent years, with the broadcast of film and television programs such as &quot;I Repair Cultural Relics in the Forbidden City&quot; and &quot;National Treasure&quot;, archeology has gradually entered the public eye. Many of his own students were influenced by these programs and decided to apply for the archeology major. The first lesson he taught these young students was to pour cold water on them: &quot;Break their romantic imagination of archeology - TV programs present the most interesting and accomplished aspects of this subject, but behind the fun and achievements, It is extremely long and hard work. If you can’t stand the loneliness, don’t enter this industry.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, it took Zhang Liangren himself many years to fall in love with archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;870&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258069 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Let more people understand archeology&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When I took the exam When he was in college, he had no idea what his interests were, so he muddleheadedly applied for the Department of Archeology. During his undergraduate and postgraduate years, Zhang Liangren spent his time attending classes, reading materials, and writing papers. It was difficult and boring, just like the public&#39;s stereotype of archeology. It wasn’t until I started to come into contact with a large number of historical materials from all over the world during my PhD studies and participated in field surveys and excavations around the world that I felt the joy of this subject. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The part that he enjoys the most is the most feared &quot;digging&quot; part of archeology: sleeping in the open air, exposed to the sun and rain, under the pressure of scholars Title, doing heavy physical work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I like this kind of life to explore in inaccessible places, bask in the sun, look at the scenery, and breathe fresh air.” Moreover, compared to sitting in the library and studying Archeology can always surprise him with the achievements of predecessors and the first-hand information that is freshly excavated and stained with real historical dust, inspiring him to discover new problems. &quot;I am very excited and not boring at all.&quot;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, after using a basin of cold water to extinguish the romantic imagination of young people, he will use the true connotation of this subject to &quot;warm&quot; them back - after all, he has given This introductory course for freshmen is called &quot;The Archeology of Charm.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Curiosity is the answer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;History The Xianlin campus where the department is located is 20 to 30 kilometers away from downtown Nanjing. After working here for nearly ten years, Zhang Liangren’s life trajectory has never exceeded five kilometers around the campus. He mainly eats in the school cafeteria, and goes out to hang out when friends come. A meal as a supplement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But since he became a food blogger, he &quot;goes to the city to eat delicious food&quot; every day, and has even become a food trendsetter in Nanjing&#39;s archaeological circles. His colleagues always ask questions when they see him. One sentence: Which restaurant have you been to recently? He thought, how could he ignore so many delicious foods in Jinling, the capital of gourmet food? This kind of shop-hopping life seems to be pretty good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This career, which was originally just a means of &quot;saving the country through curves,&quot; now takes up a little more time every week than teaching. He has already begun to make long-term plans: after exploring Nanjing cuisine, he will also explore national cuisine, and then world cuisine; not only cooking food, but also introducing other archaeological related knowledge, such as the two issues of &quot;Three Whitening Tips of the Ancients&quot; and &quot;A 400-degree myopic guide to traveling through ancient times.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258070 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren participated in excavations in Russia in 2019&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One The video shooting session, which initially made him feel uncomfortable, gradually became more comfortable. Only then did he realize that those food programs on TV were all &quot;acted&quot;. &quot;A plate of meat was filmed at different angles for 20 minutes. When you eat it, it&#39;s cold in your mouth, and you have to act like it&#39;s delicious. What about &quot;Journey to the West&quot; &quot;The flat peach eaten by Sun Wukong in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real flat peach, and the bowl of wine Wu Song drank before fighting the tiger in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real bar? In order to stay awake, the actor must have drank water.&quot; He analyzed seriously. , as if he had discovered some incredible truth, which made the young man opposite him laugh. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Originally, he wanted to &quot;facilitate&quot; archeology to the public. Unexpectedly, in the process, the daily life of the public unknowingly entered his pile of old papers, which made this old scholar Got caught up in the fireworks and became a &quot;slash professor&quot; at the age of 58. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Now he can answer the question: What is the connection between archeology and daily life? Zhang Liangren’s answer is: curiosity. Whether it’s archaeology, gourmet food or being a short video blogger, it’s curiosity that pushes him to move forward. This experience can also be extended to other humans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“People are curious and want to know where they come from and where they are going, so everyone likes to go to museums and see ruins and cultural relics. And archeology It provides a kind of tangible history that can be seen directly with the eyes, which is more intuitive than the history presented in words. It is not only a key to the historical truth, but also an entrance to explore the development laws of human society.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nowadays, Zhang Liangren will tell his students that academic issues must be related to things that the people care about. Because there is a lot of fun in the world, and you can get it as long as you are willing to &quot;dig&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“能用的条文总是这么少”，专家呼吁立法解决网暴治理“九龙治水”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The governance of online violence needs to be solved urgently The problem is that the legislation is too fragmented. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the governance of online violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of overly fragmented legislation. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As of June 2023, the number of Internet users in China has reached 1.079 billion. A survey in early 2022 showed that 38.6% of people in China have suffered varying degrees of online violence on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;All cases of cyber violence have one thing in common, that is, they are violent and the consequences are tragic.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, in the &quot;Cyber ​​Violence Rule of Law&quot; Liu Yanhong, dean of the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, said at the seminar. On the forum, some scholars also expressed that they had suffered cyber violence and information intrusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From &quot;Dr. Deyang An committed suicide&quot; and &quot;Rumors were spread about a Hangzhou woman picking up express delivery&quot; to Liu Xuezhou and Zheng Linghua died in unbearable cyber violence, vicious cyber violence incidents have occurred frequently in recent years. Various reports. “When cyber violence occurs, it stings the nerves of us legal professionals, because our first reaction is to quickly search for any provision in the criminal law that can convict people, but we are very surprised to find that the available provision is always So few.&quot; Liu Yanhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Many participating scholars believed that for the governance of cyber violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of over-dispersed legislation, and anti-cyber violence legislation needs to be gradually promoted in a hierarchical manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But on the other hand, some scholars have reminded that the essence of the governance of cyber violence is the governance of speech expression, and the difference between cyber violence and criticism needs to be carefully clarified. boundary. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Not even the criminal law can catch up”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2013 On September 5, 2019, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Illegal Crimes of Cyber ​​Violence in accordance with the Law&quot;, which classified cyber violence for the first time and explained the alleged crimes of different cyber violence behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For example, if the perpetrator of cyber violence creates and spreads rumors on the Internet, derogating others&#39; personality and damaging their reputation, and the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of defamation; Those who publicly insult others by means of wanton abuse, malicious slander, disclosure of privacy, etc., and if the circumstances are serious, shall be convicted of the crime of insult; organize &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and if the circumstances are serious, they shall be convicted of the crime of infringement. Conviction of citizens’ personal information crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong believes that the current judicial interpretation has a narrow definition of cyber violence and pays less attention to cyber intimidation, stalking and bullying. On the other hand, as to whether human flesh search constitutes the crime of infringing on citizens’ personal information, “it needs to reach a certain number and change from quantitative to qualitative changes to constitute a crime. Therefore, it is difficult to determine that a general manual search conducted by multiple people infringes on personal information of citizens. Information crime”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Even the criminal law is unable to catch up.&quot; Liu Yanhong said that in the field of civil adjudication and administrative law enforcement in the field of online violence, this kind of &quot;law does not punish the public&quot; &quot;The tendency remains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of procedures, there is a lack of unified norms and standards for evidence collection in cyber violence cases. Yin Bo, a professor at the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, mentioned that in private prosecution cases of cyber violence Among them, the party’s ability to produce evidence is relatively weak. In order to break down technical barriers, evidence is usually extracted by internal or external professionals under the auspices of the public security or other judicial organs. However, the existing electronic evidence production still lacks technology and methods. &quot; Even the grassroots public security organs do not know how to collect evidence, dare not collect evidence, and cannot collect evidence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On August 3, 2023, the Beijing Internet Court released a number of typical cases involving online violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu is a &quot;big V&quot; blogger with nearly 500,000 Weibo fans. Another Weibo user, Sun, was involved in a dispute over a current affairs issue. Liu had a different view and sent insulting words to Liu through Weibo private messages. Liu posted Sun&#39;s private messages, Weibo account, photos and other information on Weibo, along with insulting remarks, triggering online violence against Sun from netizens. In the end, the court ruled that Liu had infringed the law and deleted the Weibo and comments involved in the case that infringed on Sun&#39;s portrait and reputation. Both parties apologized to each other in writing, and the amount of mental damage compensation was offset by each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong previously wrote that netizens who posted negative comments to insult Sun could have been held liable for civil infringement and administrative liability for disrupting online order, but in the judicial process In law enforcement practice, such acts committed by non-initiators and non-organizers are generally ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the other hand, for the current governance of cyber violence, there are relevant provisions in the Civil Code, Criminal Law, Administrative Penalty Law and other laws and regulations that can be used, but different laws Each has its own value orientation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, the current legislation on the governance of cyber violence is like a flood in Kowloon.&quot; She advocates comprehensive and progressive legislation, such as being first formulated by the State Council. Regulations on the Prevention and Control of Cyber ​​Violence, followed by legislation on the prevention and control of cyber violence, and finally the establishment of an organic law for cyber violence governance agencies, and finally the unified rise to the Anti-Cyber ​​Violence Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Wang Sixin, deputy director of the Research Institute of a Community with a Shared Future for Mankind at Communication University of China, also said that step-by-step legislation is more likely to achieve practical results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;To prevent platform abuse of power&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the seminar, Some scholars also warned that we should be cautious about anti-cyber violence legislation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;The governance of online violence is essentially the governance of speech.&quot; Zhi Zhenfeng, a researcher at the Institute of Law, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that for normal criticism and Supervision and discussion of different opinions should be protected. &quot;Online violence must be controlled, but everyone&#39;s rights to speech and expression must also be protected.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As to how to distinguish normal online criticism from illegal online violence, Shi Jiayou, a professor at Renmin University of China, said that subjectively speaking, online criticism is generally well-intentioned and its purpose is Often it is about safeguarding public interests or one&#39;s own legitimate rights and interests. From an objective point of view, Internet criticism is generally based on basic facts. The facts criticized are generally well-founded or have reasonable information channels, and are not groundless or randomly fabricated; even if the facts confirmed in the end are different from the initial There are discrepancies or partial inaccuracies in the critical remarks, but as long as the critical remarks do have an objective basis as a whole and the critic has reasonable grounds to believe in the authenticity of the facts cited, then the critical remarks should be considered to be a reasonable exercise of freedom of speech. scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, Zhi Zhenfeng emphasized that the focus of combating cyber violence should be organized manipulation of public opinion, “For example, behind cyber thugs and cyber trolls, there are often Organized ones, where one organization can control dozens or millions of accounts at the same time, as well as overseas account matrices involving national security, are all targets that should be targeted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, he believes that as a platform that builds a public opinion space, it has an obligation to maintain the order of the public opinion space. “The platform has technical strength and can intervene through front-end and make samples. Use database modeling and other technologies to control cyber violence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Professor Wang Limei from the Data Law Institute of China University of Political Science and Law added this. She believes that platforms should first improve the real-name system, which can be based on the different natures of the platform and spokespersons. , implement front-end or back-end real-name. Secondly, platforms should set up preventive technical measures so that those who are cyberviolated can trigger the protection mechanism with “one click”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, Zhi Zhenfeng said that it seems that the platform has been imposed obligations, but in fact it has been given power. &quot;Then will the platform abuse this?&quot; Power, to make the already imbalanced power between the platform and users even more imbalanced? I have discovered that some platforms use the banner of supervision to delete posts that they do not like.&quot; He reminded that attention should be paid to preventing platforms from abusing their power and controlling speech. Abnormal market manipulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[犹太人向左，以色列向右：从知识分子幼稚病到游民心态]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out, which also caused shock in the United States. The American intelligentsia has a tradition of sympathizing with Palestine and boycotting Israel. At this time, the mainstream media in the United States basically no longer criticized Israel for retaliation, but instead condemned Hamas as never before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also a few student organizations in American universities that refuse to condemn Hamas and continue to target Israel. In response, many Jewish entrepreneurs announced in a high-profile manner that they would cut off funding for these universities. The influence of wealthy Jewish people and Jewish organizations in the United States far exceeds its population ratio. This is regarded as another example of &quot;Jews exerting the power of money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current Israeli government is governed by the Likud Group and a group of center-right parties. The Likud Group is the right-wing core of Israeli politics. The current Prime Minister Netanyahu and the famous military strongman Sharon are all representatives of this party. It seems that this is an echo of right-wing Jews in Israel and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, people who are familiar with international relations know that Jews as a group are generally not right-wing, but are famous for being left-leaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The contemporary American political left is the liberal wing represented by the Democratic Party. There are approximately 6 million Jews in the United States, the largest number of Jews outside Israel. The vast majority of Jews vote for Democrats in every election, and this has been the case for more than a hundred years. &quot;Jews side with the Democrats&quot; is common sense in the political arena. As everyone knows, black people are the die-hard vote base of Democrats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the Republican Party&#39;s firm support for Israel, Democrats continue to criticize Israel. They often criticize the Israeli government&#39;s tough methods and ruthless style, and demand ceasefire and peace talks. American Jews&#39; criticism of the Israeli government is even more intense. On October 16, two American Jewish groups launched a large-scale protest. Hundreds of people rushed into the White House waving Palestinian flags and demanded that the United States urge Israel to cease fire. This farce was so angry that Israel called them &quot;Jewish traitors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although American public opinion generally supports Israel this time, in the long run, most Jews in the United States are still critics of the Israeli government, sponsors of American universities that are the stronghold of liberals, and have basically nothing to do with the so-called right. Even within Israel, the left has a strong presence. After the establishment of the state of Israel, the left-wing Labor Party has been in power for more than thirty years. At the end of the 20th century, the Likud Party rose and had to form a coalition with the Labor Party to govern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you extend the time and broaden your horizons, you will find that the left-wing color of the Jews is too strong to be ignored. Whether in times of peace or war, Jews as a whole lean left. This means that they are &quot;restless&quot;, like construction, love sports, have radical political leanings, and pursue &quot;equality&quot; economically. Why do the Jewish people have such characteristics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it is related to the experience of the Jewish nation. After the Jews lost their country, they have been wandering throughout history. They have used scriptures and religious organizations to unite the ethnic group, rarely integrating into the local ethnic groups and culture (the Kaifeng Jews in history are an exception), and their relationship with the local people is somewhat estranged, and there is no negotiation. . Many Jews hope to establish a new country where everyone is &quot;equal&quot;, which is related to their messianic religious tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rise of Zionism, a large number of Russian and Eastern European Jews rushed to Canaan, becoming the seeds of Israel&#39;s revival and founding. Israeli agriculture includes kibbutzim and moshav, which are collective agricultural cooperatives; industry is a mixed economic system dominated by state-owned enterprises. Diplomatically, Israel opposed colonialism. During the Cold War, Israel turned to the United States and became its ally in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s Israel, although the left wing is still a considerable force, it has faded much compared to the early days of the founding of the country. In a harsh environment surrounded by powerful enemies in the Middle East, Israel has taken some measures to turn to the right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kibbutz farms have begun to be privatized, their economic role is weakening, and their community functions are increasing. Israeli agriculture no longer relies on collectivization, but relies on science and technology to develop modern agriculture. Mixed ownership, in which state-owned enterprises account for a large proportion, has also transitioned to privatization, with private enterprises becoming the main force in the economy. Israel encourages entrepreneurship and attracts foreign investment, making the country a technological and entrepreneurial powerhouse in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to attract overseas Jews to return and provide financial support, Israel continues to strengthen its national and religious identity. Compromising with the ultra-Orthodox and granting non-soldiers the privilege of not being educated is largely to treat them as the &quot;condensation core&quot; of the Jewish nation. The Israeli government&#39;s financial support for the ultra-Orthodox is also related to the high birth rate among the ultra-Orthodox. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the Israeli government promulgated the &quot;Jewish Nation-State Law.&quot; Article 1 of the law stipulates that Israel is the historical home of the Jewish people and the nation-state of the Jewish people, and Hebrew is the official language of Israel (removing the official status of Arabic). This approach of strengthening ethnic distinctions runs counter to Western political correctness, and Netanyahu&#39;s government has been criticized as &quot;extreme right&quot; for this reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The left-wing forces in Israel reached their peak in the early days of the founding of the country, but have declined since then. By the 21st century, left-wing parties have basically lost their governing position. At the same time, Israeli Jews abroad fully embraced American left-wing culture and became the backbone of liberal circles. This divide is related to another reason why Jews tend to lean toward the left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jews have a good educational tradition (from the priestly class tradition), the overall cultural level is high, and a large number of intellectuals have emerged. In the field of natural sciences, outstanding achievements of Jewish scientists can often be seen. More Jews entered the intellectual class and became doctors, lawyers, professors, reporters, editors, artists and professional managers. Since the last century, the proportion of Jews in knowledge industries in European and American countries has been very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jews, whose number is not very large, are the nation with the highest proportion of intellectuals in the world. This is a remarkable achievement. Problems arise. Certain problems among intellectuals (especially those in the humanities and social sciences) are evident among the Jewish community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a kind of childish disease among intellectuals, who are often obsessed with creating theories and are divorced from reality. They are eager to build a better world, but they are not very concerned about the costs and resistance in the real world, so they can only rely on the state to push it forward. Paying attention to plan construction and ignoring daily experience often results in disaster. Intellectuals often show love and compassion, and their exaggerated &quot;moral sense&quot; obscures rational thinking, which often makes them fall into sincere stupidity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jews cannot avoid these intellectual problems. They move around various countries, lack the accumulation of ancestral property in the countryside, are excluded by mainstream society, and can easily develop a &quot;nomad mentality.&quot; The homeless are dissatisfied with the existing order, lack feelings for the local culture, and lack interest in establishing and continuing their families. They just want quick success, and the loosening and disintegration of the old order is obviously to their advantage. The more wandering Jewish intellectuals are, the easier it is for them to create and spread radical ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese thinker Mencius once said, &quot;Those who have permanent property have perseverance, and those who do not have perseverance have no perseverance. If you don&#39;t have perseverance, you will do whatever it takes to ward off evil.&quot; This can also explain why many new immigrant groups are &quot;vagrants&quot; Mentality&quot;, while native peoples or old immigrants who have been rooted for generations tend to tend towards conservatism. Once wealthy Jewish businessmen from all over the world have taken root in a certain place for generations and have deep-rooted industries, they will also move closer to conservatives. The five wealthy Jewish business families in Hong Kong are considered to be old Hong Kongers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look back at Israel. Most of Israel&#39;s early immigrants were left-wing intellectuals. After a few generations, the law of &quot;perseverance comes to those who have perseverance&quot; began to take effect. Compared with overseas Jews, the local people have a long-term view and are pragmatic and cold-blooded in their approach. Many native Jews moved to the right. Diaspora Jews lack this sense of belonging, and intellectuals continue their left-leaning inertia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today’s diaspora Jews, especially young people, are almost liberal. They have complicated feelings about Israel. On the one hand, they recognize that Israel is the motherland to which they belong, and that a strong Israel can effectively deter anti-Semitic countercurrents. They also feel that the current Israeli government is too barbaric, cruel and inhumane. In every Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the protesters at the forefront are young Jewish people. However, this time, they paid a heavy price for their sincerity and kindness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The music festival tragedy stung many Western Jews. This is why wealthy American Jews and Jewish organizations immediately stopped funding universities when they heard they refused to condemn Hamas. Despite this, the public opinion of the American Jewish community is still left-leaning, and their habit of firmly supporting the Democratic Party may be difficult to change. The trend of &quot;Jews moving to the left and Israel moving to the right&quot; will continue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, it is emphasized that Jews as a whole are left-leaning, and there are still Jews who are moving toward the &quot;right&quot; ideological path. Mises and Hayek, the masters who defended the free market, both have Jewish ancestry; Friedman, who won the Nobel Prize in Economics and popularized market common sense to the public, and libertarian philosopher Ayn Rand, they are also Jews. There are also many Jews in European and American intellectual circles who have deeply reflected on the shortcomings of Jewish leftism. These wise men who transcend the limitations of national psychology deserve more attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[果敢同盟军为什么这么能打，他们打仗的钱又是哪来的？丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260332]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/4Xu03XgA21c9Frt8lwYWw3yzX5mJWg3WxMlVOdBF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4Xu03XgA21c9Frt8lwYWw3yz X5mJWg3WxMlVOdBF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 28, 2023, Qingshui River, Myanmar, Myanmar October 28, 2023 On the Qingshui River in Myanmar, members of the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army took a group photo with members of the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army on Qianshao Mountain and weapons seized from the Myanmar army on Qianshao Mountain &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, Myanmar’s ethnic local armed forces headed by the Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army launched a military operation called “1027 Joint Operation” to cooperate with the Myanmar military in Fierce fighting broke out in Lashio, Guidai and other places in northern Myanmar. A few days ago, Myanmar military government spokesman Zaw Min Tun has admitted that the Qingshui River in the China-Myanmar border area has been occupied by the Allied Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fighting in northern Shan State has intensified since the alliance announced a full-scale offensive on the Kokang region, with an ethnic minority alliance claiming to have captured four towns and dozens of military posts, blocking access to China. trade routes. And continue to destroy roads, communication facilities and bridges used by government forces to support the Shan State front line. This has forced the Myanmar military to rely on air transportation to support Lao Cai, the capital of Kokang, including using helicopters to transport supplies, pick up the wounded and family members of senior officials, and even airdrop special operations personnel to strengthen defenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This can be said to be the biggest military challenge faced by Myanmar&#39;s military government since Aung San Suu Kyi was captured by the army in 2021. As we all know, during the Spring Festival in 2015, the Kokang Allied Forces launched a military operation in an attempt to counterattack the Kokang Autonomous Region, which they had lost since 2009. However, the operation failed due to the full stranglehold of the Burmese army, and they were forced to evacuate the Kokang area and continued to attack along the Salween River. Fighting in the Hongyan guerrilla zone. At present, it seems that the intensity and progress of the Kokang Allied Forces&#39; attack on Kokang this time are significantly greater than those in 2015. Therefore, many people are puzzled by the increased strength of the Allied Forces. Various conspiracy theories have even arisen around this question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why does the Kokang Allied Forces seem to have increased in strength, and why is this offensive so powerful? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the Kokang Allied Forces did not suddenly become stronger. In the attack on Lao Cai in 2015, the three main brigades of the Allied Forces performed quite well. Not only does it have very strong mobile warfare capabilities, but it is also quite skilled in long-range sniping. Such combat effectiveness is inseparable from the long-term mountain guerrilla warfare after the Allied Forces were reestablished in 2010. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, no matter how strong the combat effectiveness is, the army also needs a sufficient economic base to support it. The outside world knows very little about the financial resources of the Kokang Allied Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are rumors on the Internet that the Kokang Allied Forces have been fighting guerrillas in the virgin forest since 2009. In fact, it still maintains a relatively fixed base area, namely the famous Hongyan District, located in the eastern part of the Red Star District of the Kokang Special Administrative Region. Adjacent to the China-Myanmar border, the Nu River and Baihu Mountain cover an area of ​​approximately 36 square kilometers. In addition to the base areas within Kokang territory, the Kokang Allied Forces also have other footholds. The Fourth Special Administrative Region in eastern Shan State has allowed the alliance leadership and some troops to enter since 2009. The current government chairman of the Fourth Special Administrative Region, Lin Mingxian, is the son-in-law of Peng Jiasheng, the founder of the Kokang Alliance Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the areas controlled by the Kokang Allied Forces, they can raise funds through taxation and border trade. In addition, the Kokang Allied Forces also control some docks in the Salween River and Mekong River basins, which can be used for material transfer and to collect tolls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, after the Kokang conflict in 2015, because the Kokang Alliance Army showed quite good combat effectiveness in the conflict, it was regarded as a backer by other surrounding ethnic and local armed forces. These ethnic and local armed forces began to support the Kokang Alliance. The military directly provides economic support and logistical supplies. The Kokang Alliance Army, the Arakan Army, and the Ta&#39;ang Liberation Army further formed the famous Three Brothers Alliance (3BHA) in 2017. Subsequently, they often cooperated with each other to fight, and they also shared their financial and logistical needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Rakhine and De&#39;ang have their own stable and controlled base areas, and the base areas have the economic foundation of primary and secondary industries such as jade and jade, minerals, mahogany, tea, agricultural products, sugar cane and sugar, and also have Border trade, specialty tourism and other tertiary industries, so the economic situation is naturally much better than that of the Kokang Allied Forces with a small base area. Their support for the Kokang Alliance undoubtedly strengthened the entire alliance in general. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Three Brothers Alliance, the United Wa State Army and the Kachin Independence Army, as the two largest ethnic local armed forces in northern Myanmar, also have considerable support for the Three Brothers Alliance. The local armed forces have certain military manufacturing capabilities and can produce light weapons, ammunition and even light artillery on their own. Many of the logistical equipment of the local armed factions of various ethnic groups in northern Myanmar rely on the support of the Kachin and Wa States. The late founder of the Kokang Alliance Army, Peng Jiasheng, also had good personal relationships with leaders of the Kachin and Wa states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there is a core demand behind the support of the Kokang Alliance Army by ethnic and local armed forces in the region, that is, they hope that the Kokang Alliance Army can bear more pressure when the Myanmar government forces attack. After all, the other forces have stable bases and ethnic populations. Fighting with the government forces is not conducive to the development of local people&#39;s livelihood. The Kokang Allied Forces have lost their &quot;hometown&quot; and have a small remaining territory. They also want to &quot;fight back home&quot;, so they are obviously more willing to spare their efforts. For the Kokang Allied Forces, even if they lose the Hongyan base, the worst they can do is continue to fight guerrillas in the guerrilla zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the news footage of this &quot;Operation 1027&quot;, the Kokang Allied Forces have not significantly improved their equipment. Although some weapons have been updated, they are still various light weapons common in northern Myanmar. As for combat equipment, helmets and new military uniforms, they are also low-end private products that can be bought everywhere. In terms of personnel recruitment, in recent years due to the internal divisions of the Bamar ethnic group, the Kokang Allied Forces have also begun to recruit non-Kokang soldiers. For example, the 611 Brigade established in 2022, most of the members are non-Kokang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest upgrade in weapons and equipment of the Kokang Alliance this time is actually the drone, but it is also a common commercial model. In recent years, anti-government forces have begun to use drones extensively in Myanmar&#39;s civil war, especially after the military government captured Aung San Suu Kyi. The People&#39;s Defense Force (PDF) formed by Aung San&#39;s supporters has quite a bit of knowledge from Myanmar universities. Molecules and technologists who are able to build their own drones by purchasing parts. These also include fixed-wing drones with corrugated skins, which are almost invisible to radar because they have very few metal parts. The local ethnic armed forces in northern Myanmar also often use this kind of drone as a patrol missile, and it is said that the actual combat effect is good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2015, the Kokang Alliance Army assumed a role similar to that of the vanguard army and training team of ethnic local armed forces in the region. Through continuous actual combat, it opened up the situation on the one hand and helped train personnel of other friendly neighboring forces on the other. , so the combat effectiveness has been very stable. In March 2017, the Kokang Allied Forces attacked the Lao Cai Casino, causing more than 30 casualties and sweeping away the casino&#39;s treasury. After exchanging fire with the Myanmar government troops and pro-government local armed forces who came to support, they escaped unscathed. Therefore, before the conflict broke out on October 27, 2023, the Kokang Allied Forces were likely to have the strength to directly attack Lao Cai, and what they were waiting for might be a suitable opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老师，你为什么不让孩子课间离开教室？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260452]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As a primary school teacher, I feel that there are a lot of hot news in the education sector recently. First, the &quot;ten minutes of silence between classes&quot; sparked heated discussion, and then the teacher&#39;s heavy burden of &quot;non-teaching tasks&quot; also became a hot search topic. Earlier, a school charged 200 yuan for a lunch break, which was also controversial. These things seem to me to be inextricably linked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some children were imprisoned in the classroom or even on their seats during recess, which made netizens sad. Recalling the free recess in their childhood, they couldn&#39;t help but ask: Why can&#39;t today&#39;s children be unrestrained during recess? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media pointed out that some parents are to blame for their tendency to hold schools accountable. In order to reduce safety accidents, the school adopted a simple and crude &quot;one size fits all&quot; approach and banned running and jumping activities during recess. As for chronic consequences such as slow development of athletic ability and lack of social interaction, the school cannot take care of it. Therefore, the media called for loosening school management and dividing responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents holding schools accountable is indeed a pain in the ass for teachers. During a recess not long ago, two girls in my class were holding hands and spinning in circles. Later, the game was upgraded and they started spinning back to back. It was originally a warm and beautiful scene, but during acceleration, a girl fell to the ground, and her two front teeth were unfortunately shattered. I saw all this clearly, but it was through the video in the corridor. When the incident happened, I was downstairs, leading another class in physical education class across subjects. The student&#39;s teeth have become permanent teeth, and the parents are very worried. I reported it to the school step by step, and the safety office said after analysis that it was not a safety incident, but an accident that occurred while playing between classmates, and the parents of both parties could just negotiate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The parents of the girl who played together proposed that the treatment costs should be split equally between the two parties. However, the parents of the injured girl said that because the accident happened at school, the school should also be responsible. I was dealing with three parties and was very embarrassed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parents are not unreasonable. In European and American countries where we often learn from educational experience, schools should theoretically be held responsible for accidents on campus. It&#39;s just that most parents don&#39;t tend to hold the school accountable. Instead, they negotiate on their own with the mentality that bumps and pains are inevitable in their children&#39;s growth. Campus accident insurance in these countries has wider coverage and can effectively reduce the financial burden on all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I believe that in addition to the soft conditions of division of powers and responsibilities, hard conditions such as teacher-student ratio, school hours and campus venues are also important reasons that affect students’ freedom between classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, Xinhua News Agency published an article titled &quot;The Ministry of Education Responds to the Problem of Being Restrained for 10 Minutes Between Classes.&quot; The article proposed that schools should &quot;strengthen the inspection of outdoor facilities and personnel on duty...minimize the risk of safety accidents and allow children to be happy and safe in their activities.&quot; This reasonable sentence made my heart rise in my throat: &quot;Personnel on duty.&quot; , what kind of personnel are they? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our school has never prohibited students from recess activities due to safety reasons, although chasing and fighting is absolutely prohibited. However, if there is an outbreak of influenza in a class, in order to avoid cross-infection, teachers and students will become tense during class breaks: teachers must take turns in the toilets and corridors, reminding students to wash their hands with hand sanitizer after going to the toilet, and not to stay in the corridors; The teacher should hand over the class and ensure that the classroom is supervised. The scope of students&#39; activities has been reduced, and teachers&#39; class breaks have been filled up, leaving no time for rest. Some colleagues have sprained while rushing to a classroom on another campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many teachers often ask on various social media: &quot;When can teachers only do the job of teaching and educating people?&quot; Is it the teacher&#39;s job to take care of students during breaks? The incident of charging for lunch break while lying on the table clearly shows the contradiction behind this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the hot search came out, staff from the relevant departments responded quickly, saying that the charges were reasonable and approved by the government. Lunch break charges mainly take into account the overtime wages of teachers after class, and even if there is a fee subsidy, many teachers are not willing to pay for lunch breaks. Public opinion did not buy it, and netizens were confused: students take lunch breaks on their own, why do they need teachers to take care of them? Aren&#39;t we going to rest together? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not to mention that some schools do not allow custodial teachers to take breaks. Even if the school is &quot;lenient&quot;, after settling more than 30 or 40 students, then taking a while to relax is definitely not the same as taking a lunch break on your own. Feel. When students take lunch breaks at school, they essentially create a large class break; as long as students are in school, they are the school&#39;s safety responsibility, and the teachers are directly responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government or school can purchase teachers’ lunch breaks through subsidies to ensure student safety. However, in the scattered classes, it is impossible for teachers to go to outdoor places with students in order to arrive at the classroom for the next class on time or to have a little communication with students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In developed countries, teachers do take care of recess and lunch breaks, but most of them adopt a class-based system, with &quot;one teacher per class&quot; and teachers follow the class. In our country, teachers are divided by subjects, and teachers need to teach across classes and grades. Traveling between different classrooms or even campuses often consumes an entire class period, and caring for students during class time has become an &quot;unbearable burden.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The advantages of the private class system are significant: teachers have a more comprehensive understanding of students, and teachers and students can form deeper connections; multi-subject teaching is conducive to cultivating students&#39; interdisciplinary awareness and avoiding teacher burnout. Why is it difficult to implement it in our country? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the examination selection system puts the pressure down to primary schools. Teachers who only focus on one subject can be more familiar with the &quot;test points&quot; and make it easier to take the test. Secondly, most European and American countries adopt small class teaching. Taking the ordinary public primary school where I am as an example, there are no less than 50 students in each class. Finally, most primary schools in Europe and the United States only have half-day classes. After teachers watch the students for half a day, they have complete time to prepare lessons in the afternoon. In order to match the work schedule of our parents, primary school students can stay in school for up to ten hours, from morning reading to lunch break and extended services. If a teacher has to take care of 50 students for a full day of classes and care, not to mention the mental stress, there will be absolutely no time for correcting homework and preparing lessons. What&#39;s more, teachers already have too many non-teaching tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insufficient campus space is also one of the important reasons for restricting students’ freedom between classes. At this stage, the number of students is large and the campus is large. In cities where land is at a premium, school teaching buildings often have four or five floors. In order to cope with the pressure from the Education Bureau to expand enrollment, many old schools have expanded their original areas: the buildings have been built higher, but the playground and basketball courts are often still the same size as they were decades ago. As a result, even several classes in the physical education class had to compete for seats, not to mention the students swarming out during the ten-minute break. If you rush to the basketball court from the fourth or fifth floor, the ready bell will ring again before the ball is touched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, except for the lucky ones whose classrooms are on the first floor, most students’ activity space is limited to the corridor outside the classroom door. If many students are running in such a small space, the probability of stampedes and collisions is unimaginable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the birth rate in our country is declining, which may become an opportunity to implement the &quot;package system&quot;. However, along with the decline in the birth rate, there is also an increase in parents&#39; work pressure and an increase in social costs of raising children. It is difficult to change quickly the length of time students are in school and financial investment in education, and it is also difficult to change quickly the planning of outdoor space on campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the current conditions, I have some immature attempts during class time: teaching children physical games that do not require a large space, such as &quot;carrot squat&quot;, &quot;rock paper scissors&quot; for feet, etc.; Take turns using flying chess and other toys. At the school level, it may be possible to adjust more 15-minute &quot;big breaks&quot; and organize classes to take turns going downstairs; if there is financial resources, break managers can be hired to strengthen care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public public opinion’s attention to recess activities reflects the rising national attention to education. But returning recess to students cannot be solved simply by calling on schools to relax their hands and parents not to criticize teachers harshly. Only by improving the safety of students&#39; recess activities, expanding the space for recess activities, taking away some responsibilities from teachers and returning teachers to students can we truly allow students to run freely during recess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a primary school teacher in Shenzhen, Guangdong Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email ：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说｜陈来：文化保守主义和文化开放主义都是我的立场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260488]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73440&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70249&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/9ca8375979.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, the 7th Nishan World The first high-end dialogue of the Civilization Forum, Chen Lai, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Tsinghua University..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, the 7th Nishan World Civilization Forum, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Tsinghua University Chen Lai. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ 9ca8375979.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258047&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, seventh Chen Lai, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, attended the Nishan World Civilization Forum. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;Doctoral File&lt;/h5>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Chen Lai was born in Beijing in 1952 and his ancestral home is Wenzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·1973-1976, at Central South Institute of Mining and Metallurgy (now Central South University of Mining and Metallurgy) University) Department of Geology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·1978-1981, studied as a graduate student in the Department of Philosophy, Peking University, and stayed at Teach in school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1985, he received a doctorate in philosophy from the Department of Philosophy of Peking University, becoming the first person in New China to A self-trained Doctor of Philosophy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1986, he was appointed associate professor of the Department of Philosophy of Peking University, and in 1990 he was appointed as professor of the Department of Philosophy of Peking University . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1991, he was awarded &quot;Chinese Ph.D. with Outstanding Contributions&quot; by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council and the National Education Commission. Degree Recipient”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1993, he was rated as a doctoral supervisor by the Academic Degrees Office of the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·Transferred to Tsinghua University in 2009 and currently serves as deputy director of the Academic Committee of Tsinghua University and Tsinghua University Senior professor of university liberal arts, dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, and professor of the Department of Philosophy at Tsinghua University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Lai, dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, is renowned for his research on Confucian philosophy since 1980. Since the beginning of the 1990s, I have been thinking about a question: In a modern society, what can traditional culture still do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Reform and opening up brought a &quot;cultural craze&quot; to the ideological circles at that time. Chen Lai remembers that the most popular one was the editor-in-chief of the &quot;Towards the Future&quot; series at the time. Bao Zunxin said, &quot;When he went to Peking University and said a word, the crowd applauded.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The school of thought, represented by Bao Zunxin and others, believes that Confucianism is incompatible with modern spirit, which has caused the decline of society, the ignorance of the public and the country&#39;s decline in modern times. Being poor and weak needs to be reviewed or even abandoned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the beginning, Chen Lai was just a bystander of the &quot;cultural craze&quot;. He is the first independently trained doctor of philosophy in New China. In the autumn of 1977, Chinese colleges and universities resumed postgraduate enrollment, and Chen Lai read the news in the newspaper. A week later, he went from his workplace in the eastern suburbs of Beijing to register at Peking University in the western suburbs of Beijing, and finally chose the Chinese philosophy major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Philosophy is the traditional strength major of Peking University. After the major restructuring of departments in 1952, all philosophy teachers from universities across the country gathered at Peking University. In the following years, the Department of Philosophy at Peking University was the only philosophy department in the country. A large number of outstanding scholars such as Tang Yongtong, Feng Youlan, Jin Yuelin, Zhu Guangqian, Zhang Dainian, Ren Jiyu, etc. gathered in Yanyuan, which can be called the &quot;Jixia Academy of the 20th century&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the resumption of enrollment in the late 1970s, the Chinese Philosophy Teaching and Research Office, where Zhang Dainian was the director, enrolled the first 10 graduate students, and Chen Lai was one of them. Chen Lai recalled that more than 200 people applied for the History of Chinese Philosophy exam at Peking University this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the context of Western modernization ideas constantly attacking the Chinese cultural world, Chen Lai returned to Chinese tradition and completed his doctoral thesis &quot;Study on the Philosophy of Zhu Xi&quot; in 1985 , made a detailed and detailed investigation of Zhu Xi&#39;s philosophical thoughts and development. Soon after, he visited Harvard University for two years. After noticing the &quot;cultural craze&quot; in China and the ubiquitous Christian tradition in the United States, he began to think about the relationship between traditional culture and modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, in the &quot;cultural craze&quot; in China, an important issue was how to promote cultural modernization, and how to treat traditional Confucianism and traditional culture was the focus of debate. The opinions of Bao Zunxin and others once prevailed. When many scholars were &quot;cutting their ties&quot; with Confucianism, Chen Lai&#39;s voice seemed out of place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1987, at the &quot;China in the New Era&quot; international symposium held in Manila, Philippines, Chen Lai submitted a paper &quot;Review and Prospect of Modern Chinese Thought&quot;, It opposes the complete eradication of traditional culture, including Confucianism, advocates the protection of traditional culture, holds a cultural conservatism stance, and boldly makes the judgment that &quot;the greatest condition for the revival of traditional thought is modernization.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In February of the following year, at the International Symposium on &quot;Issues and Prospects of the Development of Confucianism&quot; held in Singapore, in response to the views of Bao Zunxin and others, Chen In response, he submitted a paper &quot;Confucianism and its Positioning in a Multicultural Structure&quot;. He talked about the spread of money worship, utilitarianism, opportunism and undisguised greed in society, and the young generation was at a loss in an atmosphere of emptiness. Siblings. It is precisely in this utilitarian trend and value rupture that the value rationality of Confucianism can provide a set of ethical values ​​and a humanistic worldview that are compatible with modernization reforms and guide the spiritual direction of contemporary Chinese people. He pointed out that modern society is a multicultural society, in which Confucianism does not propose specific designs for reform, but rather proposes a humanistic worldview that complements reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To this day, China&#39;s ideological circles are still digesting the legacy of the &quot;cultural craze&quot; many years ago. The direction of history is as he judged, and the craze for traditional culture continues to this day. Chen Lai is worried: &quot;In every era and every activity, when someone advocates it, some people will excessively push these things to extremes. This is worthy of vigilance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Mr. Zhang For classes, read Mr. Feng’s book”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the degree system was restored, You applied for a graduate degree in the Philosophy Department of Peking University and later became the first independently trained doctor of philosophy in New China. Can you talk about your educational experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am the first batch of graduate students after the reform and opening up. In October 1977, the country officially announced that it would recruit college students through the college entrance examination. A month later, &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; published another news, which was to resume the postgraduate enrollment system. At the time of admission, because there was no official document stating the nature of the postgraduate degree, we all thought that this postgraduate degree was equivalent to the Soviet associate doctoral degree. Associate doctoral students were recruited from universities in the 1950s after the country learned from the Soviet Union&#39;s experience. They are equivalent to doctoral students in the West, because in the Soviet Union, there were full doctorates on top of associate doctoral degrees, and they almost required professors. At that time, the personnel treatment for returning to China after obtaining an associate doctoral degree in the Soviet Union was equivalent to that for those who obtained a doctoral degree in Western countries. However, by 1957, this system was abolished, and associate doctorates were no longer recruited. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;When we entered school, we also thought it was based on the associate doctorate. Everyone has higher expectations for themselves, and they are all based on the standard of a doctorate. Asked by myself. It wasn’t until the second semester of the second year of graduate school that the country introduced a new system, saying that our first batch of graduate students were master’s students, which was not equivalent to associate doctorate students in the Soviet Union, but was one level lower than doctorate students in the United States. At that time, everyone still Not so satisfied. But we are disappointed. In terms of professional attainments, our first batch of graduate students strived to reach the Soviet Union&#39;s associate doctorate level at the master&#39;s level, which is close to the level of American doctorates. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What was the opportunity to continue studying for a PhD? What were the criteria for awarding doctorates at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduating from graduate school in the fall of 1981, I stayed at Peking University to teach. The next year, the school announced the list of the first batch of doctoral supervisors. With the doctoral supervisors, it was stated that they would continue to award doctorates. I also decided to give it a try. Later, I was changed from a teacher to a doctoral candidate, and my original salary was paid as usual. There was nothing special about it. In addition to English writing and speaking courses, I basically focus on writing my doctoral thesis. At that time there were no clear criteria for awarding degrees. Now when you are studying for a Ph.D., you will have clear requirements for being awarded a Ph.D. after being admitted. For example, Tsinghua University School of Humanities stipulates that the number of words for a doctoral thesis should be between 150,000 and 200,000 words. We didn&#39;t establish it in this way when we were in school, so we relied on our own imagination. Referring to the requirements of the Soviet Union&#39;s associate doctorate, we probably had to write about 200,000 words. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What do you think are the characteristics of the education you received at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The education we received is different from that of Chinese students in the 1950s and 1960s. Likewise, previous education was severely disrupted and academically weak. Speaking of my major in Chinese philosophy, there were two old gentlemen at that time, one was Mr. Feng Youlan and the other was Mr. Zhang Dainian. Mr. Zhang gave us two courses: Historical Materials of the History of Chinese Philosophy and Methodology of the History of Chinese Philosophy. Mr. Feng stopped taking classes because he was older. Once upon a time, a reporter summarized my words and said that the characteristic of our postgraduate studies was &quot;taking Mr. Zhang&#39;s class and reading Mr. Feng&#39;s books.&quot; Mr. Feng and Mr. Zhang were already leading scholars in our discipline in the 1930s, so the professional education we received was directly connected to the academic and educational traditions of the 1930s and 1940s, while those students in the 1950s received It was an education influenced by Soviet experts. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What role did these two gentlemen play in your life? What learning methods did you learn from them? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Zhang is my mentor, from scratch to PhD degree , Mr. Zhang’s academic thoughts and academic methods had a great influence on me. He specifically guided me from the primary stage of learning to the advanced stage. After graduation, I worked as an assistant to Mr. Feng, mainly helping him compile the &quot;New History of Chinese Philosophy&quot;. I took the initiative to learn from Mr. Feng through conversations, how to learn from him and how to think philosophically. Unlike Mr. Zhang, Mr. Feng helped me rise to a higher level after I had already reached a relatively advanced stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Mr. Zhang&#39;s academic method can be said in one sentence to be &quot;easy to learn and think deeply, and know what he means.&quot; The original words of this sentence come from Sima Qian&#39;s &quot;Historical Records&quot;: &quot;If you don&#39;t love to learn and think deeply, and know its meaning in your heart, you will be short-sighted and ignorant.&quot; Mr. Zhang extracted the eight words &quot;Love to learn and think deeply, and know its meaning in your heart&quot; to emphasize research. When studying the history of Chinese philosophy, on the one hand, we must conduct an in-depth and detailed interpretation of the literature to grasp its original meaning; on the other hand, we must use a clear logical analysis method to explain it layer by layer, and we must not swallow it in a hurry or explain it vaguely. Confused, this clear logical analysis method was called &quot;analyzing names and analyzing principles&quot; in ancient China. This is the fundamental method and attitude for studying and researching the history of Chinese philosophy. It can also be said to be the basic method I learned from Mr. Zhang. My doctoral thesis &quot;Study on Zhu Xi&#39;s Philosophy&quot; is to study Zhu Xi&#39;s philosophy using the method of &quot;love to learn and think deeply, and know the meaning from the heart&quot;, which fully reflects Mr. Zhang&#39;s influence on me. Mr. Feng has been a philosopher for a long time, and his research focuses on thinking about the realm of life in philosophy. Later I published another book called &quot;The Realm of Being and Absence&quot;. This &quot;realm&quot; is the &quot;realm&quot; of &quot;realm&quot;. When I was studying Wang Yangming, I put the issue of realm at the center. This was also inspired by Mr. Feng&#39;s The influence of realm emphasis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a teacher now, what methods do you teach your students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Now I ask students to still emphasize Mr. Zhang’s method, because Mr. Zhang’s method helps students move from the primary stage to the advanced stage. The only way is to lay the foundation, and Mr. Feng’s method is a higher-level choice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73441&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70250&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/8a9509b256.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111388227602.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;June 19, 2022, parents with their children Visiting the Confucius Museum in Qufu City, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/13/8a9509b256.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258048&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;June 19, 2022 On the same day, parents took their children to visit the Confucius Museum in Qufu City, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cultural openness is also my stance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the reform and opening up, the discussion on &quot;tradition and modernity&quot; was very intense. In your 1987 article &quot;Review and Prospect of Modern Chinese Thought&quot;, you made &quot; &quot;The greatest condition for the revival of traditional thought is modernization&quot;, holding a cultural conservatism stance and opposing the complete eradication of tradition. Why did you choose this stance at that time? Has this position been established since your research on Zhu Xi? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The relationship between tradition and modernity was the most heated discussion in academic circles in the 1980s Regarding the issue, I started doing research on Zhu Xi in 1979, and when I completed it in 1985, I still didn’t have such a position. It wasn’t until 1986 that I visited Harvard University in the United States and observed that Christian traditions are ubiquitous in modern society in the United States. This made me think about the relationship between tradition and modernity, and whether we must completely oppose tradition. Only by completely breaking away from tradition like the New Culture Movement can we move towards modernization. Some people at that time believed that tradition was feudalism and that we must be more resolute in our anti-feudalism in order to move toward openness and modernity. I wrote some articles at that time, firmly opposing the complete eradication of tradition, and I was still writing articles on this stance until the 1990s. This is parallel to my academic research. On the one hand, I have relatively pure academic research, and on the other hand, I continue to participate in discussions of social and cultural trends of thought. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be said that I have two positions, one is cultural conservatism, and the other is cultural openness. I would like to emphasize cultural conservatism. American sociologist Daniel Bell once said that cultural conservatism is mainly aimed at the cultural tendency of over-commercialization in modern society, emphasizing authority and cultural value in culture, and focusing on protecting the value of traditional culture. . However, since the mid-1990s, some dogmatists have stigmatized cultural conservatism, calling it extreme retroism and conservatism. This is wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;mentioned at that time that &quot; Is &quot;conservative&quot; a bit sensitive? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The concept of &quot;conservatism&quot; does not seem to mean much in modern China. Very positive, but in Western concepts, &quot;conservative&quot; is not necessarily a bad word, but can reflect positive values. Cultural conservatism is a cultural attitude that values ​​the culture that humans have created and inherited throughout history. I emphasized from the beginning that cultural conservatism is not political conservatism and has nothing to do with politics. However, when some people hear cultural conservatism, they think it is against reform and opening up. In fact, this is not what it really means. It is about culture. value. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You mentioned in the Qizhi interview that you suffered attacks from some scholars because of your insistence on Chinese culture in the late 1980s. For example, you mentioned that in those years, your important academic works also won awards in various awards. Only the third prize can be awarded. With the development of the times, your position has gradually been recognized and realized. Have you personally experienced the process of moving from the edge to the center? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The description from edge to center is not appropriate and I was shocked. At that time, I was not on the edge. Now that I am not affected by it, I cannot be said to be in the center. These blows only affected my personal situation and did not affect my own academic development and progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You have always been firm in your stance. Many people may have stopped speaking out after being hit. Why are you so persistent? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because what I said is right, on the contrary, those things that hit me I find their behavior very despicable, but I don’t care that much. I will do my own thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, traditional culture has become more and more popular among young people In your opinion, what changes have occurred in the “traditional culture craze” in China? Which of these are exciting, and which are cause for alarm? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I can intuitively feel that young people are becoming more and more interested in elements of traditional culture. Interests, like wearing Hanfu, etc. In principle, it is gratifying to absorb the elements of traditional culture and adopt them in today&#39;s cultural forms. For example, many of the cultural and creative products in various places are related to local cultural traditions or Chinese cultural traditions. . &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for what we need to be vigilant about, in abstract terms, it is the promotion of traditional culture, which should be more natural and should not be blunt or rigid. Excessive promotion away from natural needs. For example, in the past few years, there were many classic reading classes for children, which required children to memorize hundreds of thousands or even 200,000 words. I think this is unnecessary. When children learn traditional culture, it becomes their values ​​in life, and it doesn’t matter how much they memorize. In every era and every activity, when someone advocates it, there will be people who push these things to extremes. This is something to be wary of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73442&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70251&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c856153e2f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111457714756.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;October 4, 2023, Nanjing, Tourists wearing Hanfu visit the Laomendong Scenic Area. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;754&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/c856153e2f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258049&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 4th, in Nanjing, tourists wearing Hanfu visited the Laomendong Scenic Area. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Confucianism is not about ideology”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What changes have occurred in society&#39;s attitude towards Confucianism in different historical periods? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The pre-Qin period was the growth period of Confucianism. Confucius founded Confucianism. Disciples continued to pass it on, but because it was in the Warring States Period, the ruling class at that time was particularly interested in military doctrine, that is, how to develop the military. They had a more positive attitude towards the Legalist thoughts of the pre-Qin era and felt that Legalist methods could be effective immediately. They were very interested in Confucianism. No interest. In the Han Dynasty, a unified country based on the system of prefectures and counties was formed. The ruling class deeply reflected on the rapid demise of the Qin Dynasty. At first, they wanted to replace Legalism with Taoism, but they soon found that the Taoist attitude was only suitable for There was no active governance strategy for the restoration of the economic ecology after the war, so Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty decided to only respect Confucianism and regard Confucianism as the leading value. The following dynasties did not change much. They all used Confucian values ​​​​to implement state governance. Of course, they were not just Confucianists, but also absorbed Taoist and Legalist ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In modern times, Western learning based on the Scientific Revolution and the Industrial Revolution entered China. The society was in a period of transformation, and the traditional society was going to Modern society based on the scientific revolution and technological revolution has some different attitudes towards traditional culture and traditional thoughts during this period. The most important one is total westernization, which takes a negative stance towards traditional Chinese culture including Confucianism. At the same time, there are also some The other type, with a relatively small number of people, adheres to Confucianism and traditional culture and has its positive significance - although the social foundation has changed, as a result of wisdom gained from historical human exploration of nature, society, life, including literature and art, Traditional culture and Confucianism are not meaningless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can it be understood as Are the values ​​advocated by Confucianism particularly important to social reform and transformation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s not just values, of course values ​​are included. The &quot;Review and Prospects of Modern Chinese Thought&quot; I wrote in 1987 was aimed at the reform issues at that time. At that time, some theorists actually put forward the slogan &quot;Everything depends on money.&quot; I emphasized at that time that &quot;all things are about money&quot; would never become the spiritual tradition of a great nation. The role of Confucianism in the process of modernization and reform is not to propose specific designs for reform, but to propose a humanistic worldview that complements reform. The task or function of Confucianism is not to directly promote reforms, but to provide a humanistic spirit that complements modernization reforms to guide people&#39;s general spiritual direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Confucianism does not have to be directly related to the social transformation of Westernization. Social modernization can occur while basic values ​​remain unchanged. of. For example, Japan&#39;s basic cultural values ​​did not change much from 1880 until its economy re-developed in the 1960s. No region in Asia with Confucian culture first overthrew Confucian culture before achieving modernization. The success of modernization in regions and countries such as Hong Kong, South Korea, and Singapore has proven that societies that have grown up under the influence of Chinese culture can achieve modernization well. In a developed modern market economy, the general trend of commercialization makes the moral norms and spiritual civilization requirements of this society more prominent than before. In the era of big pot rice, this problem is not prominent. Therefore, the value and significance of Confucian modernization are not just viewed from the perspective of utilitarianism. The most important thing is that in an era when commercialization is prevalent, market economy and utilitarianism require a value system to constrain and regulate society as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now in the general sense From what angle do you consider the revival of Confucianism? Are there political factors? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To a large extent, it comes from philosophy or culture. Think about it, not politically. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The revival of Confucianism in the general sense began during the May Fourth Movement. Liang Shuming and Xiong Shili both wanted to inherit Confucianism philosophically. Tradition developed the New Confucianism of this era; culturally speaking, when we talk about the decline of Confucianism, it is mainly at the level of secular social culture, including the integrated forms of existence such as socialization, institutionalization, and secularization, including some aspects of all aspects of society. Basic institutions and some basic culture. Private schools, academies, etc. did not exist in the 1990s, but today there are already many. In fact, there is no shortage of metaphysical constructions of Confucian philosophy in the 20th century. The most important thing now is how to restore Confucianism as a life ethic to influence the public and society. Of course, it is impossible to completely restore, but it can be partially or improvedly restored. For example, the restoration of ancestral halls, academies, and private schools has its own positive significance today. The moral decline and value loss in society in recent years is not due to the lack of a few philosophers, but the lack of the cultural foundation of Confucianism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion , Who should be responsible for the revival of Confucianism as a culture? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is not a single person, it can be a group, or it can be Social organizations, for example, many civil servants with various professions are now involved in the revival of Confucianism, including how to promote Confucianism into schools, villages, communities, and folk culture so that it can play a role in this era , there are many social forces doing this work now. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I was in Shandong in September and went to Qufu Sage Education School. The philosophy of their two principals was to use Confucian concepts to Guiding education does not mean learning all the content, but using Confucianism to guide. Whether in primary school or middle school, the first class for students every day is to study Confucian classics, as well as some activities similar to meditation to help students become more stable and calm down for learning. It is easy for students to accept it, and parents also feel that students in this school are not impetuous and are relatively quiet. I think it is very effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to the power of the people , should the government promote it? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The government does not specifically use Confucianism as a guiding ideology for education. Instead, it is collectively referred to as Chinese cultural education. How are these policies implemented in the national education system? Courses require hours of study. It is useless to say that there are no hours of study. How are teachers trained? This is what the Ministry of Education can do. It is not difficult to provide teaching hours, develop teaching materials, and have trained teachers teach. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are in the book &quot;Watching the Value of Tradition&quot; When it comes to shaping the spiritual temperament of Chinese people, the most important thing is through education. Are you optimistic about rebuilding the value system of Confucianism through education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are many aspects of work involved in reconstructing the value system of Confucianism. Primary school curriculum education is one aspect. Our emphasis on traditional culture in the past ten years has been more conducive to the creative transformation and innovative development of traditional Chinese culture in terms of educational environment. But this work also needs to be recognized by the entire society. From government leaders, institutional regulations and systems to grassroots school teachers, all must persist in order to do it well. This consensus is much better now than before, and we should be optimistic about rebuilding our cultural and educational system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have the ultimate idea about social value rules? What kind of cultural structure is it? What role does Confucianism play in this? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My 1988 paper &quot;Confucianism in a Multicultural Structure&quot; As stated in &quot;And Its Positioning&quot;, my own wish is that in a new cultural structure, there will not only be institutionalized constructions such as democracy and science, but also the human interest motives provided by a rational economic structure. Confucianism has still become one of the sources of value for Chinese people, providing Chinese people with the principles of life, the meaning of life, principles and norms for dealing with the world, and even the basic attitude towards the universe, nature, society and human destiny. Today, our cultural structure is not like the single structure of traditional society. It must be a pluralistic structure. Confucianism is not intended to be an ideology, but to have a leading influence on the people as a cultural temperament and spiritual temperament. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Young people lie flat and need neither attention nor criticism&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the perspective of students, young people nowadays are more willing to study economics and management, and it seems that they will not choose philosophy. The golden age of philosophy seems to have passed. Do you agree with this statement? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In every era, only a few people choose philosophy, and philosophy has always been It is not a popular knowledge, but a niche cultural field, but it plays a great role. Today&#39;s society is more utilitarian, so fewer people will choose it. This is a fact, but I think it doesn&#39;t matter, because it is pursued by a small number of people. But in terms of opportunities, the status of the Chinese nation in the world today is different. We who engage in philosophy are also more relaxed. We are not as squeezed by Western culture as before. What we are thinking about now is how to understand what we have learned over the years. The Western things are combined with our traditional things to form a new philosophical thinking. Therefore, it is an opportune time to study philosophy in today’s era. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;In addition to professional choices, when it comes to career choices, many young people also choose to &quot;lay down&quot; or become &quot;full-time children&quot;. Doesn&#39;t it seem to be in line with the &quot;hard work and enterprising&quot; in our traditional culture? What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think these situations are surprising and I don’t need to pay attention to them. , no need to criticize. What we want to see is the diversity of employment, and everyone should have a variety of choices. As for choosing to live alone and stay full-time, one reason is that society has created conditions that allow children to live peacefully and have a guaranteed life. In fact, having children who live alone and work full time is not only inconsistent with the concepts in traditional culture, but also in line with the concepts of modern society. However, on the one hand, we cannot easily condemn those who care about their personal destiny. On the other hand, we must also encourage young people with strong idealism and willingness to take responsibility to pursue greater goals. For example, some students should be encouraged to teach wherever they are willing to go after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Now that school has started, what do you want to say to college students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think there is anything to worry about in professional studies. We still need to correctly establish three views, which have an important impact on life. From a small perspective, it is beneficial to personal mental health. Nowadays, many college students are mentally unhealthy. From a large perspective, it is to further develop social responsibilities and so on. In middle school and high school, there were guidance from class teachers and parents. After reaching college, I think every college student still needs to pay attention to how to control the construction of his own three views. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/ a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部就《电信网络诈骗及其关联违法犯罪联合惩戒办法（征求意见稿）》 面向社会公开征求意见]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260499]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 11:14:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to thoroughly implement the &quot;Anti-Telecommunications Network Fraud Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, the Ministry of Public Security, together with relevant competent authorities, recently The &quot;Joint Punishment Measures for Telecommunications Network Fraud and Related Illegal Crimes (Draft for Comments)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot;) was drafted and widely solicited opinions from the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; has a total of 19 articles, which mainly include six aspects: disciplinary principles, disciplinary objects, disciplinary measures, graded punishment, disciplinary procedures, and complaint verification. It follows the legal determination and excessive punishment. Principles of proportionate and dynamic management, clarifying the scope of individuals and units to be included in punishment targets, stipulating specific measures for financial, telecommunications network, and credit punishment, applying punishments at different levels according to the illegal behavior of punishment targets, standardizing procedures such as review and determination, punishment period and notification, and clarifying appeals , procedures and time limits for acceptance, verification, feedback and cancellation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; insists on legal identification and prevention, strictly determines the scope of punishment objects and identification standards in accordance with the &quot;Anti-Telecommunications Network Fraud Law&quot;, and lists the specific behaviors that are subject to punishment in accordance with the law. , distinguishes the scope of review and identification of punishment objects by public security organs at or above the districted city level and public security organs at or above the provincial level, and effectively strengthens warning education to achieve the effect of preventing crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; insists on graded punishment and proportional punishment for excessive punishment. For those who are held criminally responsible for committing telecommunications network fraud and related crimes, the punishment period is 3 years; If a person is identified as a subject of punishment by the public security organ at or above the municipal level, the period of punishment shall be 2 years. While comprehensively applying financial punishment, telecommunications network punishment, credit punishment, and incorporating financial credit information basic database and other disciplinary measures, the basic financial and communication services of the disciplinary targets are retained to ensure that their basic living needs are met and the appropriateness of the punishment is fully reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Disciplinary Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; not only strengthens punishment according to law, but also implements dynamic management of disciplinary information data, clearly requires that the disciplinary basis, time limit, measures and appeal rights be informed in writing to the punished object, and The procedures and time limits for appeals, acceptance, verification, feedback and dismissal are clarified to fully protect the legitimate rights and interests of those being punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈慧翎：日子是用来好好过的丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260372]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/YdHZeV8AZfOlptdOaA2uwe1vhw2Z1S3FmVWOCmql.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/YdHZeV8AZfOlptdOaA2uwe1vhw2 Z1S3FmVWOCmql. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chan Huiling (1975-2023) Taiwanese director and screenwriter&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, the Taiwanese idol drama &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; quickly became popular as soon as it was aired, becoming the runner-up in the ratings of an idol drama in the history of Taiwanese television at that time. As this drama Director and screenwriter Chen Huiling has entered the audience&#39;s field of vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Huiling has been &quot;fed&quot; since she was a child and has known her interests early on. In the composition class in the first grade of middle school, she wrote a thick book because she wanted to express too many things. The teacher revised it very carefully and encouraged her to continue writing. This planted a seed in the heart of 13-year-old Chen Huiling - &quot;Ah, I can write. Then I will continue to write.&quot; In this way, Chen Huiling began to create her artistic world bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, when she first debuted in 2008, she won the Drama Program Director Award at the 43rd Taiwan Television Golden Bell Awards for her first drama work &quot;The Golden Thread&quot;. In the same year, his work &quot;Secret Conversations with My Boyfriend&#39;s Ex-Girlfriend&quot; won the Golden Bell Award for Miniseries Screenwriting and Editing. Therefore, &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; is more like an opportunity for Chen Huiling to push her works to a more popular stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She always focuses on the subtle emotional exchanges between people. In the following three years, she created &quot;That Year, It Rained Never Stopped&quot;, which won the Drama Program Director Award at the 45th Taiwan TV Golden Bell Awards, the romantic drama &quot;The Money Worship Queen&quot;, and the feature film &quot;Moonlight in Jilin&quot; and other works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Chen Huiling was diagnosed with cervical cancer. In the following 10 years, the disease recurred many times. The joke of fate did not stop her from creating and enjoying life: as soon as she finished her treatment, she would travel abroad while she was still in good condition. In 2016, she directed the unit drama &quot;Rolling Stone Love Story&quot;. In 2019, she starred in &quot;Your Child&quot; &quot;Not Your Child&quot; won the Golden Bell Award for Best Director again. In the interview, she mentioned her thoughts on the relationship between parents and children in the Chinese world - &quot;A baby will cry when it is hungry, but a teenager who longs for love cannot cry or scream? Our generation has already (in such an atmosphere) (Part 2) After finally growing up, do we still treat our children like this?&quot; In February 2023, she also went to Turkey to participate in the earthquake relief work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Chen Huiling, who has always shown an optimistic outlook, had not shared her anti-cancer journey on Facebook, we would not have imagined that the disease would have caused her so much suffering. &quot;The physical condition is not something you can control. Those who can maintain mindfulness, take deep breaths, and meditate when the pain makes you roll on the bed are capable people. I am just a mortal.&quot; Even so, she will still be troubled by the growth of her shaved hair. I felt happy because my blood test was normal and I had my eyebrows bleached. I was happy because I heard the teacher talk about her favorite Szymborska in the writing class. Illness can take away a healthy body, but it cannot take away the ability to perceive and convey happiness. She said, &quot;It would be good to move forward a little bit more each day. Even if it doesn&#39;t, it would be good. At least I am still alive and have finished chasing &quot;Fake&quot;. &quot;Face Girl&quot;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 3 pm on November 1, 2023, 48-year-old Chen Huiling passed away in a hospital in Taipei. The final moments were surrounded by family and friends. The splendid life did not want to be trapped in a small box, so she chose to be buried in a tree and return to the earth, which can accommodate all free souls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months before her death, Chen Huiling wrote on her Facebook, &quot;How precious life is, how lovely life is, life is not for complaining, life is for living well.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>