<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[告别“三元时代”，饮料集体提价：“都有经营数据压力”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261176]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:55:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 24/243f95be7b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The price adjustment effect is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverages are bidding farewell to the &quot;Three Yuan Era&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Starting from November 2023, Master Kong&#39;s beverage prices will increase across the board - the retail price of packaging of Master Kong&#39;s tea and juice series products will be adjusted from 3 yuan/bottle to 3.5 yuan/bottle bottle, the retail price of 1L bottle is adjusted from 4 yuan/bottle to 5 yuan/bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Kong iced black tea is favored by users because of its low price and high cost performance. Master Kong’s customer service stated that the price increase was due to rising raw material and labor costs, and that retail prices across the country will be adjusted uniformly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the prices of two sizes of iced black tea in many Wumart supermarkets in Beijing have been consistent with the price adjustment notice. The prices in convenience stores such as Lawson are slightly higher. The 500ml package sells for 4 yuan. The price in online channels is slightly lower, but it is also higher than before. The price of 12 bottles of 1L iced black tea sold in Tingyi Tmall flagship store is 54.9 yuan, which is about 4.6 yuan per bottle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Master Kong is already a latecomer to price adjustments, and this wave of beverage price increases has already begun in the second half of 2022. In February 2023, Nongfu Spring announced that it would adjust the price of 19L bottled water in Hangzhou by 2 yuan, and Yakult also announced that the unit price of original products would increase from 11.7 yuan to 12.8 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historically, this is the fifth wave of price increases in the beverage industry. Since 2006, the domestic food and beverage industry has experienced four price increases, namely in 2010, 2012, 2017, and 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The effect of price adjustment is immediate. Take Coca-Cola as an example. In the second quarter of 2023, Coca-Cola&#39;s revenue increased by 6% year-on-year, exceeding expectations. The important reason is that the price of Coca-Cola increased by 10% compared with the same period in 2022. It is against this background that Coca-Cola President and Chief Financial Officer John Murphy said that Coca-Cola will continue to increase prices in the second half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Beverage companies are all under pressure from operating data.&quot; Zhang Yi, chief analyst of iiMedia Consulting, pointed out to Southern Weekend reporters that there will naturally be comparisons when beverages are sold at low prices. Good sales data, but profits are relatively disproportionate, so companies need to raise prices to increase profits in financial reports. This is the &quot;most direct way.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar prices continue to rise&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao, a partner of Analysys Analysis and Consulting, told Southern Weekend reporters that the rise in sugar prices and packaging bottle raw material prices is the reason for this increase. The reason for the price increase of beverages “is the result of transmission throughout the industry chain.” A Haitong Securities research report shows that among the costs of the soft drink industry, manufacturing and labor on the raw material side account for 20%, white sugar accounts for 15%, and fruit juice accounts for 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Food and beverage marketing expert Yu Runjie told Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, white sugar accounted for 20%-30% of the total cost of beverages, but now many companies choose sweetened sugar. Flavoring agents are used to replace or partially replace white sugar, resulting in a reduction in the proportion of white sugar in costs and a reduction in the correlation between beverage prices and sugar prices. &quot;Of course, the prices of beverage brands and products that still insist on using white sugar will still be greatly affected by rising sugar prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the food and beverage industry , The price increase chain is generally transmitted from global commodity price increases to domestic bulk raw materials, then to the manufacturing industry, and then to midstream consumer goods companies, and finally downstream consumers feel the price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data released by the China Sugar Association in October 2023 show that in the 2022/23 sugar production period, the country will produce a total of 8.97 million tons of sugar, a year-on-year decrease of 590,000 tons. . The cumulative average sales price of finished white sugar by sugar industry enterprises across the country is 6,270 yuan/ton, a year-on-year increase of 516 yuan/ton. The average sales price of finished white sugar in August was as high as 7,035 yuan/ton, while in August 2022 the price was only 5,747 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main sources of sugar production are sugar cane and beets, of which sugar cane sugar accounts for 80%. Due to climate problems such as drought, sugarcane production will drop significantly worldwide in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the case with India, the largest sugar producer. Zhang Yi pointed out that under the influence of geopolitics, energy prices have risen, and more sugar has been used as biofuel. India plans to use 4.5 million to 5 million tons of sugar cane required for sugar production to produce ethanol, which will also occupy part of the sugar cane supply and affect India&#39;s sugar production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is against this background that, according to CCTV news reports, India announced a ban on sugar exports starting in October in response to domestic sugarcane production reductions due to climate change. Sugar supply is tight and prices are soaring. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sugar substitute products are also rising in price&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s not just sugary drinks. Southern Weekend reporters found that in this round of price increases, The prices of some sugar-free drinks have also increased.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, starting from January 2023, Yakult not only increased the price of the regular version, but also the low-sugar version with sucralose. It was adjusted from 12.7 yuan to 13.8 yuan, an increase of about 8.6%, which is equivalent to the regular version. In addition, Suntory&#39;s sugar-free oolong tea and sugar-free version of Vitasoy have also raised prices one after another, by about 1 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, sugar substitute products used in beverages include aspartame, sucralose, erythritol, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The September price adjustment letter from the sugar substitute manufacturer Kangbao Biochemical shows that the price of sucralose products has been adjusted to 180 yuan/kg for large packages and 182 yuan/kg for small packages. Kilogram, it was previously 140 yuan/kg; another company, Jinhe Industrial, adjusted its price twice in a row in September. After the price of sucralose increased from 138,000/ton to 150,000/ton, it was adjusted to 180,000/ton. According to data from Haitong International, the market price of acesulfame potassium also rose from 38,000 yuan/ton to 48,000 yuan/ton in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The increase in the price of sugar substitute products is related to the increase in their raw materials. Herbalife Biochemical pointed out in the price adjustment letter that the price of DMF, the main raw material for glycerol production, has increased by nearly 7,000 yuan/ton, acetic acid has increased by nearly 2,000 yuan/ton, white sugar has increased by nearly 1,000 yuan/ton, sulfoxide chloride and other The price of raw materials generally increased by 300-800 yuan per ton, and all raw materials continued to rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the impact of rising raw material prices, sugar substitute product manufacturers also attribute the increase in sucralose production costs to the approaching heating season, raw material transportation costs, steam energy Consumption costs continue to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At present, not only upstart beverage companies like Yuanqi Forest, but also traditional beverage manufacturers such as Master Kong and Nongfu Spring have launched sugar-free products to seize the market. Coca-Cola&#39;s annual report shows that the sales growth rate of sugar-free Coca-Cola in 2022 will reach 11%, which is much higher than the regular version of Coca-Cola. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on this, Yu Runjie believes that after the price of sugar rises, many companies will choose to replace sugar with lower-cost sugar substitute products, especially in the &quot; In the &quot;zero sugar&quot; trend, more companies are choosing sugar substitute products, which will also lead to a rapid increase in demand for sugar substitute products and an increase in the price of sugar substitute products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/f198ca73ce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;COFCO Sugar stated in the minutes of the investor exchange meeting disclosed on November 1, 2023 that the current domestic and foreign sugar prices are at historically high levels, and are generally expected to remain high next year. There is a gap between supply and demand, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The leader takes the lead in raising prices, and competing products follow up in 3-6 months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Generally speaking, based on market competition Considering that in the face of high-priced raw materials, downstream beverage manufacturers maintain a wait-and-see attitude and choose to postpone the replenishment of sugar stocks or maintain costs through other means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, Guangzhou Langqi stated in its reply to investors that Huatang Food, a subsidiary that operates refined sugar and beverage businesses, carries out arbitrage in white sugar futures and white sugar options. The long-term hedging business effectively avoids and reduces operating risks caused by fluctuations in raw material prices and ensures the relative stability of product costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the continued rise in sugar prices has not stopped. COFCO Sugar stated in the investor exchange meeting minutes disclosed on November 1 that the current domestic and international sugar prices are at historically high levels. It is generally expected that there will still be a supply and demand gap next year, and sugar prices are likely to remain high. Suntory said in the price increase notice that the company has hedged against the increased costs through internal operating cost optimization and other measures. However, the current cost increase &quot;has reached the limit that our company can bear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Manufacturers will also observe the choices of competitors. &quot;If the leading company does not raise prices, it will basically be more difficult for other companies to raise prices, or they will simply not dare to raise prices.&quot; Li Yingtao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Take Master Kong as an example. This round of price increases starting in the second half of 2022 has given it enough confidence. Tingyi&#39;s previous financial report was not good-looking. Goldman Sachs also lowered Tingyi&#39;s sales forecast for the second half of the year in October 2023. Tingyi urgently needs to break the current situation of &quot;increasing revenue without increasing profits&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, the timing of price increases is also a consideration. Beverage price increases are usually carried out in the fourth quarter, the off-season sales season. A beverage distributor told Southern Weekend reporters that it would take 1-2 months for price increases to be transmitted to the sales terminal market, and requested that promotion activities be reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie said that during the peak beverage sales season from May to September, dealers and channels have more goods. If the price is adjusted at this time, firstly, it will easily lead to The second reason is that the market mixes goods and the channels have random prices, which have a greater impact on sales. Adjusting prices after the peak sales season is over can minimize the impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A research report from Ping An Securities also shows that price increases usually occur after 1-2 quarters of rising raw material costs, with leading companies taking the lead in raising prices. Other competing products will follow in about 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Use price increases to increase channel profits? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The exact same drink is more expensive to buy in convenience stores than in large supermarkets, and large supermarkets are often more expensive than online channels. This is because of the price increases in different channels. different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beverage price increases generally include increases at two levels - an increase in factory ex-factory prices and an increase in terminal sales prices, both of which usually occur at the same time. In addition to rising production costs, channel profits are also an important factor affecting price increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yingtao said that channel distribution fees are also the main cost of beverages, accounting for about 20%. In addition, dealers and agents at all levels in provinces, cities and counties play a major role. Cost also accounts for about 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In supermarket containers, the price of a wide range of beverages is generally above 5 yuan, and the price that dealers are willing to pay for these high-priced beverages is generally higher. Currently, channel push is still an important force in the sales growth of FMCG, especially new beverage brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yu Runjie believes that the increase in beverage prices not only increases costs, but also increases channel profits through price increases, so as to improve the channel and The competitiveness of terminal stores. Vitasoy directly pointed out in the price adjustment notice that while the price adjustment is being made, it will &quot;reasonably increase channel gross profit and bring better sales profits to customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Personally, I don’t think that the new beverage brands with higher prices on the market are more high-end in terms of product content, but they just bring more profits to the channel than traditional beverage brands. It&#39;s just higher, which leads to higher selling prices.&quot; Yu Runjie believes that after the price increase of traditional beverages such as Master Kong, the profits at the channel end will increase, the push of the channel will also be enhanced, and the competitiveness of new beverage brands will also be enhanced. From this perspective, price increases will not have a negative impact on sales, and may even increase sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/a058015cf1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 18, 2023, consumers were buying juice drinks in a Wumart supermarket in Beijing. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“There is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On one side, beverage manufacturers are increasing prices; Consumers are looking to downgrade their spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Chinese Consumer Monthly Tracking Data&quot; released by the consulting company Mintel shows that for non-alcoholic beverages, the proportion of consumers with consumption upgrade plans has increased since 2021. It has been on a downward trend since April 2023 and reached a low of 21% in July 2023, ranking at the bottom among all food and beverage categories. At the same time, the proportion of consumers with downgrade plans increased from 11% in April 2021 to 18% in October 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lu Ruixun, deputy director of food and beverage research at Mintel, told Southern Weekend reporters that this shows that even if the unit price is relatively low, consumers&#39; spending on non-alcoholic beverages has changed. Consumers need to be more cautious as price increases may further influence consumers&#39; purchasing decisions for non-alcoholic beverages. The more positive news is that overall consumer demand for upgrades in non-alcoholic beverages still outweighs downgrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Aside from all the rhetoric about rising raw material prices, Zhang Yi particularly noticed that beverages such as Master Kong, Coca-Cola, and Pepsi-Cola are significantly priced compared to trendy domestic beverages. Low. &quot;Young people can actually buy these products whose unit prices are one or two yuan higher, or even two or three yuan higher. Theoretically, there is room for price increases in the market, which is the most important thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;iiMedia data shows that soft drink consumers are mainly young people under the age of 30, and this group is generally not sensitive to price. According to its survey data, taking carbonated drinks as an example, young people’s monthly consumption expenditure on carbonated drinks between 50 yuan and 100 yuan accounts for the highest proportion, reaching 46.4%. Those priced below 50 yuan accounted for 36.5%, and those priced between 100 yuan and 300 yuan accounted for 14.5%. This shows that this group’s demand for beverages in daily consumption tends to be rigid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The data of e-commerce platforms also reflects this. Data from the consumption data platform Star Map shows that during the &quot;Double Eleven&quot; that just passed, online sales of food and beverages were 55.8 billion, accounting for 5.7%, an increase of 3.9 billion compared with 2022, an increase of 0.5 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Zhang Yi also found that consumers&#39; brand loyalty to beverages &quot;is generally not too fixed.&quot; The survey shows that consumers usually switch between two to three brands, accounting for 57.8%, and the proportion of consumers who are fixed on one brand is about 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From this perspective, affordable price tags may not be a good thing for brands. &quot;Our survey found that consumers pay more attention to the brand and the taste of drinks than health. For example, Yuanqi Forest and some other new tea products are more expensive than Master Kong, which does not hinder consumer consumption. Brand influence and Trendiness will play a very important role,&quot; Zhang Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被告人吴亦凡强奸、聚众淫乱案二审维持原判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 11:09:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 24, 2023, the Beijing No. 3 Intermediate People’s Court appealed against Wu Yifan for rape and gathering for lewdness in accordance with the law. The verdict of the case was announced publicly, and the appeal was dismissed and the original verdict was upheld. ​​​&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690 &quot; height=&quot;1739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/92ddba54b96d991f333ca5ccdc0819da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259486&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0 &quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孟庆旸：记住那一抹青绿就好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM5s1DwfYW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM 5s1DwfYW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is probably the busiest year for young dancer Meng Qingyang. On the stage of the 2023 Year of the Rabbit Spring Festival Gala, the dance poetry drama &quot;Only Green&quot; starring Meng Qingyang became popular all over the country and was well known to the public. On multiple social platforms, netizens rushed to imitate her classic dance move &quot;green waist&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Qingyang is a dancer of China Oriental Performing Arts Group and has been dancing for 11 years. She has been the leading dancer in many large-scale national events and foreign affairs events. Dancers are harder to remember than film and television actors. Large-scale dances have a large number of people, a variety of formations, and are covered by makeup and costumes, so most of the dancers&#39; faces are blurred. Now that his work has become popular, Meng Qingyang still maintains his sobriety: &quot;I think labels are not a bad thing. They can help everyone remember the role you played and the image you created. In a few years, people may forget that Meng Qingyang played Qinglu, but they can remember It&#39;s enough to have a touch of green.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, Meng Qingyang performed in Huanggang, Hubei. She is tall and straight, and her dancer&#39;s temperament is fully displayed. Many people rate her as &quot;stable&quot;, which is not only reflected in her stable dancing skills, but also her outstanding personal characteristics. Although during the interview she had to re-answer the questions she had already answered due to equipment problems, she did not show any impatience or displeasure and always kept smiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2021, in the rehearsal hall of China Oriental Performing Arts Group, the main creators talked about the fact that the entire dance drama was based on the Northern Song Dynasty&#39;s masterpiece &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; and used this as the background to create the dance drama. Prior to this, the actors all knew that directors Zhou Liya and Han Zhen were going to produce a dance drama with our company, and everyone had made full preparations. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s view, working with two directors can improve an actor&#39;s artistic career and enhance his artistic aesthetic, so no matter what drama they collaborate on, everyone is fully committed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Green&quot; is a freehand character. In the dance drama, it is the scroll-roller that connects modern times, leading the audience into the landscape of the Song Dynasty. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s eyes, she is like a connector of time and space. Meng Qingyang also experienced many physical and mental twists and turns in playing such a character that has no reference to reality and is even a bit nihilistic. When she first put on the practice skirt, because it was a very long fishtail skirt, the director said that she looked like a mermaid in a wedding dress, without the simple and quiet feeling of a painting. &quot;You have to feel like you are in this painting that lasts for nearly a thousand years, just like the scene where people in our century see the picture of mountains and rivers thousands of miles away.&quot; Through the guidance of the two directors, Meng Qingyang found the direction little by little. and grippers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To create a character, a dancer must first understand the cultural value and connotation behind it. In addition to directing, Meng Qingyang also learned a lot about the art of the Northern Song Dynasty, and went to the Palace Museum to see the working scenes of cultural workers, such as how to restore a painting bit by bit. A painting may need to be restored for several months or even longer. This spirit of devoting himself wholeheartedly to cultural and cultural undertakings made Meng Qingyang feel a certain kind of &quot;immersion and tranquility&quot;. The creative team also invited a number of intangible cultural heritage experts to explain the selection of silk and pigments in &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. Every detail contains rich cultural significance. Only by comprehensively grasping the various aspects of that era can we shape the characters for the actors. Add a little &quot;realness&quot; to the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, Meng Qingyang felt that standing there did not look like the person in the scroll that had been sealed in the museum for thousands of years. However, after a long period of immersion and learning, it was a &quot;sudden enlightenment&quot; when she really knew how to play this role. &quot;All of a sudden, it lights up your nerves and makes you catch Qinglu.&quot; When playing the role of Qinglu seriously, Meng Qingyang found that Qinglu also had a special persistence to work hard. That persistence seemed to guide her to the studio and pick up the strokes. Like &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, she had pictures and infinite reveries in her mind. At that moment, she was green, and green was her. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Immersive encounter with characters&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Qinglu is a freehand character. What qualities did you capture to express this character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The character Qinglu is almost always looking down. When a dancer stands on the stage, the body is the first way to output emotions, and the second is the eyes. But this character lowers his eyes, and there is a sense of alienation as the audience said, and that sense of alienation is very quiet and mysterious. It&#39;s an oriental aesthetic, so it&#39;s quite difficult to grasp this role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember which node you thought you found Qinglu Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the play, the stage design had a large scroll, and I was standing in the scroll. When the music started, the scroll slowly opened, and a very cold light shone on Qinglu. At that moment, she stood there like a scroll that had been sealed for thousands of years. When she moves, the entire space-time scroll moves with it, and then our modern scroll unfolder comes out. At that moment, it is like a human emotion that has been sealed for thousands of years and can only be generated when it moves. I would imagine that my body went from pale to filled with red blood, and gradually gained warmth and human emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think Green will be the most satisfying to you? Works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So far, I can say that it is my most satisfying work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you choose three keywords to describe yourself, Which three would you choose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing I would choose is freedom, because I think I am a person full of freedom in my heart. The second one I think is determination. I started learning dance when I was 5 years old and am now 31 years old. I have been on stage for 11 years. This persistence stems from my determination for dancers and my dance career. The third one can be said to be faith, because I don’t treat dance as a job, but as a faith. In this way, when you face your dance, face the stage, and face the audience every day, you will feel very happy. status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a dancer, he is well known to the public through Qinglu , you have now become a new face in the public eye. How do you understand this kind of accumulation and the word &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I am really lucky, because in fact, we dancers and actors are the same. It is very difficult to find a good role. And dancers are always waiting for good roles. After joining China Oriental Performing Arts Group as a dancer at the age of 20, you will absorb a lot of knowledge. At that time, you want to grow up quickly, gain good experience and mature appearance quickly. When you meet Qinglu at the age of 30, you suddenly slow down because of this character, and slowness is also very determined and powerful. I felt very cherished at that moment, and every day of rehearsal was an immersive encounter with her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The perfect score is not afraid of setbacks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How has dance shaped you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think my personality comes from learning dance since I was a child. Since I was 5 years old, I have had to endure physical pain, such as tearing my hips and lowering my waist, so I feel that dance has given me a character that is soft on the outside and strong on the inside. So until now, I don’t think there’s anything that would particularly break me down. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current status? Can it be called a perfect life? How do you define a perfect life or a perfect state? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am quite satisfied with every situation. Except for the year when I took the college entrance examination, which was quite stressful, I am quite satisfied with the rest. . It’s not like living a perfect life, because I feel that I am only 31 years old, and I have not returned home with a full score, and I still have to keep running. I think it is a psychological state that cannot be satisfied by any material life conditions. I think it is through an experience. I have experienced many setbacks. When I can face these things calmly, it is a very perfect state. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Dance is also a way of expression. Expression is especially important now. Do you think you have been able to express yourself through dance over the years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Dancers do not express themselves through themselves, they must be separated from themselves. For example, when I go on stage at 7:00, I will definitely forget the Meng Qingyang in my life. I will definitely put down my phone and forget what takeaway I ate today, which hotel I stayed in today, where I will go to play tomorrow, everything must be forgotten. The moment you actually get on stage, you&#39;re rendering this character on a blank sheet of paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you take photos of the performance now? Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, sometimes the audience will take some photos. I don’t like taking photos. I don’t like taking selfies and checking in at places to take photos. But I will take photos to record through my perspective, not to photograph me. I think (photography) is like this. All the scenes and states you see at the moment are composed through your eyes, just like painting. Everyone may have different viewing angles and moods. I will use my eyes to compose the picture. When I go to take pictures, there is no need for professional composition or anything like that. I just record them casually. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What kind of photos do you think are worthy of the title? A good photo? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it is a photo with a sense of memory. For example, when flipping through the photo album on your mobile phone, you accidentally turn to this photo, and you will suddenly feel the mood and happiness at that time through this angle and this scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, what kind of mentality should you maintain? Can I leave at any time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t be afraid of the setbacks and difficulties you face. Many people say that setbacks and difficulties are good things. I don’t think they are good things, but I think we must first start from our own mentality and not be afraid of these things. When you really do something and it doesn&#39;t succeed, just accept its failure. I believe that my next thing will be better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[臭虫重启“全球旅行”，人类如何甩掉“吸血鬼”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023 local time, Seoul, South Korea, to prevent Bed bugs are spreading, and railway rolling stock staff in the capital are disinfecting subway facilities to prevent the epidemic. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of a bug, this is a story about restarting the journey in 2023 after being depressed for three years due to the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beginning in France in August 2023, bed bugs have caused panic in many countries in Europe and Asia. According to Yonhap News Agency&#39;s report on November 8, South Korea reported 30 suspected or confirmed bed bug infections, and the government announced the establishment of a joint bed bug response command to declare war on bed bugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bedbugs, also known as bedbugs, are the size of mung beans, have a foul odor, come out at day and night, and specialize in sucking human blood. In the 1960s, it was one of the &quot;four pests&quot; along with flies, mosquitoes, and rats. Later, it disappeared due to the advent of chemical pesticides such as DDT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a type of wingless insect that feeds on human blood, bed bugs usually travel long distances with the help of suitcases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It identifies the host through carbon dioxide, heat signals and human body odor, follows the &quot;human smell&quot; to get into the gaps in the suitcase, and hides in dirty clothes with sweat. . By the time the suitcase is opened again, the bedbugs may have crossed continents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have never been bitten before, and I thought it was allergies. Now I am very scared, and I completely killed it at home.&quot; On November 11, Zhang Minru came from South Korea When I returned to Beijing from Seoul, I found traces of bed bug bites on my body. It was only after taking into account recent media reports that I discovered that I had been infected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, the Food and Environmental Hygiene Department of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Government issued an announcement stating that in order to minimize the chance of bed bugs being introduced into Hong Kong from overseas, it has worked with relevant authorities Departments and agencies have strengthened publicity and education work at different levels and will closely monitor the situation and developments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed 11 patients who had suspected or confirmed bed bug bites and found that bed bugs often appear in families with a recent history of business travel. In China, it occurs most frequently in the Pearl River Delta region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Jianguo, a professor at Jiangxi Agricultural University and technical director of Nanchang Jiangnong Pest Control Co., Ltd., told Southern Weekend reporters that bedbugs did not suddenly break out, but have always existed in society. In the short term, the possibility of widespread epidemic in mainland my country is low, and whether it constitutes a &quot;crisis&quot; remains to be discussed. On November 21, Chongqing Disease Control and Prevention tweeted &quot;Don&#39;t panic if bed bugs are active again, correct treatment is key&quot;, pointing out that there have been cases of bed bug infestations in Chongqing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, bed bugs do not pose a threat to human safety, but they are a big problem for individuals. After being bitten, the skin is often itchy, and some people will have it. Allergic reactions affect work and life.&quot; Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bed bugs are rampant as tourism recovers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bugs cannot fly, but they can travel with humans around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Changlu, an urban pest control expert and professor of the Department of Entomology at Rutgers University in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that since the late 1990s, due to the increase in the international movement of people, prevention and control Due to insufficient investment and resistance to insecticides, bed bugs are re-emerging around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen, associate professor at the Department of Entomology, School of Plant Protection, South China Agricultural University, has long been committed to research on bed bug biology and comprehensive prevention and control. He told Southern Weekend reporters that currently bed bugs are responsible for many All types of insecticides have developed significant resistance. The increase in resistance is directly related to the insect&#39;s behavioral resistance, resistance gene mutations and body wall thickening. The thickening of the body wall will lead to a weakening of the permeability of the pesticide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Natalie Bangay of the British Pest Control Association said that bed bugs have been a public health problem in the UK for many years. Found across the UK, having seen a decline during Covid due to a lack of global travel, any growth in bed bugs may now simply be a return to normal as people return to free movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The British &quot;Guardian&quot; reported that France&#39;s national health and hygiene agency Anses found that 11% of French households were plagued by bed bugs between 2017 and 2022. With the 2024 Paris Olympics approaching, the presence of insects suspected to be bedbugs in the Paris subway, trains, cinemas and airports has caused concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many entomology experts told Southern Weekend reporters that bed bugs most often appear in places with dense crowds, high population mobility, and untidy environments, such as dormitories. , train carriages, massage chairs at high-speed rail stations, and movie theaters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thigtaxis and phototaxis require bed bugs to settle in a dark environment where their bodies are surrounded by four sides, so bed bugs usually hibernate in small dark places. After having the opportunity to feed on the host&#39;s blood, the flat body will swell into a ball. They have a pair of stink glands on their bodies that release a foul-smelling fluid when frightened - hence the name bedbugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9F67146102.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 819 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9F67146102.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259417 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Symptoms of the human body are bitten by a bug. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; A few allergic people will have an allergic shock when they are serious &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The other name of the bug is the bed lice, after entering the family environment They will climb up the mattresses such as mattresses and sofas along the furniture legs. If the furniture is against the wall, they will also climb from the gap between the wall to the furniture. Although the active diffusion distance is very short -a study published in PLOS One (&quot;Public Science Library: Comprehensive&quot;) found that the distance between the active diffusion of the bug was only a few meters to tens of meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Wei, who is in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that when the bugs in the family were the most fierce, she once held a flashlight in the middle of the night to find &quot;It will appear anywhere, including clothes, beds, plush toys, walls, toilets ... Its larvae are particularly small, small enough to be like a needle, and occasionally climb your mobile phone screen. Sometimes you find it on the bed to find on the bed. A thing like fat particles is it. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Wang Deson told the southern weekend reporter that after being bitten and blood-sucking by a bug, the human body will have a lot of discomfort. For example, erythema pimples or blisters will appear in the biting parts, and skin damage and secondary infection caused by scratching will also occur. In severe cases, allergic shocks and life -threatening will occur. Because the bug hiding is hidden, it is only difficult to capture than mosquitoes at night. Long -term troubles in the troubles of the odor will cause people to have symptoms such as insomnia, anxiety, neurasthenia, and mental depression. Although there is no report on the diseased disease, a large number of studies have shown that a variety of pathogens related to human diseases can be detected in the body, so the worm is still an important media for human disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A citizen who lived in Hong Kong encountered a bug two years ago. It will explode my mentality on the week. It will be itchy and painful when the wound encounters hot water. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; It should be noted that the traces of the bite can not be judged whether the traces of the bite cannot be judged whether From the bug. In an interview with BBC, Natalie Bang also stated that the concentration of media or the public about the concentration of the odor of the bug often leads to misunderstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Deson found in the survey that many residents are prone to confuse the bugs, fleas, lice, tadpoles, and mites. Flies are like flying ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Factory dormitory and group rental houses are high incidence areas &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Burmese belongs to the department of semi-winged foam, which is highly popular temperate insects and tropical tropics and tropical tropical The bug is closely related to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At present, the largest bug in China was hosted by Deng Guofan of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Feng Lanzhou, the Chinese Academy of Medical College. Deng and Feng collected China 81 between 1950-1951 Bewamed specimens in the region, research results &quot;CIMEX Lectularius L., CIMEX HEMIPTERA F. Geographical Distribution in China&quot; was published in 1953. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The above studies have shown that both green bugs and tropical bugs have been discovered in China. Tropical bugs are mainly distributed in Guangdong and Guizhou provinces. , Northeast and northwest provinces generally occur, and Xiamen, Fujian, Qujiang (Shaoguan City), Guilin, Guangxi, Montzi, Yunnan, Guiyang, Guizhou, and other places are also distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Jianguo introduced that the popular bed lice in the world usually refer to green strap. In China, temperate odor bugs are distributed in the Yangtze River and the Yellow River Basin, but South China is also distributed and is worldwide. Tropical bugs are distributed in South China, Taiwan and tropical regions. Wang Deson believes that with the changes in the indoor environment brought about by the warming of climate and the use of northern heating, tropical bugs may also appear in temperate regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/543Ded6239.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 682 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543Ded6239.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259418 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Ginseng bug adult and tropical bug adult. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Southern Weekend reporters looking for domestic patients on social platforms to be bitten by the abnormal bugs in China. The triangle region is consistent with the existing research conclusions in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Researchers and other researchers in 2013 have published a investigation survey against insects in Shenzhen, and found that the workers in the Dongguan and Shenzhen Industrial Zone were found. The collective dormitory is the heaviest, with an average positive rate of 52.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Deson surveyed the hazards and prevention of insects in some areas of Guangdong between 2017-2019 and found that Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Dongguan, Foshan, Guangzhou, etc. There are bugs in the ground, and factory dormitories and rental houses with dense personnel, strong liquidity, and poor sanitary conditions are high incidence areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;We visited the factory dormitory and found that many factories had insect harm, and the back and forth scheduling of employees in different factories could easily cause the diffusion of the bug.&quot; Wang Deson said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Avoid prevention and control, recommend non-chemical means &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Although it is difficult for the bug to form a &quot;crisis&quot; that threatens human health at this stage, the patient &quot; The experience of being bitten by hundreds of red bumps &quot;proves that it still has the power of&quot; suffering &quot;, and it is necessary to take scientific control measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The prevention and treatment of insects include physical control, chemical prevention, and comprehensive prevention and control. For ordinary residents&#39; families, it is recommended to use comprehensive prevention and control methods for physical control and chemical prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; physical control, refers to the use of heat treatment, inorganic powder, and insect interception device to prevent and treat bugs. Based on the characteristics of high temperatures that are very sensitive to high temperature, residents can clean up and dry bed supplies and clothing, and use hot steam machines (such as hanging perm) to deal with the harmfulness of furniture and items. After the heat treatment, the air humidity is reduced, and the inorganic powder represented by diatomic soil can also effectively kill the bugs in the corner of the stench, the bed frame, and the mattress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 498 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259419 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The hiding location of the bug. Wang Demon | Photo &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is necessary to point out that the common misunderstanding of the insects is to place the furniture that discovered the bug in the sun. Because the temperature of the sun exposure cannot instantly reaches the death temperature (50 ° C), it may cause bugs to spread to other unbroken places, especially in apartments or residential buildings with many rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;In general, chemicals are not recommended, because commonly used in the market to be poisonous It is not recommended. If you need to use it, you should strictly follow the recommended dosage of the agent. Do not use it in a place where the sofa, bed, etc. are directly exposed to the human body. &quot;Wang Changlu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For people who often travel and travel, Wang Deson recommends that mosquito repellent water spray luggage in time, check and clean the suitcases and box underwear in time to avoid Bring the bugs into home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In a densely personnel community, once the bug burst out, all houses in the entire community are risked by infringement. Therefore, during the prevention and control of insects, governance should be considered in the entire community. Wang Deson pointed out that after removing the bug, he must also establish a long -term awareness of prevention. You can regularly check the corners of the bed, the gaps of the wall, etc. to determine whether there are traces, molting or feces of mosaic activity, molting or feces; in addition, long -term monitoring of placing the traps under the bed can also be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; For dense places such as hotels, schools, unit collective dormitories, etc., Wang Jianguo suggested that PCO (harmful biological prevention) enterprises for professional monitoring and thorough disinfecting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;It is difficult to do a kind of pests to destroy &#39;completely. Caused a great harm. In addition to the &quot;Four Hurgers&quot; for so long, humans have been fighting them, but as long as people enhance their awareness of prevention and treatment of insects, it can avoid its large -scale outbreak. It may become a big harm like cockroaches, flies, and mosquitoes. &quot;Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (in the text Zhang Minru, Zhang Wei is a pseudonym) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陆仙人：从乡村地头走到巴黎时装周]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261166]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4jYjgJrc6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4 jYjgJrc6h. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Lu Xianren appeared for the first time on the Paris Fashion Week show. He was invited to walk the show, wearing a black silhouette suit, white trousers and a neat hairstyle. He was one of the few non-scientific models present, and his starting point on the catwalk was on a rural road in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Lu Xianren, who was working in Guangdong, quit his job and returned to his hometown in Guangxi to shoot short videos full-time. He always wanted to be a model, so most of the photos he took were of him walking in shows. The clothing is all homemade, made from woven bags, blankets, waterproof plastic sheets, old lampshades, branches, leaves... match the upper body and walk in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked hard for more than a month, but the account was not as popular as he imagined. It was already summer, and the sultry weather also affected his mood: Was he unable to achieve results no matter what? It&#39;s better to be more casual and show yourself. So in the high temperature, he put on the red blanket at home as clothes and walked barefoot for a while. This random move immediately brought about a heat stroke and high fever, but it also brought a huge number of likes. Lu Xianren woke up from his sleep and saw the number of likes on the video rising, and even doubted the authenticity of the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, this video became popular on the platform, with more than 2 million likes. He&#39;s on fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short video era gives everyone the opportunity to experience the &quot;15 minutes of fame&quot;. It has become easy for ordinary people to produce a popular video. In the ocean of traffic, there will always be a point where you can Hit a group of people. However, it is not easy to make this flow sustainable. But Lu Xianren did not hesitate. When he decided to shoot short videos full-time, he had already conceived many ideas. So if it wasn’t because of the red blanket that it became popular, would it also be because of other creative ideas? Lu Xianren laughed at this: &quot;Not necessarily.&quot; He still showed a cautious attitude towards his fame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren, whose real name is Lu Kaigang, was born in Heng County, Guangxi in 1999. His parents worked outside all year round, and he was raised by his grandparents. When he was in fifth grade, he saw a modeling competition on TV and was attracted by the models&#39; aura and outfits. It became his dream to walk on the catwalk. From then on, when he got home from school, he would take time to practice Tai step. He was originally a little hunched, but after practicing he opened his shoulders and held his head high. When practicing, hold a book on your head. &quot;The book cannot go away, so the steps are formed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After three months, the book is firmly on the head. &quot;But what I learned more is their confidence on the stage and the way they want to express themselves on the stage.&quot; Today&#39;s Lu Xianren said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dropping out of middle school, Lu Kaigang went to Guangdong to work. He worked as an apprentice in a barber shop and a restaurant, and then worked in a factory. He used his spare time to continue his modeling studies. He recorded videos and compared them with professional models&#39; pace, down to the time to keep his head and the number of seconds to pause when positioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, he started shooting his own videos. When choosing the nickname for his account, he thought of his home in the mountains. Every day when he got up, he could see the mist outside the window. It was &quot;very fairy&quot;, so he named himself &quot;Lu Xianren&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year later, he decided to quit his job and return to his hometown to shoot short videos full-time. &quot;Give yourself half a year, and if it doesn&#39;t work, go back and work honestly.&quot; Hence the subsequent story. After that, his creative juices flowed and his modeling career got on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren is 180 centimeters tall and wears women&#39;s clothing in most of the videos. This time it was not understood. Some relatives saw the video and ran to ask Lu Xianren&#39;s family: &quot;Why is your child like this?&quot; Grandma said: Young people have their own ideas, and they must have their own reasons for what they do, so just leave them alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo taken by Honor 100 series)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My current life is not It counts as a full score, but try to go in the direction of full score&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 3 In March, you participated in the Paris Fashion Week catwalk for the first time. You are a new face in the international fashion world. What new characteristics do you think you have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The fashion industry has never lacked new faces. On the international stage, I have been recognized by more people, and the global fashion media have discovered me. A new face, discovering maybe a new strength. Mainly, I (this type) are relatively rare in the fashion industry, and I personally feel more special. And &quot;new&quot; represents a new force, the ability to move forward, and an opportunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;catwalk on the international stage and in the countryside What&#39;s the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I personally think it is a change in mentality. At the beginning, when I walked the show on rural trails and country roads, I was just enjoying the scenery, which I thought was beautiful. After going to Paris Fashion Week, I felt a little nervous for the first time. I slowly adapted and enjoyed it. I slowly began to interact with the audience and resonate with the designers. I seemed to have a passion for their clothes and their love. Perception, there is a spiritual connection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The show left in your mind What is the first screen? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; When the last curtain was tested, the audience beckoned with the designer and applauded. I have walked in so many shows, some of which were applauded by the audience, and some of which the audience left immediately after the show. In that show, most of them stood up and applauded. They must have found something they like and resonated with. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The way you appear in the camera is very professional , what kind of training have you received for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;While visiting the scene, I observed some photography teachers. In what state did they take photos? I think taking pictures has something to do with the state. I don’t like to pose in a pose for taking pictures, or to set up a big scene for taking pictures. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I personally take photos more casually. When I encounter good scenery or beautiful things, I will take pictures and record them. I bought a smartphone in 2016. At that time, I was still shooting the scenery, I didn&#39;t dare to shoot myself, and I was not very confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think a good photo should look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing is to attract attention, and then have a sense of story and impact. I may not pay much attention to a certain detail in the whole photo, but I will pay attention to the general appearance. A photo cannot be 100% perfect, 98% or 95% perfect, and this photo may be remembered for a long time. I don’t really like to make perfect photos. When I photoshop, I will keep my flaws and spots. I am still satisfied with myself and pay more attention to the quality of the photos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any suggestions for everyone to take photos? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If you are not particularly confident, then you don’t have to look at the camera all the time. The camera is not that important. Taking photos is to record what is happening at the moment. When you are not looking at the camera, you can fully show your relaxed state. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My confidence comes from my love for the lens, plus I like taking pictures - the feeling of the camera clicking out. The moment the camera presses the shutter button, it records the present moment. I think it is a very magical thing. Nowadays, everyone can take a camera and take pictures at any time. When I take pictures, I don’t necessarily mean what kind of pictures I will take. When I take pictures, I record what I want to do at the moment. When you look at it later, you will know that you were quite happy at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How would you rate your current life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the ideal full-scoring life is half life and half the work. But I think it doesn’t have to be perfect to have a perfect life, it depends on the pace of life. For example, I may have been very busy some time ago. After finishing my work, I went home to take a rest, spend time with my grandma, and look for new inspiration. Life and work need to coordinate with each other. My current life is not perfect, but I will try my best to move towards it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从入园难到关停潮，高速增长15年的幼儿园数量迎来拐点丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会顺利闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261168]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 21:24:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 23, the closing event of the Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was held in Shenzhen International, Guangdong Province Held at the Convention Center. Yu Jiadong, deputy director of the conference organizing committee and deputy minister of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, and Lin Tao, deputy director of the conference organizing committee and vice governor of Guangdong Province, attended the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484000c0413bb5e94fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;392&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484000c0413bb5e94fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259427&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At the closing event, the conference announced the final winning projects of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition and the list of winners of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Skills Competition. Representatives of the final award-winning projects of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition roadshow display, 12 human resources services On-site signing of supply and demand projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a68f9ac859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a68f9ac859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259429&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98abfa2c995c1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98abfa2c995c1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23f95df018807535855354580dccd1fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23f95df018807535855354580dccd1fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference achieved fruitful results. 144 leading human resources service companies and key employers in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area participated in the exhibition. 294 human resources service cooperation projects were negotiated and docked during the conference, with an intended amount of 20.7 billion. Yuan, the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area youth talent recruitment activities provide more than 50,000 high-quality jobs online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/96af7e89af02ae54faad37f372086e58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/96af7e89af02ae54faad37f372086e58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259432&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713b5a21840ece0263755c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713b5a21840ece0263755c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c1500f0af88.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c1500f0af88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837f66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837f66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770bc55b77c916a267369fc81.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770bc55b77c916a267369fc81.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259434&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human Resources Society Responsible comrades of the Ministry of Security, relevant units of Guangdong Province and Shenzhen City, responsible comrades of the Human Resources and Social Security Departments (Bureaus) of all provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, experts and scholars, representatives of human resources service agencies, key employers, and media reporters Attend the closing event of the conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636e4adbd5a23072100e910fbbe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636e4adbd5a23072100e910fbbe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259435&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[瓦依那乐队：哪段水域都不能代表这条河流]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261164]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/RCWqUthWT9bwFoGh9mNh9XvHssFluG0f7YPvWT8s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/RCWqUthWT9bwFoGh9mNh9XvHssFluG0 f7YPvWT8s. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage of the third season of &quot;Summer of the Band&quot;, the song &quot;Big Dream&quot; made the Waina band popular, and there were many invitations to perform. This debut has been for more than 10 years The band has become a very popular new face this summer. The lives of the three members are filled with various schedules, which are far more intense than the busy schedule of farming. Before they stand on the stage, they live in the ground. Ban farmers are busy planting in spring. Passers-by work as bricklayers on construction sites all year round, and occasionally go to the streets to sing and sing. Shiba was farming in his hometown and working as a street singer in Guilin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to maintain the order of life as much as possible in Vaina&#39;s busy life, the three members have agreed to spend half the month wandering outside and the other half living at home. For now, they are still looking for a new rhythm. Lu Min and Shiba have not yet adapted to the sudden increase in cameras and flashlights. They feel uncomfortable facing the camera, their eyes flicker, and they don&#39;t speak much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, Shiba went to the streets to sing, spending half the time singing and the other half taking photos with the audience. He made a promise to himself: go there at least once a month. &quot;After all, it&#39;s been 18 years since I first started singing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, &quot;Big Dream&quot; - using age as a node, written from birth to death, has every age Duan&#39;s Dilemma - Before the stage broadcast, we conducted an exclusive interview with the Waina band. They detailed the beginning and end of the establishment of the Waina band and the lives of the three individuals. But at that time, there was still a short period of time before they really became popular, and they belonged to the &quot;former Waina&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will they change? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Real creation is a portrayal of people’s sense of distance on the land of this era&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You performed outstandingly in &quot;Summer of the Band&quot;. Although it has been 10 years since your debut, you are a new face to the public. What do you think of this “newness”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The reason why we went to participate was just for a stage. I have loved writing songs for a long time, but I haven’t had the opportunity to communicate with everyone. This stage allows us to freely express our original attitudes. Sing the songs we want to sing authentically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of Lumin and Shiba, they are indeed young and new. And I (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Editor&#39;s Note: 岜 岜 而 &lt;/span>;) has sang for many years, but I just heard that everyone heard this stage for the first time. Some of our songs have a different angle from the songs that everyone often hears, and (the audience) has a new feeling. But it is not new to us. We have always been ourselves. What is new (in the eyes of the audience) is something very old about us. It has always been some of our emotions and states of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjPeNhz0AExO9YK8KzSq2BkFbY9EhfybgPc3kk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjPeNhz0AExO9YK8KzSq2BkFbY9EhfybgPc3kk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ban farmers inspect old rice varieties in their fields&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After getting on this stage, will the invitations and performances that are pouring in come to me? Destroy your rhythm of life and affect your original attitude? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If we don’t have a clear direction, we will be destroyed, but if we have a good direction, it is not destruction; To help us build the state we want, it mainly depends on how we grasp it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We still pay more attention to our own lives, and now we have agreed to spend half a month living at home and half a month doing more communication outside. Of course, this half-month plan is a regular plan. If you are busy with farming or have something to do at home, you can adjust it slightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will your creations be affected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s still land, it’s the relationship between land and people, it’s something real (things) related to life, coming from experience A little more stuff. We prefer to express some emotions from contemporary real life, rather than purely creating or imagining something. This kind of thing derived from reality also has artistic modification techniques. But man is a thing on the land and has a close relationship with the land. Many of people&#39;s sorrows today may be a sequelae of a certain separation between people and the land. People must be inseparable from a relationship with the land and life as a whole, including the countryside and the city. If your creation is real, it must be a portrayal of a person&#39;s sense of distance on the land in this era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have no limits on what we want to create, but there may be a starting point. The Wayna band wants to retain the style of Wayna, but we all have other creations privately, some very different creations based on personal hobbies. But in Waina, it is better not to go off topic. Like when we sing now, we have a little interaction, but in fact I (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Editor&#39;s note: Banong &lt;/span>;) Make some pure music, which is not very similar to Waina’s songs. I have also tried a lot of electronic music. Therefore, we limit our vision to the countryside and describe some changes in people and nature, people and society in contemporary rural areas. This is the main style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A song like &quot;Big Dream&quot; is not considered traditional Waina style, but it has attracted many people now. Will your future creations be biased? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is still close to a portrayal of real life, like &quot;Grandma Returns&quot; written by Lu Min. That song is Hakka. But Waina is from the Zhuang ethnic group, so that’s fine. It’s still a very rural and authentic creation. The so-called reality means that it is like something growing out of the ground. It does not mean that we just make a flower. Of course, that is also a kind of beauty and a kind of consciousness, but Wayna prefers this aspect (reality). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(Everyone likes &quot;Big Dream&quot;) It&#39;s okay, everyone likes it. Let&#39;s just sing &quot;Big Dream&quot; three times first and then sing country. Good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It mainly depends on how to design. Everything has to be redesigned. There is no fixed life or a satisfactory life for you. , you should (adjust) it based on comfort and realism at any time, and don’t drift. We are quite free and can allocate our time as much as possible. If you want to go out and sing tonight, you can go out. If you don&#39;t want to go out, you can&#39;t go out. Take the initiative to do things without getting tired. It’s a bit hard to be regulated and do it. It was difficult for me to eat because I was probably trying to sleep at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Waina Band was not a banker at the beginning , Lu Min and Shiba 3 members, will you stick to the current lineup in the future? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is sometimes like asking whether you will get divorced after getting married? I feel like it&#39;s flowing, don&#39;t try to kidnap a band. I hope that everyone will do something with their heart wherever they go, instead of just doing it for the sake of making money. Regardless of whether we stay together or not, everyone can continue to sing and live life truthfully. This is the most important thing. If the three of us get tired of our relationship and want to break up, then we will break up. But it doesn’t matter. From now on Shiba can continue to write good songs, I can continue to make music, and Lu Min can continue to sing the songs he wants to sing. This has nothing to do with whether we break up or not. The important thing is to always maintain the expression and experience of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You enjoy the feeling of being photographed in front of the camera ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shakes his head&lt;/span>; )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wayna:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;岜农&lt;/span >;) Usually I can take pictures if I want to. I still like to take pictures of picking wild fruits and pricking them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think is the standard for a good photo? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes I look through my hard drive and find some photos that I thought were interesting at the time and beautifully posed, but in fact they are not. use. What&#39;s really useful? I did it, I filmed it. It reminded me of the actual experience and feelings of doing that thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you define a perfect life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Everyone should be different. He should find his most comfortable state, live freely, and be able to realize the meaning of life. Everyone is looking for that spot in him, and I found it early on. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The word &quot;full marks&quot; divides life. From the perspective of the whole life, every stage is a part of your life, just like a river. Which section do you like best? Waters? In fact, no stretch of water represents the river. I think every individual is a perfect score. If you can love yourself and let go like this, you will be a perfect score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨曾志平：坚守正确就是意义所在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping, the first doctor of military law in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1966 in Yudu County, Ganzhou, Jiangxi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1984-July 1988, studied at the Nanchang Army Academy of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army , received a bachelor&#39;s degree in military science. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1988-1995, successively&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as an officer of the People&#39;s Liberation Army stationed in Zhangzhou, Fujian and an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1995-July 1998, studied at Xi&#39;an Political College and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2004, he served as an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy and a military lawyer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 2004-January 2007, studied at China University of Political Science and Law, receiving a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Ph.D. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From January 2007 to August 2018, he served as professor and senior professor of Nanchang Institute of Technology Professor, Dean and Vice President of the School of Political Science and Law. From July to August 2010, he served as a visiting scholar at the China Research Service Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;April 2012-April 2013, at the University of California, Hastings He served as a visiting scholar at the School of Law (now the University of California, San Francisco School of Law) and the U.S. Institute of Military Justice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 2018-January 2019, served as the Faculty of Law, Xiamen University Kah Kee College professor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2019 to January 2022, he served as the Wenzheng College of Soochow University/Suzhou City Professor of the Department of Law and Political Science of the college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2023 to present, he serves as a professor at the Law School of Guangzhou Business School. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zeng Zhiping is China&#39;s first doctor of military law. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping is China’s first doctor of military law. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the PhDs interviewed, Zeng Zhiping may be the last to obtain a PhD. In January 2007, he graduated early from China University of Political Science and Law and became China&#39;s first doctor of military law - 24 years had passed since the first batch of doctors trained after the reform and opening up were awarded degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as a secondary discipline under the category of law, the process of military law becoming a discipline is relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1984, legal scholars Zhang Youyu and Pan Nianzhi first proposed that military law is a branch of the legal system in the &quot;Encyclopedia of China·Law Volume&quot;; three years later, in May 1987, the former State Education Commission Formally listed military law as a branch of law; in 1993, the first teaching institution in the country to engage in military legal education -Xi&#39;an Institute of Political Science (now the Xi&#39;an Campus of the School of Political Science, School of Political Science of the People&#39;s Liberation Army) was established. Military law professional education is officially on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, Xi&#39;an Political College became the first school with the right to award a doctorate in military law; in the same year, China University of Political Science and Law opened a military law research center. In 2004, China University of Political Science and Law began to recruit doctoral students in military law. Also in this year, Zeng Zhiping, who had the rank of lieutenant colonel, transferred from Nanchang Army College and was admitted to China University of Political Science and Law in September of the same year, becoming the only doctoral student in military law enrolled that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Zhiping studied under Professor Zhou Jian, a well-known expert in the field of military law and the first director of the Military Law Teaching and Research Office in China. Zhou Jian once pointed out in an article: &quot;Among the top ten legal disciplines identified by the Ministry of Education, military law (030110) can be said to be the one with the least talents and the most difficult to research.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with law Among other majors, military law is a relatively mysterious and niche subject. Before changing careers, Zeng Zhiping worked in the army for 21 years. In a sense, it was his status as a soldier that gave him the opportunity to specialize in military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zeng Zhiping’s view, today’s “openness” of military law is related to the atmosphere of the rule of law and the society’s demand for military legal talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Military academy, army, and then to military academy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1984, you were admitted to Nanchang Army College (now the Army Infantry College of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army) as an undergraduate student. Why did you choose a military school at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our time, especially in rural areas, everyone’s life was not guaranteed. The ones with relatively better treatment were the military. . When I graduated from high school, I participated in the military draft. At that time, I was recruited to be a pilot, and the requirements were relatively high. I was rejected during the physical examination. When Nanchang Army Academy came to recruit students, the head teacher recommended me. I didn’t have any particularly strong ideas at the time, but my father thought it would be good to be an officer, so he went for it. If you want to say that I have any strong (ideas) towards the military or officers, I don’t think I have any. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is special about undergraduate education in military academies? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Before I went to the military academy, I didn’t know much about the military or the military academy, but physical training was the most beneficial thing for me in the military academy. When I first went to school, I couldn&#39;t do any pull-ups. The school organized physical training, and during the training process, I made the fastest progress. Later, I became an all-around athlete in school and also participated in military sports competitions. Some of the teachers are from the army and will teach tactics, shooting, military fitness, formation and the like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating from Nanchang Army Academy, what did you do Which jobs? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduation, I was sent to the front-line army in Zhangzhou, Fujian. At that time, I was a platoon leader in a regiment. After a few months, I was transferred to the agency. During the training of all division cadres, the instructor of one training subject did not demonstrate accurately, so the regiment leader &quot;picked&quot; me out. Later, I became an instructor for many projects. This (experience) made me stand out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been in the front-line army for four and a half years. I have served as an officer in the Organizational Section of the Political Department and as an instructor. After the Lantern Festival in 1993, I was transferred to Nanchang Army Academy to teach, which I applied for on my own initiative. At that time, I went to the Marxist-Leninist Teaching and Research Office, and the director of the Military Teaching and Research Office asked me: &quot;Why don&#39;t you come to me?&quot; He was my instructor when I was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In school, I taught Introduction to International Politics when I first arrived because there were relatively few teachers taking this course at that time. I was also interested in the introduction to law class, and after one semester, I was teaching introduction to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Discipline Positioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why will you continue? Study law on your own? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s a bit of a coincidence that something happened in the spring of 1993 that had a great impact on college students across the country: the International College Debate Competition , the one Jiang Changjian and the others participated in. It was really interesting for us to watch this competition at that time. Jiang Changjian majored in National Politics, so I wanted to go to Fudan to study for a graduate degree in International Politics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But later at school, I learned that several young men we hung out with were preparing to take the bar exam. I felt that this matter was definitely the right thing to do. After weighing it, I said that I would study law instead of international politics. International politics is a &quot;dragon-slaying art&quot; and law is more practical. In 1994, I began to study law on my own in accordance with the requirements of the bar qualification examination syllabus. In October of that year, I ranked first in the military and qualified as a lawyer. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Note: The national judicial examination system had not yet been established at that time, and you could obtain lawyer qualifications by passing the bar qualification examination.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When I took the postgraduate entrance examination, I was not afraid of majors related to law. Because I had already passed the bar exam and my brain was good at that time, I thought I could pass the exam for any major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You already teach in a military academy, why do you want to study for a master&#39;s degree? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I had not thought about leaving the army at that time, but I did want to leave Nanchang Army Academy. Many professors in the school are older. I feel that if I don’t leave the school, I may not be as good as them when I get older. However, it is still relatively difficult to transfer to the army. The postgraduate entrance examination is a means of leaving school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to take the international law major at Wuhan University, but someone told me that if you study as a graduate student at a local university, you have to go back to your original school after graduation, because it is impossible for local universities to You stay. So I chose Xi&#39;an Political College, which is also a military school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think about it, if I had gone to Wuhan University from the beginning, my academic foundation might have been more reliable. If I received systematic academic training when I was young and read a lot of books, then my most source knowledge would be complete and my academic research would have a beginning and an end. My current knowledge cannot reach this level, which is a lifelong regret of mine. Now I mainly feel that my years have been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you were studying for a master&#39;s degree, what did you know about military law? Do you have any idea about what kind of disciplines and what kind of problems are to be solved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is true because I have a background in law. I have read a lot of materials before and also studied military law. In my master&#39;s degree, my direction is military justice, mainly studying the military prosecutorial system. What impressed me most was that I read a lot of English materials at that time and discussed with some famous professors the structure of criminal theory of the three levels of German and Japanese criminal law. This also had a great influence on me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You developed a love for military law during your Ph.D. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I can’t say it’s love. I just accumulated knowledge to a certain extent and have an understanding of this subject. On the other hand, I see a lot of work that is poorly written. I feel that my participation in this subject may make it better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Let’s go back to discuss the positioning of the discipline of military law Question, do you think it belongs to the branch of military science or the branch of law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It depends on how you treat belonging. This issue can be discussed from the subject management of the Ministry of Education, from the professional fields involved in the subject, and from the classification of knowledge. I only recognize the classification of knowledge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In June 2022, Wenzheng College of Suzhou University, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) is with students. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022 In June of this year, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) was with students at Wenzheng College of Soochow University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I am also a product of the times”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you graduated with a master&#39;s degree, your original plan was to continue on the academic path? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, before graduation, I want to go to the Shanghai Military Procuratorate or leave the original school. At that time, I returned to Nanchang and took an introduction to law class at school. Because there were several teachers taking the same course, I could only attend a few classes in one semester. In addition to taking classes at the military academy, I was also teaching part-time at several private universities. It can be said that teaching has nourished my psychology. In private universities, many students look at you with hungry and passionate eyes, which is different from what I encountered at my original school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then why did you go to China University of Political Science and Law? Where&#39;s Beau? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a bit of a coincidence. I had always wanted to change my job before the Spring Festival in 2004, but at that time the unit leader had not announced our job. There is news that I can change my job, I am just applying. At that time, I saw the information about various schools recruiting Ph.D.s, and I was thinking, &quot;Will it be approved (for career change) this year?&quot; Around January 10, 2004, after my application for job change was approved, I quickly checked the admissions information of various schools. I had always wanted to go to Wuhan University, but the registration had closed at that time. However, that year, because the Chinese Political Science and Law added a new doctoral program in military law, its registration period was extended, so I signed up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When looking at school admissions information, I will also consult some teachers. I met Teacher Zhou Jian when I was studying at Xi&#39;an Political College, and I called him. I originally wanted to major in criminal law, and I have been teaching criminal law. Then teacher Zhou Jian said, you don’t want to major in criminal law. I teach military law in China’s political and legal field, so you can study military law with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also told Teacher Zhou, &quot;I have changed careers, why should I study military law? I am still more interested in criminal law.&quot; Therefore, military law is really a product of the times, and I am also a product of the times. It is a coincidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Was the competition fierce to apply for a doctorate in military law at China University of Political Science and Law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, China University of Political Science and Law had three professors who could teach PhD students in military law, but that year only Professor Zhou Jian enrolled students, and the quota only one person. I was particularly impressed. There were 10 people who signed up at that time. I also checked the scores of other candidates using the score checking rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rule for checking scores at that time was to just enter your admission ticket number. According to the numbering method of the admission ticket number, the first digits are the same, and the difference is in the last single digits and tens digits. Based on where we were in the exam room at that time, I could probably guess how many people were in front of me and behind me. After I checked my scores, I guessed their numbers, and I actually found out my scores. Seeing that the second place was 20 points lower than me, I was easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How will it be for you to get a doctorate from China University of Political Science and Law? Something more important? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this is a very important turning point in life. At that time, I changed my career and had a doctorate in military law. Teacher Zhou said, China’s political and legal affairs will definitely keep you, so my life plan at that time had a general direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for my master&#39;s degree, I once went to Beijing. While reading in the Beijing Library, I met an old gentleman. He went to an event at Peking University and we had a brief chat. He said something to the effect of &quot;If I can go to Peking University to be a professor in this life, I can do whatever I want.&quot; I had a very imaginary idea at that time: It would be great if I could become a professor of political science and law in China, so sometimes life is very strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there were some changes later, and I did not stay at China University of Political Science and Law after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cognition is the core of personality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You Studying for a master&#39;s degree is to leave the original school; studying for a doctorate is to stay in a new school. So these choices you made were not based on professional choices? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have always wanted to teach in a better university, but people are like duckweeds of the times. My current thoughts may be more mature thoughts, because my career is nearing the &quot;end&quot;. I think it is like this: you need to go to school, your school, the teachers and classmates you meet should work together to help you find your interests in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think an ideal society should be one where everyone is encouraged to do what you want to do and find your interests and passions. If every young person&#39;s growth is to learn based on his own love, then this will enhance his love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The first doctor of military law after the founding of New China&quot; label, for Has it had a big impact on your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t realize this when I graduated. In 2007, my son was going to take the college entrance examination. My simple thought was, can I graduate early? If I stay in China Political Science and Law, it will be very convenient for my son to go to school in Beijing. But my son didn&#39;t think it was necessary. He got good grades and was admitted to Wuhan University. But I finished my thesis and graduated half a year ahead of schedule. I didn’t mean to be the first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I passed the graduation thesis defense in the morning, and the &quot;Legal Daily&quot; reported it in the afternoon. Later, some foreign media also followed up and reported the matter. It still seems very interesting now. I don’t know if the foreign media paid attention to the first doctorate in other disciplines, but at that time many foreign media reported on me and even mentioned the title of my thesis &quot;On Military Power&quot; and said that I was interested in Such a major theoretical issue is well researched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t told anyone about this label myself. Now that I have to say it has brought me any special benefits, I don’t think it has. After all, I haven’t used it to apply for a job. Or do some publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., you applied for Nanchang Institute of Technology and were ordered to establish Nanchang Institute of Technology Department of Political Science and Law, College. Compared with the “five colleges and four departments” in the legal world, what do you think the law department of a private university should look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I came to Nanchang Institute of Technology in 2007 and received the National Social Science Fund in 2008. At that time, there were only a dozen colleges and universities with law departments and law majors in Jiangxi, so it had a great impact. For a long time, the school regarded me as a signature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of undergraduate education, I am very conscious. I have not included military law in the professional courses of law undergraduates. I have only made it a public elective course for the whole school. It would be very shameless if you become the head of the department or the dean of the law school and then turn your own courses into professional courses, compile textbooks, and ask people to buy your books. Until now, I have not compiled a textbook on military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I started the courses based on the most basic law undergraduate major. If there is anything special about it, it can be said that I taught several very important general courses: general logic, grammar and rhetoric, introduction to political science, introduction to sociology, etc. At that time, these courses were not available in law schools. universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, we became the construction unit for the master&#39;s degree awarding project in Jiangxi Province, which was issued by the relevant units. I want students to receive a good education, which can also be regarded as a relatively direct achievement at work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the sense of accomplishment I get from teaching also gives me the motivation to continue. Why do I keep teaching? It&#39;s because I think there are many mistakes now, and teaching is also wrong teaching. Sometimes I say it very negatively, even though I am definitely not popular, I can at least eliminate those false popular ones, because I occupy a position, so that there is one less false popular person. Location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I stick to what is right, that’s what it means to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any experiences or ideas that you would like to share with current college students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is true that people cannot escape the fate of duckweed, but whether they care about knowledge or not is always different. After all, cognition is at the core of personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起底缅北电诈头目祝寿视频背后产业链：有明星报价一条14万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261143]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Which celebrities can be invited to record blessing videos for less than 2,000 yuan/5,000 yuan/10,000 yuan?&quot; &quot;Backstage private message recording of celebrity blessing video&quot; &quot;can be released in 3 days!&quot; Many celebrities were exposed to have filmed birthday videos for the leader of telecom fraud in northern Myanmar, causing an uproar. Recently, reporters from Nandu and N Video found on some e-commerce and social platforms that there are still an endless stream of merchants hyping and selling &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;birthday boy&quot; who caused the controversy is Bai Yingcang, the son of Bai Suocheng, one of the four major families in northern Myanmar. Bai Jiaci is recognized as the head of the &quot;four major Kokang families&quot; in northern Myanmar. Zi, who is also the deputy director of the Kokang Finance Bureau and the captain of the Kokang Autonomous Region Militia Brigade, controls Cangsheng Science and Technology Park, an electronic fraud park. Even though some celebrities said that filming a birthday video for them was &quot;out of favor&quot; and they did not know them, it still failed to dispel netizens&#39; doubts. The &quot;Celebrity Blessing Video&quot; industry chain has once again entered the public eye. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is it illegal to make a birthday video for a scammer? &quot;Celebrity blessing videos&quot; have been around for a long time. How is the trend now? Why are consumers so keen on buying, and how do celebrities view this phenomenon? Reporters from Nandu and N Video interviewed entertainment company agents, buyers and sellers of blessing videos, lawyers and experts, etc. to get to the bottom of the industry chain behind &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259403 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Someone promotes celebrity blessing videos on social platforms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Controversy: Celebrities send video of birthday wishes to Dian Toutou&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Here, I I wish Bai Yingcang a happy birthday and a bright future...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After several leaders of telecom fraud groups in northern Myanmar were arrested, a message &quot;Many celebrities paid tribute to the four major families in northern Myanmar. The news that Cheng&#39;s son Bai Yingcang recorded a video to celebrate his birthday caused an uproar in public opinion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this birthday party, the large screen in the center of the stage played congratulatory videos from many stars, including Hong Kong artists Eric Tsang, Wong Yifei, and Charlie Chao, as well as actor Du Xudong and crosstalk actor Hou Yaohua. wait. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eric Tsang, known as the eldest brother of the Hong Kong film industry, explained to the outside world, &quot;It may be that friends help each other by saying, &#39;This is my good friend&#39;, and then record it. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;After this, some unfamiliar people will try to avoid it.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Actor Charlie Cao released an apology video He said that he came back from Canada in August last year. &quot;When the manager sent this thing over, I asked why it seemed to be a dialogue from Jiang Hu, and I didn&#39;t want to shoot it. He said it&#39;s okay, many celebrities have filmed it, so I filmed it.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He said that he didn’t know where the manager put the video. Many celebrities did it for money. “I made this video just for money, because I want to live and live. There is no way to eat, but I have never communicated with the people in northern Myanmar. &quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Nandu reporters found that before this incident, there had been similar &quot;overturning&quot; of celebrity blessing videos. Artist Yang Di once fell into a whirlpool of public opinion for filming a promotional video for a P2P platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July 2020, a large number of investors reported on social networks that the loans on the &quot;Lili.com&quot; platform had not been paid after they expired, and posted on Yang Di&#39;s Weibo account , calling on him to speak out about the &quot;Yiwang Fraud&quot; incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Subsequently, Yang Di issued a statement on Weibo, stating that he recorded the video for the promoter during the movie promotion period and was not the spokesperson of &quot;Yiliwang&quot;, nor did he record the video. Charge any fees. &quot;I will help the users who were deceived in this incident to pursue the case to the end, and I deeply apologize to the viewers who suffered losses due to the video recommendation.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is the reason why celebrities record blessing videos? For favor or for money? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July this year, Hong Kong media reported that Luo Jiaying and other actors shot exclusive blessing videos to endorse online club groups. Some people were deceived and transferred tens of thousands of yuan to stock trading platforms. Afterwards, the money cannot be withdrawn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Afterwards, Luo Jiaying admitted, &quot;I read the script according to the arrangement of the manager. I don&#39;t know this person.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Quotes: Someone has to collect an intention fee of more than four figures before making an inquiry&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 22, a Nandu reporter used keywords such as &quot;celebrity blessing video&quot; A search on some e-commerce and social media platforms found that many users with the words &quot;celebrity agent&quot; and &quot;media culture&quot; in their names have posted multiple celebrity blessing videos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Click on the user&#39;s homepage, and the introduction will have a prompt of &quot;backstage private message celebrity blessing video recording&quot;. Several sellers showed the Nandu reporter a quotation list, which included the celebrity&#39;s name, avatar, masterpieces, and the price of recording blessing videos for personal and commercial purposes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Most of them are singers, &lt;/span>; actors, hosts, and Chinese and foreign athletes from the Mainland, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. In the same quotation, the price difference is huge, as low as 100 yuan, and as high as 140,000 yuan. There are also celebrities who appear in the alternatives without price tags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259401&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The price of a celebrity shooting blessing video shown on a quotation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A seller introduced&lt;/span>; that the price quoted by such celebrities is more than 100,000 yuan. If you want to name them to record a video, the seller will need to charge more than four figures. Only if you need an intention fee, you are willing to contact the star company to inquire about the quotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen &lt;span>;Jian (pseudonym), who claims to work in the media circle, admitted to Nandu reporters that the prices of celebrities are naturally different depending on their status. Faced with doubts about the higher prices compared with peers, he said, &quot;The difference lies in the service.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He recommended a Taiwanese actor’s blessing video service with a quotation of 30,000 yuan. On the quotation sheet of Zhang Yong (pseudonym), the actor’s quotation was 23,000 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I offer low prices without any additional fees.” Zhang Yong claimed to be an artist manager and a first-hand general agent. “I can not only connect with media companies, but also You can connect with artist managers, or even directly contact the celebrities themselves.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Chen Jian said that the duration of celebrities&#39; blessing videos is generally controlled within 30 seconds, and in addition, the specific details need to be The content is reported to the star, and an accurate quote can only be given after confirming that it can be recorded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another seller, whose name is from a media company, made it clear to Nandu reporters that the video length is generally about 10 to 15 seconds, &quot;the normal speaking speed is 20 to 25 seconds.&quot; Between the words.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for the production time, it is generally determined according to the star&#39;s own time. &quot;It usually takes about 7 days, if faster, 3 to 5 days.&quot; Some sellers also write that &quot;it can be released in 3 days.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Yong revealed that his quotation list marked a group of celebrities who often record blessing videos because they are &quot;highly cost-effective, fast, and highly cooperative.&quot; Be recommended to buyers first. Some lesser-known celebrities will take the initiative to ask him to help recommend and record them first. The blessing videos of such celebrities will be &quot;packaged&quot; and sold at a uniform price. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some sellers told Nandu reporters that although some &quot;top&quot; names appeared in the quotations, in fact they did not accept orders specifically for A-list celebrities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for which celebrities are “top-tier”? &quot;Let&#39;s put it this way, you feel that celebrities or athletes who have endorsed many brands will basically not record blessing videos.&quot; Chen Jian said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Regulations: Some companies have clear regulations&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Why are celebrities recording blessing videos so popular? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai (pseudonym) once spent more than 200 Australian dollars (over 900 yuan) to purchase and customize two clips of English football legend Michael Owen on Cameo, an overseas video customization website. blessing video as an encouragement to myself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;603&quot; height=&quot;933&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259400 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Maimai received a blessing video recorded by Irving. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She fell in love with Owen when she was young and started to play football. It has been 17 years now. She recalled to Nandu reporters that when she decided to buy the video, she was going through a divorce and ended a seven-year relationship. She needed encouragement. &quot;When words of encouragement come from the mouth of an idol, it feels different.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai got the video&lt;/span>; within about a week after paying. And the moment she saw the video, she felt it was all worth it. &quot;This video gave me strong strength and belief at the lowest and saddest time in my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Guiping, associate professor of the Department of Audiovisual Communication, School of Journalism and Communication, South China University of Technology, analyzed to Nandu reporters, like The recording of videos by celebrities is a satisfying and public presentation of their mimetic intimacy, but there is another situation as well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individuals have profit-seeking appeals to the appeal of celebrities. &lt;span>; In layman&#39;s terms, it can be understood as &#39;traffic&#39;, that is, using the celebrity&#39;s popularity to increase one&#39;s visibility and discussion. Some even It can be directly converted into fans and platform revenue on social media platforms,” she said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters saw from Zhang Yong’s “Buyer Show” that there were many enthusiastic orders from various companies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;The psychological demands of companies for celebrities to record videos are more pure. There is no relationship demand, but mainly interest demands.&quot; Huang Guiping explained that in fact, it is to take advantage of the celebrity&#39;s popularity and Public trust endorses one&#39;s products, brands, and company image, reducing the public&#39;s doubts and uncertainty when purchasing its products. &quot;This kind of &#39;bringing goods&#39; is relatively risky for celebrities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Peng (pseudonym) is the manager of a well-known domestic female talent show team. He told Nandu reporters that he usually tells the artists directly that the company has clear regulations that do not allow recording of these blessing videos. &quot;In my opinion, these incomes are not scientific.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At work, he will strictly distinguish the nature of video recording. &quot;For example, for holiday greetings or cultural promotion, we will charge &#39;travel fees&#39; for recording as appropriate. &lt;span>;But if you record a video for an enterprise, it is a proper business behavior. Our requirements will be higher and we will not just record it easily.&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters found that sellers who sell celebrity blessing videos often do not only engage in this business. Celebrity business endorsements, rummage videos, commercial performances, group photos... In the profiles they showed, various celebrity-related businesses emerged one after another. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259402 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The seller shows a business case of celebrities recording blessing videos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“They often have commissions.” Sun Peng revealed to Nandu reporters, “In fact, the fixed salary of artist agents is not high, and sometimes they all earn commissions by doing work for others. Or rebate. But everyone has their own life, and it is difficult to evaluate the quality of this phenomenon.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Risk: Celebrities may be held legally responsible&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Celebrities recording blessing videos may seem like a business deal that can be concluded with just a few words, but in fact there are hidden risks that cannot be ignored. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If it is a birthday occasion, celebrities record blessing videos out of favor or for a fee, which generally does not violate public order and good customs, but if it involves platform, &quot;endorsement&quot; and other properties, it cannot be easily understood As &quot;if one party is willing to give money, the other party can shoot&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiaxin, a lawyer at Guangdong Guangxin Junda Law Firm, analyzed to Nandu reporters that providing blessings to individuals can be regarded as an economic behavior for fans. This form is not a civil legal act and does not actually infringe legal interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if a celebrity shoots a blessing video for a company or product, due to the celebrity&#39;s celebrity effect, such videos are actually using advertising language &lt;span>; and positive statements to imply or express the outside world&#39;s view of the company or product. Enterprises and products should be widely promoted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Therefore, this type of video is an act of advertising endorsement. If the company involved in the video blessing is suspected of illegal business, and the star has knowledge of the business, the star is also suspected of breaking the law and will be held liable. Responsibility.&quot; Wang Jiaxin said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When it was revealed that many celebrities had recorded birthday videos for telecom fraudsters in northern Myanmar, many netizens questioned, &quot;Why did the telecom fraud leader harm so many innocent people? Is he celebrating his birthday?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;But if these blessing videos are later exposed to congratulate the leader of the electronic fraud, the netizen&#39;s report is actually not valid, because they are personal blessing videos and are not It’s not targeting the company.” Wang Jiaxin further explained that if a celebrity’s blessing video emphasizes an electronic fraud company, it must also be proven that the celebrity is aware of the company’s suspected electronic fraud, such as whether the celebrity participates in the company’s operations or holds shares in the company, but It is generally difficult to prove. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As the manager of a well-known domestic talent show girl group, Sun Peng also feels that &quot;irregular forms of cooperation&quot; such as recording blessing videos will increase the risks to the artists themselves. . At the same time, he also admitted that sometimes companies spend millions of yuan to invite artists to participate in brand promotion and endorsement. During the promotion process, it is actually difficult for artists to refuse the company&#39;s request to take photos or record videos. Once you agree, how the subsequent photos and videos will be used by the other party is uncontrollable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Before relevant laws, regulations and policy provisions are introduced for control, the transaction of celebrities shooting congratulatory videos will indeed be in a gray area, which will lead to what we call&#39; There is a hidden worry of recognizing money but not people.&quot; Huang Guiping, a communication expert, told Nandu reporters that in the absence of regulations and controls, celebrity individuals, companies, and consumers are all in a state of lack of protection, which is likely to lead to a situation where everyone loses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Therefore, when relevant departments take action, celebrities realize the consumption of their own image and turn back, or companies realize that the efficiency of benefit conversion is low but the risk is high, this If any of the three situations occurs, it is possible that the &#39;celebrity blessing video chaos&#39; can be alleviated.&quot; Huang Guiping said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄乌电子战，矛与盾的游戏丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQgEpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQg EpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, in the Donetsk region, unmanned troops of the Ukrainian army Aircraft operators are training not far from the front line &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Ukrainian military claimed that it had Soldiers drove out their positions on the east bank of the Dnieper River in the occupied Kherson area and established multiple bridgeheads. Russia also admitted for the first time that the Kiev army had crossed the Dnieper River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is of course a result worthy of attention, because the establishment of a bridgehead on the east bank of the Dnieper River poses a great threat to Crimea. If Ukraine can deploy long-range weapons on the east bank, Crimea may It’s hard to stick with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General Zaluzhny, Commander-in-Chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, emphasized in an interview with The Economist that Ukraine needs to develop and deploy its own advanced technology to regain the upper hand in the war. Behind the establishment of the bridgehead It is the tactical advantages brought about by a series of technological updates, especially in electronic countermeasures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the outbreak of the Russo-Ukrainian War, Ukraine has been engaged in invisible electronic countermeasures with Russia. The battle in the Kherson area is the forefront of this confrontation, because the two sides can often only use it across the river. Long-range firepower exchanges, so drones become the key to victory, because both sides rely heavily on drones to find targets and correct artillery. Whoever can use electronic countermeasures to suppress the opponent&#39;s drones will gain an advantage in the battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the most efficient way to fight drones is to suppress them through electromagnetic interference, which will directly cause the drone to crash. It has been previously reported that the area near the Dnieper River has become a no-fly zone for drones, because both sides will use electronic jamming methods to suppress and interfere with the flight of drones. On this invisible battlefield, the two sides have been engaged in a very complex and cruel battle. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For nearly a century, electromagnetic interference has been an important part of warfare. Traditional electronic warfare methods are to find the radio frequencies being used by the enemy and create overwhelming noise on the same frequencies, making it impossible for the opponent to attack use. In World War II, electronic warfare mainly targeted radio communications and radar. As long as the opponent was unable to communicate and detect, the mission was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern communication technology has developed various means to combat electronic interference, but the main reason is not just for electronic warfare, but because there are a large number of electromagnetic signal sources in human society. During World War II, a 50-watt radio could easily carry out point-to-point communications in China and even East Asia. However, now it is difficult for a 50-watt radio to cover even one province - this is not because the radios back then were more advanced, but because the radios were more advanced. It was because the electromagnetic environment was good back then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electromagnetic communication can be regarded as a conversation between two parties. If the room is very quiet, the two parties can hear what the other party is saying without making a loud sound. If there are not only many people chatting in the room, but also people watching movies, shooting balls, playing and singing, then the two parties must raise their voices or be very close to each other when communicating. The reason why modern communication technology attaches great importance to anti-interference is because the electromagnetic background environment is too complex, making it impossible to complete communication simply by increasing power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Software technology is also improving. For example, in the past, changing the frequency and signal characteristics of a radio station required replacing hardware. However, with the softwareization of radios, only changing the encoding can completely change the spectrum of the equipment. In other words, problems that in the past required major repairs after being interfered with can now only be solved by adding a patch to the software, or even reusing the software to replace the encryption method. In the past, to change the encryption method, each receiving end needed to change the machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;UAVs used in the military generally use more complex control methods to combat interference. For example, frequency hopping is used to connect back-end control, which can skip the interfered frequency band. This is commonly used in radio communications. Anti-interference means; you can also use inertial navigation in the case of interference, continue to execute the original flight path, and then connect satellite navigation and rear control when the interference weakens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, as the ability to resist interference becomes stronger, the ability to resist interference will also become stronger accordingly. Spears and shields compete with each other and develop with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, as long as your electronic warfare capabilities are strong enough, you can construct an electronic golden bell that prevents all drones from flying in and prevents precision-guided weapons from hitting targets in the golden bell. If the interferer&#39;s equipment reaches 100% power, anti-interference methods are often difficult to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the reality is that interference means cannot provide full-level signals in all areas, which depends on the location of the interference source, the orientation of the antenna and its own power. The drone is a mobile platform that can continuously fly for reconnaissance and interfere with weak signal locations to find better flight routes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And sometimes the problem can be solved in less &quot;electronic&quot; ways, such as using radio triangulation to directly find the approximate location of the interference source, and using long-range firepower to cover the opponent, even if it misses the target. It can force the opponent to shut down temporarily to avoid the blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, there are many tactics in actual combat that can weaken the effect of the opponent&#39;s electronic interference, and these tactics themselves are also an important part of electronic warfare. Therefore, there is no omnipotent secret weapon. On the invisible battlefield of electronic warfare, only by continuously strengthening technology and constantly changing and updating countermeasures can we gain an advantage in action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx. run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>