<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[孟庆旸：记住那一抹青绿就好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM5s1DwfYW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Bqru7WMcdfHRqls0ItzRUG3DZZT75HxM 5s1DwfYW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is probably the busiest year for young dancer Meng Qingyang. On the stage of the 2023 Year of the Rabbit Spring Festival Gala, the dance poetry drama &quot;Only Green&quot; starring Meng Qingyang became popular all over the country and was well known to the public. On multiple social platforms, netizens rushed to imitate her classic dance move &quot;green waist&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Qingyang is a dancer of China Oriental Performing Arts Group and has been dancing for 11 years. She has been the leading dancer in many large-scale national events and foreign affairs events. Dancers are harder to remember than film and television actors. Large-scale dances have a large number of people, a variety of formations, and are covered by makeup and costumes, so most of the dancers&#39; faces are blurred. Now that his work has become popular, Meng Qingyang still maintains his sobriety: &quot;I think labels are not a bad thing. They can help everyone remember the role you played and the image you created. In a few years, people may forget that Meng Qingyang played Qinglu, but they can remember It&#39;s enough to have a touch of green.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the interview, Meng Qingyang performed in Huanggang, Hubei. She is tall and straight, and her dancer&#39;s temperament is fully displayed. Many people rate her as &quot;stable&quot;, which is not only reflected in her stable dancing skills, but also her outstanding personal characteristics. Although during the interview she had to re-answer the questions she had already answered due to equipment problems, she did not show any impatience or displeasure and always kept smiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2021, in the rehearsal hall of China Oriental Performing Arts Group, the main creators talked about the fact that the entire dance drama was based on the Northern Song Dynasty&#39;s masterpiece &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; and used this as the background to create the dance drama. Prior to this, the actors all knew that directors Zhou Liya and Han Zhen were going to produce a dance drama with our company, and everyone had made full preparations. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s view, working with two directors can improve an actor&#39;s artistic career and enhance his artistic aesthetic, so no matter what drama they collaborate on, everyone is fully committed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Green&quot; is a freehand character. In the dance drama, it is the scroll-roller that connects modern times, leading the audience into the landscape of the Song Dynasty. In Meng Qingyang&#39;s eyes, she is like a connector of time and space. Meng Qingyang also experienced many physical and mental twists and turns in playing such a character that has no reference to reality and is even a bit nihilistic. When she first put on the practice skirt, because it was a very long fishtail skirt, the director said that she looked like a mermaid in a wedding dress, without the simple and quiet feeling of a painting. &quot;You have to feel like you are in this painting that lasts for nearly a thousand years, just like the scene where people in our century can see the picture of thousands of miles of rivers and mountains.&quot; Through the guidance of the two directors, Meng Qingyang found the direction little by little. and grippers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To create a character, a dancer must first understand the cultural value and connotation behind it. In addition to directing, Meng Qingyang also learned a lot about the art of the Northern Song Dynasty, and went to the Palace Museum to see the working scenes of cultural workers, such as how to restore a painting bit by bit. A painting may need to be restored for several months or even longer. This spirit of devoting himself wholeheartedly to cultural and cultural undertakings made Meng Qingyang feel a certain kind of &quot;immersion and tranquility&quot;. The creative team also invited a number of intangible cultural heritage experts to explain the selection of silk and pigments in &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. Every detail contains rich cultural significance. Only by comprehensively grasping the various aspects of that era can we shape the characters for the actors. Add a little &quot;realness&quot; to the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, Meng Qingyang felt that standing there did not look like the person in the scroll that had been sealed in the museum for thousands of years. However, after a long period of immersion and learning, it was a &quot;sudden enlightenment&quot; when she really knew how to play this role. &quot;Suddenly, it lights up your nerves and makes you catch Qinglu.&quot; When playing the role of Qinglu seriously, Meng Qingyang found that Qinglu also has a special persistence to work hard. That persistence seemed to guide her to this studio and pick up the strokes. Like &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, she had pictures and infinite reveries in her mind. At that moment, she was green, and green was her. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Immersive encounter with characters&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Qinglu is a freehand character. What qualities did you capture to express this character? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The character Qinglu is almost always looking down. When a dancer stands on the stage, the body is the first way to output emotions, and the second is the eyes. But this character lowers his eyes, and there is a sense of alienation as the audience said, and that sense of alienation is very quiet and mysterious. It&#39;s an oriental aesthetic, so it&#39;s quite difficult to grasp this role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Remember which node you thought you found Qinglu Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the play, the stage design had a large scroll, and I was standing in the scroll. When the music started, the scroll slowly opened, and a very cold light shone on Qinglu. At that moment, she stood there like a scroll that had been sealed for thousands of years. When she moves, the entire space-time scroll moves with it, and then our modern scroll unfolder comes out. At that moment, it is like a human emotion that has been sealed for thousands of years and can only be generated when it moves. I would imagine that my body went from pale to filled with red blood, and gradually gained warmth and human emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think Green will be the most satisfying to you? Works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So far, I can say that it is my most satisfying work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you choose three keywords to describe yourself, Which three would you choose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first thing I would choose is freedom, because I think I am a person full of freedom in my heart. The second one I think is determination. I started learning dance when I was 5 years old and am now 31 years old. I have been on stage for 11 years. This persistence stems from my determination for dancers and my dance career. The third one can be said to be faith, because I don’t treat dance as a job, but as a faith. In this way, when you face your dance, face the stage, and face the audience every day, you will feel very happy. status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a dancer, he is well known to the public through Qinglu , you have now become a new face in the public eye. How do you understand this kind of accumulation and the word &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I am really lucky, because in fact, we dancers and actors are the same. It is very difficult to find a good role. And dancers are always waiting for good roles. After joining China Oriental Performing Arts Group as a dancer at the age of 20, you will absorb a lot of knowledge. At that time, you want to grow up quickly, gain good experience and mature appearance quickly. When you meet Qinglu at the age of 30, you suddenly slow down because of this character, and slowness is also very determined and powerful. I felt very cherished at that moment, and every day of rehearsal was an immersive encounter with her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The perfect score is not afraid of setbacks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How has dance shaped you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think my personality comes from learning dance since I was a child. Since I was 5 years old, I have had to endure physical pain, such as tearing my hips and lowering my waist, so I feel that dance has given me a character that is soft on the outside and strong on the inside. So until now, I don’t think there’s anything that would particularly break me down. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current status? Can it be called a perfect life? How do you define a perfect life or a perfect state? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am quite satisfied with every situation. Except for the year when I took the college entrance examination, which was quite stressful, I am quite satisfied with the rest. . It’s not like living a perfect life, because I feel that I am only 31 years old, and I have not returned home with a full score, and I still have to keep running. I think it is a psychological state that cannot be satisfied by any material life conditions. I think it is through an experience. I have experienced many setbacks. When I can face these things calmly, it is a very perfect state. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Dance is also a way of expression. Expression is especially important now. Do you think you have been able to express yourself through dance over the years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Dancers do not express themselves through themselves, they must be separated from themselves. For example, when I go on stage at 7:00, I will definitely forget the Meng Qingyang in my life. I will definitely put down my phone and forget what takeaway I ate today, which hotel I stayed in today, where I will go to play tomorrow, everything must be forgotten. The moment you actually get on stage, you&#39;re rendering this character on a blank sheet of paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you take photos of the performance now? Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, sometimes the audience will take some photos. I don’t like taking photos. I don’t like taking selfies and checking in at places to take photos. But I will take photos to record through my perspective, not to photograph me. I think (photography) is like this. All the scenes and states you see at the moment are composed through your eyes, just like painting. Everyone may have different viewing angles and moods. I will use my eyes to compose the picture. When I go to take pictures, there is no need for professional composition or anything like that. I just record them casually. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What kind of photos do you think are worthy of the title? A good photo? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it is a photo with a sense of memory. For example, when flipping through the photo album on your mobile phone, you accidentally turn to this photo, and you will suddenly feel the mood and happiness at that time through this angle and this scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, what kind of mentality should you maintain? Can I leave at any time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Meng Qingyang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t be afraid of the setbacks and difficulties you face. Many people say that setbacks and difficulties are good things. I don’t think they are good things, but I think we must first start from our own mentality and not be afraid of these things. When you really do something and it doesn&#39;t succeed, just accept its failure. I believe that my next thing will be better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[臭虫重启“全球旅行”，人类如何甩掉“吸血鬼”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 23/bdcecf6ad2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023 local time, Seoul, South Korea, to prevent Bed bugs are spreading, and railway rolling stock staff in the capital are disinfecting subway facilities to prevent the epidemic. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of a bug, this is a story about restarting the journey in 2023 after being depressed for three years due to the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Beginning in France in August 2023, bed bugs have caused panic in many countries in Europe and Asia. According to Yonhap News Agency&#39;s report on November 8, South Korea reported 30 suspected or confirmed bed bug infections, and the government announced the establishment of a joint bed bug response command to declare war on bed bugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bedbugs, also known as bedbugs, are the size of mung beans, have a foul odor, come out at day and night, and specialize in sucking human blood. In the 1960s, it was one of the &quot;four pests&quot; along with flies, mosquitoes, and rats. Later, it disappeared due to the advent of chemical pesticides such as DDT. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a type of wingless insect that feeds on human blood, bed bugs usually travel long distances with the help of suitcases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It identifies the host through carbon dioxide, heat signals and human body odor, follows the &quot;human smell&quot; to get into the gaps in the suitcase, and hides in dirty clothes with sweat. . By the time the suitcase is opened again, the bedbugs may have crossed continents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have never been bitten before, and I thought it was allergies. Now I am very scared, and I completely killed it at home.&quot; On November 11, Zhang Minru came from South Korea When I returned to Beijing from Seoul, I found traces of bed bug bites on my body. It was only after taking into account recent media reports that I discovered I had been bitten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 8, the Food and Environmental Hygiene Department of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region Government issued an announcement stating that in order to minimize the chance of bed bugs being introduced into Hong Kong from overseas, it has worked with relevant authorities Departments and agencies have strengthened publicity and education work at different levels and will closely monitor the situation and developments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters randomly interviewed 11 patients who had suspected or confirmed bed bug bites and found that bed bugs often appear in families with a recent history of business travel. In China, it occurs most frequently in the Pearl River Delta region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Jianguo, a professor at Jiangxi Agricultural University and technical director of Nanchang Jiangnong Pest Control Co., Ltd., told Southern Weekend reporters that bedbugs did not suddenly break out, but have always existed in society. In the short term, the possibility of widespread epidemic in mainland my country is low, and whether it constitutes a &quot;crisis&quot; remains to be discussed. On November 21, Chongqing Disease Control and Prevention tweeted &quot;Don&#39;t panic if bed bugs are active again, correct treatment is key&quot;, pointing out that there have been cases of bed bug infestations in Chongqing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, bed bugs do not pose a threat to human safety, but they are a big problem for individuals. After being bitten, the skin is often itchy, and some people will have it. Allergic reactions affect work and life.&quot; Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bed bugs are rampant as tourism recovers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bugs cannot fly, but they can travel with humans around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Changlu, an urban pest control expert and professor of the Department of Entomology at Rutgers University in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that since the late 1990s, due to the increase in the international movement of people, prevention and control Due to insufficient investment and resistance to insecticides, bed bugs are re-emerging around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen, associate professor at the Department of Entomology, School of Plant Protection, South China Agricultural University, has long been committed to research on bed bug biology and comprehensive prevention and control. He told Southern Weekend reporters that currently bed bugs are responsible for many All types of insecticides have developed significant resistance. The increase in resistance is directly related to the insect&#39;s behavioral resistance, resistance gene mutations and body wall thickening. The thickening of the body wall will lead to a weakening of the permeability of the pesticide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), Natalie Bangay of the British Pest Control Association said that bed bugs have been a public health problem in the UK for many years. Found across the UK, having seen a decline during Covid due to a lack of global travel, any growth in bed bugs may now simply be a return to normal as people return to free movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The British &quot;Guardian&quot; reported that France&#39;s national health and hygiene agency Anses found that 11% of French households were plagued by bed bugs between 2017 and 2022. With the 2024 Paris Olympics approaching, the presence of insects suspected to be bedbugs in the Paris subway, trains, cinemas and airports has caused concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many entomology experts told Southern Weekend reporters that bed bugs most often appear in places with dense crowds, high population mobility, and untidy environments, such as dormitories. , train carriages, massage chairs at high-speed rail stations, and movie theaters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thigtaxis and phototaxis require bed bugs to settle in a dark environment where their bodies are surrounded by four sides, so bed bugs usually hibernate in small dark places. After having the opportunity to feed on the host&#39;s blood, the flat body will swell into a ball. They have a pair of stink glands on their bodies that release a foul-smelling fluid when frightened - hence the name bedbugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9f67146102.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;819&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9f67146102.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Symptoms of human body being bitten by bed bugs. Wang Desen | Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A few people with severe allergies will suffer from anaphylactic shock&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another name for bed bugs is bed bugs. After entering the home environment , they will climb up mattresses, sofas and other human resting places along the legs of furniture. If the furniture is against the wall, they will also climb onto the furniture from gaps in the wall. Although this active dispersal distance is very short - a study published in PLOS ONE (&quot;Public Library of Science: General&quot;) found that bed bugs actively dispersal distances are only a few meters to tens of meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Wei, who lives in the United States, told Southern Weekend reporters that when the bed bugs were at their worst, she used a flashlight to look for them bit by bit in the middle of the night. , &quot;It will appear anywhere, including in clothes, on the bed, stuffed toys, walls, toilets... Its larvae are very small, as small as a needle tip, and will occasionally crawl across your phone screen. Sometimes they are found on the bed It’s something like a fat particle.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen told Southern Weekend reporters that after being bitten and sucked by bedbugs, the human body will experience a lot of discomfort. For example, erythematous papules or blisters may appear at the bite site, and skin damage and secondary infection may occur due to scratching. In severe cases, anaphylactic shock may occur and be life-threatening. Because bed bugs hide and only appear at night, they are more difficult to catch than mosquitoes. Long-term bed bug infestation can cause symptoms such as insomnia, anxiety, neurasthenia, and mental depression. Although there have been no reports of bed bugs transmitting diseases, a large number of studies have shown that a variety of pathogens related to human diseases can be detected in bed bugs, so the bugs are still a potentially important vector of human diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A citizen who lives in Hong Kong encountered bed bugs two years ago. He described the state of being bitten like this: &quot;Every night, I was so itchy that I couldn&#39;t sleep. I was bitten by one. My mood explodes every week. The wound will be very itchy and painful when exposed to hot water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be pointed out that it is impossible to judge whether the bite is serious or not just from the traces of the bite. From bed bugs. Natalie Bongay also said in an interview with the BBC that the media or public&#39;s focus on bed bugs often leads to false alarms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen found during the survey that many residents easily confuse bed bugs with cockroaches, fleas, lice, ticks and mites, and some residents think bed bugs and mosquitoes , flies have the same ability to fly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Factory dormitories and group rentals are high-incidence areas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bugs belong to the family Hemiptera, among which the temperate and tropical bed bugs are more prevalent. Bed bugs are closely related to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The largest bed bug survey in China is currently conducted by Deng Guofan of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Feng Lanzhou of the Chinese Union Medical College. Deng and Feng collected 81 bed bugs in China between 1950 and 1951. Bedbug specimens from various regions were collected, and the research results &quot;Geographical Distribution of Temperate and Tropical Bedbugs Cimex lectularius L., Cimex hemiptera F. in China&quot; were published in 1953. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above studies show that both temperate bed bugs and tropical bed bugs are found in China. Tropical bed bugs are mainly distributed in Guangdong and Guangxi provinces, while temperate bed bugs are found in East and North China. It commonly occurs in the provinces of , northeast and northwest, and is also distributed in Xiamen, Fujian, Qujiang, Guangdong (belonging to Shaoguan City), Guilin, Guangxi, Mengzi, Yunnan, Guiyang, Guizhou and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Jianguo introduced that bed bugs prevalent around the world usually refer to temperate bed bugs. In China, temperate bed bugs are distributed in the Yangtze and Yellow River basins, but are also found in South China and are a cosmopolitan species; tropical bed bugs are distributed in South China, Taiwan and tropical areas. Wang Desen believes that with the changes in the indoor environment caused by climate warming and the use of northern heating, tropical bed bugs may also appear in temperate areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543ded6239.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/543ded6239.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Temperate bed bug adults and tropical bed bug adults. Photo by Wang Desen |&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters searched for domestic patients bitten by bed bugs on social platforms and found that most of the patients who shared suspected or confirmed bed bug encounters on the Internet were concentrated in Zhuhai. The triangle area is consistent with some domestic research conclusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Changlu and other researchers published a study on bed bug infestation in Shenzhen in 2013 and found that bed bugs were infested among migrant workers in Dongguan and Shenzhen industrial zones. Dormitories are the worst affected, with an average positivity rate of 52.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Desen conducted an investigation on the harm and prevention of bed bugs in some areas of Guangdong Province from 2017 to 2019, and found that Shenzhen, Zhuhai, Dongguan, Foshan, Guangzhou, etc. Bedbugs appear everywhere, and factory dormitories and group rental housing with densely populated people, high mobility, and poor sanitary conditions are high-incidence areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We visited factory dormitories and found that many factories are infested with bed bugs. The movement of employees back and forth between different factory areas can easily cause the spread of bed bugs.&quot; Wang Desen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Avoid prevention and control misunderstandings and recommend non-chemical methods&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although bed bugs are unlikely to pose a &quot;crisis&quot; that threatens human health at this stage, patients &quot; The experience of being bitten with hundreds of red bumps all over the body proves that it still has the power to make people suffer, and it is necessary to take scientific prevention and treatment measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bed bug prevention and control includes physical control, chemical control, comprehensive control and other means. For ordinary households, it is recommended to use a comprehensive prevention and control method that focuses on physical control and supplements chemical control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Physical control refers to the use of heat treatment, inorganic powders, bed bug interception devices, etc. to prevent and control bed bugs. Since bed bugs are very sensitive to high temperatures, residents can treat bed bug-infested furniture and items by frequently washing and drying bedding and clothing with hot water, and using a hot steam machine (such as a garment steamer). After heat treatment, when the air humidity is reduced, spraying inorganic powder represented by diatomaceous earth in the corners of walls, seams of bed frames, under mattresses and other areas where bed bugs often move can also effectively kill bed bugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/6b407e6b8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bed bug hiding spots. Photo by Wang Desen |&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be pointed out that a common misunderstanding in preventing bed bugs is to expose the furniture where bed bugs are found to the sun. Since the temperature of sun exposure cannot instantly reach the lethal temperature of bed bugs (50°C), it may cause bed bugs to spread to other uninfested places, especially in apartments or residential buildings with many rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Generally, it is not recommended to use chemical agents, because the common pyrethroid insecticides on the market are toxic and should not be used by families with pets and children. It is not recommended to use it. If you need to use it, you should strictly follow the recommended dosage of the drug, and do not use it on sofas, beds and other places that are in direct contact with the human body.&quot; Wang Changlu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For people who frequently travel for business and tourism, Wang Desen recommends always keeping mosquito repellent water in your suitcases, and promptly checking and cleaning your suitcases and the clothes inside them after returning home to avoid Bringing bed bugs into your home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In densely populated communities, once a bed bug outbreak occurs, all residences in the entire community are at risk of being infested. Therefore, community-wide treatment should be considered during bed bug control. Wang Desen pointed out that after removing bed bugs, it is also necessary to establish a long-term awareness of prevention. You can regularly check the corners of the bed, wall gaps, etc. through visual inspection to determine whether there are traces of bed bug activity, molting or feces; in addition, you can also use traps placed under the bed for long-term monitoring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For crowded places such as hotels, schools, unit dormitories, etc., Wang Jianguo suggested asking PCO (Pest Control) companies to conduct professional monitoring and thorough disinfecting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It is difficult to completely &#39;eliminate&#39; a pest. We can only reduce its population as much as possible on a local scale and prevent it from spreading. Cause great harm. After getting rid of the &quot;four pests&quot; for so long, humans are still fighting against them. But as long as people increase their awareness of bed bug prevention and control, they can avoid large-scale outbreaks of bed bugs. Bed bugs are no longer very common nowadays. It may become a serious pest like cockroaches, flies and mosquitoes,&quot; Wang Jianguo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Zhang Minru and Zhang Wei are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陆仙人：从乡村地头走到巴黎时装周]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261166]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4jYjgJrc6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/pUiN7Fe8pusqH3OomDLXfM6s07kkkw4 jYjgJrc6h. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Lu Xianren appeared for the first time on the Paris Fashion Week show. He was invited to walk the show, wearing a black silhouette suit, white trousers and a neat hairstyle. He was one of the few non-scientific models present, and his starting point on the catwalk was on a rural road in Guangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Lu Xianren, who was working in Guangdong, quit his job and returned to his hometown in Guangxi to shoot short videos full-time. He always wanted to be a model, so most of the photos he took were of him walking in shows. The clothing is all homemade, made from woven bags, blankets, waterproof plastic sheets, old lampshades, branches, leaves... match the upper body and walk in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked hard for more than a month, but the account was not as popular as he imagined. It was already summer, and the sultry weather also affected his mood: Was he unable to achieve results no matter what? It&#39;s better to be more casual and show yourself. So in the high temperature, he put on the red blanket at home as clothes and walked barefoot for a while. This random move immediately brought about a heat stroke and high fever, but it also brought a lot of likes. Lu Xianren woke up from his sleep and saw the number of likes on the video rising, and even doubted the authenticity of the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, this video became popular on the platform, with more than 2 million likes. He&#39;s on fire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short video era gives everyone the opportunity to experience the &quot;15 minutes of fame&quot;. It has become easy for ordinary people to produce a popular video. In the ocean of traffic, there will always be a point where you can Hit a group of people. However, it is not easy to make this flow sustainable. But Lu Xianren did not hesitate. When he decided to shoot short videos full-time, he had already conceived many ideas. So if it wasn’t because of the red blanket that it became popular, would it also be because of other creative ideas? Lu Xianren laughed at this: &quot;Not necessarily.&quot; He still showed a cautious attitude towards his fame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren, whose real name is Lu Kaigang, was born in Heng County, Guangxi in 1999. His parents worked outside all year round, and he was raised by his grandparents. When he was in fifth grade, he saw a modeling competition on TV and was attracted by the models&#39; aura and outfits. It became his dream to walk on the catwalk. From then on, when he got home from school, he would take time to practice Tai step. He was originally a little hunched, but after practicing he opened his shoulders and held his head high. When practicing, hold a book on your head. &quot;The book cannot go away, so the steps are formed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After three months, the book is firmly on the head. &quot;But what I learned more is their confidence on the stage and the way they want to express themselves on the stage.&quot; Today&#39;s Lu Xianren said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dropping out of middle school, Lu Kaigang went to Guangdong to work. He worked as an apprentice in a barber shop and a restaurant, and then worked in a factory. He used his spare time to continue his modeling studies. He recorded videos and compared them with professional models&#39; pace, down to the time to keep his head and the number of seconds to pause when positioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, he started shooting his own videos. When choosing the nickname for his account, he thought of his home in the mountains. Every day when he got up, he could see the mist outside the window. It was &quot;very fairy&quot;, so he named himself &quot;Lu Xianren&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year later, he decided to quit his job and return to his hometown to shoot short videos full-time. &quot;Give yourself half a year, and if it doesn&#39;t work, go back and work honestly.&quot; Hence the subsequent story. After that, his creative juices flowed and his modeling career got on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Xianren is 180 centimeters tall and wears women&#39;s clothing in most of the videos. This time it was not understood. Some relatives saw the video and ran to ask Lu Xianren&#39;s family: &quot;Why is your child like this?&quot; Grandma said: Young people have their own ideas, and they must have their own reasons for what they do, so just leave them alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;719&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/lwNsWIxZetPBREzLyXo9UMpLziZ4l8bAyimNpdE0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo taken by Honor 100 series)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My current life is not It counts as a full score, but try to go in the direction of full score&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 3 In March, you participated in the Paris Fashion Week catwalk for the first time. You are a new face in the international fashion world. What new characteristics do you think you have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The fashion industry has never lacked new faces. On the international stage, I have been recognized by more people, and the global fashion media have discovered me. A new face, discovering maybe a new strength. Mainly, I (this type) are relatively rare in the fashion industry, and I personally feel more special. And &quot;new&quot; represents a new force, the ability to move forward, and an opportunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Taking shows on the international stage and in the countryside What&#39;s the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I personally think it is a change in mentality. At the beginning, when I walked the show on rural trails and country roads, I was just enjoying the scenery, which I thought was beautiful. After going to Paris Fashion Week, I felt a little nervous for the first time. I slowly adapted and enjoyed it. I slowly began to interact with the audience and resonate with the designers. I seemed to have a passion for their clothes and their love. Perception, there is a spiritual connection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The show left in your mind What is the first screen? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At the final curtain call, the audience waved to the designer and then applauded. I have walked in so many shows, some of which were applauded by the audience, and some of which the audience left immediately after the show. In that show, most of them stood up and applauded. They must have found something they like and resonated with. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The way you appear in the camera is very professional , what kind of training have you received for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;While visiting the scene, I observed some photography teachers. In what state did they take photos? I think taking pictures is related to the state. I don&#39;t like to put a look in order to take pictures, or to set up a big scene in order to take pictures. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I personally take pictures when I take pictures. When I encounter good scenery or beautiful things, I will shoot and record it. I bought a smartphone in 2016. At that time, I was still shooting the scenery, I didn&#39;t dare to shoot myself, and I was not very confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What do you think of a good photo like? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The first is definitely to attract the attention, and then have a sense of story and impact. I may not pay attention to a certain detail in the whole photo, and I will notice a general look. A photo cannot be 100%perfect, 98%or 95%perfection, and this photo may be remembered for a long time. I do n’t like to make a perfect photo. When I p pictures, I will retain my flaws and leave it. I am still satisfied with myself and pay more attention to the texture of the photo. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Do you have any suggestions for everyone? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; If you are not particularly confident, you don&#39;t have to look at the camera all the time, the lens is not so important. Take pictures is a record of the current thing. When you don&#39;t look at the camera, the relaxed state can be displayed. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; My confidence comes from my love for the camera, plus I like taking pictures -the feeling of the camera out. The moment the camera presses the shutter is the moment of recording the moment, I think it is a magical thing. Now everyone can take a camera to take a picture at any time. I don&#39;t necessarily say what kind of photos will be taken. I took a picture. I recorded what I was going to do at the moment. I watched it myself in the future and knew that I was quite happy at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are you playing for your current life? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Lu Xianren: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The ideal full score life I think life is half, and then half of work is OK. But I don&#39;t think it is necessary to be full of points to be a perfect life, it depends on the pace of life. For example, I might be particularly busy a while ago. After I was busy, I went home to rest again, accompanied my grandma, and found new inspiration. Life needs to cooperate with work. My current life is not full, but try to go in the direction of the full score. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从入园难到关停潮，高速增长15年的幼儿园数量迎来拐点丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261170]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 23:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会顺利闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261168]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 21:24:16 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 23, the closing event of the second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was in Shenzhen International, Guangdong Province The exhibition center was held. Yu Jiadong, deputy director of the organizing committee of the conference, deputy minister of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, and Lin Tao, deputy director of the organizing committee and deputy governor of Guangdong Province, attended the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e725648413bbda6fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 392 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484413bbda6f7503.jpeg &quot;data-key = &quot;259427&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; At the closing activity, the conference announced the winning project of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest and the list of winners of the Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area Skills Contest, Human Resources Services Innovation and Entrepreneurship Contest Finals Road Show Show, 12 Personal Resource Services Signing contracts for supply and demand projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a6859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 426 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/A6859A8B26AA76461c.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;259429&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98C995C1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; Opages y: 1; &quot;width = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406ABFA2C1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259 428 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23F95DF01880753535354580DCCD1FD.JPEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; Opages : 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;Height =&quot; 427 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23F95DF01880753535354580DCCD1FD.JPEG &quot;Data- key =&quot; 259433 0 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; The 2nd National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference has achieved fruitful results. 144 leading enterprises of human resources services and key employers of the Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area participated in the exhibition. Yuan, Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area Youth Talent Recruitment Activity provides more than 50,000 high -quality jobs online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/96AF7E89AF02AE54FAAD37F37208.jpeg&quot; BORder = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 427 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/96AF7E89AF02AE54FAAD37208.jpeg &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;259432&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252FDFBFF713B5A2184ECE0263755C8.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPACI Ty: 1; &quot;width = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713ba21840263755C8.JPEG&quot; data- key = &quot;25 9431 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c6c1500f88.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;opigny: opign: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;Height =&quot; 427 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6c6C6C688.jpeg &quot;Data- key &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f8377778518904eadd&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opages: 1 ; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot; Height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837F66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;259433&quot;>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt; img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770b777c9167369fc81.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; sayle = &quot;Opages: 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height = &quot;427&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770b777c9167369FC81.JPEG&quot; data- key = &quot;259434&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Resource society Responsible comrades of the Ministry of Security, Guangdong Province and Shenzhen City, the responsible comrades of the Human Resources and Social Security Department (Bureau) of various provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities, and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, experts and scholars, human resources service agencies, key employers and other representatives, and media reporters Participate in the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636E4ADBD5A23072100E910FBBEG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;OPAC it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 480 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/A4349636E4ADBD5A23072100FBBE.JPEG &quot;Data- key = &quot;259435&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[瓦依那乐队：哪段水域都不能代表这条河流]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261164]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 21:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/RCWQUTHWT9BWFOGH9MNH9XVHSSFLUG0F7YPVWT8S.JPG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 664 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i MAGE/23/11/22/RCWQUTHWT9BWFOGH9MNH9XVHSSFLUG0F7YPVWT8S. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259201 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (picture by Honor 100 series Shooting/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the third season of &quot;The Summer of the Band&quot;, a &quot;Dream&quot; made the Wayana band popular, and the performance invitations have come. The band has become a new face that is very popular this summer. The life of the three members was filled with various itinerary, and the intensity was far better than farming. Before standing on the stage, they all lived in the ground. The farmers are busy in spring. Lu Min served as a tile at the construction site all year round, and occasionally went to sell it on the street. Eighteen, he planted land in his hometown, while being a stray singer in Guilin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The current Wayina, in order to maintain the order of life as much as possible in the busyness, the three members agreed: half a month drift outside and live at home for half a month. At present, they are still looking for a new rhythm. Lu Min and 18 have not adapted to the sudden and more cameras and flash. In the face of the camera, they are not free, their eyes are flickering, and they don&#39;t talk much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not long ago, he went to the streets to sing on the street, sang half of time, and took a photo with the audience in half. He promised himself: at least once a month. &quot;After all, I have been singing for the first time for 18 years.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In September 2023, &quot;Dream&quot; -using age as a node, from birth to death, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age, there is every age. Dilemma of Duan -Before the stage broadcast, we had a interview with the Wayanan band. They detailed the beginning and end of the Wayana band and their respective life. But at that time, there was a short period of time before they really became popular, belonging to &quot;former Wayana&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Will they change? &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Real creation is a portrayal of people in this era. Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; You have performed well in&quot; The Summer of the Band &quot;. Although it has been debuted for 10 years, it is a new face for the public. What do you think of this &quot;new&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The reason why we go to participate is for a stage. I love to write songs for a long time, and I have no chance to communicate with you. This stage allows us to freely express our original attitude. Original singing the song we want to sing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of Lumin and 18, they are indeed young and new. And I (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Editor&#39;s Note: 岜 岜 而 &lt;/span>;) has sang for many years, but I just heard that everyone heard this stage for the first time. Some of our songs have different angles as everyone often hear, and (audience) has a new feeling. But for us, we have been doing ourselves. The new thing (in the eyes of the audience) is our very old things, and it has always been some of our emotions and state of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjpenhzo9yk8kzsq2bkfybgpc3kk3kk3kk.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjpenhz0aexo9yk8kzsq2bkfybgpc3kk.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;259205&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The farmers look at the old rice varieties in their own place &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (provided by the interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After this stage, the invitation and performance will be invited. Destroy your rhythm and affect your original attitude? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;瓦依那：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果我们没有清楚的方向就会被破坏，但是有很好的方向，它就不是破坏，而是Help us build the state we want, mainly to see how we grasp it. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; We still pay more attention to the part of our lives. Now it is agreed that there must be half a month to live at home and do more exchanges outside half a month. Of course, this half month is a conventional plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Will your creation be affected? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; is still the relationship between land and human beings, and it is some of the life -related (things) from life. More things. We are more inclined to express some emotions from contemporary real life, rather than pure creation and imagination. This kind of thing that comes from real also has artistic modification methods. But people are a thing on the land, which is closely related to the land. Many people&#39;s sorrows may be a sequelae that is generated after a person from a certain departure from the land. People must be inseparable from a relationship with the land and the overall life, including the countryside, including the city. If you are true (created), it must be a sense of distance of a person in this era on the land. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; We have no limited to create, but there may be a starting point. The Wayana band wants to retain Wayana&#39;s style, but we have other creations in private, and all kinds of different creations for personal hobbies. But in Waya, this piece is still relatively unwilling to run. Like we sing a little interaction now, but in fact I (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Editor Note: 岜 farmer Note: &lt;/span>;) Making some pure music is not like Wayana&#39;s songs, I have tried a lot of electronics. Therefore, Wayana is limited to the village as the horizon, describing people and nature of contemporary villages, and some changes in people and society. This is the main style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The song like &quot;Dream&quot; is not a traditional Wayana style, but now it has attracted a lot of people. Will your later creation be biased? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; is still close to the real life portrayal, like the &quot;Ama Return&quot; written by Lumin, the song is also a Hakka In the case, Wayana is the Zhuang tribe, so it is okay. It is still a very rustic and real (creation). The so -called truth refers to what it grows from the land, not to say that we make a flower blind. Of course, it is also a kind of beauty and a consciousness, but Wayana is biased towards (real). &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; (Everyone likes &quot;Dream&quot;) It&#39;s okay. Everyone likes it. Let&#39;s sing &quot;Dreams&quot; three times first, and then sing the countryside. Good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Are you satisfied with your current life? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; It mainly depends on how to design it. , Follow (adjustment) according to comfort and authenticity at any time, don&#39;t float. We are quite free and we can try to prepare time. Eighteen tonight, if you want to go out and sing, you can go out without wanting to go out. Take the initiative to do things. It is a bit hard to be regulated to do it. I was regulated to eat, because I might want to sleep at the time. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot; , Lu Min and Eighteen 3 members, will you fix it with this lineup now? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Sometimes this is a bit like asking for a divorce after getting married? I think it&#39;s flowing, don&#39;t deliberately kidnap a band. I hope that everyone does something to do with everything, instead of making money and cope. No matter if you walk together, everyone can continue to sing life, this is the most important. If our three feelings are tired and want to disperse, it will be dispersed. But this is okay. In the future, the eighteen can continue to write good songs, and I can continue to make music. Lumin can continue to sing the song that he wants to sing. This has nothing to do with scattered, and the important thing is to maintain the expression and experience of life forever. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You enjoy the feeling of being filmed in front of the camera ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Shake head &lt;/span>; ) &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Do you like to take pictures? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; (&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 岜 岜 &lt;/span &lt;/span &lt;/span >;) I usually want to shoot me. I still love to take a wild fruit. I still love to shoot. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What do you think of good photos? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Sometimes I re -turn my hard disk and find that some photos are interesting at the time, and they are very beautiful. use. What is really useful? I did that, I took it. It reminds me of the real experience and feelings of that thing at the time. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How do you define a full score? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wayana: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Everyone should be different, find his most comfortable state, live and free, and can exert the meaning of life, Everyone was looking for his point, and I found it very early. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The word full score has split life. From the perspective of the entire life, each stage is part of your life, just like a river, which paragraph do you like best, which paragraph do you like best Water? In fact, no section of water does not represent this river. I think that each individual is full. If you can love yourself like this so that you can let go, you are full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨曾志平：坚守正确就是意义所在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261152]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-23 20:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Dr. File: &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p >; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; Zeng Zhiping, the first doctorate in military law in New China. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1966, born in Yudu County, Ganzhou, Jiangxi. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 1984-July 1988, study at the Nanchang Army Institute of the People&#39;s Liberation Army Get a bachelor&#39;s degree in military science. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1988-1995, successively &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaita, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; The PLA officers in Zhangzhou, Fujian, and instructor of Nanchang Army College. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 1995-July 1998, studying at the Xi&#39;an Institute Master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1998-2004, he successively served as the instructor and military lawyer of the Nanchang Army College. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; September 2004 to January 2007, studying at China University Doctorate. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; January 2007-August 2018, he has been a professor and senior professor and senior of Nanchang Institute of Technology. Professor, dean of the School of Political Science and Law, and Vice President. From July to August 2010, he served as a visiting scholar at the China Research Service Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; April 2012-April 2013, at the University of California, U.S. The School of Law (now the University of California San Francisco Law School) and the Institute of Military Judicial in the United States as a visiting scholar. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; August 2018-January 2019, served as the Law School of Jiageng College of Xiamen University professor. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; February 2019-January 2022, Ren Suzhou University Wenzheng College/Suzhou City City Professor of the Department of Law and Government. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; From February 2023, he has been a professor at the Law School of Guangzhou Business School. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Zeng Zhiping is the first doctorate in military law in China. (Interviewee confession)&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ Medias/Image/23/11/23/BA4C195B53.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1080 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/Mes/image/23/23/23/23/23/ 11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259413 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Zeng Zhiping is the first military law doctor in China. (Photo of the respondents) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the doctors interviewed, Zeng Zhiping may be the latest doctoral degree. In January 2007, he graduated from China University of Political Science and Law and became the first military law doctor in China. At this time, the first doctoral degree trained after the reform and opening up was awarded a degree and had passed 24 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, as a second -level discipline under the category of law, the subjectization process of military law is relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1984, the legalist Zhang Youyu and Pan Nianzhi proposed for the first time in the &quot;Chinese Encyclopedia and Law Volume&quot;. Formally listed military law as a branch of law; in 1993, the first teaching institution in the country to engage in military legal education -Xi&#39;an Institute of Political Science (now the Xi&#39;an Campus of the School of Political Science, School of Political Science of the People&#39;s Liberation Army) was established. Military law professional education officially entered the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2003, the Xi&#39;an School of Political Science became the first school to have a doctorate degree in military law; in the same year, China University of Political Science and Law opened a military law research center. In 2004, China University of Political Science and Law began recruiting doctoral students of military law. It was also this year, Zeng Zhiping, the ranks of the Chinese Colonel&#39;s rank, transferred from the Nanchang Army College, and was admitted to China University of Political Science and Law in September of the same year, becoming the only doctoral student of military law who enrolled in that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zeng Zhiping, Professor Zhou Jian, is a famous expert in the field of military law and the director of the first military law and research office in China. Zhou Jian once pointed out in an article: &quot;Among the top ten legal disciplines determined by the Ministry of Education, military law (030110) can be said to be the least talent and the most difficult research.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Compared to law science In other majors, military law is a relatively mysterious and niche discipline. Before turning around, Zeng Zhiping worked in the army for 21 years. In a sense, it is the identity of the soldier that gives him the opportunity to study military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Zeng Zhiping&#39;s view, today, the &quot;openness&quot; of military law is related to the atmosphere of the rule of law, and it is also related to the needs of the society for military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;军校，部队，再到军校&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1984, you were admitted to the Nanchang Army Academy (now the People&#39;s Liberation Army Army Infantry Academy) to study undergraduate. Why did you choose a military school at that time? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In our era, especially in the countryside, everyone&#39;s life is not guaranteed. . When I graduated from high school, I also participated in the recruitment. At that time, I had to recruit a pilot and asked for a higher request. I was brushed off during the medical examination. When the Nanchang Army Academy came to enroll, the head teacher recommended me. I didn&#39;t have any particularly strong thoughts at the time, but my dad felt that being a officer was good and ignorant, so I went. You have to say that I have a strong military or officers (ideas), and I think there should be nothing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are the special places of undergraduate education in the military school? ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Before studying the military academy, I do n’t know about the military and military academies, but physical training is the most benefited from the military school. When I first went to school, I couldn&#39;t pull it up. The school organizes physical fitness training. During the training process, I am the fastest improvement. Later, I became the all -around athlete of the school and also participated in the military competition. Some teachers also come from the army to teach tactics, shooting, military body, queue and the like. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; After graduating from the Nanchang Army Academy, you have done it, you have done it Which jobs? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; After graduation, I was sent to the front -line troops in Zhangzhou, Fujian. At that time, I was in a row in a group, and after a few months, I was transferred to the organs. During the training of all teachers and cadres, there was an inaccurate instructor in a training subject. The head of the team &quot;picked up&quot; me, and later I became the instructors of many projects. This (experience) stood out. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have been in the front -line troops for 4 and a half years before and after the front -line troops. I have organized stocks in the Political Department and have been a instructor. After the Lantern Festival in 1993, I was transferred to the Nanchang Army Academy to teach, which I took the initiative to apply. At that time, I went to Marxism -Leninism and the director of the Military Teaching and Research Office also asked me, &quot;Why can&#39;t you come here?&quot; He was a trainer when I was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In school, I taught international politics when I first went, because the teachers who took this class were relatively less at that time. I am also interested in the League of Law. After a semester, I taught the Law of Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Disciplinary positioning &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Self -study law? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; It is a bit coincidental. In the spring It was the session they participated in Jiang Changjian. At that time, we were really interesting to watch this competition. Jiang Changjian was from the national political department, so I wanted to go to Fudan to study graduate students of international political majors. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But at school, I learned that there are a few young people who we often play together to take the lawyer qualification examination. I think this matter must be right. After measuring, I said that I learned law and did not learn international politics. International politics was &quot;dragon slaughter&quot;, and the law was more practical. In 1994, I began to study myself in accordance with the requirements of the lawyer&#39;s qualification examination. In October of that year, I obtained the lawyer&#39;s qualification with the first achievement of the army. &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend Note: At that time, the national judicial examination system has not been established, and the lawyer qualification can be obtained by passing the lawyer&#39;s qualification examination.) &lt;/span>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; Later, in the postgraduate entrance examination, I would not be a little related to law. Because I have passed the lawyer&#39;s qualification test, my brain is also good at that time, and I think I can pass any major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You have already taught at the military school, why do you want to go to a master&#39;s degree student again ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I haven&#39;t thought about leaving the army at the time, but I really want to leave the Nanchang Army Academy. Many professors in the school are older. I will feel that I will not leave the school, and I may not have a good state when they are old. However, the troops&#39; adjustment is still difficult. The postgraduate entrance examination is a means to leave the school. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I wanted to take the majors in Wuhan University at that time, but some people told me that if you are a graduate student at local universities, you have to return to the original school after graduation. You stay. So I chose the Xi&#39;an School of Political Science, and it is also a military school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Now I think of it, if I go to Wuhan University at the beginning, the academic foundation may be more reliable. If I received systematic academic training when I was young, and read a lot of books, then my best knowledge is complete, and my academic research is head and end. My knowledge does not reach this level. This is my regret in my life. Now I mainly feel that the years have been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What is a master of military law when you read a master&#39;s degree. What kind of problems do you want to solve? Is there a concept? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; This is because I am the foundation of law. I saw a lot of materials before and learned military law. At the master&#39;s degree, my direction is military justice, mainly studying the military procuratorial system. What I was impressed most was that I read a lot of English materials at the time. At that time, I discussed the criminal structure of Germany and the three -level criminal theory of Germany and Japanese criminal law. This also had a great impact on me. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You have loved military law in the doctoral level ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; It can&#39;t be said to be loved, I just accumulated a certain degree of knowledge and knew this subject. On the other hand, I saw a lot of works writing badly. I think I will participate in this discipline may make it better. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; We look back to discuss the positioning of military law disciplines Question, do you think it belongs to the branch of military science or a branch of law? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; This depends on how you treat it. From the discipline management of the Ministry of Education, from the professional fields involved in the discipline, you can discuss this issue. I only recognize the knowledge classification. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In June 2022, Suzhou University Wenzheng College, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) with students. : //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot;//iMages.infzmmmmmmm .com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/23/CB781E6727.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259414 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; 2022 In June of the year, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) was with the students. (Photo confession of the interviewees) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;I am also the product of the times&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style Kaiti_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; When you graduated from a master&#39;s degree, the original plan was to continue the academic road? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;Span>; Nor did it. Before graduating, I wanted to go to the Shanghai Military Procuratorate or leave the original school. At that time, I returned to Nanchang and Introduction to law in school, because several teachers took several teachers together, and they could not take a few lessons for a semester. In addition to class at military schools, I was also in several private universities at the time. It can be said that teaching has made my psychology moisturizing. At private universities, many students look at you. Their eyes are hungry and passionate, which is different from what I encountered in the original school. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Then why did you go to China University of Political Science and Law to study later What about Bo? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; This matter is a bit coincidental. I always wanted to change my job before the Spring Festival in 2004, but at that time The news that can be transferred, I just apply. At that time, I saw the information of doctoral Dr. in various schools, and I was wondering, &quot;Can you criticize this year (whether you have changed his career)?&quot; Around January 10, 2004, after the application for transfer was approved, I quickly went to see the enrollment information of each school. I have always wanted to go to Wuhan University, but the registration at that time has ended. However, that year, because of the new doctoral point of military law in China and law, its registration time was extended, and I reported it. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When looking at the school enrollment information, I will also consult some teachers. When I was studying at Xi&#39;an School of Political Science, I met Teacher Zhou Jian, and I called him. I originally wanted to report to the criminal law. I have always taught the criminal law, and then Mr. Zhou Jian said that you should not report the criminal law. I have military law in Chinese political and legal. You follow me to read military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I also told Teacher Zhou, &quot;I have been transferred, what do I still learn military law? I am still more interested in criminal law.&quot; Therefore, military law is really a product of the era, including myself as the product of the times, which is a very good thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Is he fiercely competitive? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; China University of Political Science and Law had 3 professors at the time to bring a doctorate in military law, but that year, only Mr. Zhou Jian enrolled. only one person. I was particularly impressed. At that time, I signed up 10 people. I also found the results of other candidates using the rules of the check. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The rules for checking the score at that time were just to infes your admission ticket number. According to the compilation of the admission ticket number, the previous numbers are the same, the difference is the last single digit and ten digits. According to the position on the test room at the time, I could probably guess how many people in front of me and behind. After I checked my grades, I speculated that their numbers were speculated, and the result really found out the score. Seeing that the second place was 20 points lower than me, I was easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The doctor of Chinese University of Political Science and Law will be the doctor of China. Is it more important? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; yes, this is an important turning point in life. At that time, I was transferred to my karma and was a doctor of military law. Teacher Zhou said that Chinese and law must keep you, so my life plan at the time had a rough direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;读硕士的时候，有一次我去北京，在北京图书馆看书的时候，我遇到了一位老先生。他去参加北大的一个活动，我们简单地聊了几句。他当时说了句话，大意是“如果这辈子能去北大当教授，就怎么着怎么着”。我当时就有一个很虚的想法：如果我能去中国政法当教授就好了，所以有时候生活就是很奇怪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，后来又有了一些变动，毕业后我也没有留在中国政法大学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;认知是人格的核心&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你读硕士，是为了离开原来的学校；读博士，是为了留在一个新的学校。所以你的这几次选择，都不是出于对专业的选择？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;曾志平：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，我一直想的就是到更好的大学教书，但人就是时代的浮萍。我现在的想法可能是比较成熟的想法了，因为我的职业生涯已经靠近“末期”了。我想是这样的：你需要去读书，你的学校，你遇到的老师、同学，应该共同帮你找到人生的兴趣所在。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我觉得，一个理想的社会应该是让每个人都受到鼓励，去做你想做的事，找到兴趣和热爱所在。如果每个年轻人的成长都是在自己的热爱之下去学习，那这会增强他的热爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“新中国成立后首位军事法学博士”的标签，对你的人生影响大吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;曾志平：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我毕业的时候也没有意识到这个事情。 2007年，我儿子要参加高考，我很简单的想法就是，我能不能提前毕业？如果我留在中国政法，儿子到北京上学也很方便。但是儿子觉得没必要，他成绩很好，后来考上了武汉大学。但我论文又写好了，就提前半年毕业了，没有说非得争第一个的意思。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我上午通过毕业论文答辩，下午《法制日报》就报道了，随后一些国外媒体也跟进报道了这件事。现在看来还是很有意思的，我不知道国外媒体有没有关注别的学科第一个博士，但当时很多国外媒体对我的报道甚至还说了我的论文题目《论军事权》，说我对这样一个重大的理论问题做出了很好的研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己倒是没怎么跟其他人说过这个标签，现在要说起来它给我带来什么特别大的好处之类的，好像也没有，毕竟我也没有利用它来求职或者做一些宣传。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你博士毕业之后应聘南昌理工学院，并受命组建南昌理工学院政法系。相较于法学界的“五院四系”，你觉得一所民办大学的法律系应该是什么样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;曾志平：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我2007年来的南昌理工学院，2008年就拿到了国家社科基金。那时候，整个江西有法律系和法律专业的高校总共也才十几个，所以影响很大，在很长一段时间里，学校都把我当作招牌。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本科教育上，我很自觉，我没有把军事法学放到法学本科的专业课程里，我只是开了全校的公选课。如果你自己当系主任，当法学院的院长，再把自己的课开成专业课，编本教材，让大家买你的书，这是很没面子的事。到现在，我也没有编一本军事法学的教材。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我都是按照最基本的法学本科专业来开课的。如果要说有什么特殊之处的话，可以说我开了几门通识课里面非常关键的课：普通逻辑、语法修辞、政治学概论、社会学概论这些，那时候这些课在法学院还不universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，我们成了江西省硕士学位授予立项建设单位，这是有关单位下了文的。我想让学生们接受好的教育，这也算是工作上比较直接的成绩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在教学上获得的成就感，也让我有了继续下去的动力。我为什么会坚持教学？是因为我觉得现在有很多错误，教学也是错误的教学。有的时候我很消极地说了，尽管我肯定不是popular（受欢迎的），但是我好歹可以让那些虚妄的popular被淘汰掉，因为我挤占了一个位置，让他这个虚妄的popular少了一个Location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我坚守正确的，这就是我的意义所在了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有什么经验或想法想跟现在的大学生们分享吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;曾志平：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;人固然难逃浮萍的宿命，然而，是否属意知识，总是不一样的。 After all, cognition is the core of personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起底缅北电诈头目祝寿视频背后产业链：有明星报价一条14万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261143]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;“2000元/5000元/1万元以下可以请哪些明星录祝福视频？”“后台私信明星祝福视频录制”“3天可以出！”多位明星被曝给缅北电诈头目拍祝寿视频，引发轩然大波。 Recently, Nandu and N video reporters found on some e -commerce and social platforms that merchants selling &quot;Star Wishes Video&quot; for hype sales are still endless. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;引发争议的“寿星”，是缅北四大家族白所成之子白应苍，被公认为缅北果敢“四大家族”之首的白家次子，也是果敢财政局副局长、果敢自治区民兵大队队长，掌控着苍胜科技园这一电诈园区。 Although some stars said that the life of the birthday video was &quot;hindered by love&quot; for him, and he did not know himself, and he still failed to let the netizens question. &quot;Star Wishes Video&quot; industry chain has once again entered the public&#39;s vision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;给电诈头目录制祝寿视频是否涉嫌违法？ &quot;Star Wishes Video&quot; has a long history. What is the market now? Why are consumers who are keen to buy, and how do stars think of this phenomenon? Nandu, N video reporters interviewed the agent of the entertainment company, the buyers and sellers of blessing videos, lawyers and experts, and other parties to the back of the &quot;Star Wishes Video&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;社交平台上有人推广明星祝福视频。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;风波：明星给电诈头目录祝寿视频&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“在这里，我祝白应苍生日快乐、鹏程万里……”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;缅北电诈集团多名头目落网后，一条“多位明星给缅北四大家族白所成之子白应苍录视频祝寿”的消息引起舆论哗然。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这场生日宴会上，舞台中央大屏幕播放着多名明星的祝贺影片，囊括了香港艺人曾志伟、黄一飞、曹查理，以及演员杜旭东、相声演员侯耀华wait. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被称为香港影坛大哥的曾志伟对外界作出解释，“可能是朋友与朋友之间帮忙说两句&#39;这是我好朋友&#39;，就录了。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;经过这次，一些不相熟的会尽量避免。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;演员曹查理则发布致歉视频称，他去年8月从加拿大回来，“经理人发这个东西过来的时候，我说为什么这个好像是江湖上面的对白，并不想拍。他说没事啊，很多明星都有拍，我就拍了&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他说，并不知晓经理人把视频放在哪里，很多明星都是为了钱，“我就是为了钱拍这个视频，因为我要生活，要吃饭，没有办法，但我从未与缅北电诈的人来往”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;南都记者梳理发现，此次风波之前，已有类似的明星祝福视频“翻车”现象。 Artist Yang Di was caught in public opinion vortex because of shooting promotional videos for the P2P platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2020年7月，大量投资人在社交网络上反馈在“有利网”平台的出借金到期后迟迟未兑付，并在杨迪微博下喊话，呼吁其为“有利网诈骗”事件发声。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;随后，杨迪在微博发表声明，表示自己是在电影宣传期间，帮宣传方录制的视频，并非“有利网”代言人，录制视频也没有Charge any fees. “我会协助此次事件被欺骗的用户追究到底，对因视频推荐承受损失的观众致以深深歉意。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;明星录制祝福视频，究竟是碍于情面还是为了钱？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;今年7月，有港媒报道，罗家英等演员拍摄专属祝福视频，为网上俱乐部群组加持背书，有人因此受骗，转账数万元至炒股平台后，无法提取款项。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;事后，罗家英承认，“经理人安排而照稿读，我不认识这个人。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;行情：有人要收超四位数意向金才能询价&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月22日，南都记者以“明星祝福视频”等关键词在部分电商及社交媒体平台搜索发现，不少名字中带有“明星经纪”“传媒文化”字眼的用户，发布了多个明星祝福视频。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;点进用户主页，简介中均带有“后台私信明星祝福视频录制”的提示。 Several sellers showed the quotation fiders to Nandu reporters, including celebrity names, avatars, masterpieces, and prices of blessing videos for individuals and business. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他们大部分是内地、香港、台湾的歌手、&lt;/span>;演员、主持人，还有中外运动员。同一张报价单中，价格差异巨大，低至100元，最高则达14万元。还有明星出现在了备选项中，并没有标注价格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;一份报价单上显示的明星拍摄祝福视频价格。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一名卖家介&lt;/span>;绍，这类明星报价都超过10万元，如果想要点名他们录制视频，卖家还需收取超四位数的意向金，才肯联系明星公司询问报价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自称在媒体圈工作的陈&lt;span>;健（化名）向南都记者坦言，明星咖位不一样，自然价格就不一样。面对相比同行价格较高的质疑，他说，“差别在于服务”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他以3万元报价推荐了一位台湾演员的祝福视频服务，而在张勇（化名）的报价单上，这位演员的报价是23000 Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“我走低价，没有任何附加费用。”张勇自称是一名艺人经纪，也是一手总代理，“我既可以和传媒公司对接，也可以和艺人经纪对接，甚至可以直接联系到明星本人。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;陈健说，明星的祝福视频时长一般控制在30秒以内，此外还需要把具体内容报给明星，确认可以录制后才能给到准确的报价。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;而另一名称是来自一家传媒公司的卖家则向南都记者明确，视频时长一般在10到15秒左右，“正常语速就是20到25个字之间吧”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;至于出片时间，一般根据明星本人时间决定，“一般是7天左右，快的话3到5天”，也有卖家写明“3天可以出&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;张勇透露，他的报价单里标注了一批经常录制祝福视频的明星，因为“性价比较高，速度较快，配合度高”，常常被优先推荐给买家。有一些不太知名的明星会主动请他帮忙优先推荐录制，这类明星的祝福视频，会被“打包”以统一价出售。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;还有卖家告诉南都记者，虽然报价单里出现某些“顶流”名字，但其实他们都不接指明找一线明星的订单。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;至于哪些明星属于“顶流”？ “这么说吧，你感觉代言过很多品牌的明星或者运动员，基本上就不会录祝福视频。”陈健说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;规制：部分公司有明确规定&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为何明星录祝福视频如此盛行？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;麦麦（化名）曾花费约两百多澳币（超900元人民币），在海外视频定制网站Cameo购买定制了两段英格兰足球名宿迈克尔·欧文的祝福视频，作为送给自己的鼓励。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;603&quot; height=&quot;933&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;麦麦收到由欧文录制的祝福视频。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;她于年少时喜欢上欧文，并因此开始接触足球，至今已经17年。她向南都记者回忆，决定购买视频时，自己正经历离婚，结束了一段7年的关系，需要鼓舞，“当鼓励的话从偶像口中说出来的时候，感觉不一样”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;麦麦付款后大约一周内就拿到了视&lt;/span>;频。而在看到视频的那一刻，她觉得一切都值得了。 “这个视频在我人生最低谷、最难过的时候，给予了我强大的力量与信念。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;华南理工大学新闻与传播学院视听传播系副教授黄桂萍向南都记者分析道，喜欢的明星为其录制视频是一种对其拟态亲密关系的满足和公开呈现，但同样存在另一种情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“个人对明星所具有的号召力有利益性诉求，&lt;span>;通俗来讲可以理解为&#39;蹭流量&#39;，即借助明星知名度增长自己的可见性和讨论度，有些甚至可以直接在社交媒体平台转化为粉丝量和平台收益。”她说道。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;南都记者从张勇的“买家秀”里看到，当中不乏来自各类企业的踊跃下单。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“企业对明星录制视频的诉求心理反而更纯粹，不存在关系类需求，而主要是利益诉求。”黄桂萍解释，其实就是借明星的知名度和公众信赖度为自己的产&lt;/span>;品或品牌、公司形象背书，减少公众购买其产品时的怀疑和不确定。 “这种&#39;带货&#39;对明星而言，风险相对更大。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙鹏（化名）是国内知名选秀女团的经纪人。他告诉南都记者，自己一般会直接和艺人说，公司有明确规定不允许录制这些祝福视频，“在我看来，这些收入并不科学”。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在工作中，他会严格区分视频录制的性质。 “比如节日祝福或者文化推广，会酌情收取&#39;车马费&#39;录制，&lt;span>;但若是为企业录制视频，就是妥妥的商业行为，我们的要求会更高，不会轻易说录就录。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;南都记者发现，售卖明星祝福视频的卖家，往往并不只进行这一项业务。明星商务代言、翻包种草视频、商演、合影……在他们秀出的简介里，各类涉明星业务层出不穷。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;卖家展示明星录制祝福视频业务案例。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“他们往往都会有佣金。”孙鹏向南都记者透露，“其实艺人经纪固定工资并不高，有时候全靠给别人拉活儿赚佣金或者返点。但每个人都有自己的生活，不好去评价这个现象的好坏。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;风险：明星或需承担法律责任&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;明星录制祝福视频，看似动动嘴皮子即可达成的商业交易，实际上潜藏着不可忽视的风险。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;若是生日场合，明星碍于情面或是收费录制祝福视频，一般不违反公序良俗，但若是涉及站台、“背书”等性质，便不可简单理解为“一方舍得给钱，一方就能拍&lt;/span>;”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广东广信君达律师事务所律师王家欣向南都记者分析，为个人提供祝福，可以视为粉丝经济行为，该形式不属于民事法律行为，且未实际产生法益侵害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如果明星针对企业或产品拍摄祝福视频，由于明星具备名人效应，所以此类视频实际上是在用广告语言&lt;span>;、积极陈述的行为来暗示或明示外界对这个企业、产品应该得到广泛推广。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“因此，此类视频属广告代言行为。如果视频祝福涉及的企业涉嫌违法业务，且明星对业务知情，该明星亦涉嫌违法，需承担法律责任。”王家欣说道。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当多位明星被曝光为缅北电诈分子录制祝寿视频时，不少网友质疑，“电诈头目害了多少无辜的人，为什么要为他庆生？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“但若这些祝福视频是在之后被曝出来为电诈头目祝贺的，网友的举报其实不成立，因为那是个人祝福视频，并不针对公司。”王家欣进一步解释，若明星祝福视频里强调了电诈公司，还需证明明星对该公司涉嫌电诈行为知情，如明星是否参与了公司运营，或持有该公司股份，但一般较难举证。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;作为国内知名选秀女团经纪人的孙鹏也感觉到，录制祝福视频这类“不正规的合作形式”，会增加对艺人自身的风险隐患. At the same time, he also admits that sometimes companies spend millions of yuan to invite artists to participate in the promotion and endorsement of the brand. During the promotion, it is actually difficult for artists to refuse the company&#39;s request for taking photos and recording videos.一旦答应，后续照片、影片会被对方如何使用，结果都是不可控的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“在没有出台相关法律法规和政策条文进行管控之前，明星拍摄祝贺视频这种交易确实会处于灰色地带，因而会带来我们所说的&#39;认钱不认人&#39;的隐忧。”传播学专家黄桂萍向南都记者表示，在缺乏规范和调控的时候，明星个人、企业、消费者都处于缺乏保障的状态，很可能会造成多输的局面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“因此，当相关部门出手整治、明星方意识到对自身形象的消耗而迷途知返，或者企业意识到利益转化效率低但风险高，这三种情况出现任何一种，都有可能让&#39;明星祝福视频乱象&#39;得以缓解。”黄桂萍说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄乌电子战，矛与盾的游戏丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQgEpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQgEpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年11月16日，顿涅茨克地区，乌克兰军队的无人机操作员在离前线不远的地方进行训练&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，乌克兰军方宣称已将俄罗斯士兵赶出被占领的赫尔松地区第聂伯河东岸阵地，并建立了多个桥头堡，俄罗斯也首次承认基辅军队已越过第聂伯河。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这当然是非常值得关注的战果，因为在第聂伯河东岸建立桥头堡对克里米亚的威胁非常大，如果乌克兰能够在东岸部署远程武器，克里米亚恐怕很难坚守下去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰武装部队总司令扎卢日尼将军在接受《经济学人》采访时强调，乌克兰需要开发和部署自己的先进技术，以重新在战争中占据上风，桥头堡建立的背后正是一系列技术更新所带来的战术优势，尤其是电子对抗方面的优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄乌战争爆发后，乌克兰一直与俄罗斯进行着看不见的电子对抗战斗，赫尔松地区的战斗则是这种对抗的最前沿，因为双方往往只能隔着河流使用远程火力对轰，于是无人机成为制胜的关键，因为双方都非常依赖无人机发现目标和矫正火炮。谁能够使用电子对抗手段压制住对方的无人机，就会在战役中取得优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前来看，对抗无人机效率最高的方法就是通过电磁干扰压制对方，直接导致无人机坠毁。此前曾有报道称，第聂伯河附近已经成为无人机的禁飞区，因为双方都会使用电子干扰手段压制干扰无人机飞行，在这个看不见的战场，双方一直进行着非常复杂而残酷的战斗. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近一个世纪以来，电磁干扰一直是战争的重要组成部分，传统的电子战手段就是找到敌人正在使用的无线电频率，并在相同频率上制造压倒性的噪音，让对方无法use.二战中，电子战主要针对无线电通信和雷达，只要让对方无法通信和探测，就算完成任务了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代通信技术发展出了各种对抗电子干扰的手段，不过其主要原因并不仅仅是为了电子战，而是因为人类社会出现了大量电磁信号源。在二战时，一台50瓦功率的电台可以轻松在中国甚至东亚地区进行点对点的通信，然而现在一台50瓦的电台连覆盖一个省都困难——这并不是因为当年的电台更先进，而是因为当年的电磁环境好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以把电磁通信看作双方交谈，如果一个房间内非常安静，双方不需要很大声音就可以互相听到对方在说什么。如果房间内不仅有很多人聊天，还有人在看电影，有人在拍球，有人在吹拉弹唱，那么双方交流就必须提高嗓门或者挨得非常近。现代通信技术之所以非常重视抗干扰，就是因为电磁背景环境过于复杂，导致单纯靠增加功率来完成通信已经成为不可能的任务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;软件技术也在提升，比如过去要让一个电台的频率和信号特征改变需要更换硬件，而随着无线电软件化，只需要改变编码就可以让设备的频谱情况彻底改变，换句话说，过去被干扰后需要大修才能解决的问题，现在只需要给软件加个补丁就行了，甚至可以重新用软件更换加密手段。而过去要更换加密手段，需要每一个接收端都更换机器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;军事上使用的无人机一般采用更为复杂的控制方式来对抗干扰，比如使用跳频方式连接后端控制，可以跳过被干扰的频段，这是无线电通信常用的抗干扰手段；也可以在被干扰的情况下采用惯性导航，继续执行原来的飞行路径，在干扰减弱的时候再联通卫星导航和后方控制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，抗干扰的能力变强了，干扰的能力相应也会变强，矛与盾相互竞争，也在相互发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上只要你的电子战能力够强，就可以建构一个电子金钟罩，让一切无人机无法飞进来，精确制导武器也无法命中金钟罩里的目标。如果干扰方设备达到了100%的功率，抗干扰手段往往也很难奏效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现实的情况是，干扰手段不可能在所有区域都是满级信号，这取决于干扰源的位置、天线朝向和本身的功率。无人机是个机动的平台，可以不断飞行侦察，干扰信号薄弱的位置，从而找到更佳的飞行路线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且有时候还能用一些不那么“电子”的方式解决问题，比如通过无线电三角定位法，直接找到干扰源的大概位置，用远程火力覆盖对方，即便未曾命中，也可以迫使对方暂时关机躲避打击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，实战中有很多战术可以削弱对方电子干扰的效果，而这些战术本身也是电子战中的重要组成部分。所以不存在什么万能的秘密武器，在电子战这个看不见的战场上，只有不断加强技术、不断变化和更新对抗手段，才能在行动中取得优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省人大常委会原副主任李春生受贿案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:08:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月23日，湖南省郴州市中级人民法院一审公开开庭审理了广东省人大常委会原党组副书记、副主任李春生受贿一案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The Chenzhou Municipal People’s Procuratorate alleged that from the second half of 2001 to May 2022, the defendant Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County, Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security, director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province, and provincial Director of the Public Security Department, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress, etc., and provide convenient conditions for the formation of authority and status to provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc. , illegally accepting property from others, equivalent to a total of more than 79.4 million yuan in RMB. The procuratorate requested that Li Chunsheng be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审中，检察机关出示了相关证据，被告人李春生及其辩护人进行了质证，控辩双方在法庭的主持下充分发表了意见，李春生进行了最后陈述，并当庭表示认罪悔罪。 At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人大代表、政协委员及各界群众三十余人旁听了庭审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>