<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[既嫌弃又上头，霸总式微短剧正成为00后的电子榨菜？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257206]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;The President&#39;s Billionaire Imprisoned Wife&quot;, &quot;The Heaven-defying Princess Leaves Too Wild&quot;, &quot;Son-in-law Dominates the World&quot; and &quot;Security &quot;The President&#39;s Daughter and Little Beloved Wife&quot;... If you come across micro-short dramas like this on short video platforms or other social platforms, don&#39;t be surprised. These micro-short dramas are becoming a creative craze, with people complaining about tyrants. Young people who always follow the same old tricks quietly hide in bed at night and start practicing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Detawen&#39;s Micro Short Drama Market Report for the First Half of 2023&quot; shows that a total of 481 new micro short dramas were released in the first half of 2023, compared with only 454 new ones in the whole year of 2022. This year The number of micro-short dramas in the first half of the year has exceeded that of the whole of last year. In July alone, 361 online micro-short dramas were recorded and announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, micro-short dramas are becoming a creative trend, on the other hand, the roughness and vulgarity of micro-short dramas are also despised by many netizens - why are micro-short dramas so popular? Is the only way for micro-short dramas to break out of the circle is the &quot;three vulgarities&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/gKB1xSTLiZ9trVAlnaHNSx5FO0tI7vY3tA5mLdg7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;947&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/gKB1xSTLiZ9trVAlnaHNSx5FO0tI7vY3tA5mLdg7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Short, flat, fast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with previous long dramas or short dramas, the difference between micro-short dramas is the length. Each episode can be up to ten minutes, and the shortest can even be only A few dozen seconds is in sharp contrast to the average length of a long drama episode of 40 minutes. In the past two years, the creation of micro-short dramas has become a trend, mainly due to the &quot;short, flat, and fast&quot; nature of its creation form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Short&quot; means that the duration of micro-short dramas is very short, the shooting threshold is very low, and the shooting techniques are much simpler. It can be said that as long as you have a mobile phone and a story outline, you can shoot a short drama. A short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Assuming 20 episodes, each episode is 1 minute, a short drama is only 20 minutes long, which is less than the length of one episode of a long drama. With such a low threshold for creation, everyone can enter. Various small film and television production companies have used micro-short plays as the starting point for creation, easily triggering a creative boom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Plain&quot;, micro-short dramas are generally not so particular in film and television arts, and can be plain and mediocre. This is because micro-short dramas are parasitic on short video platforms. They are not meant to be viewed on large screens such as TVs, and mobile phone screens have limited capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially for micro-short plays with a vertical screen, if you take a close-up shot and see the expressions of the characters clearly, you can probably only accommodate two characters, so it is difficult to pay attention to the depth of field, Space layout and shot scheduling. Therefore, many micro-short dramas are just about filming the characters and the plot, and they are all about saving money on the art and scenery, the service, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fast&quot; means that the filming time of micro-short dramas is very fast, the broadcast cycle is very fast, and more importantly, the money comes in very quickly. The cost of many micro-short dramas is only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. You can shoot one in three to five days. After filming one, you can directly launch a short video or small program. If it becomes popular, you can copy another one in ten days. It&#39;s a good money, you can quickly get a lot of traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many ways to make money from micro-short dramas. Although micro-short dramas with an episode length of one or two minutes are not available on long-form video platforms such as &quot;Youai Tengmang&quot;, they are very popular on short-video platforms. After micro-short dramas become popular, the protagonists of micro-short dramas can transform into Internet celebrities and carry out live broadcasts to promote products; some micro-short dramas are customized by advertisers, and the entire episode revolves around the advertising brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those micro-short dramas that are parasitic on small programs can also be watched on a paid basis. A drama usually has more than 100 episodes, and each episode is one minute. The first part can be watched for free, but the subsequent episodes require payment. Unlocked viewing, watching a mini-series is even more expensive than watching a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creative threshold is very low, the creative techniques are simple, the shooting time is short, and the money comes in quickly... It is not surprising that micro-short dramas have become a new trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/KEwiaPCVhglej8e5wja668usJKahucGEiupeCjE4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/KEwiaPCVhglej8e5wja668usJKahucGEiupeCjE4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Vulgar, vulgar, kitsch&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth noting that on the one hand, micro-short dramas are very popular, and on the other hand, micro-short dramas have been criticized and criticized by many people. The root cause is that a large part of micro-short dramas on the market have strong &quot;three vulgarities&quot; characteristics: vulgarity, vulgarity, and kitsch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Swarmed are all micro-short dramas. There are too many content for the audience to choose from. If you don’t find it interesting, just flick it by in three or two seconds, and the micro-short dramas will not get traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to catch the attention of users at the first glance, the orientation of many micro-short dramas can only be very &quot;vulgar&quot;. As some netizens summarized, they are nothing more than &quot;The Domineering President Falls in Love with Me, The Hero&quot; Saving an American but being rescued, falling in love while playing hard to get, seeing the true love in a kidnapping case&quot;... It&#39;s just a &quot;picking up&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a girlfriend&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a boyfriend&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a husband&quot;, &quot;accidentally picking up a boss&quot; Contents such as “Get a CEO Husband” are flying all over the place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some micro-short dramas have further slipped into &quot;vulgarity&quot; and made a big fuss over the edges. In particular, some micro-short dramas in mini programs have not obtained online registration numbers. The content is very large, full of sexual innuendo, or has bloody and violent scenes. Moreover, because the broadcast channel is very hidden, it has repeatedly escaped supervision, which is quite bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is vulgar or vulgar, it is all about pleasing and flattering the audience. It not only caters to the instinctive parts of human nature, but also tries its best to tease users&#39; emotions and create traffic by selling emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This emotion is composed of &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;pleasure&quot; - many micro-short dramas remind us of Mi Meng in the public account era - interestingly, after the transformation, Mi Meng has also become a micro-short drama The manipulator behind the show: The targets of the micro-short drama are &quot;bitches, low bitches, scumbags, scumbags, and vicious female supporting characters.&quot; These &quot;enemies&quot; combine all kinds of personality flaws that the audience is tired of. The method maximizes the various flaws of the &quot;enemy&quot; to arouse the audience&#39;s hatred, and then humiliates, criticizes and attacks these villains through the protagonist&#39;s counterattack, allowing the audience to gain a sense of emotional catharsis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;happiness&quot; brought about by this kind of kitsch simplify human nature, breed intolerance between people, intensify estrangement, and have a subtle influence on social mentality. negative impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HZf8qSQLY6dllV6303J3HB0mSaiUAleQfqMVMN0W.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HZf8qSQLY6dllV6303J3HB0mSaiUAleQfqMVMN0W.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253985&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The possibility of being &quot;micro&quot; but not &quot;vulgar&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The recklessness of micro-short dramas has attracted official attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially in May this year, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television issued new rules for the broadcasting of online dramas. After June 1, 2023, online dramas, online mini-series, online movies, and online cartoons that have been planned and registered will be Adopt a management approach with full license coverage. Only broadcasts can be broadcast after obtaining the &quot;Online Drama Distribution License&quot; in accordance with the law. Those without a license are not allowed to be broadcast; for those that have previously passed the planning and filing, licenses or numbers will be issued based on the circumstances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, starting from June 1, 2023, newly launched online dramas, online micro-shorts, online movies, and online cartoons must be declared through the &quot;Key Online Film and Television Drama Information Filing System&quot; , and works that have obtained the &quot;Online Drama Distribution License&quot; or online registration number after passing the content review of the radio and television management department at or above the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this, there was a brief regulatory blank period for micro-short dramas. That is, many micro-short dramas were filmed and released casually. Take whatever you can to catch people&#39;s attention. Some short dramas on mini programs have become a place for &quot;harboring evil and evil people and practices&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the new regulations are released, the creation and broadcast of micro-short dramas will also face strict review. Only those that pass the review can be broadcast online on the platform. This also means that it is difficult to follow the &quot;three customs&quot; path of micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Micro short plays can only be &quot;micro&quot; but not &quot;vulgar&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, micro-short dramas can also be &quot;high-quality&quot;. For example, &quot;Youai Tengmang&quot; is also entering the micro-short drama industry. Each episode of the micro-short dramas they produce is only ten minutes long, and they use regular techniques for filming film and television dramas to shoot micro-short dramas. This makes micro-short dramas have A certain aesthetic style makes it more meaningful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in this year&#39;s popular &quot;Invitation&quot;, director Zeng Qingjie&#39;s camera language is very sophisticated, and he shoots a story in a pure and beautiful way. It has the simplicity of a short play and the texture of a long drama. The box office is divided into two. More than 16 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, for those micro-short dramas with a single episode of only tens of seconds or two or three minutes, the production team does not have the money to pay attention to quality, so they have to make a fuss about the theme expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it cannot be &quot;vulgar&quot;, it is necessary to find another way, either to maximize the &quot;refreshing feeling&quot;, or to refresh the audience through creativity. Otherwise, the micro-short drama will either end up being filmed but not broadcast, or it will be passed over by the audience after it is broadcast. Even if the cost is not high, it will end up in the street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[恶狗撕咬幼童引发强烈关注，防止烈犬伤人重在防患未然丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 20:56:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of a vicious dog biting a child went viral on social networks, and netizens strongly demanded that the vicious dog be severely punished. Owner. According to the latest report from the joint investigation working group of Chongzhou City (a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Chengdu City): At about 3:00 on October 17, Tang Mou, the owner of the black Rottweiler, arrived at the case. At present, the police have opened a case for investigation into the incident and have taken criminal coercive measures against Tang, the owner of the black Rottweiler dog, in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video posted online showed a big black dog wandering in the open space in front of the building. As soon as a child and his parents walked out of the corridor, the black dog stepped forward and bit the child. The parents quickly protected the child. , but the big dog threw them both to the ground and continued to bite. It wasn&#39;t until the neighbor brought a mop and stick that the big dog was driven away. On October 16, the Chongzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau reported that in the morning, when Deng and her daughter Tang were walking downstairs in the community, a black dog attacked Tang and bit her. Tang suffered multiple bites all over his body, contusion and laceration on his right kidney, and fractured ribs on his right side. After all-out treatment, the wound debridement surgery was completed and his vital signs were stable. Deng suffered abrasions on his body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police have taken criminal coercive measures against the owners of vicious dogs, but this wounding incident has once again reminded us that illegal dog-raising must be severely cracked down on, and we must take precautions before it happens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there have been many similar incidents of vicious dogs hurting people recently. In April 2021, a second-grade student in Chongqing was bitten to death by a neighbor&#39;s dog on his way to school, and a pit bull bitten four adults in Huangshi, Hubei; in December 2020, a 3-year-old child was bitten to death by a dog in Hebi, Henan. ; In November, a mother and daughter were bitten by their own dogs in Dujiangyan, Sichuan. The mother died and the daughter was injured...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the dogs that killed and injured people were stray dogs, and many had owners. Raised. Is it because similar incidents occur frequently because there are no regulations regulating dog breeding? No. From the national level, the Animal Epidemic Prevention Law, which will take effect on May 1, 2021, has a special provision for dog breeding, requiring dogs to be vaccinated regularly and to wear dog tags and leashes when taking dogs out of the house. Major cities have already enacted local regulations regulating dog keeping. The Standing Committee of the Chengdu Municipal People&#39;s Congress formulated regulations on the management of dog breeding in 2009, which stipulates that individuals are prohibited from raising aggressive dogs and large dogs. In restricted areas, dogs must be registered with the public security organs and apply for certificates. When taking dogs out of the house, dogs must be put into dog cages and dogs. The dog must be held in a bag or led by a person with full capacity for civil conduct using a dog leash to promptly stop the dog from barking and attacking pedestrians. In 2018, Chengdu police also carried out the work of collecting and disposing of prohibited dogs in restricted areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the 2018 police interpretation, the restricted breeding areas in Chengdu include Wuhou District, Chenghua District, Jinniu District, Jinjiang District, Qingyang District and High-tech Zone, as well as restricted breeding areas designated by other districts, cities and counties. It is not clear whether Yangma Street in Chongzhou City, where the vicious dog wounding incident occurred, is a restricted area. Rottweilers that bite people are not among the dog breeds banned in Chengdu’s restricted areas. However, even if it is not illegal to raise a Rottweiler, if the owner allows the dog to roam freely in the public area downstairs, without a leash, without a lead, and fails to stop the dog from attacking others in a timely manner, he must bear corresponding consequences for these actions. legal liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is civil liability for compensation. The dog owner must bear the medical expenses of the bitten girl and the injured parents, and must also compensate the victim for her mental losses. Being bitten by a vicious dog not only causes serious physical injuries, but also causes huge psychological trauma to young children, and they should receive corresponding compensation. It should be pointed out that China’s mental damage compensation standards have always been on the low side. For example, in the case of a primary school student in Chongqing who was bitten to death, the dog owner only paid 550,000 yuan in compensation. It should be greatly increased so that dog owners who cause harm to others pay a high price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dog owners should also bear criminal responsibility. If the injuries suffered by the bitten girl are judged to be minor injuries, the dog owner can be held criminally liable for the crime of intentional wounding (an adult should be presumed to know the consequences of not restraining a vicious dog). If the injury does not amount to minor injuries, you can also be convicted of &quot;crime of endangering public safety&quot; because allowing ferocious dogs to roam freely in public areas has seriously threatened the safety of unspecified members of the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s more important is that dog-raising laws must be strictly enforced in normal times, and illegal dog-raising behaviors must be severely punished. You cannot always wait until the harm is caused before dealing with it, because it will be too late. If the law stipulates that aggressive dogs and large dogs cannot be kept, dogs must be tethered when taking them out of the house. But in reality, there are quite a few people who keep aggressive dogs and walk their dogs without leashes. Dog-raising management regulations in various places stipulate the management departments for dog-raising behavior. These departments should take responsibility and strictly punish illegal activities in accordance with the law. Those who illegally raise vicious dogs, neglect their management, and allow dogs to roam freely in public places must be strictly punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the demarcation of restricted areas and prohibited dog breeds in various places should be more detailed and scientific. The Rottweiler that bit people this time is also a violent dog that is banned in Hangzhou, Beijing and other cities, but it is not on the banned list in Chengdu. It is necessary for all localities to delineate the list of prohibited dogs in a more scientific and detailed manner, and at the same time, individuals should be prohibited from keeping aggressive dogs, regardless of whether they are in restricted areas or not. The very few who need care and need to keep aggressive dogs must obtain permission in advance, but the dogs must be kept in captivity and must not be allowed to go out. Violators will be severely punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps it was influenced by the vicious dog bite incident in Chongzhou. Targeted measures such as the &quot;Special Action on Civilized Dog Breeding&quot; have been carried out in many places recently. I especially hope that all parts of the country will take action and continue to do so, so as not to become a gust of wind and &quot;nephew lighting up lanterns&quot; again in a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海底捞拒绝给玩偶过生日：应尊重企业的自主经营权丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258738]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some netizens posted on online platforms to complain, &quot;Does Haidilao discriminate against people who bring cotton dolls?&quot; , became a hot search topic. The post wrote that when he and his friend each brought a cotton doll to Haidilao for dinner, the waiter showed incomprehensible emotions when he asked for the doll to sit in a baby chair in the store. During the meal, the two also experienced bad experiences such as service that felt like they were being neglected, missing dishes that were not replenished until almost finished, and being rejected by the waiter when they wanted to celebrate the birthday of Cotton Doll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cotton dolls are a type of doll that has frequently appeared in the entertainment industry in recent years. By matching clothes and changing hairstyles, you can create a unique and exclusive doll, which is sought after by many young people. Regarding whether the doll can sit in a baby chair, Haidilao customer service said that the company has no relevant regulations and needs to consult the store. Regarding whether it is possible to celebrate the birthday of the doll, the customer service said that it is also necessary to consult the store. &quot;Under normal circumstances, birthdays are celebrated for customers.&quot; This matter has caused waves on the Internet, and it is worthy of discussion and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Haidilao is well-known in the industry for its &quot;god-like service&quot;. Many unique service categories have also won the reputation of &quot;Haidilao, you can&#39;t learn it&quot;. &quot;Celebrating birthdays for customers&quot; is one of them. As a special service, we even created derivatives such as &quot;Birthday Culture&quot; and &quot;Haidilao Birthday Song&quot;, which have won the favor and recognition of customers. If a customer goes to eat hot pot alone, Haidilao will also place a doll opposite to provide this kind of personalized service to &quot;accompany you when you go to Haidilao alone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customer’s behavior of “giving the doll a birthday” may be inspired by this special service. There is no shortage of posts on social media about &quot;birthday for Cotton Doll&quot;, and there are also popular posts that read &quot;Waiters are forced to stay open&quot;. The person involved this time also mentioned this in the article. I am afraid that he did this after seeing similar &quot;experience posts&quot;, intending to follow the same example and enjoy Haidilao&#39;s birthday service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the question is, does the waiter have an obligation to be &quot;forced to open business&quot;? Obviously, there is a difference between &quot;can&quot; and &quot;should.&quot; Haidilao &quot;can&quot; celebrate the birthdays of previous cotton dolls, but it does not mean that they &quot;should&quot; celebrate the birthdays of future cotton dolls. It can also be seen from Haidilao&#39;s response to this incident that they only have a service habit of &quot;celebrating birthdays for guests&quot;, but they do not have a service commitment of &quot;celebrating birthdays for guests&#39; dolls&quot;. Celebrating a doll’s birthday is not written into Haidilao’s service contract, nor is it an agreed-upon special service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, Haidilao is just a catering company. Its main business is to provide catering services to customers, providing consumers with a variety of drinks, food, consumption venues and facilities, integrating &quot;instant processing and production, commercial sales and Service labor&quot; in one. Unique and special services are additional &quot;add-ons&quot; and are no different from marketing methods such as discount coupons, consumption coupons, and membership coupons. In addition to birthday celebrations, Haidilao also provides free manicures, free snacks and other special services, which all fall within the scope of the merchant&#39;s independent operating rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, Haidilao&#39;s starting point for providing these special services is to enhance customers&#39; consumption experience, increase the reputation of its own brand, and bring positive feedback to business operations. However, these special services are a matter of affection, not duty. Therefore, Haidilao certainly has the right to operate independently on &quot;how to provide goods or services&quot; and has the right to adjust the rules and scope of special services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Haidilao has also made many adjustments, such as canceling free beef cubes, canceling free manicures in some stores, requiring at least one pot base to be ordered, no longer allowing bring-in dishes, etc. Similar measures have triggered great discussions, but they still fall within the scope of autonomous business rights and do not involve public interests such as food safety. Haidilao has the right to decide how to adjust the transaction rules, and customers also have the right to decide whether to come and consume. Everything will be left to the judgment of the market, allowing consumers to choose. There is room for two-way choices between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that if the waiter really fulfills the client&#39;s wish and gives the cotton doll a &quot;birthday and a doll chair&quot;, then it may also squeeze out the opportunity for customers with children to obtain the doll chair service. , or push up Haidilao’s operating costs. If some kind of incentive is formed, more dolls and even pets will celebrate their birthdays. Who will bear the rising costs? If the dining environment is regressive for ordinary customers, it is a lose-lose situation for both Haidilao and ordinary customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the party’s “let me go” mentality displayed between the lines of the text is also suspected of emotional blackmail: asking the merchant to provide special services that it is not obliged to provide, or even It is also unreasonable to satisfy its emotional value and cater to certain preferences of subcultural groups. Haidilao naturally has the right to refuse certain excessive or unreasonable requests. The parties concerned can look for restaurants willing to provide such services, or simply organize their own friends to open a Cotton Doll themed hot pot restaurant at their own risk and bear their own profits and losses. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, even if it is &quot;celebrating a customer&#39;s birthday&quot;, members and non-members can enjoy different services in Haidilao. After all, the cotton doll is not a real baby, and the store has the right to decide whether to treat the two-dimensional and three-dimensional dolls equally. In short, the &quot;controversial points&quot; in this incident are still within the scope of independent management rights. &quot;Whether to celebrate Cotton Doll&#39;s birthday&quot; should be left to Haidilao itself to decide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会开幕，展览总面积、展位数和参展企业数量均创历史新高]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258741]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, two overseas buyers visited the Canton Fair venue The bustling crowd inside took photos in the background.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/218f8aca90.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/218f8aca90.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254274&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, two overseas buyers took a group photo with the bustling crowds in the Canton Fair venue as the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, the 134th China Import and Export Fair (Canton Fair) was officially launched. From small but beautiful new consumer products to sophisticated cutting-edge technologies, each booth attracted a large number of interested buyers and visitors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the entrances of the Canton Fair exhibition hall, a large number of overseas purchasers entered the hall in an orderly manner.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/7d1f64b0fa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/17/7d1f64b0fa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254275&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 16, 2023, Guangdong In Guangzhou, at each entrance of the Canton Fair exhibition hall, a large number of overseas purchasers entered the hall in an orderly manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the exhibition hall was crowded and very lively.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/17/45b759e65b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 17/45b759e65b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 16, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, crowds of people in the exhibition hall Surging, very lively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas exhibitor wore a cultural shirt with the brand slogan &quot;Imported from China&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/70a4621458.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/70a4621458.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254277&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas exhibitor wore a cultural shirt with the brand slogan &quot;Imported from China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the new energy vehicle exhibition hall is one of the most popular venues at the Canton Fair.&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/457cf5198c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/457cf5198c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254278&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the new energy vehicle exhibition hall is one of the most popular venues at the Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, a buyer was test driving a new energy vehicle in Guangzhou, Guangdong.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/499c08a56a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/17/499c08a56a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 10 On March 16, a buyer was test driving a new energy vehicle in Guangzhou, Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Xu Bing, spokesperson of the Canton Fair and deputy director of the China Foreign Trade Center, the scale of this Canton Fair has reached a new high, with the total exhibition area expanded to 1.55 million square meters. , an increase of 50,000 square meters compared with the previous session. The total number of booths is 74,000, nearly 4,600 more than the previous session, and the total number of exhibition areas is 55. Statistics are not repeated for each period and exhibition area. There are 28,533 exhibitors, an increase of 3,135 compared with the previous session. Among them, there are 27,883 export exhibition exhibitors. There are 650 exhibitors at the import exhibition. More than 100,000 buyers from 215 countries and regions have pre-registered, and the number of pre-registrations from countries involved in the Belt and Road Initiative has increased by 11.2% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, exhibitors selected home appliances and small commodities at the Canton Fair.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/0d5663c1b2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/17/0d5663c1b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 16, 2023 , Guangzhou, Guangdong, exhibitors select home appliances and small commodities at the Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a buyer took a photo with the Canton Fair mascot.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/633e9138a5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/17/633e9138a5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 16th, a buyer took a photo with the Canton Fair mascot in Guangzhou, Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 16, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas exhibitor walked his baby while visiting the exhibition.&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/2d90dd87b6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/2d90dd87b6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On October 16, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, an overseas exhibitor walked his baby while visiting the exhibition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 134th Canton Fair has five exhibition areas for industrial automation and intelligent manufacturing, new energy vehicles and smart travel, maternity and infant products, new energy, and pet products for the first time. Brand exhibition area. The number of brand companies in the electromechanical industry has increased significantly compared with the previous session. Electronic and home appliance companies have increased by more than 120%, industrial manufacturing companies have increased by more than 100%, lighting and electrical, vehicles and two-wheelers, and hardware tools companies have all increased by more than 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of 17:00 on October 16, 2023, more than 72,000 overseas purchasers have attended the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;As of 17:00 on October 16, 2023, more than 72,000 overseas buyers have attended the 134th Canton Fair.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/17/1c7ac5e75f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/17/1c7ac5e75f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of 17:00 on October 16, 2023, A total of more than 72,000 overseas buyers attended the 134th Canton Fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[谷村新司：再会吧，昴！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258760]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/MmDoFpTlNWOk5XuZXUDBnBWIbwmiFjx4zcQlJgZp.webp&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/MmDoFpTlNWOk5XuZXUDBnBWIbwmiFjx 4zcQlJgZp. webp&quot; data-key=&quot;254299&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alice band, from left: Takao Horiuchi, Shinji Tanimura, Toru Yazawa&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Pleiades&quot; and China&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In childhood, born in Osaka As soon as Tanimura Shinji closes his eyes, he will see a scenery: endless grassland, mountains in the distance, stars all over the sky, cool breeze, swaying grass and trees. &quot;I have a feeling that I have been there. That scenery is my hometown in a previous life. This feeling is very strong and real.&quot; Tanimura said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1980, this feeling became the creative inspiration of Shinji Tanimura. He wrote his most famous masterpiece &quot;Subaru&quot; (also called &quot;Subaru&quot;) in the future. In China, fans are accustomed to (called &quot;Star&quot;): I closed my eyes, my heart was at a loss, I looked up sadly, my eyes were full of desolation, there was only one road leading to the wilderness... I will travel far, see you again, the Pleiades hang high! ——The Pleiades star cluster is located in the constellation Taurus and consists of more than 3,000 stars. It is extremely bright in the night sky and is especially dazzling in autumn and winter. The brighter ones form the Pleiades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 1980, this song was included in the album of the same name. On the album cover, a line of light and shadow cuts across the darkness. Half of Tanimura&#39;s body is buried in the darkness, and half of his body stretches out from the light. He nods slightly, eyes fixed forward, and is ready to go. This song has a melancholy tone, bleak lyrics, and sad images, but its perspective is bright. After the song came out, it became very popular in Japan and sold more than 600,000 copies. In 1987, Shinji Tanimura participated in Japan&#39;s annual &quot;Red and White Song Festival&quot; for the first time, singing &quot;Subaru&quot;, and the TV ratings exceeded 63%. Since then, he has participated in the &quot;Red and White Song Gala&quot; for many years and has become a veteran singer in this most representative show at the end of the year in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1980, the ATV TV series &quot;The Love of the Earth&quot; was launched. In early 1981, singer Guan Zhengjie included the Cantonese version of &quot;Star&quot; in his TV original soundtrack album &quot;The Love of the Earth&quot;, with lyrics written by Zheng Guojiang . In 1982, Teresa Teng sang the Japanese and Cantonese versions of &quot;Star&quot; at the Elizabeth Stadium concert in Hong Kong. As a result, this song became popular in southern China and radiated to the north. Singer Shen Xiaocen included the Japanese version of &quot;Star&quot; in his second album. Since then, this song has been covered by singers such as Alan Tam, Xu Xiaofeng, Feng Feifei, Han Baoyi, and Cheng Lin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend told Shinji Tanimura that the picture in his mind seemed to depict Northeast China, so going to China became his dream. &quot;I have always wanted to visit China, but I don&#39;t know why. But I know that as long as I go, I will understand why I want to go to China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ErfVwIuysKLtiuXt85wPVpvEalqyFAaBsvloZd0K.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ErfVwIuysKLtiuXt85wPVpvEalqyFAaBsvloZd0K.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2004 On November 5, 2019, Shinji Tanimura participated in the &quot;Jewel Heart&quot; Shanghai Concert&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1981, Tanimura Shinji participated in the &quot;Hand in Hand Beijing&quot; concert held at Beijing Workers&#39; Stadium with Chinese singers. He recalled that as soon as he landed at the Chinese airport, he felt like going home. &quot;Even the earthy smell that hit my face felt very familiar. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert lasted for two days. At this time, pop music was in its infancy in China. The tens of thousands of spectators in the work hall sat in silence, with no applause or cheers. They were used to the warm live atmosphere in Japan. Tani Cun was very uncomfortable with it. He and the members of his rock band Alice tried every means to mobilize the audience. After they sang a rhythmic song, people in the venue stood up and applauded continuously. Shinji Tanimura was very excited: &quot;Everyone feels the same about music, and music has no national boundaries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He sang &quot;Subaru&quot; live. This was the beginning of his singing reaching the ears of Chinese audiences. So far, nearly 50 of his works have been adapted into Chinese songs, including Leslie Cheung&#39;s &quot;Who Resonates&quot; (adapted from &quot;Like a Dream&quot;), Anita Mui&#39;s &quot;Walking Alone&quot; (adapted from &quot;This&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;my&amp;nbsp;trial&quot;) &quot;), Jacky Cheung&#39;s &quot;The Distant Her&quot; (adapted from &quot;Romantic Railway&quot;), Priscilla Chan&#39;s &quot;Forgetting Sorrow&quot; (adapted from &quot;Autumn Stoppers&quot;)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ggCgEZS20DHJmkrzEv4rKCSqGjdClLEWCol2l890.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ggCgEZS20DHJmkrzEv4rKCSqGjdClLEWCol2l890.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2007 On September 20, in Nantong, Jiangsu, at the opening ceremony of the 9th China Asian Arts Festival and the Gala &quot;Under the Same Starry Sky&quot;, Shinji Tanimura sang &quot;Flower&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2001, Shinji Tanimura, who was already successful, came to the Yellow River specifically to try to find similar feelings from his childhood, but found nothing. From this, he became more certain that the scene should be near Heilongjiang in Northeast China. Tanimura said with a smile: &quot;Maybe I was Chinese in my previous life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, China suffered from the SARS epidemic. In order to help China fight against SARS, Shinji Tanimura held a &quot;Concert to Support China in Fighting SARS&quot; in Osaka and donated all the 15.34 million yen (approximately US$120,000) raised to the Red Cross Society of China. After SARS ended, he flew to China and held a concert to thank medical workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2010 Shanghai World Expo, Teng Junjie, the chief director of the opening and closing ceremonies, invited Tanimura to perform on stage at the opening ceremony, and Tanimura agreed. For this reason, he canceled several performances in Japan and made compensation. On the evening of April 30, 2010, at the Shanghai World Expo Cultural Center, Asian girls walked out from both sides holding stars in their hands. They complemented the lights of the audience and seemed to stretch out into a galaxy. Shinji Tanimura, China&#39;s overseas promotion ambassador for the 2010 Shanghai World Expo, brought the audience to the audience. The familiar classic song &quot;Subaru&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teng Junjie and Tani Cun have been friends for nearly 20 years. He recalled in an interview: &quot;When Abe and Koizumi were in office, (Japan) had trouble getting along with China, he went directly to Koizumi and told him that his attitude towards China must change. Japan must stand with China, and we two Asian countries must Take this responsibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tanimura is very willing to spend time face-to-face with young Chinese people. In March 2004, the Shanghai Conservatory of Music hired Shinji Tanimura as permanent professor of the Department of Music Engineering and consultant of the Sino-Japanese Music Culture Research Center. This job lasted until 2008. While serving as a visiting professor at the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, Shinji Tanimura spent one week every month in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theme of Tanimura&#39;s class is &quot;How to express music.&quot; Start with the lyrics first. A reporter visited his class. Tanimura entered the classroom, first put half a glass of water on the table, pushed the glass over, and the water came out. He asked the students to write lyrics about it. He left the classroom for 20 minutes and came back to check. The lyrics of a classmate impressed him deeply: When water flows outside, water never knows what its own shape is... &quot;The most important thing is the inner feeling. Only there are people, and I am. If people want to be connected, music is The best medium. Music can best enter people&#39;s hearts, resonate and move, and hearts can meet.&quot; Shinji Tanimura told the reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspiration and core of the song &quot;Subaru&quot; became one of the important narratives of Shinji Tanimura&#39;s future life. As written in the song, he has always felt that &quot;starlight leads the way.&quot; When the 32-year-old Tanimura composed this song, he had no idea of ​​its vast magic, which could transcend time and travel through space, and continue to echo throughout his artistic career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, Japan&#39;s economy was developing rapidly, giving people the illusion that as long as they had money, they could buy everything. But this song tells people: truly precious things need to be felt with the heart. Care, tenderness , consideration, love, etc., these invisible things are crucial to us.&quot; Tanimura said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than 40 years, he has performed and visited various Asian countries and often heard local people singing this song, regardless of gender, young or old. The other person even thought it was the song of his own country. He was once asked: &quot;Do you know this song?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;&quot;Subaru&quot; is the key to opening the door to all Asia and can connect everyone together. .&quot; Tanimura said, &quot;There is no doubt that &quot;Subaru&quot; changed my life. This song took me on a magnificent journey.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ySeRpyen0Uwh75lRWyAvnWYQHCCcx08ReNwaKxuB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;589&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ySeRpyen0Uwh75lRWyAvnWYQHCCcx08ReNwaKxuB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shinji Tanimura and Teresa Teng Singing on the same stage &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (video screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Showa &quot;Legendary&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; On September 21, 2018, Shinji Tanimura, who was almost 70 years old, held the &quot;38th Year of Stars&quot; concert at the Shanghai Grand Theater. At the age of 25, Tanimura&#39;s hairline began to recede, and he began to grow a beard to achieve visual balance on his face. Nearly 45 years have passed, and his works have stayed at a certain point like his hairline, becoming synonymous with his achievements. And his voice is inevitably aging like his hair color. His beard and hair are all white. Even if he sings &quot;Pleiades&quot; with exactly the same arrangement, you can hear the decline in function, but there are gains and losses. At this time, It has the mellowness and sweetness given by age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tanimura Shinji grew up and became famous during the Showa period, and he has obvious Showa characteristics. Shinji Tanimura appears in public and has a decent image. He always had a smile on his face, and his eight teeth were gleaming white. He is diligent, confident, vigorous and friendly, and uses subtle strokes to outline the complexity of the grand narrative. Since his debut, he has held 3,620 concerts in Japan and is still the number one in Japan. He has released 63 albums and 62 singles, with a total sales volume of more than 30 million. He is called the godfather of the Japanese music industry. In the media description, he always promotes Sino-Japanese friendship from the bottom of his heart, cultivates young people with full expectations, and pours his blood into music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps partly due to the language barrier, Chinese reporters said his voice was soft and slow. If you don’t prick up your ears to distinguish it carefully, it may even be masked by the sound of the indoor air conditioner. &quot;People are as quiet as songs.&quot; But if you listen to his works and understand his experience, both the premise and the conclusion of this sentence will be invalid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1948, Shinji Tanimura was born in Osaka. When he was a child, he was overweight and was nicknamed &quot;Fat Pig&quot; by his classmates. His self-esteem was greatly affected. When he was in elementary school, he heard singer Xiao Linxu singing &quot;Migratory Bird&quot; in a performance. He was attracted by Xiao Linxu&#39;s gesture of strumming the guitar and started learning guitar, deciding to regain his confidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, he formed the band Rock Candie with his classmates. Their style was more country folk and their rebellious playing style made the audience feel novel. In 1970, this band held an &quot;American Continent Tour&quot;. They first arrived in Vancouver. Because they were too poor, they had to take a bus across the North American continent all the way to New York. After ten days of tossing, they finally reached their destination. In New York, Shinji Tanimura watched a local rock performance. He shed tears at Janis Joplin&#39;s performance, &quot;It turns out that music still has such a possibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China, He formed a new band, Alice, but the band&#39;s American blues style was not accepted by the Japanese audience. Alice had to perform in various places to meet daily expenses and continue her acting career. During her frequent performances, Alice set a record of holding 303 concerts a year. As the band&#39;s popularity expanded in various places, their songs such as &quot;Winter Thunder and Lightning&quot; and &quot;The Pledge of Tears&quot; also gradually became popular. In 1978, they became the first group of Japanese artists to successfully hold a three-day concert at Nippon Budokan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/Ampapw9ET99MTYyV8EyROgmZOTbNC7vffFfSy6l6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/Ampapw9ET99MTYyV8EyROgmZOTbNC7vffFfSy6l6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2018, in Beijing, Shinji Tanimura held the &quot;38 Years of Stars&quot; concert &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 1974, Shinji Tanimura&#39;s first solo album &quot;蜜&quot; was released. He wrote the lyrics and music for the entire album. One year later, in December, Tanimura Shinji released his second solo album &quot;Umimako&quot;. In this quiet work, there are many shining works, such as &quot;Port Lights&quot;, &quot;Sunflower&quot;, &quot;Warmth&quot;, &quot;Sunset&quot;, &quot;The Road of Sand&quot;... After entering the 1980s, Tanimura produced more and more excellent works. In the 1990s, the theme song &quot;Fengzihuaden&quot; of Toei animation &quot;Three Kingdoms&quot; was released, and &quot;Hometown&quot;, a collaboration with singer and actor Yuzo Kayama... are all Widespread. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tanimura’s life is very interesting. After a concert, he once walked into a small bookstore and offered himself to collect money for the store manager while he was having dinner. Fans who come to the bookstore after listening to Tanimura&#39;s concert will receive an oncoming surprise when paying. In Japanese variety shows in the 1990s, he was experienced, relaxed, unencumbered, and spoke humorously. One second he was not ashamed to share his embarrassing story with the host: due to a bad gastrointestinal condition, the stool collapsed in his pants when he farted; the next second he picked up the guitar and taught them his valuable experience in the music industry for many years: the most important thing is the song Express your heart, not whether it can be passed down to the world or how many people will sing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his later years, Tanimura conducted a deeper exploration of musical expression. The subtleties of his singing have been accurate to every modal word. In the song &quot;Woo Hu&quot;, he poured different techniques into each &quot;ah&quot; to achieve the emotions he expected, such as the feelings in his heart that he wanted to suppress but couldn&#39;t. Sigh while staying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Tanimura held a concert &quot;Commemorating the 45th Anniversary of the Normalization of Diplomatic Relations between China and Japan - 2017 Shinji Tanimura&#39;s 45th Anniversary of His Performing Career in Shanghai&quot; at the Shanghai Grand Theater. At the scene, a beam of chasing light hit the side of the stage and enveloped an empty chair. The prelude of &quot;Restaurant Corner&quot; sounded, and on the other side of the stage, Tanimura picked up the microphone and said: &quot;Next, I will sing a set of narrative love songs for everyone...&quot; &quot;Narrative Love Songs&quot; is his new attempt ——&quot;Explain&quot; the ins and outs of creating the song at the beginning of each song by chatting and heart-to-heart with the audience. In a set of five &quot;narrative love songs&quot;, Tanimura uses the woman&#39;s mood and the man&#39;s perspective to connect the ups and downs of love emotions, just like a love short film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To commemorate the &quot;two 45th anniversaries&quot;, Tanimura released a set of three albums called &quot;Standard&quot;, each with 15 songs, for a total of 45 songs. The first album is representative works selected from the songs he composed; the second album is taken from Alice&#39;s period works; and the third album is Japanese classic songs sung by him. His criteria for selecting tracks to enter this album are: &quot;Children 100 years from now will think that these works are indeed classics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These tracks are also arranged in the order of the ups and downs of life and the ups and downs of emotions. The first part is full of ambition, and in the end there will be a starry reverie like &quot;Pleiades&quot;: &quot;A person&#39;s daily life must be ups and downs, but he will not stick to these emotions and feelings every day. Life and music have something in common . I want to reflect the ups and downs of life into music... Even if the melody on the stage is occasionally sad and disappointing, it must be exciting and upward in the end!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 28, 2018, The &quot;38th Year of Stars&quot; concert in Beijing became Shinji Tanimura&#39;s last public performance in China. On October 8, 2023, Shinji Tanimura died of illness at the age of 74. The funeral was held on October 15, with only close relatives in attendance. On October 16, the news of his death was made public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive reports from Global Figures, The Paper, Xinmin Evening News, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年前8个月基本医保基金收入同比增长9.3%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258746]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Medical Insurance Administration recently released data showing that from January to August 2023, the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance ) total revenue was 2.092333 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 9.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the income of the basic medical insurance fund for employees (including maternity insurance) was 1.473806 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 13%; the income of the basic medical insurance fund for urban and rural residents was 618.527 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 1.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to August 2023, the total expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance) was 1.786477 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 18.3%. The expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund for employees (including maternity insurance) was 1.12573 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 19.6%, of which the expenditure of maternity insurance fund benefits was 70.945 billion yuan; the expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund for urban and rural residents was 660.748 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 16.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“早睡早起身体好”？早睡和早起哪个更难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258744]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The old saying goes, &quot;Early to bed and early to rise are good for good health.&quot; Is this true? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard University analyzed data from nearly 840,000 adults and found that their average sleep time is to fall asleep at 11 p.m. and get up at 6 a.m. Then their &quot;sleep time midpoint&quot; (the halfway point between the time to fall asleep and the time to wake up) is 3 am. If the &quot;sleep midpoint&quot; is moved forward by one hour, the risk of major depression will be reduced by 23%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a study in the journal Sleep Medicine found that people who went to bed early had a 29% increased risk of death or major heart disease compared with those who slept at normal hours (10 p.m. to 12 p.m.). Risk of vascular events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Sleep Research Report (2022)&quot; released by the Chinese Sleep Research Association, more than 40% of young people aged 19-25 in China stay up after midnight, and 40% of young people aged 26-35 stay up after midnight. One-third of people habitually stay up late, and even minors have a 24% rate of staying up late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/JHLH9Shht1otyVAHvNq4J9QsSbTBDGEqlbRo17Bs.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;647&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/JHLH9Shht1otyVAHvNq4J9QsSbTBDGEqlbRo17Bs.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Screenshot of &quot;China Sleep Research Report (2022)&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly affects you to go to bed early and get up early? Which is more difficult, going to bed early or getting up early? Let’s talk&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[咬伤2岁女童的恶犬主人被找到]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258758]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:15:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At about 8:00 on October 16, 2023, Hengda Xichen Oasis Community, Yangma Street, Chongzhou City A girl was bitten by a dog. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the incident, Chongzhou City quickly organized the public security, health, Yangma Street and other departments to set up a joint investigation working group to carry out the investigation. The illegal facts have been initially identified, and the relevant The situation report is as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It was found that at 7:20 on October 16, the two dogs involved ran into the community where the incident occurred, and an injury incident occurred at around 8:00. At 8:20, the white Labrador involved was captured at the scene, and the dog owner, Jia, arrived at the case at about 21:00. At about 22:00, the black Rottweiler was captured. At about 3:00 on October 17, the owner of the black Rottweiler, Tang, arrived at the scene. At present, the police have opened a case for investigation into the incident and have taken criminal coercive measures against Tang, the owner of the black Rottweiler dog, in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to get better treatment, the injured girl was transferred to West China Hospital at about 23:00 on October 16 for further treatment by a team of medical experts. Her vital signs are currently stable. We will continue to do a good job in treating and caring for girls. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Chongzhou City Joint Investigation Working Group&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;October 17, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[越来越多的女性获得诺奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/Gye4nF1LMB1HIOx3viFpaemOfhUEm408X0cHkb6R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/Gye4nF1LMB1HIOx3viFpaemOfhUEm408X0cH kb6R. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Female Nobel Prize winners from 1901 to 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Nobel Prize Outreach/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 4 women winners of the 2023 Nobel Prize, and 11 winners in all 6 prizes Among them, accounting for 36% (4/11). In the history of the Nobel Prize, it is the class with the second most female winners and the second highest proportion. In 2009, there were the most female award winners, with 5 women winning the award, accounting for the highest proportion of 38% (5/13, a total of 13 people won the award that year). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year’s four female winners are Katalin Karikó, the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine; Anne L’Huillier, the Physics Prize ); Narges Mohammadi for the Peace Prize and Claudia Goldin for the Economics Prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, the achievement that won the economics prize was the study of gender differences. US economist Claudia Goldin was awarded the prize for her research on key drivers of gender differences in women&#39;s participation in the labor market. The award citation said her research &quot;has advanced our understanding of women&#39;s labor market outcomes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In layman’s terms, Goldin won the award for studying why women’s income is not as good as men’s. This can be seen as the gender difference in labor remuneration between men and women. Gender differences exist in all aspects of social life, and even the winning of Nobel Prizes has huge gender differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Golding not only studies the difference in income between men and women, but even after winning the award, he complained that there were more men than women in the economics prize. She said that &quot;serious inequality still exists&quot; between men and women in the Nobel Prize in Economics. Indeed, Goldin is the third female economist to win the Economics Prize. From 1969 (the Nobel Prize in Economics began to be awarded in 1969) to 2023, the Nobel Prize in Economics has been awarded 55 times, with a total of 93 winners, of which women account for only 3.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the Nobel Prize comprehensively from the statistical data on the official website of the Nobel Prize, the gender gap between men and women winning prizes is also quite disparate. From 1901 to 2023, the Nobel Prize was awarded a total of 621 times, with 970 individuals and 30 organizations (groups) winning the prize, and a total of 1,000 people and organizations winning the prize. Among them, 65 are women. Looking at individual proportions, the proportion of women is about 6.7% (65/970). However, if we take into account that Marie Curie won the prize twice (in 1903 for Physics and 1911 for Chemistry), only 64 women won the prize, so the actual proportion is 6.6% (64/970). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the various Nobel Prize categories, due to wars and various reasons, different Nobel Prize categories in history have had different awards and number of winners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1901, the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine has been awarded 114 times, with a total of 227 winners, of which 13 were women, accounting for 5.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Physics Prize was awarded 117 times, with 225 winners, of which 5 were female winners, accounting for 2.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chemistry Prize was awarded 115 times, with 194 winners, of which 8 were female winners, accounting for 4.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Literature Prize was awarded 116 times, with 120 winners, of which 17 were female winners, accounting for 14.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Peace Prize has been awarded 104 times, with 141 winners, of which 19 were female winners, accounting for 13.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the six awards, the highest proportion of female winners is the Literature Award, which is 14.2%, and the lowest is the Physics Award, where women account for 2.2%. The economics prize that Golding complained about is considered good. Women account for 3.2%, which is not the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is the proportion of female winners so low? Looking at the total number, they only account for 10.3%. In this regard, Goldin analyzed that the reasons why women earn less than men can also be used to explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Goldin believes that there are many reasons for the gender pay gap, such as gender discrimination, she coined a term - greed for work to explain it, believing that this is the main reason. Greedy work is when a person works longer hours or has less control over their hours and is paid disproportionately more per hour, effectively penalizing women who need to seek flexible labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this situation also creates a lose-lose situation for both sexes. For men, they give up time with their families, while for women, they often give up their careers. The essence is that many jobs pay much higher hourly rates when working longer hours, being on call, busy schedules, evenings and weekends, or unpredictable hours. However, in most couples who are highly educated, have careers and children, the woman is the on-call professional at home, and the man is the on-call professional at work. Therefore, men earn more than women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason behind this is that women have to have children and take care of the family, so they have less time to work, and of course their income is less than men. If this reason is used to explain why women have only accounted for 10.3% of Nobel Prize winners over the past 100 years, it is also valid. Because women devote less time to work and research than men, this prevents them from achieving higher achievements in different fields and therefore winning Nobel Prizes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever career and work achieve results, one is talent and the other is diligence. There may be different opinions on the proportion of the two, but it cannot be denied that diligence is the most important factor in producing results. factor. &quot;A person who is capable of one thing can benefit himself by a hundred, and a person who is capable of ten can benefit himself by a thousand.&quot; This is the true meaning of it. As long as you engage in a job or profession, and persevere over a long period of time, practice makes perfect and results will come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The importance of professional perseverance can also be seen from the history of the Nobel Prize. As long as women participate in scientific research and work, the chances and number of awards will increase. From 1901 to 1925, 4 women won the award; from 1926 to 1950, 8 women won the award; from 1951 to 1975, 3 women won the award; from 1976 to 2000, 15 women won the award Award-winning, from 2001 to 2023, 35 women won the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, in the 50 years from 1901 to 1950, 12 women won the award, but in the 22 years from 2001 to 2023, 35 women won the award. This not only shows that the number of female award-winners has increased with the development of the times, but also shows that modern women’s large-scale participation in work and scientific research is an important reason why they can achieve the same results and win awards as men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These explanations and facts are also reflected in Golding&#39;s research. In her latest book, &quot;Career and Family: Women&#39;s Centennial Journey to Equality,&quot; she mentions the impact of multiple factors on women&#39;s careers, such as the history of women&#39;s pursuit of careers and families, coeducation in higher education, and the impact of birth control pills on women&#39;s careers. The impact of women&#39;s career and marriage decisions, women&#39;s married surnames as a social indicator, and the reasons why women make up the majority of undergraduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Goldin analyzes more than two hundred years of data to demonstrate how and why gender differences in earnings and employment rates have changed, such as the use of birth control pills, which has provided new insights into women&#39;s career plans. opportunities, giving them more time and opportunity to work and participate in scientific research, so that they can achieve the same results as men, and these results may win the Nobel Prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, receiving higher education, participating in work and scientific research are important foundations for women to gradually win more Nobel Prizes and increase their income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独臂船长徐京坤和他的超级赛船丨封面人物]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258546]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/3KlQURn8IAiq75Cy8HWajQ9l7ECu7pLrtLJOg8Ig.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/3KlQURn8IAiq75Cy8HWajQ9l7ECu7pL rtLJOg8Ig. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 23, 2023, at Qingdao Olympic Sailing Center, Xu Jingkun sailed a sailboat out to sea&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2021, Xu Jingkun decided to buy a super racing boat to participate in the 2024 Vendée Singles. Intermittent round-the-world sailing race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Vendée Globe, held every four years, is the &quot;Mount Everest&quot; of competitive sailing - more than 26,000 nautical miles (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;48,000 kilometers&lt;/span>;) is an ultra-long race in which one person and one boat sail around the earth without any supplies or supplies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I know this is difficult, and I may not be able to do it, but I may be the closest to it. If I don’t do it quickly, there may not be any Chinese people in the next twenty or thirty years. Come and touch this event.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To win a ticket to the 2024 Vendée Globe, he must first participate in the designated qualifying competition-in the 2022 season, Xu Jingkun became the first person to be selected for the &quot;Rum Road&quot; &quot;The Chinese skipper of the solo transatlantic sailing race is also the first Asian skipper to finish the race in the IMOCA category. In July 2023, he and Five-Star Red Flag appeared on the official website of Vendée Globe for the first time, becoming the first official candidates for the 10th Vendée Globe in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, he received a confirmation letter from the Coffee Road Organizing Committee. The team passed the 1,200 nautical mile storm test and won the qualification to participate in the 2023 Coffee Road Double Transatlantic Sailing Race. It will be held on October 10 On the 29th, it set sail from the race village of Le Havre, a famous seaport in France. This is the first time a Chinese team has been selected for the world&#39;s top two-person transoceanic competition, and it is also the first Asian team in the history of Coffee Road. Although the Café Road is not one of the five single qualifying events designated by Vendée Globe, it, like other world-renowned high-difficulty championships, can help racing boats accumulate difficult sailing miles. When the team that has obtained Vendée Globe qualification review exceeds the limit When the quota is determined, help the team win in the competition of selecting the best among the best. If the coffee road is successfully completed, Xu Jingkun is expected to seize the ticket to the 2024 Vendée Globe and become the first Chinese person to participate in the world&#39;s top offshore sailing competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Hd3xHdzNkoG4N6kRSfJqHQTcMGvEn9wAdP9Oe8rZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Hd3xHdzNkoG4N6kRSfJqHQTcMGvEn9wAdP9Oe8rZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun’s super racing boat IMOCA60&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; The road ahead is too long”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Buying the IMOCA60 is indeed an important turning point. I used to sail around the China Sea and around the world. Most people can do it with hard work, but entering the field of racing , everything is different.&quot; Xu Jingkun calls the recognition from the media and insiders &quot;everyone&#39;s praise&quot;. He himself does not take it too seriously. Only when he talks about his identity as &quot;rowing captain&quot;, he is full of pride. . &quot;Although I used to sail my own boats and others called me &#39;captain&#39; very early on, in my mind, I didn&#39;t really consider myself a captain until I drove IMOCA60 and managed the racing team.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;IMOCA60 is the designated boat type for the 2024 Vendée Globe. In 2007, Xu Jingkun was training overseas in Rhode Island, USA as a member of the Chinese Disabled Sailing Team. He saw the IMOCA racing boat on the cover of a sailing magazine for the first time. &quot;It&#39;s so dreamy, like a spaceship!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/esXSHu2ovTOfUKr558ukBPh2CzYb143BbZNgzYBv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/esXSHu2ovTOfUKr558ukBPh2CzYb143BbZNgzYBv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253646 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun gathered with friends at the restaurant bar where he worked back then&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the continuous upgrade of IMOCA racing performance, traveling around the world in 80 days has long since become a reality from science fiction. The route of the Vendée Globe is not the most economical and safe trade wind route. Instead, it tries its best to incorporate dangerous capes, equatorial windless zones, and stormy waves into the course. Even so, there have been five captains in the history of the Vendée Globe. After reaching the 80-day mark, the fastest record is 74 days, 3 hours, 35 minutes and 46 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jingkun never thought that one day after the Paralympic sailing team was disbanded, he would go out to sea alone, own a super racing boat, and race against the waves with the captains of the world&#39;s top professional racing boats. In 2021, there are less than 20 hydrofoil super single-hull racing boats in the world. Standing on the boat, he had a strong sense of unreality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IMOCA60 integrates the most cutting-edge monohull sailboat design and shipbuilding technology. The signature design is the swinging keel inserted vertically into the sea and the hydrofoils extending from both sides of the hull. The carbon fiber hydrofoils are light and elegant but strong enough to When standing in the wind, it looks like the wings of a flying fish, helping the ship reduce the friction of the water and achieve faster speeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/igg3a26AZN6NW6OYjC1NyCVraXPlAaupJur759F5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/igg3a26AZN6NW6OYjC1NyCVraXPlAaupJur759F5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253641&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun and his wife Xiao Shuyao in their first year of circumnavigation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;It can sail unimpeded in the world&#39;s dangerous sea areas and harsh sea conditions, with a maximum instantaneous speed of more than 40 knots (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1 knot Equivalent to 1 nautical mile per hour, which is 1.852 kilometers per hour&lt;/span>;). If captains want to stay ahead of others in the Vendée Globe, they must maintain an average boat speed of more than 20 knots day and night for several months. The resistance of sea water, the load of ships and the attack of storms mean that the optimal speed of modern warships can only be about 30 knots. For a full carbon fiber monohull ship, traveling at such a speed in the deep sea is already equivalent to traveling at sea. Driving an F1 car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Before I boarded a ship for the first time, I had never experienced it in real life. I only learned about it from watching videos. When I got on board, I found that the ship was really ‘flying’ on the sea.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Xu Jingkun was selected into the Chinese Disabled Sailing Team in 2005, he has been constantly exposed to various types of boats. He has completed extreme challenges such as a solo circumnavigation of the China Sea and a non-stop solo transatlantic crossing in a 6.5-meter boat. He also used it with his wife Xiao Shuyao. It took three years for the Chinese to complete the first catamaran circumnavigation of the world. &quot;Among the many boats I have sailed before, none of them can compare with it. It is a completely different concept.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A brand-new IMOCA60 sells for more than nine million euros. He bought a second-hand boat with excellent performance for &quot;only&quot; two to three million euros. Parking the ship at the pier of the port of Lorient, France, he carefully hung a sign on the bow to remind passing ships to keep their distance, &quot;Don&#39;t touch my ship, I can&#39;t repair it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;From then to now, he is always short of money. “The money on hand is not enough to overhaul a racing boat.” The money to buy the boat is sponsored by various brothers who love sailing. “I have never had a dedicated business team to help I found all the big sponsors myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he bought the boat, he insisted on going to France alone. &quot;I didn&#39;t even bring any luggage, I just carried a backpack.&quot; He had already done it. Plan and save when you can. &quot;The road ahead is too long, and we may not be able to go on at any time due to lack of funds.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no upper limit on the budget to form a racing team. In his words, &quot;Buy The boat is the first step. To maintain the racing boat every offseason, you have to spend money to buy a boat.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The labor cost alone for a large racing team is one to two hundred per season. 10,000 euros, &quot;We have kept the funds to a minimum. Now there are 5 people in the team, and we will add more people before the start of the game. The German team has 50 people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tipTMrAtBG4M91Sqq3Rsc12lE0td8rQvP1t0AF0W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tipTMrAtBG4M91Sqq3Rsc12lE0td8rQvP1t0AF0W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014, Xu Jingkun participated in the MINI TRANSAT solo transatlantic competition. &quot;No one told me how to control this MINI with one hand. I had to find my own method&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The boat was parked at the dock and he slept in the car. After buying the boat, his wife Xiao Shuyao soon joined. The two born in the 1980s formed the &quot;Xu Jingkun Global Sailing Team&quot;. Each person plays multiple roles: Xu Jingkun is the captain, maintenance worker, chef and video editor; most of the time, Xiao Shuyao is the only captain. His subordinates are the press officer, translator, administrator, and cashier of the fleet. Before the start of the Coffee Road race, the couple simply moved to a boat because short-term rentals were too expensive. &quot;This boat is too spacious for two people to sleep, and it can also save an hour of commuting time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating is on the shore. In the container, &quot;I also renovated a small kitchen, which is very convenient for cooking. It&#39;s great!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Excellent&quot; is Xu Jingkun&#39;s mantra, even if he is afraid of heights and climbed to a 30-meter-high mast. While working, his legs would tremble with nervousness, but he would still grab his phone to take pictures of the evening clouds, &quot;It&#39;s so beautiful! It&#39;s great!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4L7PolWNYc5Ak9whvzGtNJ2qPLJosnJdOoE8G6aR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/11/4L7PolWNYc5Ak9whvzGtNJ2qPLJosnJdOoE8G6aR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253635&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Length 6.5 meters, width 3 meters, interior The 529 has less than 2 square meters of space. I only got this boat a week before the start of the season. In order to save budget, I moved to that boat from that day on. When I went to sea for training during the day, I had to move all the daily necessities to the dock. I went out for the boat race, came back in the evening and moved back and it became my home. In the cold and windy Lorient, 529 became my warmest home” &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no running water in the container, so they have to go out to get water to wash the dishes. When they are busy, they often fail to wash the dishes in time, &quot;just grab one from the dirty bowl and use it.&quot; Xu Jingkun说最有意思的是妻子从来不抱怨，“反倒是我有时候会矫情一下，会嚷嚷几句，&#39;我们这过的是什么日子啊，跟野人一样！明天必须去租房子，我要睡在床上，在餐桌上吃饭，用干净的碗！&#39;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“租什么租！那么贵！”肖姝瑶断喝一声，一把提起他一会儿下水刷船要用的氧气瓶，“干活儿去！赶紧走！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7PA4ssxJBAqoD0g6olcyIBVOhz0Nl6ADOhxnCG4E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7PA4ssxJBAqoD0g6olcyIBVOhz0Nl6ADOhxnCG4E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253636&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2008年北京奥运会青岛会场开幕式，徐京坤（右一）担任护旗手&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“这孩子废了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“她太有意思了，有时我也在观察她的变化，我现在最大的乐趣就是逗她。 ”遇到徐京坤之前，肖姝瑶是一个百分百的文艺女青年，大学毕业后云游四方，到云南开客栈、跑西藏看珠峰……肖姝瑶自己也感叹，“这几年长发、长裙、长披肩都遗失在路上了，越来越中性，每天在中法两个时区疯狂工作。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们两个缺了任何一个人，这个项目都走不下去。 ”徐京坤说肖姝瑶对航海“有一种信仰”，“她说起航海圈的掌故、人物头头是道，就连IMOCA60的数据、性能她都了解得比我还多。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;肖姝瑶是航海圈儿颇有名气的自由撰稿人，笔名“阿九”，她采访过很多水手和船长，用专栏和播客记录并传播航海人的热血和疯狂。徐京坤觉得肖姝瑶比自己更热爱大海，更有水手气质，“她很浪漫，很随性，我很现实，很谨慎。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0aQr1T8Z76WAbukzDH33EH3wzHbPhuxgYZxyqWAa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0aQr1T8Z76WAbukzDH33EH3wzHbPhuxgYZxyqWAa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2012年，徐京坤一个人用7个月的时间，一点一滴地把第一条梦想号修复好&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当面他没有这样说过，他是追求完美的处女座，特别苛刻，从来不夸我。 ”肖姝瑶现在帮助徐京坤管理赛队，除了浪漫，工作内容无所不包。她承担了赛队一切杂务，每次报名参赛都有一大堆表格要填，“以前上学上班的时候，最讨厌填表，哪怕是评奖，如果要填表，宁可不参加了，懒得填”，这几年“把一辈子的表都填了”。每个赛事完成下来都有数千封电子邮件沟通，“还有付款、协调、各种讨价还价……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年俩人在三亚初识，徐京坤正在谋划自己的首次单人跨大西洋，肖姝瑶帮他一起梳理参赛条件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你觉得有可能实现吗？ ”徐京坤忐忑地问道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“理论上可行，不过船不能坏，人不能病，天气也不能出问题。一旦有一场比赛取消或者缩短赛程积分，一切就结束了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/t7N3qu2le5RTx8hXa2hMumRdke4FMLMpRDHxyehD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/t7N3qu2le5RTx8hXa2hMumRdke4FMLMpRDHxyehD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253649&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年11月9日，徐京坤驾驶梦想号从圣马洛出发前往加勒比海，3750海里的航程&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俩人从那时候开始紧紧捆绑在一起，一个在海里乘风破浪，一个在岸上披荆斩棘。“她对我比我对我自己还有信心，她总是很肯定地说，&#39;你一定行！你就是行的！ &#39;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们现在比那时候要好很多了，虽然缺资金，但是不像刚开始的时候，买船都需要拿自己的钱。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VeA34TiTI4hRqhQJeid6N3zz2uYdCIxJkqBGYGJO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VeA34TiTI4hRqhQJeid6N3zz2uYdCIxJkqBGYGJO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253653&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电力、机械、液压、结构维修、船帆粉刷都是徐京坤的工作，最需要体力的是每周两次的船底清理，水下一待就是两三个小时&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了参加2015 MINI TRANSAT跨大西洋比赛，徐京坤买了一条名为529的6.5米旧船，刚成家的小两口把这条船当作了临时的家。早晨徐京坤开船出海训练，晚上俩人挤在两平米不到的小船舱里过夜，把米和土豆块儿、胡萝卜丁都投进一只从国内背去的小电饭锅里一锅焖，就是俩人在法国布列塔尼港口的“中式大餐”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;肖姝瑶从没当着徐京坤叫过苦，徐京坤嘴上不说，心里暗暗称奇，“其实我到现在也经常在想，她也不像我从小就很苦，为什么能跟我一起吃这样的苦？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐京坤12岁的时候因为意外被炸伤，截断了左手和左小臂的三分之二，大脑出于自我保护删去了很多痛苦的记忆，只记得在被抬去医院的担架上，耳边一个老乡的声音，“这孩子废了！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2015年开始，徐京坤参加的比赛都是世界顶级离岸航行竞赛，对残疾人没有特殊优待，他必须证明自己具备正常人一样的竞技能力才有资格入围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;肖姝瑶曾经问他为什么一路如此艰难却从没想过放弃，“因为我没有退路，退回去就是那一句&#39;这孩子废了！ &#39;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7V9ZkmW2b7jpDZyeanHEPJMDCt4IYAkAAAn2hCQC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7V9ZkmW2b7jpDZyeanHEPJMDCt4IYAkAAAn2hCQC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253654&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电力、机械、液压、结构维修、船帆粉刷都是徐京坤的工作，最需要体力的是每周两次的船底清理，水下一待就是两三个小时&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;投奔怒海&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;肖姝瑶刚跟徐京坤在一起的时候，身边朋友很多不理解，但只要一跟他们接触，就会很自然地忘了徐京坤少一只手臂，“我的朋友说他身上没有残缺感。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐京坤总是很自然地露着左胳膊，用它托着手机打电话、在分享会上夹着话筒，“我可以切菜、切肉，我还能包饺子……很多次在海里落水我都是靠它把我搂上来的，特别棒！它跟着我真的出了好多的力气，这是我的标记。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;肖姝瑶相信是航海治愈了徐京坤，“他曾经遭遇无数质疑和指责，一定程度上刺激到了他，让他的起航带着一丝战斗欲。随着航行渐远，他感受到越来越多的关心和帮助、越来越多的善意，变得平和、理性，航行也变得更加纯粹。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐京坤很赞同，“航海彻底改变了我。 ”从16岁进入体校，他在竞争中总是没有安全感，“如果不是因为搞体育你根本都出不去，我就说我一定得在这留下来。 ”他常常有落入无望的忧惧，曾经非常激愤，参加残奥队选拔时，他每天都对自己说，“如果你这一次失败了，你就不用回去了，跳到海里边死掉就行了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;残奥队解散后，很长时间他都找不到自己的生活目标。他讨厌没有目标感的生活，翟墨船长环球航行归来给了他一个方向，“原来队伍解散了，我还可以自己去航行。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的第一条船和第一次环中国海航行充满了悲情色彩，“一个人住在崂山小船厂里，每天像疯子一样忙碌，与生活脱离，失去了所有联系，甚至好像开始被人遗忘。 ”他用了7个多月的时间修复改造了一条几乎要废弃的船，给它取名“梦想号”。2012年9月18日从青岛启航，“带着壮士一去不复还的那种悲壮心情，甚至也带着一些怨念，为什么我这个人一辈子要这么难？为什么我起航出发父母却不能来到现场？你们不相信，我就拼死一搏！带着这种劲！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发小“猴子”在岸上高喊着，“京坤！ ”“京坤！ ”“哎呀，他喊的那个凄厉啊，我都不敢回头，心里跟命运赌着气，死了就死了，怎么着？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4AwubDVqVgNDKraQShoUGUTLCudu23xeqOlwKoPZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4AwubDVqVgNDKraQShoUGUTLCudu23xeqOlwKoPZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253652&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电力、机械、液压、结构维修、船帆粉刷都是徐京坤的工作，最需要体力的是每周两次的船底清理，水下一待就是两三个小时&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;勇气与爱&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这些年当徐京坤完成一个又一个目标，感觉自己能够把握生活之后，忧惧退去，愤怒止息，他越来越舒展，越来越职业。身边的朋友、大哥和赞助商都不太知晓事业起步时期的他，很多人是通过肖姝瑶写他的那本《卑微的梦想家》才了解到那些过往。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我认真读了那本书，非常触动。 ”殷志成是青岛海运职业学校海豚俱乐部的副总经理，接触过很多航海人。“京坤很专注，不会轻易分心，执着于自己的目标，一步一步往前，旁人猛一抬头，会发现他已经达到了难以企及的高度。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“京坤最大的特点是严谨、专业，”诺亚天泽保险经纪公司从2017年徐京坤和肖姝瑶开始双体帆船环球航行时成为他们的合作伙伴，到现在一直为赛队提供保险服务。天泽董事长田丰密切关注着赛船的状况，“咖啡路1200海里资格赛，他们按照规定必须穿越风暴赛段，追着风暴跑下来，赛船完好无损，充分证明他工作做得很细。那么大一条船，每个细节他都亲自维护到位才能有这样的状态，这种职业精神是对自己负责，也是对赞助商、对家人负责。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其实在海上偶尔我还是会（情绪）爆发。 ”2022年朗姆路单人跨大西洋的时候，他连续穿越3个大风暴，最大风力超过70节，“整个海面鬼哭狼嚎，非常让人恐惧。 ”孤身一人在风浪中，徐京坤冲着大海怒吼，“来吧！怎么样吧！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他笑了起来，“没有人看到过我那个样子，以前也没跟人说过。很戏剧化，一边叫喊着，一边开着我的船迎向风浪！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那次还干了一个非常冒险的事，”IMOCA60赛船上有8面帆，每面帆都有一百多公斤重，一趟朗姆路跑下来，大风吹坏了3面帆。“有一面帆直接掉到海里去了，船还在跑，三百多平米的帆兜着几十吨的海水，靠人力是根本拉不上来的。 ”徐京坤拿着一把利刃跳进冰冷的大西洋，“一点点切，把它切成碎片拿回来了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深海航行最忌讳的就是人船分离，大洋深处，连救援力量都没有能力抵达，“事后想来想去，以后还是不能这样干了。 ”徐京坤说这种行为跟自己理性稳妥的天性严重不符，他甚至都无法解释，“但这都是人在岸上、在正常情况下的想法，紧急时刻，你的想法会不一样。如果不跳进海里，帆可能会把船拖沉，比赛会被迫终止，而我为这个比赛付出了那么多，绝对不甘心就这样放弃。我的船也不只是一条船，它像我的孩子一样，不可能不去救它。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了充满勇气的冒险竞赛，极限航海中也有许多关于人与船、人与人之间的爱的传递。2020旺代环球就曾上演61岁的传奇航海人让·勒·卡姆和几位船长冒死营救船只发生灾难性断裂的船长凯文的故事，极少流泪的徐京坤说，“这些故事很容易触动我的泪点。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;船长们是懂得表达爱的，那些在最凶险的海域守望相助过的水手们，常常会结伴参加咖啡路双人跨大西洋赛。肖姝瑶在“徐京坤环球航海赛队”公众号上除了发布关于徐京坤赛队的消息，还会介绍很多航海英雄和海上传奇，她写了这样一段话——&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“1997年，前一年在旺代环球80节暴风中救下几乎失温的拉菲尔·迪内利的皮特·戈斯，作为伴郎参加完迪内利的婚礼，两人又组合来咖啡路拿了个CLASS2组别冠军，成为离岸航海界的一段美谈。 2012年旺代让·勒·卡姆（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对，就是2020年救人的这位&lt;/span>;）翻船18个小时之后，文森特·里乌赶来救了他一命，两人搭档到咖啡路拿了个IMOCA组别冠军。旺代生死之交的组合来咖啡路&#39;刷&#39;冠军，似乎已经成为传统了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“阿九是懂航海的！ ”虽然他总爱开玩笑称肖姝瑶为“不靠谱的阿九”，内心里却深知她的宝贵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐京坤由衷赞叹这些海上传奇超越了胜负，“我很喜欢听她给我讲这些人和故事，不过一问她，她就停不住了，我就喊停停停，我要去干活了……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方人物周刊》记者9月底在青岛见到徐京坤时，距离咖啡路开赛还有不到一个月的时间，“前段时间太累了，我必须调整。这次回来基本没有安排什么事情。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们一起往奥帆中心走，秋天的风吹过来，他眯着眼睛，“真棒！这是最好的季节！很舒服！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你左胳膊怎么了？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛奥帆中心看门大哥的脸晒得黝黑，可能来城市的时间也不长，说话还是乡音。徐京坤和一行人从他面前经过，大哥竟然脱口而出这么一问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小时候出了点儿事故。 ”徐京坤的语气和神情都非常平静，并且停下脚步，面带微笑地定定望着大哥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看门大哥坐着不动，抬起脸，眼里满是关切疼爱，带着乡里人的直接和热忱继续发问，“现在生活还好吗？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“还好，挺好的。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他给我们指他的“梦想号”曾经停靠的地方，“那里，那条红船的旁边。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[患认知障碍的老人“被消费”60万：公检法对“坑老”现象应有力介入]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据上海《新民晚报》2023年10月14日报道，市民任阿姨反映，她的哥哥患有严重的认知障碍，无法与人正常交流，至今未婚。任阿姨称，哥哥日常和她们生活在一起，外出超2016年，北京一美容店把不少大妈拉到店里做免费足疗，顺势推荐“能治病”的按摩项目，让客户花钱办卡，骗取十余人百万余元。海淀法院一审以诈骗罪，判处美容店经理赵某和店长冯某有期徒刑10年，判处3位美容技师4年至5年不等的有期徒刑，并处罚金。可见，美容美发行业针对老人尤其是失能老人的诈骗行为，无论是经手具体事宜的工作人员，还是企业管理者，情节严重者都需为此承担刑责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;司法机关应让法律有牙齿，对更多同类案例强化问责，也是向各行业商家发出警示：对老人设以种种消费陷阱，甚至利用其身体或精神疾病，诱导加强制其消费，公检法应有力介入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过一两公里就要家人陪同。 2019年，他独自去了家门口的文峰宛平店理发，迄今竟在文峰美容美发宛平店和天钥桥店内“被消费”近50次，妹妹们多年来省吃俭用为他积攒的近60万元看病钱、养老钱被掏了个干干净净。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓认知障碍，据首都医科大学宣武医院主任医师贾建平介绍，认知障碍又称认知缺陷，常分为轻度认知障碍和痴呆两类，患者可同时出现性格、情绪改变、异常行为等表现。一个存在认知和沟通障碍的独身老人，是限制民事行为能力人。民法典第二十二条规定，不能完全辨认自己行为的成年人为限制民事行为能力人，实施民事法律行为由其法定代理人代理或者经其法定代理人同意、追认。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从任阿姨哥哥的反馈来看，门店不仅派“专人”跟着去银行或取现或转账，还“帮”着他们眼中的“笨爷叔”借贷。如此行为，显然是利用老人的认知障碍欺骗或强制其消费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任阿姨还发现，其哥哥不仅在该美容店消费近60万，还存在充值与电子付款记录在时间和金额上均不相符、数万元消费只有手写充值凭证而没有出现在文峰收款记录、收款方显示为外地广告公司、“文峰全身养护金典精油”单次消费达1万元等反常情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果任阿姨陈述属实，该文峰美容店已涉嫌诈骗罪。 《关于公安机关管辖的刑事案件立案追诉标准的规定（二）》规定：合同诈骗案以非法占有为目的，在签订、履行合同过程中，骗取对方当事人财物，数额在二万元以上的，应予立案追诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刑法第二百二十四条关于合同诈骗罪的规定：诈骗公私财物，数额较大的，处三年以下有期徒刑、拘役或者管制，并处或者单处罚金；数额巨大或者有其他严重情节的，处三年以上十年以下有期徒刑，并处罚金；数额特别巨大或者有其他特别严重情节的，处十年以上有期徒刑或者无期徒刑，并处罚金或者没收财产。司法解释《关于办理诈骗刑事案件具体应用法律若干问题的解释》第一条规定：诈骗公私财物价值三千元至一万元以上、三万元至十万元以上、五十万元以上的，应当分别认定为刑法第二百六十六条规定的“数额较大”“数额巨大”“数额特别巨大”。对照刑法及最高法、最高检相关解释，任阿姨哥哥在文峰美容店“被消费”近60万已属“数额特别巨大”，司法机关当立案调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任阿姨哥哥的遭遇并非个案，随着中国逐步进入老龄化社会，老人群体的权益保障备受各界关注。 2016年，全国老龄办、民政部等共同发布的第四次中国城乡老年人生活状况抽样调查结果显示，我国失能、半失能老年人大致4063万人，占老年人口18.3%。其中伴随失智的老人比例也不低。失能、半失能老人往往全部或者部分丧失了生活自理能力，而作为监护人的配偶、子女，受种种原因所限无法时刻伴随身边，也就容易给某些不法者可乘之机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老吾老以及人之老”本为社会伦理，但某些人却视老人为待宰羔羊。近年来，针对老人群体的不法案例屡屡曝出，2022年4月，平安中国建设协调小组牵头部署全国打击整治养老诈骗专项行动。 6月，最高检公布6件打击整治养老诈骗犯罪典型案例，6件典型案例覆盖了投资养老产业、预定养老公寓、销售收藏品、提供老年人诊疗服务、代办“养老抚恤金”等多种养老诈骗典型手段，涉及集资诈骗罪、非法吸收公众存款罪、诈骗罪、侵犯公民个人信息罪等涉养老诈骗相关罪名。坑害老人的套路有多深，法律所应发挥的问责效力就应有多大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>