<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[跨国药企扎堆进博会，多款创新药首秀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被传收购碧桂园？中国平安回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 09:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 8, foreign media reported the news of Ping An’s acquisition of Country Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4b28e3afa0ab6ee807d2c994e8a6fd08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4b28e3afa0ab6ee807d2c994e8a6fd08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257517&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Ping An issued a statement saying that the company has noticed a news report published by Reuters about the company being required by relevant government departments/institutions to acquire Country Garden Holdings Co., Ltd. and inherit its debts. The company solemnly declares that the report This is completely untrue and the company has never received any relevant request from any government department/agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statement pointed out that the company had previously provided clarification in writing to Reuters when receiving relevant inquiries, but Reuters still insisted on publishing relevant false reports, and the company deeply regretted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern+ reporters noticed that as of press time, the latest share price of Country Garden (02007.HK) was HK$0.82, up 10.81%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[少林寺在非洲设分支：黑人武僧是切实的文化输出]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260162]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Shaolin Temple Abbot Shi Yongxin and his party visited Bolivia, Argentina and other South American countries to carry out a series of cultural exchanges Activity. On the morning of October 21, 2023, local time in Bolivia, the Shaolin cultural delegation watched the Shaolin Kungfu report performance of Bolivian Shaolin disciples and interacted on the spot. While in Bolivia, the Shaolin cultural delegation also visited the South American Shaolin Cultural Center, Bolivia Baoen Temple and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, a video on Weibo of a young black monk practicing Shaolin Kung Fu also sparked heated discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the young monk boxing in the video black, but the master is also black. This is a branch of the Shaolin Temple in Africa. Some people say that this is the flowering of Chinese culture within the wall and the loss of culture; the Shaolin Temple is becoming more and more international, making people feel that it has lost its original flavor. This view is of course wrong, and someone has refuted it very well: once it is exported, it will be lost, and if it is not exported, it will be criticized as cultural weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shaolin Temple has been engaged in systematic cultural dissemination, forming many practice platforms that influence and disseminate Shaolin Kungfu and its culture, and building a global dissemination mechanism centered on Shaolin culture at home and abroad. It has had a huge social impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2001, Shaolin layman &quot;foreign disciple&quot; Deller opened the Shaolin Cultural Center in Berlin, Germany. This was the first overseas branch directly authorized to cooperate with the Shaolin Temple. Currently, there are nearly 200 overseas Shaolin cultural centers distributed around the world. According to data from relevant institutions, there are no less than 60 million people practicing Shaolin Kung Fu around the world; there are hundreds of Shaolin cultural institutions in more than 100 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, the &quot;Shaolin European Federation&quot; was established in Vienna; in 2004, the California House of Representatives unanimously passed a resolution and established in law March 21 of each year as &quot;Songshan Shaolin Temple Day&quot;. In 2010, the &quot;Shaolin European Federation&quot; was announced in Vienna, Austria; in 2011, the &quot;Shaolin North American Federation&quot; was established in Los Angeles, the United States. In 2014, the 10th anniversary of the establishment of &quot;Songshan Shaolin Temple Day&quot; in California, the then US President Obama said in his congratulatory message: &quot;Shaolin culture can provide us with spiritual space and help us cultivate a strong sense of social responsibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shaolin Temple recruits foreign disciples and even goes out to build temples and Kung Fu training classes, which can not only promote Buddhism, but also Shaolin Kung Fu and spread Chinese culture. Shaolin Temple is the place where Patriarch Bodhidharma stayed the longest after he came to China. It is known as the ancestral palace of Zen Buddhism. Zen Buddhism absorbs a large amount of ideological content from Confucianism and Taoism, turning foreign Buddhism into a Chinese Buddhism that corresponds to China&#39;s specific social and historical conditions and ideological and cultural background. Therefore, Zen Buddhism has realized the transformation from the Sinicization of Buddhism to Sinicized Buddhism and is rich in profound Chinese cultural elements. Shaolin Kung Fu and Shaolin Temple have gone global, and Chinese culture has also expanded its influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although black young monks and black abbots seem to be inconsistent, it is just because they are not used to it. It should be pointed out that the process of cultural export, success and acceptance cannot remain unchanged. It will also change and alienate according to local social, cultural, technological, economic, moral, conceptual and other factors, forming new ones to some extent. culture. We must maintain a tolerant attitude toward such changes and mutations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the influence of the Chinese New Year (Spring Festival) is growing, and many countries and regions have designated the Chinese New Year as a legal holiday. There will be a holiday on this day, and national and regional leaders will extend holiday greetings to those celebrating the Spring Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the international context, the Chinese New Year is often written as: Chinese new year. &quot;Happy Chinese New Year&quot; is translated as &quot;Happy Chinese New Year&quot;, indicating that this New Year comes from the Chinese calendar. However, with the growing influence of the Spring Festival, there is now a trend to translate the Spring Festival into &quot;Lunar New Year&quot;. Lunar means &quot;moon&quot; and can be understood as &quot;lunar calendar&quot;. Nowadays, many people use it this way. US officials use &quot;Lunar New Year&quot; when issuing New Year greetings. United Nations Secretary-General Guterres also used &quot;Lunar New Year&quot; in his New Year greeting video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that this is an attempt to de-Sinicize the Spring Festival and steal a Chinese festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You don’t have to look at it this way. This is the normal state of cultural export. The Romans originally used the Egyptian lunar calendar. In 46 BC, Roman commander Julius Caesar decided to recompile the Julian Calendar based on the Egyptian solar calendar. In 325 AD, the Roman Emperor Constantine established the Julian calendar as the Christian calendar. By the 6th century AD, Christians regarded the day when Jesus, the founder of Christian legends, was born more than 500 years ago as the first year of AD. Before the 16th century, most Western countries adopted the Julian calendar. In 1582, Pope Gregory XIII, with the assistance of the Neapolitan astronomer and physicist Giraldi and the German mathematician and Jesuit Clavius, corrected the Julian calendar promulgated in 46 BC. Errors formed the Gregorian calendar commonly used in our modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Revolution of 1911, the Provisional Government of the Republic of China legislated to use the Gregorian calendar from January 1, 1912, and stipulated that January 1 of the Gregorian calendar would be the &quot;New Year&quot;. This is now recognized around the world as the starting point of the new year. However, now everyone in the world can only say &quot;Happy New Year&quot; but not &quot;Happy Roman New Year&quot;. This is not stealing a holiday from the Romans or Christians, but a normal process of cultural export. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many countries in Asia also celebrate the Lunar New Year, such as South Korea, Vietnam, Singapore, Malaysia, etc. From their point of view, they may not want to use an obviously regional name like &quot;Chinese&quot;, so they will use &quot;Happy Lunar New Year&quot; to express &quot;Happy Spring Festival&quot;, which is just like the Chinese people don&#39;t know how to express &quot;Happy Lunar New Year&quot;. It&#39;s the same as saying &quot;Happy New Year Roman&quot;, but what does it matter? This calendar was passed down from China. Under the tributary system in the traditional era, the Chinese dynasty would issue calendars and allow surrounding vassal states to &quot;honor Shuo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, whether it is African black Shaolin Temple disciples or it is called &quot;Lunar New Year&quot;, it is a real cultural export. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[争论“开门杀”责任与赔偿：为何司机负主责，为何保险要代赔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260160]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Taxi parked on the roadside in Beijing. &quot;Opening the door to kill&quot; has become a hot topic in recent years . Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Yi Haifei China News Service Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f1e419dff4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f1e419dff4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A taxi parked on the roadside in Beijing. &quot;Opening the door to kill&quot; has become a hot topic in recent years. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Yi Haifei China News Service Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-October 2023, the incident of a child in Tianjin being &quot;killed by opening the door&quot; and then being run over by a bus attracted attention. While riding an electric bicycle to carry her daughter, a woman hit the newly opened door of a passenger bus on the side of the road. The child fell to the ground and was crushed to death by the wheels of a passing bus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is another &quot;open door killing&quot; case. Southern Weekend reporters searched the relevant judicial documents website and found that in recent years, &quot;open door killing&quot; accidents have occurred frequently. Dai Xianfeng, secretary-general of the Legal Affairs Committee of the China Communications and Transportation Association, believes that with the substantial growth of private cars and non-motor vehicles, the public generally lacks awareness of the dangers of &quot;opening the door to kill&quot;, resulting in the frequent occurrence of such accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters that door-opening killings are mainly divided into two types: one is when the driver opens the door himself and collides with a non-motorized vehicle, in which case the driver bears full responsibility; If a passenger opens the door and collides with a non-motor vehicle, the passenger will generally constitute a joint tort with the driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latter situation can be subdivided into different accident types, and the final liability for compensation will also be different. Two common situations are: the driver and the passenger have an operational relationship, such as taxis, online ride-hailing and other passenger-carrying activities; the driver and the passenger are friends or relatives, and there is no operational relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;&#39;Opening the door to kill&#39; is a hot topic in traffic accidents. It is very lethal and its liability determination has always been controversial.&quot; Zhou Bo, a senior lawyer who has been representing traffic accident cases for many years, added that at present, all over China The traffic control department in China still lacks unified identification standards when determining responsibility for &quot;opening the door to kill&quot; accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What responsibilities does the online ride-hailing platform bear?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 18:00 on November 3, 2020, just after work, 39-year-old Zhang He was riding an electric bicycle on the non-motorized lane on his way home. He collided with an online ride-hailing car that had just opened the door, causing Zhang He to be seriously injured and unconscious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident occurred on Zhongshan 2nd Road, Songjiang District, Shanghai. Relevant judgments show that after completing a trip, the online ride-hailing driver Xia Moulin temporarily stopped the vehicle and did not keep the vehicle close to the right side of the road. He also did not remind passenger Fang Mouxin to observe the traffic coming from behind. Fang Mouxin opened the right door. , resulting in Zhang He’s injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My husband now can’t even remember the names of his father, mother and son, nor his own name.” Zhang He’s wife told Southern Weekend reporters that Zhang He was originally the backbone of the family because The car accident resulted in a craniocerebral injury that constituted a tenth-level disability, and the treatment has not healed yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The traffic police detachment of the Songjiang Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau determined that the driver Xia Moulin bore the primary responsibility for the accident, the passenger Fang Mouxin bore the secondary responsibility, and Zhang He was not responsible. The court later ruled that the driver and passenger constituted joint infringement. Among them, the driver&#39;s compensation ratio is 70%, and the compensation is 820,000 yuan; the passenger&#39;s compensation ratio is 30%, and the compensation is 350,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The transportation department will first issue an accident liability determination document to determine the primary and secondary responsibilities of the driver and passengers. Later, the court will make a judgment based on the liability determination document during the trial.&quot; Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters , the responsibility determination letter issued by the transportation department will not clarify the responsibilities of the driver and passengers into specific proportions. As for how the final court divides the proportion of primary and secondary responsibilities, it is within the scope of the people&#39;s court to exercise discretion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the judgment of the above-mentioned case shows that Xia Moulin did not actually have insurance related to operating vehicles when using a private car, and his online ride-hailing platform Didi Chuxing Company failed to perform its due review duties. ; And as a platform, Didi and Xia Moulin share profits, bear risks, and ensure operational safety, and they are both considered as the carrier of passengers. Therefore, Didi shall bear joint and several liability with the driver Xia Moulin for the losses suffered by the injured in accordance with the law, and jointly compensate 820,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Regardless of whether the online ride-hailing car has the relevant qualifications to operate a vehicle or not, the driver taking the order is regarded as performing his duties. The driver may not be an employee of Didi, but legally, as long as he performs his work tasks , the platform has the responsibility.&quot; Dai Xianfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 16 of the &quot;Interim Measures for the Administration of Online Reservation Taxi Operations and Services&quot; stipulates: &quot;Online taxi-hailing platform companies assume the responsibility of the carrier and should ensure operational safety and protect the legitimate rights and interests of passengers.&quot; The Chinese Civil Code also states Relevant regulations require online ride-hailing platforms to assume the responsibilities of the carrier under the transportation contract between the driver and the passenger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that when facing consumers, the carrier’s responsibilities and compensation obligations originally belonging to the driver under the transportation contract may be borne by the online ride-hailing platform to a large extent. The same goes for taxi drivers and taxi companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a passenger pushes the door and causes a &quot;door kill&quot;, but the driver has fulfilled his obligation to remind him, does he still need to bear responsibility? Dai Xianfeng told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Unless the passenger was intentional, the driver still needs to bear certain liability for the accident. There is a platform or insurance company behind the driver, which has a stronger compensation ability. It is the substantive fairness of the law to allow the victim to receive compensation according to the law. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But not all situations require the owner of a motor vehicle to be held responsible. Zhou Bo added to Southern Weekend reporters that if a vehicle parked on the roadside and opened its door in compliance with regulations, and a non-motor vehicle drove in the wrong direction or caused an &quot;open door kill&quot; casualty accident due to other reasons, the traffic control department may also determine that the non-motor vehicle bears major or even full responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Should insurance recognize the car or the person?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhou Bo told Southern Weekend reporters that in the case of &quot;open door killing&quot; caused by passengers, there are two main controversial links: one One is how the front-end traffic control department determines the primary and secondary responsibilities of the driver and passengers; the other is the insurance company that insures the vehicle. Should it compensate on behalf of the passengers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The most critical link is the identification of front-end responsibilities, under what circumstances passengers should bear responsibility, how to divide primary and secondary responsibilities, and under what circumstances passengers are not required to bear responsibility.” Zhou Bo told Southern Weekend reporters that the traffic control department The methods and standards for determining responsibility are currently not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, in the &quot;open door killing&quot; cases represented by Zhou Bo, the identification standards of traffic police in various places have been different, which also directly affected the final court judgment. For example, when they both open the door for a passenger, some traffic police believe that the passenger and the driver are one and the same tortfeasor; some traffic police believe that the driver should bear full responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, a judgment made public in 2020 showed that after a &quot;door-opening killing&quot; accident occurred in Luocheng County, Guangxi, the &quot;Road Traffic Accident Determination&quot; issued by the local traffic police department on the accident involved determined that the passenger If you obstruct the passage of other vehicles when opening and closing the door, you will bear all the responsibility for the traffic accident. The driver is not responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dai Xianfeng said that under normal circumstances, the court&#39;s judgment will be consistent with the accident liability determination issued by the transportation department, unless there is other direct evidence to the contrary that is sufficient to overturn the liability determination. &quot;On the one hand, from a professional perspective, judges are no better at handling traffic accidents than traffic police; on the other hand, the probative power of evidence issued by state agencies is higher than other general evidence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the driver is responsible If the passenger is fully responsible, there will not be much controversy, because the insurance company will pay in the end. But if the passenger is held responsible, there will be controversy.&quot; Zhou Bo said that when the passenger is found responsible, the main point of dispute will become : Should the insurance company that insures the vehicle bear the liability of the passengers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked multiple judicial documents and found that when the driver and the passenger who took the initiative to open the door did not have an operating relationship, but were relatives or friends, many drivers would claim that they were fully responsible. The reason is that drivers, as car owners, have purchased compulsory traffic insurance or commercial third party insurance, and the insurance company can compensate them on their behalf. It is precisely because of this that in such &quot;open door killing&quot; cases, there are endless lawsuits between insurance companies and the infringers of the cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2019, a &quot;door-opening killing&quot; accident occurred in Fengtai District, Beijing. The car driver Zhang Mouyan was friends with the passenger Ma Mou who pushed the door open. After handling by the Fengbei Brigade of Fengtai Traffic Detachment, the car owner and passengers in this case were equally responsible for the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In court, the car advocate Mouyan argued that he failed to fulfill his obligation to remind and should bear full responsibility. Passenger Ma Moushuang also pointed out that if there is no vehicle, there is no act of getting out of the vehicle. Insurance companies should identify the insured vehicle rather than the person who caused the vehicle accident. The insurance company argued that the company was only responsible for the insured car claimant&#39;s compensation amount, that is, compensation at a rate of 50%, and did not recognize that Zhang Mouyan bore full responsibility. It said: &quot;According to the insurance law, Zhang Mouyan violated the principle of good faith and took the initiative to increase her own responsibilities, which may have resulted in excessive compensation for our company. Our company reserves the right to pursue the two of them for insurance fraud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the court ruled that the insurance company should be liable for the injured person&#39;s various losses within the scope of insurance based on the joint and several liability of the car owner and passengers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that in such &quot;open door killing&quot; cases, there were many verdicts in which insurance companies were ultimately responsible for compensation on behalf of passengers. In the aforementioned &quot;open door killing&quot; case in Luocheng County, although the court ruled that the passengers were fully responsible, the final compensation for the injured was paid by the insurance company that insured the vehicle involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Insurance companies generally defend themselves. They believe that insurance compensation is for the insured car owner. Once the driver is not the car owner, no compensation should be paid. However, this defense opinion can only be said to have a certain degree of truth, and the court often does not Adopted.&quot; Zhou Bo said that at present, the exemption clause in this aspect of the insurance contract itself is not clear, and different people will have different understandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, some online ride-hailing platforms and taxi companies require passengers to open the right door to get in and out of the car as a measure to prevent &quot;open door killing&quot;. Dai Xianfeng believes that it is necessary to strengthen the education and publicity related to &quot;opening the door to kill&quot; for students: &quot;I think that &#39;opening the door to kill&#39; should also be a key part of the training when taking the driver&#39;s license test. We will ask to look at the reflector before starting and after stopping the car. , but there is no direct training for &#39;opening the door to kill&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(Zhou Bo and Zhang He are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改革开放45周年—建言者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;45 years ago, under the guidance of Deng Xiaoping’s requirement to “turn banks into real banks”, China began a planned and Step-by-step financial system reform. Finance, the core of the modern economy, has been given an extraordinary mission in China&#39;s reform process. 45 years ago, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance separated, and China&#39;s &quot;unified&quot; financial system reform began. Although it was once trapped in the reform detour of the &quot;Five Major Contracts&quot;, it entered a &quot;big step&quot; process since 1993. 45 years later, &quot;deepening the reform of the financial system&quot; has become the action plan, and the reform and opening up of the financial market has also entered the deep water zone. Taking history as a mirror can help us understand gains and losses. To this end, we conducted in-depth interviews with the promoters, experiencers and witnesses of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up to provide suggestions for the stable and long-term development of China&#39;s financial industry.</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中华白海豚“迷路”，广州正在追踪施救]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260218]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清华国家金融研究院张伟：房贷证券化是双刃剑，目前更不宜推出丨首席访谈⑬]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260180]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The much-watched Central Financial Work Conference proposed “&lt;span>;Aiming to accelerate the construction of a financial power&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;This is the first time that the central government has proposed the goal of “financial power”. Among my country&#39;s major financial fields, the banking industry is the largest and is the main transmission system for macroeconomic control policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the banking industry is facing multiple challenges: under the counter-cyclical trend, the net interest margin of the banking industry has dropped to a historical low; at the same time, as the real estate industry enters a new stage, banks regard it as high-quality assets. The mortgage business is facing difficulties; after testing the waters of equity investment, the investment research capabilities of bank wealth management subsidiaries have also been questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China’s A-share “profit king”—can the banking industry achieve breakthroughs by leveraging financial technology? Has it reached a critical point in transformation? How do banks shape their core competitiveness? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A researcher from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center interviewed Zhang Wei, deputy director of the National Institute of Financial Research at Tsinghua University. Zhang Wei focuses on researching monetary policy and financial crisis early warning mechanisms. He also took the lead in compiling the &quot;2023 China Banking Industry Ranking Top 200 Research Report&quot; and taught more than 300 training courses for the five major state-owned banks and some joint-stock banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/zslPwg6O7gV7qMYCXPkV9k3e0LDmM0nIxuTB425I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;307&quot; height= &quot;410&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/zslPwg6O7gV7qMYCXPkV9k3e0LDmM0nIxuTB425I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Wei, deputy director of the National Institute of Financial Research at Tsinghua University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mortgage securitization&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;High risk&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our research found that housing mortgage loans in my country basically have floating interest rates. Most foreign bank mortgage loans have fixed interest rates. Why is it different? What is its background? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Most foreign mortgage interest rates are fixed interest rates, while our country’s mortgage loans have quasi-floating interest rates, that is, they are not completely floating. There is an essential difference between the two. In the past, after the central bank adjusted interest rates, existing mortgage interest rates were not adjusted immediately, and were often adjusted accordingly the following year. In other words, the central bank can adjust the interest rate multiple times within a year, but the borrower&#39;s mortgage interest rate remains basically unchanged within a year and can only start to adjust on January 1 of the following year. Therefore, it is not a fully floating interest rate but a quasi-floating interest rate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the development of the banking system, the primary purpose of various policies was to make banks grow and grow, and to reduce bank capital operation risks. The choice of a floating rate form stems from banking tradition. Fixed-rate mortgages are lower risk for the borrower but higher risk for the bank. In the past two years, some reforms have been made to mortgage interest rates. Borrowers can choose fixed interest rates or floating interest rates. However, existing housing loans still account for the majority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We also found through research that the balance of domestic housing mortgage loans is huge, but Mortgage asset securitization (MBS) has developed slowly since its inception in 2006. In the first half of 2023, there will be zero issuance of RMBS. This is also very different from the mortgage business in developed countries. Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four reasons for the slow progress of domestic mortgage asset securitization. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, mortgage asset securitization is an imported product. Mortgage securitization tools such as MBS in the United States have been developed since the 1970s. China&#39;s housing loan market developed relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, domestic mortgage asset securitization started in 2006, just as the U.S. real estate bubble began to burst. The following year, the U.S. subprime mortgage crisis triggered a chain reaction of MBS defaults and credit derivatives such as CDO and CDS, which eventually led to the 2008 global financial crisis. The external crisis requires us to re-understand the pros and cons of mortgage securitization. For regulatory agencies, a more cautious approach has been chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, mortgage asset securitization is a financial derivative. China has always been cautious about the development of financial derivatives because derivatives are highly leveraged and risky. Domestic laws on futures and derivatives were promulgated many years after the subprime mortgage crisis broke out, and did not include credit derivatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, over the past 20 years, my country’s commercial housing market has experienced a process of development and regulation of relaxation-tightening-relaxation-retightening-relaxation again. Maintain strict control over the financing of the real estate market through asset management products such as credit and trust to prevent the real estate market from overheating. Mortgage asset securitization is an important means of real estate financing and will also be strictly controlled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think it is possible to accelerate the implementation of asset securitization to activate the market? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Activating the real estate market through MBS is an option. my country&#39;s real estate credit market is an issue and hold model. If mortgage assets are securitized, banks can package the mortgages and sell them through securitization, and brokers can then distribute them to institutional investors including funds. The final investor may be an individual or a business. Mortgage risk is thus dispersed. Banks also receive more liquidity as a result. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But mortgage asset securitization is a double-edged sword. Because it has high leverage, if there is any disturbance or unfavorable situation, the impact it will have will be huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, mortgage securitization is indeed a direction. However, I believe that the risks are relatively high, the supporting systems and regulatory measures are still weak, and it should not develop too fast. Especially in the current situation where risk prevention is the keynote, it is even more unsuitable to launch. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Need to shift to intensive&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;development&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;model&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Under the counter-cyclical situation, the profits of the banking industry generally increased slightly and even the profits of individual banks dropped sharply, and the provision coverage ratio and capital adequacy ratio both declined. The 2023 interim reports of various banks revealed this group signal. However, under the current capital market conditions, refinancing on the stock market is difficult to achieve. How do you think banks can replenish core capital at this stage? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Commercial banks can replenish their first-tier core capital by issuing common shares, increasing capital from existing shareholders, or issuing additional shares. In addition, endogenous funds are also important channels. Such as retained profits, other comprehensive income and risk reserves, etc. This is to make &quot;blood&quot; by oneself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listed banks are the &quot;outstanding elements&quot; among banks. There are more than 4,000 small and medium-sized banks that cannot replenish capital through the stock market and can only increase capital through targeted capital increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks mainly issue subordinated bonds, preferred stocks and perpetual bonds to supplement secondary capital. However, the threshold for issuance of perpetual bonds and subordinated bonds is relatively high, and not all thousands of small and medium-sized banks are eligible. In addition, the issuance of special bonds by local governments is also an important means to supplement the capital of small and medium-sized banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that endogenous funds are also very important. How do most banks get rid of the predicament of becoming increasingly dependent on external financing as they develop? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the past few decades, the scale of the banking industry has expanded rapidly and interest rates have been earned. In recent years, both the return on assets and the return on capital have been declining, and companies can only &quot;win&quot; by relying on scale. Large scale, low efficiency, and rapid capital consumption. If you cannot support the rapid expansion of asset scale by relying on your own &quot;blood production&quot;, you must rely on more external financing to replenish capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To completely get rid of this predicament, banks need to conduct refined operations on existing assets and earn more profits with the same asset scale, rather than simply increasing absolute profits by increasing scale. Extensive way. The core is to shift from the current extensive development model that emphasizes scale to an intensive development model that emphasizes efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, interest rate spreads have fallen to historic lows, and the financial sustainability of bank operations is in doubt. When the current scale remains unchanged or even continues to decline, banks must find ways to be more refined and detailed, increase revenue and reduce expenditure, especially to reduce management fees and other costs. At the same time, it is necessary to improve the efficiency of fund utilization. For example, adjust the direction of loan investment, make more efforts in the financial market, and do more financial market business. In addition, efforts need to be made to improve risk control levels and reduce bad debt costs and risk losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Core competitiveness cannot be shaped through outsourcing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now digital finance has become the transformation path for banks, and it is also the only way to achieve inclusive finance. You also had similar views in the &quot;2023 China Banking Industry Ranking Top 200 Research Report&quot; published by &quot;Tsinghua Financial Review&quot;. You also believe that when financial institutions build underlying business logic in accordance with the genetic requirements of the Internet, they need to break the internal data barriers of the institution and make comprehensive adjustments to the working mechanism. In this process, banks are bound to be exposed to many risks. What do you think is the underlying business logic of banks’ Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core of bank digital transformation lies in data connectivity. At the same time, the organizational structure and top-level design must be reconstructed according to Internet thinking. There will be many challenges and risks involved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there are many obstacles in data connection. A bank is a behemoth that involves many businesses, institutions, personnel, and outlets, and the phenomenon of data islands is serious. The problem is particularly serious for large banks, where it is difficult to integrate data between head offices and branches, between various departments of the head office, and even between departments within the same department. In addition to breaking through internal data barriers and breaking down information islands, it is also necessary to achieve safe and standardized connections with external data such as government data, corporate data, alternative Internet data, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always held the view that the banks of the future will be technology companies with banking licenses. It requires data, scenarios, and technology, that is, &quot;no data, no finance&quot;, &quot;no scenario, no finance&quot;, &quot;no technology, no finance&quot;. This is a trinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, in order to open up external data, banks need to build some scenarios themselves and have the ability to continuously generate new data. Therefore, establishing the scene is particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks need to pay attention to this matter from the top-level design and reconstruct the business logic structure and organizational structure that are different from traditional banks in the past. The difficulty is that traditional genes may eat away at Internet genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the traditional business of banks is still strong - the Internet business is still &quot;Sesame&quot;, and the traditional business is still &quot;Watermelon&quot;. However, in the future, the Internet business will grow into a &quot;watermelon&quot; and the traditional business will gradually shrink into a &quot;sesame&quot;. Due to operating pressure, traditional businesses still have to pay attention. &quot;Sesame&quot; cannot become &quot;watermelon&quot; overnight. It requires a process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform must not only prevent some new businesses from being cannibalized by traditional businesses, but also prevent traditional businesses from simply being moved online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Judging from the recruitment situation this autumn, most bank IT R&amp;D positions Hiring is down. This may be related to the rise of large model technology. Some banks’ fintech strategies are shifting from building their own intelligent customer service systems to cooperating with external technology platforms. What do you think of this phenomenon? Will outsourcing financial technology business bring greater risks to banks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Outsourcing has advantages and risks, and different organizations should have different choices. Large and medium-sized banks should maintain their core technologies and avoid relying on outsourcing institutions; while small and medium-sized banks can consider outsourcing part of their business or partnering with other platform companies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on external institutions can quickly solve the bank&#39;s current problems. In the long run, over-reliance on outsourcing institutions and platforms and loss of opportunities to develop internal skills is the biggest risk, followed by the risk of data security. The reason is that relying on outsourcing makes it difficult for banks to establish solid core technical capabilities over time. This is particularly important for large banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long run, banks, especially large banks, will still have to build their own systems. Core competitiveness cannot be shaped through outsourcing. It is a long-term solution for large banks to improve their internal capabilities. For some small banks, they can choose to outsource most of their businesses to build their core competitiveness in other aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Test the equity market&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Establish a high-level &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;investment research team&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Yes Important matters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bank’s financial management subsidiary is testing the waters of equity financial management The product is 3 years old, but generally performs poorly. As of October 16, 2023, among all 34 bank equity products, 29 have broken the net. What do you think of this phenomenon? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the new regulations on asset management, the development model of bank financial management has undergone fundamental changes. The development of equity financial management products is one direction. . Compared with public funds, wealth management subsidiaries or the asset management departments of many banks are too young. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of equity products of bank wealth management subsidiaries being depleted is, on the one hand, the downward environment of the entire market, which is also the main reason. On the other hand, it is caused by the lack of management capabilities of the financial management subsidiaries themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novice, the wealth management subsidiary is inferior to the market in equity investments, but it is still tolerable at the moment. But in five to ten years, if there is no improvement, the road for equity bank financial products will only become narrower and narrower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Should financial management subsidiaries cooperate with fellow fund companies and share the latter investment research results? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Wei:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the long run, building a strong investment research team is a top priority for financial management subsidiaries. It is difficult for wealth management subsidiaries to cooperate with fund companies under the parent bank because competition between the two outweighs cooperation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，理财子公司的激励机制和薪酬水平是一大短板。受工资分配约束，国有大行旗下的理财子公司的薪酬水平显著低于公募基金。这对于打造高水平的投研团队是很大掣肘。这方面需要突破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[串标围标在工程建设等领域多发；招标方设租寻租不容忽视丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，最高检在官方网站发布了一批依法惩治串通招投标犯罪典型案例。最高检有关负责人表示，近年来，招投标环节问题突出，在工程建设、设备采购等多个领域，串通投标、行贿、受贿等违法犯罪案件多发，给工程质量、安全管理造成隐患，严重扰乱市场秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;招投标，是一些大型项目所采用的一种采购方式。理论上，招投标是一种可以促进竞争的手段，尤其是公开招标。从招标人的角度，让自己的采购需求触达更多潜在供应商，尽可能促进他们之间的竞争，以便用最少的钱，买到最好的商品、服务等。对投标人来说，通过公开招标渠道，可以获悉更多的商业机会，参与竞争，靠实力赢得生意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，国家法规规定，一些特定的项目必须通过公开招标确定供应商。比如，政府采购法规定，一定金额以上（具体金额由省级统一规定，不少省份定为200万元以上）的货物和服务政府采购项目，必须公开招标。有关建筑法规则规定，房屋建筑和市政基础设施工程的施工单项合同估算价在200万元人民币以上，或者项目总投资在3000万元人民币以上的，必须进行招标，其中全部使用国有资金或者国有资金占控股或主导地位的，必须公开招标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果多个投标人甚至招标人相互勾结、串通投标，那投标就会变成掩人耳目的幌子，达不到招投标的目的。比如在最高检此次发布的典型案例中，有一项某单位信息化项目向社会公开招投标，有两家公司串通投标，结果项目中标价格3500余万元，远超实际造价。这样的结果，给招标单位造成了严重的损失。另外，多家供应商串通投标也会影响市场竞争。有些投标人甚至通过贿赂评标委员等手段，给自己的标书打出高分，以便中标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有些串标围标，可能招标人并不知情，只是投标人之间串通一气，以抬高报价，获取更多利益。但也有不少串标围标，招标单位的工作人员不仅知情，甚至可能是他们主动与投标人勾结，把价格做高，或把项目给某家指定的投标人，自己从中捞取好处。至于另一些参与投标的公司，则只是“陪标”，以满足有多家供应商参与竞标的要求。实际上他们的标书内容都比指定的投标人差，不可能中标，他们出场，只是为了合作演戏，获得一点“陪标费”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这无疑是设租寻租、行贿受贿。如果招标单位是国企甚至政府机构、事业单位，那就涉嫌公职人员受贿。即使招标单位是私营企业，串通招投标也会构成职务侵占、非国家工作人员受贿等罪名。投标方则是行贿。这种寻租背后的腐败是相当惊人的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《浙江日报》曾经报道，绍兴市城投集团原董事长朱志祥在2018-2020年期间，作为招标单位主要负责人，在相关项目招标过程中，伙同他人与投标人串通，投标人中标金额合计达44.2亿余元。2023年4月，朱志祥以受贿罪、串通投标罪一审被判十一年六个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在一些领域，围标串标已经形成了一个完整的产业链。有些从业者自己没有相关资质，就“挂靠”有资质的单位，被挂靠的单位则收取中标金额一定比例的“管理费”，分享中标收益。还有专门搞串标的职业黄牛、工程掮客。他们神通广大，有的可能和招标方有关系，有的甚至能及时拿到评标专家的联系方式，向他们行贿。还有能够侵入评标专家库的“黑客”为他们提供专家名单和联系方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浙江警方就曾查获一家仅有9名员工的公司，甚至都没有施工队，却屡屡中标大工程项目，在短短两年里，共参与工程项目投标338个。调查发现，这是一个职业串标团伙，他们中标后再把项目非法出售，从中获利。这些工程项目被层层扒皮、层层转包，不仅工程造价会上升，工程质量也难以保证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，根据最高检和公安部2022年制定的最新刑事立案追诉标准，串通投标，中标金额400万元以上，违法所得20万元以上，或者采取威胁、欺骗、行贿等手段的，多次串通投标，等等情况，都已经涉嫌犯串通投标罪，应该立案追诉。尤其对于涉及招标方内部人员的招标寻租和腐败，更要严厉打击，以维护公正的市场秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[允许博士生分流转为硕士，你支持吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260095]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[平均降价58%！南周记者直击第九批国家药品集采现场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄乌情报体系对抗：“外卖小哥”下毒引发的暗战 | 智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月24日，俄媒报道，近日，一名“外卖小哥”企图以“下毒”的方式，消灭俄罗斯阿尔马维尔高等军事航空学校校友庆祝活动上的数十名俄军官员和飞行员，被俄罗斯情报部门及时识破而行动未遂。据悉，“外卖小哥”是来自乌克兰梅利托波尔市的32岁男子叶戈尔·谢苗诺夫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯阿尔马维尔市法院以“扰乱治安罪”逮捕了叶戈尔·谢苗诺夫，并将其拘留15天，接下来可能还将面临更严重的“恐怖主义”指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯阿尔马维尔高等军事航空学校退伍军人委员会主席维克多·菲森称，这是对该校毕业生进行的大规模毒杀企图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起事件也引发了社会对俄乌情报特工“暗战”的关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“有毒大蛋糕”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月21日，俄罗斯克拉斯诺达尔边疆区的阿尔马维尔高等军事航空学校的77名2003届校友回校参加毕业20周年的庆祝活动，其中包括多位俄罗斯空军现役飞行员和高级官员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在餐厅聚会期间，一个“外卖小哥”突然送来20公斤重的大蛋糕和几箱威士忌酒，声称是一名无法参加聚会的校友送来的礼物，巨大的两层蛋糕立刻吸引了所有人的注意。大家在第一时间开始拍照，并在聊天群里发帖表示感谢。与此同时，所有人都在相互打听送出这份大礼的人究竟是谁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，由于没人“认领”这份礼物，参加聚会的人对蛋糕和威士忌的来历产生了怀疑。出席活动的一名俄军官阻止了在场的飞行员喝酒和吃下蛋糕，并立即向俄罗斯联邦安全局报告。随后，俄联邦安全局对蛋糕和威士忌进行检测发现，里面含有剧毒物质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，学校的一名安全官员从监控视频中截取了“外卖小哥”的身影。俄罗斯安全部门的特工确认这名“外卖小哥”是32岁的叶戈尔·谢苗诺夫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄警方很快查明了谢苗诺夫的身份并将其逮捕。高中毕业后，谢苗诺夫成为一名举重教练，经常参加各种举重比赛，后来还当过保安。2015年以来，谢苗诺夫居住在俄首都莫斯科郊区，从事视频监控系统和对讲机的安装工作。近年来，他开始对枪支和运动射击产生浓厚的兴趣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在送完剧毒蛋糕之后，谢苗诺夫计划飞回莫斯科，却在机场被俄罗斯安全人员拦截并带走。谢苗诺夫对他的行为供认不讳，并向审查人员透露了自己如何获知庆祝活动的举行。他甚至还把军校的标志画到了蛋糕上面，以获得更大的逼真效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄方认为，谢苗诺夫可能是基辅派遣到莫斯科的间谍，这次谋杀俄罗斯飞行员的“毒计”，很可能就是在基辅的授意下执行的，这是乌克兰国防情报总局策划的一次暗杀行动。假如这次俄罗斯放松警惕思想麻痹的话，那么这次事件就会付出惨重的代价。目前，俄罗斯安全部门正在“寻找制作蛋糕的人和其他参与这次破坏活动的人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;俄乌超限战&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国家安全部门或军队情报部门，服务于国家安全军事斗争的需要，某种程度上讲，置对手于死地，或者被对手置于死地，二者必居其一。俄乌两国情报部门之间的较量，堪称互为对方的影子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄乌战事焦灼之际，乌克兰“外卖小哥毒杀”事件，表明俄乌双方在手段、谋略、节操等方面，都呈现出“超限战”的特点，这种“阴招”的杀伤力，虽然难以改变冲突胜负，但是对改变战场局部态势、打击对方士气、选择作战手段等方面，都会产生一定的负面效应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，乌克兰的情报体系架构和对抗能力有较大程度提升。美国的情报机构庞大，美国情报特工部门对乌克兰的人力和技术情报支持下,乌克兰与俄罗斯在“隐秘”战线上展开情报“暗战”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰军情局涉足不少在俄罗斯境内的暗杀活动。2022年，乌克兰国家安全局策划并执行了炸死杜金娜的汽车爆炸事件。乌克兰一位安全官员说：“杜金娜是俄罗斯宣传家的女儿。汽车爆炸和在俄罗斯境内的其他行动是为了向乌克兰的敌人表明，即使是那些&#39;不尊重乌克兰的人，惩罚也是近在眼前的&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名乌克兰国家安全局第五局前官员表示，这些行动只能给泽连斯基留下“深刻印象”，却无法帮助乌克兰军队迈向胜利。“杀死一个人，很快就会有另一个人来接替位置”。乌克兰的暗杀行动显然更受冲动而非逻辑的驱动，不仅缺乏战略目标，可能还会暴露乌克兰情报人员。这种“暗杀小组”可能游离于总统或军方手里，成为“恐怖主义”的乱源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄乌冲突，西方国家对乌克兰情报支持产生的影响甚至超过武器的援助。乌克兰的新情报能力在俄乌冲突开始就证明其价值。乌克兰安全局获得有关俄罗斯高价值目标的情报，从而实施打击，击毙了数名指挥官。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰国家安全局最优先的目标，莫过于连接俄罗斯本土和克里米亚岛的大桥。2022年，乌克兰安全局曾两次袭击这座大桥，乌安全局在一辆卡车内放置了威力巨大的爆炸物，后来又使用无人机对大桥发动了第二次破坏袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌军情局还利用自己的无人机编队在俄罗斯境内发动了数十次袭击，包括穿透俄罗斯防空系统袭击莫斯科的建筑物。2023年5月，一次行动曾波及克里姆林宫的一部分屋顶。这些袭击既有从乌克兰境内发射的远程无人机，也有在俄罗斯境内工作的特工和游击队负责执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于美国支持的乌克兰情报部门实施的一系列暗杀和偷袭事件，俄罗斯政府多次指责乌克兰采取“恐怖袭击”策略，也采取了一系列有力反击行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月9日，俄塔斯社报道，俄罗斯联邦安全局逮捕了一名被乌克兰情报部门招募的俄罗斯公民，并指控他于6月试图炸毁克里米亚地区的一条天然气管道。8月13日，俄罗斯国防部公布了一段俄无人机击毁乌军使用的“星链”卫星系统通信终端的画面。俄军无人机操作员发现了美军支持、被乌军伪装的“星链”卫星系统通信终端，无人机精准打击并击毁了这一通信终端。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯外交部发言人扎哈罗娃10月24日在电视节目中表示：“无论是在俄罗斯境内，还是周边，大量恐怖袭击绝非始于2022年，而是从更早开始。基辅政权下属的安全部门应对这些大量恐怖袭击负责，这对任何人来说都不是秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;对手就是对手&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从历史来看，俄乌情报体系都脱胎于苏联时期的克格勃。苏联解体后，俄乌情报部门采取权力分散、各管一块的行政体制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1995年，俄罗斯组建新的联邦安全总局、对外情报局、反情报的联邦安全局。俄军总参谋部建立负责军事情报的“格鲁乌”，即俄罗斯武装力量总参谋部情报总局，其局长由一名俄军副总参谋长兼任，主要目标是搜集战略级到战术级的军事情报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰于1992年3月, 组建国家安全局,维持由乌总统直接领导的特殊体制，并继承苏联时期克格勃的几乎全部职能。1993年7月，乌克兰在乌国防部成立军事情报局，类似于俄罗斯的总参谋部情报局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当前乌克兰的情报体系构建，还得到了美国的全力支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了控制“被俄罗斯联邦安全局严重渗透”的风险，美国中央情报局花费数千万美元将乌克兰的苏联式间谍机构改造成反抗莫斯科的有力盟友。美国中央情报局与乌克兰国家安全局合作成立针对俄罗斯的全新部门“第五局”，意在对付俄罗斯实施“迫切措施”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰国家安全局还增加了第六局，与英国军情六处合作。训练基地设在基辅郊外，由美国中央情报局人员指导精心挑选的受训人员，要求特工人员“能够在后方行动，并作为秘密小组开展工作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在帮助乌克兰安全局建立“第五局”的同时，美国中央情报局还投资“数千万美元”改造乌克兰军事情报机构。一位曾在乌克兰工作过的前美国情报官员说：“我们计算过，军情局是一个更小、更灵活的组织，在那里我们可以产生更大的影响。军情局是我们的小宝贝。我们为他们提供了全新的装备和培训。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在乌克兰以及后来在美国的基地，乌克兰军情局特工接受了从敌后秘密演习到武器平台和爆炸物等各种技能的培训。美国中央情报局提供了最先进的监视和电子窃听系统，包括可放置在乌克兰东部俄罗斯控制沿线的移动设备，用于窃听从莫斯科访问被占领土的俄方官员手机的软件，收集到的所有信息都与美国共享。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一名前军情局高级军官说：“一天之内，我们可以拦截来自俄罗斯军队和联邦安全局的25万至30万次单独通信，信息量大到我们自己都无法管理。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成千上万的数据通过中央情报局新建的设施传回华盛顿，由中央情报局和国家安全局的分析人员进行仔细检查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;军情局还在俄罗斯安全机构中建立了线人网络。作为美乌互信的一项措施，中央情报局获准与乌克兰情报机构招募和管理的特工直接接触。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄乌双方的情报特种战，由于不同的国家、不同的社会制度、不同的战争背景和性质，战法手段也千差万别，效果迥然不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乌克兰外卖送毒蛋糕给俄罗斯飞行人员的事件，表明乌克兰特工一直试图通过各种渠道对俄罗斯进行突袭，试图削弱其军事力量和国家安全，俄罗斯情报部门及时采取了有力的反制行动。这说明，俄乌双方都有不同程度的强有力的情报体系作支撑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>