<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《再见爱人》：婚姻里谁都没错，日子怎么就没法过]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261541]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/92I6YaI3L2s2KiC36TxIsoT8b4MEQEvR9IDfU0Kz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/92I6YaI3L2s2KiC36TxIsoT8 b4MEQEvR9IDfU0Kz. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; producer Liu Le&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; reached its third season, and producer Liu Le finally realized his dream when he proposed the plan - bringing guests with him Entered the Civil Affairs Bureau for a day of filming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The service hall of the Aheqi County Civil Affairs Bureau is less than 200 square meters, and marriages and divorces are completed here. Three pairs of guests who didn&#39;t know whether they would get divorced witnessed the union of several local couples and the separation of families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Le used to be a social news reporter and worked in the Civil Affairs Bureau. After deciding to make &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, she asked the team to squat in front of the Civil Affairs Bureau. Although it was fruitless, the members all faced the original shock. They couldn&#39;t say anything at the moment. After returning, everyone had ups and downs. &quot;I want to shoot joys and sorrows all in the same place, and human feelings are not the same. When you made the promise, did you ever think about separation? When you separated, did you remember the promise?&quot; Liu Le said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the first season of the reality show &quot;Goodbye Love&quot;, which is closely related to &quot;divorce&quot;, will be launched. In the program, three pairs of guests who have problems in their marriages went on an 18-day trip to review the beauty of love, analyze marriage problems, and find answers to relationships. The program presents the trivial and difficult-to-discern life in public, and explores the details and deep conflicts of marriage, which resonates with the audience. In the autumn of 2023, the third season of &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; will be broadcast. Fu Seoul and Lao Liu, Ji Huanbo and Wang Shiqing, Wang Sleepy and Zhang Shuosheng are three lovers who &quot;look beautiful&quot; to outsiders, exposing the illusion, facing their respective dilemmas, and once again Generate discussions about intimacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Le, the core producer and chief director of this show, has been a social news reporter for four years and the director of &quot;Happy Camp&quot; for ten years. In the past three years, in addition to the &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; series, her His other works include &quot;The Delayed Departure of Spring&quot; - also related to divorce. She has been paying attention to emotional topics for a long time. She liked to post emotional jokes on the Internet from time to time many years ago. She has written most of the program copywriting for &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; and &quot;Spring Departs Again&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; is the summary of Liu Le&#39;s more than ten years of experience in the industry, which combines the touch and sensitivity of a traditional journalist, the entertainment and dexterity of a variety show director, and the sharpness and sharpness of an emotional blogger. As a single woman, she has pushed many married people to take a step forward in their exploration of marriage and intimacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the show was broadcast, Liu Le received more concern and support than expected. Some colleagues even wanted to get married after reading it. Hu Yanbin, a guest in the observation room, told her: &quot;If parting is not so terrible, and we still have such deep care for each other, such good wishes, and such a decent separation, then I would also long for marriage.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《 After the recording of the third season of &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; ended, Liu Le accepted an exclusive interview with us and talked about the joys and sorrows related to the show in the past three seasons and the subtleties of human nature she has explored. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Can&#39;t we get a divorce without quarreling? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; reaches its third season and is still touching What&#39;s yours? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What shocked me the most this season was the sense of blamelessness between Seoul and Lao Liu. Before coming to Seoul, tell me, is it okay if I don’t quarrel? I said that whoever said &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; would quarrel, and if there is no quarrel, there will be no quarrel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we went to the Civil Affairs Bureau, the director asked why we couldn’t survive. What happened? Are you not going home? Was it drinking? Did he hit you? He has a lot of &quot;clinical experiment&quot; experience, and the questions he raised are very valuable. When we hear about other people’s divorce in our daily lives, we also ask what questions there are. If he says there is no problem, then why should he get a divorce? Good days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inertial thinking of many people is that I have to have an affair, have a violent family, and have to defraud me of money before I can get divorced. no. So our main concept this season is dull pain and slow growth. I can&#39;t tell you exactly what it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the first few episodes were aired, you may have thought that you were complaining for no reason, that you were forcing yourself to express your sorrow, and that you just made up a set of words just to be on the show. Like Seoul, in the first half and second half of the broadcast, I read some public accounts and wrote from the beginning that Fu Seoul must be here to make money, and she will definitely not get divorced. After a few episodes, another public account wrote that Fu Seoul must be here to make money, because she had already planned to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How people will recognize her is also the most difficult part to convince Seoul. Everyone will doubt whether she is motivated by utilitarianism. I told her, if you are willing to face your real dilemma, come. This sound will never dissipate. The most important thing to convince her is that she has real emotional appeal. The marriage of more than ten years has truly taken root in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have known her for several years. When I was still in &quot;Happy Camp&quot;, she came to be my guest. She said that I am particularly envious of your state, a state where you can fall in love at any time. I said, did you encounter any confusion in your marriage? Chatted with her a bit. After doing &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, she often sent me some comments after watching the first two seasons. I felt that what she said actually brought her own personality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seoul is very defensive. She will protect herself, but she wants to speak, but she won’t speak very thoroughly. She looks happy and cheerful, but there must be a lot of devastation in her heart buried under the surface of her wanting to make everyone happy, and I really want to dig this thing out. I mentioned it to her after the second season ended, and there must have been a process of persuasion. I told her that as long as you make up your mind, nothing will happen. The problem is a problem, but it can be solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My judgment is that she will face it sooner or later. I am not saying that she must come on the show, but she has many knots in her heart that cannot be relieved by chatting with friends. On the one hand, she wants to seek change, and on the other hand, she also longs to be understood by more people. She still has the &quot;old script&quot; part to a large extent. I have been married for more than ten years and no one has made any mistakes. We have all tried our best. Why can&#39;t we live well? If so, can we choose to separate? I feel that she and Lao Liu are both in a trapped state. She can&#39;t really reconcile this matter, so much so that she is willing to go on a show to reveal everything to everyone. The real situation is like this, then I Can it be understood? She is so eager to be understood. She is pioneering and conservative, active and passive. She is a very charming contradiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I hope that one day she can accept her real difficulties and not move forcefully towards another life. This may be easier, but Seoul is not an easy person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/l2mMKm7vnUfWoevoLlB9wzEMH9GCU4sFugv5gJIt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/l2mMKm7vnUfWoevoLlB9wzEMH9GCU4sFugv5gJIt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the third season of &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, six guests celebrated the 14th wedding anniversary of Fu Seoul and Liu Yi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Don’t separate easily, and don’t drag it out to death&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you find the other two pairs of guests? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The other two pairs signed up by themselves. Wang Shiqing signed up for the second season, but when I talked to her at the time, there were no such big conflicts as this season. This year, I feel much more profound. After we reopened from the closed state last year, we entered a dynamic that will bring many severe impacts. If the relationship itself is good, this dynamic has the potential to make you even better. If it is not good in the first place, it will fall apart faster. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shiqing has more job opportunities, and she obviously feels that she is stronger. Her connections and feedback from society have become extremely concrete. She really feels like &quot;I am flying high.&quot; &quot;. As for the person who wanted to hold me back, his actions became more obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Sleeping signed up after the second season. At that time, the many quarrels between Zhang Wanting and Song Ningfeng reminded her of herself. She felt that she also liked to curse people and was unhappy, so she filled out the registration form. When I first looked at their materials, I didn’t see as many problems as those presented in the show. In the first round of contact, many directors judged them to be trivial and the problems were too trivial. They didn’t seem to be worth analyzing in daily life, not so thought-provoking, and not so promising. Expansion space, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it possible that trivial things are really worth extending? Could the program team be trapped by the so-called desire to pursue quality? Is it that when we present intimate relationships, we are too obsessed with those things that are invisible, intangible, and unclear, while those things that can be clearly seen, touched, grasped, and can be directly judged as right or wrong? Are we all excluded? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let&#39;s reflect on it. In the first season, Zhu Yaqiong expressed a lot of feelings, but in the end what people remember is that one-minute hug. Or implement it on specific events. Specific events can give people something to grasp, reflect on whether they have behaved like this, and better establish a comparative coordinate system, so we set them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people say that &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; relies on fierce quarrels to attract attention. No, the program team does not want endless quarrels. That thing makes people desperate and suffocating. But since it’s a reality show, we can’t interfere once they start. It is impossible for us to go up and tell them to stop quarreling and make peace with me quickly. It is even less possible for us to tell them that you two can start quarreling now. This is ridiculous. All we can do is record it truthfully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What topics will the flying guests bring when they join, and what new projects can they do? We can invisiblely implant these into the journey to trigger changes in them. The others exploded without even knowing what game they would be in, and any one sentence made him angry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look, Zhang Shuo sent a WeChat message to the best man at that time &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (In the first issue, Wang Sleepy and Zhang Shuo had a dispute over their marriage. They had a quarrel, and the two broke up. Later, they quarreled over other things. At this time, Zhang Shuo sent a WeChat message to the best man to try to ease the conflict with Sui Suo. His most real feeling at that moment was that it was a good thing to do. , it can definitely be undone: She was angry with me because of other things, and I immediately had to do something to make up for it. But precisely because he did these things, the audience intuitively felt that his model was to tear down the east wall to repair the west wall, and the demolition was not good, and the repair was not good, and the whole person was very perfunctory. Is this perfunctory social norm? yes. So it resonated the most. A quarrel can only make people watch the fun, but what can make everyone stay after the fun is the pain behind the quarrel. It’s a point of empathy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Zhang Shuo still represents a very common phenomenon: I don’t need to achieve 100 points in this matter, I always control my efforts, just achieve 10 points, 20 points That&#39;s it, lay flat everywhere, whether it&#39;s work, socializing or love for him. Huang Zhizhong is right, he is very stingy with his energy. Now that I have paid 10 points of energy, if you don’t recognize the value of my 10 points, I will not be happy. Is this selfish? of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of the hot search for &quot;Mirror of Society&quot; posted by Zhang Shuo, I think the audience can also very intuitively feel how powerless such an emotional model is for contemporary young people. Why do so many people not want to fall in love? Everyone said that I don’t need to be so full, if I don’t love deeply, I won’t love you deeply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Zhang Shuo has many advantages. We are angry at him, but we cannot hate him. He is indeed a very kind-hearted child who is very considerate of the emotions around him. But why is this the pattern in intimate relationships? It’s been explored in the program, and it’s also being talked about in the observation room. (One of the reasons may be) People crave positive feedback, which is a physiological mechanism. If I make a mistake, do I want to get some advice instead of being asked if I am wrong? No one likes to be whipped all the time. After being whipped, I may do worse. This is a behavioral mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are many words &quot;Sleep, sleep and run&quot; in the program barrage. No one can understand why the two of them are still together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the audience has directly seen a presentation, and they will think that since this is the case, why don&#39;t they break up? But as far as Suisie is concerned, this person is my first love. We have been together for 10 years. He used to be very good to me. It is not easy to decide to break up. When encountering problems, I must first think about how to solve them. What has changed? Can I change it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People must have hope, this is a very positive thing. Most people in the past went to the other extreme. No matter how hard, how tired, how many grievances we suffered, we had to live this life and never get divorced. Now the new trend is: if something is slightly wrong, say goodbye immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; has always wanted to find a middle balance, neither to separate easily nor to drag it out to death. We hope to have the ability to leave and repair. Maybe this is a healthier love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that for Wang Sleepy, when she decided to appear on the show, she just wanted to give the relationship one last chance. If it works out well, she will continue it, and if it doesn&#39;t, she will break up. In this process, every wavering, anger, and softening of her heart is extremely sincere. She is trying to re-recognize this person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the program was broadcast, Zhang Shuo’s behavior caused a lot of controversy controversy. What was his feedback? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He is in pain. I feel like my self has been completely shattered and completely denied. During the broadcast, he would come to discuss with us from time to time, basically introspection, which I found very difficult. No one can really quickly admit that they are a terrible person. This is a cruel thing and takes time, but we see that Zhang Shuo has been working hard. He still has an exploratory attitude. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shuo is considered a very sunny person in the show, and he is quite able to have fun for himself. Whether these public opinions are correct or not, they have a great impact on him. He was in pain, but he had to admit that some of the comments might be quite reasonable. Just like when a person wants to digest a knife, a knife is already in the flesh. It is cutting my tumor. I scream in pain, but I have to endure it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nLyveKvA0eqTxGrsUpslEL6wyPrRU1fvAaZcq6UT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nLyveKvA0eqTxGrsUpslEL6wyPrRU1fvAaZcq6UT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260013&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; Season 3 guests Wang Sleepy (left) and Zhang Shuo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Women are strong and men are weak. This is a common comment from the outside world about this season. This is your intention. For that? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was not intentional. Usually we don’t save materials just because they have something in common. We discover that we can come up with something during the process of saving. The title of the first issue, &quot;Looks Beautiful,&quot; is the commonality we picked out. The three couples were all collected separately. From the massive amount of material about each of them, we came up with the point that our marriage may look good to outsiders, but in fact it is not. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether women are strong and men are weak, I think we are just providing a discussion angle. Maybe everyone will come to this conclusion after reading it. In fact, none of these three couples are absolutely strong women, and they also have weaknesses. So we discussed what is strong, is it economic strength? If there is only one dimension, it can be considered that the three pairs are all strong women and weak men. But what about the right to speak? What about the need to be loved? What about the sense of presence in marriage? What about ease and comfort? Who is the emotional superior? Returning to these dimensions, they may not be strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just said that you hope this program will be a platform for exploration. This is The original intention of the show? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have this direction only by doing it. Every time we meet a couple and they come to our show, their behavior may be somewhat beyond the threshold: too manipulative, too insecure, too patient, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For all parts that exceed the threshold, we hope to make everyone realize that this is a bit beyond the limit and you can come back. We strive to stand in a safer area. But sometimes, when some problems occur, I hope that everyone will not think that this matter is such a big deal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now NPD&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(narcissistic personality disorder)&lt;/span>;, gaslighting&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(a means of psychological manipulation)&lt;/span>;, borderline personality and other terms often appear. When people encounter something, they may immediately make a conclusion. So what are the real meanings of these words? What is the definition of professional? Will there be any overkill? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have also been thinking about this question since the second season. Can we conclude that this person is a lunatic once his behavior exceeds our daily cognition? Or once we make a judgment on a person, will everything he says next be untrustworthy? I don&#39;t think so. Teacher Guo &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Guo Keyu)&lt;/span>; said in the first season: &quot;People have too many sides.&quot; I particularly agree with this sentence. . There are all kinds of people, including crazy, depressed, high-value, and low-value people. People themselves are complex and imperfect animals, but their desire to be loved is true. Everyone is equal in love and everyone is equal in intimate relationships. This is why &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; does not strictly distinguish between celebrities and amateurs. We put them all in one field for discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I read a review that said &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; is like untying a Luban lock, making those that are not tight enough buckle tighter and letting those that are on the verge of falling apart fall to the ground smoothly, rather than violently dismantling or never untying them. Open, let’s find a final ending for all the shaky Luban Locks. I agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No more shame when talking about intimate relationships&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;How did you come up with the idea of ​​doing such a show at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From an industry perspective, there was a vacancy in the divorce track. At that time, all major platforms were exploring divorce IP. In the existing domestic and foreign divorce IP, some problems have not been really solved. For example, what is the appeal? If you are divorced and you are put on a trip together, do you have any appeal? Or is this the appeal of a program? Is it a request to watch? If the character has no appeal, what is presented may be very empty and ungrounded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The divorce cooling-off period is the key to why I think of this IP. It can be used as an appeal. The first people I target are couples who have entered a cooling-off period. We only have 30 days to see if we can get this order. In marriage, everyone may have thought about divorce countless times. Why? What actions did you take after thinking about it? Repair it, or ignore it? ...There are a lot of character dynamics that can be told here, and because the divorce has not really been completed, we still have room to explore. The guests in the third season should be said to be the most suitable for my earliest plan, and they are not finished yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first two seasons are also based on this idea. The people we choose are not cold at least in our judgment. If they are cold, there will be no stories to tell. It is not good to divorce for too long, preferably within two or three years. The two people still have some contact from time to time, and some people have even proposed getting back together, etc. There are still ties, demands, and some confusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In daily life, I see other people&#39;s affairs very clearly, but I can always put off my own affairs, and maybe they will get better again. Without the support of a huge event, it is not easy for people to rise and fall in a relatively gentle and ups and downs of emotions. We are not aware of the deep-seated rifts. How can we have the strength to detect this? Who would take an X-ray to illuminate their emotions? Many people do it either out of fear, laziness or avoidance. That&#39;s almost enough. Why do you keep saying this? It&#39;s so pretentious. This is especially common among men in relationships. Is there anything to discuss? I&#39;m going out for a drink. I have many colleagues and the company has many things going on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Communication and communication are often a matter of two people, not a unilateral choice. If I tell others, I want to talk to my lover about the problems in our eight-year marriage, but He doesn&#39;t talk to me properly, so if I want to divorce him, others may say you are sick. But in the context of &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot;, no matter how small the issue is, it will be taken seriously, and everyone will discuss it. So how do you talk about this, and whether you should divorce your marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; focuses on many issues in intimate relationships. I took a magnifying glass to this area, and everyone said that your issue seems to be really worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is at least a starting point for people who are stuck in marriage, people who want to get married, and people who want to talk about these things but are embarrassed. I am no longer ashamed, I want to talk to you today. Chat, let’s communicate your neglect of me. I don’t think it’s very abrupt, I don’t feel ashamed, it’s healthy, it’s also a kind of courage, and it’s also a kind of bravery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why do most of the travel destinations chosen have beautiful scenery, but Somewhere relatively off the beaten track? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Choose these places because they look good. The original and natural beauty is very important. People should get in touch with nature when they are confused, but few people do this. The place we chose is because we hope to stay there for a long time, making it very difficult for them and allowing them to feel the vastness of the world and the insignificance of human beings. This is an intuitive psychological suggestion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nature still has a strong healing effect. We strive to create a high-purity (shooting) environment so that they can safely enter deep water areas to discuss. This process is not easy, the beautiful scenery is a short-term comfort, no matter what, they are a very, very brave group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/G88G4ZHWNzmH6EHkOGMANJgGwKJAOQbYgcR9CwpO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/G88G4ZHWNzmH6EHkOGMANJgGwKJAOQbYgcR9CwpO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; Season 2&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Praise to love, praise romance&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have no marriage experience, and the sweetness and pain of marriage in daily life are very small. And really, how do you grasp these subtleties in a divorce show? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have to understand why he did this at this moment. Why does he feel this way? Why make such a judgment? It’s certainly not 100% empathetic, but in this process, what are the questions worth asking? These can be developed through training, which is asking questions about intuition. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think it is a good thing that I have never been married. I have contacted some colleagues, and I heard that I was going to do this subject, and I especially wanted to chat with me. After talking with me, I felt that everyone was too focused on themselves, and it was easy to draw conclusions, &quot;What is marriage?&quot; With sentences like this, I I heard a lot during that time, and they were all very different. The only thing they had in common was that they all believed in their own judgment in marriage. At this time, I clear my mind. I don’t listen to anyone’s words. I only present the words of all of you as a sample. The sample can have many cores for the audience to summarize on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I were already in a marriage, I&#39;m not sure I would say this doesn&#39;t exist, because I haven&#39;t encountered this situation in my marriage. This is ridiculous, cut it for him. Not having an open mind is very dangerous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Love must come in all kinds of different forms. When I was doing the show, I would also look back on my past relationships and realize that I had made mistakes of one kind or another. This is a very interesting thing. You can see it clearly in others. When it comes to yourself, who is a perfect partner? So looking back at myself, I feel that love is a long-term lesson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I prefer that my views on emotions come from real emotions rather than from the show. I hope &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; is an auxiliary, it should not be the main course. You have to feel the specific people and real people, not some truths. Fu Seoer is already very reasonable, and Wang Sleepy is also very reasonable, but why are they still not so happy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The program has progressed to this point, and the audience has also experienced a lot of laughter. . But laughter cannot offset the real pain in a marriage. What do you think the meaning of &quot;laughing&quot; is? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Pain is pain. If pain is downward, laughter is upward. It may increase a little energy to resist pain, or allow people to see the full picture of pain more clearly. Responding to pain with a smile is art. As Mu Xin said, a person who comes out of sadness with grace is an artist. This smile is a kind of generous. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fmMsEze0OeD4DDlhxS62rJ0TiM23umaiU2JTGhDs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;872&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fmMsEze0OeD4DDlhxS62rJ0TiM23umaiU2JTGhDs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; Season 1&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you come up with the program&#39;s slogan &quot;Goodbye is easy, goodbye is hard&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, I felt that young people gave up too easily. I used to like to persuade people to get sober, but when more and more people were saying that it was no big deal to get sober and give up, I realized that this might be a new trend. When we discussed it, Talk about bringing together these people who want to break up. Is the act of &quot;Let&#39;s talk again&quot; a bit old-fashioned and inconsistent with the current situation of young people: &quot;I always want to find new people&quot;? That&#39;s why we say goodbye is easy or hard, and we think of &quot;goodbye&quot; and &quot;goodbye&quot;, which in English are &quot;see you&quot; and &quot;see you again&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern people are too easy to see the flaws of others. They cannot enter the deep water area and always swim in the shallow water area. No matter how many people they come into contact with, they will all be the same after a few months, and they will miss the conversation very much. When we have been in love for several years, it seems that people receive different nourishment at that time. Nowadays, short videos are teaching you, &quot;You should be wary if he does this&quot;, &quot;If he doesn&#39;t say this, he doesn&#39;t love you&quot;... This kind of dismantling is very rough. There are still many unattributable parts in relationships. It would be a pity if everyone is influenced by these crude logics and thinks that we can just play on the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an era when you can get a lot of happiness without falling in love, it is an extremely romantic thing to fall in love. I hope I can sing (this kind of love and romance). In the past, people may have had many practical needs when getting married. I needed someone to face life with me. But now, it seems that mobile phones have solved everything. Even if we don’t fall in love or get married, everyone can live quite well. In such a situation, it is such a romantic thing to find intimacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think people still need to seek intimacy in this situation? What is the reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Le: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because it is really good. If you have been to that mountain, you will know that the scenery there is very good, but the mountain climbing The process is very tiring. I hope you won’t stop climbing just because you are tired. Don’t think that the most fun is on the ground. The ground is safe, relaxed, comfortable, and ok, but you don’t. I’ve been up there, so I don’t care about the scenery on the mountain. &quot;Goodbye Lover&quot; shows everyone the rugged mountain road, but everyone can still climb their own mountain. Those who work hard will gain more scenery, this must be the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东最能生但也最多单身，四川离婚人数遥遥领先，趣说人口数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261460]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[保障性住房，如何让城市居民顺利安家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261407]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:26:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Removal, replacement, and acquisition of existing housing... While ensuring the source of affordable housing, in order to revitalize the existing housing supply, various places A series of explorations were conducted. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡静林任国家税务总局党委书记，曾在财政部任职20年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261536]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Newly appointed Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation Hu Jinglin. Image source: Official website of the Ministry of Finance&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b4f256f4bd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b4f256f4bd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260048&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >; Hu Jinglin, the new Party Secretary of the State Administration of Taxation. Picture source: The official website of the Ministry of Finance&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the State Administration of Taxation announced that on the morning of November 28, 2023, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Taxation and announced the central government’s decision: Comrade Hu Jinglin will be appointed as the national Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation, Comrade Wang Jun is removed from his position as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking over as Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation, Hu Jinglin was Secretary of the Party Committee and Director of the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Served in the Ministry of Finance for 20 years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin was born in 1964 in Shexian County, Anhui Province. He graduated from Renmin University of China and received a doctorate in economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1992, Hu Jinglin has worked in the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau as deputy director of the Policy, Regulations and Judicial Regulations Division. According to the &quot;Historical Dictionary Series of the Communist Party of China&quot;, in order to straighten out the relationship between state-owned assets and establish and improve the state-owned assets management system in the process of reform and opening up, in November 1988, the state established the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information from the Chinese Government website, in 1994, the State-owned Assets Administration became a national bureau (deputy ministerial level) managed by the Ministry of Finance. Its main task is to comprehensively manage state-owned assets within and outside the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 1998, the State-owned Assets Administration Bureau was officially abolished. In the same year, the Large Enterprise Working Committee of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China was formally established. During this period, the management structure of state-owned enterprises changed several times until the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council was established in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the time of the organizational reform in 1998, Hu Jinglin entered the Property Appraisal Department of the Ministry of Finance, and then served as Director of the Economic Construction Department of the Ministry of Finance, Director of the General Office of the Ministry of Finance, and Spokesperson of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the official website of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin has long been engaged in state-owned enterprise reform and macroeconomic theoretical research and practical work. He has rich work experience and profound theoretical foundation. He has participated in a number of major reforms of financial and industrial management systems and He is engaged in research on important macroeconomic policies and has authored (translated) many works such as &quot;State-owned Enterprise Reform and Approaches&quot;, &quot;Financial Asset Assessment&quot;, and &quot;U.S. Federal Government Budget&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Hu Jinglin served as Assistant Minister of Finance and member of the Party Leadership Group. Five years later, he was promoted to deputy minister of finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, when he was promoted to Vice Minister of Finance, Hu Jinglin was in charge of the General Office, Department of Agriculture, National Agricultural Comprehensive Development Office, Bureau of Retired Cadres, Information Network Center, and China Finance and Taxation Museum, assisting then Minister of Finance Lou Jiwei is in charge of the Office of the State Council’s Comprehensive Rural Reform Working Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure at the Ministry of Finance, Hu Jinglin repeatedly emphasized the importance of budget management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Jinglin emphasized at the National Financial, Administrative, Political and Legal Work Conference that as far as the budget is concerned, it is necessary to enhance the legality and binding force of the budget and how to solve the problems of inaccurate budget preparation at the beginning of the year and mid-year budget. To deal with the problems of frequent adjustments and excessive budget balances at the end of the year, &quot;we need to work with departments to establish the concept of &#39;budget is law&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Never let the medical insurance fund become &#39;Tang Monk Meat&#39;&quot;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;After four years as Deputy Minister of Finance, Hu Jinglin was transferred to the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2018, the First Session of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress voted to adopt a decision on the institutional reform plan of the State Council, establishing the National Medical Security Administration of the People&#39;s Republic of China (deputy ministerial level) and becoming an agency directly under the State Council. Hu Jinglin became the first director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The institutional reform plan of the State Council at that time proposed that the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security’s basic medical insurance and maternity insurance responsibilities for urban employees and urban residents, the National Health and Family Planning Commission’s new rural cooperative medical responsibilities, and the national The National Development and Reform Commission&#39;s drug and medical service price management responsibilities and the Ministry of Civil Affairs&#39; medical assistance responsibilities were integrated to form the National Medical Security Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, during his tenure, Hu Jinglin actively promoted the solution of problems such as difficulty and high cost of medication for ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, during the National Two Sessions, Hu Jinglin said in an interview at the &quot;Ministerial Channel&quot; that more life-saving and emergency medicines should be included in medical insurance by optimizing the directory structure to further alleviate and alleviate the epidemic. It is difficult for the people to use medicine and it is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the State Council Information Office press conference in May 2023, Hu Jinglin introduced that in the past five years, the National Medical Insurance Administration has accelerated the pace of medical insurance negotiations and promoted a large number of exclusive drugs such as camrelizumab and nosinaxin sodium. A variety of anti-cancer drugs and drugs for rare diseases are included in medical insurance at appropriate prices, and after reimbursement, the cumulative burden on patients has been reduced by more than 500 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the official website of the National Medical Insurance Administration published an article written by Hu Jinglin, stating that the next step is to strengthen the management of medical insurance funds, continue to carry out in-depth special operations against fraudulent insurance, and &quot;look back&quot; on some provinces Conduct random inspections and reviews of work. In addition, give full play to the power of the reporting reward system and establish a reporting clue supervision and feedback mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Make good use of the agreement management system. Medical institutions whose agreements have been terminated shall not be included in the medical insurance designated areas within 3 years. Build a long-term mechanism for fund supervision and &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Never let the medical insurance fund Become the new &#39;Tang Monk Meat&#39;&lt;/span>;.&quot; Hu Jinglin introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the above-mentioned press conference of the State Council Information Office, Hu Jinglin said that medical insurance funds are &quot;life-saving money&quot; for the people. The National Medical Insurance Administration has always regarded strengthening the supervision of medical insurance funds and maintaining fund security as its top priority, and severely cracked down on various forms of fraud. Such illegal use of medical insurance funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past five years, the total annual revenue of the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance) has increased from 2.14 trillion yuan to 3.09 trillion yuan, and the total annual expenditure has increased from 1.78 trillion yuan to 2.46 trillion yuan. The fund is running smoothly and has a balance,&quot; Hu Jinglin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Wang Jun has been the director of the State Administration of Taxation for ten years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Chinese government website shows that Wang Jun, the current director of the State Administration of Taxation, was born in 1958. He graduated from Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun served in the Ministry of Finance from 1987 to 2013. In March 2013, Wang Jun, then deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group and deputy minister of the Ministry of Finance, was promoted to secretary of the Party Leadership Group and director of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2023, Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation, held talks with the Director of the Qatar General Administration of Taxation. Image source: Official website of the State Administration of Taxation&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/29/0d9b6d6ebb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/29/0d9b6d6ebb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260049&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, Wang Jun, Director of the State Administration of Taxation, and The head of Qatar’s General Tax Authority held talks. Image source: The official website of the State Administration of Taxation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 1993, the State Council issued a document stating that in order to adapt to the national tax work, the organizational specifications of the State Administration of Taxation would be adjusted from the deputy ministerial level to the ministerial level. In January 1994, China began to implement the reform of the fiscal and taxation system with the tax-sharing system as the core, which significantly increased the central fiscal revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the reform of the tax-sharing system, the State Administration of Taxation has successively had five directors, namely Liu Zhongli, Jin Renqing, Xie Xuren, Xiao Jie, and Wang Jun. Among them, Wang Jun has served the longest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All five of them have worked in the Ministry of Finance, and four of them have served as Ministers of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zhongli served as Minister of Finance and concurrently Director of the State Administration of Taxation from 1992 to 1998. Jin Renqing, Xie Xuren, and Xiao Jie all served as Ministers of Finance after serving as Directors of the State Administration of Taxation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, Wang Jun has served as the director of the State Administration of Taxation for ten years and is 65 years old. In March 2023, Wang Jun was elected as a member of the Standing Committee of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the resumes of Wang Jun and Hu Jinglin, they have worked together in the Ministry of Finance for more than ten years, and both have served as director of the General Office of the Ministry of Finance, spokesperson, assistant minister, deputy minister, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the ten years since Wang Jun served as director of the State Administration of Taxation, China&#39;s tax system reform has continued to deepen, including a series of actions such as replacing business tax with VAT, individual tax reform, merging state and local taxes, and tax and fee reductions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from October 2018, the &quot;threshold&quot; for personal income tax will be increased from 3,500 yuan/month to 5,000 yuan/month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five months later, Wang Jun said at the &quot;Ministerial Channel&quot; of the National Two Sessions that the personal income tax reform will bring 100% tax reduction to the working class, and about 80 million of them will no longer have to pay a tax. Taxes will be reduced by more than 70% for about 65 million people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same year, the First Session of the Thirteenth National People&#39;s Congress passed the institutional reform plan of the State Council. The State Council will reform the national and local tax collection and administration systems, merge the national and local tax agencies at the provincial and sub-provincial levels, and specifically bear the responsibilities of various taxation agencies within its jurisdiction. Responsibilities such as tax and non-tax revenue collection and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tax-sharing system reform in 1994 established two sets of tax collection and management systems: national tax and local tax. After 24 years of operation, the state and local taxes were merged and a new tax collection and administration system was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the effects of tax cuts and fee reductions, the 2023 State Council Government Work Report concluded, “In the past five years, a cumulative tax reduction of 5.4 trillion yuan and a fee reduction of 2.8 trillion yuan have been achieved.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[考公考研人数一升一降：替代还是互补，如何读懂两者间的关系？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261528]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 26, 2023, the written test for public subjects of the national examination will begin. The number of applicants for the national examination exceeded 3 million for the first time. A total of 2.613 million candidates confirmed their registration before the examination, and 2.252 million actually took the examination, which is unprecedented. Vertical comparison shows that a total of 1.422 million people actually took the exam last year. From 2020 to 2024, the number of people recruited for the national examination will be approximately 24,100, 25,700, 31,200, 37,100, and 39,600, which is rising steadily, but it is far from meeting everyone&#39;s application needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, this year is the first time in eight years that the number of people taking the postgraduate entrance examination has dropped, which may indicate that the enthusiasm for the postgraduate entrance examination has reached its peak. This shows that it is a high probability event that the public and postgraduate entrance examinations will go their separate ways. Because for most people, the purpose of taking the postgraduate entrance examination is to delay employment and postpone the employment decision for two to three years, in the hope that a graduate degree will give them a certain competitive advantage. However, on the one hand, the employment situation is becoming increasingly difficult. Today’s undergraduate degree vs. For graduate students after two or three years, the latter may not have a significant advantage in finding a job. On the other hand, the opportunity cost of obtaining a graduate degree is getting higher and higher. Changing from a master&#39;s degree to a professional master&#39;s degree means higher tuition expenses. The public examination is different. If you use the time and money to take the postgraduate entrance examination, you can take the public examination in multiple places in a year. Until you pass the examination, the probability of &quot;getting on board&quot; will be higher. The two go off and on, and it is obvious that more and more people believe that taking the public examination directly is more cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the relationship between the postgraduate entrance examination and the public examination is complex. In addition to substitution, there is also a complementary relationship. For example, some people still want to take the civil service exam after taking the postgraduate entrance examination. This is because there are more civil servant positions that they can apply for with a postgraduate degree. Educational qualifications become higher and more attractive, and there is also an additional channel for selecting students to enter politics. In short, you can expand your options for public examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the recruitment requirements for national examination positions, the threshold for academic qualifications is constantly rising. This year’s national examination recruitment requirements are all for a college degree or above. As the number of recruits increases year after year, the number of positions that require a college degree as a starting point is decreasing year by year. This year, there are 56 positions that college students can apply for, a decrease of 106 year-on-year. At the same time, the number of positions requiring a master&#39;s degree and the planned number of people have increased significantly. According to statistics from China Youth Daily, there are 2,046 positions requiring a master&#39;s degree or above this year, an increase of 814 year-on-year; there are 24 positions requiring a doctoral degree, an increase of 14 year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to explain this phenomenon? A common view is that the demand for highly educated talents in government agencies has increased. This actually amounts to no explanation. Are these positions really only available to those with a master&#39;s degree or above? Probably not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current employment environment, the attractiveness of jobs within the system has been further enhanced: there is a &quot;establishment&quot;, decent salary, complete benefits, high social status, and stable work. As long as you don&#39;t make big principled mistakes, you will not be unemployed. The danger. Therefore, competition for these positions will continue to intensify. The ratio of the number of people admitted to the national examination to the number of people taking the examination was 1:38 last year and 1:57 this year. The ratio of popular positions is even more exaggerated. When competition intensifies, one of the main criteria for selecting talents will naturally be academic qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For employers within the system, when they are recruiting someone, why not choose someone with a higher academic qualification and a better school? Based on purely objective indicators, this is equivalent to obtaining &quot;better talents&quot; with the same staffing and cost, and neither leaders nor the public can find fault. On the contrary, if you do not recruit people with higher academic qualifications and better schools, but recruit people with average academic qualifications, you will most likely need to explain to the public why it is not a &quot;carrot recruitment&quot; and the people you recruit are the most suitable for the position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this logic and mentality, it is not difficult to understand the following phenomena that are hotly debated by the public: Peking University’s Ph.D. in nuclear physics obtained the urban management establishment, Shanghai Jiao Tong University’s M.D. became a middle school doctor, and Harvard University’s master’s degree applied for education Non-career positions in the Overseas Study Service Center of the Ministry of Education. It is not difficult to understand why the academic qualifications threshold for recruitment within the system continues to increase: last year, we required a bachelor&#39;s degree, but we recruited several master&#39;s degrees from prestigious universities; this year, we simply require all master&#39;s degrees, and people are willing to come and don&#39;t have to spend more money, so why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, this is very different from the recruitment logic of free competition industries. Except for the R&amp;D departments of some leading companies, generally the company&#39;s academic qualifications are only a reference when recruiting people. The key is to see whether personal ability and character match the company&#39;s job requirements. If you have too high academic qualifications, you will have the problem of over-qualification. For the same position, undergraduates may do better than those with master&#39;s or doctorate degrees, because from the perspective of the company, everyone must receive vocational training anyway. Being young is an advantage, the mind is not yet rigid, the person has the courage to try and accept new things, and can get started quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, some undergraduates complained that they could not get offers (invitations) when applying for jobs as undergraduates, but they got many offers by pretending to be high school students. The reason why high school students are required rather than &quot;high-achieving students&quot; is because in the eyes of the company, high school students are enough to complete the job. All they need to do is behave in a disciplined manner, follow the procedures honestly, and listen to instructions. They hope that employees can calm down and maintain stable work. ; If you are looking for undergraduates, they may think that they are overqualified and are just making do for the time being, or they may be riding a donkey looking for a horse, and they are not willing to work without peace of mind. Why bother asking for trouble because of a false reputation? After a while, the &quot;top students&quot; leave, and new people have to be recruited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, after understanding the difference in recruitment logic and mentality between the system and the free competition industry, students can decide whether they need to go to graduate school, whether to take the public examination as an undergraduate to get a job, or to go to graduate school to make themselves available. Wider choices. These are factual judgments, not value judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in the long run, encouraging the best students to engage in innovation, create wealth in free competition industries, and create a good institutional environment and motivation mechanism for them will naturally be a blessing to society and a country. blessing. For some time, the government has introduced many measures to stimulate the development of the private economy. Recently, eight departments have introduced &quot;25 specific measures to support the private economy.&quot; This effort is in the right direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雷军向母校武大捐13亿背后：曾领两千奖学金立志万倍还回来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261522]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 29, Wuhan University celebrated its 130th anniversary. Lei Jun personally donated 1.3 billion yuan to his alma mater. . The official account of Wuhan University stated that this set a new record for the largest single donation since the founding of Wuhan University, and was also the largest individual cash donation from an alumni received by universities across the country. Nandu reporters learned that when he was studying at Wuhan University more than 30 years ago, Lei Jun received a &quot;huge sum&quot; of 2,000 yuan and was determined to pay it back ten thousand times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7fb2543f6dfa9e1e8eee615866c61337.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7fb2543f6dfa9e1e8eee615866c61337.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Donation site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned from Wuhan University that Lei Jun is a 1987 computer science alumnus of Wuhan University and the founder, chairman and CEO of Xiaomi Group. This donation mainly focuses on three directions: supporting research in the six basic disciplines of mathematics, physics, chemistry, literature, history and philosophy, supporting scientific and technological innovation in the computer field, and supporting the training of college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lei Jun recalled that more than 30 years ago, as an outstanding student representative, he was awarded the highest scholarship at Wuhan University at that time, which was a full two thousand yuan, sponsored by a company. He said that for a student from an ordinary county family, this is really a huge sum of money. To this day, he still clearly remembers the excitement and pride he felt at that time. At that time, Lei Jun secretly swore in his heart, &quot;No matter how much scholarship I receive today, I will pay it back ten times, a hundred times, or ten thousand times in the future.&quot; In 1997, six years after graduation, Lei Jun started donating to his alma mater. At that time, his salary Only 4,000 yuan. He began his journey to fulfill his vow and donated money to establish the &quot;Lei Jun Scholarship&quot; (then called the &quot;Tengfei Scholarship&quot;) at the School of Computer Science. He has continued to donate for 26 years now. Lei Jun lamented that today he has finally fulfilled his wish to repay 10,000 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 29th, Lei Jun posted on Weibo to congratulate his alma mater on his birthday: Today is the 130th anniversary of Wuhan University. Happy birthday to my alma mater! He said, &quot;Every time I return to my alma mater, I feel very excited.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打造中国版甲骨文：易鲸捷与贵阳银行的双向冒险]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guiyang Bank Head Office Building. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/cc53458590.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/29/cc53458590.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guiyang Bank Head Office Building. Zhao Jilin/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the seventh floor of the head office building of Bank of Guiyang (601997.SH), there is a place where outsiders are prohibited from entering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The computer room covering an area of ​​more than 80 square meters is filled with large electronic display screens and computer terminals. All business operations and accounting processing related to deposits and loans need to be completed here. Supporting the operation of the entire set of equipment is the new core business transaction system that was just launched on November 6, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of banking core business transaction systems, foreign companies such as Oracle and IBM were once absolute monopolies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2020, an unknown startup company suddenly broke in. Guizhou Yijingjie Information Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Yijingjie), founded in 2015, won the bid for the domestic database application project of Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system with a price of 426 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yijingjie plays two roles, one is the supplier of database products, and the other is the general contractor of the entire project. Its purpose is to create a full-stack core transaction system for domestic banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After its official launch, this high-profile trading system did not win praise. Instead, it pushed Yijingjie to the forefront. For a time, the Internet was flooded with comments such as &quot;fake domestically produced products&quot; and &quot;shelling Oracle&quot;, and Bank of Guiyang and Yi Jingjie became the target of public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It may be very difficult for us to build a (database) nuclear weapon for daily use for the country, but we must take this risk.&quot; Li Jing, chairman of Yi Jingjie, spoke quickly He told a reporter from Southern Weekend, his voice was trembling. She looks very capable, with short hair, tattooed eyebrows, and a red coat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the moment, the &quot;nuclear weapons&quot; Li Jing talks about have not yet been put into production. He Xin, general manager of the Information Technology Department of the Bank of Guiyang, revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the current main database of the Bank of Guiyang is Oracle, and Yi Jingjie is used as a follow-up database, which is exactly the opposite of the original plan. &quot;I invested them all at once. To be honest, the risk will be relatively high.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xuerong, Secretary of the Party Committee and Director of Guiyang Big Data Bureau, further explained to Southern Weekend reporters that due to the influence of negative public opinion on the Internet, superior supervision Out of the principle of prudent supervision, the department does not agree to the online launch of Yijingjie database for the time being. &quot;As long as the regulatory authorities relent, it can be launched in any minute.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Delayed launch&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The biggest doubt from the outside world is whether Yi Wingjie, which started with distributed databases, can build a more technically difficult bank core transaction system database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The databases currently used in the financial industry are still mainly centralized, but distributed is the general trend and has computing advantages under massive data and high concurrency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The branch president of a state-owned commercial bank told Southern Weekend reporters that the difficulty in developing the bank&#39;s core transaction system database lies in the large amount of data that needs to be stored for many years and ensure that the system does not go down. In addition, each bank needs to do some customized development according to the needs of customers. For example, it has to open separate interfaces with the credit reporting system and tax system of the People&#39;s Bank of China, which &quot;has strict requirements for security.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years since Guiyang Bank purchased the Yijingjie database, it has not been able to go online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Wingjie was originally relatively optimistic about the launch time. According to the company&#39;s internal documents, the construction goals are divided into three stages:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the end of June 2020, achieve an average success rate of 99.999%, and successfully implement the &quot;dual database parallel&quot; plan for Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system in 2021. The main database uses the domestic Yijingjie database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the end of September 2021, the Yijingjie database for typical applications such as banking financial core, graphical front-end, process banking, and credit systems will be transformed and put online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third phase will comprehensively plan and transform the information system of Guiyang Bank, and realize the localization transformation of the full-scenario application system by the end of July 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information can also be seen that the launch time of Yijingjie database has been delayed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2021, the evaluation report of Yijingjie’s shareholder China Software (600536.SH) showed that the core transaction main database purchased by Guiyang Bank is planned to be officially launched in the first half of 2022. Apparently it didn&#39;t happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already two years later, in May 2023, that there was any further news. When accepting a survey from investors, the Bank of Guiyang stated that the Yijingjie domestic database application project has entered the testing phase and is advancing various testing tasks in an orderly manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, another investor asked about the progress of Yijingjie’s domestic database at the Bank of Guiyang’s third quarter performance briefing. Chairman Zhang Zhenghai replied, “The development of the new core business system of Bank of Guiyang has been completed. Testing work, the system has entered the online preparation stage, and the system is expected to be online from 17:00 on November 3, 2023 to 8:00 on November 6.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until November 6, Guiyang Bank issued an announcement stating that &quot;the new system has been successfully launched&quot;, but did not declare what database it adopted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the current situation of Yijingjie as a backup follower library, He Xin explained that for relatively mature bank core trading systems, it usually takes 18-24 months from research and development to launch. However, the Guiyang Bank project has many innovations, such as the full-stack core business system and the first application of eCas4.0 in the banking industry, so it takes a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also added that as early as the beginning of 2021, Guiyang Bank signed a contract with Oracle to allow Oracle and Yijingjie to run parallel databases to back up each other, creating a relatively safe structure. The performance of Yijingjie database is acceptable, but the database does not only rely on performance. &quot;If it is actually put online, we would like to test it more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yijingjie is located on the 24th floor of Tower C, No. 1 Gaoke. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/7d85715829.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/7d85715829. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yijingjie is located on the 24th floor of Tower C, No. 1, Gaoke. Zhao Jilin/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“No city dares to do this”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the top of Building C, No. 1 Gaoke, Changling South Road, High-tech Zone, Guiyang City, the big words “Big Data National Engineering Laboratory” are very Eye-catching, Yi Wingjie is located on the 24th floor of the building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Yijingjie, Internet companies such as NetEase Haowu and Qilin Software have settled here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of big data in Guizhou Province started in 2012. The development of the big data industry is considered by Guizhou as an excellent opportunity to change lanes and overtake. In 2015, the country established the country&#39;s first comprehensive big data pilot zone in Guizhou. One of its important tasks is to solve the security and independent controllability issues of China&#39;s big data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Yi Jingjie, he has never had access to the core transaction system database of a bank before, so he faces great technical challenges. Similarly, for the Guiyang Municipal Government and Guiyang Bank, betting on Yijingjie is also a risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A representative of Guiyang State-owned Assets who once participated in the investment in Yijingjie revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that at the end of 2015, Guiyang State-owned Assets learned about Yijingjie and visited Yijingjie’s technical team, launching a long-term Half a year of due diligence, interviews included Tencent Music (NYSE: TME), the three major telecom operators, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before investing in Yijingjie, Yijingjie signed an agreement with Guiyang State-owned Assets, stipulating that Guizhou Yijingjie would be the headquarters, and Shanghai Yijingjie and American Yijingjie would be the subsidiaries of Guizhou Yijingjie. &quot;When we invested, we promised to invest 20 million yuan first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person familiar with the Guiyang government revealed to a Southern Weekend reporter that although Yi Jingjie is not well-known, it does distributed databases , the leaders at the time also saw it, the technology was relatively new. &quot;The problem with it is that no one uses it, and there is no actual application scenario verification.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xuerong said frankly that Guiyang&#39;s big data started slowly, but it can attract a database company and regard it as a treasure, or even treat it as a treasure. Unicorns to breed. &quot;No city in the country dares to do this. We take real application scenarios and let them verify the database.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016-2019, Guiyang Industrial and Information Industry Development Guidance Fund Co., Ltd. , Guiyang Service Outsourcing and Call Industry Venture Capital Fund Co., Ltd., Guizhou Provincial Venture Investment Promotion Center, Guiyang Comprehensive Bonded Zone Development Investment (Group) Co., Ltd., Gui&#39;an New Area Emerging Industry Development Fund (Co., Ltd.) and other state-owned industrial funds , successively became shareholders of Yijingjie by increasing capital, with a cumulative investment of 128 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people from the Guiyang Municipal Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the initial investment and introduction of Yijingjie was based on its overseas technology. According to the official website of Yijingjie, the company is &quot;one of the few domestic database manufacturers with independent core technology.&quot; The R&amp;D team originates from Tianteng Company, with 30 years of technology accumulation and a complete team structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yijingjie was initially chaired by Chinese-American Li Weichong, and Li Jing, as his Chinese wife, served as the legal representative. Li Weichong has a glorious resume. He graduated from Carnegie Mellon University and received dual doctorates in finance and computer chemistry. Before founding Yijingjie, Li Weichong served as a senior executive in Lucent, Accenture, HP, China Unicom and other companies. Among them, asking Yao Ming to endorse China Unicom New World has become a classic case of publicity and promotion model, which once caused a sensation in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person close to Li Weichong and his wife described to Southern Weekend reporters that Li Weichong is personable, has extraordinary conversation, and has a gentle personality. Li Jing is on the strong side and has been in the clothing business in her early years. After the establishment of Yijingjie, Li Jing also participated in the daily management of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The original architecture is basically that of a small multinational company.” A former employee of Yijingjie told Southern Weekend reporters that in the early days, Yijingjie was relatively leading in the field of integrated distributed databases, and many people in the team were Colleagues or students of Turing Award winner Jim Gray have a relatively luxurious technical lineup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American Yijingjie was born first in Guizhou Yijingjie, one was established at the beginning of 2015 and the other at the end of the year. In Li Jing&#39;s own words, he is a &quot;father who has his son first and then looks for him.&quot; &quot;My biggest request for the American team is to pass on the technology of database development to the domestic R&amp;D team. This matter is not a secret among the American team.&quot; Li Jing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yijingjie&#39;s headquarters is located in Guiyang High-tech Zone. Zhao Jilin/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 29/056f76c471.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/056f76c471.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yijingjie&#39;s headquarters is located in Guiyang High-tech Zone. Zhao Jilin/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Small companies take on big projects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to verify the technical reliability of Yijingjie, the Guiyang government selected Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Behavior as pilot projects, starting with the sandbox project rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called sandbox refers to a virtual database environment used for development, testing and experimental purposes, which is completely isolated from the production environment database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xin said that the original core business system of Guiyang Bank was built and launched in 2005, using IBM&#39;s Informix database. Because the system is aging, performance has dropped significantly, and operation and maintenance are worrying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An internal document obtained by Southern Weekend reporters also confirms this. The document mentioned, “In March 2020, the core system mistakenly placed the key synchronization program in the day change process, causing the day to be continuously and incorrectly switched at the end of the day, resulting in a large amount of production data disorder that day. More than a dozen engineers repaired it overnight. It took hours to resolve; a production accident occurred in May 2020, and UnionPay and core logic errors resulted in duplicate entries, resulting in a short payment in the bank.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xin further explained that as the customer scale of Guiyang Bank increases, both the database and the application system have obvious deficiencies in business carrying capacity. In addition, in response to the country&#39;s requirements for the development of the credit innovation industry and the self-reliance of the bank&#39;s financial technology system, Guiyang Bank is also making local substitutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Jingjie was keenly aware of this opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a work report to Li Zaiyong, the former vice governor of Guizhou Province, on January 14, 2019, Yi Jingjie said that promoting its database has great strategic significance: &quot;Solving the country&#39;s problems in finance and government affairs , communications and other core fields of information security issues; breakthroughs in the core basic technology of the database will drive the efficiency of the entire industry; replace the international database led by Oracle, which accounts for about 90% of the domestic market, and can be exported to the Belt and Road Initiative and even the European and American markets, from These two perspectives can effectively reduce China&#39;s service trade deficit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zaiyong instructed that from the perspective of institutional support, efforts should be made to build Yijingjie into an innovative platform for the development of Guizhou&#39;s big data industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate on November 21, 2023, Li Zaiyong&#39;s suspected bribery and abuse of power case was concluded by the National Supervisory Commission and transferred to the procuratorial organ for review and prosecution. However, the news did not disclose whether Li Zaiyong&#39;s fall was related to Yi Jingjie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former employee of Yi Jingjie who has worked with Li Weichong and his wife for many years told Southern Weekend reporters that unlike Li Weichong, Li Jing has particularly outstanding planning skills and can grasp the core needs of customers. &quot;She clearly understands what the Bank of Guiyang, Guiyang Municipal Government and participating manufacturers want, and has strong ability to make decisions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 2, 2019, the core business of Guiyang Bank&#39;s domestic database construction The sandbox testing system project was sold, with Yijingjie becoming the sole supplier, and the winning bid price was 43.98 million yuan. According to the announcement, this procurement adopts a single-source procurement method because &quot;according to project construction requirements, procurement can only be from a single supplier.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why use single-source bidding? He Xin said that Guiyang Bank&#39;s procurement is based on the &quot;Interim Provisions on the Management of Centralized Procurement of State-owned Financial Enterprises&quot; implemented by the Ministry of Finance on February 5, 2018. &quot;If we violate the law, I think we can be held accountable according to law. If we comply with the law, I think it will be No problem, no further explanation is needed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the project plan, Guiyang Bank uses the Yijingjie database to build a core business sandbox test application system, using the system as a sandbox for the existing core business system, and using the transactions of the core business system on the sandbox Data, carry out the testing and verification work of Yijingjie database. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 8 of the same year, Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank purchased another project of Yijingjie - a domestic database application pilot, with a transaction amount of 123 million yuan. This project adopts the &quot;dual database parallel&quot; solution with mutual backup and free switching, and has been officially accepted in May 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A project leader of Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank told Southern Weekend reporters that the dual-bank parallel plan has three stages. In the first stage, Oracle is used as the main database, in the second stage, Yi Jingjie is used as the main library, and in the third stage, Oracle is completely excluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the person in charge admitted that Yi Jingjie has not yet become the main warehouse. “We must first admit the gap, then push our own things up, and let others stand guard for us for a while. , this is a more cautious approach.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee structure of Yijingjie obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that Yijingjie was still a start-up company with a small scale when it received the bank order. From 2017 to 2019, the number of employees was 69, 100, and 144 respectively. Among them, there are 46, 74 and 105 technical personnel respectively. There are less than 20 people with master&#39;s degrees in the company, and only one with a doctorate. In addition, Yi Jingjie has a team of more than 30 people in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, according to the China Software Shareholders’ Equity Assessment Report, from 2017 to June 2021, Yijingjie’s R&amp;D expenses totaled 62.8922 million yuan, of which the R&amp;D expenses in 2017 were 0, and in 2018 they were only 1.03 million. , it was 19.6471 million yuan in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Most of the revenue is outsourced&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the surface, Yijingjie won large orders from Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank in the early stage. But in fact, Yi Wingjie did not gain much benefit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An insider told Southern Weekend reporters that of the 123 million yuan order signed by Yi Jingjie and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank, the self-owned product part was only 25.9709 million yuan, accounting for 21.11%; with Guiyang Bank Among the contract value of 43.98 million yuan signed, the self-owned product part was only 10.9251 million yuan, accounting for 24.84%. Most of its revenue is achieved through outsourcing, and even some of its external procurement revenue costs are inverted, causing the company to suffer heavy losses year after year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the asset appraisal report issued by Zhongrui Shilian Asset Appraisal Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Zhongrui Shilian) in January 2021, from 2017 to 2019, Yijingjie’s operating income (parent company caliber ) were 2.2858 million yuan, 15.0113 million yuan and 91.5668 million yuan respectively; net profits (parent company caliber) were -1.8598 million yuan, 4.0166 million yuan and -49.3269 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it doesn’t make money in the early stage, why does Yijingjie need to develop a more difficult core banking transaction business system? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Yijingjie shareholder told Southern Weekend reporters that although Li Jing claimed to have a strong sense of mission for information security, the actual situation was that the company was on the verge of bankruptcy and had to seek transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October to November 2019, Yi Jingjie’s capital chain was in crisis. The company had no money in its accounts and could not even pay wages for a time. Li Jing and shareholder Peng Yimin also repeatedly offered 6% of their annual income. Lending funds to Yi Jingjie at interest rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned shareholders revealed that during the early years of Yi Jingjie&#39;s business, although it had customers such as China Unicom and China Mobile, the amount of a single order was not large, ranging from hundreds of thousands to millions of yuan. Li Jing once said more than once in internal meetings, &quot;When will this continue to end?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side of the Pacific, in the United States, the company’s annual sales revenue is only two to three hundred thousand US dollars, but the team’s annual expenses exceed US$5 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the husband and wife have different positions on the development of the bank&#39;s core transaction system and database. Li Weichong objected many times, and company CEO Ding Hong also firmly opposed it. &quot;But Li Jing saw the market and insisted on doing it.&quot; said the above-mentioned shareholder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person close to Li Weiyong told the southern weekend reporter that Li Weichong&#39;s personality is very cautious, and the company’s losses are constantly high. big. On October 7, 2019, Li Weichong and Li Jing agreed to divorce. Li Weiyong stepped down as the chairman and handed all the Yibble Jie who was founded to Li Jing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Aiming at the many issues of Yibi Jie, reporters in the southern weekend contacted Li Weichong many times. He declined the interview with &quot;inconvenience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In December 2019, Li Jing held a meeting in the underground conference room in Beijing&#39;s home. The company&#39;s backbones and representatives of Guiyang have participated in more than 20 people, but they excluded Li Weiyong and Ding Hong representing the American team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A shareholder who participated in the meeting told the Southern Weekend reporter that at this meeting, Li Jing asked the company to make a comprehensive transformation, based on the core business of the bank, and decided to leave the US team. &quot;This is the company&#39;s direction and the place where money is made.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The more you understand the technology, the more you know the border, the more you don&#39;t understand the technology, the more you dare to rush.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person who has participated in Evilist financing told the Southern Weekend reporter that stripping the US team has a lot to do with Anke (safe and reliable). &quot;Later we learned that if you want to do the core business system, you must pass the Anco first. You can&#39;t get this off, don&#39;t do any bank core.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Later The price has achieved a wholly -owned holding of Yibbles in the United States. Then, the US team disbanded and cleared the last obstacle of Yibi Jie&#39;s localization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 19, 2020, the Guizhou Sunshine Property Exchange announced that the core business system of Guiyang Bank&#39;s core business system was transaction, with a total price of 426 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He Xin revealed that the project involves the full business chain, from the front, back to core, disaster recovery system, network, monitoring management platform, security and other related projects, involving more than 20 suppliers. Among them, the amount of the Yibble Jie database project was only over 40 million yuan, accounting for over 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Become a &quot;national team&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; For a software startup, sufficient ammunition can maintain this &quot;burning money&quot; game. The method of Yibijie is to marry Chinese software and become the &quot;national team&quot; in the database field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China Software is a large high -tech central enterprise, which is controlled by China Electronics Information Industry Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as China Electronics). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jing took over the end of 2019, and began to contact China Electronics. In May 2020, China Electronics and Yibai Jie reached an exclusive investment intention, which will complete investment in Yibai Jie through two steps: first to acquire part of the original shares of Li Jing&#39;s Yibi Jie, through Chinese software, and then complete further capital increase Expand shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In April 2021, China officially invested in Yibius, holding 7.6438%of the equity of Yibi Victoria at a consideration of 56.7897 million yuan. One year later, China&#39;s software decided to increase capital. It is intended to adopt a direct investment+newly -held holding sub -enterprise &quot;China Software Investment&quot; investment to register the capital of 22.91 yuan/1 yuan. According to calculations, the actual capital contribution does not exceed 1,819.213 million yuan), and the subscribed by Yi Yibai has added up to 16.9723 million yuan in registered capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the evaluation report of the Sino -Swiss Shilian, the capital increase of China Software to Yibble Jie is nearly 18 times the book value premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On February 21, 2023, the Chinese Software Board issued an announcement saying that the company had moderate control of actual investment and payment progress in the consideration of prudential and controlling investment risks. As of November 10, 2022, the company had paid 17.91 million yuan in capital increases, and China Software contributed 47.24 million yuan in capital, a total shareholding ratio increased to 11.09%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This investment amount is far from the original plan that &quot;the total contribution does not exceed 389 million yuan, and the total holding of a total of not exceeding the 25%equity of the Yibbles&quot; is far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On August 17, the Beijing Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued a warning letter to the Sino -Swiss Period, and proposed that the &quot;business income prediction data basis was not sufficient&quot; for Yibijie. In the first evaluation project, the implementation of the company&#39;s profit prediction data was not fully analyzed and reviewed. The reason for the second evaluation project did not fully pay attention to the reasons for the extension of the extension of the Easy Whale and the extension of the large order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, the warning letter mentioned that &quot;the&quot; first &#39;and other expressions were used in the two evaluation reports, but there was no sufficient evidence to support related expressions in the draft. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since then, Yibi Jie has no big financing trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A person who has worked in Yi Whale Jie for many years told the Southern Weekend that the early integrated distributed database of Yibble Jie was relatively leading, but as other companies rose rapidly, the advantages of Yibi Jie&#39;s technical advantages gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually gradually. No longer, there are some problems with the company&#39;s strategy. &quot;In the final analysis, it must be quickly listed, and then pull to resources to expand the R &amp; D team. A world -class technology, relying on small companies of one or two hundred people, how to get a leading position?&quot; Today, the National People&#39;s Congress Jincang, Dameng, Nanda General and Shenzhou GM are known as the &quot;four golden flowers&quot; of domestic databases. Not only are IT giants such as Alibaba, Tencent, and Huawei, but also small entrepreneurial manufacturers for market segments, such as Star Ring and Pingcap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another former employee who was responsible for Easy Whale&#39;s financing pointed out that even if the company wants to go public, it is difficult to meet the standards. The first is that the income does not meet the standard. Another key issue is a single customer. Except for Guiyang Bank and Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank, Yibi Jie basically does not have large customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A former employee of Yibi Jie revealed to the south weekend reporter that starting in October, Yi Whale Jie has begun layoffs, because of &quot;financing issues and normal optimization of personnel&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[怀念奶奶丨到此的路程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261493]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 13:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;img alt = &quot;art history scholar Xu Xiaohu. Information chart &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1622 &quot;data-src =&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259891 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style: #999999; text-align:: text-align: Justify; &quot;>; artist Xu Xiaohu. Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Mom and Dad when they got married in Nanjing, the capital of the Republic of China in May 1933, grandma and her old man invited some Chinese ladies who did not think much. Stand with the bride at the ceremony. This is because the grandmother chose the 20 -year -old German girl selected by her loved three sons, and she was startled: tea yellow loose hair, thin and long face, her eyes fell into their heads, flattened Pull the tall nose, so ugly abnormal! Why did this be? Grandma was anxious, and desperately wanted to find some even more ugly ladies to reconcile this horrible situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;img alt = &quot;1933, Xu Dao neighboring and Barbara Schuchard had a wedding in Nanjing. /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 827 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259892 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: justify; &quot;>; 1933, Xu Dao neighboring and Barbara Schuchard had a wedding in Nanjing. Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The introducer at the time was the father of his father in Germany, the cheerful and advanced Mr. Jiang Fuxi, and Mr. Jiang later promoted it when the curator of the National Central Library. Many advanced and effective governance measures, and advocated that all books are data to be permanently preserved. Later, Uncle Jiang became the first dean of the Taipei Palace Museum, where he implemented many new measures. Out of the consideration of employees, at the time, there were still people with dormitory and welfare agencies near the museum outside the suburbs at that time. Wait for facilities. In 1933, he witnessed his parents&#39; wedding ceremony in Nanjing. Later, he told me that he &quot;eats the red egg of Xiaohu&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Moms from Germany who fell into Nazism to marry Xu Dao neighbors in China, and found that many traditions of this ancient state were very difficult for her. At first she refused to kneel in front of her grandmother like her father. Barbara Schuchard, who grew up in Berlin, has never giving anyone or God overwhelming in his life. Before many curious viewers, her spine became an iron bar that could not be bent. At the beginning, the poor dad could only run between the mother and wife to explain, and became a &quot;diplomatic&quot; expert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Next spring, there is a huge typhoon in Nanjing. The young bride went to the Central Hospital to have their first child. Blowed up by the typhoon. She thought excitedly, ah! This must be a &quot;presidential&quot; boy! Dad is also waiting for his son, and they have prepared a lot of names -they are all boys. In this case, when he saw a red and wrinkled little girl, the two of them were completely stunned, and they couldn&#39;t say surprise and disappointment. They looked at each other and didn&#39;t know what to do. One day passed, two days passed, and I couldn&#39;t think of any girl&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; On the third day, grandma spoke. She explained to the new parent&#39;s ins and outs of the child. Feng Conghu and Yun Conglong, this coming person is obviously the big cat named Xiao Hu when he was a child. The cat was suddenly pressed by the car, and the &quot;Three Balds&quot; of the Xu family (shaved his head for all his sons, refused to stay full of braids). . Grandma comforted Dad and said, don&#39;t cry, Sanbu, your little tiger will fly back to you as soon as possible, accompany you for a lifetime. Dad was so relieved and slowly returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Grandma holding this new little baby said: You see, isn&#39;t this the little tiger who has been waiting for so many years to accompany you? Who do you say? This is the little tiger who is back. My parents had nothing to say, so my grandmother looked at her mother&#39;s face and gave her daughter-in-law a name for the first time- &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; You said Isn&#39;t it, Huzi Niang? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;img alt = &quot;In the summer of 1934, Xu Xiaohu and his parents are in Lushan Lingling. .infzm.com/cms/Medias/Image/23/11/28/3FB66ea181.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1089 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.CMS/cms/cms/cms/cms /medias/image/23/11/28/3fb66ea181.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 259893 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: justify; &quot;>;&quot; Xiaohu and his parents were in Lushan Lingling. Data Map &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Eight years later, we were accompanied by the capital of Chongqing outskirts. time. From 1938 to 1941, his father had been the Republic of China in Italy for four years. The outbreak of World War II was broken, and my parents took me and my sister Xiaoyu back to China. Grandma also came to Ge Le Shan from Ge Leshan to meet the three sons of the third son from Chengdu&#39;s aunt&#39;s house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Our plane landed in Chongqing. Welcome to the parents and speak Chinese words that adults speak. I walked down the rail and the land that walked to China, which was so moved. This is my motherland! My eight -year -old heart burst out. In Rome&#39;s elementary school classmates, I asked me, uncle shouted! (This is the pronunciation of foreigners say Xu Xiaohu&#39;s pronunciation) &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Uncle Sake! Why is your face so flat? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; I thought about it and answered: This is because I am from a long and old country. The Chinese embassy you saw at Vialepola, a strong guards in front of them wearing beautiful uniforms and high feather helmets. That&#39;s my ancient and luxurious motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Now I kneeling to the land of the motherland, bent down and lowered my head, and kissed my dream of four years of belonging, happy and moved, shed tears, shed tears, shed tears, shed tears, shed tears, shed tears and tears. Gently tell the motherland that the great land, Xiaohu is back, and your child is back. I will learn Chinese as soon as possible, Chinese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The land at that time was so dirty, not as bright and clean as Rome. I saw a dirty child. The clothes were torn, full of sores, stood there with naked noses, staring at us. Like adults, they spit out sputum from their mouths and vomited to the ground. The little tiger who returned to China was very sad, but insisted on thinking about this is my favorite motherland, the far away, very old and old motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Later, I took a few hours of hillside with a flower rod sedan, and finally came to the small black soil house of No. 15, Eight Tian, ​​Geleshan. Someone moved the luggage in, and her mother and sister walked into the house and turned their luggage to find things. I stayed on the balcony and watched my father knelt next to the grandma tied to the foot. The mother and child hugged each other, the grandmother cried loudly, and the high and high voice shot on the sky. Dad cried silently, and they cried for a long time. I also felt sad when I saw it, and I didn&#39;t understand it, but I fully appreciated the feelings in their hearts. I left quietly, walked into the door, climbed a chair next to the big round table, and saw a pot of tea on the table and a few cups of no man controlled. I don&#39;t know what the drink is, but it must be the drink of my motherland. I poured myself a drink for myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; bitter and astringent. Adult. taste of China. I love it, I want to love it. Drink another glass to taste it. Another cup. This taste has not been tasted for a lifetime. It has no taste in Italy. I am Chinese, I will drink Chinese taste. One cup after receiving this ancient taste and sucking into my soul. Xu Xiaohu and her motherland gradually became one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; The sky began to be dark. The crying and complaints outside had not stopped, but the room was not clear. Someone put a lamp on a large table. It is a green long -handle oil lamp made of ceramics. A white light core floated on the bowl of oil. Is this the only lighting in our big room (restaurant)? The new Chinese who returned home found that she could not see anything. She was not like the light of the Roman electrical chandeliers, and she immediately felt ashamed. This is the ancient lighting of my motherland. No matter how bright, I will love it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; I don&#39;t remember how I fell asleep on the first night in Gelshan, I just remember that I insisted on going to school right away, and learned my mother tongue again. Chinese elementary school students. I did not expect that I expected to go to elementary school to continue to study in the fourth grade but was sent to the first grade to learn Chinese. I went to school happily, and I still remember that the first lesson said, &quot;Come, come to school, everyone come to school.&quot; All Chinese characters have no phonetic symbols -we go directly to know the ancient Chinese characters. On the way home, the classmates chased the stones behind, and shouted loudly &quot;Madam!&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; My hair was not black and straight, Tea red curved. After I went home, I desperately brushed with water and brush, trying to brush it directly. No matter how wet and how to brush it, it rolls up again. I had to face these students myself, fight with them, and hit them one by one. After all, I am eight years old, a little higher than the first -year classmates. When I got along with Italian classmates, there was no negative behavior, and I began to release an inherent energy, and I felt very proud. It turns out that the children of the motherland in the war persuaded each other with physical strength. Well, start learning Chinese words, and start to become a Chinese hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; . &amp; nbsp; &lt;/span>; Grandma said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; I will not come down from the tree. This tree is my home. &lt;/span>; I answered happily and naughty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; . &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; at my place. I look at the world from here. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot; Give me it from that tree. Grandma told you to come down from that dirty tree. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; No. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; We will not be filial now. Little tiger, a good child, come here to grandma. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Tree? Why must I go to my grandma? I like to live in this tree. Here I can count the enemy aircraft! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; At that time, my Chinese had already spoken well, on the pine tree near the small mud house in Geleshan, I remembered Before the Grand Garden, the official residence of the elegant embassy in Rome, the freedom of free flowerless trees that were not observed and found. I have a high ceiling in the bedroom in Rome. The ceiling to the wall covers the colorful murals with classical mythical characters ... There is a two or three -story doll houses in the bedroom, which can play with the furniture, doll bed and cabinet, chairs and tables. And several puppet dolls who can stand and stand. These are not interesting to me. After lunch, I will slip into the garden outside, find the highest flower fig tree to climb up, hiding in the leaves that are rich and overflowing with milky liquid. No one can see me, and no one will go there to find me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; In the months of autumn, I can pick juicy fruits on this huge tree. Even if there is no fruit, I can sit on its big branches to enjoy the breeze, height and happiness. For a child with a family nanny, this is difficult to get lucky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; My cute little sister Xiaoyu is three and a half years younger than me, and has always been in the embrace of the French Switzerland nanny of Mademoiselle, from the embrace of the French nanny of Mademoiselle. Roman years at the age of 4 to 8, they are very free, and they are more committed to exploring unknown loneliness, not chatting with servants or dolls. In the changing trees that pass through the cool breeze, I will talk from the people from the higher favorable position to talk about the sound of people on the ground, and I can feel the movements of adults. That perspective made me from a wonderful distance and adults from an adult. The world is separated from a buffer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; On those generous big branches, everything has lost the persuasion of &quot;adults&quot;. From the perspective of tree living, everything on the ground has become less urgent and threatening. Observe them from a higher perspective than adults, and find that adults often destroy the scope of secular wisdom or common sense. Surprisingly, they are often like this and spend a lot of time to participate in unnecessary words and deeds; do a lot of unnecessary action, unreal behavior, and raise a hypocritical mentality. Adults will spend a few days and nights that are not important or even ridiculous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; For example, they created very difficult clothes, my mother&#39;s clothes out of the house, there is a large row of buttons-but they are all behind! Walking behind her, I can see that one of the buttons is not right, tilting her head aside, causing all the other buttons to be wrong, forming a scene that looks very funny. The adults would pretend not to see it, but they giggled behind her all day. No one pointed her to this, and no one helped her to deduct the whole row of buttons again. I can only walk behind and watch them, thinking about how stupid and unnecessary this time is spent, but our children are not allowed to point out this, giggle or laughing; Leave it to yourself and attribute this to the adult&#39;s love for spending time, and the children can only endure silently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Give me the tree. Did you hear it? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Why, grandma? Why do I leave my beloved habitat? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Because I must teach you now embroidery. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Embroidery? Use needle and line? Hit holes on my fingers? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Now you must learn embroidery. When you learn some useful things! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; What? What is the use of embroidery, grandma? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; All girls learn embroidery. This is absolutely necessary! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Why? I have never heard of embroidery in class! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; When I think of sitting in a closed room, holding a thin needle, piercing a cotton cloth stretched in a round hoop, entering and leaving Out, isolation of all breeze sounds, fresh air in the sun, the singing of birds, or people&#39;s voices, it is like I isolating life itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; In addition to sitting on the pine tree at home, I also like to sit on a small square stone under another pine tree. Through the valley on the way home from school, under the winding corner of the winding mountain trail, under the big stone mansion of General Chen Cheng, I will reach the habitat after a few steps, sit there and stare at the distant Shapingba Valley Plain. , The Jialing River in the sun meanders into the distance. There is a Central University, and my father teaches there, and also works in the Chongqing Central Government. In that habitat, I will listen to the voice of people living in the plain. They sell the goods, the parents yell at the children, and the children shouted each other. I would think of my father and work with my head alone to do all my heads. People serve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Every Sunday, he will take the &quot;two-person human car&quot; to leave our black mud house, go down the mountain along thousands of steps, reach Shapingba below Shapingba below Entering his Chongqing and his lonely rooms, I have always been thinking like my dad. I think about my dad&#39;s inner world ... He is alone, satisfied everything that we can do, and make our country better. Some. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; That is the time when the start of World War II. Japan has a ruthless bombing of Chongqing every day in Japan, hoping to eliminate important government goals. However, Chongqing has been in haze, and Wuyun is densely set, and the Japanese aircraft is difficult to bombard the target. Every few days, we will hear the alarm sounds over the head of our heads. Everyone will even rush out of the people who live in Gele Mountain and squeeze into those humid and dark air -proof caves. Water vapor. Every time I slip out alone, sit on the rocks under my favorite tall pine, counting enemy planes, try to identify different brands of the aircraft based on black and white photos -those photos are me and my classmates from the police station. Get. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在给我停止一切，虎头儿， Give me it immediately. You come to learn embroidery, starting today. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Why? What is the use of embroidery when the Japanese drove the plane on top of our heads? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Because you will get married, You have to prepare to be a bride! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Too terrible, grandma! Is this really the case? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Of course, fool. Of course you want to get married! Marriage and give birth to children! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;-&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Grandma, please tell me, Was our life when we were young to get married and gave birth to children? ——This is so painful, grandma! Each of you has given birth to a child! Mom and dad have done it too! Grandma&#39;s child is born in front of grandma! Now that our children are finally here, we must start a interesting life. We come here for our special and unique life of children! &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; I suddenly became crystal clear. The reason for our birth is to be born! Become a child who is married to our parents. Now we are finally born, the purpose of growing up is successful, and we don&#39;t need to get married and have children anymore! The life explained by my grandmother is completely unacceptable to my broad -minded way of thinking. Is this really the life everyone said? So in this way, obviously adults are really ignorant! The real purpose of life is not just for the existence of human beings. I saw it clearly at the time that humans obviously had not asked this question, the meaning of survival -why do we live -this is the question! Why do we come to this fun place? Of course, come to appreciate this life and play it thoroughly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Play in pain to the end-this is the purpose of us-no? The most basic and important test of this is from my heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Grandma told me a lot of stories. There is a large round metal barrel on the elevated in her room. Grandma shook around and moved her little feet, and she could walk to the elevated elevated and took off the particularly bright barrel, mixed it, and opened it to take out her own maltose. There is nothing in the world than the maltose that rolls with grandma. Round and flat, with white powder on the outside, so that they are not sticky into a group. Therefore, of course, eating maltose can also count on one of the main goals of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Listening to grandma telling stories is also one of the wonderful goals, too charming! Grandma&#39;s story will include the heroes of our family. For example, the grandma&#39;s surname is Xia, and the Xia family comes from Yue Fei&#39;s hometown. Grandma&#39;s voice as sweet as honey and high as a bird, slowly using her Xuzhou cavity story, all have a taste. Xiaohu sat next to her grandma&#39;s knees and listened, and she forgot everything else. The entire countryside loves Yue Fei. He helped the emperor from returning from Jin Guo to restore the throne of the emperor, but Gao Zong was unwilling to return the throne he had already sat to his father and father -this unsuccessful son called Yue Fei and Yue Fei&#39;s eldest son Concerned as an enemy and chopped his head. Xiaohu cried loudly when he heard it, and his tears flew around. The villagers who love Yue Fei are also speechless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Grandma also likes to tell the story of Grandpa to Mongolia- &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot; FONT-FAMILY: Kai style, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Tiger Head, one day, the country wants Mongolians to stay in China and cannot leave the motherland to go out independently. So your grandpa-General Xu, then, did not bring any army or weapons. He ran to Mongolia alone, and only took his flute and the old mother of Xuzhou with his cake. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Find a hill and sit down on the top. Grandpa inserted his big &quot;Xu&quot; military flag on the ground -just sitting there, singing, singing, watching the moon, eating pancakes, and waiting for the Mongolian chief to surrender calmly. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; coming. He looked up, wow! Hearing the voice of Kunqu opera. Seeing the big &quot;Xu&quot; character flag, it was startled, and immediately climbed up respectfully. When he saw Grandpa, he knelt down and squeezed his head to apologize desperately. &quot;Oh! The president is coming in person, the little ignorance is incompetent, so I dare not be! Xiao&#39;s unwilling to disturb the uncle!&quot; I regret that the buns and apologies are too late. . Hahaha! If you don&#39;t say a word, you ca n’t say a word, so you caught the Mongolian back. You said that your grandpa is more capable. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; This is how my grandma tells the story of Grandpa who recovered Great Mongolia, which has also become one of our private family history. When the great -grandchildren who are scattered in various countries are gathered together, this story will perform the &quot;historical drama&quot; of multiple versions of the story, expressing the story of General Xu Shuzheng regaining foreign Mongolia from various perspectives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; Dad, of course, have never heard of grandma. In front of my father, no one dares to mention the name or past of Grandpa. Thinking of his favorite father, his father would shed tears. Xiaohu likes to listen to the story of grandma, which is much faster than Yue Fei&#39;s story. Every time I heard the chief sweaty, I laughed at the period when I was too sweating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; At this time, the national, struggle, self-sacrifice, integrity, and various ideals of serving the public have taken root in the bottom of the heart. I began to think about the purpose of our survival repeatedly; how important and huge time and space worlds were felt. But at the deepest point in my heart, I started to have a question that could not be overwhelmed ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“我想当大明星”：地下偶像疯狂在2023年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261515]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“营造女友感”：追地下偶像的男人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261499]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 12:10:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“蓉漂之后，再无漂泊”：年轻人与成都的双向奔赴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 10:57:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 20, 2023, &quot;Chengdu Marathon &amp;amp; World Science Fiction Conference City Walk &quot;The flash mob event was held at the main venue of the World Science Fiction Conference on the Greenway around the Lake. Chengdu Commercial Daily/Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/228de3a407.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/228de3a407.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 259913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 20, 2023, the &quot;Chengdu Marathon &amp;amp; World Science Fiction Conference City Walk&quot; flash mob event was held at the World Science Fiction Conference The main venue of the conference was held on the greenway around the lake. (Chengdu Business Daily/Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 5-day 81st World Science Fiction Convention was held in a city that has not changed its name for more than 2,000 years - —Chengdu&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>; has come to an end. This is the first time that China has held such a science fiction event. In October 2023, more than 20,000 science fiction fans and more than 1,200 guests from 35 countries and regions around the world gathered in Chengdu to talk about the future in this modern city with a long history. Imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the conference, 27-year-old science fiction writer Bai Ben stayed in a hotel in Pidu District. On the 19th floor of the hotel, through the window, he saw a shopping mall not far away, which happened to be the one he participated in the design and construction of when he was a real estate company at his former employer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bai Bi could not describe his feelings for a moment: it was a sense of time and space intertwined in Chengdu, where the past and present, ideals and reality merged. He just came to Chengdu in 2021 and worked as a designer in a real estate company. After 9 months, he was too busy to &lt;span>;home&lt;/span>;; but it was also in Chengdu that he got closer and closer to his science fiction dream, and he successively won several projects in China The Science Fiction Galaxy Award for Best Newcomer and the Chinese Science Fiction Nebula Award for Best Short Story Silver Award. Now, he also has his own book signings at science fiction conventions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As one of the millions of young people &quot;floating in Chengdu&quot;, Bai Bi from Jiangsu has a reason to stay in Chengdu. At present, he is mainly engaged in the Internet industry and works part-time in science fiction writing. There are few cities that can simultaneously host good Internet companies, embrace the vision of building a science fiction industry, and also create a comfortable, livable and smoky urban atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu attracts Bai Ben, and young people like Bai Ben also attract Chengdu. For years, this rapidly rising megacity in the Midwest has struggled to recruit and retain young talents. I don’t know who was the first to say the words, “After Chengdu, there will be no more wandering.” This has become the essence of Chengdu’s talent work branding and the pursuit of the city’s builders. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Beside Xinglong Lake, look up and meet the doctor&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After five years, I faced the computer screen with a picture of Aba, Sichuan Province in 2018 Huang Ying is still quite moved by the high-altitude bird&#39;s eye view of Aerzhai, Wenchuan County, Prefecture. That year, a landslide suddenly hit Aerzhai. Half of the village collapsed &lt;span>; and half of it was buried. Fortunately, no one died. The geological disaster monitoring and early warning platform developed by Sichuan Zhongke Chuanxin Technology Co., Ltd. played a role. Villagers moved in advance and escaped this natural disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying is now the deputy general manager of this company. However, going back to 6 years ago, Huang Ying was still confused on the eve of changing careers. At that time, the 24-year-old was working in a survey and design institute in a province in Central and South China. The industry was gradually declining. A colleague asked: &quot;Should we transform into high technology?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Huang Ying is somewhat tempted, but where to settle is a problem. He thought of Chengdu, where he spent four years in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, major cities across the country have increased their efforts to attract young talents. Chengdu also needs more young people to participate in urban development and construction. Li Rong, a talent worker in Chengdu, told Southern Weekend reporters that Chengdu has launched version 1.0 of its new talent policy around the idea of ​​“gathering people to prosper the city”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Settlement first and then employment&quot; is a policy initiative that has led to a nationwide trend of settling down and attracting talents. &quot;Those under 45 years old and with a bachelor&#39;s degree or above can directly settle in Chengdu with their graduation certificate.&quot; Li Rong said that in the past six years, Chengdu has attracted more than 710,000 college students to settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying took a fancy to the convenience of settling down and joined the trend of &quot;Peacock Flying Southwest&quot;. He and his partners founded a company in Chengdu High-tech Zone, focusing on geological disasters and Environmental disaster prevention and reduction platform construction and product research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everything is difficult at the beginning. Huang Ying&#39;s new company encountered obstacles in financing, human resources, sales and other aspects. Initially, he traveled to almost every county in western and southern Sichuan to introduce himself to the local land and resources departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu gave him a hand. Huang Ying remembers that when the company first settled in Chengdu High-tech Zone, the government provided policy support of halving office rents. At the end of 2017, the company sold the first batch of prototypes to a county in western Sichuan. Half a year later, the machine successfully warned of landslides twice, and since then it has gradually opened up the market in southwest China. However, government assistance has not stopped. Three years after the epidemic, the company has also received financial subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying said that currently, the company has applied its equipment and platforms to water conservancy dams, mine safety, foundation pit support, transportation, etc., and has Go nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying’s career is developing, and Chengdu’s talent policy is also iterating. In 2020, Chengdu launched the New Talent Policy Version 2.0 around the construction of the Western Science City, focused on technological innovation, launched and implemented Tianfu Laboratory&#39;s global high-end talent recruitment plan, created Chengdu&#39;s characteristic professional group, and supported high-level platforms to open to the society. In 2022, The Chengdu Innovation Index ranks 29th in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three years have passed, and there are many scientific research institutions in the Chengdu Science City located in Tianfu New District, Sichuan. Liu Hongyan, a 34-year-old assistant researcher at the Institute of Urban Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, joked, “If you walk around Xinglong Lake, you might just look up and meet a doctor.” In 2019, she came to the institute as a postdoctoral fellow to work on functional Food development and other work, becoming a member of Xinglong Lakeside&#39;s army of doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shi Jian, the 36-year-old assistant director of the DC Research Institute of Tsinghua Sichuan Energy Internet Research Institute, is also a Ph.D. from Xinglong Lakeside. Looking back on his two years in Chengdu, he felt that he had achieved what he had hoped for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shi Jian is pursuing the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. He once worked for 7 years in a research institute affiliated to a state-owned enterprise in a southeastern province, focusing on research on ultra-high voltage DC engineering and new energy power generation. He has always been troubled by the fact that the cycle of transferring scientific research to application is too long. After arriving in Tianfu New District, Sichuan, he was able to flex his muscles. Right now, the Shijian team is developing the most critical projects in the power industry such as series of power equipment and power chips for DC projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 22, 2023, Peking University Qiu Deba Gymnasium, the scene of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Peking University special event. Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6490cf2092.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6490cf2092.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259914&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 22nd, Peking University Qiu Deba Gymnasium, the scene of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Peking University special event. (Talent Office of Chengdu Municipal Party Committee/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why did the six million &quot;Rong Piao&quot; come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of October 2023, a group of students from Tsinghua University At a job fair, a doctor of medicine expressed mutual interest in a state-owned enterprise in Wenjiang District, Chengdu. State-owned enterprises do not &quot;go round and round to make appointments&quot;. Instead, the person in charge directly reads the resume, interviews, and talks about job content, remuneration and benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a scene from the Beijing special event of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; series of events. Li Rong introduced that as the most important series of talent recruitment activities in Chengdu in recent years, the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; has held more than 1,000 talent recruitment activities in key cities at home and abroad, and signed more than 200,000 contracts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, Chengdu has focused on leading the city’s talent work with branding strategies. &amp;nbsp;The slogan &quot;Rongpiao&quot; has been shouted out, but there has been some controversy in society as to whether the talent brand should continue to use this name. After all, like Beipiao and Shanghai Piao, there is still the word &quot;piao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Chengdu has been a typical immigrant city since ancient times, with cultural characteristics of openness, tolerance, generosity and friendliness. According to talent workers in Chengdu, the genetic inheritance and cultural core of &quot;Rongpiao&quot; have long been rooted in the urban development trajectory, and have become Chengdu&#39;s endless driving force, changing the original meaning of &quot;piao&quot; and enriching the meaning of &quot;piao&quot;. &quot;Connotation. Chengdu respects every individual&#39;s dream, cherishes every upward force, and uses the greatest sincerity to help &quot;Rongpiao&quot; realize their personal value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has fully launched the practice of talent work branding strategy, creating a deeply rooted &quot;Rongpiao&quot; brand, and is also the first country in the country to apply for trademark registration The city&#39;s talent work brand has created a series of flagship products and a series of derivatives, such as the &quot;Rongpiao Plan&quot; to attract talents, the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; to recruit talents, the &quot;Rongpiao Cup&quot; to gather talents, and the &quot;Rongpiao Cup&quot; to educate talents. Talent Development Institute”, Jingcai’s “Rongpiao Talent Day”, Licai’s “Rongcheng Talent Green Card”, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has been exploring ways to solve practical difficulties for young college students who have just entered society. &quot;Thinking about it from a talent perspective, what does a newly graduated college student lack when going to a city to find a job? It must be a place to live.&quot; Li Rong said that based on this idea, Chengdu has created 26 &quot;Rongpiao&quot; cities in recent years. &quot;Youth Talent Station&quot; provides short-term free accommodation for fresh graduates who come to Chengdu to find jobs, as well as a series of value-added services such as employment guidance and urban integration. &quot;As long as the interview notice is held and applied online, young college students can stay in the apartment for free, up to a month of up to one month.&quot; As of now, a total of more than 80,000 young college students have been received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that in the past, when enterprises and institutions in Chengdu went to first-tier cities and well-known universities to recruit, the results were not good because they worked alone and lacked visibility. not good. Later, they changed their approach and maximized the effectiveness of talent introduction by building a collaborative talent introduction model of &quot;government guidance, employer leadership, and broad social participation&quot; to unify publicity themes, unified promotion processes, and unified logos and slogans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking this year&#39;s &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Tsinghua University and Peking University as an example, Chengdu mobilized 26 public institutions and 16 municipal state-owned enterprises to come up with For high-quality positions, university research institutes and Fortune 500 companies are invited to participate in recruitment. According to statistics, this event released 782 recruitment positions and attracted more than 1,800 young college students to participate. The activity includes city promotion, opportunity list release, job promotion, doctoral and postdoctoral policy promotion, etc. Each recruitment unit &quot;can add their own creativity&quot; and set up stalls to recruit talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recruiting young talents is only the first step. In order to retain talents, Chengdu also spent real money. From the city level to the district (city) and county level, there are a series of talent project applications and talent level assessments. Liu Hongyan recalled that after she achieved certain scientific research results, she was evaluated as a senior talent category C in the &quot;Tianfu Talent Plan&quot; of Sichuan Tianfu New District in 2022. The new district will provide a subsidy of 500,000 yuan within five years. The following year, she applied for scientific research funds from the Chengdu Agricultural Science and Technology Talent Cultivation Program. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Right now, a laboratory in the institute is filled with freeze-dried fruit and vegetable solid drinks developed by Liu Hongyan’s team, and a whitening and moisturizing set containing phloretin. and other technological transformation achievements. This Inner Mongolian native has bought a house and settled in Chengdu. &quot;Currently, Chengdu is the city that best coordinates my work and life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Chengdu Youth Development Report (2022)&quot; released by the Chengdu Municipal Committee of the Communist Youth League and the Chengdu New Economic Development Research Institute shows that the population of &quot;Rongpiao&quot; reaches 6.8349 million. Among them, the proportion of young people from outside Sichuan Province is 21.85%, and the proportion of young people from &quot;Rongpiao&quot; who come from outside the province is 32.9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rongpiao Youth Talent Station, Jinjiang District, Chengdu. Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/c8611cc39a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/c8611cc39a.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;259915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rongpiao Youth Talent Station, Jinjiang District, Chengdu City. (Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Camping in the city, looking at the snow-capped mountains on the rooftop&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is little research in Hu Peng’s life dictionary Such lofty words as institute and laboratory. He is just an ordinary person who loves life. In Chengdu, he felt another attraction of this city for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;30-year-old Hu Peng is from Leshan, Sichuan. He works as a tour guide in Chengdu, taking tourists to appreciate the different flavors of the city, including city gates, city walls, streets, and museums. , listen to historical stories and observe the lifestyle of local residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He has developed two niche routes, one from the small city in the west of the city to Fuqin, and the other from New Er Village in the north of the city to Caojiaxiang. In Fuqin, he had seen a cup of tea costing 3 yuan, and a bowl of noodles costing 89 yuan. The old man went out to eat noodles and drink tea in the morning, and sat there all day, feeling relaxed and happy. In Xiner Village, &quot;the size of the community is the size of the market.&quot; The market men and women lingered in the market in the morning, and he felt a vibrant beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Young people can always find the livable side of Chengdu. Science fiction writer Huo Zhongwu came to Chengdu in 2005 to study at university and settled here after graduation. He enjoys the pleasant cost of living here. Similarly, renting an apartment near the city center is about a quarter of that in Shanghai. A &quot;Rongpiao&quot; young man admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that one of the important reasons why he came to Chengdu to work three years ago was that Chengdu&#39;s housing prices are extremely cost-effective among provincial capital cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Have fun&quot; is a business card of Chengdu. Huo Zhongwu’s observation is that life in Chengdu is much slower than in first-tier cities, and there are always people in the teahouses and cafes on the roadside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bai Ben was deeply impressed by a salon at the World Science Fiction Convention. A writer mentioned that he had seen a netizen post asking: It will be rare to have sunny weather in Chengdu tomorrow. Does anyone want to go to a high-rise building to watch the snow-capped mountains together? The writer went to the top of the building the next day, and many people were waiting for them. “This kind of thing is hard to imagine in other cities,” Bai Ben said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has also captured the needs of talents for urban environment and quality of life. In 2022, Chengdu will launch the &quot;Talent New Deal 3.0&quot; version with excellent platforms and ecological management, attracting more young talents to take the initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When the water accumulates, fish gather&lt;span>;, and when trees grow thicker, birds gather.&quot; The relevant person in charge of the Talent Office of Chengdu Municipal Party Committee introduced that Chengdu has been We strive to protect the value attribution of talents with the highest quality services and create a value ecosystem where everyone is seen, respected and cared for. What can be proved is that Chengdu has been ranked first in &quot;China&#39;s happiest city&quot; for 14 consecutive years, ranked first in &quot;Fortune&quot; magazine&#39;s &quot;Attractive Cities for College Students and Young Job Seekers&quot;, and won &quot;China&#39;s Best Talent Attracting City&quot; for 4 consecutive years. &quot;prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Talent work is ultimately inseparable from improving the quality of the city.&quot; For example, in order to cater to young people&#39;s fun-loving and quality-of-life mentality, Chengdu continues to optimize its environment , a 100-kilometer first-level greenway of the Ring Ecological Park has been built inside and outside the city ring expressway, with billowing green wheat fields, lush grassland, and swaying woods; while building a park city, Chengdu has opened up a large number of wetlands and green spaces As a camping site, &quot;everyone goes camping and basking in the sun on weekends&quot;, creating a new picture of urban life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 3, 2023, a unique &quot;underwater bookstore&quot; next to Xinglong Lake, a famous internet celebrity check-in place in Chengdu. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/238c595079.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/28/238c595079.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9, 2023 On March 3, Chengdu’s famous internet celebrity check-in place was a unique “underwater bookstore” next to Xinglong Lake. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Resonance among young people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu’s life scene that attracts young people also includes abundant public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The streets and alleys here hide &lt;span>;three&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thousand&lt;/span>; more than one bookstore, far more than any other city in the country. It is difficult to count the number of public activities that are closely connected to it - reading clubs, movie viewing parties, script screenings, and sharing by scholars and experts. Some active spaces can host hundreds of events a year. The event was small in scale, with only twenty or thirty people at most, but it provided an opportunity for connection and resonance for countless young people eager to express, share, and see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 2015, Wang Miaomiao worked as an account manager for a brand company in Chengdu. At that time, she fell into depression for a time due to family reasons. She began to participate in a large number of offline public activities and spent three or four nights a week in various sharing sessions. Although most of the time, she couldn&#39;t understand what the sharer was saying, she liked the friendly and warm atmosphere, which allowed her to temporarily escape the pain in her life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Product manager Di Hao came to Chengdu to work in 2016. At the beginning, he couldn&#39;t find anyone he could play with, whether at work or in life. A year later, he saw the activities of the Toastmasters Club in the same city on Douban and tried to participate. Since then, he has been hooked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He has vivid memories of many activities. During the reading party, they read Tolstoy to understand human greed; after the movie viewing party, someone explained Plato&#39;s Allegory of the Cave. Once, scholar Wang Di came to a tavern in the suburbs of Chengdu to share. More than a hundred people came and &lt;span>;Wang Di&lt;/span>; talked until midnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Di Hao felt that the young friends who participated in the event gave him a sense of belonging. These activities also opened up a new world for Di Hao. In the past, when facing big figures, he had a sense of order based on distinction between superiority and inferiority. The egalitarian atmosphere of public activities gradually made him accustomed to dealing with others as an equal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After 2018, Hu Peng also often went to Chengdu to participate in public events. In his early years, he met a Polish man and a British man at a sharing meeting. They worked for a few months a year, teaching English and doing project planning, and the rest of the time was spent traveling around. This way of life surprised him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Peng prides himself on being a young man from a small town, having graduated with a bachelor&#39;s degree. Many people in his hometown have nothing to do in their spare time except playing cards. These activities made him realize that there was another possibility in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Also in 2018, Wang Miaomiao, who has participated in numerous public activities, became the director of Xunlu Library. This is a community library, but it aspires to become a &quot;humanistic beacon&quot;. Wang Miaomiao discovered that people lacked general education, so he invited professors from Sichuan University to come to the library to teach general education courses about Du Fu and visual culture. She listened to lawyer Zhang Ying&#39;s &quot;Bright Dialogue&quot; series of public debates and thought it was good, and invited Zhang Ying to the library for a discussion on psychology. Some participants said that these discussions responded to the rising enthusiasm for psychology since the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Miaomiao feels that these public lives have reshaped her life. She likes to study people and society, and is curious about where strong vitality is born, and the sharers &lt;span>;also&lt;/span>; responded to her questions in their own ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, she will become busier. Offline activities in Chengdu are very prosperous. In addition to creating more in-depth public activity content, she also needs to run a &quot;reclamation community&quot; that unites participants with reading as the core. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this corner of the southwest, public space is so prosperous, and Hu Peng connects it with the characteristics of the city. Chengdu has a tradition of chatting in teahouses and cafes. In addition, maybe many busy young people have rushed to first -tier cities such as Bei, Shang, Guang, and came to Chengdu&#39;s &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; young people to pursue spiritual filling and &lt;span>; longing &lt;/span>; a better life. They find resonance in Chengdu and at the same time inject new vitality into Chengdu&#39;s public life. People and cities always choose and nourish each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Rong and Di Hao are pseudonyms, Bai Ben and Huo Zhongwu are pen names)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>