<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[全国人大代表萧志伟：澳门可以发挥“精准联系人”的角色]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261850]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[辽宁大连旅顺口老铁山水域一钓鱼艇涉险 已致4人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261866]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 18:48:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At about 23:00 on December 3, the Dalian Maritime Search and Rescue Center received an alarm. The &quot;Shuiyuan 69&quot; fishing boat was Contact was lost in the waters of Laotieshan, Lushunkou, Dalian, and there were 7 people on the fishing boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, as of 5:30 on December 4, the Dalian Maritime Search and Rescue Center organized 1 professional rescue ship, 5 maritime, coast guard, and fishery law enforcement ships, and 1 social ship. , 3 fishing boats and 3 passing boats searched the waters at the scene. After all-out search and rescue efforts, as of 10:10 on December 4, 4 people had been found dead and 3 others were still being searched and rescued. Currently, the maritime search and rescue force is searching the sea area where the incident occurred based on the drift prediction model, and the Lushun Wanzhong Emergency Rescue Team is searching the land area at the junction of sea and land based on the drift model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After preliminary verification, the seven people on board reported to the maritime department that they were going fishing, and the vessel was registered as owned by individuals. Relevant departments are investigating the circumstances surrounding the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大闸蟹在英国泛滥成灾，吃蟹大户上海人酸了慕了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261840]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/04/562ce5f544472e6f5cadf4c0f40e761a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;6406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/04/562ce5f544472e6f5cadf4c0f40e761a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/ 04/180ff81a20b3c2af8f45cfeeeca3fa76.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;7707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/04/180ff81a20b3c2af8f45cfeeeca3fa76.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/ 9f16f9bcb779852119c6ef069d8ce2db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;10377&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/ 04/9f16f9bcb779852119c6ef069d8ce2db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[易会满：全力维护资本市场平稳运行，更好发挥资本市场枢纽功能]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261854]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 17:26:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/04/271dd016d0e5649128ac1a1b298e3a8b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;7034&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/04/271dd016d0e5649128ac1a1b298e3a8b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recently held Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that the hub function of the capital market should be better utilized and the stock issuance registration system should be promoted in depth and depth. Reality. How does the China Securities Regulatory Commission implement the relevant arrangements of the Central Financial Work Conference? How to better support the high-quality development of the real economy? How to promote the smooth and healthy operation of the capital market? A reporter from Xinhua News Agency conducted an exclusive interview with Yi Huiman, Secretary and Chairman of the Party Committee of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Speedly formulate a policy framework for building a modern capital market with Chinese characteristics&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference made arrangements for &quot;accelerating the construction of a financial power&quot; and &quot;promoting high-quality financial development in my country&quot;. How will the China Securities Regulatory Commission implement it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Since the meeting, we have focused on comprehensively implementing the spirit of the meeting and accelerating the construction of a safe, standardized, transparent, open, dynamic and resilient The capital market has planned a series of implementation measures. To sum up, it is to grasp &quot;one main line&quot; and achieve &quot;three highlights&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;one main line&quot; is to strengthen political leadership. Adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, deeply grasp the political and people-oriented nature of capital market supervision, strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership over the capital market, especially maintain the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and strengthen the political functions of party organizations at all levels and organizational functions, and effectively implement the party’s leadership into all areas and aspects of capital market work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three highlights&quot;: First, highlight the main responsibilities and main business. Comprehensively strengthen the main responsibilities and main businesses of supervision, improve supervision efficiency, improve the source prevention and control of risks in key areas of the capital market, secure the bottom line of risks, and build a solid foundation for the healthy development of the capital market. The second is to highlight the deepening of reform. Adhere to promoting capital market reform and innovation on the track of marketization and rule of law, strive to solve the outstanding problems of imbalance and inadequacy in the capital market, better utilize the hub function of the capital market that affects the whole body, and provide high-quality services to the real economy and investors. services. The third is to highlight self-revolution. Adhere to the principle of turning the blade inward, promote comprehensive and strict governance of the party in the China Securities Regulatory Commission system, make greater efforts to promote the normalization and long-term effectiveness of central inspection and rectification, and forge a team of high-quality professional cadres who are loyal, clean and responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, we are following the central government’s deployment and focusing on the above aspects to formulate a policy framework for building a modern capital market with Chinese characteristics. We will adhere to the principle of mature one and launch one, and solidly promote the implementation to achieve results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Introduce more pragmatic measures around improving the functions of the capital market&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference clearly stated that &quot;adhere to the fundamental purpose of financial services to the real economy&quot; and &quot;better play the hub function of the capital market.&quot; What specific considerations does the China Securities Regulatory Commission have in supporting high-quality development of the real economy? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Better giving play to the hub function of the capital market is the new positioning given to the capital market by the Party Central Committee in the new era and new journey. The capital market is not a large financial market, but it has unique advantages in serving the real economy. First, capital market information is highly transparent and price signals are sensitive. It is an important channel for resource allocation and policy transmission. Second, the capital market has the characteristics of risk sharing and benefit sharing, which can promote and improve corporate governance and effectively stimulate social innovation, creativity and entrepreneurship. Third, it can optimize the financing structure and help stabilize the macro leverage ratio. Fourth, the capital market covers a wealth of investment and financing tools such as stocks and bonds, as well as on and off-market, and can meet the diversified financial needs of the real economy and investors. In the next step, we will adhere to a problem-oriented approach, be honest and innovative, and launch more pragmatic measures around improving the functions of the capital market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, promote the deepening and solidification of the stock issuance registration system. We should unswervingly adhere to the concept of information disclosure as the core, adhere to the basic structure of the registration system, and increase support for key areas such as high-level scientific and technological self-reliance and the construction of modern industrial systems. Increase efforts to promote investment-side reforms, attract more medium and long-term funds to enter the market, dynamically optimize institutional arrangements such as IPO pricing, refinancing, and shareholding reduction, and promote the dynamic balance of investment and financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, improve the multi-level capital market system. Actively develop diversified equity financing, adhere to the positioning of each exchange sector, support the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges in building world-class exchanges, build the Beijing Stock Exchange with high quality, promote the New Third Board and regional equity market system and business innovation, and better Give full play to the active role of private equity venture capital funds and further improve the progressive market structure. Promote the high-quality development of the bond market and promote the expansion and quality improvement of the real estate investment trust funds (REITs) market. Develop futures and derivatives markets in a prudent and orderly manner to help increase the influence of commodity prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, vigorously improve the quality of listed companies. The &quot;barometer&quot; function of the capital market is mainly reflected through listed companies. Last year, more than 5,000 listed companies achieved an added value of more than 18.23 trillion yuan, accounting for 15.1% of GDP, and their R&amp;D investment accounted for 50% of the national R&amp;D expenditure. We will solidly promote the implementation of a new three-year action plan to improve the quality of listed companies and highlight the construction of corporate governance with Chinese characteristics. Optimize mergers and acquisitions, equity incentives, dividends and other institutional arrangements, improve the normalized delisting mechanism, supervise listed companies to standardize governance and operate with integrity, support more listed companies to become better and stronger, and drive collaboration between upstream and downstream industrial and supply chains, as well as large and medium-sized enterprises. development, helping to consolidate the micro-foundation for high-quality economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, promote high-level institutional opening up of the capital market. Coordinate opening and security, steadily promote the three-dimensional opening of markets, institutions, and businesses, deepen and expand interconnection, facilitate cross-border investment and financing, and simultaneously strengthen the construction of regulatory capabilities under open conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Efforts to maintain the stable operation of the capital market&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Central Financial The working meeting emphasized the need to comprehensively strengthen financial supervision and effectively prevent and resolve financial risks. Everyone is very concerned about the stable and healthy operation of the capital market. What measures will the China Securities Regulatory Commission take in this regard? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Strengthening supervision and preventing risks are important guarantees for high-quality financial development. In recent years, we have adhered to the regulatory philosophy of &quot;respecting the market, respecting the rule of law, respecting professionalism, respecting risks, and leveraging the joint efforts of all parties&quot;, and resolutely fought the battle to prevent and resolve major financial risks. Risks in key areas of the capital market have continued to converge and are generally controllable. In the next step, we will focus on improving regulatory adaptability and pertinence to create a more favorable environment for the reform and development of the capital market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, make every effort to maintain the stable operation of the capital market. Calm sea makes sailing easier. We will strengthen the monitoring of stock market trading behavior and capital flows, and establish and improve a comprehensive risk analysis and early warning mechanism. Improve the countercyclical adjustment mechanism in the primary and secondary markets, encourage and guide listed companies to repurchase and shareholders to increase their holdings, and give full play to the inherent market stabilizing role of various business entities. Improve the emergency response mechanism to maintain the stability of the capital market, strengthen hierarchical consultation and rapid response, and maintain the bottom line of risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to implement the main responsibilities of supervision and the main business. Adhere to early identification, early warning, early exposure, and early disposal, strive to improve the ability to catch small companies early, and strengthen the source management of potential risks such as capital occupation by major shareholders, excessive leverage, and lack of isolation between industrial capital and financial capital. Improve the anti-counterfeiting and anti-counterfeiting mechanism in the capital market, improve the administrative, civil and criminal three-dimensional accountability system, and use &quot;zero tolerance&quot; to crack down on fraudulent issuances, financial fraud, market manipulation and other illegal activities. At the same time, we will work with relevant parties to prevent the transmission and resonance of real estate risks, local debt risks and financial risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to resolutely eliminate the regulatory vacuum. Strengthen regulatory coordination, bring all types of securities activities under supervision in accordance with the law, severely crack down on &quot;fake private placements&quot;, and clean up and rectify gold exchanges and &quot;fake gold exchanges.&quot; Collaborate with relevant departments to strengthen monitoring and supervision of debt risks of large enterprise groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to strengthen supervision capacity building. Implement the party and state institutional reform tasks, improve internal coordination mechanisms, and effectively improve the effectiveness of supervision. At the same time, we will strengthen the construction of regulatory technology, strengthen cross-departmental information sharing, and improve the level of digital intelligence to provide stronger support for regulatory performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[ESG宇宙繁荣背后有泡沫？我们应关注什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261852]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 17:41:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every decade people see one or two buzzwords that may have been overhyped. During discussions and dissemination, the meaning of the word itself may lose focus, and different interpreters may join in, bringing in different understandings. It seems that it is an all-encompassing semantic kaleidoscope, anyone can interpret it, and it can explain everything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, in the business field, ESG has a tendency to become such a term, and it is beginning to appear a bubble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Picture source: Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f19cb2de39.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;861&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f19cb2de39.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260678&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Picture source: Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to clarify misunderstandings and guide the direction, Xiangguangnian will be held on November 28-29, 2023 The conference was held in Shenzhen, with the theme of &quot;Value Innovation of ESG and Sustainable Development - ESG Ecological Conference&quot;, bringing together experts and institutions in the field of ESG and sustainable development to build ESG information disclosure, sustainable finance, corporate sustainable strategy, management We will hold forums on multiple topics such as gender diversity to understand the series of phenomena and issues behind the prosperity of ESG, return to the origin, reaffirm the value, and start again on a better footing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The bubble behind the prosperity of the ESG universe&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To put it simply, ESG is the abbreviation of Environmental (Environmental), Social (Social), and Governance (Governance). Enterprises are evaluated from these three dimensions. The sustainability of business activities is also a method of identifying non-financial risks and opportunities for enterprises. In the capital market, investors use ESG standards to screen companies and determine investment plans, which is called ESG investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It requires not only evaluating the development capabilities of enterprises from a financial perspective, but also follows the concepts of corporate social responsibility and corporate citizenship. However, because it clarifies the three dimensions of environment, governance, and society, it is compared with related concepts. It is clearer and more direct; it also includes a set of simple and easy-to-understand indicators and disclosure methods, which is more operational for corporate practice and more instrumental for investors. Therefore, with the trend of &quot;catch up from behind&quot;, it is gradually being adopted by more and more people. It is accepted and widely used by enterprises, regulators and investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a well-functioning ESG universe, regulatory authorities regulate corporate behavior through laws and regulations, guide companies to accurately disclose information, improve ESG performance, and promote healthy market operation; third parties such as rating agencies sift through massive amounts of information. Enterprises with excellent comprehensive performance in social, environmental, governance, etc. and low risks are given indexes, rankings or reputations; investors make corresponding investment decisions based on the purpose of promoting sustainable development and combining different evaluation information; enterprises internally Consciously and externally driven, we will continue to improve ESG performance and realize the co-creation of economic and social values ​​- the light of business will shine into dark corners, so that the weak will be helped, the environment will be sustainable, and the benefits will be shared...&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;ESG universe ecological map picture drawing: Kanghua&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/906124ae9d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;801&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/906124ae9d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260679 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;ESG universe ecological map&amp;nbsp;Picture drawn by: Kang Hua&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the vision that everyone is looking forward to, but Reality is complex and full of contradictions. At the &quot;ESG and Corporate Financing Innovation&quot; forum at the Xiangguang ESG Ecological Conference, Zhang Yalong, executive director of the Shenzhen Institute of Sustainable Development, pointed out some contradictions:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;On the investment side, green finance , ESG innovative financial products have emerged one after another, but some products are still in a &quot;self-promotion&quot; state. The products are implemented in a limited scope and limited areas under policy guidance. The project investment returns are low, and the relationship between the sustainable values ​​of the parties is unclear;&lt;/ em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;In practice, companies not only want to overtake through ESG corners, but are also subject to &quot;being rated&quot;, focusing more on information disclosure and failing to realize the relationship between ESG work, operation and development. relationship, rarely combining business strategies with social and economic sustainable development requirements;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;On the evaluation side, evaluation results and scores are often quoted, but different institutions There is no correlation between the results; and some evaluators do not have an in-depth understanding of corporate management and practical logic, and are not familiar with industry risks and opportunities, which makes it difficult to get recognition for the evaluations given to companies;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;em>;On the industry side, the ESG ecosystem is growing day by day, but the professional capabilities of the majority of practitioners are uneven and lack the ability to integrate disciplines and collaborate. There are many problems such as those who understand investment but do not understand ESG practices, and those who are familiar with ESG practices do not understand finance. , resulting in a disconnect between ESG work and business development. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind these contradictions are the objective factors that ESG itself still needs to continue to grow, and the subjective reasons that the purposes and demands of all parties in the ESG ecological chain are not unified. The two interact with each other, causing bubbles behind prosperity. Ascend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;If there is a bubble, is there no value?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Take the controversial ESG rating as an example. People’s doubts about it mainly focus on whether the rating results can truly reflect the sustainable development capabilities of the company. , whether it can be used as a sustainable investment suggestion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Xiangguang ESG Ecology Conference, Wei Juchang, a professor at the School of Public Affairs at the University of Science and Technology of China, announced a study on 6 domestic and foreign mainstream ESG rating agencies. The results showed that the evaluation results of different rating agencies were different. There is no correlation between them, and there is a significant difference in the magnitude of score changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The difference in rating results is affected by the rating agency’s evaluation indicators, evaluation weights, data acquisition sources, and update frequency,” explained Zhang Bohui, Executive Dean of the School of Economics and Management at the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), “But this It does not mean that they have no reference value.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is a good thing that more and more companies pay attention to ESG ratings. It means that they have to start caring about the sustainable development concept behind them and want to increase their recognition in this area. degree, recognition, and competitive advantage. It is recommended that companies should not simply focus on rating scores, but regard ratings as a tool for self-improvement, communicate more with different rating agencies, observe their own behavior from the other party&#39;s perspective, and make targeted improvements. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Improvements in ESG performance can not only improve ratings and expand financing, but also bring substantial benefits.” Zhang Bohui said, “In the United States, there are already companies using artificial intelligence to analyze ESG performance. See which indicators can improve performance in the short term, and then increase investment in those indicators. Therefore, we recommend that companies collect and disclose ESG data and accumulate a certain amount of data, which will help with correlation analysis and better identification. Risks and judgment of growth opportunities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of information disclosure, although ESG disclosure has problems such as inconsistent calibers, inconsistent standards, insufficient comparability, and greenwashing, as supervision becomes stricter, With the expansion of coverage, the quality of data disclosure and the value of data applications will be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Xiaoliang, Chair Professor of the Business School of Southern University of Science and Technology, pointed out that research shows that investors in areas with more ESG information disclosure tend to have greater confidence in the stock market, especially areas where the media pays special attention to ESG information. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although mandatory ESG information disclosure will increase corporate costs and reduce corporate profits in the short term,” Zeng Xiaoliang said, “it will have a positive impact on the environment and society, and will also have a long-term impact on the company. Positive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A series of academic studies have proven that as ESG performance improves, the company&#39;s operating performance will also improve. Value = expected cash flow - uncertainty, uncertainty between revenue and cost decline, the possibility of resisting negative impacts increases, and the value of the enterprise naturally increases.&quot; Professor Zhang Bohui further explained the economic value of ESG from the perspective of cost vs. risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first criticism of ESG investment is that its screening rules are confusing and its name is not worthy of its name. The second is that the returns are not high and the returns are low. Li Wei, managing partner of Songhe Capital Management Co., Ltd., believes that this is a tortuous development process that ESG investment needs to go through. Take technology investment as an example. For more than ten years, technology investment has been moving in waves. When the waves are high, there are many bubbles. As time goes by, there is a gradual clearing process, and eventually real technology innovation companies win investment favor and grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Having bubbles is not necessarily a bad thing. Just like beer, if you don’t give you bubbles, you will think that the merchant is fake; if you give you too much bubbles, you will think that the merchant is too black-hearted. Bubbles represent people’s attention, and people An imagination of the future development direction.&quot; Li Wei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to make it work better&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;ESG is &quot;popular&quot;, but whether it can be &quot;built to last&quot; and have lasting vitality depends on whether it can help companies solve problems Question, create value, and whether the way of value creation is consistent with the objective reality of the enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, behind the huge noise, there is still a lack of operational management tools and scalable models. ESG ratings, lists, and awards are booming, and there are many excellent practices and innovative projects among them. However, there are few refining, analyzing, and applying guidance on excellent models from the perspectives of policy, management, finance, technology, etc. It would be difficult to change a company or industry. The inability to put it on the ground makes the value of ESG like a castle in the air, visible but intangible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, when talking about outstanding ESG companies and projects, more focus is placed on large companies and projects, and insufficient attention is paid to small, medium and micro enterprises. A survey shows that 64% of small and medium-sized enterprises believe that the biggest difficulty in implementing ESG is the lack of relevant knowledge and funds. What they need most is financial support, industry guidance and talent training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everyone is too impatient,” Zhang Yalong said. “We must face up to a series of problems in ESG applications. By building a platform, an ESG working group will be formed by the government, financial institutions, media, enterprises and other relevant parties. We track and serve several types of companies for a long time, identify and solve problems, and determine the company&#39;s medium and long-term ESG development model, thereby empowering corporate growth and making substantial contributions to the sustainable development of communities and cities.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In fact, such innovative platforms are already being explored. In June 2023, the Monetary Authority of Singapore and the United Nations Development Program launched &quot;Project Savannah&quot; to use digital tools to help small, medium and micro enterprises around the world simplify the ESG reporting process, generate certified ESG data certificates, and help small and medium-sized enterprises. Microenterprises deliver key ESG data to business partners, thereby enhancing their ability to access global financing and supply chain opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hong Kong, in response to the sustainable development requirements of small, medium and micro enterprises, the Hong Kong Trade Development Council has launched the &quot;T-box Upgrading and Transformation Plan&quot; with professional organizations, chambers of commerce and enterprises, introducing ESG support projects to help small and medium-sized enterprises implement ESG Integrate into business and use innovative technology to solve inherent problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the shortcomings in ESG and financial talent, the Hong Kong SAR government launched the &quot;Green and Sustainable Finance Training Pilot Program&quot;, allocating HK$200 million to subsidize local qualified people to participate in green and sustainable finance-related training , to expand the local talent pool to support the development of green and sustainable finance in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the importance of a good ESG ecosystem is recognized by more and more relevant parties, more similar platforms are gradually being established to provide substantial help to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let better business light the way forward&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When something is given too much attention, too high expectations, and too much value, it is not far from disillusionment . ESG is still growing. Its connotation coincides with a series of development themes such as national high-quality development, new urbanization construction, protecting ecological civilization, promoting common prosperity, and governing enterprises according to law. This is why it has attracted huge attention at present. , the reason for releasing widespread influence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for it to go further as a methodology, a guide, and a tool, relevant parties in the ESG ecosystem need to exert the power of aggregation, expand theory with innovative research, and inspire practice with scientific evaluation. , benefit the society with solid actions, avoid being eager for quick success and short-sightedness, and maintain the unity of words and deeds with a more peaceful mind, a more open attitude, and a more caring mind. We will implement, expand, and extend our practice step by step, and promote the light of business to a brighter future. Many places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[路遥的土地：从王家堡到郭家沟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261838]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Old photos of Lu Yao. Data map&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/bd488f6744.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/04/bd488f6744.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260616&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Old photos of Lu Yao. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been thirty-one years since Lu Yao left us. I have written many articles about Lu Yao. This time I will talk about the land where he was born and raised, and the people on that land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always believed in the existence of destiny, and everyone lives in his own destiny. If God wants to create a character, he will suffer a lot and give him a lot of experiences. If you can&#39;t withstand these blows, you will fall on the road, and God will look for new candidates. If you can withstand these hardships, you will become stronger by treating these sufferings as spiritual nutrition and milk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao was not defeated by the difficulties of life, and carried out overloaded literary creation with strong perseverance, and became a &quot;chosen son&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao has a consciousness that will never allow him to remain mediocre. Once mediocre, he will return to the living state of his ancestors, &quot;facing the loess and turning his back to the sky.&quot; The local energy accumulated by a family for several generations, or even dozens of generations, finally gives birth to such a character, who will be beaten back to his original shape and return to the original class at any time. Writing is a kind of self-salvation for Lu Yao. All the ascending channels in the world are blocked, and only a pen can change destiny. Every time he published a work and every award he won, he escaped from that tragic fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Lu Yao passed away, I was the last person to visit him. As soon as I left, Linda came to sign the divorce agreement. As soon as Linda left, Lu Yao passed out. After resuscitation for two days and two nights, he finally died. In Lu Yao&#39;s ward, I wrote this on the prescription: Brother Lu Yao, I heard from Zhao Xi that your illness has turned around. You are a strong person. Remember you said you are invincible! All your friends are praying for you. You can definitely cross this threshold. Your good friend and brother Gao Jianqun, at 10:30 am on November 15, 1992. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the tenth anniversary of Lu Yao&#39;s death, the world was quiet, without any sound. Only Professor Liu Lu of Shaanxi Normal University held a memorial service at the school and invited Lu Yao’s daughter Yuan Yuan (now named Lu Mingming). I spoke on behalf of the Provincial Federation of Literary and Art Circles and the Provincial Writers Association. I said to the child, Lu Yao hopes that you will play football when you grow up, even if your leg is broken, you will kick the ball into the net with your leg. The child took my hand and said a little shyly that I was weak and did not choose to play football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have basically read all the county annals in northern Shaanxi. I was commissioned by the Yan&#39;an City Editorial Committee to draft the preface to the &quot;Yan&#39;an City Chronicle&quot; that year in the Yan&#39;an area. Reading through these county annals made me understand that the history of the Northern Shaanxi Plateau is half a history of hunger, half a history of war, and the whole is a history of suffering! Lu Yao also felt this way back then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The severe drought caused by Li Zicheng during the Chongzhen period of the Ming Dynasty is still often talked about by people in northern Shaanxi. The severe drought in Shaanxi in 1929 was worse than the severe drought during the Chongzhen period. In northern Shaanxi, 70% of the ten people starved to death. The people called this the &quot;New Year&#39;s Eve of the Eighteenth Year of the Republic of China.&quot; It is recorded in the county annals that there was a severe drought and people ate each other and exchanged their children for food. I have children and I can’t bear to eat them. You have children and you can’t eat them. Exchange them with each other and cook them. There is a folk song circulating in rural areas of northern Shaanxi: &quot;People eat people, dogs eat dogs, uncles cook nephews in the pot, and father-in-law cooks sons-in-law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yanchuan County Chronicle records a conflict during the Tongzhi period, which was as tragic as a war. Some counties disappeared from the map. Gulin County, which was briefly restored during the Yan&#39;an period, became Nanniwan later. Here you can reclaim wasteland and grow rice. The reason why there was no population for a time may be due to the conflict during the Tongzhi period. The population on this land was exterminated, the fields were barren, and the administrative system was abolished. The conflict extended from the Xiuyan River Basin to the Wuding River Basin, and the situation in many counties was even worse. There are still many legends circulating in the local area. Hengshan County used to be called Huaiyuan, and there was a village called Zhangjiapan. It was said that everyone on the ground was dead. The two sons of a family named Zhang went to the salt pond to sell salt and escaped death. After returning, the Zhang family was rebuilt on the original site and the later Zhang family was formed. Zhangjiapan is today’s Jingbian County. In the early years, salt merchants went to Yanchi and Dingbian to sell salt from Qingyang Chagou to Zhangjiapan. Folk song from northern Shaanxi: I got up from Zhangjiapan, stood at Liujiamao, and looked at me kissing people at the bottom of Maojia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I lived in Fu County when I was a child. When I was a child, I went up to the mountains to cut firewood. I often turned around a mountain col and passed through a small forest. I found a kiln courtyard with neat cave dwellings and a rolling mill in front of the kiln. It had been abandoned for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yanchuan County Chronicle records that after the county seat was breached, the county magistrate drew his sword and committed suicide, and the county magistrate&#39;s wife committed suicide by jumping into a well. The common people were almost exterminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, people fleeing from famine and famine, and refugees from neighboring provinces slowly filled the river road. Until 1940, the government of the Shaanxi-Gansu-Ningxia Border Region was still calling for immigrants to this area. It can be seen that at that time, the Yanchuan area had not yet returned to its former prosperity. The king of Wangjiabao in Qingjian came to Yanchuan with his wife and three sons Wang Yude, Wang Yukuan and Wang Yufu, intending to find a good family business for his children and grandchildren. They settled in Guojiagou in Yanchuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zaichao is Lu Yao&#39;s grandfather, Wang Yukuan is Lu Yao&#39;s biological father, and Wang Yude is Lu Yao&#39;s adoptive father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in this desolate wasteland, Lu Yao, like all people in northern Shaanxi, inherited the sense of urgency in the genes of his ancestors, and he had to survive tenaciously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What people in northern Shaanxi say about being hungry and what people in Guanzhong say about being hungry do not mean the same thing. The people in Guanzhong feel hungry after a meal, but the people in northern Shaanxi say they are hungry, meaning they are struggling on the verge of death! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an old proverb in northern Shaanxi: A pig has three liters of chaff on its head! Once a person is born, he has the right to live. People in northern Shaanxi often say that when a life is born, God will definitely provide him with solid food so that he has something to rely on to survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao has a far-sighted grandfather, who is the guarantee for Lu Yao&#39;s survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I think about Lu Yao’s appearance, I can always think of Attila the Great, one of the three great grassland kings in the world. After the Huns fled to Europe, Emperor Attila swept across Europe and Asia and established the Huns Empire. A priest treated Attila and recorded his appearance in detail: &quot;short stature, broad chest, big head, small eyes, sparse gray beard, flat nose, and uneven body shape.&quot; These are common physical characteristics of the Huns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao looks almost like this. He is of medium height, with a round face, brown skin, and a slightly flat nose. He often squints his eyes to look at things, as if he is afraid of seeing the light, and looks forward. The book &quot;Steppe Empire&quot; describes Attila the Great, &quot;Standing on the bank of the Danube, squinting his small eyes, staring at the continent of Europe, ready to swallow it into his belly at any time. Standing on the ground is very ordinary, once he jumps on the horse&#39;s back, he will be with the horse. Form a fighting unit and become instantly vicious and unstoppable.&quot; Lu Yao&#39;s arms are thick and powerful, very strong, and his lower limbs are a bit shorter and a bit introverted. If you have a beard all over your face, including your nostrils and ears, especially the ears, if you don’t cut them for two days, the hair will grow out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao&#39;s biological father is one size younger than Lu Yao. Lu Yao is 1.68 meters tall, and his biological father should be about 1.6 meters tall. A bouncing little old man, wearing a white hat on his head, which has become less white after being washed frequently due to exposure to wind and sun, and a pipe pot on his shoulder. There are many such little old men in Suimi, Yanchuan and Qingjian areas, and they are all very smart. During the Yan&#39;an period, Guo Hongtao, who served as the secretary of the Shaanxi-Gansu-Ningxia Border Region, looked like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Helianbobo died one year before Tongwan City was destroyed, and his burial should be very beautiful. There are many theories about his tomb. The currently recognized tomb site is Baifutu Temple in Yanchuan County. It is very possible that the Luyao family has Huns genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao’s adoptive father is similar to the image of most old farmers in northern Shaanxi. He is tall, about 1.7 meters tall, with a good and straight figure, long cheeks, a high nose bridge, and a full beard. He wears an Aries belly towel on his head and a dry tobacco bag on his shoulders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao&#39;s second brother is a little taller than Lu Yao, about 1.72 meters tall, and he is serious in speech. I&#39;ve been here a few times, and I always wear a hat on my head. He originally worked in a factory in Xi&#39;an, but later Lu Yao was contacted to work as a city manager in Yan&#39;an Erdao Street. He wore a uniform and was clean-shaven, and his name was Wang Weijun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Tianyun is Lu Yao&#39;s third brother. He is small and has lived in my office several times. He is also a figure. I said, I have to go to work during the day, and you go for a walk on the street. At night, when I get off work, you come and stay. My office is on the second floor of Bo Keer Cave House. The stairs on the first and second floors are lined with brickwork walls. After editing the manuscript for a long time, I came out to smoke and relax. I saw this old man standing in front of the brick wall on the second floor, with his hands on his hips and his hair messy. He looked like a great man, pointing the country and looking down on the world. I laughed, walked up and said, if you didn&#39;t study well or write well when you were a child, look at your brother Lu Yao, he has become a great writer. The third child said something astonishing: I just can’t stand what he does for a living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao also has a younger sister who married in Yan&#39;an. Three years ago, I went to Yan&#39;an Study College to give a lecture. The leader of Yan&#39;an brought a middle-aged woman over and said that she claimed to be Lu Yao&#39;s sister. You can judge for us. I said, girl, did you grow up in Yanchuan or Qingjian? She said Qingjian. I said that when you were the production captain, you led the commune members to cut down dozens of trees beside the national highway and had them captured by the commune. Do you know this? The middle-aged woman said, I know this. I even gave me a meal. Later, my brother found someone to fish me out! I smiled and said, your brother asked Zhang Tao to fish for it. In this way, I told the leaders of Yan&#39;an that it was absolutely true, this was sister Lu Yao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Tianle is the fourth child, and the name Wang Tianle was given by Lu Yao. His original name was Houman. Wang Tianle recruited workers to work as miners in Tongchuan Coal Mine, which was the quota given by my father. My sister jumped in line in the countryside and found a villager. This was the quota she asked for, but he didn&#39;t go. Seeing that the check-in time was coming, I asked for this indicator and gave it to Tianle. My father was the executive deputy mayor of (small) Yan&#39;an City at the time. I have told many of his stories before, so I won’t repeat them here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth child is called Jiu Wa. Counting Lu Yao’s brothers and sisters together, there are nine. This is the youngest. When I went to Yulin, he came to see me several times and said that he wanted to set up a &quot;Luyao Research Society&quot; and asked me to be the president. I told you I was inappropriate. He also said, let me tell the leaders of Yulin and give them support. I wholeheartedly agreed. Later I told Zhou Bo. I also wrote him a picture: The Last Watcher of Home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao&#39;s biological mother is a very shrewd woman who can be seen everywhere in northern Shaanxi. She is very neat and tidy up. She spit into the palm of her hand, brushed her hair back and forth, and made it smooth. She took care of everything in the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been to Luyao Qingjian’s hometown several times. Around 2001, I was passing by Yulin. From the Chuandao Highway, I walked up the slope to the kiln courtyard. There was a roller in the courtyard, and below it was a waist-high grinding plate. There was a roller on the grinding plate, and there were several trees against the courtyard wall. There are jujube trees and mountain peach trees, and there is a three-hole stone kiln to the south. I was very moved when I saw the three-hole stone kiln. Lu Yao asked Tianle to carry the money back to his hometown of Wangjiapu in Qingjian and built a three-hole stone kiln. I said, Lu Yao, you did the right thing, respect the elderly and improve their living conditions. People in northern Shaanxi say that I owe my son a wife, and my son owes me a coffin. You can do this while they are alive. Really respect the elderly. But Lu Yao said, no, this is not a matter of respecting the elderly, this is a declaration. I put the three-hole interface in the stone kiln and declared to the world: My father’s son is older! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About ten years ago, I went to attend the opening of Lu Yao Memorial Hall. I remember that it was snowing, so I arrived in Yan&#39;an before dark, had some food, and then arrived in Qingjian before twelve o&#39;clock in the evening to live in the county town. The next day I went to Wangjiabao Village in Shizuiyi Town to attend the opening ceremony. I made a speech and had a meal there at noon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Northern Shaanxi has experienced two foreign population impacts in the past hundred years, which have successively changed the concepts of northern Shaanxi people and changed the fate of many northern Shaanxi people. In 1935, the Central Red Army went to northern Shaanxi, and in 1969, educated youth from Beijing went to Yan&#39;an to join the army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People in northern Shaanxi wear old cotton-padded jackets with large crotch pants and a sheep belly towel on their heads. The older ones wear a belt around their waists. Beijing’s educated youth came and brought China’s most cutting-edge fashion. Cloth shoes with plastic soles are the most typical. Educated youths call these slip-ons. They can be worn with the heels raised and worn like slippers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s educated youth arrived in January 1969, during the Lunar New Year. They probably took a train from Beijing to Xi’an and then took a truck to Yan’an. Dozens of cars were sent to Yan&#39;an in a mammoth manner. I was in Fu County at the time and participated in the welcome. I remember that right at the intersection of Tea House, the sky was extremely overcast, the snow was not very heavy, and snow seeds were falling. The northwest wind blew the snow seeds onto my face, which made me feel painful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The newly arrived attire of the educated youth is a cotton monkey, the women wear a flower one, the men wear a blue one, and wear a Lei Feng hat on their head. These newly arrived educated youth seemed to have an innocent curiosity about the countryside. They followed the donkeys on the road and jumped up and down in the cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yao is four years older than me, and many of my friends among them are educated youth from Beijing. Bai Ma&#39;s wife, Bi Yingjie, is from Beijing and jumped in line at Xinshi River in Yichuan. Once a local youth combines with the educated youth, he will immediately have a relatively strong connection with the outside world. Otherwise, he will have to shrink into a cave dwelling, facing the loess and back to the sky, almost like his ancestors for generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked Lu Yao, why do you have to find an educated youth from Beijing? Do you have to find such a reliable rope to climb up to prevent yourself from falling into the mediocre world? Lu Yao replied that he would not rule out this idea. &lt;p>; Cui Haichao, editor Liu Shuan of Northwest University Press, assistant Niu Yanning for help with this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[乔治·布什美中关系基金会主席：美国为何会害怕中国崛起？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261836]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贺州交警警棍砸倒电动车：不应让暴力执法伤害政府公信力丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 14:58:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of a traffic policeman using a baton to knock an electric car driver to the ground has caused intense anger on the Internet. focus on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is circulating on the Internet is a picture captured by a camera in a shop along the street. The video showed that on the road outside the door, a man in a traffic police uniform waved a stick in his hand and smashed it down hard. An electric car fell to the ground. The driver fell to the ground and hugged his legs, unable to stand up. Another video showed a man being carried on a stretcher into an ambulance, with a heavily armed police officer standing next to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This video quickly aroused public doubts about the violent law enforcement of the traffic police. On November 30, the traffic police in Hezhou, Guangxi issued a notice admitting that the incident took place in the city. They said that the traffic police were conducting traffic violations at the time. A man drove an unlicensed electric vehicle to evade inspection. The police officers used batons during the interception. The electric vehicle lost control and the driver fell to the ground and was injured. The report also stated that the police supervision department has been organized to investigate the incident, and the traffic police involved have been suspended from duty and will be dealt with seriously in accordance with the law and disciplines based on the investigation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar violent law enforcement incidents have been repeatedly exposed, and this is not the first time that violent law enforcement has caused serious personal injuries. Also this year, an auxiliary police officer in Zhuzhou, Hunan was filmed pushing a moving motorcycle multiple times. The man on the bike was pushed down a slope and injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is of course illegal to ride an unlicensed electric vehicle or motorcycle without a helmet. It is also the duty of the traffic police to investigate and deal with these illegal acts. However, the ultimate goal of investigating and punishing illegal activities is to maintain road traffic safety. Using dangerous means to intercept cyclists who commit minor violations may result in more serious consequences, which runs counter to the fundamental purpose of traffic police law enforcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these cases, although the cyclist broke the law first and may have been injured in the accident, the improper interception behavior of the police officers made this small possibility immediately become a reality. This kind of improper interception on the road may also cause more serious traffic accident risks. The injured may not only be the intercepted offender, but also the traffic police or a third party. In another video circulated on the Internet, an electric car with an illegally installed awning was driving left and right on the motorway to avoid being chased by the police. It was almost rear-ended by a car. It was a dangerous situation. In the end, the chasing traffic policeman was killed by a car on the inside lane. The car failed to brake and crashed to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Precisely because forcibly intercepting vehicles on the road may bring great risks, the traffic police road enforcement regulations formulated by the Ministry of Public Security clearly stipulate that when traffic police investigate and deal with illegal activities, they encounter motor vehicle drivers who refuse to stop. When driving, &quot;you are not allowed to stand in front of the vehicle and forcibly intercept it, or step on the vehicle pedals, put your head, arms, etc. into the vehicle cab or climb on the vehicle to force the driver to stop&quot;; except when the driver escapes and &quot;may cause damage to the vehicle&quot; Unless there is a serious threat to public safety and the life safety of others&quot;, traffic police are not allowed to drive motor vehicles to pursue. The purpose of these regulations is to regulate the law enforcement behavior of traffic police and avoid greater accident risks caused by improper law enforcement behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously there are law enforcement regulations that explicitly prohibit it, and there are many previous cases as a reference. Why do some people always &quot;continue to do it&quot;? The reason may be that the cost of violating the regulations is too low. In a similar incident, the police report did not mention any responsibility for the on-duty officer who intercepted the vehicle with a stick. Instead, the injured motorcyclist who fell to the ground was criminally detained on suspicion of obstructing official duties. In response to the Hezhou incident, the Hezhou traffic police initially said that the traffic police involved were &quot;young people who are ignorant and have a bit of a temper.&quot; The implication was that they did not think this was a big deal, but that young people were ignorant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Explained from organizational behavior, on the one hand, an organization will naturally tend to safeguard the interests of individuals in the organization in order to protect the work enthusiasm of &quot;its own people&quot; and maintain the centripetal force of the organization. On the other hand, in the current public system, it is not easy to punish a formal public official, and it requires the approval of unit leaders, organizational departments, etc. This is a cumbersome process that may require the preparation of a lot of materials. Even if subordinates are punished for violating laws and disciplines, it may have a negative impact on the work evaluation of the relevant leaders. Therefore, within the organization, there is always a tendency to turn major issues into small ones, and do not punish them if possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, protecting &quot;one&#39;s own people&quot; in this way may give the public a very bad impression and seriously damage the government&#39;s credibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to the Hezhou incident, judging from the video, the traffic policeman drew out his baton and viciously hit the electric car, almost in a manner that would kill people. This is no longer normal law enforcement, but more like It is to vent the anger in your heart. In the eyes of ordinary people, stopping illegal activities is just an excuse, but in fact it is law enforcement breaking the law and intentional harm. Hezhou Traffic Police said it has launched an investigation and will deal with it seriously based on the results of the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the incident of pushing down a motorcycle in Zhuzhou, Hunan, the auxiliary policeman who directly pushed the motorcycle and injured the rider was fired. The policeman who led the team was also given a demerit and was removed from the position of deputy squadron leader. This result was well received by netizens. Hezhou traffic police should learn from their counterparts in Zhuzhou, make handling conclusions as soon as possible and make them public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“五月天”假唱？文化市场稽查部门启动调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:24:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a social media blogger released a video expressing doubts about whether the 12 songs from the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert are true. Sing expressed doubts, and the information quickly rose to the top of a social media trending list. &quot;Mayday&quot; has not yet responded to this matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the social media blogger used human voice extraction to conduct the analysis, and the result is the blogger’s unilateral judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reporters learned this morning (December 4) that the original video and audio of the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert have been submitted to the Shanghai Municipal Culture and Tourism Bureau Law Enforcement Team, which will review the provided audio and video content. Conduct scientific evaluation and analysis and publish the survey results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Measures for the Self-Discipline Management of Entertainers in the Performance Industry&quot; stipulates that &quot;performers are not allowed to deceive the audience by means of lip-syncing or performing during commercial performances.&quot; The &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Commercial Performances&quot; also requires that &quot;Actors shall not deceive the audience by lip-synching, and the performance organizer shall not organize actors to lip-sync. No unit or individual shall provide conditions for lip-synching. The performance organizer shall send a dedicated person to supervise the performance. Prevent the occurrence of lip-syncing behavior.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the ticket price for the &quot;Mayday&quot; Shanghai concert is 355 to 1,855 yuan, and the number of attendees for the 8 concerts exceeded 360,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访国务院发研中心金研所原所长张承惠：应更好利用监管科技，避免“一放就乱，一管就死”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:43:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In 45 years, China has transformed from a small financial country to a large financial country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many financial indicators are among the best in the world. What is particularly commendable is that the scale of green loan stock ranks first in the world, and digital financial innovation has always been at the forefront of international peers. At the same time, both the bond market balance and wealth management scale rank second in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is no denying the current situation that finance is big but not strong. On its new journey from a financial power to a financial power, what leading indicators can China achieve to become a financial power? At the same time, risks always accompany the development of the financial industry. In the new process of deepening reform and further high-level opening up, how to resist the transmission of international financial risks? How to resolve local risks and avoid internal systemic risks? How can financial supervision improve efficiency in the digital era? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Financial Research Institute of the Development Research Center of the State Council. She is currently the executive director of the China Society of Modern Finance and a member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. Zhang Chenghui has been engaged in financial research for 30 years. He has participated in more than 30 major and key projects of the Development Research Center of the State Council, including the &quot;Overall Concept of Financial System Reform&quot;, and presided over dozens of projects such as &quot;Research on the Supervision, Control and Management of China&#39;s Money Market&quot;. , won many awards such as China Development Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, she said that building a financial power must meet at least five conditions, such as: financial institutions must be internationally competitive, the RMB must become a mainstream international currency, and China&#39;s financial market must be in the international financial market. They must have a voice in formulating rules. She also hopes that, with the rapid development of digitalization, technology should be better used to improve regulatory efficiency after the regulatory system is established, the regulatory framework and regulatory policies are clear. The use of modern regulatory technology can, to a certain extent, avoid the situation of &quot;if you let it go, it will lead to chaos, but if you put it under control, it will die&quot;, and better improve the efficiency of financial institutions in serving the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Financial Research Institute of the Development Research Center of the State Council, current executive director of the Modern Finance Society of China and member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f16024cc02.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1993&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/04/f16024cc02.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;State Council Development Research Zhang Chenghui, former director of the Central Institute of Finance, executive director of the Modern Finance Society of China, and member of the Strategic Advisory Committee of Tsinghua University PBC School of Finance. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rectifying the financial order has laid a solid foundation for financial stability&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans -serif;&quot;>;You have been engaged in financial research at the Development Research Center of the State Council for many years. This period was a critical period for China to promote the reform and opening up of the financial industry. What&#39;s the thing that impressed you most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was transferred to the Development Research Center of the State Council in 1993. I initially studied finance in the Macroeconomic Department because there was no Established a financial research institute. Since 2003, I have served as deputy director and director of the Institute of Finance. So far, I have been engaged in research work on financial reform for thirty years. What impressed me most during this period was attending the first national financial work conference in 1997 and listening to the passionate unscripted speech of the then State Council leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;Why this meeting deep impression? &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;span>;The general background of this meeting is that after China&#39;s reform entered the fast lane in the 1980s, the original administrative controls were relaxed, but the regulatory logic and regulatory structure in line with market rules have not yet been established, which has led to financial disorder and financial risks. The three typical problems at that time were random fund-raising, random financial institutions and financial business. In terms of market access management for financial institutions and quasi-financial institutions, various financial markets such as bill markets, regional over-the-counter securities markets, and futures markets have flourished everywhere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around the core of controlling financial chaos, this meeting introduced a series of measures, focusing on rectifying and standardizing financial order, preventing and resolving financial risks. For example: the People&#39;s Bank of China reformed its own institutions; approved the establishment of the Central Financial Working Committee; canceled the control of loan limits of state-owned commercial banks; issued special treasury bonds in a targeted manner to replenish the capital of state-owned commercial banks by 270 billion yuan; replenished the capital of commercial banks; established The four major asset management companies, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The series of decisions made at this meeting are of far-reaching significance. For example, the approval of the establishment of the Financial Working Committee of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China not only shows the importance of financial work, but also strengthens the party&#39;s leadership over financial institutions. This is a big reform; the central bank&#39;s restrictions on the loan quota of commercial banks are cancelled, and the restrictions on commercial banks&#39; loan quotas are replaced. Banks implement asset-liability ratio and risk management, and the regulatory model is closer to the direction of market economy development; capital replenishment of state-owned banks and the establishment of four major asset management companies have laid the foundation for solving the problem of deterioration of the balance sheets of the four major state-owned banks. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It now appears that these measures laid a solid foundation for domestic financial stability at that time. During the outbreak of the Asian financial crisis in 1997, some Southeast Asian countries suffered heavy losses, but the domestic financial market was not directly affected, and the finance and economy continued to remain stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reports are often years ahead of reality because they are forward-looking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;China has been promoting financial reform and opening up. Financial reform has also been one of your main research directions. Among the major key projects that you have participated in or chaired by the Development Research Center of the State Council, which research reports have given you a particularly sense of accomplishment? Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;span>;The State Council’s positioning of the Development Research Center is “four characteristics”, namely forward-looking, strategic, overall, and comprehensive. Therefore, one of the characteristics of our reports is that they are forward-looking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among our many reports on financial risk prevention, capital market reform, small and medium-sized enterprise financing and green finance, the most fulfilling one was completed with my colleagues during the 1997 Asian financial crisis. Asian Financial Trends Tracking Report. At that time, the Development Research Center of the State Council selected eight Ph.D.s to set up an Asian financial trend tracking group, and I was one of the members. As an advantage, the Information Center of the Development Research Center of the State Council began to establish an information system in the 1990s. This is the first among government departments, allowing us to track overseas financial trends in real time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We work overtime every day, producing one report or even two or three reports in one or two days on average, reflecting international financial trends in a timely manner and putting forward response suggestions. These reports were promptly delivered to the prime minister or deputy prime minister in charge. These reports were later compiled into two books. This was the first time since my country&#39;s reform and opening up that China had to deal with a financial crisis originating overseas. Some of our suggestions played a good role at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second thing that gives me a sense of accomplishment is that I organized and wrote several reports on the full circulation of China&#39;s stock market in 2002, and conducted an in-depth analysis of the congenital institutional defects of the capital market, namely split shares. Calling for the advancement of equity split reform in the capital market. It was in 2005 that the State Council made the determination to promote the share-trading reform. The third is that based on the examination of international experience and in-depth research on the domestic financing guarantee industry, it was found that my country&#39;s commercial financing guarantee system is not sustainable, and it is recommended to establish a policy financing guarantee fund at the national level. This suggestion was later adopted and implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because we are forward-looking and because reform decisions require careful design, our recommendations often precede the implementation of policies by several years. In addition, I write a lot of reports, so I don’t pay much attention to the implementation of each report. &lt;strong>;Financial risk prevention needs to be considered in a specific context&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In addition to the major reform and opening up In addition to this topic, you have also participated in or chaired research on many major topics on financial risk prevention. Why is there so much focus on this aspect? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is very important to China. If financial risks cannot be controlled, all opening up and deepening reforms will be empty talk. Once financial risks detonate and systemic financial risks occur, it is a financial crisis, which will have a huge impact on a country&#39;s wealth, economy, financial order and financial markets. Risk prevention is the first concern of all regulatory authorities in the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are some dialectical relationships that need to be handled here. For example, how to properly handle the relationship between financial openness and financial risks, and how to properly handle the relationship between economic development and financial risk prevention and control. In different periods, the forms and degrees of risk are different, and the strategies and measures to deal with risks are also different. Therefore, attention to this area is a dynamic and dialectical work that needs to be considered within a specific historical context. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the first National Financial Work Conference, every government has paid great attention to the issue of financial risks and invested a lot of energy and resources in preventing and resolving financial risks. As a national think tank, the issues that the leaders of the State Council are concerned about are the focus of our research. Therefore, the prevention and resolution of financial risks has always been one of the important contents of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the 45 years of reform and opening up of the financial industry, our country has been affected by international economic crises or financial crises many times. , but there is no internal systemic financial risk. What do you think is the main reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Over the past forty years, there have definitely been local or certain industry risks. Being able to deal with local risks in a timely manner will have a positive impact on the entire industry. There has been no major impact on the financial system, which is an important achievement of China&#39;s financial supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two main reasons: First, my country has controlled the pace of opening up the financial market and opened up to the outside world in a more prudent and steady manner. When the country does not have regulatory capabilities and financial institutions are not competitive, hastily opening the market will only bring many opportunities for international financial predators and put great pressure on domestic financial stability. This is the case in some Southeast Asian countries. National history lessons. In contrast, my country&#39;s opening up to the outside world is prudent and steady. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, after the risks are discovered, the central government’s macro-control is relatively powerful and can deal with and resolve the risks in a timely and effective manner. Taking the four major state-owned commercial banks as an example, after undergoing three major steps: financial restructuring, corporate governance reform and capital market listing, state-owned banks have successfully resolved financial risks and ushered in a new stage of reform and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Better use of financial technology and regulatory technology&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed, There are still many hidden economic and financial risks, and we must persist in preventing and defusing risks. In addition to strengthening supervision, what do you think can be done more effectively? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, it must be clear that as long as you engage in finance, there will always be risks. Because the essence of finance is to allocate financial assets across regions, time, and markets. In this process, risks such as maturity mismatch and risk-return mismatch will definitely arise. The key is how to manage financial risks. Secondly, financial supervision is to prevent individual, small-scale financial risks from spreading and developing into regional risks. Sometimes regional risks are unavoidable, so it is necessary to prevent them from becoming systemic risks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the financial history of various countries around the world, there was no financial supervision at the beginning. It is precisely because of the risks that it has had a great impact on the economy and finance. Slowly, countries have begun to establish and improve financial supervision systems. What financial supervision needs to solve is how to better handle the relationship between efficiency and risk so that finance can better serve the real economy. We can neither control financial institutions in order to control risks, nor allow them to engage in various self-liberating financial innovations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the construction of a regulatory system is very important. Today, with the rapid development of digitalization, after the regulatory system is established, the regulatory framework and regulatory policies are clarified, technology should be better used to improve regulatory efficiency. The use of modern regulatory technology can, to a certain extent, avoid the situation of &quot;if you let it go, it will lead to chaos, but if you put it under control, it will die&quot;, and better improve the efficiency of financial institutions in serving the real economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, the Financial Regulatory Authority of Singapore established a chief technology officer. The latest establishment of my country’s State Administration of Financial Supervision includes a chief risk officer, chief prosecutor and chief lawyer, but does not have a chief technology officer. I feel a little regretful. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have a say in the formulation of international financial rules&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Since the reform and opening up, China has grown from a small financial country to a big financial country, and many of its financial indicators are among the best in the world. Which financial indicators do you think deserve special attention? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After more than 40 years of reform, opening up and financial development, my country has transformed from a weak and small country to a big financial country. The scale of our financial market, the size of financial institutions and the number of financial assets rank among the top in the world. This is something to be proud of. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, China is now the world’s largest deposit market and loan market, the world’s largest commercial banking system, the world’s second largest insurance market, the world’s second largest bond market, and the world’s second largest Wealth management market. The 2023 Top 1000 World Banks released by the British &quot;Banker&quot; magazine shows that ICBC, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Bank of China have ranked among the top four for the sixth consecutive year. Overall, China holds 32.67% of the world&#39;s first-tier capital and 27.69% of its assets. China&#39;s finance has become an important force that cannot be ignored in the international financial market. In addition, China’s financial technology is also far ahead of other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed for the first time that we should speed up the construction of a financial power. What is the most fundamental difference between a financial power and a financial power? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A few years ago, I did relevant research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that a financial power must meet at least the following five points:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, financial institutions must be internationally competitive. At present, most of the business of major domestic financial institutions is concentrated in the domestic market. The business volume in the international market is not large, and the competitiveness of profitability is relatively insufficient. For example, in the field of wealth management, domestic asset management institutions have basically no reputation among their international peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the RMB must become a mainstream international currency and be more widely accepted by the international financial market. Data released by the Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication shows that in September 2023, in the ranking of global payment currencies based on amount statistics, the RMB accounted for 3.71%. Although this proportion has set a new historical record, it is 40% more than the US dollar and 20% more than the euro. There is still a large gap in the proportion of %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, China’s financial market is influential in the international financial market. At present, the domestic commodity market and gold market have begun to have some influence in the international market, but there are still quite a few commodities that lack pricing power in the international market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, on the premise of effectively controlling risks, it can attract international capital to enter our country&#39;s capital market and capital market, serve the real economy and promote financial development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, we must have a say in formulating rules for international financial markets. For example, financial regulatory rules, ESG standards, etc. To achieve this goal, you must first do your own things well. Only by doing better than others can you have a say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Central Financial Work Conference proposed that “efforts should be made to promote high-level financial opening up” ” and “steadily expand institutional opening up in the financial sector.” What do you think are the differences between &quot;high-level openness&quot; and &quot;institutional openness&quot; compared to the past? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>; &quot;High-level opening up&quot; focuses on the market access level, opening up to foreign financial institutions including capital markets, capital markets, insurance markets, etc. Factor markets have lower entry thresholds and fewer constraints than before; institutional opening up must be based on international economic and trade rules and international financial market rules to form some institutional environments that are conducive to China&#39;s opening up to the outside world, especially high-level opening up to the outside world, and improve China’s institutional supply capacity. At the same time, the role of rule-maker is transformed from participant to rule-maker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a dialectical relationship, &quot;high-level opening to the outside world&quot; is the premise of &quot;institutional opening to the outside world&quot;, and institutional opening to the outside world is the guarantee of &quot;high-level opening to the outside world&quot;. Compared with the opening of commodity and factor markets, institutional opening is a higher level of opening and is an inevitable choice to achieve high-level opening to the outside world. Through institutional opening, we can further deepen the connotation of high-level opening up and improve the quality of opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: #9a0000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If China wants to transform from a financial power to a financial power, what do you think it should do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhang Chenghui:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;How to build a financial power is a big topic. I can&#39;t answer in a few sentences. To summarize at a high level, in one sentence, we must further deepen reform and opening up in the financial sector. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Chen Meixi also contributed to this article.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨宝璋：平生就会说个相声丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261262]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-04 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/Dd34cho2HqZvGA39Sg3sgxnASTbJoXvgeQ5P3IhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;778&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Dd34cho2HqZvGA39Sg3sgxnASTbJoXvgeQ5 P3IhT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259266&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yang Baozhang (1925-2023), Henan cross talk actor&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The life of cross talk master Yang Baozhang is very similar to the script of traditional opera: he comes from a poor family and does not study hard. He often goes to Kaifeng Xiangguo Temple not far from his home to listen to cross talk, and he becomes famous. Fascinated, he finally gave up on literature and art and became a crosstalk actor. At that time, it was still the Republic of China, where storytelling, singing, juggling and fortune-telling were all commonplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Baozhang was in his teens and had no professional training. He formed a grass-roots team with several other car repairmen and hairdressers who were fond of cross talk. In 1943, Tao Xiangjiu, a famous crosstalk artist from Beijing, came to perform in Kaifeng, and Yang Baozhang officially became his apprentice. After he opened the business in 1945, he stopped going to school. He got up early and memorized the passages &quot;Geographic Map&quot;, &quot;Reporting the Names of Dishes&quot; and &quot;Eight Screens&quot; three times every day. Once the technology is over, the cultural foundation becomes thin again. There is a section of a letter written by Zhuge Liang to Cao Zhen in &quot;Eight Screens&quot;. Yang Baozhang only knew how to recite it but did not understand the meaning. He did not recognize many words in &quot;Geographic Map&quot;. He had been reading &quot;Quebei River&quot; for many years. When talking about these in his later years, Yang Baozhang, who has become a master, does not hide it. He came from a grassroots background and has never left the folk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1960s and 1970s, he could no longer talk about cross talk, so he went to the construction site and made cement. The foreman knew that he was good at jokes, and in turn advised him to save his energy during the day so that he could have the energy to talk long stories at night. . At that time, there was no stage decoration. There was a light in the barn, and there were cows and horses around. You could stand or sit in any position. If someone listened, you would open your mouth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 10 years of doing this, my performance style has become more simple and natural. Although what he talks about is all literary, such as &quot;Su Dongpo Eats Fish Three Times&quot;, &quot;Confucius Eats Yuanxiao&quot; and &quot;The Legend of Liu Luoguo&quot;, they are either historical allusions or intellectual jokes, but Yang Baozhang can always speak in a homely and homely way without leaving any trace. After the 1980s, Yang Baozhang resumed performing. In 1993, he was invited by CCTV to record 20 episodes of the stand-up comedy &quot;The Legend of Liu Luoguo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many famous crosstalk masters have passed away, and Yang Baozhang has become almost the only living fossil in the crosstalk world. In 2010, Kaifeng City held an event for Yang Baozhang&#39;s &quot;86th Birthday Celebration, 68 Years in the Arts&quot;. Yu Qian went to celebrate his birthday, and Yang Baozhang performed a piece of &quot;Ghost Story&quot;. When Yu Qian returned, he sighed: &quot;Master Yang has so many things in his belly.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On his 90th birthday, Guo Degang also went to celebrate his birthday. During his speech, he joked: &quot;I will definitely come to Mr. Yang&#39;s 90th birthday. Today I have promoted a commercial performance worth 80 million.&quot; &quot;Two years later, courtesy reciprocated, Yang Baozhang went to attend the 20th anniversary celebration of Deyun Society. When he came on stage, he threw away the &quot;baggage&quot;: &quot;In order to participate in this event of Deyun Society, I recommended a 160 million yuan. Tanghui, why? It’s the acupuncture point set by my senior brother Baolin, and I don’t dare to go there!” Hou Baolin is also a famous master of the Bao generation, and he left Hexi in 1993. Two things in one sentence made the audience laugh instantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 12, 2023, Yang Baozhang still could not escape the &quot;tang meeting&quot; and passed away. According to actor Yi Cun&#39;s recollection, Yang Baozhang lost his hearing and speech in his later years, and relied on others to take care of him for food and movement. Fortunately, his descendants did their best and Yang Baozhang died peacefully. His funeral was simple and simple, just like what he often said during his lifetime: &quot;I am an artist. I only do one thing in my life, and I know how to talk about cross talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 13:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>