<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[人为什么变胖，问题可能没那么简单]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260883]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The global obesity and overweight problems have become increasingly apparent in recent decades. According to data from the World Health Organization, in 2016 Nearly 40% of adults worldwide are overweight, of which 13% are obese. There are approximately 2 billion overweight people. This increase continues despite public health measures to prevent and slow obesity in many countries. Along with the obesity epidemic comes a large disease burden. How to better manage weight has become an urgent problem in the field of health sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Balancing the quality and quantity of carbohydrates&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Carbohydrates, as a major source of dietary energy for people, have long been the focus of weight loss. Coping strategies such as the &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; of eating less or no staple food, or even strictly limiting carbohydrate intake have been derived. The &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; cuts off carbohydrates as an energy source and attempts to promote weight loss by burning fat to provide energy. Although this method has some short-term experimental support, what will happen if it is persisted in the long term is still a mystery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; requires maintaining a high level of fat intake while maximizing carbohydrate intake, which may increase the risk related to cardiovascular disease. In addition, it will also put pressure on the liver, kidneys and maintenance of nutritional balance, and there is a risk of a series of adverse reactions such as cognitive decline, constipation, fatigue, and nausea. Therefore, long-term adherence to such a diet for weight loss remains controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with the controversial &quot;ketogenic diet&quot; that strictly limits carbohydrate intake, a diet that reasonably controls carbohydrates has actually been widely recognized, including paying more attention to nutritional balance and simplicity. Processed “Mediterranean Diet” etc. Recently, scientists from Harvard School of Public Health and other institutions also found through long-term observational studies that instead of focusing generally on the total amount of carbohydrate intake, it is better to pay more attention to the quality and source of carbohydrates, so as to achieve better long-term weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because their research data shows that some carbohydrate-containing foods do make you fatter as you eat them, but there are also some carbohydrate-rich foods that may actually have a weight loss effect if you eat too much of them. Overall, higher glycemic index and glycemic load will lead to weight gain. Adding 100 grams of starch or added sugar per day increased weight gain by 1.5 kilograms and 0.9 kilograms respectively over four years. Relevant research was published in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) in September 2023. The main sources of daily starch are seeds and tubers such as wheat and rice, which are various staple foods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starchy vegetables such as potatoes and peas, and refined grains are also associated with weight gain. A 100-gram daily intake increase will increase weight gain by 2.6 kilograms and 0.8 kilograms respectively. But if it is non-starchy vegetables and whole grains, the increase in intake will actually reduce weight gain and help control weight. Increasing the intake of non-starchy vegetables by 100 grams per day will reduce weight gain by 3 kilograms, and the intake of 100 grams of whole grains will reduce weight gain by 0.4 kilograms. Similarly, consuming carbohydrates through fruits can also help reduce weight gain, with a daily intake increase of 100 grams corresponding to 1.6 kilograms less weight gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why these data are limited to four years to assess weight change is because some health data in the study are updated on a four-year cycle. Using data from more than 130,000 people in projects such as the Nurses&#39; Health Study, researchers analyzed the relationship between people&#39;s diet and weight changes over more than two decades and discovered these overall patterns of carbohydrates. Over the past two decades, people&#39;s average weight has increased by 8.8 kilograms, about 1.5 kilograms every four years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Highly processed carbohydrates have become a target&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If a person pays more attention to the management of carbohydrate quality and sources, use equal amounts of non-starchy vegetables, fruits and Substituting whole grains for foods like refined grains, starchy vegetables, and sugary drinks will result in less weight gain. In addition to foods such as vegetables and whole grains that are consumed in large amounts, an increase in dietary fiber intake also helps with weight management. Every 10 grams of increase per day corresponds to a reduction of 0.8 kilograms of weight gain. Considering that the age of the people in the study happens to span the middle-aged and elderly stages, including the critical period of weight gain in middle age, this large-sample long-term follow-up study has important reference significance for middle-aged people to strengthen weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, although the latest research data has the advantages of large volume and long follow-up time, and can capture more changes in diet and health, there are still some limitations, such as carbohydrate intake and Information such as weight is reported by the respondents themselves. There may be certain errors in these data, which will affect relevant conclusions and interpretations. To better understand the long-term health effects of carbohydrates, more randomized, controlled, long-term studies are needed to further confirm the conclusions in the latest findings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for why people become obese, the most popular explanation is energy imbalance, which is commonly known as &quot;eating more and moving less&quot;, but this is not the exact answer to the common obesity phenomenon in humans. As obesity rates remain high, some scientists think the problem may not be that simple. Two common explanations currently take into account more complex body system factors. For example, one view is that on the basis that energy intake exceeds consumption, because modern people eat too much ultra-processed food with high energy density, there may also be endocrine, metabolic and nervous system effects, making it more difficult for people to eat food. Self-control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another explanation related to insulin is that the hormonal response triggered by a large amount of ultra-processed carbohydrates causes the body to store more energy in fat, resulting in a lack of energy required for basic metabolism of the body. , after the brain recognizes this state, it will issue a hunger command, thus entering a vicious cycle of getting fatter and overeating. While the understanding of obesity remains controversial, these analyzes and a host of health studies have focused on carbohydrates in processed foods, including all types of so-called &quot;junk food&quot; that are high in sugar and fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ultra-processed carbohydrates are classified as &quot;junk food&quot;, which is not unrelated to the current scientific community&#39;s understanding of the functions of carbohydrates. Carbohydrates are the only macronutrient for which there is no minimum intake requirement. In reality, in some places people eat a lot, but in other places people eat very little. What specific ranges of carbohydrate intake humans need to maintain in order to survive, be healthy, and even live longer are specific questions that need to be answered by scientific evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The risks and costs of eating out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From an evolutionary perspective, larger brain capacity is consistent with the evolutionary process of humans, and larger brain capacity is consistent with the evolutionary process of humans. The brain needs more energy support. After humans entered agricultural civilization, typical lifestyle changes included growing and eating grains, which are foods rich in carbohydrates. For this reason, the human digestive system has become more adapted to starch, but accordingly, new eating habits have also brought about a series of new health problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Latest research suggests that the mechanisms by which carbohydrates, glycemic index, and glycemic load may have negative health effects on weight may include enhanced responses to changes in insulin and other hormones that favor fat accumulation. . In recent years, some studies have shown that in addition to weight gain, the quality of carbohydrates may also increase a series of other health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, a systematic analysis study published in The Lancet showed that compared with those who ate the least dietary fiber, people who ate the most dietary fiber had better health outcomes. The risks of a range of diseases are 15% to 30% lower, including lower cardiovascular disease mortality, coronary heart disease incidence, stroke incidence and mortality, and lower risks of type 2 diabetes and colorectal cancer. In addition, clinical trial data also shows that eating more dietary fiber will lower blood pressure and total cholesterol. The lowest risk dietary fiber intake is 25 to 29 grams per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, studies have found that whole grain intake may also help reduce overall disease risk. Increasing the intake of dietary fiber in the daily diet, replacing refined grains with whole grains, and eating more coarse grains will not only help with weight management, but also improve people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that with the epidemic of obesity in recent years, scientists have tried to verify a variety of weight loss and weight management strategies, most of which are related to &quot;eating&quot;, including the total energy of meals and the amount of food consumed. time. In 2022, a one-year intermittent fasting trial carried out in China found that while restricting food energy, arranging eating times from 8 am to 4 pm every day and not eating at other times, such a The weight loss effect of this dietary pattern is no better than that of energy restriction alone, indicating the importance of controlling energy intake for weight loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in April 2023, Australian researchers further narrowed the eating time window to 8 am to 12 noon every day, limiting the intake of 30% of the required energy to only these four hours. And you stick to this eating method for three non-consecutive days in a week, and you can eat whatever you want at other times. The experimental results found that under certain circumstances, intermittent fasting that limits meal times still has its own unique effect, not only can Lowering the weight of trial participants could also improve people&#39;s glucose tolerance and reduce their risk of type 2 diabetes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leonie Heilbronn, a professor at the University of Adelaide School of Medicine and others who have long studied fasting and meal times, explained to Southern Weekend reporters that human metabolism is governed by biological rhythms The brain operates downwards, alternating between day and night 24 hours a day. Improper eating time will cause the brain&#39;s light and dark rhythms to be out of sync with the biological clocks in other organs and tissues. Moving meals earlier and avoiding eating at night will help the body coordinate these rhythms. combine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, a randomized controlled trial in the UK also supported the conclusion of eating early, but it was not because of differences in metabolism at different times, but because the study at that time found that if you eat more in the morning, your overall health will be reduced throughout the day. If the meal time is moved forward, people will not feel too hungry that day, and appetite and total energy intake will be controlled. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Weight management should be a long-term plan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For weight control, no matter what the strategy is or how difficult it is, whether it can be persisted in the long term is the key to weight management. key. Otherwise, no matter how radical and rapid the weight loss method is, it will rebound when you can&#39;t persist, and destroy people&#39;s confidence in weight management during the continuous rebound. Some people whose obesity problem is particularly serious and whose weight loss through conventional methods has been ineffective can only reduce their health risks through extremely limited methods such as bariatric surgery. However, this method requires the removal of part of the stomach, which is extremely invasive and does not work. Not suitable for most people who have less severe weight problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, the latest research controls weight by managing the source of carbohydrates, which does not involve harsh food intake restrictions or long fasting times, and has positive implications for people&#39;s long-term weight management. significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the researchers also found that the relationship between carbohydrate sources and weight management was more obvious in overweight or obese people than in people of normal weight, indicating that these people may be more susceptible to weight changes. Sensitive, more fragile, but in turn suggests that those who pay more attention to the sources of carbohydrates in their diet may benefit more from this type of weight management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reflected in specific foods, it is necessary to limit sugary drinks and various types of steamed, fried, and baked refined rice noodles, and instead eat more roughly processed grains, fruits, and non-starchy foods. Vegetables etc. The &quot;Mediterranean diet&quot; widely praised by scientists is actually more scientific in managing carbohydrate sources and maintaining nutritional balance. In addition to consuming more vegetables, fruits, and whole grains, it also eats more beans and nuts, and more Fish and moderate amounts of poultry and dairy, but not a lot of red meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[拿电动汽车对比主战坦克：券商的“奇葩研报”为何层出不穷？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260891]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a screenshot of a research report comparing BYD’s U8 and T-90 main battle tanks was exposed. This screenshot of the research report comes from the special research report on BYD released by the Western Securities R&amp;D Center on October 24, 2023: &quot;BYD (002594.SZ) first coverage report: Cost is the shield, technology is the spear, and the sword points at the global automotive leader&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On page 26 of the research report, in order to present the output power of BYD&#39;s Yi Sifang four-wheel motor, Western Securities compared the output power, engine, and body of BYD&#39;s U8 and T-90 main battle tanks. , amphibious, on-site U-turn, lateral travel, zero-hundred acceleration and the number of driving wheels, and concluded: &quot;The technical indicators of Yi Sifang&#39;s four-wheel motor are comprehensively leading the industry.&quot; Looking up at the amphibious and lateral travel functions of U8, T -90 tanks are &quot;none&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Blue Whale Finance, a relevant person from Western Securities responded that the report was not written by an intern, and that the comparison of BYD’s U8 with main battle tanks was affected by relevant publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the impact of relevant publicity? Previously, many self-media compared BYD’s U8 with tanks. Regardless of whether the research report of Western Securities was influenced by self-media, but comparing electric vehicles with main battle tanks, and then claiming that its technical indicators are comprehensively leading the industry, whether the relevant arguments and conclusions are rigorous and reasonable will naturally be questioned by investors and public opinion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in June this year, Western Securities and analysts were punished for research reports. According to the warning letter from the Shaanxi Supervision Bureau of the China Securities Regulatory Commission: After investigation, the internal control mechanism for the securities research report publishing business of Western Securities is not sound, individual surveys did not fulfill the pre-approval procedures, sales staff participated in the assessment of research report analysts, and compliance management did not cover expert consulting services. The main business links; the quality control and review of research reports are not strict, and some research reports have unreasonable valuation forecasts and imprudent conclusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant securities research report produced by Luo Yamein, the signed analyst of BYD’s research report, has problems such as imprudent research methods, lack of reasonable justification for some assumptions, and insufficient basis for some conclusions. Not only was it shown The warning letter is also recorded in the securities and futures market integrity files. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than half a year later, Western Securities and the same analyst released another controversial research report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this was not done by a securities firm called Western Securities. In recent years, there have been numerous cases of securities companies being fined for &quot;weird research reports&quot;. On December 30, 2021, the Jiangxi Securities Regulatory Bureau issued two law enforcement documents, punishing Guosheng Securities and its researchers for their conduct related to the research report &quot;A Preliminary Study on the Application of Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches in Timing&quot;. On October 18 of that year, a report titled &quot;A Preliminary Study on the Application of Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches in Timing&quot; by Guosheng Securities attracted public attention. In the report, it is explained in detail how the &quot;Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches&quot; dominate the market&#39;s time cycle, and how to apply the &quot;Heavenly Stems and Earthly Branches&quot; in timing. Liu Fubing, who issued this research report, has been in the industry for more than 12 years and has been listed as the best analyst of New Fortune 8 times, including No. 1 6 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we say that the above-mentioned research report is &quot;even if it is not shocking, it will never stop&quot;, so it has become a talking point for people. There is also a type of &quot;weird research reports&quot; that are more likely to mislead investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, the Jiangsu Securities Regulatory Bureau posted an administrative penalty decision against two analysts Ma Haobo who signed the research report &quot;Fucheng In-depth Report 2: Three 10 billion to support doubling of market value&quot; , Tang Weiliang were fined a total of 200,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, a research report released by Soochow Securities boldly predicted that Fucheng Shares (600965.SH), &quot;the number one A-share funeral stock&quot;, would be the absolute leader in the funeral industry in the future. And gave Fucheng shares a &quot;buy&quot; rating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, on October 25 of that year, Fucheng Shares issued a &quot;clarification announcement&quot; to clarify the relevant contents of the research report. Soochow Securities&#39; &quot;Fucheng Research Report&quot; stated that the number of tombs after the completion of the third phase of Fucheng&#39;s pagoda cemetery will reach 400,000. Based on this data, it was concluded that Fucheng&#39;s net profit would be 15.5 billion yuan. After investigation, Fucheng Co., Ltd.&#39;s pagoda cemetery plans to build about 125,000 tombs. &quot;Fucheng Research Report&quot; also stated that the industrial merger and acquisition fund jointly established by Fucheng Co., Ltd. and an investment company has a total scale of 10 billion yuan. The current scale is 1 billion yuan, and the follow-up fund scale will be 9 billion yuan. After investigation, as of October 2016, the size of the above-mentioned M&amp;A fund was only 1 billion yuan. The status of subsequent funds will need to be made by Fucheng Shares based on the progress of the first-phase fund and the quality of the assets acquired. Third, &quot;Fucheng Research Report&quot; stated that the company&#39;s major shareholders have 10 billion in cash and have sufficient funds to serve as the backend of the above-mentioned merger and acquisition funds. After investigation, as of October 2016, the major shareholders had not made a decision in this regard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant quoted data in the research report released by Soochow Securities is far from the actual data of Fucheng Shares. I am afraid that the source of the information and whether the data has been investigated and verified are all a mess. How can a research report like this deserve market credibility? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called research reports are analysis reports prepared by financial institutions such as securities companies, fund companies, banks, etc. They mainly include company analysis reports, industry analysis reports, investment strategy reports, etc. The purpose of the research report is to help investors better understand the market, the company, and the industry so that they can be used as a reference when investing. However, the content is full of errors and omissions, pointing the research direction towards Feng Shui, or making gimmicks of comparing electric vehicles with main battle tanks, which reflects that some brokers do not pay attention to the professionalism of the research report, and even use the research report as a tool for speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The motivation behind securities firms’ “weird research reports” cannot simply be attributed to sensationalism. In financial markets, information release is a form of power to some extent. Therefore, regulatory authorities have corresponding standards for financial institutions, listed companies, and media to release various types of investment-oriented information. As professional information providers, brokerage research reports influence investors&#39; decisions to a considerable extent. However, in the process of pursuing so-called market influence, some securities companies make some shocking remarks to attract attention and attention. There will be traffic or profit considerations, and they may even interfere or distort market trends. Since brokerages are also one of the important stock holders in the stock market, if a brokerage publishes a research report that is &quot;bullish&quot; or &quot;short&quot; on a listed company or a certain sector in an exaggerated way, and secretly buys or sells the corresponding stocks, wouldn&#39;t it be typical? Manipulation of the stock market? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, regulatory authorities have also promulgated relevant new management policies many times in recent years. In May last year, the regulatory authorities sent the &quot;Notice on the &quot;Double Random&quot; On-site Inspection of the Securities Research Report Business to all securities firms. The report shows that in 2022, a special &quot;double random&quot; on-site inspection of research and reporting business will be carried out in the entire industry, covering a total of 45 securities companies and 300 research reports. In September of that year, the China Securities Association reiterated the self-regulatory management of the securities research business of securities firms, including that holdings of more than 1% of the research target stocks must be disclosed and that reverse operations are not allowed within two trading days of the release of the research report; however, various management measures do not seem to hinder The continuation of &quot;Weird Research Reports&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This shows that for strange research reports, the regulatory authorities’ punishment and supervision need to be strengthened. Warning letters, inclusion in integrity files, etc. cannot touch the core interests of relevant personnel and securities companies, so that they would rather have short-term market effects than adhere to compliance. Only by clarifying the responsibilities of securities firms in the production and release of research reports and continuing to increase penalties for violations can the regulatory authorities stop the vicious cycle of &quot;bad coins eliminating good coins&quot; in securities firms&#39; research reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[18亿元起拍，衡阳政务数据资源特许经营权转让为何暂停？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;This round of transfers in Hengyang is considered the &quot;first sale&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/17a4e58168.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/17a4e58168.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This round of transfers in Hengyang is considered the &quot;first sale&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the Hengyang Municipal Public Resources Trading Center issued a notice stating that according to the request from the transferor Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Resources and Intelligence&quot; is now suspended. &quot;Urban franchise rights transfer project&quot; transaction activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five days ago, the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center announced that it would sell Hengyang municipal government data resources and smart city franchise rights through online bidding, with a starting price of 1.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowhere has previously auctioned and transferred government data resources in the form of a franchise. Therefore, this round of transfer is considered the &quot;first auction&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After receiving a letter from the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the transaction was suspended, but the letter did not explain the specific reasons.” A staff member of the Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center told Southern Weekend reporters that there had been The company called to inquire about the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two staff members of the Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that the above-mentioned franchise transfer project was suspended because they received notification from the superior department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The state is coordinating this (public data) work, and they will give some guidance before proceeding.&quot; A staff member of the Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that the project is on hold. , the plan still needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Does not involve national security, business secrets or personal privacy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center, the transfer was approved by the Hengyang Municipal Government, and the subject matter is divided into two parts: government affairs data resources and smart cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Hengyang, Hunan Province issued the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Sharing and Open Management Measures&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the Management Measures). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management measures clearly state that government data refers to various types of information such as documents, materials, charts, pictures, videos and data produced or obtained by government departments in the course of performing their duties and recorded and saved in a certain form. Resources include information resources collected by various government departments directly or through third parties in accordance with the law, authorized and managed in accordance with the law, and information resources formed by relying on the government information system to perform their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Encourage the open utilization of information under the conditions of ensuring data security, personal privacy and corporate commercial confidentiality.&quot; The management measures state that it is necessary to promote the registration and confirmation of open data, value assessment and other work, and actively explore the data market operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management measures state that public data that involves national security, business secrets and personal privacy, or that is not allowed to be opened in accordance with laws, regulations and other regulations, are parts that are not allowed to be opened. Any leakage of state secrets, work secrets, business secrets and personal privacy will be dealt with in accordance with the National Secrets Law and relevant regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, Guizhou issued a document requiring that big data authorities at all levels authorize qualified market entities to operate government data at the same level and develop data that does not involve state secrets, commercial secrets, or personal privacy. Data services and products and trade through Guiyang Big Data Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned management measures of Hengyang state that the data rights belong to the government, and Hengyang Development Investment Group Co., Ltd. is authorized to develop and operate it through a franchise. According to the Enterprise Alert, the company is the largest urban investment platform in Hengyang, with assets exceeding 140 billion yuan, and is 100% owned by the Hengyang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Hengyang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government believe that the government data operation effect of Hengyang Development Investment Group needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 27, 2023, the official website of the Hengyang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released the &quot;Notice on the Progress of Inspection and Rectification by the Committee of the Communist Party of China Hengyang Development Investment Group Co., Ltd.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second issue reported is &quot;Ineffective implementation of the decisions and arrangements of the municipal party committee and municipal government.&quot; In this regard, the rectification situation reads, &quot;Accelerate the injection of some asset resources that have been expressly determined by the municipal party committee and government... Actively strive to complete the joint review of the implementation plan of government data resources (including Hengyang Mass App) and smart city franchise rights.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;What content is involved in smart cities is not mentioned on the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center and the transaction attachments. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The pricing method for public data is not yet clear&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the official website of Hengyang Public Resource Trading Center, the transfer of government data resources will adopt a bidding method, with a starting price of 1.8 billion yuan, each time The price increase is 10 million yuan. It is disclosed in the transaction attachment that the starting price is the appraisal price of the target, but the columns for the appraisal agency and the appraisal base date are both blank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the project evaluation price reach 1.8 billion yuan? Staff from the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the pricing of data resources is an industry problem. In February 2023, Zhao Jingwu, associate professor at Beihang University School of Law, wrote an article stating that data valuation indicators are not unified and data quality standards are difficult to determine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that even in general data trading activities, the so-called market pricing is just the result of self-negotiation between the parties to the transaction. This &quot;one thing, one discussion&quot; data valuation model is difficult to achieve for digital purposes. The market provides sufficient reference basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Government data faces the same problem. On November 16, at the main forum of the 2023 China Data Element Industry Innovation Conference, Wang Jiandong, deputy director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission, said, “Before the end of this year or early next year, management measures for government-guided pricing of public data may be introduced. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center shows that the return mechanism of the government data resource franchise project is “user pays”. During the franchise period, the franchisee can charge fees from users within the scope of the franchise in return for project construction. However, the official website did not announce the specific number of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One interviewee’s company is responsible for building a government data platform for a southern province. He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that users who will pay mainly refer to enterprises in various places that have information business needs, rather than individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, Hangzhou, Qingdao and other places have also tried to authorize operations for public data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Hangzhou released the &quot;Public Data Authorized Operation Implementation Plan (Trial)&quot;. The document states that the next step is to determine the operating entity of the authorized operation platform, and with the consent of the municipal government, will be specifically responsible for the construction and operation, data management, operation and maintenance, and security of the authorized operation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hangzhou’s plan states that priority will be given to supporting the development of public data authorization operations in the fields of credit, transportation, medical care, health, employment, social security, education, technology, finance, enterprise registration and supervision, housing construction, provident funds, and public security. , led by the competent departments in the field. Public data that is prohibited from being opened shall not be authorized for operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 卞建林：刑诉法要保障个人权利]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bian Jianlin, the first litigation jurist in New China PhD. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1953 Born in Taixing, Jiangsu Province in October. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1960 -1965, Jinjiang Primary School, Taixing Town, Taixing County, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1965 -1971, junior high school and high school department of Taixing Middle School in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1972 -In 1979, a worker at the commercial refrigerated ship repair and manufacturing plant in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979 From September to July 1983, he was an undergraduate student in the Law Department of China University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1983-July 1986 In September, he graduated from the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law, majoring in criminal procedure law, and received a master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In August 1986, he stayed at the school and served as a full-time researcher at the China Legal Research Institute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 1987, he studied for an on-the-job doctoral degree in litigation law at the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In July 1991, he was awarded a doctorate in litigation law, becoming the country&#39;s first doctorate in litigation law. Professional doctorate;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Associate professor in 1992 and professor in July 1997;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In May 2000, he served as a doctoral supervisor in criminal procedure law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as deputy director of the China Legal Research Institute of China University of Political Science and Law in 1991 and director in 1995;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2001 to 2006, he served as Executive Vice Dean of the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 1993-August 1994, served as a visiting scholar at New York University School of Law;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 1999-August 2000, served as a senior visiting scholar at Harvard Law School and Yale Law School Scholar;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2006 to 2022, he served as the Chairman of the Criminal Procedure Law Research Association of the China Law Society Chairman, President of China Criminal Procedure Law Research Association;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2006-2019, served as Dean of the Institute of Litigation Law, China University of Political Science and Law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003 to 2013, served as the State Council Member of the fourth and fifth legal discipline evaluation groups of the Academic Degree Committee. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bian Jianlin, the first doctor of litigation law in New China. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/18/728ed89d3b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;745&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /18/728ed89d3b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bian Jianlin, the first doctor of litigation law in New China. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Enrolled into university at the age of 26 and graduated with a doctorate at the age of 38. This year, Bian Jianlin turns 70. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 18, 2023, Bian Jianlin appeared at the door of the office of China University of Political Science and Law on time. He was tall and thin, wearing a fitted black casual suit and a trousers. He was wearing trousers and holding a red paper bag in his hand, which contained three volumes of &quot;Governing the Country by Law and Criminal Procedure - Collected Works of Bian Jianlin&#39;s Legal Studies&quot;. For his 70th birthday this month, the publisher specially planned this collection of essays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1979, eight years after graduating from high school, Bian Jianlin left his hometown in Jiangsu and entered Beijing Political Science and Law School, which had just resumed school after the Cultural Revolution. College, which is now China University of Political Science and Law. Relying on employee scholarships provided by the state, Bian Jianlin completed his bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s degrees. Just before life was about to reach another fork in the road, &quot;a major event happened.&quot; In 1986, the third batch of law doctoral programs in the country was confirmed, and two law professors from China University of Political Science and Law were appointed as doctoral supervisors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1987, Bian Jianlin studied under Professor Chen Guangzhong, who is recognized as the &quot;founder of criminal procedure law&quot; in China. Four years later, he became the first doctoral student in criminal procedural law independently trained by the People&#39;s Republic of China, and embarked on a career development path similar to that of his mentor. To date, Bian Jianlin has trained 87 doctors and 11 postdoctoral fellows. He also serves as the honorary dean of the Procedural Law Institute of China University of Political Science and Law, the executive director and academic committee member of the China Law Society, and the honorary president of the China Criminal Procedural Law Research Association. He works as a professor at Jilin University, Wuhan University, Zhongnan University of Economics and Law, East China University of Political Science and Law, Northwest University of Political Science and Law, People&#39;s Public Security University of China, and National Prosecutor&#39;s College. On social media, he always actively participates in various seminars and academic lectures to share his understanding and suggestions on the construction of the criminal procedure system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unwilling to flaunt himself, Bian Jianlin almost never talks about his past experiences in public. Even in this two-hour interview, the topic never got around to his mentor. And he himself seemed to be just an ordinary student who was &quot;older and started school late&quot;, and he was lucky enough to get to where he is now by accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Accidentally became the &quot;first&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the preface of the anthology, it seems that this is the first time you mentioned your experiences as a student. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t like to talk about my resume. This collection of essays has a profound impact on my academic work. It means life summary, so I said a few words in the preface. I was admitted early at the University of Political Science and Law, and was in the first class after the school was re-established. However, compared with other scholars who entered earlier, I was still relatively older when I entered. Fortunately, I completed my bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree and Ph.D. in one go, so I gained some time back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; What were you doing before you were admitted to the Beijing University of Political Science and Law in 1979? How did you think of studying law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduating from high school in 1971, I went to work in a provincial factory. Later, the college entrance examination was resumed, but after all, it was not a required option. Very few of my high school classmates went on to college. At that time, everyone had a job and even got married and had children. But I still have a little bit of ambition, and I have such an ambition to take the exam. As for studying law, it is almost an inevitable choice. First of all, during the ten years of turmoil, our generation was wasted. Basically, we did not learn mathematics, physics and chemistry, and we were seriously partial to subjects. It was not easy to take the science and engineering exams, so we had to choose from liberal arts. Foreign languages, Chinese, history and law, among which law is definitely the most attractive. The main reason is that many of the books I read in the past were about solving crimes, about identifying doubts and clearing grievances, punishing evil and eradicating evil, and upholding justice, so I naturally developed a legal feeling. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Why study Criminal Procedure Law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was an undergraduate, the school had only one law major, and there was no further subdivision. major. When I was about to graduate, I decided to take the postgraduate entrance examination. According to my personality and interests, I didn’t really like civil law. What I liked most was the “study of criminal justice”, so my major choice should be criminal law. However, there is a certain degree of chance in choosing criminal procedure law. The school&#39;s master&#39;s entrance exams for Criminal Procedure Law and Criminal Law only differed in one subject, Criminal Procedure Archeology Chinese, while Criminal Law was the history of the legal system. In the year of the postgraduate entrance examination, I went home to celebrate the Spring Festival. After the Spring Festival, I had to take the exam. I thought that I would have to work hard to prepare for the legal history course, and there is always some basic knowledge in ancient Chinese, so it was just a matter of thought. The choice of exam subjects suddenly determined the direction of my major, so it was not that I realized the procedure from that time on. value and importance, because in fact substantive law was still ranked ahead of procedural law at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Law is a practical subject. During your studies, didn’t you ever think about getting into practice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To learn the law, you must use it. Logically speaking, you have to work in the practical department , plus I was relatively old when I entered school. At that time, a bachelor&#39;s degree was enough, and I also studied for a master&#39;s degree. So I faced two choices at the time. One was to follow my family&#39;s wishes and return to Jiangsu. The Provincial High School wanted to recruit a Mature judges are more interested in me; if they stay in Beijing, they want to go to the Interpol China National Central Bureau through an old leader of the Ministry of Public Security. I did have some thoughts, but in the end both options were given up, and they were not implemented to the extent of signing a contract. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Why gave up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1986, before I graduated with my master’s degree, the school was approved for two doctoral programs, including Two teachers were identified as doctoral supervisors, namely Professor Wang Xuan and Professor Chen Guangzhong. Teacher Chen is responsible for the litigation law major. They are also the first batch of doctoral supervisors at China University of Political Science and Law. After receiving the PhD approval, Teacher Chen once talked to me. First, he told me that I had the opportunity to continue my studies; second, he expressed his affirmation to me. After Teacher Chen chatted with me, I was more tempted, although I didn’t fully appreciate the school’s advantages at the time. The most important thing is that my nature is that I am always uneasy about the status quo and have an upward spirit. I have never thought of being rich and settling down. In this way, I decided to continue studying for a Ph.D. after graduating with a master’s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You obtained your master&#39;s degree in 1986 and your doctoral program was approved in the same year. How come it was only a year later that you started studying for your Ph.D.? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I started preparing for the Ph.D. exam before and after I graduated with my master’s degree. However, although the doctoral program was approved at that time, there were insufficient preparations for public announcements and enrollment listings. Due to various reasons, neither doctoral program enrolled students that year. However, Teacher Chen happened to be the deputy dean of the Graduate School at the time, and the school established a new research institution, the Chinese Legal Research Institute, with Teacher Chen also serving as the director. So I stayed in school and worked at the China Legal Research Institute, doing full-time research, doing projects, and writing articles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; How many doctoral students studied with you under Professor Chen? Why were you the first doctoral student to graduate? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Frankly speaking, in the first year of enrollment, the instructor has candidates in mind , but you still have to follow the formal process when applying. At that time, unlike now, the papers were basically judged on the spot after the exam, and the results were known quickly. Finally, Teacher Chen recruited me, and also recruited someone from our school. He was a master&#39;s student in criminal law in 1984, just one class after me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Speaking of this, it is also a coincidence. If the school had recruited doctors in 1986, he had not graduated with a master&#39;s degree at that time, and we would not be classmates. . However, although we are both in the first batch of doctoral students, he is a full-time student, while I am a part-time PhD student because I have already stayed in school to work. According to the country&#39;s degree regulations at that time, those studying for a PhD on the job would have to study longer than those studying full-time. As for how long, there is no clear regulation. So I extended my studies by one year and graduated in 4 years. If calculated according to this time, it is possible that he graduated before me, then I will not become the first doctorate in criminal procedural law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the students in the same class later went to study in the United States and never came back, leaving me alone to hold on. Later, I joked that if he didn&#39;t leave, he would definitely graduate before me, and the title of the first doctor of litigation law would belong to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Follow the teacher&#39;s steps&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekends:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first batch of 18 Ph.D.s was produced in 1983, but the first recipient of a doctorate in law was graduated in 1987. Among all disciplines, law is not a niche, and it is not too early to cultivate a doctorate in law. What do you think?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the reason for getting a doctorate in law is a little later. First, the doctoral program was of high value at that time. At that time, the approval of the doctoral program and the determination of the doctoral supervisor required the approval of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, which was very strictly controlled. The second reason is that from the perspective of faculty and research level, law was still a discipline with relatively scarce talents and did not have the conditions to train doctoral students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1988, Professor Chen Guangzhong edited the book &quot;Comparative Research on Foreign Criminal Proceedings&quot;. Three years later, your doctoral thesis &quot;Comparative Research on Criminal Prosecution Systems&quot; was approved. From a professional research perspective, did Professor Chen have a great influence on you? big? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Teacher Chen has always attached great importance to understanding and learning from foreign litigation systems. When we were still studying for master&#39;s degrees, there was a very lack of teaching materials. Basically, each school compiled and printed its own teaching materials. It happened that when Mr. Chen was the deputy dean of graduate students, he brought a topic from the Institute of Law of the Academy of Social Sciences on foreign criminal litigation. A comparative study of procedures. At that time, reform and opening up had already begun, and we were encouraged to study China&#39;s issues from a global perspective. Based on a group of experts from the Law Institute, Teacher Chen recruited some scholars from our school and other schools who studied this field to work together on this work. . Several of our classmates who are still studying for master&#39;s degrees also participated in part of it. I participated in writing a chapter, that is, compulsory medical measures, but I did not sign my name separately. I completed it under the guidance of my supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, this book was the first domestic comparative and systematic study of foreign criminal procedure. It was both authoritative and precious. If you want to know more about it, If you know something about it abroad, you must read this book. For those of us who participated in writing this book, because writing required research on foreign materials, only the University of Political Science and Law had this condition at the time, so it was the first step for me to broaden my academic horizons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the previous In an article, you called Professor Chen &quot;the leading figure in criminal procedure law in New China.&quot; Do you have any observations about his academic studies and his conduct as a person? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Teacher Chen is a recognized master and an important founder and leader of our discipline. people. I feel that my husband&#39;s biggest specialty in learning is to learn from the best of other schools, to be open to all rivers, and to be tolerant, so later on he suddenly surpassed other teachers of his generation and was beyond the reach of others; the second is to know people and make good use of them, and make full use of their talents. Every time he writes something or works on a project, he can always hand over the relevant content to the most suitable person; the third thing is to be able to pay attention to and accept new things, and constantly improve himself by guiding students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to learning, the teacher also has a strong sense of responsibility and mission. He cares about current affairs and is now 93 years old. He is still paying attention to social phenomena and judicial practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Professor Chen’s Do personal traits influence you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Chen has had a great influence on me. Over the years, I can say that I have been closely related to him. He followed suit every step of the way. In addition to the master-disciple relationship, my position also determines why my behavior, knowledge and knowledge are closer to those of my husband. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You and Professor Chen have been promoting the localization and application of some overseas experiences. In this process, what impact has reform and opening up had? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Chen is an iconic figure in the field of criminal procedure law in my country. The development and improvement of the criminal procedure system can be said to have made a great contribution and deserved the most credit. In terms of participation in legislation, when the Criminal Procedure Law was formulated in 1979, there were relatively few scholars involved. Mr. Chen was still in Guangxi at that time. I feel that this was his regret. The revision of the Criminal Procedure Law in 1996 was an opportunity to make amends, and Mr. Chen played a great role in the revision of the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I still remember that in the winter of 1992, after Mr. Chen became the president of China University of Political Science and Law, his first symposium was held at the school. In the now demolished international student building, the director of the Criminal Law Office of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress came with the director. At that time, the law was being revised. In 1993, because I assisted Mr. Chen in promoting the first revision of the Criminal Procedure Law, I was sent to study at New York University as a core member of the research team. Later, I participated in an inspection delegation led by Mr. Chen to several European countries. The director of the Criminal Law Office of the Legal Affairs Commission also participated in the inspection. After returning to China, the Legal Affairs Committee formally sent a letter to the school, entrusting Mr. Chen to lead a research team to provide opinions on the revision of the law. A year later, Mr. Chen’s research team submitted a 350,000-word “Recommendation Draft for the Criminal Procedure Law of the People’s Republic of China” to the Legal Affairs Commission, of which 65% of the provisions were absorbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to domestic projects, I assisted Mr. Chen in conducting some international exchanges and cooperation and conducting some comparative law research. For example, it selects students to study abroad, translates and publishes the criminal procedure codes of some representative countries, promotes the implementation of international human rights conventions and United Nations criminal justice guidelines in China, etc. It should be said that it has done a lot of useful things to promote the development and improvement of my country&#39;s criminal procedure system, and also promoted the discipline construction and talent cultivation of procedural law at China University of Political Science and Law. These were unique to the University of Political Science and Law at that time. Other schools neither had this team strength nor the necessary conditions and capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Amending the Constitution in 2004 At that time, Professor Chen proposed that &quot;the state respects and protects human rights&quot; be written into the Constitution; in 2012, when the Criminal Procedure Law was revised for the second time, this article was written into the Criminal Procedure Law. As his student, you have always advocated that criminal procedure law should protect individual rights. Why have you been so concerned about this issue? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Human rights protection is very closely related to criminal proceedings. Criminal procedure law is a typical field where public power operates and an important tool for national governance. For a long time, influenced by concepts, systems and even ideologies, we have regarded criminal proceedings as a contest between the state and crime, emphasizing the punishment of crimes, resulting in the lack of effective restrictions on the power of specialized state agencies in litigation activities. Correspondingly, the rights and interests of criminal suspects, defendants and other litigation participants cannot be fully protected. From the perspective of social development trends, the country&#39;s comprehensive promotion of governing the country according to law and building a country ruled by law means regulating public power through the rule of law and procedures to prevent power from being alienated and abused. Mr. Chen has a full understanding of this and has done a lot of work , through their own efforts to strengthen human rights protection in the judiciary, influence legislation, and improve the judiciary. Under the leadership of Mr. Chen, we have also made our own efforts and contributions to this end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;It is not enough to do it yourself&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In a previous school lecture, you and the students discussed the vindication of unjust, false and wrongful convictions. Judging from past news reports, lawyers representing many cases are known as &quot;hard-nosed lawyers&quot;. What do you think of this group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The defense system and the lawyer profession reflect the level of the rule of law in a country. If the level of lawyers in a country is very weak and the defense system is not perfect, it is impossible to progress in criminal litigation. When the Criminal Procedure Law was formulated in 1979, there were basically no lawyers. Interim Regulations on Lawyers were only introduced in 1980. Therefore, the legislative provisions on lawyer defense are relatively backward. However, several revisions to the Criminal Procedure Law since 1996 have improved the lawyer defense system. Overall, the progress of the defense system is obvious to all. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But at the same time, it should be noted that there are still many problems in the legal provisions regarding lawyer defense, especially in judicial practice. I think one of the important reasons is that we have not found an accurate positioning of the lawyer profession and lawyer defense. In criminal proceedings, the defense lawyer&#39;s duty is to defend the defendant, find faults and discover problems from various angles such as facts, evidence, legal application, procedural operation, etc., so as to promote the fair handling of the case and thereby improve the level of the rule of law. By nature, lawyers do not exercise public power and are not members of the case-handling agency. Our management of lawyers is different. Lawyers are managed by judicial administrative agencies, which are part of the specialized state agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In judicial practice, in order to provide effective defense, to protect the legitimate rights and interests of the parties, or to ensure that legal procedures are complied with, lawyers need to be more truthful when performing their defense duties. Sometimes there are conflicts with the case-handling agencies, so some lawyers are called &quot;die-hard lawyers.&quot; But if they are not serious and fight to the death, they will not be able to protect the interests of the parties involved, and they will not be able to carry out defense work normally. Recently, some extreme examples have occurred, such as a court in Laibin, Guangxi, which forced lawyers to undergo security checks, made things difficult for them, and violated their legitimate rights and interests. This had a very bad impact, which attracted the attention of people across the country and was named by the Supreme Court. I think after such an extreme thing happens, the entire court system should take a warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Seems like this contradiction This occurs in many of our legal systems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is not enough to do it yourself. It does take time for the law on paper to become law in action, and various problems will arise during the implementation process. In a certain sense, many of the problems or difficulties faced in my country&#39;s current judicial practice are caused by the development of the system. Some things that seem good are actually very difficult to do. It may touch the interests of some people and even intensify conflicts. I believe that problems in development must still be solved by development. On the one hand, we must know more about the situation and pay attention to practice when designing the system; on the other hand, once the law is revised, the authority of the law must be maintained, and the case-handling agencies must strictly enforce the law. Take the lead in abiding by the law and earnestly abide by the procedures prescribed by law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In the past, everyone said that law is a humanities and social science, but now it is said that law is an engineering discipline within the humanities and social sciences. What do you think of this view? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no doubt that law is a humanities and social science, at least a discipline, or It is science, and it does have some attributes of engineering. Especially our discipline is very applicable and operable. When we studied in the past, we studied &quot;Criminal Procedure Law&quot;, but now it is called &quot;Criminal Procedure Law&quot;. The addition of the word &quot;study&quot; actually means that we realize that this is a science and a knowledge system. It is not just about interpreting the meaning of the law, but also using it to govern society and achieve good results. Taking the ascertainment of case facts as an example, it is not only an epistemological issue, but also involves axiology and methodology. Due procedures must be used to regulate the exercise of power by the case-handling agencies. Generally speaking, procedural law is an operational norm. It must have a specific set of principles, rules, methods, procedures and institutional norms, and it must be meticulous and operable, so that litigation activities can be followed by law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; With more than 40 years of study and academic experience, do you have any experience that you can share with young students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether I am a scholar or a teacher, I actually learned from Mr. Chen , he set an example for us, teaching us to be patriotic and caring for the people, to have an open vision, and to have a spirit of research. This is what I strive to follow when doing academic work. In addition, I often remind students to care about current affairs and pay attention to the present. Many things happen around us every day, or there are examples closely related to our profession every day. Don&#39;t turn a deaf ear or be indifferent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for how to learn and how to write articles, this is indeed not an easy task. I think that first of all, individuals need to work hard, and at the same time, they also need opportunities. When we were studying, we should say that there were more opportunities. There was a shortage of people in front of us because of the passing of generations, and the society was in urgent need of talents, so that we would be the first in this and the first in that way. Nowadays, law has become a prominent school. Young people are under great pressure, but there are not many opportunities. Then they need to be more diligent, redouble their efforts, be calm, endure loneliness, and never let go of their youth. If they really learn, they will achieve something. There are times when you can use force and give appropriate rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《等待戈多》作者最喜欢的戏剧来中国，观众看得很精神]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A black box stood on the stage. &quot;Endgame&quot; had not officially started, but the two characters were already inside. Extremely similar clips are repeated over and over again, as if the stage has turned into a machine that plays on a loop due to malfunction. The servant Clover wrung his fingers and walked the same route repeatedly with a strange gait. He stepped back from the door to the right of Master Ham&#39;s wheelchair, walked to the corner on the left, and then to the door on the right, taking fourteen precise steps, every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue has not changed either. &quot;Do you want me to leave you?&quot; &quot;Of course.&quot; &quot;Then I will leave you.&quot; &quot;You can&#39;t leave me.&quot; &quot;Then I won&#39;t leave you.&quot; The door was opened and closed again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot; brought Beckett worldwide fame, but his favorite work was &quot;Endgame&quot; written four years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258749&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; will be performed at the 10th Wuzhen International Theater Festival in 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This play shows four deformed people in an empty house that is approaching the end of the world. : The master Ham is paralyzed from the lower body, blind, and has been sitting in a wheelchair; the servant Clover has a disease in his knees and cannot sit down. Ham&#39;s parents, Nag and Nell, have lost their lower limbs and live in two trash cans. The relationships between masters and servants, husbands and wives, and parents and children all show an extremely cruel side, but they are interdependent and inseparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impression of Tobias Bianconi, Director General of the International Theater Association, in the past, the audience&#39;s reaction to Beckett and even absurdist plays was sometimes &quot;very frustrating and unhappy&quot;, but After he walked out of the theater, he found that after watching this version of the Vienna Volkstheater&#39;s performance, the Chinese audience was full of energy and had lively discussions. They all felt that the play was very fresh. &quot;Why is there such a reaction? What is the background that makes the audience like this play so much?&quot; he was curious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 20th century, which experienced the ravages of two world wars and was immersed in industrialization and the post-industrial era, the rationalism admired by Western civilization fell into crisis, belief in God collapsed, and self-doubt and self-denial became the themes of the times. This also brought profound conceptual changes to drama. What Beckett&#39;s drama expresses is the antagonistic relationship between human beings and nature, society, self and others who are completely alienated in social crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Absurd drama, which was born in Paris, France, in the early 1950s, was echoed again in Wuzhen, China, seventy years later. &quot;At the beginning, we thought the most exciting thing was this very unhealthy and toxic relationship between characters. Later we found that it had some parts related to war. As it slowly developed, we found that it might be related to climate change. Recently, We found that it was combined with the COVID-19 epidemic.&quot; During the dialogue, theater director and German director Kai Vogels said that this version of &quot;Endgame&quot; has been performed for eleven years. &quot;The point of it being constantly performed is that it is always new. , what we see from this drama keeps changing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18 /yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.j pg&quot; data -key=&quot;258748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; was written in the late 1950s. The version that came to China has already been sold in Europe Acted for eleven years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vogels refined the four characters into two clown-like people, retaining the main theme A very tense contrast between servants: Ham is physically disabled, but has the power to control Clover; Clough is relatively able to move freely, but is always dominated by his master to do unnecessary trivial things, and his spirit tends to be paralyzed. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching adaptation is Vogels’ emphasis on the sense of looping. The line, which was on an infinite loop before the show even started, only appeared once in the original script. Vogels uses this as the opening or closing line of every dialogue, repeating it a dozen times throughout the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new plot in the play brings an &quot;anti-climax&quot;: after Clover struggled, he shot Hamm, but the expected relief brought by death did not happen. After the monologue, Ham suddenly answered and got up from the ground, as if nothing had happened. Clover and he returned to their usual endless conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Beckett actually demonstrated a ritual cycle on the stage. The ending of this ritual cycle is satisfaction, nothingness, or the end of the world. Everyone can see it differently. Each point has its own interpretation, and what I present on the stage also has this meaning.&quot; At the beginning of the rehearsal, Voges hoped to show the inextricable cycle of repetition on the stage without making the audience feel bored. This balance Feeling is what he is looking for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1998 Vogels has been a theater and opera director in Austria and Germany. German drama is relatively lagging behind in digital innovation. From 2010 to 2020, while serving as the artistic director of the Dortmund Theater in Germany, Vogels began to try to combine digital media with drama and introduce digital thinking to the drama stage. He is a pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these works, digital techniques such as VR, real-time imaging, and on-site editing are emerging in endlessly. &quot;Endgame&quot; pursues Beckett&#39;s minimalist style. However, the artificially isolated cramped space, heavy metal-style amplified sound effects, The sudden switching of dazzling lights, the characters&#39; mechanically looping movements and lines, all give this picture of the human spiritual wasteland a cold science fiction color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more traditional images such as &quot;desert&quot; and &quot;dead branches&quot; in Beckett&#39;s original work are missing. In terms of stage design, the play chose a form that abstracted away from reality. Like the door, the few sets and props are all outlined with white chalk lines. Three-dimensional life seems to be locked in two-dimensional space. Machine guns and toy dogs are just thin wooden boards hanging on the wall when they are not picked out by actors and held in their hands. The clock has no hands and the flowers in the vase are out of proportion. The only real objects are the wooden chair with armrests in the center of the stage and the light bulb hanging in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors&#39; performances are consistent with German precision, and they achieve the ultimate in repetitive movements with slight changes. The actor who played Ham sat in a chair with his eyes closed throughout the performance, but still showed a strong sense of dominance and oppression in the relationship through his tone and gestures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The voice can be called the third &quot;starring&quot; of this drama, expanding the information and emotional density in the minimalist world. Clough&#39;s footsteps continued to echo in the space, powerful, but as flat as the scenery, with no specific sense of direction. Footsteps create a strong conflict with directionlessness. Every time Clover dropped something he was holding, there was a loud cracking sound, whether it was a telescope, a machine gun, or a toy dog. The laws of the physical world break down here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two people, who are both master and servant and father and son, are imprisoned in a lifeless atmosphere. The room they were in was, in a sense, like the final game board in a chess match. Ham is the general on the chessboard and needs to ensure that he is in the &quot;center&quot; of the room, controlling his pieces. The little soldier Clover could barely move a few steps, but under the command of blind Ham, the situation was certain to lose, but they could not and did not dare to leave the room, just like the chess pieces could not leave the chessboard. &quot;There is no nature anymore&quot; outside the house. Even when I opened the window, I saw &quot;ZERO&quot; written on the blackboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They passed the time by teasing, controlling, and torturing each other, telling the old stories again, and looking at the window that they had looked at countless times, hoping that something would happen. What happened in front of my eyes was that other people passed by the window. However, their expectations were all in vain, and all their actions no longer made much sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the play, I realized that the beginning was the end. &quot;What time is it?&quot; &quot;Same as usual.&quot; They repeated the dialogue at the opening. Everything stopped suddenly, leaving silence and darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 08:59:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Miracle Doctor&quot; sells a bunch of titles to patients. Nongjian illustration&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;&quot;Miracle doctors&quot; sell a bunch of titles to their patients. Nongjian Illustration&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao’s “veteran Chinese medicine doctor” Hou Yuanxiang, who pretended to be an expert and professor and practiced medicine illegally for more than ten years, fell for his homemade “anti-cancer drug” - in February 2023, Hou Yuanxiang was arrested by Qingdao in the first instance The Huangdao District People&#39;s Court of the city sentenced him to 12 years in prison and fined him 12 million yuan for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hou Yuanxiang, his daughter, son, wife and former son-in-law were also sentenced for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 11 to 3 years respectively. In addition, the son of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s third sister was also involved in the case. He was sentenced to 11 years in prison for &quot;fraud&quot; and &quot;harboring&quot; in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total prison term for the above six people is 50 years, and the total fine is 29.8 million yuan. Southern Weekend reporters searched online for judgment documents and found that among counterfeit drug cases in recent years, the first-instance verdict in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case was extremely rare in terms of heavy sentencing and high fines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the case has not yet been settled. After the first-instance verdict, as Hou Yuanxiang and others filed an appeal, many self-media appeared on the Internet to &quot;cry out injustice&quot; for them. Some associated the case with the &quot;folk traditional Chinese medicine&quot; group, believing that &quot;if this lawsuit is lost, almost all folk Chinese medicine practitioners must close their doors.&quot; (For details, please see the report &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260879&quot;>;&quot;The Online Public Opinion War on the &quot;Miracle Cancer Doctor&quot;&lt;/a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s agent The lawyer questioned the characterization of the drugs involved in the case, arguing that after the revision of the Drug Administration Law in 2019, the threshold for identification of counterfeit drugs has been raised. Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made of traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be identified as counterfeit drugs. Hou Yuanxiang does not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 30, 2023, the Qingdao Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the original judgment and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the first-instance judgment “had unclear facts and insufficient evidence.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;old Chinese doctor&quot; who can&#39;t take the pulse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After being criminally detained on February 17, 2022, Hou Yuanxiang only stayed in the detention center for more than 20 days. After that, the police changed the enforcement measures to &quot;residential surveillance&quot; because of his illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Gang, the second-instance attorney, met Hou Yuanxiang after the National Day in 2023. According to him, two policemen worked in three shifts, watching him 24 hours a day, &quot;maybe because there are more patients coming to him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, 66-year-old Hou Yuanxiang is from Shandong A native of Yishui County, Linyi City, the province, he once worked as a teacher in the county, but later took a leave of absence without pay and became a doctor. After that, he moved his family to Weifang and settled down. Around 2019, after purchasing real estate in Qingdao, Hou Yuanxiang and his wife and their daughter Hou Jing and his wife both moved their household registrations to Qingdao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s confession cited in the first-instance verdict did not explain his medical experience. Some self-media said that Hou Yuanxiang studied under two &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot; Zhang Moumou and Lou Moumou, but Southern Weekend reporters did not find any information about the latter two as &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is certain that Hou Yuanxiang is not from a &quot;family of traditional Chinese medicine&quot; or &quot;six generations practicing medicine&quot; as some self-media said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to what Hou Yuanxiang’s wife and sister told China News Weekly, Hou Yuanxiang was originally a primary school teacher and started studying medicine when he was about 40 years old. He had “several teachers” but “all of them are gone.” This relative emphasized that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;excellent&quot; in taking his pulse - he could tell whether it was cancer or what kind of cancer it was by just touching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a daughter-in-law, Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that she did not know how Hou Yuanxiang learned Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most patients call Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s WeChat signature is also &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. The &quot;Central Health&quot; website, which claims to provide communication, display, and promotion services for &quot;folk doctors,&quot; still has Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s personal introduction, calling him an &quot;international doctor of medicine&quot; and &quot;an authoritative international cancer expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, his online profiles, including “Professor of Chinese Medical College” and “Doctor of International Medicine”, “are all false” and “are intended to expand influence and make patients believe I&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Hou Yuanxiang did not even obtain a medical practicing certificate. Since the implementation of the Practicing Physician Law in 1999, regardless of whether it is traditional Chinese medicine or Western medicine, all practitioners must have a physician&#39;s practice certificate. Otherwise, it will be regarded as &quot;illegal practice of medicine&quot;, and they will be subject to administrative penalties in the lightest case and criminal liability in the worst case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A patient surnamed Xu testified that she began to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang in 2014. Since then, she has introduced many patients to Hou, and also asked Hou to attend a consultation at his winery. In 2019, she and Hou Yuanxiang co-organized During the hospital, he found that Hou didn&#39;t get a physician practice certificate, and he doubted his identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not only patients, but even some senior medical circles have confident Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s identity and ability. According to the first trial judgment, Hou Yuanxiang had a long -term consultation in the De Medical Hall of the Private Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital in Qingdao. Later, the person in charge of the German Medical Hall asked Hou Yuanxiang to hang the qualifications of the physician in the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the testimony of Shen Yufa, the dean of Zibo Yiyuan Ruikang Hospital, before 2010, he met Hou Yuanxiang at a medical academic meeting in Beijing. Tumor, cancer, and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular are famous. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, Shen Yufa&#39;s wife got cancer and used Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine. Shen Yufa also hired Hou as the &quot;part -time professor&quot; of Ruikang Hospital and sold Hou medicine in the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, Shen Yufa invited him to take a clinic at Ruikang Hospital, but he refused because he did not have a physician&#39;s practice certificate, and the two sides only sold drugs to cooperate. However, the son of Shen Yufa and the other employees of the hospital confirmed that Hou Yuanxiang was in the hospital for irregularities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to private hospitals, there are also public hospitals who have worked with Hou Yuanxiang. In 2016, as a public hospital, the Weifang Municipal Organ Organ Hospital had issued a post on his WeChat public account, saying that Hou Yuanxiang was a &quot;international cancer research authoritative expert&quot; and will go to the Chinese Medical Branch for consultation every month. This article has only disappeared recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The patients believe that Hou Yuanxiang, in addition to his online resume, is also dazzling, but also because of its &quot;accurate&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dong Shijie is the relative of a patient with a Jilin patient. According to him, Hou Yuanxiang travels to Changbai Mountain, entertains to eat by herself, and Hou Yuanxiang lives on the spot. &quot;There is a friend who has high blood lipids and high blood pressure, and he can touch it.&quot; Dong Shijie told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, according to the first instance judgment, Hou Yuanxiang acknowledged that he would not actually be pulse. The reason why pretending to be the pulse is &quot;to put it plainly to let the patient buy medicine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When I learned that Hou Yuanxiang would not be a pulse, Dong Shijie was shocked: &quot;He is a Chinese medicine, he won&#39;t see what he is seeing?&quot; >; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first instance, since 2011, Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Jing and others have not obtained the drug production license and the drug business license, etc., and have invested in the false personal introduction of Hou Yuanxiang on the Internet. Consultation and sales claim to be anti -cancer drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine case, the first thing that happened was her daughter Hou Jing -like her father, she also had no physician practice certificate. On January 16, 2022, after receiving a complaint report, multiple departments in Huangdao District, Qingdao jointly law enforcement, arrested Hou Jing on the spot. Subsequently, Hou Jing confessed Hou Yuanxiang and his brother Hou Lei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, Hou Yuanxiang was in the home of Weifang at that time. He didn&#39;t seem to care about it at first. After Hou Jing was detained and asked by the police, he realized that the situation was serious. And production tools, but it is too late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The court of first instance found that after Hou Jing was detained, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s wife went to the police station where he handled the case to inquire the news. After returning home, he &quot;hidden the family&quot;, and the police pursued the Hou family online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, Hou Jingxiang called him the next day, Hou Jing was arrested. &quot;Two or three days later, my father said that this is not small. Let me not use my current mobile phone. Let me go out to hide. After hanging up, I will take out the mobile phone card and throw the trash.&quot; &lt;/P >; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As for how Hou Lei participated in these business, Hou Lei said that in the winter of 2019, Hou Yuanxiang &quot;let my wife Li Jianying apply for a bank card ... let me pretend to install me ... Director Li of the hospital, some patients called me when they wanted to buy medicine, and asked me to send the bank card to the patient and let the patient make money. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, Hou Jing&#39;s relationship with Hou Lei is not good. Hou Lei knows that after Hou Jing made money, he also wanted to follow his father to sell medicines. The formula was just let Hou Lei follow him, and he paid him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jianying told reporters from the Southern Weekend that Hou Lei helped Hou Yuanxiang in Weifang, &quot;equivalent to a courier.&quot; In the first trial judgment, Hou Lei was sentenced to &quot;crime of production and sales of fake medicines&quot;, with a sentence of 8 years and a fine of 5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, after hiding for a few days, he received a call from Hou Yuanxiang with a strange number and proposed to go to the three aunts&#39; house in Qingdao to celebrate the New Year, and then the whole family arrived at the third aunt&#39;s house. According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, because he felt that &quot;it was quite big&quot;, he suggested that his father vote for the case, &quot;My father is very angry, saying that I am not his own.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Lei&#39;s son Li Shuai told Hou Lei that he had a relationship to settle the matter, but it took 4 million yuan. After several communication, Hou Lei asked his ex -brother Fu Songjie to send Li Shuai to Li Shuai to 2 million yuan in cash after paying 500,000 yuan. Li Shuai confessed that when he saw Fu Songjie with a sack of money, he was stunned: &quot;I saw so much money for the first time.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Fu Songjie was originally a district in Weifang City Attorney of general surgery of the People&#39;s Hospital, in 2019, he resigned to Qingdao under his ex -wife Hou Jing. Before his resignation, Hou Yuanxiang found him and asked him to be the legal representative of a private hospital in Hou Shen&#39;s shares. After Fu Songjie arrived in Qingdao, because he caught up with the epidemic, he did not settle in his work. Fu Songjie was sentenced to 3 years in the first instance and fined 500,000 yuan. The sentence was the least of all person involved. Fu was the only one who did not appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After Hou Lei was arrested, he confessed Li Shuai. In the next three days, Li Shuai, Fu Songjie and Hou Yuanxiang were arrested one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Hou Yuanxiang, in addition to the above 2.5 million yuan, Li Shuai also deceived him more than 2 million yuan. The first instance judgment confirmed the incident and stated that &quot;the public security organs will be investigated separately.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s false medicine case, the police checked the 8 houses of Hou&#39;s house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In late February 2022, after Hou Yuanxiang was arrested for a week, the Ministry of Public Security announced the first 8 major typical cases of drug crimes listed in supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The &quot;secret recipe&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case, the fake medicine is the four medicines made by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter, which are named &quot; Anti -Cancer No. 1 and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot;. According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, these two medicines are made based on a &quot;secret recipe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Hou Yuanxiang said differently about the origin of this &quot;secret recipe&quot;. During the investigation stage of the case, he said that the secret recipe comes from a &quot;second grandfather&quot;. This recipe originally had 5 medicines. On the basis of this, Hou Yuanxiang added shiitake mushrooms, ganoderma, and Cordyceps. I have always wanted to promote this prescription to sell medicines to make money. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, at the stage of the trial, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s statement on the &quot;secret recipe&quot; changed -he said that Fangzi was presented by his &quot;teacher&quot; at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s different rhetoric about the source of the secret recipe made a second -instance agent lawyer also felt puzzled: &quot;The truth may only be known by himself.&quot; The lawyer said that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti -cancer &quot;secret recipes&quot; include shiitake mushrooms, Cordyceps, Ganoderma, Plagractic, Black Jujube, Kunbu, Niu Gen, Dandelion Gen, Ginseng, Astragalus, Angelica and other Chinese medicinal materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A Chinese medicine medicine that has been in the world for more than forty years told the southern weekend reporter that these traditional Chinese medicinal materials in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s Fangzi have both &quot;replenishing&quot; and &quot;attack&quot;. Astragalus, cancer patients in the middle and late stages, most of them are weak in their bodies, and they are good for using some tonic; &quot;attack&quot; such as Kunbu has the effect of clearing heat and dispersing, but it is only suitable for some early tumor patients and is not suitable for advanced stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the patients of Hou Yuanxiang, there are many advanced cancer patients, and some are found by Hou Yuanxiang because they are &quot;sentenced to death by the hospital.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Different from the &quot;grabbing medicine&quot; in Chinese medicine, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti -cancer drugs are cooked in advance, and they are sold to the patient after bagging. According to his confession, Around November 2020, Hou Jing purchased a machine to make soup medicine. Since then, his father and daughter took turns to use this machine to boil the medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The price of &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; is 4620 yuan per service, and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; is 1920 yuan. Eat a course of treatment with a course, 12 days a course of treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made anti -cancer drugs, Zhao Yin, a lawyer who graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and worked at the Chinese Medicine Department of the Hospital for many years, believes that he must be illegal. According to her, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade medicine, similar to the &quot;medical institution (traditional Chinese medicine) preparation&quot; in the hospital, refers to a fixed prescription preparation that is prepared and used by medical institutions according to the clinical needs of the unit. However, the hospital preparations are the same as drugs. Generally, the approval of the drug regulatory department can be produced and sold, and in principle, only the hospital can only be used for the hospital for use, and it cannot be sold outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Yin said that after the introduction of the Chinese Medicine Law in 2017, the state&#39;s management of traditional Chinese medicine preparations has been relaxed. The provincial drug supervision and management department can be prepared after being recorded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine also did not record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Traditional Chinese Medicine Law stipulates that the medical institution formulates a Chinese medicine preparation that should be recorded but not filed, and a penalty is punished according to the production of fake drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Yin still doubts whether Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade anticancer drugs really contain a sufficient amount of Chinese medicinal materials such as Cordyceps claims in the &quot;Secret Recipe&quot;, because the medicine is made by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter. The production standards for production lack due supervision and supervision. Quantitative testing such as Cordyceps is very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Fu Songjie&#39;s confession, Hou Jing will send Liuwei Dihuang Pills and other Chinese medicines to the patient with the well -boiled Chinese medicine solution. In Zhao Yin&#39;s opinion, in this way, even if the patient feels effective after taking the medicine, it may be the role of proprietary Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In order to avoid the qualitative of &quot;fake medicine&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang tried to argue with &quot;medicine and food&quot;, which means that he sold food. However, because the names of &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; were marked, it made it difficult for him to justify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Yin believes that the drug name of &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; itself is nice, because cancer is the concept of Western medicine, and Chinese medicine generally does not have the saying of &quot;cancer&quot; or &quot;tumor&quot;. It is called the &quot;symptom accumulation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made anti -cancer drugs, the above -mentioned Chinese medicine interviewed by reporters in the southern weekend directly called &quot;too boldness&quot;. In his opinion, many Chinese medicines have secret recipes. In order not to leak the secret recipes, they generally only sell medicinal materials to patients, at most to help patients fry on behalf of them. They must not dare to sell them to patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Are there any cancer patients being cured? &lt;/H4>; &lt;p>; However, supporters have &quot;shouted unjust&quot; on the Internet on the grounds that Hou Yuanxiang cured many cancer patients. However, the southern weekend reporter&#39;s investigation found that whether there was cancer patients was really cured by Hou Yuanxiang, it was a question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the first trial of the Hou Yuanxiang case, a list of cancer patients who claimed to be &quot;cured by Hou Yuanxiang&quot; were flowing on the Internet. There were personal information of 31 patients or family members of patients on the list. This list is consistent with the southern weekend reporters with one of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s supporters Gong Feiyun. According to Gong Feiyun, at the end of June 2023, he went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang. It was the list given by Hou Yuanxiang himself. Gong Feiyun is a partner of a Chinese medicine museum in a foreign country. He has also been involved in the storm of fake drugs in the past few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter on the Southern Weekend called all 31 calls on the list, of which 11 were unaware, 13 rejected, and 7 of the 7 connected telephones acknowledged whether they were on the list. Family members, another person denied that he was the &quot;Provincial Environmental Protection Bureau Director&quot; Che Moumou, who was written by the list, claiming that he was &quot;running business.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the 6 people, 3 of them refused to interview on the grounds that &quot;there was something&quot; and &quot;involved privacy&quot;, and only 3 people accepted telephone interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The patient Song Yuan&#39;s family was from Qingdao, Shandong. He claimed to be &quot;sentenced to death by the hospital&quot; and found Hou Yuanxiang with a mentality of trying. Nothing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Song and Yuan family told the southern weekend reporter that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was &quot;ancestral medicine&quot;, which did not give medicine. He spent more than 200,000 yuan. Okay, eat &#39;Anti -Cancer No. 2&#39; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, when Hou Yuanxiang transferred the pharmaceutical and production tools overnight, he asked the Song Yuan family to help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Song and Yuan family told reporters to the south weekend that he had read Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s first trial judgment, but he was more willing to believe in the &quot;shouting injustice&quot; video on the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another interviewee Wang Jingjiang is a village in Zibo, Shandong, and the patient is his mother -in -law. He said that Hou Yuanxiang had planned to build a nursing home in the village, and he drove the village secretary at the time, so he met Hou. Later, his mother -in -law had cancer, and there was no possibility of surgery. After a period of chemotherapy, he contacted &quot;Professor Hou&quot;, &quot;at that time, he was sick.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Jingjiang said that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was &quot;good&quot;, and his mother -in -law felt &quot;energetic&quot;, but because he couldn&#39;t stand the taste, he stopped drinking anymore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the view of the drafting and demonstration experts of the Chinese Medicine Law, the lawyer Yang Fengzhu, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;anti -cancer drug&quot; is mixed together. Although the Chinese medicine treatment is rarely &quot;immediate&quot;, it is not There is no effect, &quot;You replenish qi (Chinese medicine), it must be effective.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; And Wang Jingjiang also emphasized: his mother -in -law was not &quot;cured&quot;, but &quot;no (no) criminals, no metastasis&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The third interviewee Li Cheng (pseudonym) is Jilin Yanbian. He told the southern weekend that the patient was his grandfather, and he did find Hou Yuanxiang to see the illness and had taken his own medicine. The old man has died in September 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng said that Grandpa was diagnosed with rectal cancer in July 2019 and has spread to lymphatic. Relatives introduced him to Hou Yuanxiang. He has never seen Hou Yuanxiang so far, and the two are mainly contacted through WeChat. He said that after adding WeChat, Hou Yuanxiang sent his personal profile, &quot;What world cancer, what committee, what kind of cancer treatment experts, I also searched on Baidu, and I can really find this person. sharp&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When receiving a call from the reporter from the Southern Weekend, Li Cheng still said that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang was not a professor, even when he had no physician practice certificate, he was surprised, saying that if he knew the situation at the beginning, he had to find Hou Yuanxiang to see a doctor &quot;consider.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng said that in addition to drinking Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti -cancer drugs, Grandpa also ate the &quot;nutritional meal&quot; recommended by Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;After eating three courses, (grandpa) recovered well.&quot; Li Cheng said, for this reason, he also introduced many patients to Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Li Cheng couldn&#39;t confirm that his grandfather&#39;s condition improved for a time. Li Cheng said, &quot;We all say (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine) and good use of the management and goodness may also support the spiritual state of Grandpa.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Yang Fengzhu has participated in many clinical trial arguments in drugs . In his opinion, when patients do treatment, &quot;psychological effects are important and can affect 30%(treatment) effects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng also said that during the period of taking Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine, Grandpa also performed other treatments including surgery, &quot;Chinese and Western medicine synchronized.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; After the fake medicine &quot;slimming&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Whether it is an agent lawyer or Hou Yuanxiang himself, they will not expect to be so heavy in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, according to relevant laws and regulations and the amount involved in the case found by the driver agency, once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine is identified as a fake medicine, it cannot be judged lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the first instance, many acting lawyers of the Hou family carried out innocent or guilty defense on the grounds that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade medicine did not cause harm or consequences. Hou Yuanxiang himself also proposed that his medicine &quot;can drink&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, without causing damage, it does not mean that Hou Yuanxiang does not constitute a &quot;crime of production and sales of fake medicines&quot;, nor does it mean that it cannot be re -sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the criminal law before the amendment in 2011, it constitutes the crime of &quot;production and sales of fake drugs&quot;. There is a need for &quot;serious harm to human health&quot;, which will cause death or serious injuries to sentence them to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhao Yin said that in order to increase the crackdown on fake drugs, the eighth amendment of the 2011 Criminal Law amended the &quot;crime of production and sales of fake drugs&quot;. &quot;As a threshold for crime, as long as it is produced and sold for fake drugs, it constitutes a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the eighth amendment of the Criminal Law will no longer take death and serious injuries as the only condition for the severe sentence. It stipulates that there are &quot;other particularly serious plots&quot; and can also be sentenced. In 2014, the judicial interpretation of the Supreme Law and the highest detection desk, as long as the production and sales of fake drugs reached 500,000 yuan, they constituted the &quot;other particularly serious plots&quot; in the eighth amendment of the Criminal Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The amount of Hou Yuanxiang produced and sold fake drugs, the court of first instance was determined to be more than 14.36 million yuan, far exceeding 500,000 yuan. This means that once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine is identified as a fake medicine, it is suitable for sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Whether Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade medicine can be regarded as fake medicine is based on the drug management law. Zhao Yin believes that before the revision of the law in 2019, the identification of fake drugs is relatively simple -as long as the drugs do not obtain a batch number, they will be in line with &quot;fake medicine theory&quot;, which constitutes fake drugs in the sense of criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, the revised drug management law in 2019 has made a major modification of the definition of fake drugs. Drugs that do not obtain a batch number are no longer the presence of fake drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The industry generally believes that the above -mentioned amendments to the Drug Management Law are related to the Hunan Lu Yong case. Lu Yong, a patient with leukemia, purchased generic drugs from the informal channels and helped the patients to purchase this medicine. In 2018, the film &quot;I&#39;m Not the God of Medicine&quot; based on its prototype was released, which caused public opinion to discuss the Chinese drug management system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The revised Drug Management Law &quot;lose weight&quot; for fake medicines, and only four cases can be set as fake medicines (see the post -post data link). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Cao Guoying, director of the Beijing Yangtze River Pharmacy Development Foundation, who has long been engaged in drug counterfeit practices and research, introduced that after the revision of the Drug Management Law, the fake drug case handled by the pharmaceutical regulatory department was &quot;cliff -type decline&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the website data of the State Drug Administration, in 2019, the number of fake drugs investigated and dealt with by the drug regulatory department in 2019 is 14041, and the following year after the revision of the Drug Management Law, the number of such cases in this case is Only 7361, a reduction of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The southern weekend reporter searched on the referee document network with &quot;fake medicine&quot; as the keyword. It was found that the number of criminal cases of criminal cases from the drug management law was revised. 2361 pieces, more than half. It has also declined in the past few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 2019 version of the Drug Management Law, while &quot;slimming&quot; with fake drugs, has greatly increased fines. &quot;The starting point of the fine is 15 times the production sales amount, and less than 100,000 are calculated by 100,000.&quot; Zhao Yin said, &quot;As long as it is production and sales of fake drugs, at least 1.5 million will be fined. &quot;Sales fake drugs).&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;H4>; Is Chinese medicinal materials a medicine? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In Cao Guoying&#39;s view, in the current overall environment of drugs, Qingdao can investigate and deal with the Hou Yuanxiang case &quot;very difficult&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, whether Hou Yuanxiang should be held criminally responsible for &quot;production and sales of fake medicines&quot;, but both in the legal and Chinese medicine community have caused controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The acting lawyer of the Hou family is based on the revised drug management law in 2019. It is believed that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade drug is made of Chinese medicine materials as raw materials. The crime of selling fake medicines. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, according to the first trial of the Hou Yuanxiang case, the public security organs were initially established by Hou Yuanxiang and others with &quot;illegal business crimes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One month after filing the case, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau issued a fake medicine identification letter, which was identified as a fake medicine for the four homemade drugs of Hou Yuanxiang. According to the relevant judicial interpretations issued by the highest law and the highest detection in 2014, it is difficult to determine the &quot;fake drugs&quot; and &quot;inferior drugs&quot;, and the judicial organs can determine the determination opinions issued by the drug supervision and management departments above the city level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the above identification, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot;, &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot;, &quot;liver&quot; claiming to treat liver cancer, and &quot;wild heart brain soup&quot; used to treat heart disease The medicine is identified as a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the case entered the review and prosecution stage, at the request of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Huangdao District, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau specially issued a supplementary explanation to explain why the products involved were identified as fake medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Instructions point out that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s four self -made products &quot;no drug registration certificate, no medical institution preparation filing, no drug production license, no medical institution preparation permit, no national standard, etc. Pharmaceuticals that promote the treatment of cancer, liver cancer, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, etc. are sold to patients to cure diseases. P>; &lt;p>; A second -instance agent lawyer pointed out that on the one hand, the above discussion said that the product involved in the case was &quot;in line with the definition of drugs&quot;, and on the other hand, it was &quot;non -drug&quot;. In its opinion, the reason why Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau discusses this is because according to the New Drug Management Law, &quot;the only thing that can be stuck is this one (non -pharmaceutical impersonation).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine identification issues, the reporter from the southern weekend contacted the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau. The bureau refused to interview on the grounds of the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the first instance, almost all the acting lawyers of the Hou family questioned the false drug determination of the case. One of the lawyers pointed out that most of the medicinal materials used in &quot;Anti -Cancer 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; were in the 2020 version of &quot;Chinese Pharmacopoeia&quot;, which did not conform to &quot;impersonation of medicines with non -drug&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in Zhao Yin&#39;s view, Chinese medicinal materials are not of course considered medicines -Chinese medicinal materials are only raw materials for making drugs and can be sold in the medicinal material market. Sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Where is the medicinal materials used by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter&#39;s self -made medicine? There is no explanation in the relevant confession quoted in the first instance judgment, and Hou Jing cannot provide the purchase of the purchase and legal certification documents. According to Hou Jing&#39;s ex -husband Fu Songjie, Hou Jing&#39;s herbal medicines were sent through express delivery and logistics. The consignee generally used a pseudonym. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Gang, the acting lawyer of the second instance, questioned the fake drugs involved in the case involved in the case of the case, and questioned the fake drug identification letter based on the judgment of the first trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the newly introduced judicial interpretation of the highest law and the highest prosecution in 2022 (the old judicial interpretation of the old judicial interpretation in 2014), the situation of &quot;non -drug pretending to medicine&quot; can only be in the case where there is no controversy. Below, the municipal pharmaceutical regulatory department can be directly identified as fake medicine. For controversy, it is necessary to check or determine the pharmaceutical inspection agency set by the drug supervision and management department of the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Li Gang&#39;s view, the identification of the fake drugs involved in the case of Hou Yuanxiang obviously controversial and should be tested. However, he believes that folk traditional Chinese medicine recipes lack national standards, and even if the results are tested, it lacks scientific and legitimacy. And Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was not tested at the time, and now it has been seized for more than a year. &quot;It has been deteriorated early, how to test it?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 5, 2023, another agent lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang told the Southern Weekend reporter that After the case was returned to the retrial, the procuratorial organs supplemented a lot of evidence to the court, including a inspection report on Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -pharmaceutical. According to this inspection report, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made drug detected the western medicine composition to treat diabetes. The Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau still determined that the product involved was a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s above -mentioned acting lawyer said that this shows that the pharmaceutical regulatory department may no longer determine the product involved in the case in accordance with the &quot;non -pharmaceutical impersonation medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s charges, Yang Zhiwei, a lawyer of Guangdong Fa Quan Law Firm, put forward another point of view to reporters from the south weekend: if Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; are clear and treating cancer &quot;Do not match the world&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang is entirely the purpose of selling medicines, so he may constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend found such a case on the referee document network: In 2019, Li Mouxiang, who did not qualify for medicine, was arrested for production and sales of fake drugs, but the Procuratorate arrested and arrested him with fraud. The court was sentenced to 14 years in prison for fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is Hou Yuanxiang suspected of fraud? A reporter from the Southern Weekend asked about a first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang. After a few seconds of silence, the lawyer asked: Scam? Isn&#39;t that heavier? Later, he said that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;unlikely&quot; to constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang believes that Hou Yuanxiang constitutes &quot;the crime of obstructing drug management&quot;. The crime was newly established in the 11th Amendment of the Criminal Law issued in 2020. It pointed to the criminal behavior of drugs that did not obtain a batch number but not obtained by the production and sales. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer did not accept interviews with reporters from the Southern Weekend, but said such a sentence: &quot;If he is sentenced to being innocently guilty of his (Hou Yuanxiang) family, then we can do anything in the name of traditional Chinese medicine to do traditional Chinese medicine. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; Data link: Different definition of&quot; fake medicine &quot;before and after the revision of the Drug Management Law: &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Before revision: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with the ingredients specified by national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to be medicine or pretending to be such medicines. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; A medicine with one of the following situations, according to fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The State Council&#39;s drug supervision and management department stipulates that it is prohibited; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) In accordance with this law, it must be approved without approved production and importing, or it must be tested in this law without testing without testing. ; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot; (3) deterioration; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (4) pollution; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body body body body , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (5) Use the raw material for the raw medicine of the approval number according to this law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (6) Indications or functions marked or functional beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the following situations: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to medicine or impersonating such medicines in other medicines; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (3) spoiled medicine; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font -Family: Kai, Kaidi_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (4) Indications or functions indicated by drugs or functions beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“抗癌神医”的网络舆论战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260879]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Hou Yuanxiang was investigated, a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for them on the Internet appeared on the Internet. Nongjian illustration &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 953 &quot;data- SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258747&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text -rign: center; &quot;>; During the investigation, Hou Yuanxiang appeared a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for him on the Internet. Nongjian Illustration &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang admits to the reporter from the southern weekend that for Hou Yuanxiang, who was sentenced to the first instance, the second trial was a &quot;backwater battle.&quot; The second trial of the case can be returned to retrial, &quot;the media has played a great role.&quot; (Report on the Hou Yuanxiang case for details, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260877&quot;>; &quot;For ten years of medical practitioners, relying on the secret recipe&#39;s self -made anti &lt;/a>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer&#39;s media refers to the Internet self -media. In fact, the media reports of the mainstream institutions reported Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine cases after the second instance ruling was returned to retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the help of the media, Hou Yuanxiang, who was originally unknown, was described as a &quot;cure doctor&quot; sentenced by injustice. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Women with a public security background&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In mid -March 2023, the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine case was judged for more than a month later, and an article entitled &quot;Nine -year -old Xinxin for help: Mom Mom Articles of more than 3,000 cancer patients were sentenced to 11 years, and a fine of 30 million &quot;began to spread online. The article states that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter Hou Jing used the secret recipe of Chinese medicine to heal a lot of difficulty. , The whole family is implicated. There is also a photo of Hou Jing&#39;s 9 -year -old son asking for help: &quot;Why do you sin? Mom, do you have a sin? Let netizens from all over the country comment on you ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article has aroused heated discussion among netizens. The reporter from the Southern Weekend noticed that this article emphasized that Hou Jing graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and was a Chinese medicine division, but he could not mention Hou Jing without a physician&#39;s practice certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter -in -law Li Jianying told the southern weekend reporter that after the judgment of the first instance, Hou Yuanxiang wanted to use the Internet to &quot;call unjust&quot;. At that time, she asked her children&#39;s photos. She was worried that the child would be affected and did not give it. Later, I used the photos of Hou Jing&#39;s son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2023, the media person Wu Pengfei began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. Wu Pengfei claims to be &quot;old journalists&quot; and &quot;well -known online writers&quot;. They have an account number on platforms such as Douyin, Kuaishou, and today&#39;s headlines. A reporter in the Southern Weekend found that Wu Pengfei worked in a media in Hubei Province in his early years and set up a planning marketing company after leaving the media. When he began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine, Wu Pengfei exposed a big news: a lady with a public security background had a price of 10 million. She wanted to buy Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s treatment secret recipe. Go to jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many self -media bloggers quoted Wu Pengfei&#39;s above statement, so that &quot;women with a public security background to buy medicines can not report to Hou Yuanxiang&quot; said that they became the mainstream online public opinion of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Li Gang, a second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, told reporters from the southern weekend that although he heard Hou Yuanxiang said this, he did not see relevant evidence. Control. As a lawyer, he &quot;does not comment&quot; on this statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Zining, the first instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, also told the southern weekend reporter that the above statement &quot;cannot be reflected in the (case) volume.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter of the Southern Weekend noticed that during the new crown epidemic in 2020, Wu Pengfei had picked up another &quot;divine doctor&quot; -Co Yuehua, who claimed that the injection phenol could cure the new crown, and released the news that Li Yuehua said Li Yuehua He was invited to resist with South Korea, but the news was denied by South Korea. Li Yuehua himself also told the media that he did not know the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend tried to contact Wu Pengfei, but as of press time, the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How much is the reliability of folk investigation?&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After issuing the above article, Wu Pengfei has continuously released short videos entitled &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Injection Cases&quot; on multiple platforms. Now Episode 100 has been broadcast, of which the playback volume of the Douyin platform has exceeded 16 million. In these short videos, Wu Pengfei called Hou Yuanxiang as &quot;Hou Lao&quot;, saying that he was &quot;the first person in traditional Chinese medicine to treat cancer&quot;, with &quot;unique medical skills&quot; and &quot;shocking effect&quot;, &quot;a national treasure&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot; Each hair is gold. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, Wu Pengfei also quoted a set of data to show that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;cure cancer.&quot; He said that &quot;a national folk Chinese medicine organization&quot; investigated the efficacy of the top ten cancer names in China. Only 11 people were cured. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Jianying also told reporters from the south weekend that Hou Yuanxiang&quot; cured &quot;1166 cancer patients. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) has records.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei did not say which institution of &quot;National Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Organization&quot;. In fact, even Li Gang held a question about the data that Wu Pengfei said: &quot;How much is the reliability of private investigations?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In another short video, Wu Pengfei said that Hou Yuanxiang cured more than 3,000 cancers. patient. In the personal introduction of &quot;Yangtze Health&quot; (a website that provides communication, display, and promotion services), Hou Yuanxiang is &quot;cured more than 20,000 cancer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some media have questioned Hou Yuanxiang from the media, but the click volume is not the same as Wu Pengfei&#39;s short videos. Since the media &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; posted a video, saying that Hou Yuanxiang was a &quot;liar for sale of fake medicines&quot;, calling on the public to calm down the case: &quot;If the facts are ignored, it is not love Chinese medicine, but it is harming Chinese medicine.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; After the video was released, &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; was siege by many supporters of Hou Yuanxiang. Wu Pengfei released 8 short videos to refute. It didn&#39;t take long for the video of &quot;Chinese medicine Chen Lei&quot; to get off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After seeing Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine on the Internet, Qian Hui, general manager of Nanjing Guishi Hall Traditional Chinese Medicine Museum, decided to support it. Qian Hui has experienced similar experiences to Hou Yuanxiang. According to media reports, Qian Hui did not have a physician&#39;s license. In order to avoid &quot;illegal medicine&quot;, his Chinese Medical Museum hired a regular doctor to prescribe prescriptions, and Qian Hui would &quot;guide&quot;. Self -making based on your own &quot;secret recipe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 2017, Guishi Hall was reported. Because the batch number was not obtained, its homemade medicine was identified as a fake medicine by the Nanjing Pharmaceutical Bureau. The crime of medicine was once detained by the police, and Qian Hui was locked for 28 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why do we support Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s innocence? The main reason is from the perspective of protecting traditional Chinese medicine, because once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case is guilty, many traditional Chinese medicine can not do it anymore.&quot; To the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun, one of Guishitang&#39;s &quot;partner&quot;, traditional Chinese medicine is &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang is one of many &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;. He defines &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;: The collective name of Chinese medicine outside the system has not received formal Chinese medicine education in universities, and has no physician practicing certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2013, Gong Feiyun went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang. According to Gong Feiyun, although Hou Yuanxiang had been &quot;monitored and lived&quot; by the police at that time, he was not strict at that time. He tried to make an appointment and made a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun also participated in the mediation of the Guishitang fake medicine. According to him, during the handling of the case, Guishi Hall had a &quot;public opinion war&quot; with Nanjing police: first a media in Nanjing stood on the police stand and exposed the case. the sound of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the case stayed in the public security investigation stage and failed to enter the procuratorate for review and prosecution. After this robbery, Guishi Hall has since maintained the Shanghai market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Qian Hui and Gong Feiyun, another &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot; supporter Guan Le also supported Hou Yuanxiang online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guanle claims to be &quot;the first principal of the University of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Great Wall inscription character&quot; and &quot;Chairman of the World Chinese Medicine Hall&quot;. He described &quot;the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; as the &quot;Huangpu Military Academy&quot; of folk Chinese medicine. However, the university claimed to be established 3 years ago, but it has not been established so far. Guan Le once publicly said that after the university was established, he will select &quot;Academician of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Doctor of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; and &quot;Professor of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related information shows that in June 2020, the slogan of the establishment of &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; just shouted, and Guan Le claimed to hold a establishment meeting of a branch of the university. The day after the meeting, Guan Le released an advertisement for a medical training course in multiple Chinese medicine groups, claiming that no medical foundation can learn on the spot, and the training fee is 18,000 yuan (preferential) for two days. Unexpectedly, this move with the &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; was publicly questioned by Gu Jingyu, a doctor of a three -section of Jiangsu family in Jiangsu, and Guan Le responded: &quot;Civil Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; is innovation: &quot;Since it is innovation, there must be no certificate. Without a certificate, it must be illegal ... &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After going to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, Gong Feiyun and Guan Le met in Shanghai. And ask him to speak up in the case of Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On September 9, 2023, the preparatory meeting of the Second Civil Medicine University planned by Guanle was held in Beijing. During the meeting, the Hou Yuanxiang case was discussed during the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(Hou Yuanxiang case) is equivalent to uniting all folk Chinese medicine.&quot; Gong Feiyun told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the second trial of the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine, after the re -review was returned, the supporters of Hou Yuanxiang were jubilant, and they released the &quot;good news&quot; online, thinking that the case had a &quot;major turnaround&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Soon after that, there was another news from the media -Hou Yuanxiang was on a hunger strike, and the news was &quot;true.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei quickly posted a short video to clarify, saying that Hou Yuanxiang could not eat because he was weak, and his apprentice &quot;because he was afraid that someone would hurt Hou Lao and deliberately posted a hunger hunger strike in order to attract the attention of the whole society. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few days later, Wu Pengfei posted a short video, saying that &quot;Hou Lao&quot; recovered, and began to &quot;drink a little wine&quot; every meal. … &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; According to Li Gang, a lawyer in the second instance, after the second trial retracement, because &quot;too many people who knew (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s original surveillance residential place)&quot;, the police replaced Hou Yuanxiang for a place to perform surveillance and residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;I no longer participate in this matter&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng (pseudonym) is the grandson of a patient with a Jilin cancer patient in Hou Yuanxiang. In the case, he also participated in the public opinion battle for Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 8, 2022, after Hou Yuanxiang filed a appeal, a WeChat person named &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; added Li Cheng&#39;s WeChat, claiming to be the daughter -in -law of &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Can you write a joint letter to Professor Hou for a love?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;What happened to Professor Hou?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I was reported by others , Now I still can&#39;t take my own medicine in the hospital. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng knew that Hou Yuanxiang had an accident. He told&quot; Meteor and sunset &quot;that he could help Hou Yuanxiang write a joint letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months later, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; pulled Li Cheng into a WeChat group that supported Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng&#39;s mobile phone has a number marked as &quot;Director Li&#39;s anti -cancer&quot;, which was given by Hou Yuanxiang. He bought medicine for Grandpa to contact this &quot;Director Li&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before receiving a call from a reporter from the Southern Weekend, Li Cheng always thought that &quot;Director Li&quot; was called &quot;Li Jianying&quot; and was the person in charge of the medicine of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in fact, &quot;Director Li&quot; is Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s son Hou Lei, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; is Li Jianying. She is also the only one among all the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, in the case of Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Yuanxiang said that &quot;Professor Hou&quot; was responsible for providing formula, diagnosis and treatment of cancer diseases, and selling medicines. Chinese herbal medicine, boiled Chinese medicine, etc., his son Hou Lei was pretending to be responsible for taking the medicine and returned medicine &quot;Director Li&quot;, which is Li Jianying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After more than a month of WeChat with &quot;Meteor and Santa&quot;, Li Cheng and Hou Yuanxiang also contacted. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) said that putting my information on the Internet, I said, as long as it is helpful to your case.&quot; Li Cheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng also suggested that Hou Yuanxiang talked about this on the self -media platform to increase attention. &quot;He said, let me let the family get it at home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, Hou Yuanxiang sent some case materials to Li Cheng to help him contact the media. There have been no news since then. Li Cheng failed to help Hou Yuanxiang contact the media. Until late 2023, he sent a message to Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;He gave me a sentence and said that (second instance) was about to open the trial, the problem was not big.&quot; This is Li Cheng&#39;s last contact with Hou Yuanxiang. Prior to this, the Hou family proposed that Li Cheng&#39;s personal information was put on the Internet as one of the cases of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;cure&quot; cancer patients, and he agreed. However, before the list was sent to the Internet, Li Cheng&#39;s grandfather died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After knowing the truth, Li Cheng realized that things were &quot;not so simple&quot; - &quot;I don&#39;t know these, I don&#39;t know at all. Let&#39;s help, but the premise must be within the framework of the law ... I no longer participate in this matter. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[床虱危机或已蔓延至香港：为何太阳晒不倒，杀虫剂无效？丨硬核唠科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260875]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https: //////////// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[同性性行为进化的逻辑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260881]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Same-sex sexual behavior cannot directly produce offspring, and has long been regarded as a paradox of Darwinian evolution. . Because according to general understanding, in nature where natural selection and survival of the fittest occur, same-sex sexual behavior consumes precious energy and time but fails to produce offspring. Such behavior should have been eliminated in evolution, but the reality is that same-sex sexual behavior is still in the process of evolution. There is no shortage of them in nature and human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have discovered same-sex behavior in more than 1,500 species of animals. Such behavior is not affected by gender and can occur between two males or two females. It appears in artificial breeding environments and also in the wild. It is not an accidental behavior forced by extreme environments. This also poses a difficult problem for scientists to understand its evolutionary logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, researchers from the University of Granada in Spain and other institutions tried to verify some relevant explanatory hypotheses through germline analysis of a large number of mammal same-sex sexual behavior information. Their latest research, published in Nature Communications, suggests that the evolution of same-sex sexual behavior is likely an adaptation to nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Maintaining same-sex social relationships&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Same-sex sexual behavior occurs in many mammalian species, including our relatives the great apes. Rather than classifying it as maladaptive or abnormal behavior, our study shows that this sexual behavior in mammals is a convergent adaptation that helps maintain social relationships and reduce same-sex conflicts.&quot; Lead author of the latest study, while at the Spanish Arid Zone Experimental Station Function and Evolution José M. Gómez, a professor at the Department of Ecology and the University of Granada, told Southern Weekend reporters that although same-sex sexual behavior occurs in many species, it is especially common among primates. This may Precisely because primates are more social than many other groups of mammals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a data point of view, research has found same-sex sexual behavior in more than 260 species of mammals. In more than 80% of the cases, it takes the form of back crawling or genital contact, and less than 30% Some species even display same-sex behavior through courtship or pairing. Judging from the age, same-sex sexual behavior mainly occurs in adult mammals, and young same-sex sexual behavior is only found in 10 species of animals. From an environmental perspective, more than 80% of the samples had same-sex sexual behavior occurring in wild or semi-wild environments. In terms of gender, same-sex behavior is relatively evenly distributed among mammals. Female same-sex behavior has been recorded in more than 160 species, and male same-sex behavior has been found in more than 190 species. Combined, about half of all species have same-sex behavior. Homosexuality involving two genders at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the latest study is only based on existing records of same-sex sexual behavior in mammals and does not represent the entire situation of mammals. In fact, because the discovery of same-sex sexual behavior in nature relies on observation, and in some species females and males look very similar, and it is even difficult to distinguish between male and female. Some scientists estimate that the current records of same-sex sexual behavior in nature should be underestimated. Moreover, compared with mammals, birds, reptiles, fish, insects and other invertebrates are either small in size or live far away from the ground, making observation difficult, but they have all recorded same-sex sexual behavior. Therefore, patterns of same-sex sexual behavior in nature are far more complex than what has been observed in mammals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, many hypotheses interpreted same-sex sexual behavior as maladaptive or abnormal behavior, speculating that this behavior may be a manifestation of specific conditions such as incorrect gender identity, lack of opposite-sex peers, or frustration with opposite-sex sexual behavior. From the perspective of sexual behavior scenarios, the latest research has found that same-sex sexual behavior does not necessarily require extremely special occasions. Although same-sex sexual behavior is rare in some species and can only be observed in very special circumstances, for about 40% of the mammals studied, same-sex sexual behavior can be regarded as moderate to high frequency activity during a specific period of time, and during mating Seasons are easy to observe. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Same-sex and opposite-sex coexist&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;And some behavioral observations have long shown that same-sex sexual behavior may play a positive role in some populations. For example, some same-sex behavior among male bottlenose dolphins may help strengthen alliances among small groups, and same-sex behavior among female bonobo groups may promote reconciliation among members. However, the latest study&#39;s germline analysis does not focus on the mechanisms of same-sex sexual behavior in specific species, but uses large-scale statistics to link same-sex sexual behavior to social behavior. This research shows that same-sex sexual behavior is similar to many other behavioral traits that have evolved through natural selection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jose Gomez reminded that the meaning of same-sex sexual behavior here should be understood within the framework of evolutionary biology, which is still different from the current human society’s views on gender and other related issues. Because in the study of evolutionary biology, same-sex sexual behavior is a temporary behavior of individuals in a certain period of time, not a permanent behavior or life choice. They may also have heterosexual sexual behavior at the same time. Therefore, it cannot be directly related to human society. behavior analogy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In human society, issues related to same-sex sexual behavior are rooted in different cultural environments and historical traditions in different places, and are more complicated to understand. But in recent years, the discussion of distinguishing human same-sex sexual behavior has also attracted the attention of scientists. The core concern is to what extent people who have had same-sex sexual behavior can be defined as homosexual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, researchers from Harvard University and other institutions published a large-scale genetic study in Science magazine, trying to reveal the genetic characteristics of same-sex sexual behavior, which is the so-called &quot;homosexuality&quot; Gene&quot;. Through collaboration with the British Biobank and genetic testing analysis company 23andMe, researchers finally identified multiple genetic loci related to same-sex sexual behavior from hundreds of thousands of genetic samples, indicating that the &quot;gay gene&quot; is similar to other behavioral traits. It is also polygenic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in 2021, scientists from sex and gender research institutions such as Indiana University’s Kinsey Institute publicly expressed opposition to this research, believing that it only distinguishes people by whether they have had same-sex sexual intercourse. It conflates heterosexuality, bisexuality and homosexuality, and does not accurately measure people&#39;s sexual behavior, sexual attraction and sexual identity. Therefore, the genetic characteristics ultimately discovered may not reveal the tendency to have same-sex sexual behavior, but only reveal the likes. The personality trait of pursuing novelty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because in the view of sexology researchers, heterosexuality should be a continuous pattern of sexual attraction. Just because a person has had same-sex sexual behavior does not mean that he is not heterosexual. Alfred Kinsey, the pioneer of sexology research, developed a scale very early to distinguish people who have had same-sex sexual behavior. According to the frequency of same-sex sexual behavior, people can be divided into multiple types, rather than Either gay or straight. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It may help reproduction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The controversy in human society about how to distinguish same-sex sexual behavior from homosexuality also reflects a difficulty in understanding the logic of evolution to a certain extent. Compared with human society, which highly binds concepts such as &quot;same-sex sexual behavior&quot;, &quot;homosexuality&quot; and &quot;no offspring&quot;, same-sex sexual behavior may never mean &quot;no offspring&quot; in the long evolutionary history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Darwin&#39;s paradox of evolution should be put aside; it no longer exists because the existence of bisexual behavior in various animal species ensures that same-sex behavior does not hinder reproductive success.&quot; Empire Vincent Savolainen, a professor at the Department of Life Sciences at the Polytechnic Institute of Technology, told Southern Weekend reporters that there are many concepts surrounding same-sex sexual behavior, but from a biological perspective, same-sex sexual behavior may be the same as homosexuality, bisexuality, etc. There are some similar mechanisms and evolutionary logic, which biologists can continue to study in the future. At the same time, psychologists can also delve into other aspects of this complex behavior, such as sexual preferences, to better understand the evolution of same-sex behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a historical perspective on same-sex sexual behavior, the key reason why evolutionary logic is difficult to understand lies in the inference that its adaptation costs are too high and the cost of behavior is too high. However, including the latest research, many studies in recent years have shown that same-sex sexual behavior does not mean &quot;no offspring&quot; in the evolutionary process, but may have a positive impact on the reproduction of offspring in other indirect ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Brendan Zietsch, a scientist at the Center for Psychology and Evolution at the University of Queensland in Australia, used genetic data from hundreds of thousands of samples to simulate human evolution, which also included a large number of heterosexual Partner data. The analysis shows that among people who only have heterosexual sex, genetic genes related to same-sex sexual behavior can allow people to have more opposite-sex sexual partners at the same time, which means that they have gained a sexual mating advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further analysis shows that this is also related to the personality traits of openness and risk-taking. People who are more open-minded will be more willing to try new things and have greater curiosity and imagination. Researchers speculate that genes related to same-sex behavior not only endow people with same-sex sexual tendencies, but also give people relevant personality traits, which gives people with relevant genetic genes an advantage in finding opposite-sex partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, although same-sex sexual behavior itself does not produce offspring, related genes can give people the advantage of having offspring, resulting in same-sex sexual behavior being preserved to this day in the long evolution. However, Brendan Zic emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that although this study has data advantages, the relevant explanations are still exploratory, and more research is needed to gain an in-depth understanding of the manifestations related to same-sex sexual behavior in order to understand the basis of its evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Heritability in primates&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Professor Vincent Savolainen has also conducted research on same-sex sexual behavior and reached similar conclusions supporting reproductive advantages. . In August 2023, through the analysis of three years of detailed observation data of rhesus monkeys, they found that same-sex sexual behavior is very common in the rhesus monkey community and is basically not affected by factors such as age or community structure, and it does not bring any consequences to them. What fitness costs, conversely, same-sex sexual behavior regulates peer relationships and increases reproductive success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant research was published in Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution, observing the social and sexual behavior of more than two hundred male rhesus monkeys. Combining ancestry data from decades ago, the study shows that same-sex behavior in male rhesus monkeys is both repeatable and heritable, with a heritability rate of 6.4%. This provides the first evidence of same-sex behavior in primates outside of humans. The first evidence that behavior is heritable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Rhesus macaques share more than 70% of their DNA with humans and have a common ancestor with us dating back about 25 million years. They are the main non-human primates used in biomedical research Animals are also excellent models for studying behavioral ecological issues such as same-sex sexual behavior. However, it is worth noting that there are still differences between rhesus monkeys and humans. Through research, we hope to unravel these intricate mysteries and discover the underlying Common behavior in our evolutionary history.&quot; Professor Vincent Savolainen explained to Southern Weekend reporters that the latest research shows that same-sex sexual behavior may be a common feature of primate reproductive ecology, which is important for understanding the behavior of human groups. Same-sex sexual behavior has certain enlightenment, but due to the influence of some unique social factors in human society, same-sex sexual behavior in human society does have a high cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Humans appear to be the only species that exhibits strict homosexuality.&quot; Professor Vincent Savolainen said cultural factors can influence this phenomenon. For example, in Samoa, some gay men, although they have no offspring, actually assume the role of women in society and help raise the children of relatives. &quot;I hope that our research can play a role in cultivating more tolerance culture, and to inclusive gender diversity in nature and human society.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 22:25:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网购二手“人脉”真的靠谱吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260873]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[不在职业资格目录中的“律师经纪人”，3860元拿证]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; have appeared in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (People Visual courtesy)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; appear in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023, a recommendation letter issued by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association was circulated in the legal community. The letter showed that the association recommended a &quot;lawyer broker&quot; to the Haicheng City People&#39;s Court as a litigation agent in a loan dispute case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the letters of recommendation were made public, many lawyers posted on social media to express concerns that lawyer brokers might corrupt the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyer broker&quot; is not the first time that &quot;lawyer broker&quot; has appeared. With this keyword, 27 civil and enforcement cases can be retrieved on the Judgment Document Network. Among them, 24 cases in which lawyers and brokers acted as litigation agents were heard by courts at all levels in Liaoning Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is certain that lawyer brokerage should be a job type &quot;created&quot; by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. The association recommends others as litigation attorneys in the name of social groups. However, relevant legal persons pointed out that the operations of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violated relevant legal regulations, and there are no occupations related to &quot;lawyer brokerage&quot; in the national professional qualification catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After this matter was fermented in the legal community, the local lawyers association issued a reminder: Lawyers discovered the problem of &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties. You should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of relevant companies or institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;For each case represented, 500 yuan is required to be paid to the association&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;In past cases, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; mainly appeared in insurance disputes, contract disputes, and private lending disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a motor vehicle traffic accident liability dispute ruled by the Yuhong District People&#39;s Court of Shenyang City in March 2023, Xiao drove a passenger car and rode an electric bicycle and ran a red light. Yang Mou collided, causing Yang to be injured. Yang then sued Xiao and the two insurance companies that Xiao insured, demanding various compensations totaling about 250,000 yuan. Both of Yang&#39;s litigation attorneys are &quot;lawyers and agents.&quot; In the end, the Shenyang Yuhong District Court ordered the insurance company to pay compensation of about 120,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a contract dispute with the case number (2022) Liao 14 Min Zhong No. 1093, Yang and Liu signed a tableware factory transfer agreement, stipulating that Yang A certain person paid the transfer fee of RMB 170,000 in installments, but after the first payment period expired, Yang did not pay as agreed. Liu then sued Yang to demand performance of the contract and payment of liquidated damages, totaling approximately 200,000 yuan. Yang lost the case and appealed to the Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court, entrusting a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to serve as his litigation agent. The Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court did not support Yang&#39;s appeal, and the second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The similarity between these cases is that the &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; who represent the cases come from the same social organization: the Lawyers and Brokers Special Committee of the Liaoning Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Social Organization Credit Information Disclosure Platform shows that the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was registered and established in 2007. Its supervisory unit is the Liaoning Provincial Supply and Marketing Cooperative Federation, and its business scope In order to guide the work of the brokerage industry in the province, organize broker business training and provide legal, policy, information consulting services, etc. to brokers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Special Committee for Lawyers and Brokers is a subsidiary organization of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. The association stated in the &quot;Instructions for the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate&quot; that, Possessing the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate can solve the problem of agency litigation qualification: you only need to pay 3,860 yuan once, and you can obtain the certificate after training and examination. &quot;You can pass the test without a legal basis.&quot; After that, you can act as an agent in civil litigation in Liaoning Province. cases, and engage in related activities such as appearing in court to respond to lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, those who have obtained the broker qualification certificate need to pay 500 yuan to the association to issue a recommendation letter for each case they represent. In addition, the broker&#39;s qualification certificate needs to be inspected every year, and the fee is 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Obviously different from citizen agents&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lawyer broker The events have once again put citizen agency in the spotlight. However, attorney-broker representation cases initiated by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association are significantly different from normal citizen representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the amendment of the Civil Procedure Law in 2012, the law allowed three categories of citizens to represent civil litigation cases: close relatives of the parties, relevant social groups or employees of the unit where they work. persons; other citizens entrusted by the parties concerned and approved by the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Zhiwei, deputy director of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Applied Law Research Base of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, said that the quality of citizen agency services is poor, fees are irregular, and it is easy to breed judicial rent-seeking, Regarding issues such as bribing judges, when the Civil Procedure Law was revised in 2012, &quot;other citizens permitted by the court&quot; were deleted, and the scope of citizens as entrusted litigation agents was limited to two categories: close relatives or staff of the parties; communities where the parties are located, Citizens recommended by units and relevant social groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Further requirements for community recommendation can be found in the interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the application of the Civil Procedure Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It stipulates that if relevant social groups recommend citizens to serve as litigation agents, the groups should be non-profit legal persons registered and established in accordance with the law. The principal shall be a member of a social group, or the domicile of one of the parties shall be in the area of ​​activity of the social group. In addition, the recommended person should also be the person in charge of the society or a staff member who has a labor relationship with the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with relevant regulations, Wu Zhiwei believes that strictly speaking, the behavior of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violates the provisions of Article 87 of the Judicial Interpretation, &quot;These people do not Qualified to act as an agent in legal matters.&quot; The agency affairs must fall within the business scope specified in the articles of association of the social group. The business scope of the broker association is generally related to brokers. However, judging from the currently public judgment documents, the client in the case is not Brokers, &quot;If brokers have relevant civil disputes, they act as litigation agents, which is in compliance with the regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another question is whether social groups can provide paid services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as 1993, the Ministry of Justice issued the &quot;Reply on Individual Citizens Not to Engage in Paid Legal Services Without Approval&quot; which explicitly required that citizen agents No remuneration can be collected. According to relevant regulations, travel expenses in citizen representation can be reimbursed by the parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But lawyers and brokers obviously charge fees. On November 14, 2023, the verdict of a contract dispute in Liaoning Province was circulated in the lawyer community: a lawyer and agent was sued by the client for failing to perform his obligation to appear in court in a previous divorce lawsuit, and requested the return of 5,000 yuan in legal services. fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Tips for Social Organizations to Carry out Legal Service Activities&quot; issued by the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on March 22, 2023 has mentioned that individual Social organizations illegally recommend citizens to act as agents in lawsuits and seek unfair economic benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This reminder sheet mentions that in accordance with relevant regulations, law-related social organizations strictly implement a management system with dual responsibilities between the registration management agency and the business supervisory unit. Social organizations shall carry out activities in accordance with the purposes and business scope stipulated in their articles of association and shall not engage in for-profit business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Not in the National Vocational Qualification Catalog&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although Liaoning Province The Brokers Association has issued lawyer broker qualification certificates to many people, but the profession of &quot;lawyer broker&quot; is not included in the &quot;National Vocational Qualification Catalog&quot; announced by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security in 2021. The professional qualifications stipulated in this catalog all specify the implementing departments or units, and require that no other institution or unit can set up professional qualifications for implementation on its own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend called Chen Wencheng, president of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association, on related issues. He first stated that he could only undertake work in Liaoning Province. However, he later stated that he currently does not directly engage in civil litigation, nor does he engage in lawyer-broker-related business. As of press time, the association’s official website is no longer displayed properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 16, Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Department of Justice several times. The operator said they did not know anything about &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; and that they could consult the local authorities for specific information. Lawyers Association. Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Lawyers Association several times but received no reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, relevant staff of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs responded that they would investigate the situation related to the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, the Beijing Tongzhou District Lawyers Association issued a reminder that if lawyers discover problems with &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties, , you should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of &quot;legal brokers&quot;, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; and other related companies and institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Liaoning Province, Fushun Civil Affairs Bureau, Tieling Civil Affairs Bureau and other agencies have issued similar reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>