<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[玉树光影澜湄源丨指尖华夏③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257583]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Yushu Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Qinghai Province, the birthplace of the Lancang-Mekong River has a pleasant scenery, with landscapes in the morning light and sea of ​​clouds The light and shadow change against the background, and the scenery is picturesque. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;499&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon in Yushu Zaduo County, Qinghai Province, a sea of ​​clouds appears over the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;511&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taken at Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai golden peaks surrounded by the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chadan Wetland, the source of the Lancang River, photographed in Yushu, Qinghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Chunjin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai, Lancang River A sea of ​​clouds appears in the sky. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[红河梯田上，那些逆流的追乡者丨月是故乡明③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257354]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Hani Village, the spring of the cattle herding class&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Yuanyang Hani Rice Terraces Airport Connection Line Construction has made the road conditions in the already extremely isolated mountain villages of Honghe County even worse. Most of the short 8-kilometer mountain road has turned into mud. It took more than half an hour to reach the destination of Qielongzhong Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Farmers resting among the terraces of Qielong Zhongzhai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;39 The 20-year-old Che Zhixiong picked me up at the door of my house and helped me carry my luggage up to the Datongbu room on the third floor of my old house. This is for investigators from all over the world doing ethnoanthropological research. Different from the village youths, he went to Gejiu, a major town in southern Yunnan, to work for two years before he was 20 years old. He then returned to the village and worked as a team leader and veterinarian. Six years ago, he began to organize nearby left-behind children and teach them to sing and dance traditional Hani. Song and dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun, the administrative village to which Qielong Zhongzhai belongs, is the birthplace of Hani multi-part folk songs, a national intangible cultural heritage, and Che Zhixiong’s father, Che Kesan, is the provincial inheritor. . In 2018, after attending the one-week village imaging training class of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; in the county seat, Che Zhixiong excitedly set up a Canon DV distributed by a charity organization, shot and recorded the life and festivals of Qielongzhong Village, and then recorded his The edited materials are saved to the hard drive for researchers from Kunming to take away when they come over. &quot;In the past three years, two 4T hard drives have been filled up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another house opposite the residence is Che Zhixiong&#39;s new home. . Last summer, with the help of 40,000 yuan in project start-up funds donated by a caring fan of Wang Yibo, Brother Che emptied the first floor and repainted it, turning it into a &quot;local imaging and cultural transmission hall.&quot; On the wall between the load-bearing columns, two LCD TVs are hung. The station at the door was broadcasting a CCTV set of the rice-planting gate opening ceremony filmed and produced in the village. When the rice-planting girl marries the young man from the field in early spring, the villagers who plant the rice-planting are all the bridesmaids and best men. Planting the rice-planting in a good field means marrying into a good family. Che Kesan frequently appears in the camera. As the ditch leader, he has to strictly measure the proportion of each ditch dug to ensure that the water from the forest reservoir flows fairly and accurately into the field ridges of each household. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV inside is Che Zhixiong&#39;s own &quot;Personal Film Exhibition&quot;. The sudden heavy hailstorm, the city children who came here for study tours, and the slaughter of cattle to worship the gods during the &quot;June Year&quot;, each section is an anthropological documentary with a complete narrative and clear rhythm. &quot;Most of my peers don&#39;t understand so many Hani rituals, let alone children. I only have a third-grade elementary school education, and all I can do is film and edit all the festivals here,&quot; Village Eyes &#39;People then use it to add subtitles. As for Kuaishou Douyin, it may occasionally attract attention, but it is not complete and even the surface is not captured.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New documentary director Che Zhixiong, Talk about your creative passion. He then pointed to the &quot;One Year&#39;s Festival Ritual&quot; display board on the wall between the two LCD TVs. For example, in the first month of the lunar calendar, the Hani people hold Lazuozuo and Angmatu successively, both of which are sacrificial ceremonies for the dead. &quot;Our ancestors will turn into little gods after they die, and they may come back to harass us. After death, the little gods will turn into great gods, and only then will they bless us. We kill cows for sacrifice to ensure that they can turn into great gods. . When the great god dies, it turns into dew, which drips down at night to irrigate the terraced fields and breed new life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It happened that an old man in the village was about to leave, so the driver took me to where the villagers kept watch. room. All the middle-aged and elderly people who stayed behind gathered here. The woman was in the back room, and the man was on the terrace, drinking pot-stewing wine just scooped out of a sealed earthen vat, chewing green chili peppers dipped in chili oil, and chatting in Hani dialect. The old man who smoked hookah encouraged me to be more generous, &quot;Go inside with your phone and take pictures.&quot; The daughter of the deceased man came back and told me, &quot;She is 80 years old, there is no need to stay in the hospital and suffer, let everyone have fun It&#39;s our tradition to stay with you.&quot; Later, most people would go home and sleep, but there would always be someone staying with them to wait for the final moments. Che Zhixiong carried the old man on his back, and while watching him the documentary he shot on TV, he told me, &quot;The bema (shaman) in the village will calculate the exact day to leave, and the funeral will begin three days before.&quot; . The posthumous affairs are more grand, and one or twenty cows may have to be killed and raised in the underworld for the deceased. This is not an exaggeration. Each of the children will have one, and if the spouse and family members have others, the beef will be taken back to their respective villages to be divided. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Longzhong Village keeps vigil at night. Che Zhixiong carries the departing old man on his back and watches the documentary he shot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun Village, where the village primary school is located, is only a 20-minute walk from the village. Less than ten children would go to the village every night to learn Hani dance from Che Zhixiong. The popular song &quot;Honey Baby&quot; with a hip-hop style has become a &quot;county dance&quot; vigorously promoted by Honghe primary and secondary schools, and children never tire of dancing it. The &quot;Music and Dance&quot; that has been passed down from our ancestors in production and life is more popular among energetic children because of its rich routines of squatting, jumping, lining up and circling. Accompanied by the cheerful beats and high-fives, I also followed the Hani cattle herding class and entered a selfless state of joy with nature and heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Zhixiong teaches children music and dance in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The young people of Yisa Town dedicated their entire youth to musical instruments&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Honghe County Government The town of Yisa is located at the top of a hill where two winding asphalt roads meet. At the highest edge of the ancient city, starting from the east gate with three floors and three rooms, a large and majestic ancient castle that combines Chinese and Western styles spreads out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a masonry town brought on horseback by local business gangs 90 years ago, and the primitive tribes who practiced slash-and-burn farming, carved wood and knotted ropes were upgraded into &quot;Little Shanghai outside the Yangtze River&quot;. Jiang refers to the Red River that flows to Vietnam and divides Red River Prefecture into two. Places such as Jianshui and Mengzi, which have many Han immigrants and are economically developed, are in the north and are called inside the river; while counties such as Yuanyang, Honghe and Luchun, which have developed world heritage terraced landscapes, are outside the river, which is backward. Yisa means &quot;drought and water shortage&quot; in the dialect of the Yi people who first came here to open up wasteland. During the Qianlong period, copper mines were discovered in the mountains, and immigrants followed the mining industry. These ancestors also experienced a history of prosperity and decline with the Qing Dynasty. At the end of the Qing Dynasty, the copper mines dried up and the new mountain people had no land to cultivate. They had to drag horses and go deep into the mountains and forests of Southeast Asia to do trade. They gradually developed from traditional caravans to tobacco gangs. In the early years of the Republic of China, the government&#39;s vigorous crackdown on opium led to a sharp increase in black market profits. Cigarette gangs organized and strengthened private militia to safeguard their vested interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; The French designers I knew drew drawings and hired Jiangnan craftsmen to build various stone mansions with European-style exteriors and Chinese-style interiors, row upon row on the hills. Since then, more men have dispersed overseas and reorganized their families, making Honghe County the second largest hometown of overseas Chinese in Yunnan, with more than 10,000 overseas Chinese distributed in 18 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wave of overseas immigrants on horseback has long been replaced by the wave of designated labor exports. But there are always people who insist on staying behind, such as Awen, the traditional musical instrument maker and inheritor I met at the east gate. &quot;Do you understand Honghe dialect? I can&#39;t speak Mandarin.&quot; Awen confessed in advance on WeChat. The craftsman who doesn’t speak Mandarin must be an old man with a white beard smoking a hookah, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the bluestone road, the roaring Aprilia 150 motorcycle turned off its engine. The &quot;white vest&quot; on the car took off the helmet with the three colors of the Italian flag. The cool guy with a ponytail stepped forward and said, &quot;I That’s Ah Wen.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I went from the village to the county cultural center to work when I was sixteen or seventeen years old. Now I am 35 years old, and I have dedicated all my youth to musical instruments.” In the restaurant next to Daguangtang in the center of the ancient town, Ah Wen Wen continued to introduce himself. &quot;I quit my job last year. I know nothing but making musical instruments. I&#39;m so hurt by music!&quot; Although he was a little sad, when he was flipping through the various beautiful instruments on his phone, Awen became excited again, &quot;I ride a motorcycle. When I visited various villages in Hani, I couldn&#39;t put it down when I saw these treasures. Every sanxian and every straw have different materials, appearance and sound quality. They can&#39;t be made in factories. They will be gone when the older generation leaves. I can only Take photos and videos, listen to the sounds, and restore them all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dinner, we walked through the lush Xishan Park and walked to the musical instrument workshop next to the County Cultural Center. Master Wu Zhiming was lying on a bamboo chair. When he heard me say that he had just come from Qielong Zhongzhai, memories of his life came back to him, &quot;It can be said that it was them who started my career, and I played a role as a link between past and future.&quot; 1986 In May, when Wu Zhiming, who was employed by the County Culture and Sports Bureau, went to Puchun to collect folk music, he heard the eight-part chorus of rice-planting girls coming from a distance, and followed the sound to find it... Later, he changed from a county actor to a song and dance creator. and music theory researchers, and brought Hani singing and dancing to the world. Ah Wen and Che Zhixiong have traveled as far as Shandong and Beijing respectively, but their master and father have already traveled to Taiwan, Singapore, Japan and the Netherlands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Awen from Yisa Town Musical Instrument Making Workshop&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like those young and middle-aged people in the city who are separated from their work units and pursue personal values, Awen also worries about how to monetize his hobbies. &quot;Many scholars and teachers can only provide spiritual support, but &#39;Village Eyes&#39; has raised 10,000 to 20,000 yuan for me.&quot; . But there are many others, but even a small business loan of 50,000 yuan cannot be approved.&quot; With the capital, Awen can build his own studio and improve the efficiency of working all night and three days to make two sanxian. One piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still have to be realistic and start with a wind instrument that saves time and materials. Although it is not as good as the cucurbit flutes in the pedestrian streets of ancient cities, you should try to reduce the production cost first, and then put it into Go to the Samaba Visitor Center to try out the sales.&quot; Xu Tianming, an old colleague who still works at the County Cultural Center, reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming is from the Yi ethnic group. In June 2021, under the guidance of the state song and dance troupe, he and other colleagues rehearsed the first courtyard drama &quot;Caravan Women&quot; in Honghe Prefecture. The Wanxing Courtyard was staged by relying on money. As the name of the play suggests, it tells the stories of chaste women displayed in this mansion. The dancers, from the image of disgraced grooms at the beginning, jumped to become a men&#39;s team in suits returning home joyfully, and the girls who looked through the love finally became the old mothers holding a revolving door, looking forward to the return of their husbands. Although the over-an-hour play is in a very complete musical format, it is not an original performance and is reduced to a series of popular Han-style compositions. Moreover, because the fee is not enough, embarrassing copyright information often comes out of the soundtrack. . Everything is difficult at the beginning. The ticket agent told me that starting with their play, all the counties and cities in Honghe Prefecture will create their own courtyard dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Hollowed Village, a Holiday Paradise for City People&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming suggested that Awen go to Samaba, which sells bamboo flutes. It is located at the end of the gently undulating hillside and is the most famous place in Honghe County. The scenic area has more than 14,000 acres of the world&#39;s largest concentrated contiguous terraces with more than 4,300 levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samaba Terraces&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A on the other side of the landscape terraces Although Yinxiang is the birthplace of the 600-year-old Hani Street Festival, the most beautiful historical and cultural village &quot;Zuofu&quot; failed to retain a few mushroom houses with ethnic characteristics and was replaced by reinforced concrete. house. Of course, there is nothing wrong with pursuing a once-and-for-all residence, but &quot;it is good to leave many old things in the village and tidy them up. For example, at the east gate of the county, the two mansions of Yao and Qian were used as public prosecutors and detention centers respectively before they became museums. It has always been used as a reservation.&quot; Liu Zhigang, who manages Kangteng·Honghehe Valley Tent Camp deep in Jiayin Township, as an outside operator, has a relatively objective and neutral voice on rural protection and development issues, &quot;and it is not far from Jiayin Township. There is a Tusi Mansion, and it is very grandiose. It could not have been so grand before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conten Company, which creates high-end vacation products, chose the project outside the scenic area because it had to find convenience for renovation. of hollowed out villages. &quot;Shitou Village has been empty for more than ten years. There are only one or two families who have owned houses in the new village. They use the old houses to store farm tools. It is not difficult for us to use them as campsites.&quot; Liu Zhigang is now busy developing another hollow village. , Suhong Village in the core area of ​​Samaba Rice Terraces. To this end, a tourism investment company has been established with the county government, and famous architect Zhang Yonghe has been hired as the chief planner to create timeshare real estate based on the &quot;low-involvement&quot; concept to allow urbanites to live in rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the heavy rain, the county road from the camp to Suhong Village was completely cut off by mudslides, and we had to climb down the narrow village road with hundreds of turns. The landscape along the road gradually changes from the rain-watered mulberry trees and red chrysanthemums at high altitudes to the steaming dense banana forest with broad leaves covering the sky. In the past, the smoke-traveling gang probably often did this, shuttling back and forth between alpine mountains and tropical dense forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A corner of Suhong Village&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Hani people’s hoes are But the enemy&#39;s iron gun. Seven thousand women have become widows, seven thousand children can&#39;t see their parents, the high swings have been knocked down, and the three-story mushroom houses have been burned down.&quot; An ancient Hani song once lamented the ancestors The fate of being defeated all the way and moving southward. After finally settling in the &quot;two mountains and three rivers&quot; area consisting of Ailao Mountain, Wuliang Mountain, Lancang River, Yuanjiang River and Honghe River, with the help of my good friend Old Buffalo, we dug out magnificent terraces with hoe after hoe. Nowadays, except for a few local people who work in the camp due to the demand for original ecological services, for more Honghe youths like Awen who stay in their hometown, city people come to experience the terraced life of transplanting rice seedlings, harvesting in autumn, and setting up tents. It&#39;s so familiar that it won&#39;t be rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;People chasing hometown&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The NAS system of the computer in the Kunming office of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; stores a large number of documentaries shot by Che Zhixiong. This is a public welfare organization that helps farmers and herdsmen in western rural areas record the ecological and cultural changes in their hometown through their own ethnic perspective and using cameras as tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who introduced Che Zhixiong to me was Li Xudong, a young man from his hometown who had just graduated more than a year ago. &quot;I studied hotel management at a private university. After graduation, I worked as a housekeeper in a high-end B&amp;B in Dali for two months. In August last year, I saw someone posting the official account &#39;Village Eyes&#39; in one of my most active groups. I was attracted to this charity organization after reading an article about Hani’s cattle herding class.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the male classmates in the village who went out to work and the female classmates who married early, Adong, who was born in 1996, They are very few young people who have a conscious sense of national identity early on. “Since my sophomore year, from January to April every year, I have taken leave, hitchhiked home from Kunming, participated in organizing the grand Silhouette Festival, written event planning, served as host, worked as a financial accountant, and dressed in national costumes , followed the horn team, taking the children who no longer have contact with the seedlings, to play in the terraced fields. This festival is a rest and entertainment time for the Hani people after planting the spring seedlings, and they also look forward to the rich autumn harvest in a few months.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A Dong also cooperates with four friends to operate a public account - People Chasing Hometown. Share the Hani branch, costumes, rituals, music, poetry and other content mainly in Honghe County at any time, publish essays by fellow villagers, and launch an essay collection activity for primary and secondary school students in your hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meet Hani villagers on the road&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Honghe Hani Rice Terraces were successfully applied for World Heritage status It has been 8 years, and it has given local people cultural confidence. &quot;The current situation should be said to be &#39;what goes in and what goes out&#39;. The return flow has increased. Young people go out to work, but when they are over 40 years old, more people come back. At the same time, the part-time status of half-farmers, half-workers also makes the villagers&#39; The enthusiasm for farming is back.&quot; Zhang Hongzhen, director of the Hani Terraces Protection and Development Research Center at Honghe University, recounted his observations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我所理解的五千年中华文明之精华]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257944]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China is a giant country in terms of population, land area, and history and culture. The late well-known archaeologist Su Bingqi, who proposed the &quot;starry sky&quot; theory about the origin of Chinese civilization, once said that what we want to build is a modernization with Chinese characteristics commensurate with the ancient country of five thousand years of civilization. This naturally puts forward the idea of ​​five thousand years of civilization. What is the essence, what is the national soul, and what is the spiritual pillar? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of &quot;Chinese nation&quot; was proposed by Liang Qichao a hundred years ago, but even starting from the Liangzhu Culture characterized by jade culture, the civilization creation of our ancestors on the land of China has exceeded 5000 years. The Liangzhu ancestors’ divine and animal facial patterns, head-up and head-down dragons, and tomb forms with obvious ritual connotations, all clearly show that they are an important source of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese civilization naturally has more than one origin. In addition to the Liangzhu Culture in the Taihu Lake area, there are also the Hongshan Culture in western Liaoning, the Yangshao Culture in the Central Plains, the Pengtoushan-Chengbeixi Culture in the Yangtze River Basin, the Longshan Culture that is a fusion of various cultures in China, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The basic spirit of Chinese civilization has gradually formed in the historical development, including the invention of square characters, the &quot;work&quot; of the &quot;system&quot; of the previous kings in the actual social development form, and the &quot;narration&quot; of the previous teachers, as well as The &quot;interpretation&quot; of scholars and intellectuals of all dynasties. Whether it is the &quot;new underground materials&quot; that are advancing rapidly in the modern era or the rich ancient documents dating back to Oracle Bone Inscriptions and Bronze Inscriptions, they can all help us today understand more deeply what the &quot;Chinese national spirit&quot; is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this understanding cannot only be directed towards the past. Although Zhou is an old state, its destiny is renewed. It is facing the future and participating in the present. Here, I try to summarize what I understand about Chinese civilization from five aspects: society, politics, faith, economy, and culture and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Society: Family Orientation and Individuality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a social perspective, we attach great importance to the value of a small community such as &quot;family&quot;, which leads to the spirit of benevolence and individual personality. growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benevolent people are the most important to people who are close to each other. To be close means to be filial to one&#39;s parents, to be kind to one&#39;s children, and to be friendly to one&#39;s brothers and sisters based on human blood and nature. And &quot;Old people are like the old people, young people are like the young people&quot;, and this kind of love is extended to everyone. Different from Mohism’s proposition of universal love, as the mainstream of Han culture, Confucianism admits that “there are differences in love”, but it still has a feeling of universal love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern people tend to value individualism first. Does this kind of &quot;familism&quot; conflict with respect for individual personality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a motivational point of view, parents raising their children comes from their own nature and is the best natural mechanism to help individuals grow. Family love provides relatively pure love and good emotions between parents and children. In terms of children&#39;s growth, the family structure can provide more support. From the perspective of ethnic continuity, this culture is obviously beneficial to increasing fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dear love does not advocate unconditional submission. If parents are at fault, the &quot;Book of Filial Piety&quot; advocates that &quot;there are faults in the family&quot;, but it only advises parents to pay attention to their attitude and methods. Mencius encouraged everyone to &quot;nurture my awe-inspiring spirit&quot; and &quot;even if there are thousands of people, I will go there&quot;. It is a kind of personalism with abundant independent consciousness and free spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in reality there are overbearing and irresponsible parents and rebellious children, this is precisely because they have betrayed the love of their relatives and cannot be blamed on this kind of balancing of family structure and individual personality. The social structure and value form of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family, a small community, constitutes a social unit, and the independent individuals with community and public care bred in it have become the foundation of the country. The laws promulgated by the governor should encourage this kind of love, but not destroy it. If conditions are created to make it easier for parents to raise their children and for children to get closer to their parents, it is care that nourishes this spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Political ideal: The world is for the common good&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the mainstream of our culture, individuals not only live within the family structure, but also naturally extend to the country and the world. To cultivate oneself, manage one&#39;s family, govern the country, and bring peace to the world, in &quot;The Great Learning&quot;, individuals need to constantly study things to gain knowledge, be sincere and righteous, and expand their areas of concern and efforts to the vast areas of the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When someone asked Confucius why he did not engage in politics, Confucius quoted &quot;Shangshu&quot; and replied: &quot;Filial piety is only filial piety, and friendship is with brothers.&quot; Politics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a social structure and cultural spirit, &quot;keeping the family together&quot; is already a part of public affairs. Expanding this spirit to a wider social space is also &quot;for government&quot; rather than for government. You must &quot;serve as an official in the government&quot; to enter politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern families are families of three or four, but in Chinese history, unless official laws deliberately required &quot;family separation&quot; to weaken the organizational strength of small communities, our culture often praised &quot;multi-generational families&quot;. &quot;Together under the same roof&quot; encourages large families to live together and help each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of large family living together combines the principles of &quot;kinship&quot;, &quot;respect for respect&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; to form the social autonomy of a small community. From this, the tradition of gentry autonomy was derived. This made it possible to create a &quot;small government, big society&quot; where the imperial power did not extend to the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhou system of feudalism and founding of the country directly used family as a link to establish the basic political order of the entire Chinese world: on the one hand, the eldest son inheritance system was implemented to ensure the institutionalization and stability of the inheritance of power; On the one hand, talented people are selected to govern. Of course, the Zhou system still embodies moral governance in the family and the world, and the degree of openness of power is still limited. In the political field, the value that best embodies the spirit of the Chinese nation is the spirit of &quot;the world is for the common good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original text of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; is: In the journey of the great road, the world is for the common good, selecting talents and talents, adhering to trust and cultivating harmony, old friends do not only kiss their relatives, do not only give birth to their children, so that the old will die well. The strong have their uses, the young have their talents, and those who are modest, widowed, lonely, and lonely are all supported... Another example is &quot;The king and his ministers are united by righteousness.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s not all about the same surname&quot;... These political thoughts, which exude eternal brilliance, have broken through the &quot;kinship&quot; principle of the family and become a concrete manifestation of the commonwealth of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since selfish desires are difficult to eliminate, it is extremely difficult to achieve the goal of serving the world for the common good. Needless to say, the Qin system, from the Han and Tang dynasties to the Song, Ming and Qing dynasties, the separation of imperial power and prime ministerial power, the system of admonishing officials and historians, the feudal system throughout the Han, Tang, and Song dynasties, the education of princes, and the system of co-governance of scholar-bureaucrats, etc., are only partial and It plays a certain role in the short term. Royal power is never truly under the law. The Chinese nation’s political spirit of “the world is for the common good” is so premature and yet so immature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the famous &quot;Debate between Righteousness, Benefit and Overlord&quot; with Chen Liang, Zhu Xi lamented decisively: For fifteen hundred years, he was just sitting on this, so it was just a matter of time to make up for it. Although there may have been some moderate prosperity during this period, the Tao taught by the three kings Yao and Shun, Zhou Gong and Confucius, has not yet been practiced in heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the political standard of the world for the common good continues to exist. Whether to put the interests and happiness of the people first in governance, and whether to keep the economic, social and spiritual life vigorous and prosperous? These political requirements for governors are also an important dimension of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Economy: People have permanent property&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the economy, how does &quot;the world is for the common good&quot; be reflected? For the government, it is &quot;the king, why should he call it profit&quot;. From the emperor, princes to officials, managers at all levels should not compete with the people for profit; for the common people, it is &quot;those who have permanent property have perseverance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to do this specifically? What the government wants to do is to &quot;benefit the people according to their interests&quot; and naturally carry out production, trade and consumption activities based on the needs of the people in the world. Therefore, in the choice between cannon and butter, butter obviously takes precedence. This only requires the establishment of a service-oriented government that provides &quot;benefits at no cost&quot; and cannot compete with the people for profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Benevolent government must start from the borders.” The basis for the interests of the people is to ensure that citizens have their own three-acre land, and they can use their own land according to their personal and family interests. Judgment, to produce and trade. Although Mencius&#39;s proposition mainly focused on delimiting the boundaries of mine fields, its essence pointed to the determination of property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, Mencius also advocated encouraging commerce and protecting travelers by providing warehouses for merchants and requisitioning them in accordance with the law to avoid stagnant goods, only registering and inspecting but not collecting taxes, only doing labor service but not collecting land rent, etc. Let it be beneficial to farmers, so that all merchants in the world will be happy and willing to hide in their markets, all travelers in the world will be happy and willing to go out on their own roads, and all farmers in the world will be happy and willing to plow their fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the current economic reform is concerned, the confirmation and long-term stability of agricultural land rights, as well as deepening the reform of state-owned enterprises, protecting the investment and property rights of the private economy in various fields, tax laws, etc., all fall into this category. economic issues. This also determines whether entrepreneurs have long-term confidence in the Chinese economy and whether they dare to make large investments. In short, the essence of the economic spirit of an ideal Chinese community is to achieve economic prosperity, prosperity and prosperity for the people, and ensure the material life of the people through the property rights, production and trade system of &quot;big public ownership and private ownership&quot; and the fiscal and taxation system that is light on corvee and light on taxes. of plenty. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Belief: The unity of nature and man&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For families, why should fathers be kind and sons should be filial? For rulers, why should the world be for the common good? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do ordinary people have perseverance only if they have perseverance? For a person like Yan Hui, why can he achieve &quot;a basket of food and a ladle of drink, and he cannot bear the worries, but his joy will not change even after he returns&quot;? How can he have perseverance without permanent income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This involves the fourth dimension of Chinese civilization, faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businessmen believed in the personified &quot;Emperor&quot; and were biased toward the dominating heaven; Zhou people believed in &quot;the destiny of heaven is constant, only virtue is the supplementary one&quot;, and in the dominating heaven there was a profound meaning of the heaven of righteousness; although Confucius &quot;revered &quot;Keep the ghosts and gods at a distance&quot;, but still &quot;offer sacrifices to the gods as if they were present&quot;, reminding the disciples to realize the sincere spirit of life from the great popularity of &quot;Heaven can say nothing&quot;, and firmly believe that they carry &quot;Heaven will not lose the grace&quot;, which deepened the Zhou people&#39;s The concept of destiny; in the Han Dynasty, Dong Zhongshu believed that humans are copies of heaven, that heaven and humans can sense each other, and can warn the king of his misconduct and mismanagement with &quot;disasters&quot;; by the Song and Ming dynasties, heaven mainly became the heaven of justice, tending to one an inner transcendence and infinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For heaven, most of the most outstanding kings and sages of the Chinese nation had a strong and heartfelt awe, and regarded the unity of heaven and man as their ultimate pursuit, thus giving integrity to daily life and political life. sense of meaning, certainty and direction. Mencius has a very vivid description of this realm of belief that is both ordinary and holy: what is desirable is called good, what is called self-belief is called faith, what is full is called beauty, what is full and glorious is called great, what is great is called transformation. Holy, what is holy but unknowable is called God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Father&#39;s kindness and son&#39;s filial piety originate from the &quot;nature of destiny&quot; and from &quot;the child is free from the arms of his parents for three years&quot;. If this kind of human nature is brought into full play like Shun in &quot;Yao Canon&quot;, we can A saint who acquires a set of abilities including avoiding disasters, harmonizing the family, and governing the country is a saint who unites nature and man;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Emperor&quot; regards himself as the eldest son of Heaven to gain legitimacy and even sanctity, and must serve Heaven To carry on, we must nourish all people, and the world is for the common good;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ordinary people don’t understand this enough, and they don’t have the time to cultivate themselves. They need a constant income to have perseverance. This is normal, but it has a family “kissing” mechanism. With nourishment, there is still benevolence and righteousness in the heart. As long as you don&#39;t cut it off, you can also see the virtuous and considerate people; The obsession with external objects returns to the state of life where meaning flows. March is not contrary to benevolence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is extremely difficult to truly practice faith. For ordinary people, if they have permanent property and perseverance, maintain a comfortable life and common sense rooted in the meaning of family, they can become qualified members of the Chinese community; for people in high positions, if they cannot &quot;devour their heart and soul to understand heaven, &quot;If you cultivate your mind and cultivate your nature to serve Heaven&quot;, you will begin to pollute a large area from the source of law, politics, culture and education, and spread evil to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Mencius affirmed that all people have the four ideals, he also clearly realized that &quot;human beings are somewhat different from beasts.&quot; He quoted from &quot;Shang Shu·Tai Oath&quot; that &quot;Heaven sees me and the people see me, and God listens to me and the people listen&quot;, and gave a principled explanation of the relationship between heaven and the people. God’s will is unpredictable and manifests itself through public opinion. A holy king who unites nature and man is rare to find in five hundred or even a thousand years, but secular kings who are holy because of their kings are everywhere. The reverence for heaven and the people is not empty talk, so it is necessary to establish a technical system to restrict the royal power, so that public opinion can be fully reflected, and governance can fully reflect public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public opinion may be divided and antagonistic, what should we do? Will it bring about the disadvantages of &quot;welfarism&quot;? Will the &quot;public opinion&quot; of this generation harm the &quot;public opinion&quot; of future generations? These challenges have entered the field of building a modern republic and legal system. In addition to drawing on the more mature modern governance system, we also need to give full play to the spirit of &quot;Spring of the First Year, King Zhengyue&quot; in &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot;. In the era of great changes, we should constantly return to the origin of politics and beliefs, consider profits and losses, and &quot;make&quot; new systems. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Literature and education: Respecting teachers, respecting morality, and vigorous spirit&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Liangzhu, Hongshan, Yangshao to Longshan, from Xia, Shang and Zhou to Qin, Han, Tang, Song, Ming and Qing, the Chinese community gradually formed and split frequently And it can be continuously unified, and the culture whose roots were formed over five thousand years will never be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have a unified square character that has basically not changed since ancient times. Even though &quot;the winds are different in hundreds of miles, and the customs are different in thousands of miles&quot;, a county may have several dialects, but we can still recognize and identify with each other. There is also the ideological system from Zhou Confucius, Mencius, Xun, Lao and Zhuang. They have governed themselves and made history, and they have also learned from history and classics, providing rich resources for spiritual inspiration and institutional reconstruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no insurmountable rivers or mountains in the land of China. Whether it is divided into feudal states or prefectures and counties, the gradually formed Zhou Wen and Han systems, Tang style and Song style are diverse but capable of unification, and have strong agglomeration effect. For thousands of years, no matter what force entered China, it would be transformed by Chinese culture to a large extent. They inherited Chinese culture and therefore gained basic recognition from the scholars in this tradition. This is the attraction and centripetal force of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this cultural spirit faces not only the debate between China and the West, but also the changes in ancient and modern times. How to inherit and update our cultural spirit has been a major issue that several generations of intellectuals in modern times have struggled with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Han Dynasty to the Tang and Song Dynasties, we spent thousands of years absorbing Buddhist culture, which not only gave birth to Chinese Zen Buddhism, but also gave birth to Taoism in the Song and Ming Dynasties. Since the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China, in the face of the strong Western learning and Western politics, scholars from both sides of the Taiwan Strait and three places have translated a large number of translations, digested them quickly, practiced them politically, and compared and absorbed them academically, which has initially opened up a new situation for Chinese culture. The process is far from over. To return to the roots and create new things requires a free and powerful cultural and educational system that represents the fifth dimension of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher is someone who teaches, teaches and resolves doubts. China has a tradition of scholarship. The Jixia Academy, which flourished 2,400 years ago, was once an international academic center in China, even though it was officially run by the Qi State. Scholars from Taoism, Confucianism, Legalism, Ming Dynasty, Ming Dynasty, Agriculture, Yin and Yang, Mencius, Xunzi, Shen Buhai, Lu Zhonglian, Shen Dao and other scholars whose names were important for a time and even influenced thousands of years are here to &quot;discuss without ruling&quot;, &quot; &quot;Discussing state affairs without holding office&quot;, the ideological power derived from this has surged forward with the source of living water, and its influence continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Confucius broke away from &quot;learning in the government&quot; and gave private lectures, to the &quot;Jingshe&quot; in the Han Dynasty, from the &quot;academy&quot; where individuals studied and lectured in the Tang Dynasty, to the Yuelu Academy in the Southern Song Dynasty, where Zhang Shi lectured , the Bailudong Academy restored by Zhu Xi... The folk academy system is well-established, with independent subject-based teaching systems, autonomous methods for students to participate in management, and relatively independent funding sources, finally forming a mature private school system. By the Ming Dynasty, academies such as Longgang, Guiyang, and Kuaiji, which were founded or presided over by Wang Yangming and promoted the purpose of Xinxue, changed to Donglin Academy, which criticized the shortcomings of Xinxue and advocated practical learning. This has never ceased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These academies have the character of pursuing the Tao rather than seeking official positions, the style of study of free debate, the aura of making friends to help others, and the worldly sentiments of &quot;the sound of wind and rain, the sound of reading, family affairs, state affairs, and world affairs.&quot; In &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;, Huang Zongxi even put forward the view that &quot;what the emperor is right may not necessarily be right, and what the emperor is wrong may not be wrong, so the emperor will not dare to be wrong for himself and publicize his right and wrong to the school.&quot; Right and wrong and truth were elevated to a higher status than the emperor, restoring the traditional essence of discussing politics based on Tao, and inspiring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern intellectuals need to inherit the spirit of scholars, not only to interpret and continue the great ancient Chinese civilization, but also to &quot;work&quot; according to the times and explore new philosophical, institutional and scientific principles. In short, the foundation of this cultural and educational system is the guarantee of the institutionalization and legalization of &quot;teachers&quot; and &quot;scholars&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The final conclusion: This article believes that heaven (the belief system in which heaven and man are unified), earth (the economic system in which people have permanent property), and the country (the political system in which the world is for the common good) System), relatives (kinship is the most important, a personality development system nurtured in the family structure), and teachers (a cultural and educational system full of dynamic research, preaching and civilized dialogue), the above five constitute the main content of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国跳水队包揽亚运会跳水项目首个比赛日的两枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:38:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese group Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yu Xi in the competition. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;252916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 30, 2023, the diving competition of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou officially began. The first competition day was the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final and the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final. In the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving competition, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan/Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with a huge advantage. The Chinese team achieved six consecutive titles in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving at the Asian Games. In the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final, although the Chinese team Yan Siyu/He Chao made varying degrees of errors in the fourth and sixth jumps, it did not affect their overall success in winning the gold medal with a 29.55-point lead over the runner-up South Korea. The Chinese diving team won two gold medals on the first competition day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese group will be all red Chan (right)/Chen Yuxi during the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao competed. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 30, the Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform is the first completed event in the Hangzhou Asian Games diving competition. As Olympic champions, this is the first time for the gold medal team of Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan to participate in the Asian Games. The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition does not have preliminaries and will go directly to the finals. In this project, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan are the only ones in the world in terms of strength, while the strong players in the second tier are mainly from Europe and the United States. During the competition, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan led the way from the first jump, with a total score of 375.30 points in 5 jumps, leading the runner-up Japanese team by 85.26 points, and won the first gold medal in diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, Chinese group Yan Siyu (Part 2)/ He Chao is in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard also has no preliminary schedule and goes directly to the finals. The Chinese combination Yan Siyu/He Chao ranked fifth in the order of appearance. During the competition, He Chao and Yan Siyu demonstrated their extremely high technical level and tacit cooperation ability. Taking off, turning, and entering the water, the entire set of movements of the two people is very smooth. Although he successfully won the men&#39;s synchronized three-meter springboard championship, He Chao was not very satisfied with himself because of his mistake in the last jump. &quot;The result was good, but all the movements were not perfect in the process. This is the first time for Yan Siyu to participate in an international competition. I am also participating in an international competition again after six years, which is a test for both of us. But winning this gold medal is our best gift for National Day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On September 30, 2019, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79 .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed the gold medal in their hands to the audience . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao shows the audience the gold medal in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games diving event will be held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium from September 30 to October 4, 2023. A total of 10 gold medals will be produced. gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), and the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Jili (first from the left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Linong Anak Pamg (first from the right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;785&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Matsuri (first left), the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Rinon Anak Pamg (first from right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Yan Siyu (third from left)/He Chao (third from right), the runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae-kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan ( Second from left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/01/53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;793&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/ 53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, champion Chinese group Yan Siyu (third from left)/ He Chao (third from right), runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae Kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan (second from left) and third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik Bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[易水悲风：追寻燕国往事丨古国多少事③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257352]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The wind is coming again. The imaginary group of people gradually disappeared on the other side of the misty water, but the imaginary wine and food still exuded steam, as if chasing the sound of construction and singing that had just disappeared... More than two thousand years passed by in a blink of an eye, and this road from North China The rivers flowing across the plains brought me closer to those people and things that were far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The river is named Yishui, and it is famous in history because of that famous farewell. ——That year, they sang softly by the river:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wind rustles and the water becomes cold,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strong man will never return once he is gone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yishuihan, Yixian County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yandu&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;The North China Great Plain extends to Yixian County, Hebei Province, and has reached its western edge. In the county town, looking to the west from a high altitude, a line of dark mountains stretches across the end of the plain, which is the Taihang Mountains that separate the North China Plain and the Shanxi Plateau. The Yishui that gives Yixian County its name originates from the eastern foothills of Taihang Mountain. In fact, the Yishui is not one river, but divided into three: North Yishui, Zhongyishui and Nanyishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various signs that that famous farewell should be on the shore of Zhongyi River. The man named Jing Ke, when he finished singing generously amidst the sound of Gao Jianli&#39;s construction, and everyone&#39;s eyes were splitting with anger, he had already jumped on the carriage and headed to Xianyang, the capital of Qin, two thousand miles away. In order to repay Prince Dan for his kindness, he is going to perform an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the traffic conditions at that time, there were two roads for him to choose. One was to go south, along the Great Plains to today&#39;s Kaifeng, Henan, and then turn west; the other was to follow the Yishui River, Passing through Puyinxing and Feihuxing among the eight hidden tunnels in the Taihang Mountains, they entered today&#39;s Shanxi, then traveled southwest, crossed the Yellow River from Pujin, and entered Guanzhong. For no reason, I think Jing Ke would probably choose the latter. Although the latter journey is more difficult, the mileage is shorter. What is particularly important is that perhaps, only when he slowly climbed from the flat plain to the majestic mountain - at that time, the wind was also blowing, blowing Jing Ke&#39;s white robe - he stood at the mountain pass, and then turned back to take one last look at the sad scene under the sunset. The windy home is more in line with Jing Ke’s character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Jing Ke appeared on the scene, the life of Yan State had entered a countdown. And Jing Ke, a native of Wei, is undoubtedly a colorful part of the historical drama of Yan. The 800-year history of the Yan Kingdom came to a desolate and tragic end with Jing Ke&#39;s stubbornness and despair in attacking Qin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The history of Yan State must start from three hundred miles north of Yishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is also a river, a river that is shallower and thinner than Yi Shui: Liuli River. The Liuli River is an insignificant tributary of the Haihe River Basin. When it flows into Fangshan District, Beijing, a small town surrounded by the Liuli River is named after the Liuli River. To the east of the town, a number of Shang and Zhou cultural relics and sites have been excavated since the 1940s. Now, relying on the ruins, the Western Zhou Yandu Ruins Museum has been built. There are eight big characters on one wall of the museum: Ding Tian Ge Di, appointed to the Northern Territory. These eight characters illustrate that the purpose of establishing the Yan State was to ensure the security of the northern frontier of the Zhou Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1449&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Territory tiles with Taotie patterns from the Yan State, collected by the Yandu Museum of the Western Zhou Dynasty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Shang Dynasty in the Zhou Dynasty, the princes were granted great titles. The first person to be ennobled in the Yan Kingdom was the eldest concubine of King Wen of Zhou, who was also the half-brother of King Wu of Zhou, Ji Shi. Since Ji Shi wanted to stay in the royal city to assist the emperor, he did not go to the fief to govern, but sent his son Ji Ke there. He himself was called Zhao Gong because of his fiefdom, so he was called Zhao Gong in history. This means that the nominal first monarch of the Yan Kingdom was Zhao Gong, but the actual first monarch was Zhao Gong&#39;s son Ji Ke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The territory of Yan State is roughly equivalent to today&#39;s northern part of Hebei plus Beijing. Among all the princes, Yan State is located in the north, and bordering it is the ethnic tribe called Rong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first capital of the Yan Kingdom - for the sake of narrative convenience, let&#39;s call it the first capital of Yan - is near the museum. Of course, the capital city of a feudal state more than two thousand years ago was just a larger market town. When the Yan Kingdom was first established, it was adjacent to another smaller country: Ji. Soon, Yan State annexed Ji State and moved its capital to Ji. The location of thistle is located in the Guang&#39;anmen area of ​​today&#39;s Beijing city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside Guang&#39;an Gate in Beijing, there is a Liao Dynasty Buddhist temple - Tianning Temple. The Tianning Temple Tower is the oldest above-ground building in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yan Kingdom lasted for more than 800 years, and it can be said that it had little sense of existence for the first 700 years. In other words, the only time it had a sense of existence was when this small country in the north encountered big trouble - Shanrong invaded and almost destroyed the country. Fortunately, the Central Plains region was in the era of Duke Huan of Qi, the leader of the Five Hegemons in the Spring and Autumn Period. Under the banner of Zun Wang and Expelling the Barbarians, Duke Huan of Qi contacted the princes to form a coalition. He personally led his troops deep into the hinterland of the Shanrong and fought several battles with the Shanrong until the Shanrong came far away. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, the Yan Kingdom was just like ordinary passers-by A and B, living and multiplying in the northern country in obscurity. By the time the princes turned their attention to it again, it was already three hundred years later. At this time, a major event occurred in the Yan Kingdom that shocked the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the important difference between the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period is that although the Spring and Autumn Period also had frequent wars, they generally only beat their opponents until they surrendered and admitted their mistakes, while the Warring States Period focused on occupying the opponent&#39;s territory or even annexing the opponent. Purpose. During the bloody Warring States Period, with wars and wars raging, ancient countries perished one after another, and the remote Yan State also felt great pressure to survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 321 BC, the first king of the Yan Kingdom, King Yan Yi, died. His son Ji Kuai ascended the throne and was known as King Kuai of Yan in history. Faced with the great powers surrounding the country and the weak state of Yan, King Kuai of Yan was worried. He wanted to work hard to make the backward Yan state invincible. He sincerely believes that as long as it can make the Yan country strong, he will not hesitate even if he and his family are not in power. Various signs show that King Yan is a simple and open-minded person. Only in this way can his dream be used with ulterior motives. The traitor took advantage of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The treacherous minister was his son, who was the Prime Minister of Yan State at that time and was highly regarded by King Kuai of Yan State. Zi Zhi was indeed quite talented, so much so that King Kuai of Yan mistakenly believed that Yan must rely on him in order to revitalize the country. Zizhi fully grasped the eagerness of King Kuai of Yan to seek governance. His two confidants Su Dai and Lu Maoshou often gave advice to King Kuai of Yan, praising Zizhi&#39;s ability to govern the country, and urging King Kuai of Yan to follow the example of Yao and Shun and cede the world to the throne. Son of. In this way, Zi Zhi can not only govern the Yan Kingdom well and realize the rise of the Yan Kingdom, but at the same time, King Kuai of Yan will also become a saint like Yao and Shun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kuai of Yan deeply believed in these deceptions, &quot;because the whole country belongs to the son, and the son is of great importance&quot; - King Kuai of Yan handed over all the important affairs of the country to the son, so the power of the son was extremely popular. ——Of course, I also want to sit on the throne. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, under the continued instigation of Zi Zhi and his associates, King Kuai of Yan &quot;received the seals from his son who was an official of three hundred stone&quot;, that is, he took all the seals of middle and high-level officials with more than three hundred stone in the country. Leave it to Zi, and let Zi control it. So, &quot;the son went to the south to do the king&#39;s business.&quot; The throne of the King of Yan passed from King Kuai to his son, who became the King of Yan. King Kuai instead became a minister. He no longer interfered with political affairs on the grounds of old age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucianism has always beautified the three generations and believed that the abdication of Yao, Shun and Yu was a symbol of the great unity of the world. Later, there were many abdication events, including Emperor Xian of the Han Dynasty, whose throne was Cao Pi, Emperor Gong of the Jin Dynasty, Liu Yu, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty, Li Yuan, Emperor Ai of the Tang Dynasty, Zhu Wen, and Emperor Gong of the Zhou Dynasty, Zhao Kuangyin. However, the concessions between these foreign surnames were backed by force by the recipients, and the monarch had no choice but to give in. In contrast, King Kuai of Yan&#39;s true and heartfelt surrender was unprecedented, if not unprecedented, in thousands of years of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the sage-like abdication of King Yan brought a catastrophe to the Yan country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three years of Zi Zhi’s reign, the State of Yan did not revitalize as King Kuai of Yan had hoped. Instead, it got worse. “The State of Yan was in chaos and the people complained.” Prince Kuai&#39;s son, Tai Ziping, was originally supposed to inherit the throne, but his father&#39;s abdication made him a minister. Of course, he wanted to regain the throne that belonged to him. Therefore, with Jiangjun City&#39;s support, Tai Ziping and his supporters plotted to overthrow Zi Zhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi State, which is adjacent to Yan State, saw an excellent opportunity to get involved in Yan State. King Xuan of Qi sent an envoy to contact Tai Ziping and expressed his willingness to help Tai Ziping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With Qi&#39;s promise, Prince Ping felt that great things were about to happen, so he and the city attacked the palace. However, Qi did not send troops in time as promised. The prince Pingji was defeated and died, and the Yan country was in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking this opportunity, King Xuan of Qi sent troops to attack Yan. The Yan soldiers were disheartened and fled one after another. King Kuai and Zizhi of Yan were both killed by the Qi army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qi army invaded Yan, and the Yan state suffered heavy losses. A large number of heavy weapons were transported away, the ancestral temples were burned, and tens of thousands of Yan people died. Direct evidence of the massacre of the Yan people by the Qi army has been revealed more than two thousand years after the incident: in 1966, fourteen skulls of Warring States people were discovered in Yanxiadu, Yixian County, Hebei Province. Archaeologists examined Tomb No. 5 among them. A rescue excavation was carried out. Under the loess, a large number of white human skulls were randomly buried together without any burial objects. The excavation report stated that &quot;almost all of these human bones are male adults&quot;; &quot;the largest number of skulls belong to young adults aged 18-35, accounting for about 80% of the observations&quot;; and, archaeologists also found that some of them Either part of the skull had been chopped off, or the arrowhead remained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State of Zhao is adjacent to the State of Yan. With the help of King Wuling of Zhao, another son of King Kuai of Yan, Gongzi Shi, was escorted back to the country to inherit the throne. This is King Yan Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What King Yan Zhao inherited was a mess. Ji was looted and destroyed by the Qi army and could no longer serve as the capital. So, he built a new city further south on the banks of the Yishui River. This was the lower capital of Yan; correspondingly, Ji was the upper capital of Yan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yanchu Capital ruins are located in the suburbs of Beijing. A railway is close to the ruins. Occasionally, trains pass by, making earth-shattering sounds. A little further away is the densely populated Liulihe Town. As for the ruins of Yanshangdu, it is located in a bustling metropolis with busy traffic, with cars coming and going, noisy day and night. In sharp contrast to Yanchu Capital and Yanshangdu, Yanxiadu is the largest capital among the excavated capitals of the Spring and Autumn and Warring States princes. At its peak, Yanxiadu had an estimated population of about 300,000. ——And the population of the entire Yan State will most likely not exceed three million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Liuli River Ancient Bridge in Liulihe Town, Fangshan District, Beijing. The ancient bridge was built during the Jiajing period of the Ming Dynasty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, what I see in Yanxiadu are patches of green cornfields. In the cornfield, there are occasional mounds of soil rising suddenly. The unique mounds of soil vaguely indicate that this is no ordinary crop field. This was one of the most important metropolises in China two thousand years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the cornfield, tall black poplar trees cover a small river, which flows toward Yi Shui. That year, white clothes were fluttering and the crown looked like snow. Prince Dan and a group of Yan people gathered around Jing Ke, got into the carriage, and drove slowly out of the capital of Yanxia to the banks of the Yishui River not far outside the city. There is a pavilion there; in the pavilion, wine and food have been laid out. They are about to raise a toast together for the last time...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1507&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216775&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yixian County Yanxiadu Ancient City Ruins&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Dead Time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Yan State when the capital of Yanxia was being built was undoubtedly the weakest among the seven heroes. How to rectify this mess and how to magically revitalize the sluggish Yan State were the urgent issues faced by King Yan Zhao when he came to the throne. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Yan Zhao realized the importance of talents. Only by absorbing the best talents to serve the State of Yan, could the State of Yan become rich and powerful in a short period of time. The news that King Yan Zhao was thirsty for talents quickly spread throughout the world, and many scholars with weapons in their possession went to the Kingdom of Yan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before visiting the ruins of Yanxiadu, I first went to Luoyang, Henan. In a field on one side of the road outside Luoyang, there is an extraordinary tomb. Next to the tomb is a key cultural relic protection monument in Henan Province: Su Qin&#39;s tomb. On the square at the head of the tomb, there are several tall stone tablets, one of which is inscribed with the inscription &quot;The Tombstone of Su Qin, a Co-conspirator of the Warring States Period&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the scholars who defected to the Yan Kingdom, the most famous and influential was Su Qin, a native of Luoyi who was directly under the Emperor of Zhou. Su Qin&#39;s deeds are mainly recorded in &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Warring States Policy&quot;, but there are many contradictions in the two books. This is because both Sima Qian and Liu Xiang suffered from the lack of authentic and reliable first-hand information. It was not until the end of 1973 that a batch of silk books were unearthed from Han Tomb No. 3 in Mawangdui, Changsha, and Su Qin&#39;s true identity gradually became clear. This batch of silk books was compiled by experts into &quot;Books from the Warring States Strategists and Family&quot;. Among the twenty-seven chapters, sixteen are long-lost books that Sima Qian and Liu Xiangwei have never seen. The content of the lost book happens to be related to Su Qin - so, more than two thousand years later, through these words, we can finally restore a lurker who paid the price with his life: the spy Su Qin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before defecting to King Yan Zhao, Su Qin traveled around the country, looking for opportunities. However, he was arrogant and spent all his money, but no monarch took him seriously. When he returned home, his family ignored him. Therefore, when King Yan Zhao respected him, treated him politely, and regarded him as a national scholar, Su Qin decided that the scholar would die for his confidant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Qin believed that Yan was the weakest among the seven kingdoms. Qin and Qi are powerful countries, and Zhao is a sub-powerful country. The State of Yan could not compete with any of them. If you want to defeat Qi and take revenge, you must weaken Qi. The best way to weaken Qi is to encourage and support Qi to annex Song. In this way, Qi will inevitably become the target of public criticism. In order to make Qi State implement the wrong line and achieve the purpose of weakening it, Su Qin was willing to go to Qi State for internal response. He made an agreement with King Zhao of Yan: &quot;If you don&#39;t fight against internal invaders, you can&#39;t keep away from external enemies. The king governs the outside world, and the ministers report to the inside. This is the trend of destruction.&quot; - If internal strife does not arise, the outside world cannot act easily. The king is planning to deal with Qi State while he is away, while I invade Qi State and create chaos. In this way, the situation of destroying Qi was created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Qin came to Qi State as an envoy from Yan State. Later, with his outstanding talent and eloquence, he won the trust of King Qi Min and was appointed as the Prime Minister-his status even exceeded In the state of Yan. As Su Qin was favored by King Qi Min, people around King Yan Zhao began to suspect that Su Qin might not keep his promise, and King Yan Zhao was shaken for a time. For this reason, Su Qin wrote a letter to King Yan Zhao, swearing that he would be &quot;as trustworthy as Wei Sheng, as honest as Boyi, and as filial as Zeng Shen&quot; - these top-secret communications at the time were passed down through the transmission of silk books in the early Han Dynasty, more than two thousand years later. See the light of day again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than ten years in Qi State, despite the changing international situation, Su Qin consistently implemented his agreement with King Yan Zhao, that is, when formulating foreign policies for Qi State, he always tried every means to weaken Qi State. During this period, he not only dissuaded the King of Qin from asking the King of Qi to jointly proclaim the emperor, but also successfully alienated the relationship between Qin and Qi, formed a five-nation coalition to attack Qin, and made Zhao, Chu and other countries have tense relations with Qi. Especially important, he prompted the King of Qi to invade and finally annex the Song Dynasty three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to paralyze the monarchs and ministers of Qi State, King Yan Zhao, who hated Qi State deeply, only followed King Qi&#39;s lead. When Qi State attacked Song Dynasty, Yan State sent troops to help. Even King Qi Min executed a general of the Yan army for a trivial matter. Although King Yan Zhao shed tears of grief and anger, he sent an envoy to admit his mistake to King Qi Min...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 286 BC, Qi destroyed the Song Dynasty. The Song Kingdom, located in the fertile land of the Central Plains, was established by enfeoffing the survivors of the Yin and Shang Dynasties in the early Zhou Dynasty. It had a very high level: Duke. This noble and wealthy country was annexed by Qi, which aroused strong dissatisfaction among other princes. At this time, under the painstaking management of King Yan Zhao, the Yan State had become strong and strong. The state of Qi has long been strong on the outside but weak on the inside. So, more than a year later, King Zhao of Yan poured out all his troops, led by general Le Yi, across the border of Qi and Yan like a tide, and entered Qi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the Yan army attacked Qi State, Su Qin was named the Prime Minister of Qi State, but his identity as a spy of Yan State was exposed. He was tortured by the furious King Min of Qi and was tortured by breaking a car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fury of King Qi could not withstand the revengeful Yan army. The Yan army attacked Linzi, the capital of Qi. King Qi Min fled and was later killed by the Chu army general Nao Chi - his death was very tragic: &quot;Shoot the king&#39;s stock, pull out the king&#39;s tendon, hang it on the temple beam, and die in the past.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yan army captured more than 70 cities in Qi, and only Jimo and Ju were still trapped and fighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the siege of Jimo, King Yan Zhao died. The current situation suddenly took a turn for the worse: King Hui of Yan had a rift with Le Yi when he was crown prince. Under the instigation of the State of Qi, he dismissed Le Yi, and Le Yi had to defect to the State of Zhao - the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period. , this kind of voting with feet is not uncommon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qi State, which was originally in an absolutely weak position, came back to life under the strategizing of the famous general Tian Dan - the Yan army was driven out of the country, and the lost cities of the Qi State were recovered one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short-lived prosperity of the Yan Kingdom ends here. It is like a meteor streaking across the sky. While people are still looking up at it and surprised by its brilliance, it has extinguished and fallen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Later&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is interesting is that the two most exciting historical events of the Yan Kingdom, which has been in the country for more than 800 years, namely Su Qin’s relationship with Qi and Jing Ke’s assassination of Qin, both had protagonists. He is a foreigner; whether he is a spy or an assassin, trying to defeat a country or save a country by such extraordinary means is full of wild imagination and thrilling legend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of seniority, Prince Dan is the sixth grandson of King Yan Zhao, and there is more than fifty years between them. In the half century from the death of King Yan Zhao to the reign of Crown Prince Dan&#39;s father, King Yan Xi, the national fortunes of the Yan country deteriorated from bad to worse. Four generations of Yan kings made mistakes one after another. They fought nine foreign wars and only won one small victory. Among them, when King Xi of Yan was on the throne, the State of Zhao suffered a disastrous defeat in the Battle of Changping. As a neighbor of the State of Zhao, the State of Yan not only did not suffer a loss, but instead took advantage of the situation and robbed it. However, it was severely attacked by the State of Zhao after the defeat, so that the capital of Yan was trapped. He had to pay a lot of money for peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The snipe and the clam fight, and the fisherman gains. The Qin State, which fought for the unification war after the sixth generation, was the ultimate beneficiary of the war between the princes. After Qin destroyed Han and then Zhao, Qin&#39;s forces entered Nanyishui. Previously, Yan State had built the Great Wall along the Nanyi River. However, Prince Dan knew that the simple Great Wall could not withstand Qin&#39;s tiger and wolf troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He hopes there is a way to quickly and once and for all remove the threat from the Qin State and save the precarious Yan State. Thus, there is the well-known Jing Ke&#39;s assassination of Qin; there is the windy farewell banquet by the Yishui River more than two thousand years ago...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1850&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;荆轲拜别&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末资料/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;昔时人已没，今日水犹寒。夏秋之交的易水，有风，却不寒冷，大多数河段水流平缓，沙洲上生长着诸多水草，鸟儿轻飞，看上去更像湿地。距燕下都遗址数公里的河畔，平原上隆起一座土堆，土堆上矗着一座塔，建于辽代，名为荆轲塔。据说，土堆附近有荆轲衣冠冢。那个衣冠似雪的男儿，掷下手中的酒樽，头也不回地朝着夕阳沉落的方向远去。从此，再也没有回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从远处看，荆轲塔的形状像一柄短剑，直刺蓝得空洞的苍穹。它让我想起了荆轲藏在地图中的匕首。图穷匕现，如果那把淬过剧毒的匕首刺死了嬴政；又或者，燕昭王的寿命再延续十年；历史，一定不是我们后来看到的那样。只是，世界上有苹果有芒果有开心果，却没有如果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1445&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;易县荆轲塔&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辽阔的燕下都遗址，大部分是庄稼地，小部分是林子，更小部分是村落。玉米长势良好，野花漫不经心。沟渠里，蹲伏着青蛙，向天空睁大了警惕的双眼。风来，杨树发出夸张的声响。高树多悲风，萧萧愁杀人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夕阳西下时，如血的残阳斜射在一座座隆起的土堆上，它们，要么是从前的宫殿台基，要么是埋葬死者的封土。厚重潮湿的黄土下面，杨树扎根的大地深处，还残留着一个逝去时代，渐行渐远的血泪，呼喊和挣扎……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈冠锋：苏炳添接班人？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258020]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxKabk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;715&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxK abk. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252911&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, men&#39;s 100m final of track and field events at the Hangzhou Asian Games, China Contestant Chen Guanfeng after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 21:55 on September 30, 2023, men&#39;s 100 track and field at the Hangzhou Asian Games In the meter final, Chinese player and 30-year-old veteran Xie Zhenye won the championship in 9.97 seconds, tying his personal best. 23-year-old Chen Guanfeng ranked seventh in 10.34 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Xie Zhen focused on the men’s 200 meters and won the men’s 200 meters championship at the 2010 Youth Olympic Games, the men’s 4×100 meter relay championship at the 2014 Incheon Asian Games, and the 2017 Tianjin National Games. Men&#39;s 100m and 200m champions, men&#39;s 200m champion at the 2018 Athletics World Cup in London, UK, and men&#39;s 200m champion at the 2019 IAAF Diamond League London Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252912&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, in the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Chen Guanfeng (middle) competed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2019 Doha World Athletics Championships, Xie Zhenye broke into the men&#39;s 200m final with a time of 20.03 seconds, creating Chinese sprint history and becoming the first Chinese to enter this event. Athletes in the World Championship finals. On August 6, 2021, in the men&#39;s 4×100m relay final of the Tokyo Olympics, Tang Xingqiang, Xie Zhenye, Su Bingtian, and Wu Zhiqiang represented the Chinese team and won the bronze medal, creating the best result in history. In September of the same year, at the 14th National Games, Xie Zhenye won the men&#39;s 100m and 200m runner-up, and the men&#39;s 4×100m relay championship. He is the Asian record holder in the men&#39;s 200 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Asian record for men&#39;s 100 meters is 9.83 seconds set by Chinese player Su Bingtian at the 2021 Tokyo Olympics; the Asian Games record also belongs to Su Bingtian, who ran 9.92 seconds at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games. . During the finals, he appeared in the live broadcast room to give commentary, saying that their group of old athletes had completed their tasks, and now it was time to look at the young athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 6, 2023, in the men&#39;s 4x100m relay final of the track and field event at the 31st Summer Universiade held in Chengdu, the Chinese team won the championship with a time of 38.80 seconds. Chinese players Chen Guanfeng (first from left) and Yan Haibin (second from right) hand over the baton during the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Guanfeng He is one of the young athletes Su Bingtian is optimistic about. He has repeatedly praised Chen Guanfeng in public as the best among domestic post-00 players. In an interview, he mentioned: &quot;Based on my progress that year, he should be able to take over the job in three years.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of August 2, Chen Guanfeng stood at the Chengdu Universiade Summer Games On the second lane of the men&#39;s 100-meter final, he leaned down and waited for the starting gun to sound. Twelve years ago, the 23-year-old Su Bingtian also stood on the second track of the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the Shenzhen Universiade. That time, he won the bronze medal. The media called him &quot;China&#39;s sprint hope.&quot; Later, Su Bingtian became famous all the way on the 100-meter track, collecting many records to his name, carving a place in the world of track and field, and becoming the undisputed leader of Chinese sprints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 23-year-old Chen Guanfeng almost replicated Su Bingtian’s medal-winning journey. This is the first time in his career that he has appeared in a real world competition, and it is also the first time that he has set foot in a world-class men’s competition. The track for the 100-meter final. He ran a personal season-best time of 10.16 seconds in the semifinals, and two hours later in the final, he crossed the finish line third in 10.17 seconds. After the game, Chen Guanfeng, draped in the national flag, ran around the track and field to express his gratitude to the audience. Four days later, he and his teammates won the gold medal in the 4×100m relay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;578&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252914&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese players Chen Guanfeng (front) and Xie Zhenye (first from right) competed in the competition&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The similarity in winning the medal in the 100-meter final made the media and audiences associate him with Su Bingtian. Chen Guanfeng is 1.80 meters tall, 8 centimeters taller than Su Bingtian. In 2020, his time in the 100-meter event was about 10.40 seconds, and his personal best in 2021 was 10.19 seconds. In the National Championships of the same year, Chen Guanfeng won the championship in 10.06 seconds against two famous players of the national team, Wu Zhiqiang and Xu Zhouzheng, in nearly zero wind speed. He was only 0.01 seconds away from the Olympic standard. He surpassed Ho Yuhong&#39;s 10.19 seconds in one fell swoop and became China&#39;s &quot;post-2000&quot; 100-meter sprinter. one person. He also became the fourth-best player in the history of the Chinese team after Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye and Zhang Peimeng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Guanfeng said: &quot;I will try my best to attack the Olympic podium. Although I don&#39;t know whether I can succeed, I will also help the young people behind me like Su Bingtian. , set a good example for them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Chen Guanfeng is still a fresh face in the national track and field competition, he has long been known as the &quot;Xiguan Flying Man&quot; in Guangzhou. Before the age of 17, Chen Guanfeng had been a campus player and did not enter a sports school to receive systematic professional training. He has represented Guangzhou No. 1 Middle School in inter-school competitions many times, and his running speed is much faster than that of ordinary students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have always been active since I was a child and like to run and jump. I seem to have always had better sports scores in elementary school, so the physical education teachers recommended me to practice in the school track and field team. I did not sacrifice a lot of study time to practice track and field. Like other students, they also have to do homework and take exams,&quot; Chen Guanfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He ranked first in competitions in Liwan District many times and was discovered by Gu Yanqiang, the former coach of the West Village Youth Amateur Sports School. In 2015, Gu Yanqiang took up his new position at Guangzhou Sports Vocational and Technical College. He did long-term ideological work with Chen Guanfeng&#39;s parents and himself, and recruited Chen Guanfeng into the school after the high school entrance examination. &quot;My parents are very supportive of me and have always told me that doing what you like to do and being happy is the most important thing.&quot; Chen Guanfeng recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Yanqiang commented on him: &quot;It was a bit late to receive professional training, but he is talented in sprinting, has a good figure and good jumping ability. He is a rare talent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 2, 2023, in the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event at the 31st Summer Universiade in Chengdu, China&#39;s Chen Guanfeng won the third place with a time of 10.17 seconds&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first entered the sports school, Chen Guanfeng’s foundation was relatively weak, and his best 100-meter time was 11.03 seconds. As he grows older and his coach slowly guides him, Chen Guanfeng&#39;s training gradually gets on the right track. In Gu Yanqiang&#39;s plan, he will spend two years laying the foundation, training explosive power, coordination, balance, and sensitivity, and gradually improving strength and frequency. At the end of 2017, Chen Guanfeng joined the Guangdong Provincial Team. In 2018, he became a regular from the provincial team and was selected for the Chinese national track and field team. He became the main member of the men&#39;s 4×100 meter relay event and began to launch an impact on larger competitions. He constantly refreshed his original speed and emerged in the track and field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Chen Guanfeng joined Su Bingtian’s team for training. After Su Bingtian created the &quot;myth&quot; of 9.83 seconds in the Tokyo Olympics, the Su Bingtian Speed ​​Research and Training Center, jointly built by Jinan University, Guangdong Provincial Sports Bureau, and the Chinese Athletics Association, was established to explore cutting-edge technology, discipline construction and technology in track and field training. Innovation to support the cultivation and selection of track and field reserve talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The technical team filmed Chen Guanfeng’s daily training and analyzed his technical movements. He improved his starts and runs as a result. &quot;My advantage at the start was pretty good, but my running was very bad on the way. I often led in the first 60 to 70 meters, but overtook me in the last 20 to 30 meters.&quot; Chen Guanfeng analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reviewing his performance on the 100-meter track at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chen Guanfeng said that his performance in the first half of the race was normal, but after adjusting his technique, the old problem of serious slowdown in the second half still existed. He admitted that his legs were slightly uncomfortable during the second half of the final, so he chose a relatively conservative finishing strategy. After all, there were relay tasks ahead. &quot;I am still in the process of adapting and running in with new technologies, but I have achieved my goal of advancing to the finals. With my current hard power, I am not particularly outstanding in Asia, so the finals are a process of learning and enjoying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Watching his senior Xie Zhenye break the 10-second mark in Hangzhou, Chen Guanfeng excitedly said that this is a historic moment for Chinese sprinting. Regarding the question about whether he has the chance to become the fourth Chinese athlete to break the 10-second barrier for 100 meters, Chen Guanfeng said that he will go all out and be ready to take over at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think there are too many talented people. You must train hard and maintain your best condition every day in order to not fall behind in the arena.&quot; Chen Jianfeng said, &quot;This is my first time. Participating in the Asian Games, with the current sprint level of Asian countries, I can&#39;t say that I will definitely get a ranking, but the goal I set for myself is to advance to the finals.&quot; Judging from his performance in this Asian Games, he achieved his goal. We have There are reasons to believe that this post-2000 athlete will bring us more surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中小学流行“萝卜刀”惹争议：让孩子没有害人之心，比严防死守害人之物重要得多丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a children&#39;s toy has caused heated discussion in public opinion. According to media reports, almost all primary school students have a &quot;carrot knife&quot;, which is a colorful plastic imitation knife toy that uses its own gravity to slide the knife body. The &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; is available in different colors and sizes, with prices ranging from 5 yuan to 25 yuan. There are also different styles such as &quot;printed flash radish knife&quot; and &quot;luminous gravity radish knife&quot;, which have already sold &quot;400,000&quot; online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports said that some parents reported to the Chongqing Online Political Questioning Platform that primary and secondary school students brought &quot;carrot knives&quot; into school to play together, which posed safety risks. Some parents are worried that if their children imitate actions such as stabbing and poking, it will have a negative impact on their psychology. When interviewed, some experts and scholars said that the &quot;carrot knife&quot; has safety hazards and &quot;subconsciously inspires children to be violent and do the same thing with a real knife.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance, it seems that the carrot knife is a kind of &quot;knife&quot; just like its name, and there is a danger of cutting, scratching and stabbing children. If the carrot knife is really a sharp-edged tool that can easily hurt people, not to mention that minors should not possess it, it should also be classified as a controlled knife in the adult world. However, judging from the actual situation of this toy, I am afraid that its danger is not as serious as that reported by parents and experts. Words such as &quot;danger&quot;, &quot;warning&quot; and &quot;warning&quot; are also exaggerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, judging from the appearance and material of the carrot knife, its &quot;edge&quot; is an obtuse angle and it is also a plastic product. How much harm it can do to humans can only be achieved by piercing white paper and apples with a few pieces. The photos are not convincing, and pencils and ballpoint pens can also be used to pierce them. Are they also banned because they are dangerous? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the innate nature of human beings to play with objects in their hands. Even for common stationery such as rulers and ballpoint pens, children have developed recreational uses for turning pens and placing rulers. If we have to talk about the degree of danger, any of these commonly used stationery items, such as a 30-degree triangle, a thin steel ruler, and a sharp ballpoint pen tip, is probably much more dangerous than a carrot knife. Even long fingernails can scratch the skin. A book page can also cut your finger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if it is just to prevent the possible harm caused by such &quot;blunt plastic knives&quot;, it is obvious that measures such as &quot;playing under parental supervision&quot; and &quot;not allowing children to bring it to school&quot; should be adopted. is to exaggerate the power of a plastic blunt knife toy and devote a disproportionate amount of attention to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the rhetoric of “stimulating children’s violent tendencies” when interviewed by experts and scholars is also worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long years before the advent of the carrot knife, generations of minors would also imitate &quot;stabbing, poking, poking and other actions&quot; because this is something written in human genes. Human ancestors jumped from hunting activities to becoming the spiritual beings and then ruling the earth. It is the nature of every child to imitate and use weapons. A simple wooden sword or a delicate toy sword is almost everyone’s childhood memory. Who hasn&#39;t fantasized as a child about being a superhero, or more or less a general and a vigilante? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing is a way for children to understand the world. Role-playing and imitating martial arts movements are their irrepressible nature. Advertising slogans such as &quot;Show me my carrot knife and defeat the enemy with one strike&quot; In fact, there is no big problem. If children&#39;s behavior of imitating the use of weapons is denigrated as &quot;violent tendencies&quot;, this is definitely inconsistent with formal logic and goes against common sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between small plastic toys and real sharp controlled knives, the difference between simulated games and wounding with a knife, and even the difference between legal violence and illegal violence, children with a little ability to discern After receiving education, they can be easily distinguished. The statement of &quot;stimulating violent tendencies&quot; goes too far, and it also denies children&#39;s cognitive and discerning abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, from the perspective of healthy growth of minors, it is actually unrealistic to over-protect them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Minors will always encounter various risks in their growth process. This is not only the inevitable path of life, but also the price that cannot be avoided. Traffic rules cannot yet eliminate all traffic accidents, sports competitions cannot eliminate all injuries, and even adult society cannot eliminate all risks. On campus, stationery, tree branches, tables, chairs, and benches can all injure people. Should the campus be like a prison, free of sharp objects and hard walls, and tightly controlled? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, &quot;Don&#39;t underestimate children&quot; has long been a consensus in education. Neither parents nor schools should over-protect minors or completely deny their ability to self-manage. Minors will grow up one day, and it is impossible to keep them strictly guarded in a sterile environment and worry about every possible safety risk. The correct approach should be to guide them to correctly assess risks and teach them the ability to fight risks independently. Otherwise, there would not be such a famous saying in the Chinese world as “civilized in spirit, barbaric in body.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in the face of the popularity of &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; toys, the right thing for adults to do is to provide reasonable guidance and teach children correct values. It is much more important to prevent children from harming others than to strictly guard against harmful things. After all, if you have an evil intention, you can harm others and yourself with your bare hands; if you have the right views and knowledge, you can use sharp weapons to defend yourself and protect others. Not only does a small dull plastic knife pose no safety risks, it can actually become an &quot;experience package&quot; for children to view violence correctly and learn to face risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不在景区“人挤人”，批发市场成假期新选宝地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257768]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[车臣的王，可能快不行了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257966]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/Fepy81wVavQ3ougQ4gFwpSQzxZc5lolwHTrulIGm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/Fepy81wVavQ3ougQ4gFwpSQzxZc5lolwHT rulIGm. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chechen leader Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023 local time, current Chechen President Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Ramzan Kadyrow)&lt;/span>;&#39;s assistant released a video of Kadyrov walking with his family to refute Uzbekistan&#39;s previous statement that Kadyrov was &quot;seriously ill&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier that day, the &quot;Kyiv Independent&quot; quoted a spokesperson of the Security Service of Ukraine &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(SBU)&lt;/span>; Andrei Yusov said that Kadyrov was &quot;seriously ill&quot; and &quot;his illness has worsened, leading to such a serious condition.&quot; According to the report, the source pointed out that Kadyrov had &quot;fallen into a coma&quot; and &quot;is recovering. Waiting to be transferred from Chechnya to &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(possibly the United Arab Emirates)&lt;/span>; for treatment.&quot; Yusof also told the media, &quot;He &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Kadyrov)&lt;/span>; has been ill for a long time and has systemic health problems. His condition has been very poor in recent days. Serious.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Kadyrov is smiling broadly in the video, it can be clearly seen that his facial contour and figure have changed significantly, and he seems to be far fatter than before. Some outsiders have speculated This is the swelling caused by his long-term kidney disease. In short, despite his own personal experience, there is still a lot of speculation and controversy about his health issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kadyrov&#39;s health condition aroused doubts from the outside world in early 2023 - Kadyrov, who claims to be infinitely loyal to Putin and will hardly miss any major events of the Moscow authorities, suddenly disappeared without any notice. Putin was absent from Putin&#39;s annual State of the Union address. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Father&#39;s legacy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ramzan Kadyrov, the current president of the Chechen Republic, likes to call himself &quot;Putin&#39;s little soldier&quot; and is Putin&#39;s most loyal ally. People call him Putin&#39;s fighting dog. In addition to the administrative regions, the Russian Federation also has 24 autonomous republics &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (including the internationally unrecognized territory of Ukraine)&lt;/span>;, Kaiti It is the most special one among the 24 heads of autonomous republics at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes him special is not just his relationship with President Putin, but also that he is a social media influencer. Kadyrov said that while he admired Putin, he also tried to create the same tough guy image as Putin. Therefore, he posted videos and photos of himself firing machine guns and taming tigers on social media, as well as his high-end and luxurious daily life. Kadyrov is not only eye-catching, he is also a person who cannot be criticized casually in the Russian Federation - the leaders of the other 23 autonomous republics obviously do not have this treatment. Any Russian media or individual criticizes him in public, even if he is not there In Chechnya, people will also be asked to be cautious in their words and deeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This unique status comes from his father Akhmad Kadyrov &lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed Kadyrov, the former President of the Republic of Chechnya, his presidential term ended in seven months - he was killed by a bomb in an assassination attempt in May 2004 at the age of 52 years old. Ahmed was the central figure in the Kadyrov family&#39;s rise to become the rulers of the Chechen Republic, and his life was full of ups and downs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed was born into a poor family in Karaganda, Kazakhstan in 1951. At that time, all the Chechens were transferred from Chechnya to Central Asia by the Soviet government to break up their resistance. They are the descendants of this group of immigrants. Later, with the change of the Soviet policy towards Chechnya, the Chechens were able to return to their hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ahmed worked in agriculture and construction during the Soviet era. In the 1980s, he entered the Islamic University of Uzbekistan to study religious studies, and then established the first modern Islamic religious schools in Chechnya, and later more He went to Oman and Jordan for further studies and became a famous religious scholar in Chechnya. In 1993, Dudayev, the leader of the Chechen separatists, declared the independence of Chechnya. Ahmed was a religious leader whom Dudayev relied heavily on. At that time, he also issued a famous declaration of jihad against Russia:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are 1 million Chechens and 150 million Russians. If each Chechen kills 150 Russians, we will win.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then the Chechen war broke out, and Ahmed not only called for war against Russia He launched a jihad and personally led a guerrilla force during the war. His youngest son, the current Chechen President Ramzan Kadyrov, also joined the guerrillas. He later claimed that he had successfully killed someone at the age of 19. One Russian soldier died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Russian army in the First Chechen War ended in failure and suffered heavy casualties, and was forced to make a humiliating retreat. After the war, Ahmed Kadyrov, who had become the chief mufti of Chechnya One of the main representatives of the negotiations with Russia, his guerrillas were also known as the Kadyrov faction due to their outstanding military exploits during the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is strange, however, is that Ahmed broke with the Chechen independence faction in 1999. In the same year, Putin became the president of Russia, and the second Chechen War broke out. Ahmed this time withdrew his last declaration of jihad and led his troops in an alliance with the Russian government to fight the Chechen separatists he had fought alongside. With his help, the Russian army won the second Chechen War, which became Putin&#39;s first military victory after coming to power. This success avenged its shame, and the popularity of the Putin government was unprecedentedly high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for why Ahmed defected to help Russia in the second Chechen War, the outside world generally believes that in addition to personal ambitions and desires, he also had to do with the rise of Wahhabi fundamentalists in Chechnya. Worry. As the supreme religious leader of Chechnya, he is quite resistant to the international jihad claimed by the Wahhabis. From an ideological perspective, he is still a Chechen nationalist. After experiencing the first Chechen war, Grozny, the capital of Chechnya, was not only reduced to ruins, but also suffered a large number of casualties among the local population, causing serious social problems and economic crisis. At this time, the fundamentalists among the Chechen independence faction chose to ally with bin Laden and his like during the rise of global terrorism in an attempt to expand their territory in Russia. This is obviously not something that the Chechen nation with a population of 1.5 million can accomplish. matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on national sentiments and personal safety considerations, Ahmed publicly accused extremists of using Chechnya as a base for terrorist attacks in early 1999, which was dangerous and full of conspiracies. This led him and previous The relationship between comrades quickly deteriorated to the point of tension. At this time, the Russian government extended an olive branch to him, and forming an alliance became a matter of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reciprocating the favor, after the second Chechen War, Putin gave Ahmed the throne of Chechen president until his death in an assassination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to determine whether it was Ahmed&#39;s defection to Moscow that prompted Putin to make up his mind to launch a second Chechen war, or whether Putin wanted to establish his prestige through a war after coming to power, or whether the two complemented each other. result. But looking at Ahmed&#39;s choice now, whether it is based on his personal interests or the interests of the Chechen nation, it is not a mistake. Even if he did not defect and the second Chechen War did not break out at the end of 1999, after the &quot;9·11&quot; incident in 2001, it would be difficult for Chechnya to survive independently under the banner of joint anti-terrorism between the United States and Russia. It may even cause a more serious humanitarian disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Prince&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As Putin’s biggest contributor in the Second Chechen War, Ahmed Kadyrov’s political legacy was successfully passed on to his younger son Ramzan Kadyrov. Derov succeeded, and the latter soon became the real &quot;king&quot; of Chechnya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a process for getting to the top. In November 2005, a year and a half after Ahmed was assassinated, the then Prime Minister of Chechnya Sergey Abramov was seriously injured in a car accident and resigned due to health reasons. The cause of his car accident has not yet been determined, and the possibility of assassination cannot be completely ruled out, because at that time, assassinations of Chechen military and political leaders were common, and Sergei was assassinated in 2004, so the truth may never be confirmed. In any case, the biggest beneficiary of this car accident was the then First Deputy Prime Minister Ramzan Kadyrov. He became acting Prime Minister of Chechnya on November 18, 2005. A year later, he was officially promoted from &quot;Prince&quot; as &quot;King&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ZvIZ8puCKbgy4aB6jOT5UdVh8YhdujEScHCwozQc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;746&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ZvIZ8puCKbgy4aB6jOT5UdVh8YhdujEScHCwozQc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 30, 2004, President of the Chechen Republic Akhmed Kadyrov (right) and his son Ramzan Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan Kadyrov’s first task after taking power was to rebuild Grozny, the capital of Chechnya. He built the Akhmed Kadyrov Mosque in the center of Chechnya in the name of his father, also known as the Heart of Chechnya. It is the largest mosque in Russia and one of the largest in Europe; it has the most It can accommodate 10,000 people, has a magnificent dome, a towering minaret and hand-painted by Turkish craftsmen. These are the standards for large mosques built during the heyday of the Ottoman Empire. On October 16, 2008, the mosque was officially opened. Ramzan Kadyrov and Putin both attended the opening ceremony and appeared side by side in the news. In addition to the magnificent mosque, the palace-like presidential palace, highways, five-star hotels and casinos have risen from the ground. Now Grozny has become a modern city with many high-rise buildings. Its core business district is even compared with Moscow and St. Petersburg. No less impressive. Funding for these large-scale infrastructure projects comes from the support of the Russian Federation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to reward the loyalty of the Kadyrov family, under the personal care of President Putin, the Russian Federation invested US$18 billion in the Chechen Republic in 2010 alone, with an average per capita income of more than US$1,300. In contrast, the autonomous republic of Dagestan next door to Chechnya spent less than $1.6 billion in federal investment in 2010, but the country has a population of 2.2 million. Relying on financial support from Moscow, Ramzan was able to complete the reconstruction of Grozny as one of the core achievements of his internal rule. However, the heavy economic dependence on Russia has also led to a rather deformed economic structure in Chechnya. The local area lacks core industrial chains and the unemployment rate remains high. In 2010, it even reached an astonishing over 60%. It is obviously impossible to solve the problem by relying entirely on federal funds and large-scale construction projects. The core local issue is the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/alxQC5TrmUCcwFQIdOagoa4PBKvPULr8v5AI7jxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/alxQC5TrmUCcwFQIdOagoa4PBKvPULr8v5AI7jxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 25, 2022, the Chechen armed forces held a swearing-in meeting to prepare for their mission in Ukraine. Chechen leader Kadyrov (middle) takes a group photo with soldiers &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What we must note is that La Mzan&#39;s greatest economic achievement in Chechnya is not that he built Grozny into another St. Petersburg through extensive construction, but that he successfully obtained economic autonomy from Moscow. In 2018, Ramzan Kadyrov announced that his government would take over 100% of the shares of Chechen State Petroleum Technology Company, allowing Chechens to develop, extract and sell crude oil on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, 1,100 oil wells and 2,000 land parcels owned by the Chechen State Petroleum Technology Company with a total area of ​​7,740 hectares were all controlled by the Russian state-owned oil giant Rosneft. Ramzan has been fighting for control of oil assets in Chechnya since at least 2015, the year he first proposed to Putin that the Chechen Oil Company be handed over to Chechnya. On the surface, Putin agreed to transfer the equity, but in fact he has been putting it on hold. The reason why Moscow adopts the procrastination strategy is not entirely due to economic considerations, but one of the main means of control over Chechnya for a long time is economic control. During the Soviet era, Moscow firmly controlled the extraction, transportation and sales of local oil. Local people could only engage in agriculture and handicrafts, and were almost unable to enter the oil industry. The result of this was that the local area had to rely on financial subsidies from the Soviet Union&#39;s central government, otherwise infrastructure and public spending would be almost impossible to carry out. During the first Chechen war, Chechen guerrillas obtained military expenses by stealing crude oil from Russian oil pipelines passing through Chechnya. The elites in Moscow certainly know the importance of controlling the oil industry in controlling Chechnya. Therefore, they are not only unwilling to hand over control, but also deliberately do not expand local oil production capacity. However, Ramzan successfully overcame the calculations of the oil oligarchs and economic elites by relying on his personal relationship with Putin. With Putin&#39;s personal intervention, Ramzan got what he wanted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As seen in the fight for control of oil, Ramzan Kadyrov clearly knows what he needs and how to get it from Moscow. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kadyrov&#39;s Chechnya&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chechen high school students are now required to read Akhmed Kadyrov&#39;s biography &quot;The Road Bathed in Light&quot;, according to Chechen state television &quot;, as &quot;supplementary material for the study of Russian history&quot;, the book introduces &quot;the political and spiritual legacy of Akhmad Kadyrov&quot;. Schools are required to organize regular essay and poster competitions featuring Kadyrov and his family. Teachers and school administrators are required to comment on social media posts by Kadyrov and his inner circle as part of their job evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the magnificent Kadyrov Mosque, there are more than 300 streets in the Chechen Republic named after Akhmed Kadyrov. In 2020, Ramzan Kadyrov ordered that images of American comic book superheroes be removed from Chechen children&#39;s centers and playgrounds and replaced with likenesses of his father and other &quot;real heroes&quot; in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan hopes that his father will become the only superhero in Chechnya, and he will become the first Internet celebrity in Chechnya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kadyrov family on the Internet shines brightly, and at the same time they are down-to-earth and full of true nature. Instagram has been Ramzan’s favorite platform for years, where he actively shares his outfits and lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan also opened a Telegram channel to share his carefully recorded videos and his views on the current situation. He even gained millions of followers by feuding with Elon Musk on Twitter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Run by his PR team, his father, Ahmed Kadyrov, became a loving father and hero who saved Chechnya and became a great martyr, revolutionary and Martyr Saint. Ramzan himself is a kind-hearted Chechen brother. Not only does he have an enviable luxurious and cool life, he is also a fan of President Putin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with Vesti-24 TV station in 2018, Ramzan Kadyrov stated that he was rebuilding Putin&#39;s Caucasus native cavalry division, or &quot;Barbarian Division&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very famous allusion to Tsarist Russia. The Caucasus Cavalry Division was affiliated to the Russian Imperial Army. It was established on August 23, 1914. It participated in World War I and was led by Russian Grand Duke Michael Alexander. Rovich conducts. The division earned the nickname &quot;The Barbarians&quot; for its lax discipline, but the unit was a fighting force, distinguished itself during World War I and was loyal to the Tsar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ramzan&#39;s concept of &quot;barbarian divisions&quot; actually has a deeper meaning. Since Putin intends to incorporate Tsarist Russia into the orthodox national historical narrative, Ramzan&#39;s repeated mention of &quot;barbarian divisions&quot; is precisely to borrow from ancient times. Yu Jin showed his loyalty to Putin. In fact, Ramzan has been working hard to maintain an image of himself and the Chechen nation as brave and loyal. The security forces of the Ministry of Internal Affairs controlled by Ramzan not only collaborated with the Russian army in South Ossetia&#39;s war against Georgia in 2008, but also actively participated in the Syrian war. Chechen special forces have frequently participated in various international special forces competitions, and have won the Jordan King&#39;s Cup special competitions many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lzvpOxPRgyNW9F2JGK2lIcNC5q2C7Zx2VReO5K60.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lzvpOxPRgyNW9F2JGK2lIcNC5q2C7Zx2VReO5K60.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 13, 2023, in Moscow, Russian President Putin (left) met with Chechen leader Kadyrov&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to participating in Russia-related military operations, the international community also accused Ramzan of participating in the assassination or intimidation of Russian anti-government figures, but there is not enough evidence to prove this. Prove this. Since the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, Chechnya has sent tens of thousands of troops to directly participate. Although there is no evidence to prove that they played a key role in the war, and they are not even as good as the Wagner mercenary group that successfully captured a city, their posture is undoubtedly very important. in place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What further illustrates Ramzan’s attitude is that when Prigozhin led Wagner to march into Moscow in June 2023, local troops along the way were unable to intercept him. Only Ramzan Kadyrov’s men were the last to stop him. The elite &quot;Akhmat&quot; special forces positioned themselves on a bridge near the town of Kolomna, about 110 kilometers from Moscow, preparing to intercept the Wagner rebels, saying they were ready to fight to defend Vladimir Putin. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Loyal enough, and Ramzan clearly does not look like a threat to Putin&#39;s regime. Not only because of the small number of ethnic Chechens, but more importantly, within Moscow’s power circle, Kadyrov’s only political backer is Putin. If Putin loses his support, there is no guarantee that the next Chechen president’s surname will still be Kadyrov. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it seems that the probability that the future leader of Chechnya will be named Kadyrov is still very high, not to mention that members of the Kadyrov family almost control all important positions in the Chechen government. Like his son Akhmat Kadyrov who is less than 18 years old &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Akhmat Kadyrov)&lt;/span>; was also attacked in March 2023 received an interview with Russian President Vladimir Putin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant reports, this was an informal meeting. Akhmat, who has served as the chairman of the board of directors of Chechnya’s Children and Youth Organization, introduced to Putin the youth policies and activities of Chechnya. status quo. Putin congratulated Akhmat on his upcoming marriage and shared with Akhmat his memories of his relationship with his grandfather, Akhmat Kadyrov. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one knows what they said, but they may have talked about Putin meeting a weeping Ramzan in the Kremlin after Ahmed was assassinated in 2004. News reports at the time said it was also an informal meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[外星人遗体被发现？全世界有几百万人每天都寻找外星人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258006]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021854137506&quot; data-media=&quot; audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Podcast · Some Culture Alien remains have been found? Millions of people around the world are looking for aliens every day.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http:// 1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/4182cccb5576678021854137506/jeaAQMqXAAYA.mp3&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud. com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/4182cccb5576678021854137506/jeaAQMqXAAYA.mp3&quot;>; Podcast·A bit of culture Alien remains discovered? Millions of people around the world are looking for aliens every day.mp3&lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play This podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to BitCulture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, a Mexican journalist who has long studied UFOs showed two &quot;mummy bodies&quot; suspected of &quot;alien remains&quot; at a hearing in the Mexican Congress, trying to prove that extraterrestrial Life exists, but its authenticity has also been widely questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this issue, two anchors from our editorial department will talk about the topic of aliens, including the main modes of human beings’ current search for extraterrestrial civilizations, as well as the imagination of extraterrestrial civilizations in literary, film and television works, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excerpts from golden verses&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; At present, no country in the world has officially recognized or claimed that extraterrestrial civilization really exists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, regardless of whether extraterrestrial civilization exists or not, we have made great progress in the process of exploring it. Expanded our knowledge. This search will also make us think about the existence and significance of human beings in the universe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As humans explore space more and more, they will feel that they are actually quite ignorant, so Humanity also slowly emerged with some somewhat modest works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Youxiang Southern Weekend Culture Supplement Editor&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weng Rongrong, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:32 Mexico claims to have discovered the corpses of two aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:35 There was a previous record of using mummified human children to pass them off&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 08:38&amp;nbsp;No country officially claims that extraterrestrial civilization really exists&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 10:18&amp;nbsp;Two hundred years ago, humans began to use modern technology to search for aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:27 Searchlight mode: Humans turn on lights and send out light signals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 15:06&amp;nbsp;Broadcast mode: Millions of people around the world use radio signals to search for aliens every day&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ► 21:20 Letter writing mode: The spacecraft brought a record when traveling in space&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:59 Spend 6.3 billion yuan to send a letter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 28:15&amp;nbsp; Looking for alien images that will make us think about the existence and significance of human beings in the universe&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 29:43 Impressive images of aliens in literary and artistic works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 35:30&amp;nbsp;&quot;Travel to the Moon&quot; &quot;Reflects early humans&#39; imagination of aliens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37:27 Lao She&#39;s &quot;Cat City&quot; is a long science fiction novel&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 39:24 Theme exploration of science fiction works in different periods &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 46:57 Liu Cixin’s two science fiction works about aliens communicating with humans in literature and art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:08 The image of aliens has been evolving in human imagination&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;► 55:16 Southern University of Science and Technology has coursework on how to grow vegetables on alien planets&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080 ;&quot;>;Audio editing/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operation promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun and Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子被120公斤杠铃砸死，健身房内发生的意外谁来买单？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>