<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从卖寿衣到“古装大佬”，它凭什么抢占了半壁戏服江山？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257711]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cao County has always produced coffins and shrouds, monopolizing 90% of Japan&#39;s The coffin market above. In 2008, Caoxian County encountered a popular online costume sales market, and local residents began to switch to selling costumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking at the entire development history of Hanfu industry in Caoxian County, being down-to-earth, not making excuses, making up for whatever is lacking, and being open-minded to ask for advice... have become its most prominent development labels. In this In the process, Caoxian vividly demonstrated the true qualities of Shandong people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Know&quot; tells you how Caoxian County transformed from shrouds to costumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72816&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69684&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;5863&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b490d5b814.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252254&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72817&quot; group-id=&quot; 0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69685&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 2.png&quot; alt= &quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4530&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/534658f40e.png&quot; data-key= &quot;252255&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72818&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69686&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Cao County 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4875&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/7214680d68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252256&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id= &quot;72819&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69687&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/b3e2c3432d.png&quot; img-title= &quot;Cao County 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;3435&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ b3e2c3432d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252257&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[私搭浮桥18人获罪案启动再审：“原判决适用法律确有错误”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258058]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;September 2023, Taonan, Jilin, a convenience bridge to be completed. Interviewee Photo courtesy&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;881&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/aeb688fcfb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Taonan, Jilin, the soon-to-be-completed convenience bridge. Photo provided by interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of 18 people who were convicted of privately building a pontoon that once attracted widespread attention has made new progress. On September 27, 2023, the Baicheng Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jilin Province made a retrial decision, believing that the original judgment was indeed erroneous in the application of law and met the conditions for retrial, and decided to bring the case to Baicheng Intermediate People&#39;s Court for trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The criminal verdict of the Taonan City People&#39;s Court shows that from 2005 to 2018, Huang Deyi and others secretly traveled along the Taoer River from Zhenlin Village, Wafang Town, Taonan City to Ping&#39;an Village, Ping&#39;an Town, Taobei District, Baicheng City. Build a hull pontoon bridge, intercept passing vehicles and collect bridge tolls. The toll is 5 yuan for a small car and 10 yuan for a large car, totaling 52,950 yuan. For the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, Huang Deyi was sentenced to two years in prison, suspended for two years. Another 17 relatives were sentenced to prison terms ranging from one year to three months in prison, all with suspended sentences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A legal person close to the case told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;According to our country&#39;s judicial practice, the court is very cautious in initiating retrials and usually undergoes very strict review.&quot; The legal person analyzed that correcting the original judgment There are two possibilities, one is not guilty, the other is a reduced sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Retrial decision letter. Provided by the respondent&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/e6af52d346.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252967 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Retrial decision letter. Respondents provided&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Whether it is a forced request&quot; or the focus of the retrial&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;The original judgment was indeed wrong in applying the law&quot; mentioned in the retrial decision, analyzed by the above-mentioned legal experts , according to the judicial interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court, to constitute the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, there must be certain hooligan motives and coercive objective behavior, and disrupt social order. The focus of the retrial of the case will be on whether Huang Deyi&#39;s relevant behavior constitutes the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, that is, whether Huang Deyi has the subjective intention to commit the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble and the objective behavior of forcing others to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, the focus of the retrial may be on whether Huang Deyi had objective behavior of forcing others to cross the bridge. Specifically, whether Huang Deyi forced others to cross the bridge.” The legal person believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter in July 2023, Huang Deyi explained that the reason for building the pontoon bridge was because his family had land on the other side of the river, and at the same time, his ancestors were boat builders. Huang Deyi said that the charging standard of &quot;5 yuan for a small car and 10 yuan for a large car&quot; was determined after discussion with the villagers crossing the bridge. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252355&quot;>;Village Bully Involved in Gangs , destroy lanes, return bridge tolls? Those convicted of building bridges respond to the controversy&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are different opinions in previous media reports regarding Huang Deyi’s claim that there is no mandatory toll. . In July 2023, Gu Tianfu, the party secretary of An&#39;an Village, which is only separated by a river from Zhenlin Village, said in an interview with the media that Huang Deyi had deliberately dug up the river channel, so that villagers passing by had to walk across his bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment determined that the amount of charges was 52,950 yuan. In previous interviews with Southern Weekend reporters, many villagers claimed that it was more than this amount. A villager who had also built a pontoon bridge on the Taoer River estimated that the amount built by Huang Deyi The fee charged by the floating bridge may reach millions of dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the determination of the amount to be collected will have an impact on the retrial judgment, the above-mentioned legal experts analyzed that the retrial decision stated that the original trial was an error in the application of the law, and the retrial stage should focus on the application of the law. &quot;This case is not a crime of amount. Whether Huang Deyi constitutes a crime and the sentencing has no absolute correspondence with the amount.&quot; At the same time, Article 469 of the Interpretation of the Criminal Procedure Law stipulates that, except for the protest of the People&#39;s Procuratorate, the retrial shall generally not increase the penalty of the defendant in the original trial. &quot;From this point of view, it is unlikely that Huang Deyi will be given a heavier sentence in the retrial.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the criminal verdict of the Taonan City People&#39;s Court, in addition to building a pontoon bridge, Huang Deyi also organized 17 relatives to guard the bridge. If any of the other 17 people involved in the bridge guarding case engaged in forcible behavior, would it have an impact on the case and Huang Deyi? The above-mentioned legal person said that if others forcefully demand it, he himself may not commit a crime because there is no intention to commit a crime together, but the premise is that Huang Deyi himself does not know about this behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The new bridge will be completed and opened to traffic at the end of October&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to the case itself, the &quot;floating bridge imprisonment&quot; has attracted attention, and the travel needs of villagers have also attracted local attention. In July 2023, &quot;Taonan Release&quot; issued an article stating that it plans to build a convenience bridge near the original pontoon bridge, which will be completed before the autumn harvest. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/252709&quot;>;Struggles for land, crossing rivers And bridge demolition: the dilemma of 11 illegal floating bridges behind the &quot;privately built floating bridges&quot; case&lt;/a>;》&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, the location of the convenience bridge was not in the original Near the floating bridge, it was built in Yushu Village, Fushun Town, about ten kilometers downstream. On September 30, Yushu Village Party Secretary Wang Zuoxiang told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why the Bianmin Bridge was built near Yushu Village was because the river surface in this section is narrower than that in other places. Other river surfaces on the Taoer River are four to five hundred meters long. Width, &quot;Our place is more than 200 meters wide.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the river narrow and it is easy to build a bridge, it is also because it is at the &quot;center point&quot;. There are two rivers in Taonan, the Taoer River and the Jiaoliu River. About 67 administrative villages are distributed on both sides of the two rivers. Before the new convenience bridge was built, there were only three bridges on the 156-kilometer-long Taoer River, namely No. 1 Bridge, Manchudai Bridge and Zhenxi Bridge. Wang Zuoxiang said, &quot;The bridge is located here and can be accessed from both the north and the south. After the bridge is repaired, it will be about 20 kilometers away from the Manchudai Bridge and about 35 kilometers away from the Zhenxi Bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public signboard for the project It shows that &lt;a>;&lt;/a>;&lt;a>;the newly built convenience bridge is made of steel plate material, with a length of 327 meters and a width of 5 meters. The investment is 6.852 million yuan, and the planned completion time is October 31, 2023. &lt;/a>;Wang Zuo Xiangxiang, the local autumn harvest begins in mid-October every year. &quot;Now our Taonan side has basically completed the construction, and the bridge deck has been paved.&quot; However, because the Taoer River built by the Convenience Bridge is the dividing line, one bank is Taonan City, and the other side belongs to Taobei District, Baicheng City. On September 30, Wang Zuoxiang told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;There is a branch of the river in Taobei District, about 50 meters wide, which has not been repaired yet. Now the bridge is a Duantou Bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taonan A staff member of the Propaganda Department of the Municipal Party Committee told a reporter from Southern Weekend: &quot;The situation I know currently is that they are accelerating the construction of the bridge. The main body of the bridge has been basically completed. The &#39;Duetou Bridge&#39; is the approach bridge to the other side. In the process of our bridge construction, It must be guaranteed. If the project is started and implemented, it can be completed in two or three days. It is not very complicated. There is definitely no problem with the bridge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zuoxiang believes that after the convenience bridge is completed, It will definitely be more convenient for people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait. But he has new worries. He believes that after the bridge is completed, there will be a lot of vehicles coming and going, and his Yushu Village is only about 3 kilometers away from the convenience bridge. The vehicles entering and exiting will &quot;clearly use our village&quot; and will crush the village. There is a 4-meter-wide cement road, and the risk factor for villagers&#39; travel has also become higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He hopes that the relevant departments can repair the damaged roads in the village in the future, and at the same time, set up signs at the intersections around the convenience bridge, such as marking intersections or T-shaped intersections. &quot;I am the head of a village, and I have to be responsible for the safety of the villagers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[规避现代认知框架的陷阱：读葛兆光老师序言有感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257798]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhWQU0xWSXD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XpeYfU92LInHlfvSMnOs1PA617EDgUhW QU0xWSXD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Gangsheng has two works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had time to read Teacher Bao Gangsheng’s new book &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot; (Guangxi Normal University Press, 2023), just after reading the preface by teacher Ge Zhaoguang, I felt that this book must be very interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have read Bao Gangsheng&#39;s &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; (Peking University Press, 2015) and his works on democracy. I do not study political science, but am interested in discourse analysis, so the so-called Reading is just a superficial reading out of curiosity about political science discourse, especially the cognitive evolution of terminology and the presentation of discourse. Bao Gangsheng’s academic foundation and keen awareness of issues are absolutely top-notch. Just because I read his &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, I am full of expectations for his new book, but I also have some mixed thoughts about what Teacher Ge said in the preface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is positive about Bao Gangsheng’s approach to the history of ancient thought from the perspective of modern political science, and believes that this is promoting the dialogue between Western theory and Eastern thought. He believes that it is meaningful to re-examine ancient thoughts from the perspective of modern political science. I completely agree with this, but I feel that in doing so, we must avoid the traps of modern cognitive frameworks. Cognitive frames have many functions, one of which is what William James called &quot;selective attention.&quot; One consequence of selective attention is that we pay too much attention to the similarities or differences between the objects being observed, ignoring the fundamental differences or similarities between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Give an example. When Bao Gangsheng introduced China&#39;s political outlook in &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot;, he mentioned three different political outlooks, one is modern, one is ancient, and there is also the Soviet model, that is, class rule. Let&#39;s not talk about this for now. . In the words of Bao Gangsheng, in the ancient political view, &quot;politics&quot; &quot;is most commonly understood to refer to the activities of the monarch and his ministers in ruling the country and governing society.&quot; Simply put, it actually means &quot;monarchy.&quot; According to Bao Gangsheng’s explanation, the modern political outlook is “the Chinese translation of English politics” and is a foreign concept. He quoted Sun Yat-sen&#39;s view that &quot;the management of people&#39;s affairs is politics.&quot; There is another sentence before: &quot;Government is a matter for everyone.&quot; Therefore, the politics in Sun Yat-sen&#39;s mind is &quot;administering political affairs by the people&quot;, which is the so-called &quot;democracy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to teacher Gao Quanxi in the book &quot;Modern Western Political Thought&quot;, the ancient Western monarchy is completely different from the ancient Chinese monarchy. If Bao Gangsheng’s summary and Gao Quanxi’s statement hold true, “monarchy” politics and “civil rights” politics are different concepts and belong to different cognitive frameworks with essential conflicts. Western &quot;monarchy&quot; theory and ancient Chinese &quot;monarchy&quot; or &quot;royal power&quot; also belong to different cognitive categories. According to the most basic assumptions of discourse analysis, terms generated by different cognitive frameworks and categories belong to different semantic fields and form different semantic relationships with related words. Two questions arise: 1) Is it appropriate to use different cognitive frameworks to explain political concepts expressed in the same text? 2) Is it appropriate to use words with different semantic relationships to explain the same term? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why I have such doubts is because there are many such examples in &quot;Political Science&quot; that I think are specious. For example, &quot;Confucius believed that politics should be upright. If the king above is upright, the people will be upright.&quot; When commenting on the concept of Confucius, Bao Gangsheng mentioned &quot;The Wealth of Nations&quot; and &quot;Theory of Moral Sentiments&quot; written by Adam Smith. He seemed to think that &quot;virtue&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; are synonymous with Confucius&#39; &quot;rectitude&quot;, as if It is said that Confucius&#39; &quot;benevolent government&quot; and &quot;ethics&quot; are highly similar to Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook. Is it really like this? Is Confucius&#39;s moral outlook centered on &quot;royal power&quot; and based on the differential order pattern the same as Adam Smith&#39;s moral outlook based on the concept of equality centered on &quot;civil rights&quot;? If traditional ethics are virtues, then why did Lu Xun think that ethics cannibalize people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example, &quot;General Knowledge of Political Science&quot; is based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;The master of the Ming Dynasty guides his ministers with only two handles. The two handles are the virtue of punishment. What is the virtue of punishment?&quot; Killing is called punishment, celebrating reward is called virtue.&quot; This passage makes the following judgment: &quot;The principle here is close to the management philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organizations, that is, organizational management should pay attention to clear rewards and punishments.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t understand the philosophy of modern industrial and commercial organization management. Is such a simple principle of clear rewards and punishments the fundamental principle of modern industrial and commercial organization management philosophy? Are the premise of this principle for industrial and commercial organizations to be the same as Han Fei’s? What are the standards of modern principles? What are its basic assumptions? Do the two involve the same semantic relationship? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same section, the author draws this conclusion based on Han Fei&#39;s &quot;If a person does not die, the coffin will not be bought. Love does not mean hating people, but benefits from people&#39;s death&quot;: &quot;In fact , Han Fei had a perspective similar to Adam Smith more than 2,000 years ago, and he had elaborated the &#39;economic man&#39; hypothesis and the methodology of individualism to a certain extent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;As an economic concept, doesn’t “economic man” have different basic premises and presuppositions? Is the core semantic term of &quot;individualism&quot; as an ism just &quot;profit&quot;? Are their semantic fields the same as Han Fei&#39;s? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I saw Teacher Ge’s high-level summary of some of the book’s viewpoints in the preface, such as “summarizing Taoism using methodism, weakness, inaction, and abandonment of wisdom.” Based on past readings, I even had the idea You shouldn’t have unreasonable doubts if you haven’t read the original work. I don’t know how the discussion of the book unfolded. Taoism&#39;s &quot;following the Tao, being weak, doing nothing, abandoning wisdom&quot; all have their own specific historical context and intertextual relationship. Is the &quot;wisdom&quot; mentioned in &quot;Qi Zhi&quot; a general sense? In terms of semantic relationship, can &quot;abandoning wisdom&quot; be separated from &quot;extreme sage&quot;? Although the political thought of Taoism is mentioned in academic circles, those who do not talk about &quot;governance&quot; but pursue &quot;governing by doing nothing&quot; and do not talk about &quot;law&quot; but hope for &quot;a world of supreme virtue&quot; generally use &quot;quan&quot; as the core meaning. Xiang’s “political thought”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Teacher Ge’s perspective in writing the preface is different. He criticized that &quot;some people always want to advocate &amp;nbsp;&#39;interpret China by China&#39;&quot;, meaning that these people attempt to study ancient Chinese thought in isolation from the world&#39;s modern pluralistic knowledge system. I totally agree with this. I think of Takeuchi&#39;s &quot;Asia as Method&quot; and Maruyama Masao&#39;s &quot;China as Method.&quot; The methods they advocate do not exclude the world&#39;s diverse knowledge systems. They just hope to use China&#39;s historical experience and traditional thoughts as one of the world&#39;s cognitive systems and methods. The reason why those advocates of &quot;explaining China in terms of China&quot; are problematic may be because they want to break away from the world&#39;s diverse knowledge system and develop a system that only they (here, they themselves) understand, and cannot communicate with others because they ignore consensus. The mystical explanation system of dialogue; or because its purpose is not to explain China in terms of &quot;China&quot;, but to explain China from the perspective of traditional &quot;rulers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Ge is right in criticizing that these people always want to &quot;advocate going back to ancient times&quot; to find a &quot;whole must and tail&quot; explanation system. If these people have any basic respect for common sense, they should know that they cannot go back after receiving modern education. According to the basic assumptions of pragmatics, the context on which cognition is generated is not reality, but a construction, which is the result of selecting specific parameters. The so-called ancient context is actually a modern construction they made for a special purpose and based on their chosen cognitive framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, what Teacher Ge said: modern concepts and re-division and integration, &quot;allowing the originally chaotic ancient culture to present an understandable face&quot; should refer to allowing ancient culture to be understood in the modern cognitive environment. However, any contemporary &quot;rediscovery&quot; of ancient documents is actually a cognitive reconstruction of ancient times based on modern knowledge or experience. Therefore, how close this understanding is to the original face of the research object also depends on different perceptions. Know the choice of framework. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I am not opposed to re-examining ancient ideas from the perspective of modern political science to present different modern understandings. I just want to say that the premise of this kind of review is that we cannot ignore the historical semantic fields and semantic relationships of various conceptual systems, and we cannot cut them off to suit their needs. What cannot be forgotten is that the reason why we can find modern elements in ancient concepts, that is, the so-called &quot;ancient concepts&quot;, is more because we have replaced the cognitive framework and placed related concepts in different semantics. field, a new semantic relationship is constructed based on the new semantic field. But because the words are still words from the past, it is very easy to mistake our construction for the original semantic items of these words. This is what I think is the trap of modern cognitive frameworks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book &quot;Political Science&quot; actually has a clear understanding of the differences in historical semantics. As the book points out, ancient Greece, the source of Western political science, had a fundamentally different view of politics: “In the eyes of the ancient Greeks, politics was the governance and management activities in which citizens of the city-state participated. The concept of politics at that time itself included citizen participation. The meaning of city-state affairs. Only the participation of citizens in the governance and management of city-state affairs can be called politics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, although the political words of &quot;royal power&quot; and &quot;civil rights&quot; have not changed, they Do they belong to the same semantic field? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had the chance to read &quot;Confucianism, Legalism and Taoism: Political Imagination in Early China&quot;. &amp;nbsp;These are at best a record of random thoughts caused by reading the preface of the book posted online. I will wait until I have time to read it. , be sure to read the original work carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 18:25:27 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[哪些孩子需要课外培训？我在高考大省的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258018]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 16:57:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Professor Shen Yan of Peking University HSBC Business School published a paper in Economics (Quarterly) entitled &quot;Education Burden Reduction, Family Education Expenditure and Educational Equity&quot; paper. The author uses the China Family Panel Study (CFPS) survey data of 14,960 households in 25 provinces, municipalities, and autonomous regions across the country from 2010 to conduct empirical analysis on a total of 42,590 individuals to evaluate the overall impact of burden reduction policies on students&#39; academic burden and family financial burden. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the results of the paper, students from families with incomes in the bottom 10% have an average probability of entering high school that has dropped by 9.3%, total education expenditures have dropped by an average of 21%, and weekly study time has dropped by an average of 9.19 hours. . For students from families with incomes in the upper 10%, the probability of entering high school has increased by 5.3 percentage points on average, total education expenditures have increased by 67% on average, and study time per week has increased by 10.37 hours on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall conclusion is: first, the previous burden reduction policy has brought about the differentiation of educational output, increasing the probability of students from high-income families entering high school, while the probability of students from low-income families declining; Second, the burden reduction policy has also led to the differentiation of education investment: on the one hand, the education expenditure and student learning time of high-income families have both increased, while the low-income families have experienced a decrease; on the other hand, families with high investment in the early stage will reduce their family education expenditure. And low-investment families will increase their education expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This conclusion is simply that children from high-income families invest more in educational expenditures and educational time, and the results are better. Children from low-income families, on the other hand, experience a decline in financial resources, time, and effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be said that this research is basically consistent with my observations around me. I live in Shandong, which is a province with a large population and a high level of college entrance examination. The difficulty of the college entrance examination also falls into the &quot;hell mode&quot;. In such a general environment, it is impossible to be completely &quot;flat&quot; on education issues. Parents attach great importance to education and examinations, and basically spare no effort in investing in education within their capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an English training institution downstairs from my house. Although it is not as well-known as New Oriental and Xueersi, the management is generally quite formal and the student pool is decent. Many children have signed up there. The &quot;double reduction&quot; policy was introduced and business resumed after a period of suspension. This kind of reopening is also compliant, because the &quot;double reduction&quot; has a series of clear requirements for off-campus training, as long as you fully cooperate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, except for those places in the country where the college entrance examination is in the &quot;easy mode&quot;, many places are facing the pressure of competition for higher education. In these places, even people in the education authorities are also faced with the education problems of their own children. They still have some understanding of the actual situation at the grassroots level, so with a pragmatic and people-oriented attitude, some management aspects that are more humane can play a certain buffering role during the implementation of the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reopening, prices have generally increased. For old customers, with various discounts, prices are basically the same as before. For new customers, the price has increased compared to before. Moreover, if you choose to pay fees for one year before, you can enjoy certain discounts. However, according to the latest regulatory requirements, you can only pay fees for one quarter at a time, and the discounts are no longer available. In fact, it is also a disguised form of payment. Price increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My eldest child is 11 years old this year, and my second child is 6 years old. One is in sixth grade and the other is in first grade. My child&#39;s classmates have previously enrolled in various cram schools, including mathematics, English, composition, etc. Of course, there are also those who don’t enroll in any classes. The overall situation is that those who used to enroll in various classes are still enrolling now, and I haven’t heard of a decrease. I used to rush to events on weekends, but I still rush now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original intention of &quot;double reduction&quot; is to reduce the burden on families and children. However, the specific situation in each province and each region is somewhat different. In a province with a large population like Shandong, the pressure of competition in the college entrance examination will be passed down through the layers. Although parents also hope that their children can develop in an all-round way, they do not dare to take the scores lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents of several children get together, the focus of the chat will easily fall on the issue of future studies. Not only the college entrance examination, but also the previous high school entrance examination, high school and junior high school school selection and other issues. A very real problem is that although academic performance is downplayed in policy, most parents still focus on performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not all children who need tutoring are suitable for tutoring. Top academics are never taught. Academic champions generally have strong self-learning ability and self-motivation. They don&#39;t need to make up lessons, and it can even be said that their level may be better than the teacher&#39;s. It is a waste of time and money for top students to make up lessons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, &quot;stupid students&quot; do not need to make up lessons. The diversity of this person and society must be recognized. Just as not everyone is suitable for scientific research, many children are not suitable for learning book knowledge and Test taking. Of course, this does not mean that they are really stupid, but it means that learning book knowledge is too difficult for them. There is not much difference between making up lessons and not making up lessons, so there is no need to spend money and time on it. . Those who are at the middle level and have the motivation to make progress will see results after just a little supplement. This group of students needs supplementary lessons the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, it is to improve grades, and on the other hand, it is to let children know that grades can be improved by working hard, and work can be done well by working hard. In my opinion, the learning process is also a process of building self-confidence and responsibility. Improving grades is important, and self-training and self-growth during the learning process are also important, or even more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我与白塔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257994]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/bs57e1x4IQJ6KraNGzDhWuiQBUA9SVAGzsL5VDqO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/bs57e1x4IQJ6KraNGzDhWuiQBUA9SVAG zsL5VDqO. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children feeling the winter snow under the white tower&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaaaaa;&quot;>;Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a person from a small town in the northeastern border, I have a close relationship with the White Tower in Beijing What&#39;s the fate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who has lived in Beijing for a long time has his or her own feelings and memories about this city, and more or less longing for it. That year, when the lease of my studio in Wangjing came to an end, I tried to find a house in the alleys of the old city, thinking that this would be closer to the nobility and wealth of the city and would be conducive to new development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NyevBw1waDLo7t2WNXaMdLMLJsSEndluWYr07jat.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NyevBw1waDLo7t2WNXaMdLMLJsSEndluWYr07jat.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Vendors chatting at the door of the Gongmenkou wet market&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correct In the middle of summer, I wear NB993 running shoes that are unchanging in all seasons. Because of Steve Jobs, this pair of shoes has a symbolic meaning for me that goes beyond practicality. I bought three pairs in one go and rotate them around. With the blessing of shoes, the scorching sun and showers are no longer unbearable, and the road to dreaming in a foreign land becomes easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I first went to Houhai and Huguo Temple, then searched Dongzhimen and Dongsi. After several twists and turns, I came to Baita Temple and finally found a suitable house. The agent and the landlord have agreed on the price, and I want to go back and think about it before making a decision. As soon as I turned around and hadn&#39;t gone far, the landlord suddenly came out and stopped me, saying that the old man at home wanted to chat again. It turns out that my uncle accidentally heard me talk about his hometown, where he was sent to work as a teacher when he was young. The uncle&#39;s expression reflected the special meaning of that experience to him. I saw in his eyes a trace of sadness at meeting an old friend in a foreign land. The old man took me and asked me in detail about the current situation in my hometown, big and small, and took the trouble. Because of this unexpected fate, the house was settled quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, the place where a person first starts will give life a background and determine certain choices in life. Some passes cannot be forcibly reversed by manpower alone, and trying to do so is mostly in vain; but if you let nature take its course and take things as they come, you can see the bright future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, my fate with the White Tower began, and the White Tower in my heart gradually became clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/jEn7Z0GY4C23HpNmcwD6YDqlDfw3Kaj5egrhQCDq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/jEn7Z0GY4C23HpNmcwD6YDqlDfw3Kaj5egrhQCDq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gongmenkou Hutong under renovation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;many times , I walked around the tower alone. I try to slow down and move forward with a calm and quiet mentality. It seems that it is easier to meet happiness this way. However, as time goes by, wrinkles creep up to the corners of the eyes, and white hair grows on the head. The happiness in the longing for is like a bird perching on the treetops. It seems to be close at hand, but it spreads its wings and slips away. Between movement and stillness, the tall and pure white tower always stared at me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The studio is on the second floor, and the windows face the White Tower. When the sun rises, it covers the window sill with gold; when the sun sets low, it casts the shadow of leaves on the screen window. There is a statue of Venus with a broken arm in the house. According to the uncle, it was left by a tenant painter from the Academy of Arts and Crafts. The statue and the white tower often appear in the same picture, with light and shadow flowing between them, chanting the changes of the four seasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6NdsISkOezbywy1NFtuk6TR9j6tOavRRu9rtt8LO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6NdsISkOezbywy1NFtuk6TR9j6tOavRRu9rtt8LO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Golden Dome of the White Tower under the winter sunset&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5dSDq00pAPdQZpEhhpiok1M8MxLyyb0yKUCvEC5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5dSDq00pAPdQZpEhhpiok1M8MxLyyb0yKUCvEC5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pigeons flying around the tower&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is windy in spring. When the wind blows, the alley is no longer filled with yellow sand and dust, but the gentle airflow makes pedestrians hurry. Spring brings hope, and people want to do something quickly, maybe they can seize a chance and fly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is rainy in summer. Unlike the continuous drizzle in the south, even in the rainy season here, the rain is cheerful and warm, and stops in a flash. Sometimes while walking, a sudden rain shower occurs. The huge raindrops make the leaves rustle and the roof tiles crackle. Pedestrians start running in panic, looking for shelter from the rain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Autumn is so nice. Only in autumn does her beauty fully show here. Every alley, every doorway, balcony, and both sides of the door are filled with various flowers and plants, embellishing a colorful picture against the blue sky. Perhaps only Mr. Lao She&#39;s &quot;Autumn in Peiping&quot; can fully explain that scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Winter is another scene. A heavy snowfall seems to bring time back a hundred years ago. It is difficult to distinguish north, south, east and west in the vast whiteness, but you can vaguely see the Beiping where masters gather. People stayed behind closed doors, but I ran into the wind and snow to capture this time-traveled black and white world with my camera. After the snow, the ice subsided, Lu Xun’s home turned back into his memorial hall, and I returned to reality, under the White Tower in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/T3moYVA9HC1x8ARXk9h7C6nvofjUhGIKDPF7LT9Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/T3moYVA9HC1x8ARXk9h7C6nvofjUhGIKDPF7LT9Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Residences shaded by vines and green plants&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/14Fkgiv03oPupBxYvfvRmNzScD7CZPGKsD0zSdW9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/14Fkgiv03oPupBxYvfvRmNzScD7CZPGKsD0zSdW9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;The dog taking a nap in summer&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Fan/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still remember the Xuji Shaobing Shop in Anping Alley. Big, every morning the aroma of burning pasta wafts out, and people come here to queue up to wait for the sesame seed cakes to be baked. The small tables and chairs at the door are always full of diners, and the crowd is buzzing. The crispy sesame seed cakes paired with a bowl of fragrant bean soup is a delicious treat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Master Bao at the entrance of the palace is always crowded. The Xingyuan Restaurant opposite is a time-honored state-owned restaurant, and the food is quite affordable. Walking west along Fuchengmen Inner Street, you will find Xinchuan Cold Noodles near Fuchengmen Subway Station. In the summer, a big bowl of it, paired with a bottle of ice-cold Arctic Ocean, is so refreshing. There is also a shop selling salted duck eggs downstairs from the studio. The supply is rationed every day, and each one peeled out is full of red oil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MpHQqXlXcavItT0RBSUSyhmc4sTUy7jzEVt8E7er.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MpHQqXlXcavItT0RBSUSyhmc4sTUy7jzEVt8E7er.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;冬日暖阳下晒鸟的大爷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/LdvXPQc344shLwXqCY1sMvQQRuQmYmGOwk3chv83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/LdvXPQc344shLwXqCY1sMvQQRuQmYmGOwk3chv83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;夏天的夜晚，一边乘凉一边玩手机的人们&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白塔寺一带的胡同名称既形象又有趣。印象深的有前抄手胡同、后抄手胡同、大茶叶胡同、小茶叶胡同、东廊下胡同、西廊下胡同，还有一条翠花街——只是没有酸菜炖粉条。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FbCZeRXvpWtyF9fUfvj4qeSm0tiNpzQ9dzZAVyOZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/FbCZeRXvpWtyF9fUfvj4qeSm0tiNpzQ9dzZAVyOZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;藤椅上的鲁迅与经过纪念馆的行人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MFCr0OuOwUR9HrBOKgBUVTEeKW7rWwX56uceOZtn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/MFCr0OuOwUR9HrBOKgBUVTEeKW7rWwX56uceOZtn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;灯火阑珊处的理发店&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，白塔下的夜晚并不热闹，没有后海胡同中小酒吧的狂热与激情，有的是市井烟火在黑夜中的温和绽放。自己那颗白日里躁动的心，也随着夜幕渐渐平静下来。此时不知为何会有些难过，也许是因为眼看着又一天过去了，有点不甘心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/gYOquSrzn0vxzsOINRIPLeN3C02i0PESSM7JDaFn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/gYOquSrzn0vxzsOINRIPLeN3C02i0PESSM7JDaFn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;贴门神的白塔人家&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来慢慢发现，每个人心中都有属于自己的一座白塔。这座塔，也许自己从未抵达，也许从未带人去过。但它一直在那里，巍然伫立，如神明在召唤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5s88RDyn7jAfo7CYfy6mQdIOt2FLrHUVbxzhunJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/5s88RDyn7jAfo7CYfy6mQdIOt2FLrHUVbxzhunJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;追泡泡的男孩儿&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/awM4nnKe7WF850Yn8ukCNK5J5I67EvrqZTjc6OEd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/awM4nnKe7WF850Yn8ukCNK5J5I67EvrqZTjc6OEd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252399&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;白塔下清扫积雪的老大爷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汪凡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孩子出生前，我离开了白塔寺。然而，心中的那座白塔却从未远去。我与大爷一直保持着联系，时常回去探望他，来来去去之间，一再绕塔而行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对了，白塔寺还有另一个名字——妙应寺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被份子钱暴击后，这年头结婚连喜糖也卷麻了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258052]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国庆8天假7个朋友结婚是一种什么样的体验？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博上有人吐槽起国庆节扎堆的婚礼，瞬间引发了网络热议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，当宾客被份子钱等“红色炸弹”轰炸时，新郎新娘也因喜糖喜饼陷入了纠结。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，#精心挑选的喜糖被说差劲#冲上热搜，如何准备喜糖的话题引发热议。有网友精心准备了自己爱吃的小零食，如亲嘴烧、蒟蒻果冻等作为喜糖，被质疑这样的喜糖过分差劲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不知何时开始，“沾沾喜气”的喜糖走向了内卷赛道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，中国喜糖市场短兵相接、两派分立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一派是专注喜糖领域的企业，如爱哆哆等；另一派则是传统糖果企业，如德芙、徐福记等。专注喜糖的企业从定制化以及包装上发力，传统糖果企业则主打国民度和性价比。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比以前祖父母辈的婚礼以包装简单的水果糖、奶糖为主，如今高端化的喜糖是当代新人的选择，比如他们会选用5元1粒的歌帝梵巧克力彰显品位——如今，定制化、个性化、高端成为了喜糖的关键词。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受喜糖驱动，喜铺近年来也迅猛发展，目前全国各地规模以上的喜铺有22000余家，南方喜铺文化盛行，占到了全国的六成，北方的喜糖则习惯于从糖果批发市场、大卖场、网上购买，喜铺尚有待发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;扎堆的婚礼背后，是连番轰炸的“红色炸弹”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据显示，上海、浙江等地的份子钱平均为1000元，而一向只是主张讨个彩头的广东人，平均份子钱只有100元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一边在豪掷“千金”随礼，另一边则在豪掷万元办婚礼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，近九成的中国新人都为婚礼花费了5万元以上，甚至还有0.4%的新人花费超过50万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，个性化的婚礼，比如“物哀感”婚礼、碳中和婚礼等也成了年轻人的新选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天，“知道”就跟你聊聊关于喜糖与份子钱那些结婚的甜蜜烦恼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/831b80df1d8aa019cd150056d5435eb1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/831b80df1d8aa019cd150056d5435eb1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/95c2f4acac0bd5d935b7e41ee70742e4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/95c2f4acac0bd5d935b7e41ee70742e4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/1f28cfb09adb79f1b577f5f6dbc2fe7e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/1f28cfb09adb79f1b577f5f6dbc2fe7e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/6899c96a2a3cc79f52ab82a571ba38d0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/6899c96a2a3cc79f52ab82a571ba38d0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252953&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/f9209ae4d2f9444cf823fcddca744dce.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/f9209ae4d2f9444cf823fcddca744dce.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252954&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/a841ff40895bd7c611637dac01109292.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/a841ff40895bd7c611637dac01109292.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/d58a01e5fbb6bb084b06423bea502775.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/03/d58a01e5fbb6bb084b06423bea502775.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:55:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“成年人的奶嘴儿”：人人索要的“情绪价值”究竟是个啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258008]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 13:09:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Li Jiaqi tells you to work hard&quot; incident that made a lot of noise some time ago has provided netizens with entertainment and conversation topics after dinner. In addition, it also triggered the topic: In my country, the world&#39;s largest manufacturing country, the largest informatization country in globalization, and the world&#39;s largest online retail country, why does there still exist such a gap between producers and sellers? The &quot;cyber peddler&quot; class is both ancient and modern, and occupies a huge share and decisive influence in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explanation I put forward in the previous article is: just like the eloquent salesmen in the old society, in the process of walking around the streets, they can make potential customers buy or not. Feeling relaxed. In modern society, &quot;cyber salesmen&quot; like Li Jiaqi provide their fans with more than just eyebrow pencils, powders and lipsticks, but also emotional value, which is even more important than the actual goods. (Create a link: &quot;Before the &quot;best friends&quot; said bad things to each other: How can &quot;cyber peddlers&quot; like Li Jiaqi succeed against the trend?&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, after always using &quot;all girls&quot; as the opening of the live broadcast, use The &quot;bestie&quot; who held consumers in the palm of his hand and coaxed them into the clouds with his &quot;bestie voice&quot; suddenly broke out in his fatigue. When he began to &quot;struggle to educate&quot; consumers, he himself was &quot;cut off&quot; by the emotional value of the consumer. It is also an expected result that they are pushed into the whirlpool of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that &quot;emotional value&quot; is not only the key element for Li Jiaqi from the clouds of the business empire to the center of the whirlpool of public opinion, but also the root of the survival of the &quot;cyber peddler&quot; profession in modern society. In fact, this concept has already surpassed the live broadcast e-commerce industry and has spread in all fields of this society. We should talk about &quot;emotional value&quot; in the workplace, &quot;emotional value&quot; in love, and even in family life. Let’s talk about “emotional value”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what is this &quot;emotional value&quot; that everyone wants and is more important than the commodity itself in commodity trading activities? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spiritual pacifier of the adult world&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Contrary to the intuitive impression of most people, emotional value (Emotional Value), a term that looks very much like a psychological term, is actually a complete term. The marketing concept itself refers to the difference between emotional benefits and emotional costs in the marketing process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it simply, in a shopping trip, regardless of whether the transaction is finally concluded, as long as the positive emotional experience provided by the seller to the consumer is greater than the negative experience, the consumer will obtain positive emotional value. This is a right Favorable results for the seller. On the contrary, if consumers gain negative emotional value, it will be an unfavorable result for the seller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sales industry, emotional value theory is often used to design and optimize sales processes, guide sales staff training, provide customers with a better consumption experience, and convert and fix potential customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as mentioned above, in today&#39;s society, both the concept of &quot;emotional value&quot; and the theory of emotional value itself have been greatly abused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In almost all fields of social and interpersonal communication, people’s demand for “emotional value” is becoming more and more urgent and intense. On a popular social APP, you can see everywhere that the emotional value requested is not as good as expected. Various complaints are raised: the boss cannot provide emotional value, colleagues cannot provide emotional value, love/marriage partners cannot provide emotional value, parents cannot provide emotional value, and even strangers who occasionally meet cannot provide emotional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, &quot;emotional value&quot; has changed from a marketing concept to an ability, an ability to use language to make people feel &quot;comfortable&quot;. Regardless of whether this language is the result of rational thinking, or whether its rhetoric is consistent with objective facts, as long as it can make people feel &quot;comfortable&quot;, it has the ability to &quot;provide emotional value.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People who are accustomed to asking for &quot;emotional value&quot; from others in life have a common characteristic, which is that regardless of whether they have this ability, they must require the other party to have this ability. While refusing to give in in public life, he complains that others cannot provide enough emotional value. This kind of mentality that is both strong and fragile, and wants to take but is unwilling to give, has formed one flammable and explosive tinderbox after another in social and public life, which can explode anytime and anywhere the moment they lose their pacifier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is an obvious fact that in modern society, while information technology and communication technology connect individuals more and more closely, the continuous disintegration of communities also makes individuals become more and more independent. Alone, people end up becoming what Hannah Arendt called &quot;atomized individuals&quot; - they may be very closely packed but at the same time isolated from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of &quot;noisy loneliness&quot; makes atomized individuals usually place material enjoyment in a very high position in order to alleviate and comfort the spiritual loneliness. Correspondingly, this kind of individual is psychologically lonely. Vulnerability also drives them to endlessly ask for the so-called &quot;emotional value&quot; from the outside world. Therefore, the overwhelming emotional value in modern society has long since changed from a marketing concept to a spiritual pacifier in the adult world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A paradise of clever lies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Just like in the business empire built by &quot;Cyber ​​Merchant&quot; with &quot;family members&quot; and &quot;queens&quot;, the emotional value is more important than the product itself. The &quot;emotional value&quot; that pervades other areas of society also exceeds reason, logic and objective facts themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the discussion of public affairs, the rhetoric of &quot;putting aside the facts, isn&#39;t XXX wrong?&quot; that can be seen everywhere is an excellent example of this kind of mentality, completely regardless of objective facts. Regardless of whether there is a problem with your own thinking logic (or no logic at all), as long as the other party makes you feel subjectively uncomfortable, it means that you have not provided &quot;emotional value&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an individual regards &quot;emotional value&quot; as the highest goal of social life, excessive and excessive emotional pursuit will inevitably consume and destroy their ability to think and express based on reason and logic. . The so-called &quot;thinking&quot; has become an animal conditioned reflex of &quot;if there is no pacifier, I will make a fuss&quot;. The so-called &quot;expressions&quot; are all the catharsis of accumulated emotions, and people cannot have any meaningful discussions, because all fact-based discussions will deviate from their original track and end in a hysterical mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A society full of such individuals must be a kindergarten composed of &quot;children aged 6 years and 256 months&quot; where &quot;everyone is fragile and needs to be coaxed&quot;, and it will naturally become a place where all kinds of clever words and tricks are Liars are at home in this paradise of lies. For some people, the sweet-talking online opposite sex in the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; can obviously provide higher &quot;emotional value&quot; than the &quot;low emotional intelligence&quot; partner in reality. For the elderly, the health product sellers who hang around them every day and talk about &quot;Mom and Dad&quot; obviously provide more &quot;emotional value&quot; than their own children who come back once a month and become impatient with a few words. Ultimately, a society where &quot;there is always someone to trick you&quot; will inevitably become a society where &quot;there is always a liar that suits you&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ability to regulate one&#39;s own emotions is the basic ability of adults living in modern society. It is normal for people&#39;s emotions to fluctuate under the influence of others, but if an adult&#39;s emotions are completely provided and controlled by others , then he can only be an adult in the physiological sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of social modernization is irreversible. Problems such as individual atomization, mental loneliness and vulnerability, and psychological immaturity that arise in the process of social modernization cannot be solved by reconstructing the pre-modern society where &quot;chickens and dogs hear each other&quot; solve. The ultimate solution to the problems caused by modernization is modernization itself. From the perspective of &quot;emotional value&quot;, we see a &quot;crisis of modernity&quot; that needs to be faced squarely and urgently resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“陪拍”爆红，出租自己的工具人生意也火了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257709]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访谢飞：“如果内容都讲不清楚， 这个时代的电影就不会有光彩”丨影视大咖谈⑤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257483]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 12/02/8mcJrhvBnwWykQYR6Cw86h5eBS1MXcd12I1qZ9R6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;630&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/8mcJrhvBnwWykQYR6Cw86h5 eBS1MXcd12I1qZ9R6. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;173882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 22, 1993, &quot;The Fragrant Soul Girl&quot; directed by Xie Fei and Li &quot;The Wedding Banquet&quot; directed by An jointly won the Golden Bear Award at the 43rd Berlin International Film Festival. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Fei spends a lot of time in film festivals of all sizes every year. After the epidemic, he can only When participating in the film festival in China, he thought that the directors of his generation were nearly eighty years old and had not participated in social activities for many years. He asked the film festival: Can some old filmmakers be invited? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This group of &quot;senior moviegoers&quot; has become a unique sight at the 2021 First Youth Film Festival and Pingyao Film Festival. Xie Fei and his classmates were mostly film graduates in the 1960s and are representatives of China&#39;s fourth generation of directors. They call the beautiful years of making movies the &quot;Age of Innocence&quot;. Xie Fei explained, &quot;When we were filming the first and second movies, we were very young, even naive, but we had something sincere in it.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Today, most of their lives have nothing to do with movies. 79-year-old Xie Fei is busy sorting out his parents&#39; information during their lifetimes. A few years ago, he published family letters for his father and is now sorting out his diaries. His goal is to complete them all before the age of 85, otherwise &quot;if you are confused and unable to do it in the future, you will regret it.&quot; Others praised him for his good health and that he should continue to make movies, but he disagreed. In addition to movies, there are many important things in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He publishes film reviews on Douban every now and then, and is known as &quot;the biggest film critic.&quot; His vision of watching movies is very broad, and he has to check out the latest movies, popular online dramas, and even popular animations. The Japanese science fiction anime &quot;Evangelion: The Movie: Finale&quot; has a Douban score of 9.2. Before watching this movie, Xie Fei deliberately made up for its more than 20 years of animation history, but he still felt &quot;confused. Can’t understand”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2021, the Pingyao Film Festival replayed his 2000 work &quot;Yixi Dolma&quot;. Xie Fei marked the film as &quot;seen&quot; on Douban. Netizens replied below: Have you not only seen it? &quot;Yeshe Dolma&quot; uses the life story of a Tibetan woman to reflect the changes in Tibet over half a century. Several Tibetan actors who were in their early twenties are now in their forties. Xie Fei invited them from Lhasa. They said that Lhasa is different now and more modern. Reviewing old works, Xie Fei was objective and confident: &quot;Although this movie has many shortcomings, it is not outdated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Fei&#39;s film career began after the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. He shot nine movies, &quot; &quot;Best Year&quot; and &quot;Scented Soul Girl&quot; won the Silver Bear Award and Golden Bear Award at the Berlin International Film Festival. It was the prime year for Chinese-language films to emerge in the international film industry. In 1993, the Golden Bear Award was unexpectedly awarded with a &quot;double yolk egg&quot;. Xie Fei&#39;s &quot;Scented Soul Girl&quot; and Ang Lee&#39;s &quot;The Wedding Banquet&quot; won at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Yixi Dolma&quot;, 58-year-old Xie Fei announced that he would no longer make movies. He filmed two TV series. Later, in 2003, he was infected with SARS and was classified as a seriously ill patient in the hospital. After recovering, Xie Fei stopped filming completely and devoted himself entirely to teaching at the Beijing Film Academy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Fei admires his 83-year-old old classmate Ding Yinnan the most. He is good at making biopics such as &quot;Sun Yat-sen&quot; and &quot;Zhou Enlai&quot;. In 2015, he co-directed his latest work with his son. &quot;He still has a lot of plans, so he won&#39;t stop. His physical condition is very good now. As long as his son is with him, he can take pictures until he is 90 years old.&quot; Xie Fei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The representatives of American new Hollywood movies are about the same age as China’s fourth-generation directors. Martin Scorsese and Xie Fei are the same age, and they continue to create films at a rate of two to three years. Xie Fei wrote in a Douban film review, &quot;Envy, jealousy, but not hate. Everyone has his own destiny.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On November 1, 2021, Xie Fei accepted an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend in the office of Beijing Film Academy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“You are not a real director if you don’t make three movies in a row”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the experience of veteran directors participating in the film festival this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We old comrades are very interested in watching the first and second movies made by these children in the digital age, including the later I have reviewed the award-winning films &quot;The Last Farewell&quot; and &quot;A Man&#39;s Funeral&quot; on Douban, and there are also some more traditional and solid films. And we found that such a folk film festival is doing very important work in supporting the growth of a new generation of young people. It was a very difficult process from graduating from undergraduate to graduate, shooting one or two short films, and then to making feature films. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, we were all in the era of planned economy. The biggest difference between us, apart from the difference between film and digital, was that we were assigned to traditional national studios after graduation. There will definitely be tasks in it. We will act as assistant directors and scene recorders, and let you direct independently when you have certain abilities. And the country will require: This movie is for comedy and to make money; that movie is about kung fu, you have to do it even if you don’t like it; this movie is something you can explore freely and consciously on your own. So at that time, we had better conditions for growth than young directors today. After graduation, many of us would become independent after working as assistant directors for five or eight years. After independence, everyone made one movie a year and two movies a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the studio at that time, if you had something you wanted to shoot What about movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, you have to fight for the right to shoot. For example, like the now famous director Li Shaohong, she was assigned to Beijing Film Studio after graduation. I was Xie Tieli&#39;s assistant director and worked as many assistant directors. But her first film must be one that makes money. So she made her first movie called &quot;Silver Snake Murder&quot;, which was a thriller and did well at the box office. After that, the factory believed in her, because a girl had made a good film independently, and she made the second film she wanted to make, called &quot;Bloody Morning&quot;, which is based on the Latin American fantasy novel &quot;A Pre-publicized Story&quot;. Adapted from &quot;Homicide&quot;. She transplanted it to rural China, and the final shot was wonderful. In the planned economic system, you also have to look for your opportunities. For example, director Ning Ying came back from studying in Italy. She has her own school of thought. However, her first film at the Beijing Film Studio was a romantic comedy called &quot;Someone Prefers to Fall in Love with Me&quot;. Then she could make &quot;Have Fun&quot; - an art film that she really wanted to make and that had won many awards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this era, we see that digital technology has lowered the threshold for photography. As long as you have the desire for expression and talent, you can sometimes shoot what you like, and it is very formal. Innovative films and we greatly appreciate their creativity. But after these people make this film, if there is no market in the future, no one will invest in them, and many people will not be able to take on the second film. And directing is a practical art, especially when you are around thirty years old. If you don&#39;t make three movies in a row, you are not a real director. You only have one movie, you haven’t had a creative team for several years, and you have less experience. I have met many directors at First. They made a beautiful movie and won various awards, but after three to five years, they never made another movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are many young directors short-lived? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A lot. This is also (because) as freelancers now, in a commercial market-dominated situation, he must stubbornly only want to shoot his own things. He is not adapted to, does not know how to, and does not take the initiative to engage in entertainment and popular styles. Go and learn. Li Shaohong and Ning Ying, who I just talked about, have to force themselves to study well how to shoot entertainment films, comedies, and thrillers, and they will do well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the current film ecosystem, what new directors face Are funding issues more difficult than they were then? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was not very difficult at the time. &quot;Black Horse&quot; found many people in Hong Kong to contribute money, which was actually only more than one million yuan. Because the market is small, we don’t need to invest so much. We don’t have any special technology or equipment, and they are all quite cheap. The most expensive one was the filming of &quot;Yeshe Dolma&quot;. By 1999, the filming was completed for 4.5 million. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now it depends on the director. If you want hundreds of millions or tens of millions, of course it will be difficult. The key is that the producer only dares to invest if he thinks he can make money back. How much is invested and how much is recovered is the job of the producer, not the director. The director&#39;s job is to be artistically complete. If the producer thinks that your story and actors can only make 30 million at the box office, then your investment cannot exceed 10 million. However, whether this estimate is correct or not is the producer&#39;s job. Now it is wrong to say that everything is the responsibility of the director all day long. Movies are a comprehensive art, and the director did not say that he would definitely earn 100 million. If you insist that you can earn 100 million, if you invest lavishly, if you dare to shoot with 100 million, then the protagonist will not give up until he earns several million. Some of them are very unprofitable. You should blame the producer, not the director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was filming &quot;Yeshe Dolma&quot;, when I started looking for money, I also thought that maybe using a star would make this movie better. I approached Gong Li, and Gong Li&#39;s producer said after watching it one day, who should she play in this drama? At first when I was in my twenties, and later when I was in my seventies, I couldn&#39;t rely on anyone and felt like I couldn&#39;t act. Later I discovered that this was impossible. One was that the original taste of Tibet was lost. I saw another group of actors in Lhasa, including old actors in their seventies and actors in their twenties, and they were suitable. It’s effortless. You were originally a subject of art films and suddenly wanted to enter the commercial market. This was a miscalculation. Fortunately for me, I didn&#39;t. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“Chinese films must be passed down from one generation to the next to have a bright future”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic, italic _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What old movies did you screen at the film festival? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Ding Yinnan’s &quot;Zhou Enlai&quot; was filmed in 1992, and it is now thirty years old. I very much hope that modern young audiences and The creators took a look at how our fourth generation represented the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and a great man like Zhou Enlai in the early 1990s, and how we reproduced China&#39;s reality and history. All of us old people rewatched &quot;Zhou Enlai&quot; together with the young people. It was all shot in real locations, because at that time, Deng Yingchao said that he wanted to shoot in the Prime Minister&#39;s original house, as long as you think it&#39;s artistically acceptable. Therefore, even the clothes and shoes worn by Zhou Enlai and the handkerchief he put in his pocket every day are real. The ward of Hospital 305 where Zhou Enlai was seriously ill was also the same. The restoration of the external texture is very wonderful. So today&#39;s young people, how do you use your methods to truly express and record the real life in China? This is your responsibility. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Back then, it was a mission for these directors to make movies with the main theme ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s not a task, it’s their request. No movie is made to commemorate any festival. Because the education they have received since childhood is the education of revolutionary history, they feel that these are important great men. I personally think that the main theme is also the same. The key is how you shoot it and whether you respect the audience. Many reviews of some movies today just count the stars, not the historical figures of that time at all. What is very important is that the most sensational TV series this year was &quot;The Age of Awakening&quot;. I was very excited to watch it. It was very good. It reaffirmed the achievements of Li Dazhao and Chen Duxiu, and it was also presented in a more artistic way. Further down, &quot;Mountains and Seas&quot;, a TV series about poverty alleviation, starts from the trail and writes about a village very vividly. I think if the main melody is made according to the rules of art, it may be done well and the audience will like it. The audience may also be disgusted by competing for stars and scenes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of screening and watching these old movies today? What is the meaning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Our generation is still alive now, so if you can speak, speak as soon as possible. Next year I think I will hire the fifth generation if it doesn’t work out. Except for Zhang Yimou and Chen Kaige, most of the fifth generation are no longer on the front line, and they haven’t filmed in a few years. Most of them are my students. Tian Zhuangzhuang is still filming. Recently, a film has not been cut out. Wu Ziniu has not filmed much anymore. In addition, Wang Jixing who filmed &quot;Jiao Yulu&quot; and Huang Jianxin have been doing it. Ye Daying filmed &quot;Jiao Yulu&quot; back then. &quot;Red Cherry&quot; was very sensational, and Mi Jiashan also filmed &quot;The Unruly Lord&quot;. If these films are taken out and watched today, young people will find them very vivid, and they never expected that they were so beautiful and had such pioneering consciousness and ideas. I personally feel that we need to understand the benefits of these works and the reasons of the times why they were produced. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese films must be passed down from generation to generation in order to have a bright future. For example, people of our generation watched the third generation and the second generation. The earliest ones include &quot;Street Angel&quot;, &quot;Cross Street&quot; and &quot;A River of Spring Flows East&quot;. The best tradition in the early days of Chinese films is realism, and family ethics dramas are particularly good. . Family ethics are placed in the context of the great times. You think of &quot;A River of Spring Flows East&quot;, which expresses the great times through family ethics and has become a Chinese movie classic. In the third generation, &quot;Furong Town&quot; directed by Xie Jin is also about the moral and ethical changes of the family. Therefore, the type of family ethics is something that has been very successful in Chinese film realism. We must inherit it now. We cannot simply reject it and think that family ethics is tacky and the love between children is not grand. Another example is the second and third generation of Chinese films. They created kung fu films based on Chinese martial arts. From &quot;Burning the Red Lotus Temple&quot; to &quot;Shaolin Temple&quot; and &quot;Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon&quot; they have conquered the world. We young people can’t help but be interested, and we can’t understand that whether it’s an artistic film or a commercial film, it must be passed down. We don’t require everyone to cover everything, but we hope that there will be an inheritance as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the issue of inheritance? First of all, you need to watch movies that you have never seen and have forgotten. Your mind is filled with foreign things, especially some popular foreign movies. For example, in the Chinese theater industry, Western musicals have been praised over the years. I have seen it on Broadway several times. It is very popular, but it is very short and is far behind our operas. The opera actors have better kung fu than them. Much stronger. There are obviously such good operas in China, but they don&#39;t inherit or develop them. Instead, they just insist on reviving musicals in China. They have been doing it for 30 or 40 years. Do you think there is a mature one? Is there one that is loved by the wider music audience? Chinese film and television also have this problem. I watched Japan&#39;s &quot;Neon Evangelion&quot; the other day. I really didn&#39;t understand how great it was, including the recent &quot;Dune&quot;. This is the culture of foreigners, and they have had it for decades. If we Chinese are chasing these things to the death, you will never be able to make something that represents Chinese quality. When making movies in China, you have to learn things from the fourth generation, and even a lot of things from the third and second generations. You have only heard of &quot;Spring in a Small Town&quot;. You need to take a closer look at why &quot;Spring in a Small Town&quot; is rated so highly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What traditions of the fourth generation do you think are still relevant to today’s young filmmakers? Lost it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think what is very important is social thinking and cultural thinking. I think one of the biggest characteristics of the 1980s is that after &quot;Practice is the Only Criterion for Testing Truth&quot;, it caused the whole society to reflect on the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. Scar literature and scar movies were produced on the basis of reflection, and later, root-seeking appeared. In literature, we have to look for the reason and our bad nature from two thousand years of feudal culture, so many movies are adapted from these novels. The greatest advantage of our time was that our thoughts and creations advanced side by side and encouraged each other. The stagnation of thought can easily lead to the author&#39;s self-restraint, and the author has no choice but to write some self-expression of small favors, small grudges, and small disputes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qEXM00Mnot1TgNA20aj93BJgsFbicHy87XI74aMt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/qEXM00Mnot1TgNA20aj93BJgsFbicHy87XI74aMt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;173877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xie Fei (left) and Jia Zhangke at the press conference of &quot;The Black Horse&quot; at the 3rd Pingyao International Film Festival on October 14, 2019. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“Many movies that are considered classics in China have not been seen by Westerners. to”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why the fourth generation of movies seems to have less impact on young people Is it as big as the fifth generation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have a doctoral student who is a foreign girl. Her topic is the recommendation of Chinese films by the three major Western film festivals. In the Western world, film festivals have a strong value-added function. As long as this work is selected by a major film festival and enters the main competition, it will immediately rise to a level. If it wins the grand prize, many critics will want to see it, and in the end, it may become famous in historical circles. Consider it a classic. Before the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, Chinese films were basically not produced in the West. &quot;Red Sorghum&quot; won the Golden Bear Award in Berlin in 1988. This was considered the first breakthrough. Zhang Yimou suddenly became famous all over the world, and then &quot;Qiu Ju&#39;s Lawsuit&quot; in 1992 &quot; and &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; in 1993. In the same year, all three major film festivals (awards) were won by Chinese films. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reputation of the fourth generation of directors is not as good as them, because they have continuity. Zhang Yimou later had a series of films that won awards at three major film festivals, as did Chen Kaige before and after, and they appeared in the theoretical circles The title of &quot;fifth generation&quot; was adopted, and the previous generations were deduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a student, I have read a lot of information about the three major film festivals. The third, fourth, and fifth generation films in the new era are all recognized by Westerners, but by some strange combination of circumstances, they all think they are fifth-generation films. generation. Xie Jin&#39;s &quot;Furong Town&quot; was wanted in Cannes after it was filmed in 1986. However, it was not given and was given to the Karlovy Vary Film Festival in the Czech Republic. If he had gone to Cannes at that time, he might have won the award in 1986, and the third generation would have become extremely popular. Without the award, the West didn&#39;t talk much about the overall review. In fact, in the later retrospectives, the West highly praised &quot;Stage Sisters&quot; directed by Xie Jin and thought it was a very good director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a textbook used by many universities in the United States called &quot;Understanding Movies&quot;. It was published in the early 1980s. Every time it is reprinted, new movies will be added. There are now fourteen editions. There is only one movie from China, &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;. Other Asian films, such as several films by Japan&#39;s Akira Kurosawa and even older films by Rai from India, were considered classics by Westerners, and their reputation soared. As for Chinese films, the three major film festivals have made Westerners aware of some Chinese films. The final conclusion of this study is that Western films have a one-sided understanding of Chinese films. Many films that are considered classics in China have not been seen by Westerners, do not know them, and have not been evaluated. We Chinese think it is good, but some of them do not recognize it due to political reasons. For example, they don&#39;t watch these main theme works directed by Ding Yinnan, but actually ask us to watch them. They are already very good, not much worse than their &quot;General Patton&quot;, but there are political barriers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a very clear example. The Sixth Generation was not screened in China at the beginning, but Jia Zhangke became famous all over the world. When he was probably less than fifty years old, he was awarded Lifetime Achievement Awards by several international film festivals. I heard at that time that &quot;Three Gorges&quot; is the Chinese film that has sold the largest number of films to all five continents and countries around the world, because from a humanistic perspective, Westerners think that the great migration of millions of people is a huge human social phenomenon, and this film is very Artistically expressing this change, they believe that Jia Zhangke&#39;s film is a thirty-year history of social changes in China&#39;s counties, and has very strong cognitive value. Then it was released (in China) and the box office was also very low. I remember that when &quot;The Good Man from Three Gorges&quot; was being performed, Zhang Yimou&#39;s &quot;A City of Gold&quot; was released. Jia Zhangke said sadly that no matter how good a good man is, he can&#39;t compare to gold. Jia Zhangke has organized various festivals and schools in China, and is also a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress, so his status is quite high. But if you really ask the general audience, very few people have seen his movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in the fourth generation or even the third generation, many people have not had the opportunity to go out to some of our good works back then. Some, like mine, have gone out, but people have the impression that you are one of the fifth generation. So we often tell these doctoral students that in fact, from the 1980s to the early 1990s, the glory of Chinese films in the world was jointly created by three, four, and five generations. Another thing is to see that foreign opinions have their correctness and limitations. They are curious. For example, if you praise the correctness of the light, they will not be interested. But when they enter social reality and criticize reality, they are particularly interested. interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did you care more about the recognition of foreign film festivals in the past than now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; It has always been the case until today, but now I don’t take it so seriously. It seems that there was a news last year and this year that one of the three major festivals is a Chinese film None, unfortunately. After 2007 and 2008, Chinese films also entered the main competition, but they were very scattered. There are some that have won awards, such as &quot;Fireworks in the Day&quot; and &quot;Tuya&#39;s Marriage&quot;, but these films themselves are not particularly well received in China. Unlike at that time, &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; is still the most highly rated Chinese film on Douban now, so you can&#39;t say that the masses are influenced by foreign film festivals, and it itself is genuine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/mFbNH1GMGKoFxmapTeecAQAZX2Q5CVZ0qbxQUp2E.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/12/02/mFbNH1GMGKoFxmapTeecAQAZX2Q5CVZ0qbxQUp2E.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;173887&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xie Fei and Jiang Wen on the set of &quot;Ben Ming Nian&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&quot;The complexity of human nature is not captured in the photo. The Chinese people in the future will also see I don’t understand”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After participating in domestic film festivals, what do you think of the current youth What is the overall level of filmmakers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After I came back from Pingyao and First, I wrote a Douban article, mainly to comment on several award-winning films. In fact, I feel that the form is greater than the content, and I work hard on the form, but the content and even the basic plot narration are not up to standard. This is a bad thing, because content is the core. If the content is not explained clearly, the explanation will be even less weighty, and the movies of this era will not have brilliance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many of your films are adapted from literary works , now many young directors like to write their own scripts, what do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xie Fei: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;One is that many people do not read novels or read literature, and their literary foundation is poor. There are still some good works by writers who are still active in China. You have to be patient and read them. Every year, for example, the Mao Dun Literary Award awards countless novels. Not long ago, a TV series called &quot;Zhuangtai&quot; came out, which was very successful. This author also wrote a TV series called &quot;Zhuangtai&quot;. &quot;Protagonist&quot; is also very good, and it seems that it will be adapted into a film and television work. Regardless of whether it is a full-length novel or a medium-length novel, there is still an author who is writing things seriously. If we directors can pay attention and read more, we will find that there are many things that are more important than the stories we come up with and are worthy of your expression. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一个就是自我得意，觉得自己能编剧，好的编剧写完了已经开始自导了，他觉得我干嘛要给别人做嫁衣呢？咱们对待导演吹捧过度。电视剧在全世界范围里，编剧是王，确实编剧起最大、根本的作用。像韩国就达到了对编剧很尊重，甚至三个导演轮着拍，哪集都不变样的，这个戏不会掉质量的。咱们这现在不是。很多人说，摄制组里除了几个高智商的主创以外全是民工，基层制作人员中专也没有、大专没有、蓝领学校也没有，他们的文化和技艺能力都得不到培养。一些影视教学，一天到晚说能不能培养出一个小燕子、培养出一个张艺谋来，好像这是学校的功劳，这是不对的。你应该是全面培养，因为影视制作、融媒体的视听制作，那是非常广大的天地，需要大量的技术人才和各种层次的人才。你要尊重他们，包括做服装的、设计发饰的、制作的，都需要技艺和文化。所以一个村的农民能包了中国电视的照明，这是在全世界没有的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你认为当下最好的电影会出现在哪里？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;谢飞：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不知道，因为我看得很少。一个是我们自己要肯定，一个是国际上也能肯定。我反复讲一个观点，今天国外人看不懂的东西，未来两三代以后的中国年轻人也看不懂。你不要以为他是中国人就能看得懂，因为他离开了今天的社会，比如他们会想，为什么在农村不进城？有人说有户口、有粮票，他们就说，那是什么东西？现在的外国人看不懂，原因就是他不了解，你这个电影是就事论事，没有拍出人性的复杂，他就看不懂，未来的中国人也看不懂。你非要求他一定要懂中国的计划经济是怎么回事，他干嘛要弄懂？以前经常有人说，谢飞，你的电影光是外国人叫好，中国人不叫好，你不算成功。我说，你等着看，将来过上两三代以后，中国人还叫好我这个片，你叫好的片他就看不懂了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[仙雾缭绕梵净山丨指尖华夏⑤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257587]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Fanjing Mountain in Tongren City, Guizhou Province is sometimes shrouded in clouds and mist, with cascading mountains and greenery, just like a fairyland on earth, attracting many tourists. Sightseeing tours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fanjing Mountain is the main peak of Wuling Mountains, a national nature reserve and a world natural heritage site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/h3HyHCqqpk8QvBXwH8R9WpjanmlqNzGHlzaiQHhQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/h3HyHCqqpk8QvBXwH8R9WpjanmlqNzGHlzaiQHhQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists sightseeing in the Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area in Tongren City, Guizhou Province. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/XzMqt0KcPKpnTZw3AYu3G9muLsBAQn1PlXrTiy1Z.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/XzMqt0KcPKpnTZw3AYu3G9muLsBAQn1PlXrTiy1Z.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/muNQj271snYb7MueXoGE0X9ZIzWZKhToXwRp1TL0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/muNQj271snYb7MueXoGE0X9ZIzWZKhToXwRp1TL0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/NbvDEZRSPXY6J0jmtb54xar72UpEeAFzUWMhg6pU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;792&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/NbvDEZRSPXY6J0jmtb54xar72UpEeAFzUWMhg6pU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/MSOPHBr7p5F7NrCnjLT6TkOWCwoEyyzoTapo81yJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/MSOPHBr7p5F7NrCnjLT6TkOWCwoEyyzoTapo81yJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/lfAopjzysVrJ4DO93JUI7spbABRnQL7vudH0Aogk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/lfAopjzysVrJ4DO93JUI7spbABRnQL7vudH0Aogk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. (Drone photo) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/wbWFi48oJCegzPqyHn64VphnNGC9uWkE5pfjQZca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/wbWFi48oJCegzPqyHn64VphnNGC9uWkE5pfjQZca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Tongren City, Guizhou Province Sightseeing tour of Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Guixiong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/NWj604ehS4Qvi6dSU1U53DOkIJA5afAbqLWw8URj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;733&quot; height=&quot;1100&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/NWj604ehS4Qvi6dSU1U53DOkIJA5afAbqLWw8URj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists sightseeing in the Fanjing Mountain Scenic Area in Tongren City, Guizhou Province . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/刘贵雄/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贪官八年内给女儿现金近两千万：收钱的女儿有没有罪？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258044]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a piece of news that &quot;a corrupt official transferred nearly 20 million in cash to his daughter within 8 years&quot; attracted attention, and it was disclosed that Details of the corruption of Wu Wei, the former party secretary and director of the Heilongjiang Provincial Civil Defense Office. From 2011 to 2018, Wu Wei took advantage of various opportunities to go to Beijing to send cash to his daughter. Each time, he sent hundreds of thousands of yuan in cash. Wu Wei sent nearly 20 million yuan in cash to her again and again in the past eight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people wonder: The Civil Air Defense Office seems to have no sense of existence. How could the person in charge embezzle so much money? Let&#39;s put it this way, basically everything below the ground is under the control of the Civil Air Defense Office, so there is a lot of space for renting and rent-seeking. When developers build buildings and build underground garages, they stipulate how much area must be used for civil air defense projects. After completion, they must pass the completion acceptance of the civil air defense project construction project. In order to pass the inspection and acceptance, the equipment and materials used in the civil air defense basement often have to purchase designated products, and the so-called deposit or security deposit is actually the &quot;relocation construction fee of the civil air defense project.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, many people in charge of the Civil Air Defense Office have been dismissed. For example, in September 2023, Liang Fangsheng, director of the Fangchenggang City Civil Air Defense Office, was subject to review and investigation; in July, Xue Shibang, the former director of the Jiuquan City Civil Air Defense Office, was &quot;suspected of serious violations of disciplines and laws&quot; and was subject to review and investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to the Wu Wei case, this person put cash in his bag instead of transferring money, which shows that he has a strong awareness of money laundering and anti-money laundering. Transferring money will leave an indelible record. Cash is much more concealed; giving cash to your daughter shows that you love your daughter very much, that you are a &quot;daughter slave&quot;, and that you corrupt your family and your daughter. Taken together, it shows that he is a thoughtful person and a &quot;loving&quot; father. It’s just that the agency’s calculations were too smart. Once the incident happened, it was impossible for the investigators to ignore the whereabouts of the money. If my daughter suddenly had a large amount of cash in her hand, there had to be a reasonable source, right? There is no getting around the question of whether it is money earned legally by oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, everyone&#39;s discussion of this case naturally extended to the question of whether Wu Wei&#39;s daughter was guilty or not. Logically speaking, doesn&#39;t he have an idea of ​​how much legal income his father has? My father gave himself hundreds of thousands every time, only in cash and not in bank accounts. Ten thousand yuan in cash with a face value of one hundred yuan is 115 grams, and half a million yuan is more than ten kilograms. From Harbin to Beijing, it is more than a thousand kilometers. My father worked so hard, saying I didn’t know that the money given by my father was not legal, which seemed a little unreasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Assuming that Wu Wei’s daughter is not guilty, there is still a problem of parents committing crimes and failing their children. Some netizens believe that at least the children of corrupt officials should be deprived of the right to take public exams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, there has been a saying on the Internet that &quot;one person&#39;s crime affects his children&#39;s public examination.&quot; In fact, according to the express law, there is no provision that children whose parents commit crimes do not have the right to take public exams. Article 19 of the 2019 &quot;Civil Service Recruitment Regulations&quot; issued by the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China stipulates that individuals who have &quot;received criminal punishment for crimes&quot; are not allowed to apply for civil servants. There is no provision that children whose parents have committed crimes are not allowed to apply for or be hired as civil servants. There is an &quot;inspection&quot; after passing the public examination ( Also known as the &quot;political examination&quot;), there is no provision for children whose parents commit crimes to fail the examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this is just a general situation. If you apply for secret-related positions or public security, judicial and judicial positions, there will be a substantial &quot;political review&quot; and it will be relatively strict. Take applying for a police job as an example. Article 9 of the 2020 &quot;Political Investigation Work Measures for the Recruitment of People&#39;s Police by Public Security Organs&quot; stipulates: If the family member of the inspection target has one of several circumstances, he or she shall not be determined as a candidate for recruitment, including intentional homicide, intentional injury causing serious injury, or Death, rape, robbery, drug trafficking, arson, explosion, release of dangerous substances and other serious crimes with a negative social impact, or corruption and bribery involving huge amounts and serious circumstances, subject to criminal punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, if the parents have committed vicious crimes or been criminally punished for corruption, their children will not be able to pass the political review when applying for the police examination. Therefore, judging from the express provisions, the special conditions for the establishment of &quot;parents&#39; crimes affecting their children&#39;s public examinations&quot; are: it is limited to certain sensitive and key positions, and it does not mean that parents who commit any crime will be affected by their children; general public offices are not affected, and generally speaking, &quot;parents&quot; It is not true that crime affects children&#39;s public exams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that according to the current law, even if the children of corrupt officials who have been sentenced to actual imprisonment are unable to apply for certain positions or fail the political review, they can still apply for general public offices. But there is indeed a legal and ethical issue here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern society is based on individuals enjoying their rights and taking their own responsibilities. In principle, children should not be implicated because of their parents&#39; crimes or any other faults. This is indeed good. However, the premise for this to be true is that the children do not enjoy the proceeds of their parents’ crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation is different if the child knows or constructively knows of the parent&#39;s criminal conduct and benefits from it. After telecom fraudsters defraud money, they will build a big house for their families and provide their children with the best education and living conditions. It can even be said that the original intention of some telecom fraudsters is to let their children and family live a good life. The children and family members also know that the money came from shady sources but still enjoy it without shame. What’s the problem if they are somehow implicated? On the one hand, a thief cannot just eat meat without being beaten, and on the other hand, it also serves as a deterrent to telecom fraudsters themselves, weakening their motives and incentives for committing fraud. Rather than sympathizing with the children of these implicated telecom fraudsters, everyone should sympathize more with Xu Yuyu. Xu Yuyu, a girl from a poor family, was defrauded of 9,900 yuan in tuition fees just after she was admitted to university, and she died in depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, if the children of convicted embezzlers know or are presumed to know that their parents’ money came from shady sources, and can accept it calmly and remain calm, even if they are not guilty, they cannot be called innocent, and they are restricted from taking public exams. What&#39;s the problem? Public offices are funded by taxpayers and should have higher moral requirements than ordinary people. Everyone should know that enjoying the proceeds of a family member&#39;s crime is at least immoral. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 03 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>