<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[花都华侨农场访问记：海外中国人筚路蓝缕，在国内也同样熠熠发光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent weekend, I took my son to wander around Ersha Island in Guangzhou and accidentally stumbled into the Guangdong Overseas Chinese Museum. , the overseas Chinese farm in one of the exhibition halls aroused my strong interest. As a teacher engaged in sociology, I came up with the idea of ​​visiting the overseas Chinese farm. I searched online and found out that there is an overseas Chinese farm on the outskirts of my city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were no classes on November 6, so early in the morning, I made an appointment with a colleague to go to the destination - the overseas Chinese farm located in Huadong Town, Huadu District, Guangzhou City. Huadu Overseas Chinese Farm has an area of ​​14.55 square kilometers and a registered population of more than 5,200, including residents from 13 countries and regions including Indonesia, Vietnam, Malaysia, Thailand, Japan, Singapore, Cambodia, India, Laos, New Zealand, Madagascar, Hong Kong, and Macau. There are more than 4,800 returned overseas Chinese and their family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The past and present life of Overseas Chinese Farm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After an hour&#39;s drive, we arrived at the &quot;Overseas Chinese Farm&quot; bus station. After briefly consulting an aunt at the canteen, we went to Qiao Xingyuan Community across the road. She said that many returned overseas Chinese live here. The community is not small, with nearly 30 houses together. Half of the houses have an elevated first floor, and there are some privately built houses scattered on the mountain behind. On the empty platform on the first floor of a house, we met two aunties who were busy packing mobile phone cases. They were returned overseas Chinese from Vietnam. My colleagues and I chatted with them while helping to install mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They returned to China in 1978, when they were only 10 and 8 years old respectively, and were placed here together. At that time, the management of the farm separated men and women, and they lived in collective dormitories. Even if they are a family, they must be spread out and cannot live together. The dormitory at that time was made of mud bricks, with rows of bunk beds inside. Due to the large number of people, the space was very small. Later, because too many returned overseas Chinese were accepted, the dormitories were not enough, so they had to live in ancestral halls in nearby villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of agricultural production and livelihood, the farm is similar to the surrounding villages. They are also divided into several production teams. In addition to planting rice, vegetables, peanuts, fruits, oranges, lychees, and mangoes, they also cultivate On the hillside, tea plantations are planted. It is reported that as early as the late 1970s, the Overseas Chinese Farm was the most important tea production base in Huadu. The tea industry was once prosperous, and the tea produced was well-known throughout the province and sold at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of planting tea in the mountains is still vivid in my mind. An aunt said that everyone used axes and hoes to open up the densely forested hills and turned them into tea planting bases. Without machinery, they carried small tea seedlings to the mountains with bare hands to plant them, and then carried buckets of water for watering. Gradually, a lush green tea mountain was formed in the Qifengtian and Wan Gongtang areas, covering an area of ​​several hundred hectares. At that time, we had to work on time every day. We usually got up at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning to pick tea, because the dew was thick at that time, which was the best time to pick tea. Although the conditions are difficult, everyone is very motivated. During the lunch break, everyone will gather together and listen to one of them reading the day&#39;s newspaper aloud, and sometimes someone will take the lead in singing...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is , all returned overseas Chinese who settle on farms can enjoy the same benefits and treatment as urban residents, including food stamps, cloth stamps, meat stamps and other material supplies. Now, after they have retired for many years, they can also enjoy retirement salary benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the aunt told us that rural people in eight villages within ten miles are proud to marry their daughters to the farm, because the daughter will immediately become an &quot;employee&quot; who can &quot;enjoy benefits&quot;, and her personal destiny will be A major turnaround could occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, the local government decided to implement a housing renovation project for Huaqiao Farm, investing 130 million yuan, with a total construction area of ​​more than 70,000 square meters, and built new buildings such as Qiaonan Garden, Qiaogang Garden, and Qiaoxing Garden. In residential areas, employees only need to pay a small amount of money to live in spacious and bright houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aren&#39;t the surrounding villagers envious of you?&quot; I asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That was true at the time, but it&#39;s different now. We envy them very much.&quot; said an aunt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government of Huadong Town, where the overseas Chinese farm was originally located, has taken advantage of its proximity to Baiyun International Airport in recent years and is committed to building an aviation logistics industry cluster, an aviation maintenance industry cluster, an e-commerce industry cluster and a temporary logistics cluster. It is an empty advanced manufacturing agglomeration area and carries out high-intensity development of overseas Chinese farms and nearby villages. Because overseas Chinese farms themselves are state-owned land, they are land development and utilization activities within the government that do not involve property rights replacement, and provide visible benefits to farm employees. However, the situation in nearby villages is different. Many villagers have received considerable compensation for their land expropriation. Some even only need to pay an additional tens of thousands of yuan to live in various comprehensive and complete buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aunts can earn 80-100 yuan a day by doing odd jobs packaging mobile phone cases. Anyway, when they are free at home, they just look at their mobile phones and do something, which makes them comfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original words of an aunt were, &quot;When I was very young, my mother taught me to be hardworking. Now that I am retired, but my body is still strong, I just find something to do, and I feel at ease.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some people know how to play cards and check their mobile phones after retirement, but I don&#39;t like it. I feel bad when I lose money playing cards; it hurts my eyes because I look at my mobile phone all the time. I feel uncomfortable, so I might as well do something.&quot; Another person An aunt said this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The role of returned overseas Chinese&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nearly 12 noon, the aunts will go home for dinner. After saying goodbye to them, we went to Qiao Nan Garden across the road to find food. In a restaurant, we met a family of returned Indonesians having dinner. We simply said hello to them and explained our purpose, but they were so enthusiastic that they invited us to eat with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chat during the dinner, I learned that my aunt’s surname was Wen, and she was the fourth eldest child in the family. She had an older brother, two older sisters, and a younger sister. She returned to China in 1960, when she was 6 years old. Today, the old mother is 98 years old, her mind is still clear and her spirit is still strong. Aunt Wen said that her grandfather went to Indonesia in his early years and was one of the first batch of people to &quot;go to Southeast Asia&quot;. They raised pigs, made tofu, got married and settled down locally. Her parents also inherited their ancestors&#39; business and made a living mainly by making and selling tofu in small cities or towns in southwestern Indonesia. Obviously, they have no choice to settle or make a living in capitals or big cities where competition is fiercer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diligence, frugality, running a small business, and moving forward in hardship and adversity cannot be underestimated. These traits have laid the foundation for Aunt Wen’s generation to be smart and understand business since childhood. After returning to China, Aunt Wen and her family successively ran a bean product factory, a garment factory, a wood processing factory and a restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that these so-called &quot;small and micro enterprises&quot; are not privately owned, but are owned by the farm. The products produced must be handed over to the farm for unified sales or other disposal by the farm. Compared with the nearby villagers who have been farming all day long, Aunt Wen&#39;s family and others like Aunt Wen who have worked abroad for a long time are obviously better in thinking and ideas. They have largely promoted the comprehensive transformation and upgrading of the farm, and have contributed to the farm&#39;s development. Industrial diversification has blazed a trail. Relying on their foresight and example, the farm has begun industrialization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a larger scale, Aunt Wen and a group of people took the lead in promoting the rural industrialization process in the Huadu area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as Aunt Wen is concerned, she is bold, outgoing and sociable. She obtained a Class A driver&#39;s license at the age of 18 and became the only female driver in the farm driver class in the 1980s. She often drove long trailers Traveling all over the country, I naturally have a lot of knowledge and quick thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Wen is also an authentic food maker. During every festival, whether it is a Chinese festival or an Indonesian festival, or when someone in the neighborhood gets married, has a baby, or has a child going to school or joining the military. During the banquet, she would prepare various ingredients a week in advance, sometimes even making a special trip to Hong Kong to purchase them, and make all kinds of exquisite snacks with Indonesian characteristics, such as thousand-layer cakes, manjian kueh, pagoda rice, Padang dishes, fermented soybean cubes, Gadot-Gadot, etc., for relatives, friends and neighbors to taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that the status of returned overseas Chinese has allowed the specialties of various countries to be inherited and promoted in overseas Chinese farms. The neighbors are engaged in cross-cultural exchanges while tasting the delicacies of various countries. Such coexistence and frequent exchanges day and night undoubtedly create a It creates a diverse and culturally rich community atmosphere, which plays a positive role in resolving community conflicts and disputes, building a community development community, improving community self-organization capabilities, and enhancing community governance efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The status of returned overseas Chinese also sets an example for the development of future generations. Also present at the dinner was Aunt Wen&#39;s nephew. After dinner, he was about to leave for Hong Kong and then transfer to Indonesia. It turns out that his parents settled in Hong Kong very early. He went to elementary school and middle school in Hong Kong, completed college and graduate school in the United States, and currently works for a real estate company in Bali, Indonesia. It is not difficult to see that the transnational experiences of ancestors or elders have a profound impact on the education level and life experiences of future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Wen told me that there are a large number of third-generation transnational immigrants on the farm, who to some extent benefit from or benefit from the transnational contact network built by their ancestors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My thoughts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At about 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, we asked Aunt Wen to take us to visit some of the places where she had &quot;battled&quot;. She readily agreed, and we successively Went to teams five, six and nine. Along the way, we discovered that the former temporary farm management offices, tea factories, and garment factories had long been transformed, and many new enterprises involving new energy and high-tech fields had been built on the original sites. The simple truth is that Overseas Chinese Farm is a state-owned unit, and its management methods follow the planned economic system to a large extent. Many traditional industries have difficulty keeping up with the new development situation. Many companies have gone bankrupt. Instead, new projects have been launched and new companies have entered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing the place where they once worked, with only a few labels standing there alone, Aunt Wen showed an expression of regret and helplessness. Times are changing, and overseas Chinese farms are also undergoing transformation. This is an unstoppable objective law. In the future, overseas Chinese farms will continue to be deeply integrated into urbanization and modernization. In this process, I think relevant parties can try to carry out the following things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, university teachers, relevant researchers or student groups should be encouraged to carry out oral history research on returned overseas Chinese and their descendants, conduct interviews and surveys of people of all ages, and become a representative of Huadong Town and even Huadu. An important part of district local history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, through cooperation between the government and the private sector, establish an overseas Chinese rural museum or exhibition hall to promote overseas Chinese culture and overseas Chinese spirit, and make it a feature and highlight of Huadu tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, actively apply to build a provincial or municipal international community. Overseas Chinese Farm is a real and genuine international community. Relevant departments cannot or should not do so during the upgrading and follow-up planning process. Blindly &quot;de-farming&quot;, overseas Chinese farms, as a local characteristic, have long become an important component of local knowledge in Huadong Town or Huadu District. Relevant parties need to fully respect the place and respect the authenticity of the place, so that the above-mentioned places can be recognized in the new era. During this period, the international community construction process was reflected and bloomed, which undoubtedly greatly assisted place marketing and became an important social capital for attracting investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弄虚作假？二次污染？85亿元苏钢“毒地”疑云]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:53:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257847&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On March 18, 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. There was a red alert at the gate. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Plot snapped up for 8.5 billion&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;actually&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;contains&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;poison&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&quot;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;cannot be put into operation after development and construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Listed Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lujiazui)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Requirements&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Go to court&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On November 4, 2023, Lujiazui issued an announcement to Jiangsu Province due to soil pollution problems. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;the following&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Abbreviation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and a number of Suzhou government agencies and institutions initiated litigation and claimed 10.044 billion yuan from Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. At present, the Jiangsu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court has filed the case and has not yet opened a hearing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;before &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, Lujiazui sold it at a high price&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;former site&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;17 plots of land,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;with a total construction area of ​​over 1 million square meters&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui is in&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The announcement issued on September 29, 2023 stated that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;02&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;of which 2 Lot No.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;has been&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;built into a school&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;apply at&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;School License&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&#39;s&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; ;&quot;>;Process&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;One ​​after another, including the &amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp; plot Many plots of land are polluted&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>; Since&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;Multiple&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;announcements,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;express&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation revealed that a total of 14 pieces of land were polluted, and the area and degree of pollution far exceeded what was disclosed during the listing. 2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2022, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;related&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Songti&quot;>;Plot&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; was named by the central environmental protection inspector, and the local government commissioned a third-party investigation and found that the pollution exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui stated in the announcement that the &quot;regulatory changes and transfer process of this land&quot; In the case, each defendant committed a series of violations, committed fraud, and failed to perform their duties in accordance with the law. &quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; Release&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement 6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;天&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Later, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;On January 10, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group issued a situation statement, saying&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_ GB2312&quot;>;We are actively responding to the lawsuit and putting the health of the people and the legitimate rights and interests of home buyers first. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Indicates&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Yifang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;In 2019, we have&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;learned that Lot 2 does not meet environmental protection requirements&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>;but &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Songti&amp;quot;&quot;>; was not completed in accordance with the law Soil pollution investigation and remediation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;launched the project Land project construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;and&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;During the development and construction period&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Existence&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Secondary pollution caused by irregular construction operations&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Situation&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot; &quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter’s interview found that Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The plot is a typical industrial land redevelopment case, with soil investigation and evaluation, restoration and land transfer development and utilization spanning the &lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Seven&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;year&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, during which our country The laws, regulations, technical specifications and standards for soil pollution prevention and control have been continuously improved from a few to many. The different assessment results before and after may be due to repeated changes and tightening of soil pollution assessment standards, and the rich water system in the south of the Yangtze River, which makes pollution easy to migrate. In this kind of situation, who is responsible for pollution remediation is also a legal problem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Buy &quot;poisonous land&quot; at a high price? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In 2016, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will establish a wholly-owned subsidiary&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank Real Estate Development Co., Ltd.&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; (hereinafter referred to as &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;) 95% equity is listed for sale, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;’s core assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; are 17 pieces of state-owned land. The land is located to the north of Sutong Road and east of Sugang Road, Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone. It was originally the production plant of Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. After 222 rounds of fierce bidding competition, Lujiazui became the winner of the land with 8.525 billion yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee .png&quot; data-key=&quot;257848&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Suzhou Steel History. Suzhou Steel Group official website/picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The announcement disclosed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;information about Suzhou Iron and Steel Group’s listing in August 2016,&lt;/span>; &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The soil in the non-scorched area of ​​the plot under its name and groundwater are basically not polluted and can be redeveloped and utilized; the pollution in the coking area is mainly concentrated in the local area of ​​No. 4 plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>; stated in the announcement released on April 14, 2022, &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;Based on the public market equity listing information Trust, and reasonable reliance on the administrative actions of government departments&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot; &quot;>;Bidding&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;equity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Su Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Situation Description&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Disclosure&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; Song Dynasty&quot;>;,&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; Song Dynasty&quot;&quot;>;When transferring the equity in 2016, our company has truthfully disclosed the existence of land under the name of Suzhou Green Bank to a third-party professional agency The investigation results and full text of the report on partial pollution, and the asset assessment report clearly stated that some plots in this area were originally steel coking production areas and may have soil pollution risks.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;The &quot;Memorandum on Equity Transactions&quot; signed between Lujiazui and Suzhou Iron and Steel Group shows that the two parties agreed &quot;about the existence of soil pollution in some plots of land&quot; Regarding the matter, according to the relevant investigation and evaluation report filed with the Suzhou Municipal Environmental Protection Bureau, there are no technical obstacles to soil environmental treatment. After the treatment is completed, it will comply with national and local environmental quality standards and can be carried out in accordance with the requirements of existing planning documents. Development and construction. Suzhou Iron and Steel Group will provide environmental management matters for&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Green Bank Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;Provide coordination and support&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to the plan, Lujiazui will build the first million-square-meter city in Suzhou High-tech Zone here A regional complex project, the project was launched in May 2017, and the development cycle is planned to be 8 years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In addition to building commercial buildings and &quot;Splendid Lanshan&quot; residential buildings, Lujiazui also introduced Suzhou Reading School, a nine-year consistent international school jointly built by Suzhou Lunhua Education Group and Reading School in the UK, is located on Lot 2 of the project. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Unexpectedly&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot; >;The school was built, but it could not recruit students smoothly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, in 2021, Suzhou Reading School is applying for a school license During the certification process, according to the requirements of the Environmental Protection Bureau of Suzhou High-tech Zone, Lujiazui commissioned a third-party agency to investigate The soil pollution status of the land where the school is located was found to be seriously polluted and it could not be put into use through environmental impact assessment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default &quot;>;Mentioned in the fact sheet:&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2019&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;year,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Lujiazui Yi&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitated Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;fang&lt;/span>;&lt;span data- font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;know&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_ GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. does not meet environmental protection requirements and has not been completed in accordance with the law&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;The soil pollution investigation and restoration treatment of plot No. =&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; started the project construction of this plot. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; year, due to failure to pass the environmental impact assessment acceptance Failed to enable. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot; The Lujiazui announcement in Song Dynasty also showed that the Suzhou Municipal Assets and Planning Bureau restored plot No. 2 to industrial (research and development) land, and the Reading school project objectively failed to complete comprehensive acceptance. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot; >;In March 2023, technical consultants and volunteers from the public welfare organization &quot;Beijing Grassland Alliance&quot; went to Suzhou Reading International School for investigation. Several public interest organizations launched public interest litigation on this matter. Photos provided by interviewees&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; A year later, the &quot;poisonous site&quot; was named by the Central Environmental Protection Inspection Team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;In April 2022, Jiangsu Province announced the &quot;Second Central Ecological Environmental Protection Supervision &quot;Processing Status of the Sixth Batch of Letters and Calls Transferred to Our Province&quot; mentioned that the test results of the third-party testing agency showed that many plots of land in the Suzhou Green Bank Project&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The soil&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;benzo[a]pyrene&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; and naphthalene seriously exceeded the standards and did not meet the land use standards. At the request of the Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee, Lujiazui has suspended&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou Green Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Related development, construction, and sales work, and implemented strict management of the above-mentioned contaminated land. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Inspector&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; The report&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;shows that &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee attaches great importance to it and has established a special work class&lt; /span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The investigation report obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that in 2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;In August 2019, the People&#39;s Government of Xushuguan Town, Suzhou High-tech Zone entrusted the Nanjing Environmental Science Institute of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment to conduct detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot; According to the &quot;Song Dynasty&quot; investigation, 7 plots of land exceeded the standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;Suzhou Steel&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot; >;Group&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;The situation statement mentioned&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;these 7 plots&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312 In 2016, Lujiazui Party and Su Gang agreed to commission a third-party professional organization, the Nanjing Institute of Environmental Science and Technology, to conduct a detailed investigation of the pollution situation in the land. Coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;3&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;5&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font -family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;No. and non-coking area&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>; plot (of which only &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song _GB2312&quot;>;plot has been developed and constructed) and can be safely used after treatment and restoration. &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Already occupied by residents&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;14&lt;/span >;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No., developed and constructed&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;8&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font- family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot; >;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt; span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;13&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;16&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;Plot and undeveloped construction&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot; , serif&quot;>;11&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Imitation Song_GB2312&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;17&lt;/ span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;imitating Song Dynasty_GB2312&quot;>;Plot No. is a land that can be safely used. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>; Land planning diagram. Lujiazui Announcement/Picture (Editor’s note: Because the picture is tilted, the plot number and plot location are not completely aligned.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family= &quot;&amp;quot;宋体&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Based on Lujiazui&lt;/span>;&lt;span data -font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;Announcement&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;The number of contaminated plots is more than 7 pieces&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;20&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>; &quot;>;22年以来，陆家嘴及各方环境调查机构确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;名下&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;14&amp;nbsp;块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地存在污染。陆家嘴一纸诉状将苏钢集团及其委托检测的苏州市环境科学研究所、苏州市苏城环境科技有限责任公司以及相关方苏州国家高新技术产业开发区管理委员会、苏州市自然资源和规划局告上法庭&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;案件第三人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者致电案件原告方及第三人，多名工作人员表示有关案件事宜需询问陆家嘴集团董秘办，11月9日，董秘办回复，“集团统一口径，不接受采访”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;根据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;两份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;环评公示，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者尝试联系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州市环境科学研究所和环评&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;承担&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州科技大学的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;相关人员&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;均未取得联系或&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;拒绝采访。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;参考标准不同，检测结果不同&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染场地的开发利用，需要经过严格的环境监测、评估、修复等&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;流程&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，为何房子都造好了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;才&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;向&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;外界说有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;中央环保督察提到了两种超标污染物：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苯并[a]芘和萘。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;比对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;这两个污染物在2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014-2022年的多份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;报告中的数值可以发现，苏钢地块“毒地”的后知后觉，有可能是污染的确存在，而评估时依据的标准不同，导致&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;结果不同&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;将地块分为非焦化区和焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（污染较重），&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;委托第三方环境公司分别进行土壤调查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;环保组织&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;广州绿网环境保护服务中心&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;向苏州市生态环境局申请公开，获得了《江苏苏钢集团老区（除未关停区域）土壤初步调查报告》《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域场地污染初步调查报告》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域场地污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;详细&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;调查报告》和《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤和地下水人体健康评估报告&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;四份报告调查范围涵盖了&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;非焦化区和焦化区。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苯并[a]芘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;是一类致癌物，烧烤时也会产生，属于半挥发性有机物&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;介于挥发性有机物和半挥发性有机物之间。非焦化区在2014年1月进行了土壤调查，在35个采样点中，均未测苯并[a]芘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;大部分样点（34个）未检测萘。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;彼时，调查&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;依据的标准是《展览会用地土壤环境质量评价标准》（HJ350-2007）（下称“展览会用地标准”），是原环境保护部制定的行业标准，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;没有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确这两种污染物需强制检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而在后续的其他的报告中，如&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;022年4月中央环保督察组通报、陆家嘴发布的公告、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2022年8月苏州高新区委托生态环境部南京环境科学研究所的调查均显示，非焦化区部分点位也存在苯并[a]芘、萘超标。此时，参考的标准是2018年8月1日实施的国家标准《土壤环境质量&amp;nbsp;建设用地土壤污染风险管控标准（试行）》（GB36600-2018）（下称“建设用地标准”），此前不是必测的苯并[a]芘和萘已要求必测。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;“苯并[a]芘和萘在非焦化区的污染可能一直存在，只是因为之前没有检测所以未发现。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;绿网&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;工作人员&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊猜测。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而焦化区发现的部分&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染物，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;各&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;阶段报告中有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，但&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;可能由于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;新标准中限值加严，导致之前达标，之后超标。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘就是这样。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年、2015年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;调查结果显示，仅有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;污水处理区和粗苯车间&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;（也就是前文提到的4号地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;的部分区域&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;受到污染，其他区域萘未超标。此时参考的是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“展览会用地标准”的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;B级标准，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘的限值为530mg/kg。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而在后续的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;报告中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不只是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;4号地块，有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;多&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;等污染物&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;超标。后续&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;报告参考的萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;限值加严了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;分别&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;25mg/kg(&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;第一类用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;和&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;70mg/kg(&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;第二类用地)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，均远低于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;此前标准的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;530mg/kg。 “此前标准限制得过于宽泛，现有标准基于人体健康等因素&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;更科学&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;评价，比较严格。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;257851&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;苏钢“毒地”各报告、通报中关键污染物检测结果汇总。南方周末记者林方舟黄思琪&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;南方周末实习生习丽杰整理&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;检测中的“保守性原则”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;虽然2014年的土壤污染检测要求中没有强制检测名录，但业内有一项“保守&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;性&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;原则”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2014年2月，原环境保护部发布的《场地环境调查技术导则》（HJ25.1-2014）提到了“检测项目应根据保守性原则”：一般工业场地可选择的检测项目包括半挥发性有机物。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也就意味着苯并[a]芘这样的半挥发性有机物按照保守性原则，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建议&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测。但郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;指出&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，苏钢委托的第三方环境公司并未&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;采纳，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;非焦化区没有检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;介绍，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;半挥发性有机物是钢铁厂地块土壤中的常见污染物，它们在焦化、燃煤过程中的热解和不完全燃烧过程中释放，排放到大气中，又沉降到附近的地面，进而污染土壤，“不只非焦化区，甚至厂区外的土壤也可能会超标”。其他&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;钢铁厂&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也曾&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发生过类似情况&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“苏钢地块是典型的工业用地再开发的案例，它的土壤调查、土地转让和开发跨越了我们国家土壤污染防治领域的法律法规、技术规范和标准从无到有、从少到多的过程。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在2014年苏钢地块开展土壤调查的时段&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，我国土壤污染防治的相关法律法规、标准、技术规范&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也才&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;刚刚起步&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;直至2014年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;上述技术导则才诞生&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；直至2017年7月1日，污染地块土壤环境管理办法才施行；2019年1月1日，土壤污染防治法才施行。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在此之前，仅有原环保部等部门出台的几项部门通知，并不具备较高的法律效力。一位&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤修复行业人士向南方周末记者回忆，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年左右，行业非常混乱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;重庆市生态环境局、规划和自然资源局于2021年发布《关于进一步加强建设用地土壤污染分类分级管理工作的通知》曾表述&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“早期土壤污染状况调查的认识不到位，相关技术导则规范不健全，调查技术手段受限等原因，导致部分重污染行业建设用地地块调查结果失真，修复不到位……部分建设用地土壤污染调查、风险评估、风险管控及修复效果评估报告编制质量不高、专家评审把关不严，对从业企业、评审专家缺乏约束管理。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“且不论弄虚作假等，光上述因素就会造成土壤调查精度不高，导致调查结果跟实际情况间可能有较大差距。”郭磊称。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;二次污染？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;焦化区域的污染主要集中在4号地块，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴一方在交易时即知晓，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;也曾编制修复方案和治理。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;2018年9月，《苏钢地块老区焦化区域污染场地修复工程环境影响评价报告表及专项评价》公示，建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;单位为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州绿岸，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;内容&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;为土壤原&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;位和异位修复。公示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;原网页环评报告链接已经失效，但网传有一份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;97&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;页的同名称环评报告（以下简称环评报告）。南方周末记者联系环评承担方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州科技大学&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;技术&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;人员确认，未获得&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;回应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告提到了苏钢老区焦化场地，自2015年启动初步调查、详细调查、修复方案等历时三年多，每一环节均经过专家评审，符合当时的环保要求，但是土壤修复中萘的修复目标值不符合新标准要求，修改后符合&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;GB36600-2018）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;。评价适用标准中，修复后规划为商业用地，土壤参考也是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”第二类&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;，萘的标准为70mg/kg。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257852&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;红色为曾进行土壤修复的大概位置。黄色为2022年新发现的4块污染地块。绿网公众号截图。 &lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告显示，4号地块将进行土壤修复。但2022年后的多份检测报告显示，4号地块仍然有污染。有土壤修复业内人士向南方周末记者提醒，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;焦化厂污染是疑难杂症，非常难治理。在江南地区的水文地质条件下，还需要特别注意污染迁移”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;雷丁学校所在的2号地块也被多次报告污染，地图显示，2号地块和4号地块相连。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;苏钢的情况说明提到：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;方在开发建设苏州绿岸地块期间，没有按照有关要求建设地下水阻隔墙及采取其他防护措施，存在扰动地下水、搬运土壤造成部分环境交叉污染的行为和施工作业不规范造成二次污染的行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;对此&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，陆家嘴还未有回应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2022年7月&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;被苏州生态环境局处罚1.88万，原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违反土壤生态环境管理制度&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违法&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;事实对应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤污染防治法第四十二条第三款&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;风险管控、修复活动完成后，需要实施后期管理的，土壤污染责任人应当按照要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;023年1月10日发布&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;公告表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，苏州生态环境局作出该项处罚的原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸在之前依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏钢集&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;披露的污染区域对&amp;nbsp;4&amp;nbsp;号地块土壤修复后未按要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;汇业律师事务所合伙人、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;环境资源与能源专委会执行主任张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;向南方周末&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;记者&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，如果&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;施工作业导致污染扩散，应对生态环境损害的扩大部分承担责任。但不能&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;排除苏钢集团是否需要对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;号地块的污染负责，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;其中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;可能涉及多因一果的共同侵权，依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;民法典&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;第1231条的规定，在责任大小认定上需要结合污染范围、程度，以及行为对损害后果所起作用等因素确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;毒地修复责任归谁&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;根据已有材料，目前难以断定苏钢集团在交易时是否有所隐瞒、场地调查过程中是否存在不规范行为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;出让了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;标准更迭加严，应该由谁来承担土地污染修复责任？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀告诉南方周末记者，评价交易双方的土地污染修复责任，关键看土地交易交割时期的标准，尤其是强制性标准。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;如果交易前，场地调查已有明确的国家标准，出让方不存在未披露风险情形，在企业存续期间也做到了合法合规达标排放，即使倒查，也无法追究其历史上生态环境损害赔偿责任，交易后的土壤污染风险&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;应由继受人承担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;如果土地交易时&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;缺乏&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确的标准，双方也没有遵循保守性原则严格排查，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;那么&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;现有土地使用权人&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;就&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;具有土壤污染风险管控和修复的义务&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，在本案中，也就是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;这在一定程度上归因于受让方在交易前缺乏独立严谨的环境调&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为现有建设用地使用权人，具有对土壤污染的风险管控和评估义务，应承担土地污染修复责任。至于修复费用的追偿问题，有两种途径，一是行政途径，通过土地污染责任认定程序&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;二是通过民事诉讼途径，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;基于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;投资并购交易合同。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;介绍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;月，生态环境部会同自然资源部制定了《建设用地土壤污染责任人认定暂行办法》，规定建设用地使用权人可以向有管辖权的生态环境主管部门提出土壤污染责任人认定申请。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不过，张秀秀认为陆家嘴与苏钢集团的责任认定存在较大难题。主要原因是目前国内土壤污染责任人认定办法出台时间短、实践案例少，推行阻力较大。 “很多地方的主管部门对于受理申请、启动认定程序非常犹豫，因为可资借鉴的案例很少。如果不被受理，使用权人只能通过交易合同关系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;去&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;追究历史的污染责任人。但一般的合同关系里，如果双方对于土壤污染的约定不明确，受让了污染场地的一方就会比较吃亏。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者查询发现，陆家嘴目前的公开披露信息中，未明确提及是否启动土地污染责任认定程序。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀表示，该起环境污染责任纠纷案件的启示意义在于，土地交易中买受人应注重环境法律风险的排查。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;首先，买受人要深度了解土壤污染状况和历史用途，如果地块历史用途或周边涉及污染，应重点关注土壤污染的风险。其次，买受人应对地块的调查保持一定的独立性，对于既有的专业报告、评审结论保持警惕性，不可轻信结论，如有必要，可以聘请第三方开展更详细的土壤调查。最后，基于投资的通盘考虑，愿意承担一定环境法律风险的交易，应对土壤污染治理成本进行评估，就土壤污染状况、风险转移及可追溯的相关法律责任，在交易合同予以明确。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家金监总局三定方案： 健全金融消保者保护制度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 21:18:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家金融监督管理总局职能配置、内设机构和人员编制规定&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第一条&lt;/strong>; 为了规范国家金融监督管理总局的职能配置、内设机构和人员编制，推进机构、职能、权限、程序、责任法定化，根据党的二十届二中全会审议通过的《党和国家机构改革方案》、第十四届全国人民代表大会第一次会议审议批准的《国务院机构改革方案》和《中国共产党机构编制工作条例》以及党中央对金融工作的有关要求，制定本规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局是国务院直属机构，为正部级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第三条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局在中国银行保险监督管理委员会基础上组建，将中国人民银行对金融控股公司等金融集团的日常监管职责、有关金融消费者保护职责，中国证券监督管理委员会的投资者保护职责划入国家金融监督管理总局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定确定的主要职责、机构设置、人员编制等，是国家金融监督管理总局机构职责权限、人员配备和工作运行的基本依据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第五条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局负责贯彻落实党中央关于金融工作的方针政策和决策部署，把坚持和加强党中央对金融工作的集中统一领导落实到履行职责过程中。主要职责是：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）依法对除证券业之外的金融业实行统一监督管理，强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管，维护金融业合法、稳健运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）对金融业改革开放和监管有效性相关问题开展系统性研究，参与拟订金融业改革发展战略规划。拟订银行业、保险业、金融控股公司等有关法律法规草案，提出制定和修改建议。制定银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等有关监管制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）统筹金融消费者权益保护工作。制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划，建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度，研究金融消费者权益保护重大问题，开展金融消费者教育工作，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行准入管理，对其公司治理、风险管理、内部控制、资本充足状况、偿付能力、经营行为、信息披露等实施监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行现场检查与非现场监管，开展风险与合规评估，查处违法违规行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）统一编制银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的监管数据报表，按照国家有关规定予以发布，履行金融业综合统计相关工作职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）负责银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的科技监管，建立科技监管体系，制定科技监管政策，构建监管大数据平台，开展风险监测、分析、评价、预警，充分利用科技手段加强监管、防范风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行穿透式监管，制定股权监管制度，依法审查批准股东、实际控制人及股权变更，依法对股东、实际控制人以及一致行动人、最终受益人等开展调查，对违法违规行为采取相关措施或进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）建立除货币、支付、征信、反洗钱、外汇和证券期货等领域之外的金融稽查体系，建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制，依法对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证、处理，涉嫌犯罪的，移送司法机关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）建立银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的恢复和处置制度，会同相关部门研究提出有关金融机构恢复和处置意见建议并组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）牵头打击非法金融活动，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议，按要求组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）按照建立以中央金融管理部门地方派出机构为主的地方金融监管体制要求，指导和监督地方金融监管相关业务工作，指导协调地方政府履行相关金融风险处置属地责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）负责对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等与信息技术服务机构等中介机构的信息科技外包等合作行为进行监管，依法对违法违规行为开展调查，并对金融机构采取相关措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）参加金融业相关国际组织与国际监管规则制定，开展对外交流与国际合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）完成党中央、国务院交办的其他任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第六条&lt;/strong>; 职能转变。加强和完善现代金融监管，转变监管理念和监管方式，坚持既管合法又管非法，持续提升监管的前瞻性、精准性、有效性，强化中央和地方监管协同，消除监管空白和盲区，加强金融消费者权益保护，加大对违法违规行为的查处力度，牢牢守住不发生系统性金融风险的底线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强金融监管内部治理，强化对权力运行的有效制衡，规范政策制定、市场准入、稽查执法、行政处罚、风险处置等工作流程，强化对重点岗位和关键环节的监督制约，打造一支政治过硬、专业精湛、清正廉洁的监管铁军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第七条&lt;/strong>; 与其他部门的职责分工：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）打击非法金融活动职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立打击非法金融活动工作协调机制，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。2.国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会、国家外汇管理局依据各自职责对相关非法设立金融机构、从事特许金融活动等组织调查认定，采取相关措施或予以取缔。3.教育、养老、房地产、商贸服务等行业主管部门在职责范围内开展本行业本领域非法集资等非法金融活动的防范和配合处置工作。4.互联网信息内容管理部门、电信主管部门、市场监督管理部门等相关职能部门在职责范围内开展非法金融活动防范和配合处置工作。5.地方政府负责辖内非法集资等非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展风险排查、案件查处、善后处置和维护稳定等工作。6.对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，国家金融监督管理总局负责提出相关工作建议，按程序报批后组织实施，并及时采取应急措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）金融消费者权益保护工作职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局统筹负责金融消费者权益保护，牵头建立金融消费者保护工作协调机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。2.国家金融监督管理总局统筹制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划、建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度、开展金融消费者教育等工作，中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会予以支持配合。3.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立统一的金融消费者投诉举报流程和标准体系。国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会按分工落实或督促相关机构落实投诉举报处理主体责任，依法查处侵害金融消费者合法权益的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制。1.国家金融监督管理总局与公安部、最高人民检察院建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接工作机制，实现案件信息共享、协同办理。2.国家金融监督管理总局发现违法行为涉嫌犯罪的，按照有关规定移送公安部，同时抄送最高人民检察院。公安机关经调查发现依法需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由公安部向国家金融监督管理总局提出建议。3.检察机关决定不起诉的案件，需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由最高人民检察院向国家金融监督管理总局提出检察意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第八条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局根据本规定第五条所明确的主要职责，编制权责清单，逐项明确权责名称、权责类型、设定依据、履责方式、追责情形等。在此基础上，制定办事指南、运行流程图等，进一步优化行政程序，规范权力运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第九条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设下列正司局级内设机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）办公厅（党委办公室）。负责机关日常运转，承担信息、安全、保密、信访、政务公开、新闻宣传等工作。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委办公室日常工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）政策研究司。承担金融业相关改革开放政策研究与组织实施具体工作。对国内外经济金融形势、国际金融监管改革及发展趋势、监管方法和运行机制等开展系统性研究，提出相关监管政策建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）法规司。起草相关法律法规草案。拟订相关监管制度。承担合法性审查、法律咨询服务、行政复议、行政应诉等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）统计与风险监测司。拟订监管统计制度。承担监管报表编制、信息披露、数据共享以及行业风险监测分析预警等工作。统筹非现场监管工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）科技监管司。拟订相关信息科技发展规划和信息科技风险监管制度并组织实施。按分工承担网络安全、数据安全、关键信息基础设施监管等工作，推动数字化信息化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）公司治理监管司。拟订公司治理监管制度。开展股权管理和公司治理监管等工作，承担金融控股公司、保险集团等机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）普惠金融司。督促金融机构落实普惠金融政策要求，拟订监督管理的规章制度并组织实施，指导金融机构开展对小微企业、“三农”和特殊群体的金融服务工作，规范普惠金融秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）金融机构准入司。拟订银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的准入制度，研究结构布局，对机构及其业务范围实行准入管理，审查董事、高级管理人员等任职资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）大型银行监管司。承担政策性银行、开发性银行和国有控股大型商业银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）股份制和城市商业银行监管司。承担全国性股份制商业银行、城市商业银行、民营银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）农村中小银行监管司。承担农村中小银行机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）财产保险监管司（再保险监管司）。承担财产保险机构、再保险机构、保险中介机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）人身保险监管司。承担人身保险机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）资管机构监管司。承担信托公司、理财公司、保险资产管理公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）非银机构监管司。承担金融资产管理公司、企业集团财务公司、金融租赁公司、汽车金融公司、消费金融公司、货币经纪公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十六）银行机构检查局。拟订银行机构现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十七）保险和非银机构检查局。拟订保险业机构、金融控股公司及其他非银行机构的现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十八）机构恢复与处置司。拟订相关高风险机构风险处置制度、标准、程序，对出现严重风险、难以持续经营的机构开展风险处置等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十九）金融消费者权益保护局。拟订金融消费者权益保护发展规划和制度，开展金融消费者教育工作，承担相关金融产品合规性、适当性管理工作，组织调查处理侵害金融消费者合法权益案件，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十）打击非法金融活动局。建立非法金融活动监测预警体系和公开举报渠道，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展相关宣传教育、政策解释和业务指导等工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议。拟订小额贷款公司、融资性担保公司、典当行、融资租赁公司、商业保理公司、地方资产管理公司等地方金融组织监管制度，指导和监督地方金融监管部门相关业务工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十一）稽查局。拟订稽查工作制度。组织对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证，提出处理意见；涉嫌犯罪的，提出移送司法机关的建议。指导、检查金融机构安全保卫工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十二）行政处罚局。承担行政处罚案件审理等工作，提出审理意见，组织听证和集体讨论，送达行政处罚决定并执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十三）内审司（党委巡视工作领导小组办公室）。拟订系统内审和巡视工作制度、办法，监督检查系统贯彻落实有关重大决策部署情况，组织开展系统内审和巡视工作，对发现的问题及责任人提出处理建议，指导、监督、检查系统内审和巡察工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十四）国际合作司（港澳台办公室）。承担外事管理、国际合作和涉港澳台地区相关事务。承担外资银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十五）人事教育司（党委组织部）。承担机关、派出机构和直属单位等的干部人事、机构编制、劳动工资、教育培训和离退休干部管理工作。指导行业人才队伍建设工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十六）财务会计司。承担财务管理工作，负责编报系统年度财务预决算。依法强化对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等财会监督工作的督促指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十七）党建工作局（党委宣传部）。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委落实全面从严治党主体责任相关工作。承担系统党的建设工作，指导系统基层党组织建设、党员队伍建设、党风廉政建设和反腐败工作。负责系统党的宣传工作。领导系统统战、群团组织工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;机关党委。负责机关及在京直属单位党的建设和纪检工作，领导机关群团组织的工作。机关党委设立机关纪委，承担机关及在京直属单位纪检、党风廉政建设有关工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局机关行政编制910名。设局长1名，副局长4名；司局级领导职数114名（含首席风险官、首席检查官、首席律师、首席会计师各1名，机关党委专职副书记1名，机关纪委书记1名）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十一条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设立稽查总队，作为直属行政机构，正司级，负责相关案件的调查、取证，提出处理意见等。稽查总队的编制和领导职数另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局对派出机构实行垂直管理。国家金融监督管理总局地方派出机构、所属事业单位的设置、职责和编制事项另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十三条&lt;/strong>; 本规定由中央机构编制委员会办公室负责解释，其调整由中央机构编制委员会办公室按规定程序办理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据机构编制管理权限，由国家金融监督管理总局党委决定、报中央机构编制委员会办公室备案的机构编制事项，按照有关规定执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定自2023年10月29日起施行&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《漫长的季节》文学策划考编上岸：反思“铁饭碗”的人为何拥抱“铁饭碗”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一则“作家考编”的新闻引发关注。2023年武汉市文联所属事业单位芳草杂志社公布了专项招聘名单，青年作家班宇、陈春成、王苏辛、淡豹（刘雪婷）在列。此事再次引发网友“宇宙的尽头是考编”的感叹。公示名单显示，班宇、陈春成与王苏辛“成功上岸”，淡豹则不幸名落孙山。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这则新闻的话题热度虽逊于去年的“明星考编”事件，但也提出了一些值得深入探讨的议题。此次“作家考编”之所以引发热议，还是因为在人设与选择上出了问题，让外界产生了强烈的违和感，这一点值得特别加以辨析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班宇曾被称为“东北文艺复兴三杰”之一，著有小说集《冬泳》，也是悬疑剧《漫长的季节》的文学策划。这部以上世纪末东北下岗潮为背景的热播剧，一大主旨就是对“铁饭碗”的反思，尤其是展现了其对人的束缚与异化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;淡豹拥有社会学与人类学学习背景，她的文学作品关注性别、阶层议题，也专长于非虚构写作，长期以来以“关注现实”的面目示人，怎么看都与“编制”扯不上关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无怪乎有网友评论道，看到这则“作家考编”新闻，颇有一种“孙悟空考上天宫编制”“《冬泳》终于上岸”的感觉，其中淡豹还喜提了“申公豹”的网络绰号。原因无他，只因作家之前的作品与“人设”，与考编的行为出现较大反差，让读者产生违和感。对比淡豹曾在访谈中“一个人怎么写，他就怎么活着”的说法，“作家考编”的短短四个字已经让“怎么写”与“怎么活着”互相矛盾了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说作家本人完全隐身于作品之外，并不希望读者“像吃了鸡蛋还要认识老母鸡”一样了解自己，那么“作家考编”就不会引发多么大的争议，比如那些深居简出、极少抛头露面也不搞营销的作家。问题在于，如今的文化界已经高度市场化，青年作家对外出售的除了文学作品，还有各种线上线下的访谈、演讲、见面会、分享会构筑的“人设”，也将这种鲜明的“个人IP”作为一种文化商品出售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次考编的青年作家里，或多或少都在经营着市场化的人设，这种人设也帮助他们取得了作品的成功，甚至还有作品之外的成功，花钱买书的读者购买的就不止是作家的作品，也包括他们营销包装的“人设”，以及蕴藏其中的价值观与生活方式。读者期待他们实践人设，并对未能言行一致表示失望，这种失望也恰如其分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平心而论，没有任何一条法律法规禁止这几名青年作家考编，自由开放的现代社会当然也允许一个人实践他的价值观与生活方式，但他们这种“华丽转身”也未免有些“突如其来”，自然难逃外界乃至追随者的疑问：他们为什么要去考取编制？编制又能给这些已经取得不小成功的青年作家带来什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，武汉市文学艺术理论研究所（芳草杂志社）是武汉市文联所属二级事业单位，业务范围主要是各项文学学术研究、编辑出版发行《芳草》文学期刊。官网公示的招考条件显示，报考者除了年龄要在40周岁以下之外，还需要满足“三项条件其中一项”：作品获得省级期刊文学奖项，在中文核心期刊或是省级以上出版社发表过30万字以上作品，作品入围过几个特定的文学排行榜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次编制考试的招考条件可谓相当之高，三项条件恐怕就刷掉了绝大多数“普通做题家”。而从公示的成绩表与录取名单显示，此次“入编考试”分为专业能力评审、面试成绩两大类，最后依照综合成绩排名，并没有笔试环节，可见有别于普通的“考公考编”，称得上是为“青年作家”这个群体量身定做。试问，一家文学期刊为何拥有如此之高的招考要求，又为何可以吸引多名青年作家报考？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些青年作家本已在市场取得了成功，也没有逃避竞争去“吃皇粮”的迫切需要，在体制内期刊从事文学理论或是编辑工作多少有些大材小用的味道。因此比较合理的推断是，编制带来的好处不是明面上的“铁饭碗”，而是可以为这些市场化作家提供更好的社会地位，或者说某种身份标记，青年作家之所以要求得一官半职的傍身，大约是可以把两头的好处都占了，这自然符合“理性经济人”的决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“学院憎恨天才，犹如修道院憎恨圣徒”早就是业界的共识。文学作品本就应该交给市场判断、交给读者选择，而不是一定要作家博得某个“盖章认证”，或是有一官半职傍身，其作品才能通行于世。几名青年作家遭遇的群嘲，也说明了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师手机被扣：一天后法院院长送还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[受贿超9.795亿元，中信银行原行长孙德顺一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260353]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 18:26:42&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;5413&quot; height=&quot;3371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/b302121785ce1de591e109a5f01b5503.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257805&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月10日，山东省济南市中级人民法院公开宣判中信银行原行长孙德顺受贿一案，以受贿罪判处被告人孙德顺死刑，缓期二年执行，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产，在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释；对孙德顺受贿犯罪所得及其孳息依法予以追缴，上缴国库。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4634&quot; height=&quot;3338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/4688eae7a6d36e3589bc81e09b3c7274.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257806&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明：2003年至2019年，被告人孙德顺先后利用担任工商银行北京市分行副行长，交通银行北京市分行行长，中信银行副行长、行长等职务上的便利，为有关企业在获取贷款等事项上提供帮助，非法收受财物折合人民币9.795亿余元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市中级人民法院认为，被告人孙德顺的行为构成受贿罪。孙德顺受贿数额特别巨大，犯罪情节特别严重，社会影响特别恶劣，使国家和人民利益遭受特别重大损失，论罪应当判处死刑。鉴于孙德顺归案后如实供述罪行，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，受贿所得财物及其孳息已全部查扣到案，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其判处死刑，可不立即执行。同时，根据孙德顺犯罪的事实和情节，决定在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释。法庭遂作出上述判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[女性省级党委专职副书记增至6名丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年11月7日，河南省委副书记孙梅君在兰考县调研。（河南卫视截图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/62eee4c512.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;595&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/62eee4c512.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月7日，河南省委副书记孙梅君在兰考县调研。（河南卫视截图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月4日，河南日报客户端报道，中共中央批准孙梅君任河南省委副书记。此前，她曾任北京市委常委、组织部部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;孙梅君到任后，女性省级党委专职副书记又增加一名，达到6人，另5人分别是江苏省委副书记沈莹，安徽省委副书记程丽华，江西省委副书记吴忠琼，吉林省委副书记吴海英，四川省委副书记施小琳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;其中，吴忠琼兼任赣州市委书记，吴海英兼任吉林省委统战部部长、省政协党组副书记，施小琳兼任成都市委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;河南省委副书记已空缺&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;个月&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此番履新的孙梅君58岁，四川开江人，长期在中央机关工作。1986年起，先后在国家统计局、国务院研究室、国务院食品安全委员会办公室、国家食品药品监督管理总局、国家市场监督管理总局历练，曾任国家食药总局副局长，国家市场监管总局副局长。2020年12月，孙梅君赴任地方，历任北京市委常委、统战部部长、组织部部长等职，直至此番履新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;孙梅君到任前，河南省委副书记已空缺5个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年6月，时任河南省委副书记、省委政法委书记周霁升任中央港澳办分管日常工作的副主任、国务院港澳办分管日常工作的副主任（正部长级）。此后，河南省委专职副书记一职一直空缺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2004年9月召开的中共十六届四中全会要求，必须“减少地方党委副书记职数，实行常委分工负责，充分发挥集体领导作用”。2006年开始的全国各级党委集中换届中，全国大多数地方党委均建立起了“一正两副”的领导班子架构。2015年12月印发的《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》正式将“一正两副”作为地方党委领导构成模式。但该条例也明确，个别民族自治地方需要适当增加副书记职数的，由党中央决定或者省级党委根据中央精神审批。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此后的多数时间，除新疆、西藏两个自治区是“一正四副”的班子架构，其他省份均为“一正两副”。即一位党委书记、两位党委副书记。两位副书记中，一位同时担任省级政府行政首长，另一名则为专职副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》对省委副书记的职责有明确的界定:担任政府正职的党委副书记主持政府全面工作，组织政府党组活动；不担任政府职务的党委副书记主要协助书记抓党的建设工作，同时可以根据需要协调和负责其他方面工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;值得注意的是，《中国共产党地方委员会工作条例》第八条规定，常委会委员名额，省级为11至13人。孙梅君赴任后，河南省委常委已有11人，但省纪委书记自2023年9月起空缺，省委政法委书记自2023年6月起空缺。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;人曾在国家部委工作&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;宣布孙梅君任河南省委副书记的前一天，2023年11月3日，沈莹获任江苏省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;沈莹和孙梅君同岁，也生于1965年。6名女性专职省委副书记中，最年轻的是施小琳，生于1969年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;从任职经历看，6人中，有5人曾在中央部门工作，即孙梅君、沈莹、吴海英、程丽华、吴忠琼，都有部委工作经验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;沈莹是河南罗山人，本、硕均毕业于北京大学，先后在财政部直属的出版社、国家国有资产管理局、财政部统计评价司等部门工作，官至国务院国资委副主任。2018年12月“空降”黑龙江省，先后任副省长，省委常委、组织部长，直至此次转任江苏省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;吴海英是浙江义乌人，先后在中国科学院京区党委、中央国家机关工委、中央纪委机关党委、中央纪委国家监委驻生态环境部、中央纪委国家监委驻国家税务总局等部门工作。她曾任中央纪委机关党委常务副书记、中央纪委国家监委驻生态环境部纪检监察组组长、中央纪委国家监委驻国税总局纪检监察组组长等职，2022年5月，吴海英开始到地方工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;程丽华也曾在中央部委工作。她1984年进入青海省财政厅工作，2013年从青海省财政厅厅长任上升任青海省副省长，后来又跨省调任天津市委常委，2018年任财政部副部长，2021年4月调任安徽省委副书记，是二十届中央委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;吴忠琼曾在中国国际工程咨询公司、国防科学技术工业委员会、国家国防科技工业局工作过22年，在2010年组织的中央和地方干部交流中，赴辽宁省任科技厅厅长，此后任鞍山市市长、辽宁省发改委主任。2018年1月，吴忠琼跨省升任江西省副省长，此后历任江西省委常委、赣州市委书记，2022年11月，吴忠琼获任江西省委副书记后，继续兼任赣州市委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;施小琳有丰富的地方工作经验。她是浙江余姚人，长期在上海市工作，曾任上海市民政局局长、上海市普陀区委书记。2017年5月，施小琳升任上海市委常委，兼任统战部部长，当时她是上海市委常委班子中唯一的女性。2018年5月，施小琳首次跨省交流，任江西省委常委、宣传部部长。2021年8月，施小琳再次被跨省交流至四川，任四川省委常委、成都市委书记，2023年7月获任四川省委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;在省级常委班子中，还有两位担任行政首长的女性副书记，分别是内蒙古自治区党委副书记、自治区主席王莉霞，黑龙江省委副书记、省长梁惠玲。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;人事动向&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中央台办迎来一位新任副主任】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央台办、国务院台办官网“办领导”栏目更新信息显示，仇开明已经出任中共中央台湾工作办公室副主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;公开资料显示，仇开明生于1964年10月，法学博士，此前曾任海峡两岸关系研究中心主任、中央台办研究局局长等职务。目前，中央台办、国台办有1位主任、3位副主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中央金融办、中央金融工委多名领导亮相】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央金融工作会议召开后，多名中央金融委员会办公室（简称“中央金融办”）、中央金融工作委员会（简称“中央金融工委”）领导已陆续亮相。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国人民银行主管的《金融时报》11月6日刊发的报道显示，国务院副总理何立峰已任中央金融办主任、中央金融工委书记，王江任中央金融办分管日常工作的副主任、中央金融工委分管日常工作的副书记，夏先德任中央金融办副主任，秦斌任中央金融工委副书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;王江曾任中国光大集团股份公司党委书记等职。夏先德此前曾任财政部党组成员、副部长等职。秦斌此前曾任中央第七巡视组组长等职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【淮河水利委员会新“掌门”到任】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;日前，水利部淮河水利委员会召开干部大会，宣布水利部党组关于淮委主要负责同志任命的决定，杨锋任淮委党组书记、主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;公开资料显示，杨锋生于1971年1月，浙江杭州人。他曾任水利部淮委规划计划处副处长、处长等职，于2020年11月任淮委副主任、党组成员，至此番履新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;淮委是水利部直属事业单位，是淮河流域水资源综合规划、治理开发、统一调度和工程管理的专职机构，总部位于安徽省蚌埠市。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;反腐纪事&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中国工商银行原副行长落马】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中央纪委国家监委网站2023年11月4日通报，中国工商银行原副行长张红力涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;生于1965 年1月的张红力，在加拿大获遗传学硕士学位，在美国获工商管理硕士学位，在外资银行工作将近20年，先后任英国施罗德国际商人银行董事兼中国业务主管、德意志银行环球银行全球管理委员会委员、亚太区总裁等职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2010年，张红力出任中国工商银行副行长，成为当时内地从外资银行引进的最高级别高管，2018年“因家庭原因”辞任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中粮集团原副总经理被查，曾深耕地产领域】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月8日下午，中央纪委国家监委网站发布消息：中粮集团有限公司原党组成员、副总经理周政涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;周政生于1963年3月，早年曾在航空航天部第609研究所工作，后长期在中粮集团工作，先后任中粮南方包装有限公司总经理、中粮发展有限公司副总经理等职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2008年6月至2010年12月，周政任中粮地产(集团)股份有限公司总经理，2010年12月任中粮地产(集团)股份有限公司董事长，2012年1月任中粮集团有限公司副总裁，2013年2月任大悦城地产有限公司董事会主席、执行董事，2013年12月任中粮集团有限公司党组成员。2021年3月，周政辞去在大悦城的职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【湖南益阳纪委痛批7人“酒瘾难除”】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月9日，益阳市纪委监委网站发布消息称，益阳市纪委监委深入核查市司法局原党组成员、副局长罗俊伟酒后驾车问题线索，严肃查处了7名领导干部违规吃喝问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年2月26日至3月3日，益阳市委举办市管干部学习贯彻党的二十大精神集中轮训第四期研讨班。罗俊伟违规组织同期参训的大通湖区管委会常务副区长练世宏，南县人大常委会副主任孟祥胜，南县人大常委会副主任张红君，南县人大常委会副主任陈国奇，南县政协副主席王金辉和未参训的市人大农业委副主任委员谢建军，7人一同在益阳高新区某私营企业内部食堂聚餐，其行为系“吃心不改”“酒瘾难除”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;部委信息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【民政部：鼓励有条件地区因地制宜研制婚俗礼仪标准】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月1日至3日，民政部在浙江舟山召开全国婚俗改革暨婚姻登记“跨省通办”工作推进会。会议鼓励探索将婚姻登记与公益事业联系起来，积极举办有特色的集体婚礼、慈善婚礼、绿色婚礼等。鼓励有条件的地区因地制宜研制婚俗礼仪标准，加大倡导推广力度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【人社部：坚决防范化解规模性失业等重大风险】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;新华社11月6日消息，人力资源和社会保障部部长王晓萍接受采访时表示，人社部将全力加强就业监测预警。注重兜底保障，完善重点群体就业支持体系，着力促进青年特别是高校毕业生、农村劳动力特别是脱贫人口、就业困难人员等重点群体就业，切实兜住兜牢民生底线。坚决防范化解规模性失业等重大风险，确保就业形势总体稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【应急管理部：20个考核巡视组进入各省份】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;应急管理部网站11月7日消息，国务院2023年度省级政府安全生产和消防工作考核巡查正式启动。由国务院安委会有关成员单位部级领导带队的20个考核巡查组陆续进驻31个省级政府和新疆生产建设兵团，对2023年度安全生产和消防工作开展考核巡查。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;法治播报&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【最高检发布假释监督指导性案例，明确法律适用规则】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;最高人民检察院2023年11月6日消息，最高检以“假释监督”为主题发布第四十九批指导性案例，这也是最高检发布的第一批关于假释监督的指导性案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【《办理海上涉砂刑事案件证据指引》出台】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;最高人民检察院网站11月7日消息，近日，最高人民检察院办公厅、公安部办公厅、中国海警局执法部联合印发《办理海上涉砂刑事案件证据指引》。《指引》从犯罪主体、犯罪主观方面、犯罪客体、犯罪客观方面、量刑情节等五方面分别规定了这两类海上涉砂刑事案件需要重点收集的证据，为审查办理该类案件指明方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【公安部：假章假证犯罪呈现三大新特点】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月9日，公安部在北京召开“公安心向党护航新征程”主题新闻发布会，公安部刑事侦查局副局长陈士渠在发布会上通报，2023年以来，全国共立案侦办假章假证犯罪案件7700余起，抓获犯罪嫌疑人1.1万名，收缴各类假章假证1200余万枚（本）。此类犯罪呈现出犯罪链条产业化、制假种类多元化、销售渠道网络化的新情况新特点，全国公安机关将持续保持高压严打态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【最高法：未同意加装电梯业主补交出资后有权使用电梯】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月8日，最高法举行老旧小区既有住宅加装电梯典型案例新闻发布会。最高法有关负责人表示，未同意加装电梯业主补交出资后有权使用电梯，其他业主如认为阻碍电梯加装行为给其造成损失，可另案主张权利，但不能以此拒绝业主在补交集资款后使用电梯。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;地方政情&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【内蒙古：将积极申请设立中国（内蒙古）自由贸易试验区】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年11月9日，在国新办举行的新闻发布会上，内蒙古自治区党委常委、宣传部部长郑宏范表示，内蒙古将积极申请设立中国（内蒙古）自由贸易试验区，提升互市贸易区、综合保税区等平台功能，深化与蒙古国、俄罗斯在农牧业、能源矿产、基础设施、生态环保等领域合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【河北：雄安新区承诺优秀应届本科生入职5年内每月发1000元】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;11月7日上午，雄安新区在打造创新高地和创业热土聚集新人才政策措施新闻发布会上推出了各类人才引进及重大平台落地奖励等16条政策措施。高校优秀应届毕业生来雄安参加求职应聘考试免费入住“人才驿站”；入职后5年内，每月按博士生3000元、硕士生2000元、本科生1000元发放生活补贴，让人才在雄安安居乐业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【广东：广州拟对电动自行车实行累积记分制度】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;广州市公安局近日在官网发布公告，公开征求公众对《广州市电动自行车管理办法（征求意见稿）》的意见。针对电动自行车，《征求意见稿》提出公安机关交通管理部门可以参照机动车驾驶证记分管理模式，对电动自行车驾驶人违反道路交通安全法律、法规，除依法给予行政处罚外，实行累积记分制度。累积记分达到相应分值，驾驶人应当接受道路交通安全法律、法规教育。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;【中国人民银行行长潘功胜：5%的增长已经是一个不低的速度】&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国人民银行行长、国家外汇管理局局长潘功胜11月8日在2023金融街论坛年会上介绍，今年前三季度，我国GDP增速5.2%，全年5%的预期目标有望顺利实现，“5%的增长已经是一个不低的速度。我国经济需要合理的增速，但更重要的是实现高质量、可持续的发展。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; text-align: justify;&quot;>;（综合新华社、央视新闻、澎湃新闻、《广州日报》《福州日报》等报道）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贩卖假出生医学证明：“洗白”被拐儿童是黑产重要一环丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，打拐志愿者上官正义举报湖北襄阳健桥医院院长贩卖出生证明，引起极大关注。对此，襄阳市卫健委通报称，涉事医院妇产科已停业整顿，医院院长已被采取刑事强制措施并接受调查。根据最新消息，襄阳市公安局已对此案提级侦办，并已初步查实5起买卖出生证明的犯罪事实，对贩卖婴儿等其他指控正在进一步深挖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出生医学证明，是医疗机构为新生儿所出具的证明，包括新生儿的姓名、性别、出生日期，以及父母亲的信息等等。这张被称为“人生第一证”的出生证明，在以后的落户过程中，能起到证明亲子关系的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，假的出生医学证明成为整个贩卖儿童的产业链中非常重要的一环。以收买人的信息作为父母，造一份假的出生医学证明，被拐卖的儿童就可以堂而皇之地以收买人亲生子女的身份到派出所上户口，“洗白”了。上官正义作为长期打拐的志愿者，就多次在打拐行动中遇到过对方拿出“出生医学证明”，证明孩子是自家亲生的。也正是因此，他才开始关注并举报出生医学证明造假的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上官正义上一次引起广泛关注的，是举报河南商丘妇幼保健院近5000份被盗的出生医学证明被用于贩卖儿童。2016年，他在打拐调查中发现，福建有人购买孩子后凭非法获得的出生证明上户，一部分出生医学证明出自商丘妇幼保健院。商丘妇幼保健院方面则表示早在2011年就发现大批出生医学证明被盗，当时已经报警并登报声明作废，2012年又发现有一批出生证明被盗，两次共计4885份。商丘警方加大侦破力度，最终查明是内部人员监守自盗，商丘妇幼保健院负责管理出生医学证明的时任科长、副科长等人都被抓获，并被判刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出生医学证明被盗后用于非法活动的，并不只有商丘妇幼保健院一处。这一案件只是因为被盗数量特别巨大而更引人关注。值得注意的是，这些被盗的出生医学证明，都曾经登报声明作废。所以，严格来说，以这些被盗的证明制作出来的证明，都是无效的，是假证。但是由于医疗系统的数据库并没有与公安部门对接，派出所在为新生儿上户口时，也很难去查证出生医学证明的真伪（事实上，出生医学证明并没有采用什么高端的防伪技术）。加之有些派出所并不会进行严格的检查，以致有些完全伪造的出生证明都可以拿来上户口，更不用说这些用被盗的“真证明”假造的“假证明”了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而襄阳健桥医院贩卖出生医学证明案，则更进了一步。他们伪造的假证，不仅仅只是给一份假造的证件，而是在卫生部门的系统里假造一份完整的记录。从怀孕后到医院建档开始，一直到后面的产检、分娩，全部在卫生系统里有记录，出生医学证明、疫苗接种证也都是在系统里可查的。也就是说，如果只看表面文件，那这是真得不能再真的“真证明”。这样的证明，即使派出所拿到卫生系统查询真伪，也只能得出是真证明的结论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，襄阳健桥医院及其院长叶有芝，无疑是贩卖儿童的帮凶，犯下了严重的罪行。目前，其非法贩卖出生医学证明的部分事实已经被查实，这已经触犯了买卖国家机关公文、证件罪。不过这只是一项轻罪。更重的罪名是，如果叶有芝明知婴儿是被拐卖的，还为其出具假的出生医学证明，那就可能被认定为拐卖儿童的共犯。而拐卖儿童罪，最低刑罚是5年有期徒刑，严重的可判处死刑。而叶有芝曾经自称“犯的是死罪”，可见很大可能她知道开出的那些假出生证明，是用在了被拐卖的儿童身上。她到底卖了多少假出生证明，其中又有多少被拐卖的儿童借以“洗白”，有待警方进一步查明，并顺藤摸瓜，挖出更多的犯罪分子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伪造出生医学证明的，不只有襄阳健桥医院和叶有芝。早在2019年，央视就曾经报道过四川射洪一家民营医院伪造出生医学证明的案件，其手法与健桥医院如出一辙。这次上官正义举报的，也还有广西南宁等地的医院。还有更多贩卖假出生证明的中介，活跃在网络上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一为虎作伥黑色产业链，必须严厉打击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[襄阳健桥医院“贩卖出生证明”事件：7人已被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260305]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;湖北省襄阳市一家医院近日被举报“勾结多地中介团伙贩卖出生医学证明”，引发社会关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出生医学证明是《中华人民共和国母婴保健法》规定的法定医学证明文书，是户口登记机关进行出生登记的重要依据。国家卫生主管部门多次强调要加强对出生医学证明的管理。严格规定下，出生证明在这里缘何“失守”？“新华视点”记者进行了调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;涉事医院妇产科已停业整顿&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月7日，记者来到涉事医院——位于湖北省襄阳市襄城区的襄阳健桥医院。走进大厅，记者看到医院在正常运转，显眼位置挂着一面面锦旗。查看楼层指示牌，除了医院各科室外，大楼内还有一家月子中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/c1c67129f5796f6a5ad65ea78a6a2f03.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/c1c67129f5796f6a5ad65ea78a6a2f03.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257765&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;图为11月7日拍摄的襄阳健桥医院一楼大厅。新华社记者侯文坤摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月6日，打拐志愿者上官正义（网名）在社交平台发布消息称，他经过一年多的暗访发现，襄阳健桥医院院长叶某某勾结多地中介团伙，利用社交平台公开发布办理出生证信息，物色客户，贩卖出生医学证明、疫苗接种本。据上官正义了解，这些贩卖出去的出生医学证明“真实可查”，有的是给被拐卖的孩子，有的是给代孕的孩子，有的是给弃婴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者采访了解到，涉事的襄阳健桥医院前身为襄阳102医院，2011年该院改制成为一家民营医院，2017年更为现名。2020年，襄阳健桥医院（东区）正式启用。医院大门口的简介显示，襄阳健桥医院（东区）是襄阳市一家以母婴护理为特色的医养结合医院，提供孕期检查、产前诊断、营养指导、心理咨询、分娩、坐月子、宝宝护理、早教等一体化服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者8日从襄阳市卫生健康委员会获悉，目前襄阳健桥医院妇产科已停业整顿，该院出生医学证明签发权限已被停掉。同时，已安排专业团队对涉事医院相关孕产妇会诊照料，全力保障在院孕产妇健康安全。截至目前，记者在网上搜索涉事医院发现，已无法找到其官网链接。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;7名嫌疑人已被采取刑事强制措施&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;襄阳市卫生健康委员会一名工作人员告诉记者，襄阳健桥医院的确拥有出生医学证明签发资质。对出生医学证明的发放情况，相关部门会定期检查。但产妇生产住院涉及医院内部多个部门，平时的监管往往针对某一具体环节，没有想到医院会伪造生产住院记录等材料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/8755ed5ba6f8db390e73093ebb8752eb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/8755ed5ba6f8db390e73093ebb8752eb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;图为11月7日拍摄的襄阳健桥医院内部环境。新华社记者侯文坤摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者在襄阳市卫生健康委员会采访了解到，襄阳健桥医院一直以来医患纠纷不断，卫健部门对其处罚的频次也比较高，但主要集中在医疗服务和医疗安全方面，并未涉及出生医学证明签发问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;襄阳市公安局襄城区分局有关负责人8日向记者介绍，从11月6日晚上开始，公安部门就已介入开展工作，已阶段性完成相关资料查控、人员控制等工作，目前重点是围绕举报线索逐条开展调查取证核实工作，现正紧锣密鼓进行。为提高侦查效率，市区两级公安机关成立了多警种的专案组，全力推进相关工作。包括涉事医院院长和相关工作人员在内的7名嫌疑人已被采取刑事强制措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;填补漏洞扎牢出生证明发放登记“关口”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2009年，卫生部门就下发通知，要求进一步加强出生医学证明的规范化管理，签发机构必须落实由专人分别管理出生医学证明和印章的要求，严格签发流程。2020年12月，国家卫生健康部门召开全国出生医学证明管理工作会议，强调要严格签发管理，保障制度落实。相关部门三令五申，要求加强教育培训，时刻警钟长鸣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“贩卖新生儿出生医学证明可以给被拐人口洗白身份。”一位长期从事“打拐”工作的基层民警告诉记者，在侦办拐卖人口案件时，DNA对比结果、出生医学证明和户口信息构成基本的证据链条，如果被拐人口办理了合法的出生医学证明，就能进而合法办理户口；仅凭DNA对比结果很难形成充足证据，会给案件侦办带来严重挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湖北瀛楚律师事务所合伙人潘宇指出，出生医学证明是用来证明婴儿身份的法定医学证明，是由国家相关部门统一印制、医院签发的国家机关证件。涉事医院院长的行为涉嫌伪造、买卖国家机关证件罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，有受访者表示，必须填补漏洞，健全相关管理制度，尽快扎牢出生医学证明的发放和登记“关口”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;襄阳市公安局襄城区分局的办案民警表示，目前专案组正以举报线索为切入点，加快侦查，过程中如果发现新的线索、新的犯罪，绝不会放过，一定彻查，绝不姑息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[进博会偶遇中国驻伊朗大使常华：寻找共建“一带一路”的新方式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月7日是第六届进博会正式开展的第二天，南方周末记者在一家伊朗品牌的展台内偶遇常华，他正在赏闻一瓶“大马士革玫瑰”精油。常华目前担任中国驻伊朗伊斯兰共和国特命全权大使。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今年在进博会卖得如何？”“原材料都是来自伊朗吗？”“是第几次来进博会？”……常华身边只有一位随行人员，他不时向展台负责人询问参展情况，周围多数人都未意识到他的身份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常华向南方周末记者分享了本次参与进博会的感想，“近十多年来，中国一直是伊朗的第一大贸易伙伴，当前尽管遇到一些困难，原因主要是美国制裁，不是中伊双边的问题。但是我们仍能看到中国和伊朗商人正在克服种种困难，积极发展经贸合作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，中伊签署25年全面合作计划。据媒体报道，协议约定在25年之内，伊朗将稳定向中国提供石油，以换取诸如5G通信、基建、能源设施等领域的中国投资，预计总额约为4000亿美元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外交部信息显示，截至2022年，中国继续保持伊朗第一大贸易伙伴、最大出口目的国和第二大进口来源地的地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第六届进博会的“一带一路”特色愈发明显。据中国国际进口博览局副局长孙成海介绍，今年共有72个国家和国际组织参与国家展，其中就有64个“一带一路”共建国家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“伊朗历史上就是&#39;一带一路&#39;的重要国家，在我国提出&#39;一带一路&#39;后，伊朗也一直积极表态支持这一政策。” 常华对南方周末记者说，“希望企业家们发挥主观能动性，面对美国的封锁障碍，能够突破或者打开一个新的局面，寻找（两国间）新的合作亮点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国商人重走“丝绸之路”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;张桂才事先并不知晓常华大使会莅临，“（大使）是看到昨天电视台对我们的报道，才知道有我们这么一家企业”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在伊朗展的一角，一个只有20平方米不到的展台却有不少人驻足，其中大部分是女性，这里是张桂才创办的伊朗植物精油品牌“巴莉哲（Barij）”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴莉哲是一家中国企业，但生产合作方和原料进口商均来自伊朗，“生产和提炼由伊朗方面完成，中国负责分装和品牌。”张桂才告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，中伊宣布建立全面战略合作伙伴关系，伊朗加入共建“一带一路”倡议，这一年张桂开始了创业之路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张桂才毕业于清华大学，“我最早做的是矿山设备，后来才转入芳香植物领域。”他谈到，伊朗的自然资源极其丰富，除了广为人知的矿产、原油、天然气等，农副产品也相当出名，“国人熟悉的藏红花，全世界有90%以上产自伊朗，还有在波斯帝国时期闻名遐迩的&#39;大马士革玫瑰&#39;，伊朗国花，主要产自伊朗”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张桂才最初进入香氛香料领域时，主要产品是藏红花，而后扩展到植物精油、纯露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们参加进博会第一年（2019年），才带了100瓶样品，半天不到就被抢空了，今年做了充足准备，但还是有些不够。”另一位品牌负责人指着墙边的一排新品说，这些都是加班加点让工厂赶制出来的样品。巴莉哲今年纯露类产品的销售量已经突破1000万瓶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果没有进博会这样的平台，国人根本就不可能了解伊朗的优势特产，更不会知道我们这样一个小众品牌。”张桂才说，2023年，巴莉哲被伊朗驻上海领事馆选作国庆招待会的特产伴手礼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴莉哲目前最大的供应商是一家名为Dorrin Golab的伊朗工厂，工厂负责从种植、采摘、提炼到制作的整个流程，因为中国市场的购买力，工厂从此前的60余人扩展到今年近200人的规模。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dorrin Golab是一家成立于1998年的药用植物生产企业，隶属于伊朗商业、工业、矿业和农业商会(ICCIMA)下的药用植物和食品出口商联盟。一个细节是，上述联盟官网除了波斯语和英语，也有中文页面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ICCIMA是伊朗规模最大的民间商业联盟组织，该网站9月27日的一则消息显示，该商会主席侯赛因·塞拉瓦兹当日同常华会面，表示已经成立了一个发展与中国贸易关系的特别工作组，通过两国商会平台进一步激活私营部门的贸易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年8月，在“伊朗－金砖国家：伙伴关系与合作前景”研讨会上，驻伊朗大使常华发言。图片来源：外交部网站&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e696052863.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/e696052863.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月，在“伊朗－金砖国家：伙伴关系与合作前景”研讨会上，驻伊朗大使常华发言。图片来源：外交部网站&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;全球出口贸易的重要窗口&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据伊朗《德黑兰时报》11月5日报道，由伊朗第一副总统穆罕默德·穆赫贝尔带队，50多家伊朗公司和250多名伊朗商人参加了这次进博会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;伊朗副外长萨法里对伊朗媒体表示，“我们的主要出口目标国家之一是中国……拥有14亿人口的中国可以为伊朗提供重要的出口空间。这次访问很重要，表明政府特别重视出口。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很多问题慢慢地在解决，比如签证、外汇交易等等，在&#39;一带一路&#39;体系下，中国和伊朗的贸易肯定是越来越便捷的。”张桂才指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，比如以往清关花费几周的时间不足为奇，如今进口的伊朗货物在国内完成清关，只要一个星期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据联合国国际贸易中心（ITC）在本次进博会上发布的《一带一路沿线发展中国家对华出口潜力报告》，在2013年“一带一路”之前，沿线发展中国家对华出口总额约为4450亿美元，2023年已经达到了7980亿美元，增长约79%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该中心亚太事务总监希尔维·贝唐·柯欣在进博会的一场分论坛中指出，同一时期，“一带一路”发展中国家对全球其他地区的贸易增长只有12%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柯欣在会后对南方周末记者谈到，“一带一路”国家过去十年对中国的出口增长主要集中在第一工业，也就是化工、矿石等原料领域，“我们也期待未来能在制造业有进一步增长，从初级产品变为一些高附加值的加工产品，这更能帮助这些国家的经济发展”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常华也在思考，在美国对伊朗经济制裁的大背景下，中伊贸易如何进一步发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“首先美国的制裁是无理的，我国政府坚决反对，但我们也要保护好本国企业的利益，考虑到被（连带）制裁的风险，伊朗方面的资金和产业链等还比较脆弱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他观察，今年陆续有一些中国商团参加伊朗展会，地方商务厅或地方贸易促进会都组织了相当规模的参访团，伊朗市场对中国企业越来越有吸引力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年6月，就有一个来自吉林省的45人贸易代表团访问了德黑兰，参加6月18日举行的“伊朗—中国贸易论坛”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在8月举行的金砖国家领导人第十五次会晤中，伊朗等六个国家正式成为金砖大家庭成员，成员身份将于2024年1月1日生效。这是继加入上海合作组织之后，伊朗再次加入重要的多边机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胸中剩有丘陵在，好听昭时鸣玉珂：怀念刘操南先生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260206]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/dByCLHe1G44YYJZ7YDW3EecCWQxtmxYOlNILYcho.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;497&quot; height=&quot;693&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/dByCLHe1G44YYJZ7YDW3EecCWQxtmxYOlNILYcho.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;杭州大学古籍所教授刘操南（1917-1998）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们78级的中国文学史大课，刘操南先生在先秦两汉这一段讲过几次课。他开口即是吟唱，又让大家跟着唱，场面十分热闹。他还要求大家在课后用这种方式背诵下来。这是我第一次接触吟唱，甚觉新鲜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印象最深的有三篇。一是《诗经·豳风·东山》：“我徂东山，慆慆不归。&lt;span>;我&lt;/span>;来自东，零雨其濛。&lt;span>;我&lt;/span>;东曰归，&lt;span>;我&lt;/span>;心西悲。”那时我读《诗经》，最喜欢的是爱情诗，这篇却是写出征归来的情景，十分悲凉。二是《离骚》，“荃不察余之中情兮”，满是郁闷牢骚。三是曹植的《洛神赋》，还记得刘先生吟诵“黄初三年，余朝京师，还济洛川……”的样子。他吟诵的篇章，都寓有他的人生经历和情感共鸣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘先生是江苏无锡人。吟诵原是他读私塾时的“蒙课”，他视我们如赤子，殷勤地献出珍藏。晚年更是热情倡导和推广古典诗词吟诵艺术，曾录制发行《宋词吟咏》，至今在喜马拉雅网上仍可听到。所以不同届的同学，只要回忆刘先生的课堂或讲座，首先提到的都是吟唱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诗词吟诵，如今都上了央视，十分时髦，但那时我们既觉得新鲜，又不无疑问：课堂里就该传授新知识，花这么珍贵的时间来教吟诵，有这个必要吗？但刘先生完全没有理会台下疑问的目光，沉浸在自己的世界里。他讲解《离骚》，讲着讲着就吟诵起来，吟到情深处，无语凝噎，眼中满是泪光。另外，上课上到开心处，他会在黑板上写下自己的旧体诗，再得意地吟唱——全然不想这是古代文学的课堂——对此，有些同学颇有微词。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时中文系年过古稀的老先生，已经不再给本科生上课。还在第一线上基础课的，是年过六旬而又未到古稀的老先生，因为这吟唱的缘故，刘先生成为学生印象最深的一位。只是在学生当中，既有感佩的，也有当笑话的。——大家对他，远不如对别的老先生那样尊敬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我那时年轻无知，既不懂吟诵对涵咏诗歌、体悟韵味的意义，也不能懂得他的学问。本科毕业前报考研究生，元明清文学专业的导师有刘操南、徐朔方两位先生，分别招小说和戏曲两个方向，尽管我之前对小说下过很多功夫，但最后仍然选了全无根底的戏曲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我再次聆听刘先生的课，已经是读研究生的时候。五位导师各讲三次课，构成一个学期的研究生课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘先生在课堂上提到了《史记》的《历书》《天官书》和《汉书》的《律历志》《天文志》以及《九章算术》。他说校勘天文历法算学，“我们”与前人做法不同，不是据版本来做校勘，而是用现代数学方法来做计算，然后再作校正（那时不能多说“我”，得说“我们”，以避免个人主义的嫌疑）。我闻之肃然起敬。因为这是真正的“绝学”，得有深厚的现代数学功底才行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来听说，他曾在本校教师数学竞赛（非数学专业组）中得过一等奖。现在浙江大学出版社正在编辑出版《刘操南全集》，编为22册，六百余万字。其中有关历算的著作，有《古籍与科学》《历算求索》《古算广义》《天算论丛》《古代历算资料诠释》等，另有《古代天文历法释证》（2009）单行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ny7mraO7Y5GFFm1gNHSi8vPSCMafhQDxWcHj0nBw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ny7mraO7Y5GFFm1gNHSi8vPSCMafhQDxWcHj0nBw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘操南先生著作两种。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他研究历算的单篇论文，大多是在老浙大任教时期（1942-1952）发表或流播的，如《〈海岛算经〉新解》《〈九章算术〉注祖冲之开立圆术校补》《〈周髀算经〉勾股方圆图注读记》《〈周礼〉九数解》等，影响颇大。但在我们读研究生的时候，上述著作并未出版。因为这类著作在中文系属于另类，在历史系也无人能做，甚至找不到刊物发表，可谓“走投无路”。所以刘先生高手寂寞，无人会、登临意，只好在课堂上过过瘾。他经常说这个事我写了文章，那个题我已经解决，但给听者的印象，似乎是在自卖自夸，因为他说的这些，真的是“天书”，我们完全不懂，无从印证，更无人回应于他。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他当时有资格在多个方向招研究生：先秦两汉文学、古代科技史、元明清文学小说方向。但先秦两汉的学生不好招，科技史根本不可能有人到中文系来读，所以他便定了小说方向，第一届招的是李梦生，我们这届招了陈飞。在学三年，在刘先生指导下，陈飞同学发表了明清小说研究的系列论文，在学界初露头角。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在课堂上，刘先生也讲小说研究，但讲着讲着，他就开始聊他独有的想法与做法：改写古典小说名著为通俗读物。那时他已经与茅赛云合作出版过一本《武松演义》，25万字，是以《水浒传》著名的“武十回”为基础，结合杭州评话改编创作而成。这书1959年由东海文艺出版社出版，初印6万册；1980年浙江人民出版社出修订版，初印15万册；1983年浙江文艺出版社再版，初印30万册。难怪刘先生认为这是一条新路，要按这个路子，一个个地来做，写成一个系列，既是弘扬经典，又能去其糟粕。在他看来，文学创作是文学研究的前提，不懂创作就做不好研究。他叹息自己年事已高，在课堂上鼓励大家都来参加，话语里充满了期待，可是我们却无人响应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/maxWYg8ePtn6BMpfBKdxeP0xXPCpgAH4PFnbehcw.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/maxWYg8ePtn6BMpfBKdxeP0xXPCpgAH4PFnbehcw.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;不同版本的《武松演义》。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我心中其实并不以为然，认为改写古代的白话小说没有“学术含量”。与我同样想法的人肯定不少，好像陈飞同学也没有跟着做。所以刘先生依然只能踽踽独行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我看《刘操南全集》的分册目录，《武松演义》《水泊梁山》《青面兽杨志》《诸葛亮出山》四种已经出版，都是据经典小说重写而成，其实他还有相当数量的草创之作，没有收录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新世纪后，我到日本访学，发现他们对古典名著做了系统性地改写，这才真正明白刘先生所倡导的工作的价值与意义。可惜早在上世纪末他已经离世，没法向他致歉了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘先生不仅研究古代，也留意现当代的曲艺。这种“往下走”的做法，在当下被认为是“新视野”，视作未来学术的“增长点”，但那时的“大学学术”里存在一条“鄙视链”，民间文学和说唱文学处于最底端。不过刘先生既做天文历法，又做“经学”，也做俗文学，所以对此无所察觉。他与说书艺人一直保持着密切的关系，我们读研究生时，他就请了著名评话艺人唐耿良先生来做讲座——意外发现，我也在合影之中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/n4Yl1LKt0ys3vdGzu7zzQkkVT1kK8VVfReOttdSv.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;472&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/n4Yl1LKt0ys3vdGzu7zzQkkVT1kK8VVfReOttdSv.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;前排左二起：刘操南、唐耿良、平慧善；后排左起：李剑亮、朱宏达、黄仕忠、陈飞。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘先生对《红楼梦》的研究也别有心得。他发掘了陈其泰桐花凤阁评本《红楼梦》的价值，撰写系列论文作了介绍，整理完成了《桐花凤阁评〈红楼梦〉辑录》（1981）。又广泛收罗弹词文献，辑成《红楼梦弹词开篇集》，只是在他去世后才出版（2003），其中不少是孤本。但这些工作，未能进入《红楼梦》研究的主流。他毕生对小说、戏曲、曲艺都有涉猎，可成一家，但又不够突出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/np6fLPOwejqvrR74YxGTVeGjh556GOhL2D1UbgcJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/np6fLPOwejqvrR74YxGTVeGjh556GOhL2D1UbgcJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;此两书汇集了刘先生的小说戏曲研究，但2021年才出版。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘先生用力最多的是先秦两汉文史。观《全集》所列，第一卷“《诗经》探索”，第二卷“楚辞考释”“诗词论丛”，第三卷“《史记》春秋十二诸侯史事辑证”，第四卷“《公孙龙子》笺”和“陈汉章遗著整理与研究”以及第五卷“文史论丛”。这些著作，卓然可成其一家之言。但在他生前大多未曾出版，到现在也只出了其中三卷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，刘先生从小喜爱诗词古文，吟咏不辍，至死方已。他自述一生所作诗词不下万首，但《揖曹轩诗词》（西泠印社，2002），所存不过千首。《揖曹轩文存》则尚未出版。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的精力是如此旺盛，研究的领域是如此广博，着实令我惊叹。浙大出版社因出《全集》而介绍其生平，称“治学会通中西文理，综贯经史百家，兼擅诗词文章，著述丰赡，成就卓异，蜚声海内外”，这些话并无夸大。可是事实上，即使像我这样的本系毕业生，对刘先生也缺乏应有的敬意。在我们这一届研究生入学不久，刘先生就转任古籍所，之后是集体招收研究生。前几届学生都听过刘先生的课，只有傅杰一人因做《诗经》，选了刘操南为第二导师（第一导师都是姜亮夫先生），毕业时留校做姜先生助手，傅杰说，他实际受郭在贻老师的影响更多一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mawpbCB7XRZsV5UvSBTLkbmEeNurqKZeah5mldvG.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mawpbCB7XRZsV5UvSBTLkbmEeNurqKZeah5mldvG.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1986年杭州大学古籍所师生合影，刘先生在前排右二。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1987年，学校未作知会，直接给他办理了退休手续，刘先生从此离开了自己深情热爱的教学岗位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那年他七十岁，身体健康。这个年龄的文科资深学者，那时大都仍在教学与科研第一线，而他，大约是因未获博导资格，就只能退休了。看来，名家辈出的杭州大学，并没有认识到他的价值。陈飞在毕业时放弃了留校机会，傅杰留校不久就去了复旦，所以刘先生没有在杭大留下学脉。就在杭州大学被合并到浙江大学的前夕，刘先生因病离开了人世，享年82岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回想起来，他在课堂上，喜欢穿玄色的对襟唐装，或是藏青色中山装，风纪扣紧扣，他肤色本黑，一副黑框眼镜架在硕大的鼻子上，眼神里总带有一丝忧郁。他吟唱《离骚》，痛惜屈子不被理解，何尝不是切身之感。在生命的最后时刻，他写下了《病中戊寅岁朝试笔两律》，其二云：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;八十韶华石火过，深惭书剑两蹉跎。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;祠堂往事抛书忆，黉舍新情剪烛多。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;谁说天官非国学，终教野史托悲歌。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;胸中剩有丘陵在，好听昭时鸣玉珂。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“谁说天官非国学”，犹如“天问”，但无人能答。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我查刘操南先生的履历，他字肇熏，号冰弦，晚号梁溪狂叟。1917年12月13日生于江苏无锡南门之刘源昌号，家境殷实，六岁入私塾，诵《四书》《毛诗》《尚书》《左氏春秋》等。出塾后直接考入中学，文理皆能，尤擅数学。初三时就写成《四边形之研究》长篇论文，旁征博引，发表在本校毕业纪念刊上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1937年考入浙江大学史地系，旋因故赴沪，适逢之江文理学院在沪招生，即报考并录取到土木系，在沪就读。11月，淞沪战事起，不久上海被日军占领。次年他重回浙大，仍入史地系，随校西迁，三年间转辗浙江建德、江西吉安、广西宜山、贵州遵义等地。在宜山时，他申请转系，进入新恢复的中国文学系，但仍兼修文、理两科，举凡地学、物理、微积分、春秋三传、《史》《汉》、唐宋诗词、文字训诂等课程和书籍，一并选修博览。他从钱宝琮习天文历算，从缪钺习词章文史，选修何增禄的光学、朱庭祜的地学、张荫麟的史学等，拜费巩为导师学政治学，会通中西，并非虚语。大学时所撰论文《月有迟疾、日有盈缩，兼论中西历学》，得到钱宝琮的赞许。1942年毕业于遵义，留校任教，是该系直到1947年唯一的助教。1950年兼任院务秘书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BpzJL1MrXfs621UY9ycsgV0WPey3cFZdk4jRjgqd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BpzJL1MrXfs621UY9ycsgV0WPey3cFZdk4jRjgqd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘操南先生的聘书。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，中国科学院筹编《中国科学史资料丛刊》，时任副院长的竺可桢欲调其赴京，校方不允，未能成行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;留校之后十年，老浙大文理工兼备的环境，让他如鱼得水，尽管战乱频仍，他本人却撰述颇多，如《〈海岛算经〉源流考》，讨论重差术及测定日距方法，得钱宝琮、李俨、裘冲曼诸先生激赏，裘氏称：“此继杨辉、戴震、李潢未完之业，岂率尔操觚者可比。”这是他一生最得意的时期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1952年院系调整，转入浙江师范学院（1958年改名为杭州大学）。旧日的天文历算研究已经难以为继，因工作需要，“转行”研究古代文学，主要教授先秦两汉文学。此时对古代文学的教学与研究，已经要求结合马克思主义思想来取其精华、去其糟粕，反对烦琐考据，这对从旧时代过来的学者来说，是一个新的考验，想来刘先生也不例外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1964年，刘先生通过副教授职称评定，上报教育部，但因“四清”及“文革”而暂停。1978年恢复副教授认定。1983年升为教授。1987年退休。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这中间还有一则故事。1964年10月27日，“有同学向古典文学教研组提出一份书面意见，对刘操南先生讲古代神话等提出批评”。事因是9月16日刘操南讲了“鲧禹治水”神话,新任辅导员曾前来听课，在“千万不要忘记阶级斗争”的背景下，此事被上纲到“阶级斗争”的高度。11月3日，“刘操南先生就以前所讲古代神话中的&#39;错误&#39;观点进行检查”。之后，由徐朔方老师代表教研组来收场。徐老师发表了25分钟讲话，既肯定批评者的政治敏感性，又补充了被批评者讲课不够圆满处。此事方算平息。（以上据中文系1962级学生贺圣谟《片断思忆怀徐公》一文）刘先生的讲课似未能与时俱进，于此可见一斑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用今天的话来说，刘操南先生其实是妥妥的一枚“理工男”，跨界到了中文系。他精于数学，却未测人心；做事讲究细节精确，却过于较真而不知“模糊处理”，遂致扞格不入；他对人略无心机，于事满腔热忱，常常沉浸于自我的情感之中，而不知今夕何夕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他晚年自我总结，称：“聆藕舫校长（竺可桢）、琢如（钱宝琮）、彦威（缪钺）诸师训诲，知为学之须由博返约也。中西交叉、文理渗透；而考据、义理、词章三者兼顾。学者不徒博学、审问、慎思、明辨、笃行；且须深究自然科学与社会科学之规律，开物成务，以富国利民耶。”（《古籍与科学》卷首《自序》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这确实是剖心之论。但“中西交叉、文理渗透”“深究自然科学与社会科学之规律”，哪里是做文史哲的人轻易能够做到的？调子定得这么高，听者或以为他只替自己量身定设，借此扬己而抑人，因而大多会报以冷笑吧？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古来圣贤皆寂寞。然则泰山其颓乎，梁木其坏乎，哲人其萎乎？幸好丘陵犹剩，遗文俱在，“好听昭时鸣玉珂”，且由后人评说吧！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>