<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[怕老的年轻人正被世界富豪们牢牢盯上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260613]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, German tycoon Christian Angermaier &amp;nbsp;Angermayer) invested in the longevity biotechnology company Rejuveron, which hopes to achieve the purpose of extending life by solving age-related diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, big names in the technology industry such as Zuckerberg, Bill &lt;span>;·&lt;/span>; Gates, and the founder of Google have turned to anti-aging. Investing huge amounts of money in the field, these practices have triggered controversy from all walks of life. Capital has become a key force in the study of human &quot;immortality&quot; and has been criticized by ethics and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Capital is after all profit-seeking, and they are interested in the big cake behind anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data shows that from 2015 to 2021, the global anti-aging market will grow by US$76.5 billion. Especially as China&#39;s consumption upgrades and health needs deepen, China&#39;s demand for anti-aging is growing day by day, and the anti-aging industry continues to expand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the anti-aging market gradually expands, anti-aging products and medical beauty projects emerge in endlessly, which are also subtly affecting people&#39;s understanding of aging. When it comes to getting older, most people worry about skin problems. For example, &quot;dull and yellowish complexion&quot;, &quot;enlarged pores&quot; and &quot;aging around the eyes&quot; are common problems for the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that aging is not just a problem for middle-aged and elderly people. The trend of anti-aging is blowing into the social circle of Generation Z. Under the discursive framework of advertising and the social media turmoil, more and more young people are also developing anti-aging anxiety. What provides emotional value to this group of mentally damaged young people are the various home beauty devices that are increasingly active on the grass-growing platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Bring the beauty effects of the theater home&quot;. From unique precision instruments in medical beauty institutions to miniaturized and convenient instruments for home use, home beauty instruments are deeply loved by consumers. Some brands have also launched a new concept of &quot;technological beauty&quot;, that is, using a combination of beauty instruments + skin care products to attract consumers. This has caused many young people to engage in consumer behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Research reports show that 42% of users spend more than 1,000 yuan on skin care every quarter. Under the dual consideration of economic strength and anti-aging needs, people aged 35-39 are the most willing to pay for their appearance, with 21% spending more than 3,000 yuan on skin care every quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, when faced with a home beauty device worth several thousand dollars, many people still hesitate to consider whether it is an IQ tax or what is an anti-aging product worth buying. Hot discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will talk with you about whether it is worth spending money on anti-aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8ae7276b4d.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8ae7276b4d.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258286&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343de0e4ec.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/343de0e4ec.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5020a852e0.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5020a852e0.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/4929a36023.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/4929a36023.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e9baa877a9.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/14/e9baa877a9.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258290&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/14/91b7312bdf.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 14/91b7312bdf.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 14/ddbff4839c.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/ddbff4839c.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;258292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 08:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你家附近借书便利吗？期盼普及社区借阅服务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260844]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After reading the limited collection of books at home, when I felt that there were no books to read and life was difficult, Xiao Xu called Called and said he wanted to send me a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Xu is my former colleague. He knows that I like reading. I have given them away several times before, and each time they were several large copies. I was embarrassed to ask him to give it away again, so I politely declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have two major hobbies, one is walking and the other is reading. Walking refreshes me and reading makes my life fulfilling. If I don&#39;t take a walk for a day, I feel uncomfortable all over; if I don&#39;t read for a day, my life will be boring. Reading a few pages of books every day has long become a habit of life. If you don&#39;t touch a book on a certain day, you won&#39;t feel good even if you sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, most of the books I read were borrowed from the university library by my son. My son is studying in a local university. This has a great advantage for me, that is, I can use the university library as my own private library. This is all because of my son. Now that my son has graduated from college and is working, I have lost the convenience of studying. After my son left school, the source of books suddenly stopped. I had to rummage through boxes and cabinets at home and come up with the idea of ​​collecting books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the collection of books at home was too limited and could not meet my needs, so there was a book shortage. The days without books to read feel particularly long and endless. At this moment, Xiao Xu called and wanted to deliver a book. I was secretly happy, but at the same time, I felt that I couldn&#39;t always be in debt to others. Books are expensive nowadays, and Xiao Xu is just a working-class person, so how can he keep asking people to spend money? No matter how strong the relationship is, it must be measured. So I thought, it would be great if there was a place to borrow books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, it’s not that there is no borrowing office. You can borrow books from the city’s library, but it’s a pity that the place is not close to home. It’s more than ten miles away from home. In this way, it is natural to think, wouldn’t it be great if you could borrow books near your home? For example, community libraries, etc. But I couldn’t find such a place, and when I asked people, they said they had never heard of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My son joked that if we buy a house in the future, we will buy it near the library. Even if this kind of joke can come true, it will only be a long way away. They say we want to create a scholarly society, but even borrowing books is difficult. What can we do to create a better society? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I admit that fewer and fewer people read paper books now. But even so, the public services that should be provided must be provided and cannot be omitted. We often say that we need to provide all-inclusive assistance to needy groups, and we also need to provide all-inclusive assistance for reading, because there are always people who cannot afford to buy too many books, and there are always people who face the high price of books and have to give them up after considering them again and again. Even if you can&#39;t let go, you can only reluctantly give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let reading enter our daily life and become an important part of life, thereby improving individual quality and the population quality of the entire society. This is the fundamental essence of creating a scholarly society. Not to mention anything else, just for this reason, we also need a place where people can borrow books nearby. Such a place does not need to be big, it just needs to be convenient for people to borrow. At least one community committee must have such a place. In large communities, the number of places must be determined based on population distribution. In addition, in order to save costs, books can be regularly transferred between different places to maximize the use of books and satisfy the needs to the greatest extent. The needs of readers. I don&#39;t know if such a wish can be implemented in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a citizen of Anqing City, Anhui Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪国芭蕉——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（五）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260812]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl3NZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl 3NZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258619&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Matsuo Basho Monument at Inari Shrine in Niigata Prefecture, left picture taken in April 2023 month, the picture on the right was taken in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After walking several points on Matsuo Basho’s “Oku no Homichi” in the fall of 2019, Then came three years of COVID. It&#39;s like a big dream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early April and early September 2023, in early spring and early autumn, I went to Niigata Prefecture in northern Japan twice, the Echigo country that often appears in ancient Japanese literature. Echigo Kingdom, one of the ancient &lt;span>;Reiji Kingdom&lt;/span>; in Japan, faces the &lt;span>;Sea of ​​Japan&lt;/span>; and is long and narrow from north to south. &lt;span>;Meiji&lt;/span>; Four years later, the feudal domain was abolished and a prefecture was established, named Niigata. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in April, the car was driving among the continuous farmland. The brown rice fields in early spring have just been plowed and are waiting for a new round of sowing. The September trip is already in my plan, so I started imagining the scene of autumn. For large areas of solid color scenes, yellow is the most suitable, and the combination with the blue sky is pure and gorgeous. In the Chengdu Plain where I live, there is a spectacular scene every day in March. The spread of rapeseed flowers is spectacular, and the atmosphere of early spring is quite exciting. Chengdu people who stay at home will basically go out for spring outings at this time, not to let down nature or themselves. Fortunately, I visited Niigata again in early September and enjoyed the sight of golden rice fields and blue sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many swans in Niigata’s deserted fields in April. They are pecking at the grain that falls in the soil. After being fed and fattened, they will fly back to Siberia. It migrates like this every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at these beautiful big white birds from a distance. Has Basho seen them? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Probably not. Matsuo Basho and his disciple Soryo Kawai arrived in Echigo in the summer of 1689. Echigo is a stop on the &quot;Oku no Hosomido&quot;. The entire &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot; journey is a total of 2,400 kilometers of hiking. Starting from Edo, go north, then turn west. It is said that the most magnificent journey is the monk Kukai’s tour of the eighty-eight temples in Shikoku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the trip to Japan in the spring of 2023, the excitement and yearning were mixed with a different state of mind from the trips in previous years. During the three years of the epidemic, except for a few short trips within the country, I have not traveled abroad. Three years of isolation has had a psychological effect on me, leaving me with a faint uneasiness, but I don’t know where this uneasiness comes from. When applied to the body, the hands and feet feel sluggish and sluggish. Having been separated from the same rhythm for three years, the effect is really powerful. The body is heavy and the state of mind is also sinking. I asked myself, what would happen if I never went out again? It seems to be possible. For middle-aged people, three years makes them look older. This is probably an important reason. By September, after a trip to Japan in April, a self-driving trip to Yunnan in May, and several short trips, I felt that my mind and body were beginning to adapt to the journey again, which was very gratifying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Ding Yuan settled in the village of &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>; and ran a B&amp;B called &quot;Four Seasons Inn&quot; with her husband, Mr. Nakamura Tatsuo. The couple also ran a local hotel. Various contents of travel. Regarding Basho, what Ding Yuan helped me find out is that Basho and Zeng Liang stayed in Murakami for two nights and three days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Basho accommodation in Murakami can be checked and determined based on local literature, but it has lost its former appearance and has become a salmon restaurant, so the curtain at the door is very interesting. This is a two-story Japanese-style house on Murakami Street. Three Japanese-style curtains are hung side by side at the door. They are written in black on a white background and in the middle are &quot;Izutsuya&quot;, which is the name of the restaurant. The one on the right is written &quot;Murakami&quot;. &quot;Salmon Cuisine&quot; and a book on the left reads &quot;Basho&#39;s Staying Place&quot;. There is a wooden sign at the door stating, &quot;In June of the second year of Genroku (1689), Basho and Zeng Liang arrived at Murakami during their journey on the &#39;Oku no Homichi&#39;. They stayed here for two nights and three days. , it was called &#39;Sukuzaemon&#39; at the time.&quot; In order to show that the brand was not the store&#39;s own words, the signature was &quot;Mura City Education Committee.&quot; Murakami&#39;s salmon industry is very famous. Every year, many salmon migrate here, and the output and quality are of high quality. Therefore, Murakami has a considerable number of salmon restaurants and processing workshops for curing and drying salmon. I asked Nakamura, is &quot;Izutsuya&quot; the most famous salmon shop in Murakami? Nakamura smiled and said, that&#39;s not necessarily true. It&#39;s because of the influence of bananas, but most people don&#39;t care about this, and only you cultural people care about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258620&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho and his disciple Kawai Sora went to the accommodation in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho wrote in &quot;The Thirty-Five Echigo Road&quot; in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot; , &quot;As soon as we passed the Mouse Pass, we entered the territory of Echigo from Dewa, and then we rushed to Shizhen Pass in Etchu. We walked for nine days in total. During this period, sometimes the heat was unbearable, and sometimes the cold rain poured down on us, which made us physically and mentally exhausted. Even getting sick was really miserable. So I didn’t record much of my journey.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because Basho was ill during Echigo, there are very few records about Echigo in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. Based on the results that Ding Yuan helped me check, I followed the traces in Murakami in early spring and early autumn. However, it is no longer possible to determine the location of this trace. We can only search for it based on the location of the Basho Sentence Monument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jizo-do Hall in Kamikata Town has the Basho sentence monument &quot;けふはかり人も年よれ&amp;nbsp;First Time Rain&quot;. It can be translated as: Only today do you know that you are old, this is the first shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inari Shrine has a Basho motto stone, &quot;Cloud folds 々人をやすむる月见かな&quot;. The general meaning I understand is that the shadow of the cloud covers the moon, and the shadow of the moon covers the person. The latter is a sentence from Basho&#39;s seven-part collection &quot;Spring Day&quot;, written in 1685. Basho visited Murakami in August 1689. He probably left no works due to poor health. Next to the Bajiao Monument Monument, there is a haiku poet Su Xian&#39;s Monument Stone. The handwriting is blurry. The general idea I read is: Under the moonlight, the shore of the water is covered with pine leaves like umbrellas (I don&#39;t know if it is correct or not). According to the introduction on the standing plaque next to it, these two stone sentences were erected in October 1843, during the 150th anniversary of Basho and the 17th anniversary of Susen. The introduction also specifically said that there are two important remains of Basho in Murakami, one is the Inari Shrine where this place is located, and the other is the Iwafune Shrine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Iwafune Shrine built on the seaside is much larger in scale and momentum than the Inari Shrine. It has a red torii gate and a white torii gate. In front of the red torii gate, there is a Basho sentence stone, which is engraved with the sentence &quot;On the seventh day of Hanasaki, Tsurumi will see Tsuruga&quot;, which can be understood as &quot;The cherry blossoms are in full bloom in seven days, and only Tsurumi can see such a beautiful scenery.&quot; The Basho stone in front of the white torii gate is engraved with &quot;Bunzuki や六日も长の夜には思ず&quot;, which means that the night of Bunzuki (July), when I am anxiously waiting for the letter, is also different from the ordinary night. The former Basho haiku has nothing to do with &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;, and the latter line is taken from a line written in the Hokuriku section of &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April, the day before Basho’s tour in &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>;, we went to Kameoka Monju-in, the Daishoji Temple in Yamagata Prefecture. In the drizzle, there was still residual snow on the mountain col in the distance and on the roofs nearby. When I was going down the mountain, I suddenly found a Basho sentence monument standing on the roadside, which read &quot;春の夜は桜に明けてしまひけり&quot; (Spring night, cherry blossoms are in full bloom). Tateishiji Temple (Mountain Temple) in Yamagata Prefecture is an important place to visit on the &quot;Oku no Hosōdo&quot; tour of Master Basho and his apprentice. I visited in 2019. I don’t know if they have been to the Great Holy Temple, and it is not mentioned in the book. Someone may have studied the details of these travels, and the results of these studies must be carefully explored to know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I used to read a lot of haiku in Chinese translation, but over the years I slowly started to read the original haiku. It is true that poetry cannot be translated. Because my Japanese foundation is still shallow, and it also involves issues of ancient and modern Japanese, I can only read these haiku at a loss. But maybe it was in this confusion, after leaking some clear information, that I finally understood the extremely concise and complex semantics of haiku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of Basho&#39;s activities in this area of ​​​​Murakami is Otohoji Temple. During my two trips to Murakami in early spring and early autumn, I went to Otohoji Temple twice. The cherry blossom scenery in early spring is obviously much more beautiful than the scenery in early autumn before the red leaves appear. It is said to be Murakami, but Otohoji Temple is actually located in Tainai City next to Murakami. This temple was built in the 8th century AD under the order of Emperor Shomu who was in office at the time. The temple covers a vast area of ​​more than 80,000 square meters. There is a &quot;three-story pagoda&quot; built in 1620 in the temple, which is designated as a national important cultural property of Japan. This temple is the only ancient temple in Shinji that is included in &quot;The Story of Konsai&quot;, and it is also the temple where Matsuo Basho once visited when he wandered the &quot;Oku no Hosho Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258621&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho Monument in Otohoji Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the topic, let me say a few words. It was almost noon after visiting Otohoji Temple in early autumn. Mr. Nakamura said that there was a steamed bun shop next to it that was very delicious and he hadn’t eaten there in a long time. We decided to leave it at that for lunch. When I arrived at the door, I looked at the description and found that it was founded in the first year of culture, which was 1804, and has a history of more than 200 years. The shop is really small, with a few stools and two or three tables. When the steamed buns arrived, they turned out to be red bean paste buns. Later, I looked up information and learned that in Japan, the so-called steamed buns are bean paste buns, and the outer shell can vary. There are white steamed buns made of commonly used flour, brown tea steamed buns made of wheat flour, and sweet potato flour, yam flour, and japonica rice flour. There are sweet potato steamed buns and wine steamed buns made from fermented rice flour, etc., but they are filled with red bean paste. Yiboji Steamed Buns are delicious, and I am even more impressed that such a snack shop has a history of more than 200 years. In Japan, I often come across various small shops that are hundreds of years old. I once ate at a ramen shop in Kyoto. When I came to the door after eating, I was shocked to see the signboard. It has a history of more than 400 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I posted photos of my visit to Yibao Temple in WeChat Moments, and a friend asked: Is it the Yibao Temple in &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;? It seems that its name first came from &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Story of the Past&quot; is a collection of folklore stories from the late Heian period in Japan, with a total of thirty-one volumes and more than a thousand stories. It is divided into Tianzhu (India) (volumes one to five), Cathay (China) (volumes six to ten), and Honchao (Japan) (volumes eleven to thirty-one). The current Chinese version of this Dynasty was edited by Zhou Zuoren. The stories in &quot;The Tale of the Past&quot; are all-encompassing, with Buddhist stories and secular stories mixed together. There are also many stories of gods and supernatural beings. Many creations of later generations come from this book, which is one of the source treasures of Japanese literature. It is similar to Chinese books such as San Yan Er Pai and Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio. Because each volume contains the word &quot;present and past&quot; at the beginning, it is called &quot;The Story of Present and Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Japanese writers, Ryunosuke Akutagawa made full use of &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;. It is said that about one-fifth of the material in the historical novels he created came from &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;, including &quot;Rason&quot; Door&quot; and &quot;In the Jungle&quot;. Ryunosuke Akutagawa called &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; a &quot;human comedy&quot; in ancient Japan. He said that &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; is full of &quot;wild beauty&quot; and is &quot;a kind of beauty that has nothing to do with elegance and luxury.&quot; Many of the common Onmyodo and Onmyoji content in Japanese animations also come from &quot;Kanagi Monogatari&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spacious garden of Uhoji Temple, there is a Basho Sentence Monument, a round stone monument, the handwriting has been blurred. There is a wooden sign next to the stele, which records the content of the stele: &quot;In the second year of Genroku (1689), Matsuo Basho paid homage to the Ukiyo no Kita no Yamazakura Basho.&quot; I envy). Surrounding the Basho Sentence Monument are many echoing sentences from &lt;span>;Niigata&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;local&lt;/span>; haiku celebrities at that time. Otohoji Temple has been a famous place for cherry blossom viewing since ancient times. Basho admired the beauty of the northern cherry blossoms here, even though it was not during the cherry blossom season when he visited. Looking at Sakura Leaves, he also expressed his envious mood in his imagination. Two of the echoing haiku of other haiku writers were singled out and written in the description of the stele. They were probably the most famous haiku poets in the area at that time. One of them is not jade, &quot;Mitsukoshi Road や一の Temple の花ざかり&quot;, Mitsukoshi The road and Yi&#39;s Temple are filled with flowers. One song is by Yasuda Izabo, &quot;Different gods and Buddhas&quot;. Different gods and Buddhas all have the beauty of cherry blossoms. They are all sentences praising cherry blossoms. In Japan, the word flower, if not specifically mentioned, is cherry blossom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in early April, the cherry blossoms are in full bloom in previous years, but the spring of 2023 is coming fiercely, and when we arrived, the cherry blossoms were already a little overdue. In the garden of Otohoji Temple, on the round stone monument of Basho, there are several branches of cherry blossoms hanging down, on the eve of their withering. Behind the stele is a small hill, and on the steps are several red curtains from the temple, with the words &quot;Namo Guanyin Bodhisattva&quot; enshrined. The curtains fluttered gently in the sunshine and breeze. This sentiment and scene complement each other perfectly with the haikus tablet with unclear handwriting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Othoji Temple, like other Niigata landscapes, has very few tourists. I stood on the terrace outside the main hall, watching the yin and yang scene cut by the sun with the Buddha statues in the garden below. I have done this twice. Although the weather seems to be the same, there are obvious differences in the dividing lines between sunlight and shadow in early spring and early autumn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I visited Otohoji Temple again in September and suddenly discovered Kobo Daishi (Kukai) here. I didn’t notice it at all on that trip in April. There is a stone statue of Kobo Daishi Gozun here, which is a common standard shape of Kukai wearing a hat and leaning on a staff during his journey. This stone statue of Kukai is a bit cute, shaped into a pudgy little boy. I turned to the back of the base of the stone statue to read the description. The handwriting was a bit blurry, but I could clearly see the words &quot;Pursuing the eighty-eight sacred sites of Shikoku...to commemorate...&quot; and other words. It is estimated that someone went there before and erected a statue in Otohoji Temple after returning to Niigata. Benji was the monk Kukai&#39;s practice route. It later gradually became the most famous hiking route in the world, with a total length of more than 1,400 kilometers and 88 temples in Shikoku. Currently, more than half a million people from all over the world walk this road every year. This is also a strange fate for us. After seeing Kukai at Otohoji Temple, my friend Dr. Tan Weidong and I left Niigata the next day, flew to Osaka for a short stay, and then headed to Shikoku to start our plan Three years of preparation for the trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[格力电器：董明珠“绯闻”是造谣，已向公安机关报案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260839]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: &quot;Regarding the recent efforts of many self-media To obtain traffic, maliciously edit relevant videos, and use vulgar and filthy words to insult and slander company executives, Gree Electric has reported the case to the public security organs, which have accepted and filed the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned that recently There are rumors on social platforms that Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, is in love with Wang Ziru, the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; of Gree Electric Appliances. In a recent TV program, Dong Mingzhu responded, &quot;I don&#39;t even watch it. I don&#39;t think it matters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the same program, Wang Ziru said: &quot;I didn&#39;t watch it.&quot; &quot;I passed the salary slip issued to me by Gree&quot; and &quot;asked for an office close to the Dong Zong to facilitate reporting&quot;, etc., which have attracted much attention and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Cheetah Mobile CEO Fu Sheng expressed his views on Wang Ziru in WeChat Moments. Fu Sheng said, &quot;I can only say that Wang Ziru is not only a freeloader, but also a gangster.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, Wang Ziru is the founder of ZEALER (ZEALER Network Technology). Tianyancha shows that ZEALAR was established in June 2012. It is a technology information website focusing on electronic product evaluation and Q&amp;A, and then expanded its mobile phone repair business, mobile device hardware laboratory, etc. Wang Ziru is not only the executive director and general manager of ZEALER, but also a digital review blogger with 1.97 million fans. He once became popular because of his public debate with Smartisan CEO Luo Yonghao over the review controversy of the Smartisan T1 mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258706&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from public information, Wang Ziru and Dong Mingzhu met in 2016. In an entrepreneurial program &quot;I Am the Founder&quot; broadcast that year, Dong Mingzhu served as the mentor of Wang Ziru&#39;s team. Afterwards, Wang Ziru posted a photo of herself and Dong Mingzhu on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258707&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Dong Mingzhu held a nationwide tour of live broadcast to bring goods. Wang Ziru appeared as the host many times, and together with Dong Mingzhu, they won 703 million yuan in sales. That year, Dong Mingzhu&#39;s 13 live broadcasts totaled 47.6 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 30% of Gree Electric&#39;s total revenue in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2021, Gree Electric confirmed the news of Wang Ziru joining Gree Electric. At that time, industry insiders said that Wang Ziru’s department was affiliated with Gree’s President Office and Cultural Training and Communication Center. During the same period, Wang Ziru resigned from his position at ZEALER, the media he founded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are rumors that Wang Ziru’s rank in Gree is equivalent to that of vice president, with an annual salary of more than 3 million yuan. However, judging from Gree Electric’s financial reports in the past two years, Wang Ziru has never appeared in the executive compensation table middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After joining Gree Electric, Wang Ziru rarely appeared on public platforms. Gree Electric did not disclose his specific work content. However, it is known from some public reports that he is currently in charge of the Gree channel reform project. In late May this year, Wang Ziru, who had been with Gree for two years but had not yet appeared, appeared publicly in Nanchang for the first time as the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; and spoke at the 2023 Gree Electric (Jiangxi) new marketing model presentation conference. In October and November, Gree Electric Shandong and Hebei Sales Companies also issued documents, and Wang Ziru gave a speech at a new marketing model conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the beginning of this year, news appeared on social platforms that Gree Electric Chairman and President Dong Mingzhu was in love with his company’s post-85s male executive. The news originated from the big V Gong A screenshot posted by Wen Xiang on the Internet. In February this year, Dong Mingzhu took the initiative to mention and denounced in an interview with reporters from Nanduwan Financial News and other media: &quot;Vulgar, obscene, and boring! It is not an exaggeration to use these words to describe it.&quot; She clearly denied the love scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, big V Gong Wenxiang apologized to Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, for his previous remarks in the Southern Metropolis Daily. Gong Wenxiang said in his apology statement that he made distorted remarks about Ms. Dong Mingzhu’s private life on Toutiao on February 26, which were widely disseminated and objectively damaged Ms. Dong’s reputation. &quot;I deeply regret and am deeply sorry to Ms. Dong. The special newspaper expresses my public apology and sincere remorse to Ms. Dong, and hopes to obtain Ms. Dong&#39;s forgiveness. I will use this as a lesson in the future to be a self-media person with three upright views.&quot; .&quot; Gong Wenxiang said in the statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: It is worth mentioning that the Internet is not a place outside the law. The company will take legal measures to resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the company and employees. We maintain a zero-tolerance attitude towards any malicious slander and rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the TV program mentioned above, Wang Ziru said that no company is drowned in saliva. As a business operator and manager, you should spend more time focusing on what you should do. things to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[跨越45年，披头士乐队的最后一首歌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Beatles were founded in 1960, a milestone in the history of pop music band. In 1980, lead singer John Lennon was shot and killed. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 30, 1969, on the rooftop of Apple Records headquarters at 3 Savile Row, England , the Beatles held a 42-minute impromptu concert. It was almost at the last moment that the idea was settled - they discussed it and then fell silent until John Lennon said, &quot;...let&#39;s do it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Noon Around 12:30, the four people arrived on the rooftop. As word spread, people began to gather in the surrounding streets and on the rooftops of nearby buildings. That day, Lennon wore a fur coat, and Ringo put on his wife&#39;s red coat. In the biting cold wind of January, the members sang a total of five songs in a loop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert finally came to an end with the melody of &quot;Get&amp;nbsp;Back&quot;. Lennon said humorously to the audience: &quot;On behalf of the band and ourselves, I want to say thank you. I hope we have passed the audition.&quot; However, the public at the time may not have expected that this would be the last of the Beatles. A public performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, 2023, after a span of 45 years, a new Beatles collaboration called &quot;Now And Then&quot; finally came to the public. After the familiar &quot;one, two, three&quot; timer, the accompaniment sounded, and Lennon&#39;s voice slowly flowed out:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;&quot;&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I know it&#39;s true / It&#39;s all because of you / And if I make it through / It&#39;s all because of you&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;……&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lennon in the MV The faces of George and George were still young, wearing bright costumes from that time, playing in the same space as Paul and Ringo. Different from their youthful and fresh appearance, the wrinkles on Paul and Ringo&#39;s faces are clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It was incredibly touching to hear that they were still working together after all these years,” Lennon’s son Sean said. “It was my dad and Paul and George. , the last song we made together with Ringo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;We&#39;ve been waiting almost a quarter of a century&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now And Then&quot; The story begins in 1978. Lennon recorded this vocal demo with accompaniment while playing the piano in his apartment in New York. By that time, he had focused on his family and had all but put his music career on hold, not touring or fulfilling any major label obligations. However, in his son Sean&#39;s memory, Lennon would always play music at home and record and make demos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, 14 years after Lennon’s death, during a chat with the Beatles, Lennon’s widow Yoko Ono said that she still had some of Lennon’s audio tapes. She gave them to the rest of the Beatles. &quot;If the three of us were to do something, it would be fun, but obviously not as fun as when John was here,&quot; George said. &quot;We really have to cherish hearing John&#39;s voice. I&#39;m sure he would really enjoy being with us.&quot; A chance to be together again.&quot; Now, that chance has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We can use Lennon&#39;s music to try to make a record. Since his death, this is the closest moment we have been away from him.&quot; Lin Ge said. In the face of Lennon&#39;s sample, Paul also thought about, &quot;Should we not do this?&quot; But whenever he thought so, he always interrupted himself, assuming that he had a chance to ask Lennon- &quot;Hey , Lennon, do you want us to complete your song? &quot; - What will Lennon&#39;s answer, and he believes, Lennon will say,&quot; Of course! &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The production is not as smooth as expected. At that time, there were no technologies that could separate human voices from the sound of accompaniment. To some extent, Lennon&#39;s voice was actually hidden. Whenever they want to adjust the voice of Lennon more clearly, the sound of piano accompaniment will increase, and the effect is actually worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They were frustrated, &quot;We have lost time and motivation.&quot; Paul said that it seemed that they should give up the song. &quot;The incident is not progressing, and it makes Lennon no longer this fact, and it is getting clearer in front of us.&quot; Linko said. In this way, &quot;Now &amp; nbsp; and then&quot; was put on hold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Until 2022. Prior to this, the team of &quot;Ring Rings&quot; Peter Jackson&#39;s team developed an artificial intelligence -based technology, which can separate specific voices and accompaniment sounds and repair. And this technology was proven to be successful in the documentary &quot;Get Back&quot; produced by Peter Jackson for the Beatles in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After technical help, Lennon&#39;s voice came out from the player again, &quot;as clear as crystal.&quot; &quot;We waited almost a quarter of a century until this moment, we can make&quot; Now and then &quot;again.&quot; Paul said. He called Lin Ge and told him that he wanted to continue the production of the song, and Lin Ge agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to Lennon&#39;s piano accompaniment, Paul also joined his bass part, and Link also added his drums based on this. They retained George&#39;s guitar performance in 1995. &quot;This is a tribute to George.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the help of Georgos, the son of George Martin, the old Beatles band producer George Martin, the string part has also joined. In the recording of this part, in order to keep confidential, they did not tell the string orchestra of the performance. This is a new Beatles, but pretended to be Paul&#39;s own new single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;All those memories have flooded up, my God, how lucky I can appear in my life ... I am still doing the Beatles in 2023 Music, wow! &quot;Paul sighed,&quot; Now and then &quot;should be our last song.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &quot;Think of me from time to time, old friends&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; /H4>; &lt;p>; In February 1964, the Beatles played to the United States for the first time. With them take off, it was more than 4,000 fans at Henhero Airport waved away; they welcomed their landing, and it was another group of about 3,000 pick -up teams. On the 9th of that year, Beatles performed a live TV show on Ed Shalvan show, attracting about 73 million viewers to watch, which accounted for about 34%of the American population. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That is almost the most days in the middle of the Beatles. However, separation and death have come between them prematurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September of the same year when the Beatles band played the last public performance, Lennon notified his band members in a meeting with Link, Paul and their agent Allen Claine. We intend to exit the Beatles band. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, because of business, creation, feelings, and many aspects, frictions and differences have become increasingly serious, and it seems that it is only a matter of time. In that meeting, George was absent, and Claine persuaded other band members to remain silent about the dissolution, because some important business affairs were still in progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On April 10 of the following year, Paul publicly announced that he had withdrawn from the Beatles, which was also regarded as a sign of the disbanding of the Beatles. At that time, ten years before they were founded, a American media person claimed that it was &quot;a milestone for the decline of the British Empire.&quot; When asked whether his departure was temporarily or permanent, Paul replied, &quot;I really don&#39;t know.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many years later, in a media interview, Paul denied that it promoted the band to dissolve. Due to Claine&#39;s request, they had to stop the band&#39;s dissolution, and had to pretend everything was normal for a few months. He was just &quot;enough to hide&quot;, and in the end, &quot;put the cat out of the bag.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the later time, even if the Beatles have developed each other, there are still in the hearts of music fans, and they look forward to one day, they will fit again. However, Lennon&#39;s death directly smashed this hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On December 8, 1980, after completing the work of the day, Lennon returned to his residence with his wife Ono Yoko. The two came down from the car and walked to the entrance of the building in Dako&#39;s apartment. At this moment, the 25 -year -old Mark ∙ Davido appeared. He fired five shots towards Lennon, and Lennon stopped his heartbeat forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;For everyone who hopes to exist continuously, murder is another matter. This is a assassination, a ritual killing of something that is not famous, maybe It is hope, maybe idealism, or time. It is not only lost, but also suddenly misplaced and fragmented. &quot;Critics Jei Cosks wrote in the cover article of the&quot; Times &quot;magazine of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February of the following year, musician Karl Pakins wrote a song &quot;My Old Friend&quot; for Paul. The next morning after finishing, Carl took the guitar and sat on the old double -ranging bullet in Paul, singing this song for him: &quot;If we are hard to see us in our lives ... my old friend, will you from time to time? Think of me ... &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Paul and his wife Linda sat on the floor to listen. After singing the song, Carl found that Paul cried. After that, he got up and left the room. Linda explained to him, &quot;Since the incident of Lennon, he has been unable to really collapse ... But how do you know?&quot; She said, Lennon said to Paul in the corridor of the Dako building before his lifetime. It was -at the time he patted Paul&#39;s shoulder and said, &quot;Now and then thinks of me, old friends.&quot; &lt;em>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/em>; &lt;p>; The key is to chemically react. It is very special to combine the four -person person&#39;s personality. When John lost John, we know that all this is really over. &quot;Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2001, they once again realized the pain of the death of their friends. This time, it was another Beatles member George Harrison, who died of cancer unfortunately. &quot;Lost George, this is like we have no wind on the way.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In November of the following year, the commemorative concert organized by George&#39;s widow Olvia and his son Dani Harrison was held at the Royal Albert Concert Hall in London. turn up. Before the performance, Paul walked to the microphone and said, &quot;When Danny stands on the stage, it is like we are old, but George is still young.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; maybe they may still be young. music. On November 10, 2023, with the song &quot;Now and then&quot;, Beatles reached the top of the British music rankings again, which is their 18th champion single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It not only continues the record of the Beatles in the history of the British official rankings, but also makes them the first and last time in history. The band -this song, &quot;From Me to You&quot;, the first top champion, has passed for 60 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Southern weekend interns Chen Quanxin also contributed to this article) &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;htps://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:Aorange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260737]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-17 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁老人状告保姆：虐待自己还骗走200万养老钱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260804]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-17 18:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/23/ 11/17/chqtyndsbis4falpoe4jglv3iamtpkyiookeqyy.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 691 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.cms/medias/i/i MAGE/23/11/17/Chqtyndsbis4falPoe4jglv3iaMTPKYIOOKEQYY. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258602 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; nanny abuse &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Lu Junjie /Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Who is the defendant 2, I can&#39;t figure it out,&quot; Facing the judge&#39;s inquiry, Shen Yinan sat in a seat with &quot;the defendant&#39;s agent&quot; with doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The defendant 2 is your father,&quot; the lawyer reminded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The above -mentioned slightly absurd scene occurred together to give a pre -meeting meeting of the contract dispute. On November 7, 2023, the People&#39;s Court of Huangpu District, Shanghai, exchanged evidence on the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Yinan&#39;s mother Lu Delin is the plaintiff. The nagnic nagnic Jiang Aizhen in the family is the defendant 1, and Shen Yinan&#39;s father Shen Zongli is the defendant 2. According to civil prosecution, Shen Zongli once &quot;gifts&quot; a nagged nagnic Jiang Aizhen 2 million yuan, and now Lu Delin asked to return; at the same time, Lu Delin said that he was murmured by the nagged Jiang Aizhen, asking the other party to pay the mental damage to compensate 200,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Yinan&#39;s &quot;unclear&quot; reason is that this is not a single case. Civil contract disputes and criminal cases are in progress. Relevant legal documents show that Lu Delin&#39;s abuse has been criminally filed at the Huangpu Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, and criminal cases are currently being handled. Shen Yinan has lived abroad for many years, lacks enough understanding of the Chinese environment, and returned to Shanghai to visit relatives every year since the end of 2019 that it has continued to interrupt the new crown epidemic at the end of 2019. During this period, the nanny Jiang Aizhen lived in the house to take care of Lu Delin and Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin, a 94 -year -old old man in Shanghai, released the first video on the Internet, saying that he was abused by nanny and was transferred away by nanny. Since then, the account has released multiple videos, and Lu Delin appeared in the photo to tell his experience: &quot;I will breathe a sigh of relief.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; This is not an example. On the day of exchange evidence, a similar news in Shanghai rushed into hot search again. A nanny claims that the elderly who take care of the real estate should give himself a transfer of real estate. The staff found that the transfer process was suspended after the existence was inappropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Shanghai Health and Health Committee recently disclosed that as of the end of 2022, 5.536 million household registration elderly people in Shanghai were 60 years old and over, accounting for 36.8%of the total household registration population. In modern cities with severe aging, how to be decent -decent, the problem of home care of the elderly is attracting the attention of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the court scene on the afternoon of the 7th, Jiang Aizhen did not arrive. The judge said that the court would announce the announcement and it is expected that Jiang Aizhen will be summoned again in two months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwqjhfwcourmaxryq1je8rzq5hcbreze.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;720&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwcourmaixryq1jrzq5hcbreze&quot; data- key = &quot;258606&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Lu Delin&#39;s bedroom, daughter-in-law Shen Allen has found cleaning and scaning &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Han Ruxue/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Life of 94 -year -old couples &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Pushing open the closed door in front of him, the first thing floating is a sour taste. This house should look well ventilated. The apartment is square. It is the other side of the living room. The balcony is wide and the windows are large. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Here is a certain building 2401, Lane 118, Xindu Road, Liyuanxin Village, Huangpu District, Shanghai. The other side of dirty is the expensive value of this house itself. There are 4 buildings in this community, all of which are high -rise. They are located in the center of Shanghai. There are many subways and bus routes near Shanghai. Related information shows that this community was built in the early 1990s. At present, the price of the second -hand housing market exceeds 100,000 yuan per square meter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Master Xia, who has worked in the property in the community for many years, told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that there are many elderly people in the community and are &quot;decent people with identity&quot;. It is common for hiring clock or home nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The house in front of him belongs to an old couple, Lu Delin and his wife Shen Zongli. Both of them are 94 years old and have retired for many years. Lu Delin suffered from spinalitis and was paralyzed in the bed in the lower body; Shen Zongli was blind now, and only 0.25 vision was left with one eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The only son of the two, Shen Yinan, settled in the United States for decades, and relatives have basically lived abroad. Both have been to the United States to help their son take care of their grandchildren, but each visa time is only half a year. Several round trips, the higher the age of the two, and slowly had to stay in this house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Now, this house is vacant. On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin released his first video on the Internet, saying that he was murmured by nanny Jiang Aizhen and the pension was transferred away. At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli have been taken away by his son Shen Yinan and daughter -in -law Shen Allen and placed in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Ailun opened the door and displayed the layout in the room one by one. She was careful to take pictures, numbers, and retention in these traces of life. During the investigation of the case, multiple evidence came from this. On the corner of the living room, there are more than ten kinds of supplements and mountain goods such as fungus, lily, mushrooms, etc., and more than a dozen. Shen Ailun, who was standing on one side, said that she had been looking for the cleaning staff and cleaned it inside and outside. The sour odor that can be smelled at present is not much residual. Those supplements are &quot;left. Many, many have expired, nanny does not do it for the elderly. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This home was originally &quot;stable and decent.&quot; Lu Delin and Shen Zongli&#39;s monthly pensions were more than 10,000 yuan. With fixed financial interest, there were an additional 8,000 yuan in income per month. In addition to the house where the name lives, there is another real estate before. After the demolition in the previous two years, a lot of compensation was received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; His son Shen Yinan returned to visit relatives every year, &quot;7 years in 786 days, an average of 84 days per year&quot;. From 2013 to 2019, Shen Ailun compiled the entry and exit records in these passports one by one. However, such a connection was broken by the sudden new crown epidemic. After leaving China on November 29, 2019, Shen Yinan failed to come back for more than 3 years. It was not until February 23, 2023 that he saw his parents again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5ikmmmmjzfctxyijijijkkdgj6df7z.png&quot; 0 &quot;widt =&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;399&quot; Height = &quot;601&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5ikmmm2RPAMJZFCTCKXYIGCDGJ6DF7Z.PNG&quot; Data- &quot;>; 258605&quot;>; &lt;/>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Shen Zizi returned to the country to return to China &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 3 years, two elderly people who lived in this house, and nanny Jiang Aizhen. The neighbors of the same unit told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that in the past few years, I had a relationship with Lu Delin&#39;s family. Occasionally, I did a little food, but I did n’t go to her house. Foot. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The kitchen is on the right hand of the door, with moldy and long hairboard and jar scattered on the table; the left hand side of the door is a bathroom, and a few square meters of bathrooms are covered with white tiles. This is renovated. Including shower, toilet, etc., it costs tens of thousands of yuan. The bill comes from the nanny Jiang Aizhen. The price of the shower is 4,000 yuan. Master Xia has worked in the property in the community for many years and confirmed the amount of this amount to the reporter of the Southern Character Weekly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7&quot; = &quot;1702&quot; height = &quot;1276&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bor8sa2y9epuder4qvtrMTS0J4em.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258601&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The bathroom after the nanny is renovated by hand, the shower is labeled at 4,000 yuan &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Han Ruxue/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the bedroom, the smell of rotten is even more obvious. Lu Delin was paralyzed, and he had been solving urination on a chair -shaped toilet in the bedroom. The cover of the sheets has been replaced, and the mattress full of white powder is put in the box on the side. Shen Ailun opened it to reporters to see that it was Lu Delin&#39;s bed in bed a few years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The shirt of the father -in -law Shen Zongli was also kept. There were large yellow and black stains at the neckline. These &quot;all evidence&quot;. In this unfamiliar space, Shen Ailun carefully collected traces of the past and determined to fight a lawsuit with the nuns Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; The contradictions that have long been buried &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The first contact with the nagged Jiang Aizhen of the Lu Delin family was introduced by Wang Wei, the neighbor Wang Wei upstairs at the time, when Jiang Do the clock in the nearby area. By 2017, Jiang Aizhen became the long -term and fixed clock worker of the Lu Delin&#39;s family. Wang Wei said that &quot;Xiao Jiang did a good job&quot;, Shen Allen said that because Jiang Aizhen was looking for a job, he cried from the old couple of Lu Delin before he obtained the job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For a long time with each other, in the three years when the new crown epidemic raged, the Lu Delin couple were taken care of by Jiang Aizhen&#39;s home and care. Until Lu Delin released a video, saying that he was abused by nanny, deceived pensions, etc., the conflict broke out in the public&#39;s field of vision. For a long time, the contradiction between the family and the nanny had already been buried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxbpiVRPNXI3S2CUKL3VNFCUTPGAT8thrac.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1702&quot; height = &quot;1276&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxbpiVRT0LPNXI3S2CUKR3VNFCUTPGATPG.jpg&quot; data- &quot;>; 258603&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The bedding that Mr. Lu Delin used in the previous years, the smell of moldy &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (Han Ruxue/Figure) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Initially, Jiang Aizhen went home for two hours every day to work, and the old couple paid 6,000 yuan per month. In March 2022, Jiang Aizhen moved into this house and changed from the clock to a nanny, and his salary rose to 12,000 yuan per month. Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that while Jiang Aizhen took this salary, he also did clock -oriented work at the same time in four other places. At this point, she felt that the nanny did not have a contract spirit. &quot;I have paid the salary of all the nanny of the home, how can I go to other classes outside?&quot; At the current Huangpu District of Lu Delin, an hour&#39;s salary is about 45 yuan, and it will rise to about 50 yuan during the evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The staff of the Sangcheng neighborhood committee of the community told the Southern Character Weekly that the price is a clock or a full -time resident nanny, depending on how the employer and the nanny negotiate. Judging from the registration of the neighborhood committee, as long as he spent the night at the employer&#39;s house at night, it is a nanny of the home. Jiang Aizhen has always been registered as a nanny of the home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The introducer Wang Wei who also hired the clock and the work for a long time does not think that 12,000 yuan is a &quot;buy out&quot; price. The two elderly people, who cannot take care of themselves, must add money. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; reporters consult with the current situation of Lu Delin&#39;s old couple. Do other jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of the housekeeping agencies was established in 2014. The headquarters is located in Guangzhou. There are branches in Shanghai and Shenzhen. Through employee system, they provide customers with full -time housing nanny. Each aunt has undergone background investigations. Their daily situation was supervised by the company&#39;s steward. The company will make regular return visits through the housekeeper, which belongs to a family that pays attention to supervision in similar institutions. Even so, the good or bad of aunt still depends on the active feedback of customers. When the family is not around for many years, the elderly are forced to rely on a single nanny. &quot;This kind of feedback is relatively difficult, it can be said that it is blank.&quot; .com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/17/3YPU1XBKVMKYW1XRSR2BFACSHHVL1IMYUJCSBWAD.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 720 &quot;head =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // IMA Ges.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258600&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;卢德麟老两口厨房中日常使用The cutting board &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Han Ruxue/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Money is an &quot;love point&quot; that cannot be calculated. During the new crown epidemic, the two elderly people were taken care of by Jiang Aizhen alone, pushing up and queuing to do nucleic acid, which was seen in the neighborhood committee. It is &quot;the thing that is locked in the door&quot;, and whether it is good or abused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the Shen Yinan couple returned to China, Jiang Aizhen repeatedly claimed that he &quot;saved the old man&#39;s life&quot; and took out the &quot;proof&quot; and &quot;attorney&quot; signed by Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A commissioned book on September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Our current residence will live here by Jiang Aizhen in a hundred years. In the end, they were thrown into the Huangpu River. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In another&quot; certificate &quot;on the same day, Shen Zongli expressed the presence to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s&quot; one million yuan &quot;; in a&quot; certificate &quot;on March 3, 2023 The amount given to Jiang Aizhen rose to &quot;two million yuan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not only paper commitments, but also on August 22, 2022 and February 7, 2023, Shen Zongli&#39;s personal account transferred 1 million yuan to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3 pieces of paper, corresponding to 2 RMB 2 of RMB and the residential rights of the house, all given nagged Jiang Aizhen. Whether the old man is sober, voluntarily, whether the gift is legal and effective, the question is finally handed over to the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Find evidence &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;Who was present at that time?&quot; The judge asked many times to confirm this key question, pointing to the latest gift contract -20123 On March 3, the year, Shen Zongli wrote a &quot;proof&quot; of 2 million yuan to nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang Aizhen did not arrive in the court. Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun told the judge that passing by: Jiang Aizhen took out a certificate, including Lu Delin, Shen Zongli, Shen Yinan, and Shen Yinan signed in the corresponding location. Shen Ailun was present and stopped. At that time, I thought that the matter was ended. Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun went out to work. When I returned to Shanghai, I learned that the &quot;proof&quot; was actually written long ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The suspended proof is on March 9, 2023. In fact, as early as a week ago, on March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen got the &quot;proof&quot; signed by Shen Zongli. Shen Ailun found that Shen Zongli&#39;s Alipay was registered. Find someone to restore the data of the elderly&#39;s mobile phone with technical means, and found a video recorded by Jiang Aizhen. The video content was a proof of Shen Zongli&#39;s handwritten nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tcki7m60dt3WK8OODV8EJKNT3LS4ZY9VH9CX6.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;widt h = &quot;1280&quot; height = &quot;1706&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/tcki7m60dt3wk8l81jknt3ls4zy9vh9cx6.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258604&quot;>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The power of attorney on September 1, 2022 shows:&quot; Our residence in our current residence is here by Jiang Aizhen. In the end, they were thrown into the Huangpu River. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; A recording data provided by Lu Delin&#39;s acting lawyer Zhou Zhaocheng showed that a lawyer on duty said that Jiang Aizhen had repeatedly pushed Shen Zongli with a wheelchair to the Lawyer Department of the neighborhood committee for consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen obtained a certificate of signing signature by Shen Zongli. In order to ensure that the gift of this &quot;2 million yuan&quot; is legitimate and valid, one week later, she once again took out a certificate that the money was added to Shen Zongli and added &quot;Lu Delin Shen Yinan&quot;. &quot;Gift&quot; proof. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The previous gifts of 1 million yuan, a gift of 2 million yuan, and three certificates that let the nanny live in the house. Shen Yinan saw the nanny party on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9le4c03yqusx1reuea0du9dzlxfnkoraquarp6fm.jpg&quot; width = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1280 &quot;height = &quot;1706&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9le4c03yqusx1reuea0du9dzlxfnkoraquarp6fm.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258599&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; p style = &quot;colorRor : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; March 3, 2023, Shen Zongli handwritten&quot; proof &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli, a&quot; certificate &quot;of 2 million yuan, was the person who mastered the family&quot; account &quot;. The proof was handwritten. Shen Ailun said that the way of treating Shen Zongli and Lu Delin is different. &quot;I know which one should coax, and used such a brainwashing method to deceive the old man&#39;s money.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Initially, the family trusted the nanny. For the first time, I found out that there was something wrong. It was time for Shen Ailun to mail the food to her in -laws. When I talked about the phone, I found that the in -laws did not receive it and did not know it. Earlier, Shen Ailun sent a message to the elderly mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The nanny will delete the chat history,&quot; this answer was found after Shen Ailun installed the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2023, after about 3 years due to the new crown epidemic, Shen Ailun stepped into the door of 2401 again. The mother -in -law Lu Delin asked her to see her feet, saying that she felt potholes, and Shen Ailun found that the toenail was &quot;cut&quot;, and she realized that something was wrong. Shen Ailun went to check the account and found that 2 million yuan on his in -law&#39;s account was transferred to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From a wheelchair to the wall, Shen Ailun secretly installed 7 micro -cameras to &quot;monitor&quot; nanny. The couple falsified to return to the United States. . Her husband told her that this was to obtain evidence, and she had to hold back her temper. No matter what she saw, the primary purpose was to retain evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the next day, Shen Allen still quarreled with Jiang Aizhen. She recalled that Jiang Aizhen had a habit, a bit like a teacher&#39;s feeling of training children, &quot;What are you going to, what&#39;s going on&quot;, &quot;I can hear my head buzzing.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p >; The contradiction quickly erupted to the table. One day at noon, her mother -in -law Lu Delin said that she wanted to eat crabs and asked Shen Allen to do it. Shen Ailun said that she asked her aunt (referring to Jiang Aizhen). Jiang Aizhen said that she would not eat crabs and would not do it. &quot;I wanted to scold her at that time, but I held back,&quot; Shen Ailun continued to recall. &quot;The nanny asked my mother -in -law how to do it. My mother -in -law asked her to ask me. She was normal when she asked me. Didn&#39;t you ask my mother? You can do it according to my mother&#39;s method. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Patience seems to have disappeared suddenly. Jiang Aizhen suddenly became unwilling, and the volume suddenly became larger. Ask you, you asked me to ask your mother, I really don&#39;t understand you anymore. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; As soon as this sentence came out, Shen Ali couldn&#39;t hold back the fire. I started scolding her. I said you don&#39;t want to talk to me like this. One day I asked you to cry, and you rolled it out. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At that time, Jiang Aizhen did not know how to install a camera at home, but Shen Ailun had already Seeing the normal behavior of the nanny through the video, it made her difficult to accept. &quot;She sprinkled all her breath on my mother -in -law, and her throat scolded the sound.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; After watching the camera On the night of sleeping in her in -laws, Shen Ailun was afraid that Jiang Aizhen did extreme things from the kitchen, and took away the large and small knives in the kitchen, put it in the room, locked the door, and put one of them. The knife is placed under the pillow to prepare the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; About &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Jiang Aizhen &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; It is another saying of Wang Wei, an introduced person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Wei also heard the gift of 2 million yuan, and she also saw the &quot;abuse&quot; picture circulating online video. But she always believes that the nanny is okay: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The video seen online is that the action is rude. In fact, the old man gets up like this. I used to have an old man before, and Xiao Jiang pulled like this. Jiang is also almost 60 years old. It is only a clockwork. He has not received professional training in nursing. It can only be that. We are used to this action in our house. She has a temperament and character. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; There are toenails to cut bleeding, cut asylon nails, and gray -cut nails must be bleeding. The moldy bedding must have nothing to do with Xiao Jiang. This is Teacher Lu. Their old couple&#39;s personal habits. Their habits of their family say that they have entered their family, there is no garbage, all treasures, and nothing are thrown. /P>; &lt;p>; The Xiao Jiang who hired Xiao Jiang in this building was introduced by Wang Wei. She said that only the Lu Delin family said that the problem was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang Aizhen is the clockman introduced by the security guard earlier, and it will be done at Wang Wei&#39;s house since 2012. &quot;Before the daughter -in -law returned to Shanghai this time, Mr. Lu&#39;s family had a good relationship with the nanny. They said that this nanny was his own daughter. Fortunately, there was a nanny, otherwise his life was gone. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Wang Wei told&quot; Southern Character Weekly &quot;that the money of 2 million yuan was given to Jiang Aizhen twice, all for a reason: the first time was because of the epidemic control. Time does nucleic acid almost every day. The nanny push up every day and rely on her alone. Another time is that a house of Mr. Shen was relocated. He said that he could not negotiate with him. I commissioned this nanny to do it, and finally seemed to get some money. Mr. Shen said, &quot;If it wasn&#39;t for his aunt to help him, he would not get so much.&quot; In the end, he had to ask Xiao Jiang to give himself the end of his elderly. At that time, during the epidemic closure, I did not know when the son came back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But these two things are another situation in Shen Allen&#39;s eyes. In terms of physical care, Shen Ailun said that in May 2020, there was an old man who was hospitalized with pneumonia, and Jiang Aizhen was taken care of, but paid an additional salary at the price of 300 yuan a day. This is a contract, not &quot;love or help&quot;; It is that the nanny is not done well, and the demolition funds have taken a lot less ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, which are taken care of by Shen Yinan and Shen Allen, asked Jiang Aizhen to pay for the money in the video. Before being taken away, when the elderly and nanny coexisted, &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; obtained a recording. It was a conversation between the problem of money because of the problem of money on March 22, 2023: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Babysitter: &quot;All the money is transferred.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli: &quot;My money is to keep.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; nanny: &quot;You keep it here &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli:&quot; Two. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; nanny:&quot; I want it. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli:&quot; You bully me. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; The helplessness of &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Is it voluntary to give nanny money? Shen Zongli&#39;s answer is different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At first he said that he was voluntarily gifts. He didn&#39;t change his mouth until he saw the babysitter&#39;s flowing water, recording, and video. Related recording and videos showed that the nanny personally admitted that it took 70,000 yuan for the elderly&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that Shen Zongli claimed that he had been told many times that his money was the same in the nanny account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For 3 years in the new crown, Shen Ailun only returned to China once. At that time, she was ready to visit her in -laws, but she received a note written by her mother -in -law when she received her mother -in -law, which reads &quot;Don&#39;t return&quot;. Considering that he was afraid of infection at that time, Shen Allen did not return to 2401. Afterwards, Lu Delin told Shen Ailun that the note was written by the nanny, &quot;forced.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In 3 years, the &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot; became the theme of 2401, and even the &quot;outsiders&quot; who dealt with it were seen. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Master Xia of the property told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that the two elderly people could not take care of themselves, and they had to accompany the nanny. The nanny had been around. The old man couldn&#39;t say anything even if he wanted to say anything. Usually, the two elderly people are at home, and they have no relatives. Only Lu Delin&#39;s students occasionally come, but &quot;after all, they are not family members. Many words cannot be said. Their family is decent people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A nearby chain -to -foot shop is regularly gone by nagbles Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli. The clerk called Shen Zongli as a &quot;big white rabbit&quot;, because he loves to eat big white rabbit toffee, and sometimes he eats several pieces at a time. Shen Ailun turned on the mobile phone shopping app. There were many large white rabbit toffee purchases, which were mailing to 2401. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The clerk called the &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot;: the nanny brought the big white rabbit, the big white rabbit&#39;s foot repair and nanny also repaired, and did the same project. When they paid, the babysitter paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This kind of nanny is rare,&quot; the clerk recalled the actions of the nanny Jiang Aizhen. Other families are often accompanied by their children&#39;s family. On the day of the reporter&#39;s interview, the 103 -year -old man was received by the niece, accompanied by a niece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Starting from the community, a few hundred meters apart in a shop, Jiang Aizhen sometimes takes the Lu Delin couple to eat.这次回国后，馄饨店老板曾私下告诉沈艾伦，“快把你家保姆辞了吧。”记者向老板了解，证实了这一点，“没见过别的保姆讲话这么凶的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;像卢德麟夫妇这样年纪的老人，在这个小区还有很多。桑城居委会工作人员告诉《南方人物周刊》，家属时不时来看望是普遍现象，独留保姆一人照顾则比较罕见。此前，居委会在闻讯后曾试图调解，但保姆没来，“保姆一直没有出现过。我们居委会也不能代表哪一级政府或者相关部门，不能强制传唤保姆到场，我们做不到，我们没有那个权力。还有就是，在保姆缺席或者不在场的情况下，我们也建议他们走司法途径，去法院或者公安报案都可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在该居委会工作多年的工作人员告诉《南方人物周刊》，平时碰到过保姆蒋爱珍，在打个照面的接触中，没有感受到“虐待”相关事情。但很多事情是关起门来的，没有谁会在大庭广众下去做怎样过分的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不会是个例。上海是全国老龄化程度最高的超大型城市。据2022年上海市老年人口和老龄事业监测统计信息公布的数据，2022年上海户籍的60岁及以上老年人口有553.66万，占户籍总人口的36.8%，其中，独居老年人为30.06万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是否被虐待、是否被骗，长达3年的“保姆管家”，直到矛盾大爆发、冲上热搜，很多邻居才在手机上看到这则消息。此前有的邻居曾在业主群看到过儿媳控诉保姆蒋爱珍的消息，而更多的邻居对此一无所知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中人物沈一南、沈艾伦、王维为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“清朗·网络戾气整治”专项行动启动，打击网络厕所、开盒挂人等行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;各省、自治区、直辖市党委网信办，新疆生产建设兵团党委网信办：&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;按照2023年“清朗”系列专项行动总体安排，中央网信办决定即日起在全国范围内启动为期1个月的“清朗·网络戾气整治” Special action. The relevant matters are notified as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一、明确工作目标&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;聚焦网络戾气容易滋生的重点环节版块，从严打击恶意攻击谩骂、挑起群体对立、宣泄极端情绪等突出问题，坚决惩治一批违规账号、群组和网站平台，有力遏制网络戾气传播扩散。 By carrying out special rectification, we will further consolidate the main responsibilities of the website platform, thoroughly identify problems and loopholes, improve the system and mechanism to prevent and control online violence, effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of the majority of netizens, and maintain a good online ecology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二、集中整治7类突出问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;专项行动围绕社交、短视频、直播等重点平台类型，坚决打击以下7方面问题：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1.“网络厕所”“开盒挂人&quot;Behavior. Create special BOT accounts, post bars, topics, groups, etc., and receive and publish ridicule, malicious comments, curses and insults directed at specific groups or individuals through anonymous contributions, remote shouting, etc. In the name of exposure and criticism, they maliciously &quot;open the box&quot; and &quot;hang people&quot;, publicizing other people&#39;s names, ID numbers, mobile phone numbers, home addresses, workplaces, personal photos, social accounts and other personal privacy information, inciting netizens to attack and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.借社会热点事件恶意诋毁、造谣攻击。 Spread rumors and slander relevant parties involved in emergencies, or edit and process pictures and videos that are seriously inconsistent with the facts, to induce netizens to attack and question the parties involved. Use the image of the parties involved in hot events to create and publish emoticons, and use AI software to synthesize fake pictures or videos such as vulgar pornography, bloody horror, etc., to carry out rumors, attacks, and slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.污名化特定群体、煽动地域对立。 Associate individual vicious social events and negative figures with gender, occupation, region and other characteristics, stigmatize and negatively label specific groups, publish gender-antagonistic, class-antagonistic, and regionally discriminatory remarks, carry out generalized attacks, and intensify social conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4.斗狠PK等低俗不良直播行为。 Online anchors use behaviors such as showing off their courage, fighting, drinking, and swearing to increase their followers and traffic. During other people&#39;s live broadcasts, they use functions such as barrages and mics to conduct personal attacks, and even encourage extreme behaviors such as suicide and self-harm. Make up scripts of violent conflicts such as fights and fights to attract netizens to watch and disrupt public order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5.有组织地恶意辱骂举报他人。 In the name of &quot;helping with work&quot; and &quot;relieving worries and anger&quot;, they provide paid scolding services and leave abusive messages and private message attacks on specific accounts. Organize fan groups to use the platform’s “reporting” and “anti-gangster” functions to maliciously report others in batches. Publish comments that provoke war and malicious hype in the fields of entertainment, sports, e-sports, etc., inducing fans to quarrel with each other and control reviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6.编造网络黑话、恶意造梗。 Through pinyin, homophony, pronouns, etc., maliciously fabricate vulgar memes and bad buzzwords to pollute the Internet atmosphere. Use obscene language and foul language to deliberately provoke conflicts and create conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7.煽动网上极端情绪。 Make up sensational post titles and publish &quot;venting posts&quot; that are made out of nothing and have no bottom line. Maliciously exaggerating the conflicts between teachers and students, exaggerating parents&#39; &quot;oppression&quot; and &quot;squeezing&quot; of their children, provoking conflicting relationships, and forming a negative direction for minors. Deliberately exaggerate negativity, anxiety and resentment, and spread hateful and antagonistic remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三、依法严惩违规账号、群组和平台&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;专项行动期间要坚持重拳出击，集中关闭一批严重违规、影响恶劣的账号群组，坚决取缔一批戾气聚集、&lt;/span>;问题突出的功能版块，从严查处一批履责不力、顶风作案的网站平台，形成有力震慑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.从严查处违规账号、群组、贴吧。 In-depth investigation of high-risk accounts and groups, resolutely ban accounts and groups with themes such as &quot;online toilets&quot;, &quot;opening boxes to hang people&quot;, &quot;inciting fights&quot;, etc., and seriously investigate and deal with anchor accounts that organize ruthless PKs and live broadcast fights , severely punish &quot;self-media&quot; accounts that publish &quot;clickbait&quot; content that deliberately incites online violence, close a group of circles, super chats, and post bars named with insulting words and where online violence gathers, and remove them from the shelves and provide paid compensation. Scolding merchants and shops waiting for services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.从严查处违规功能设置。 Strengthen the management of key functions such as live broadcast barrage, continuous wheat, and PK, and resolutely clean up and deal with violent content online. Centrally cancel a batch of functional applications that organize malicious reports in batches. It is prohibited to push &quot;online toilet&quot; accounts to users through functions such as &quot;Related Recommendations&quot;, &quot;TA Follows&quot;, and &quot;Potentially Interested People&quot;. Strengthen the review and management of emoticon packages, P-picture puzzles, video editing, AI synthesis and other functions, and clean up and remove emoticon packages, pictures and videos containing prank attacks, provoking confrontation and other content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.从严查处违规平台环节。督&lt;span>;促网站平台加强榜单、话题、推荐、评论、私信等环节管理，严禁在榜单、推荐等位置推送煽动、宣扬网络戾气的内容，通过设置“私信折叠”“消息盒子”等减少陌生人私信骚扰。 For websites, apps, and mini-programs with outstanding problems, punitive measures such as rectification within a time limit, fines, suspension of relevant functions, and shutdown will be taken in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四、细化工作要求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1.抓好部署推进。结合本地实际，制定细化实施方案，配齐配强工作力量，狠抓任务部署落实，视情组织对网站平台治理效果进行评估，督促做好整改落实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2.压实平台责任。指导属地网站平台全面排查问题漏洞，聚焦重点环节、版块和功能，深入开展自查自纠，完善内容管理机制，确保专项行动取得实效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3.强化宣传曝光。公布&lt;span>;专项行动启动、阶段性进展，重点平台每周公布典型案例。 Strengthen education and guidance, encourage netizens to actively participate in reporting and complaining, and jointly resist online violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;中央网信办秘书局&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年11月10日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马云继续减持，阿里巴巴刺向低价]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 15:30:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;阿里巴巴西溪园区。图片来源：阿里官网&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;阿里巴巴西溪园区.图片来源：阿里官网&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月16日，是阿里巴巴2024财年新季度业绩公布的日子，这一天，同步释出了这家巨头企业的诸多重要消息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马云继续减持阿里巴巴创始人股份；此前“1+6+N”分拆计划，部分按下暂停键，阿里云不再完全分拆；盒马上市同时暂停。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴面临着怎样的变局？此后的战略指挥棒将挥向何处？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;马云减持套现8.7亿美元&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月16日，阿里巴巴（BABA.NYSE）向美国证券交易委员会（SEC）提交了两份144表格，表示马云家族信托旗下公司JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited拟于11月21日分别出售500万股阿里巴巴创始人股份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照美东时间11月15日阿里巴巴87.07美元/股的收盘价计算，马云家族可通过此次减持套现8.707亿美元。 Alibaba&#39;s market value was about 221.75 billion US dollars on the day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;144表格，亦被称作“拟议出售证券通知书”。 SEC规定，若美国上市公司的董事、高管或大股东等在任意三个月内转让超过5000股或市值超过5万美元的上市公司股票，则必须填写144表格并向SEC申报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据阿里巴巴的美股招股书，在IPO之前，马云通过四种方式共持有阿里巴巴8.8%股份。其&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本人直接持有0.08%，通过注册在开曼群岛的APN Ltd公司和新加坡非营利机构SymAsia基金会各持有1.49%，及通过注册在英属维尔京群岛的JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited公司分别持有2.78%和2.95%的股份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马云在美股IPO中出售的股份同样来自JC Properties Limited和JSP Investment Limited两家公司，其在IPO后对阿里巴巴的持股降至7.8%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴2014年在纽交所上市以来，马云进行过多次减持。财报显示，马云的大规模减持始于2017年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，马云持股从7.8%降到7%，2018年降到6.4%，2019年降至6.2%，2020年降至4.8%，低于5%的披露红线。此后，阿里巴巴不在财报中披露马云的持股情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴曾回应，马云和蔡崇信会捐出他们所拥有的、总体规模为阿里巴巴集团总股本2%的阿里期权，用以支持环境保护、医疗健康、教育发展和公益ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年教师节，马云卸任阿里巴巴董事局主席。一年后，马云完成了其董事任期，不再是阿里巴巴董事会成员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年财报显示，马云仍是阿里巴巴合伙人委员会成员之一，其他五名为蔡崇信、张勇、彭蕾、邵晓锋及吴泳铭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴实行合伙人制度，由合伙人提名董事会的大多数董事人选，而非根据股份的多少分配董事席位。阿里巴巴现有28位合伙人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重注1688、闲鱼、钉钉、夸克&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;同在11月16日，阿里巴巴2024财年Q2业绩公布。阿里巴巴财年与自然年不同步，为每年的4月1日至次年3月31日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本季度，阿里巴巴营收2247.9亿元人民币，同比增长9%。净利润为266.96亿元，2022年同期则为净亏损224.67亿元，非公认会计准则净利润为401.88亿元，同比增长19%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“阿里巴巴集团本季度业绩稳健，多个业务展现出全新动能和活力，主动自我变革成效显著。”阿里巴巴集团首席执行官吴泳铭在业绩公告中表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本地生活集团收入同比增长16%至155.64亿元，由饿了么和高德业务的强劲增长带动，订单同比增长近20%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;菜鸟的收入同比增长25%至228.23亿元，主要由跨境物流履约解决方案带动。菜鸟在本季度面向8个国家和地区推出了全球5日达物流服务，包括头程揽收、干线运输、通关、分拣和最后一公里配送。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里大文娱在上季度终于扭亏为盈之后，赢面进一步扩大。大文娱集团本季度收入为57.79亿元，同比增长11%，主要归功于大麦网和阿里影业的线下娱乐业务，及优酷的订阅增长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月19日，阿里影业宣布收购大麦网。受惠于2023年暑假线下娱乐市场的复苏和强劲需求，大麦网本季度GMV录得三位数同比增长。 8月，大麦网携手优酷，为TFBOYS十周年演唱会的线下演出及线上直播合作售票。这场独家线上直播打破了优酷的线上付费演出纪录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而阿里影业联合出品的两部电影《孤注一掷》和《消失的她》位居暑期档票房前两位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月16日晚间，吴泳铭首次作为阿里巴巴集团CEO参加季度财报分析师电话会，他在会上介绍了阿里巴巴第一批战略级创新业务——1688、闲鱼、钉钉、夸克。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭表示，阿里巴巴对战略级创新业务的遴选标准为：具备足够巨大的市场空间；具备独特的市场定位；符合用户需求趋势和集团“AI驱动”战略。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战略级创新业务在组织上将以独立子公司的方式运营，业务上将打破以往在集团内的定位限制，用更独立的策略去面对广阔的市场。阿里巴巴集团将以3-5年为周期进行持续投入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夸克是阿里巴巴旗下的智能搜索App，钉钉是企业级智能移动办公平台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在阿里擅长的网络交易领域，1688是采购批发网，经常会与拼多多放在一起对比谁更便宜，闲鱼则是二手闲置转让平台，提高这两者在集团内的重要性，显示出阿里巴巴指挥棒向低价市场的倾斜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;阿里云分拆、盒马上市都要暂停&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴Q2财报还公布了各业务板块的分拆进展。令人惊讶的是，阿里云的分拆被按下暂停键。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5月18日，时任阿里巴巴集团董事会主席兼CEO、阿里云智能集团董事长兼CEO张勇宣布，阿里云智能集团将于未来12个月内从阿里集团完全分拆并完成上市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里巴巴在本次财报解释，美国近期扩大对先进计算芯片出口的限制，给云智能集团的前景带来不确定性。其完全分拆可能无法按照原先设想提升股东价值，因此决定不再推进其完全分拆，而是会面对不确定的环境，专注建立云智能集团可持续增长的模型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭表示，阿里巴巴集团将在阿里云战略方向上保持长期坚决的投入，同时云智能集团仍会继续保持独立公司运作方式，采取董事会授权的CEO负责制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月，彭博新闻社称盒马正在与中金、摩根士丹利等合作筹备上市事宜，准备来年在香港上市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但本次财报显示，盒马的首次公开募股计划暂缓。阿里并未解释原因。但这或许与盒马并不突出的表现有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本季度，阿里巴巴所有其他分部收入为48.052亿元，相较2022年同期维持平稳。所有其他分部包括高鑫零售、盒马、阿里健康、灵犀互娱、银泰、智能信息(主要包括UC优视和夸克业务)、飞猪、钉钉等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其他分部里，盒马、飞猪、阿里健康和智能信息的收入有所增长，但总体业绩也只是与去年持平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与盒马形成鲜明对比的是，菜鸟集团已申请在香港进行首次公开募股，并已向香港联交所递交了A1文件（上市申请表格）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴泳铭在电话会上称，菜鸟未来三年的核心策略，一是加快全球智能物流网络建设，抓住跨境电商快速发展的历史机遇，实现国际业务的快速增长，二是在国内坚持走差异化道路，输出科技能力，保持业务的健康发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：严厉打击倒买倒卖、伪造出生医学证明等违法犯罪行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:40:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国家卫生健康委高度重视出生医学证明管理工作，正在挂牌督办有关地方严肃核查处理贩卖出生医学证明等相关问题，已向湖北襄阳、广东佛山、广西南宁等地派出督导组，督促指导地方深挖彻查、回应社会关切、追究相关责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《出生医学证明》是依据《中华人民共和国母婴保健法》相关规定制发的法定医学证明文件，是公安机关开展新生儿户口登记的重要依据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家卫生健康委对于损害儿童权益、伤害群众利益、扰乱正常医疗秩序，特别是伪造出生医学证明的行为，将严厉打击、绝不姑息,发现一起，查处一起，积极配合公安机关打击倒买倒卖出生医学证明等犯罪行为，对涉案医务人员依法依规严肃处理。欢迎向当地卫生健康行政部门举报相关线索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，国家卫生健康委将指导医疗机构进一步健全完善内部管理机制和流程，并在全国开展出生医学证明规范管理专项检查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>