<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[为“被强奸”母亲讨公道的女儿丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cheng Haiyan in the old house. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1479ae442e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1479ae442e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cheng Haiyan is here Old house. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interviewing the suspected humiliation and suicide case of 44-year-old peasant woman Yi Yonghong in Wenchang, Hainan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; For details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/256716?source=131&quot;>;After eight days of struggling in the vortex of being raped, a 44-year-old peasant woman chose to commit suicide&lt;/a>;&quot; &lt;/span>;), after going through certain twists and turns, I was able to interview Yi Yonghong’s husband Cheng Shanzhi, and learned about Yi Yonghong’s experiences during his lifetime, as well as the hardships of this family who immigrated to Hainan from Hunan. But what I want to interview most is Yi Yonghong’s daughter Cheng Haiyan. My intuition tells me that this post-00s girl’s narration of this sad story should be more worth listening to. It turns out that this prediction was correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22-year-old Cheng Haiyan is the eldest daughter in the family. She also has a younger brother suffering from leukemia. She had just passed the college-to-undergraduate examination and was a freshman in Haikou. After her mother committed suicide by drowning, her grieving father fell into depression, and her younger brother was sick. As the only person in the family who had gone to college, she needed to support the crumbling family in a short time. She feels that the burden on her body is too heavy, and most of the time she carries it by force. &quot;I&#39;m very tired, but there&#39;s nothing I can do about it,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan deliberately stayed away from the extremely simple home in Wenchang, not only because of the poor material conditions of the rental house, but also because she had long recognized the old mentality of favoring sons over daughters in her family. So in addition to studying at school, she will use her spare time and holidays to work in Haikou, &quot;waiter, dishwasher, dishwasher, front desk cashier, banquet waiter, handing out leaflets, event security, militia for epidemic prevention, everything she can do.&quot; . From June 10, 2023, to the day of Yi Yonghong&#39;s suicide on July 23, Cheng Haiyan worked as a cashier in a supermarket in Haikou, earning 2,600 yuan a month, not including food and accommodation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan is also a good hand when helping the family. She bagged and packaged guavas, and could finish at least 2,000 of them in a day, which was equivalent to earning 200 yuan when working for other people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But fate played a cruel joke on Cheng Haiyan. She wanted to stay away from home, but she had to become the backbone of the family without her mother, the sister that her younger brothers could rely on, the daughter who made decisions and ideas, and she had to socialize with relatives as a junior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can clearly feel that although she knows that her mother worked hard and raised her up, Cheng Haiyan does not want to be a woman like Yi Yonghong. Maybe Cheng Haiyan doesn&#39;t necessarily know what kind of person she wants to be, but she is really trying not to repeat her mother&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong also supports her daughter in doing this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days before Yi Yonghong committed suicide, Cheng Haiyan returned to Wenchang to be with her mother. When she was taking a bath in the water room, a &quot;crazy male&quot; in the village put his head under the threshold to peek, muttering &quot;so beautiful&quot;. In panic, Cheng Haiyan hit him with her clothes and called the police, but the other party produced proof of schizophrenia, making Cheng Haiyan angry and helpless. The police told her not to take it to heart, but Cheng Haiyan couldn&#39;t do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her daughter was spied on, Yi Yonghong urged her to return to Haikou quickly. Cheng Haiyan still regrets that she was unable to bring her mother back to Haikou and leave that environment as she wished. If she had left, maybe she wouldn&#39;t have committed suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Throughout the interview, Cheng Haiyan recounted two scenes that were extremely cruel to her. One is the scene after Yoshinaga committed suicide in the reservoir. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Cheng Haiyan rushed home on July 23, she found that the door was locked and her mother was not at home. When she saw her mother’s mobile phone and wallet on the bed, Cheng Haiyan immediately panicked because her mother never Don’t carry your wallet with you. She and her father Cheng Shanzhi searched separately, calling her aunt and uncle while searching. Finally, she rushed over following her father&#39;s cry, &quot;I saw that my father had been crying and his clothes were soaked. My father was already there. I couldn&#39;t stop crying. My mother was so hard that she looked like she was sleeping, with her mouth open.&quot; At that time, Cheng Haiyan &quot;felt very hot, dizzy, dizzy, and couldn&#39;t see.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the whole interview, I think the most painful thing is that Cheng Haiyan recalled the second cold scene in a calm tone - in order to find new evidence, she was also afraid that her mother would be frozen for too long, and she hoped to be buried as soon as possible. , she and her brother decided to perform an autopsy on their mother. Cheng Haiyan stood aside, supporting her crying father, and witnessed the forensic autopsy and the funeral home staff suturing her mother. She wanted to see if there were any injuries on her mother&#39;s body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan mentioned a detail. Before the autopsy, a cockroach crawled out of Yi Yonghong&#39;s trousers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan was crying and picking at her fingernails. She said she didn’t know what to do and was very scared because it was her family members who were being dissected. She majored in nursing, so she could roughly describe the forensic workflow, including the path of the scalpel on Yi Yonghong&#39;s body, and the slight &quot;deformation&quot; of her mother under the scalpel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She left and was stabbed. I feel very sorry for her.&quot; At the same time, Cheng Haiyan was also extremely angry, &quot;I feel hated to the core of my bones.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the report was published, Cheng Haiyan was willing to give her real name. I believe that having experienced and dealt with such a major ups and downs in life, Cheng Haiyan will be stronger than she thinks she is. She was able to go to the police station with seven or eight veteran friends and decided to call the police after being spied on. She bravely questioned the police and confronted the perpetrators. Especially after witnessing her mother&#39;s anatomy, Cheng Haiyan was definitely no longer the little girl she used to be. Now, she will become a different person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老人如何安度晚年？“9073”意味着家庭养老仍是主流模式丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258844]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the &quot;Statistical Bulletin on the Development of Civil Affairs in 2022&quot; released by the Ministry of Civil Affairs shows: As of the end of 2022, 60 There are 280.04 million elderly people aged 1 year and above, accounting for 19.8% of the total population; of which 209.78 million people are 65 years old and above, accounting for 14.9% of the total population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing data from the previous year: As of the end of 2021, the country’s elderly population aged 60 and over was 267.36 million, accounting for 18.9% of the total population, of which 200.56 million were aged 65 and over, accounting for 18.9% of the total population. 14.2%. Within one year, the number of elderly people aged 60 and above and those aged 65 and above increased by 0.9 and 0.7 percentage points respectively. The former had a net increase of 12.68 million people and the latter had a net increase of 9.22 million. The aging of Chinese society has further intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two reasons for China&#39;s aging population. One is the increase in life expectancy; the other is the decrease in the number of newborns. In 2016, the first year of the implementation of the comprehensive two-child policy, there were 17.86 million newborns, which may be the last historical high. It dropped to 17.23 million the next year, and then broke through the one or two million mark every year. By 2022, it dropped to 9.56 million, a decrease of 46.5% compared with 2016, and it was almost halved in just six years. As a result, the issue of how to provide for the elderly has become more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Shanghai took the lead in proposing the goal of the &quot;9073&quot; elderly care service pattern, that is, 90% of the elderly will be provided with home care, 7% will be provided with community care, and 3% will be provided with institutional care. In April 2021, Wang Haidong, director of the Department of Aging and Health of the National Health Commission, said that most of the elderly in our country care for themselves at home and in the community, forming a &quot;9073&quot; pattern, that is, about 90% of the elderly care at home, and about 7% of the elderly rely on community support for their elderly care, and 3% of the elderly live in institutions for their elderly care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a 2023 survey by the Civil Affairs Bureau of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee Social Work Committee found that more than 99% of the elderly in Beijing choose home care, while less than 1% choose institutional care. It can be seen that no matter from the perspective of local and national elderly care strategies or from the actual situation, the overwhelming elderly care model for the elderly is still home care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that raising children to provide for old age has not become a thing of the past as some people imagine. From another perspective, raising children can also be regarded as an investment: not only will the children work when they grow up, they will transfer payments to their elderly parents and provide part of the pension funds; if the parents are seriously ill and need medical treatment and care, the children will be The role of women is irreplaceable: providing money, effort, and hands-on work for children is only one aspect; helping parents who are disabled or even mentally ill to advocate and defend their rights is also an important aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if you pay someone to take care of you, the elderly will have a higher probability of receiving better care if they have their own children with sound physical and mental abilities to supervise them at any time. When a disabled elderly person lies in bed at home and cannot move, the nanny hired has an incentive not to work as hard as he can. If he does not have his own children, it will be difficult for the disabled elderly person to advocate and protect his rights. Confucianism talks about &quot;being cautious about independence&quot;, which is a very high moral cultivation. It is difficult to require nannies or caregivers hired from the market to have such high moral awareness and professional ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, children may also be disobedient and unfilial, but there is an ongoing blood and family relationship between children and their parents. From a human perspective, if you don’t have confidence in taking care of your children and raising yourself, how can you have so much confidence in an outsider who has no blood relationship or feelings with you? This is a logical question as well as a human nature question. Moreover, if you are not confident in educating a child with normal values ​​and respect and respect for your parents, how can you have so much confidence in the retirement arrangements you designed decades in advance? This is also a logical question. Since we are talking about risks, we need to calculate the magnitude of different risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, many people work and live in cities and pay social security, which creates the illusion that &quot;they can provide for themselves in old age and do not need their children to provide for them.&quot; In fact, this pay-as-you-go social security model is essentially an intergenerational transfer payment from young people, workers and the next generation to the elderly, retirees and the previous generation, or &quot;all children support all parents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if we look at a single family, retirement care is not just a question of how much pension there is. No matter how much money you have, whether you hire someone to take care of you at home or live in a luxury nursing home, you must ensure that you can spend the money on yourself so that you can receive good care when you become disabled or even lose your mind. At this time, your sons and daughters, who are physically and mentally sound, are by your side to help you advocate and defend your rights. Their role is irreplaceable. If you have no children, and you have young close relatives with good nature, such as nephews and nieces, to act as children, or have close friends with deep feelings to help, then it is naturally possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investing in financial assets and saving money for retirement may seem like a good choice, but there are still the same problems that cannot be circumvented. When you are able to walk and move, you live in a nursing home because you can advocate and defend your rights, so you can get good care; but when you become disabled or even mentally ill, or you are conscious but unable to move in bed, or You are also unconscious and therefore unable to assert and defend your rights. Whether you can receive necessary medical and care services depends on the conscience of the nursing home operators and caregivers. Of course, there will be supervision by government agencies, but in terms of intensity and meticulousness, I am afraid it cannot replace the &quot;supervision&quot; of one&#39;s own children or close relatives or close friends who are good-natured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the above sense, it is not difficult for us to understand why home care and family care are still the main modes of care for the elderly. Behind this is still supported by the concept and practice of &quot;raising children for old age&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine Outside the emergency clinic, parents wait with their children. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ae8f944cdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254373&quot;>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 16, 2023, parents waited with their children outside the emergency clinic on the first floor of Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It’s mycoplasma again!” On October 16, 2023, Dr. Ding Guodong from Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine originally planned to see 30 special needs numbers in the morning, but he temporarily I added 10 numbers and it didn&#39;t end until one o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The doctors in our department are basically full every day, and the inpatient beds are also very tight. Some children may have to wait for several days before they can be admitted.” Ding Guodong is the deputy chief physician of the Department of Pediatric Respiratory Medicine. This overloaded work rhythm with my colleagues has started in mid-September. &quot;At this stage, almost 90% of the hospitalized children in the pediatric respiratory department are infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and there are many cases of drug resistance of Mycoplasma pneumoniae.&quot; . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae has a diameter of 50-300 nanometers, nearly one thousandth the diameter of a human hair. It is a microorganism between bacteria and viruses. Pneumonia caused by this microorganism is the most common community-acquired pneumonia in children aged 5 and above in China (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;refers to infectious diseases suffered outside the hospital Pulmonary parenchymal inflammation&lt;/span>;), mostly occurs in autumn and winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of the school season in September, not only Shanghai, but also hospitals in Beijing, Hebei, Jiangsu and other places have seen more children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and they tend to be younger. According to a CCTV News report on October 13, the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases has increased across the country recently, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae has entered the season of high incidence. Children need timely medical treatment and appropriate medication. &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;&quot;There are 246 people in front of you&quot;&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;Before four o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 15, Qin Nannan finally registered her son. At this time, a deputy chief physician at Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital The number has been queued to No. 556. While waiting for treatment, she discovered that someone had already received more than 800 numbers. Finally arrived&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[禁养名单、品种数、体高均有差异，数看15城禁养犬有何不同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258908]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Chengdu girl was bitten by a fierce dog incident&quot; once again triggered people&#39;s discussion on civilized dog breeding. Narada Big Data Research Institute combed through the management regulations and banned dog breeding regulations in the top 15 cities with GDP in 2022 and found that the list of banned dogs and the number of banned dog breeds are different in different places. Rottweilers are used by Beijing, Shanghai, Cities such as Guangzhou are clearly listed on the list of prohibited dogs, while Chengdu and Shenzhen are not prohibited. Moreover, many places have different standards for the shoulder height and body length of banned large dogs. Beijing requires key management areas to prohibit the breeding of aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult height of more than 35 centimeters. Tianjin, Wuhan, Hangzhou and other cities have mentioned bans on breeding. Violent dogs and dog breeds with a body height exceeding 45 centimeters. Nanjing, Suzhou and other cities have clearly banned the breeding of ferocious dogs, large dogs and other adult dogs with a body height (shoulder height) exceeding 61 centimeters as determined by the public security organs and veterinary authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/48466fe39e17ef0662e7a589ea8ea87c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1563&quot; height=&quot;3362&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/48466fe39e17ef0662e7a589ea8ea87c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254636&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;*Relevant management regulations for dog breeding in some cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Beijing, Tianjin, Hangzhou, Hanning and other cities&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Dog management regulations have not been updated for more than 16 years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;For In response to incidents of vicious dogs injuring people in cities, each city has now issued regulations prohibiting or strictly controlling dogs, involving dog vaccinations, registration, dog-raising behavior standards, etc., including the types of dogs that are prohibited. Among the 15 cities included in the statistics, each city has issued at least two regulations related to dog breeding management, involving dog breeding management regulations, animal epidemic prevention regulations, or regulations on the promotion of civilized behavior, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The review found that Tianjin has the largest number of dog-raising management regulations, including the &quot;Tianjin Dog-raising Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Tianjin Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot;, &quot;Tianjin Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot; 5 items including Tianjin Dog Registration and Dog Registration Management Measures&quot; and Tianjin Dog Breeding Epidemic Prevention Management Measures. Followed by Beijing and Chongqing, each with 4 items. Beijing has the &quot;Beijing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Beijing Dog Breeding Registration and Annual Inspection Management Measures&quot;, &quot;Beijing City Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot;, and &quot;Beijing Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot;; Chongqing has &quot;Chongqing Municipal Interim Measures for Dog Breeding Management&quot;, &quot;Chongqing Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;, &quot;Chongqing Municipal Animal Epidemic Prevention Regulations&quot; and &quot;Chongqing Municipal Civilized Behavior Promotion Regulations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dog management regulations are an important basis and specific reference for law enforcement in many cities. However, after sorting out the latest revision time or implementation time of some cities, it was found that among the 15 cities, Beijing, Tianjin, Hangzhou, and Wuhan Cities such as Beijing and Nanjing have not revised relevant dog management regulations for more than 16 years, and the longest has been 20 years. As early as 2017, the Hangzhou Municipal Urban Management Committee stated in response to a media interview that the revision of the regulations was included in the research project of the Hangzhou Municipal Government’s 2016 Legislative Work Plan. In 2018, the Nanjing Municipal People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee has revised the &quot;Nanjing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; and included it in the &quot;Nanjing Municipal People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee 2018-2022 Legislative Plan&quot;. In 2022, the 22nd meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Wuhan Municipal People&#39;s Congress will review the &quot;Wuhan Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations (Revised Draft)&quot;, but it has not yet been officially announced. Recently, relevant personnel from the Tianjin Municipal Public Security Bureau also revealed in interviews with the media that relevant departments are working on revising the &quot;Tianjin Municipal Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with other cities, the &quot;Chongqing Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; will be officially implemented on June 1, 2023. Previously, the 2008 version of the &quot;Chongqing Dog Breeding Management Interim Measures&quot; was implemented. Judging from the number of revisions of dog breeding management regulations in the 15 cities included in the analysis, Hangzhou and Suzhou had relatively frequent revisions. The latest revision of the Dog Management Regulations will be in 2022, and the previous revision was in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/66212136c002ea146d35a1cf91703f12.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1563&quot; height=&quot;2358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/66212136c002ea146d35a1cf91703f12.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254635&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Some cities have restrictions on the shoulder height of prohibited dog breeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rongshen has not banned Rottweilers&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Many places have banned large dogs with different physical standards and high standards&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt; p>;The Rottweiler that bit a girl in Chongzhou, Chengdu on October 16. The male dog’s shoulder height is generally 70-90 cm, and the female dog’s shoulder height is 65-80 cm. Generally speaking, it is a large dog breed (generally, the shoulder height of various places is 60 cm). Centimeters and above are considered large dogs), but the &quot;Chengdu Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; stipulates 22 types of aggressive dogs and large dogs, which does not include Rottweilers. In addition, in the Shenzhen Municipal Administration for Market Regulation’s announcement on the list of aggressive dogs, Rottweilers were not included in the list of banned dogs, but Rottweilers were banned in 13 other cities included in the statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nandu Big Data Research Institute found that in the above-mentioned cities that have promulgated dog breeding management regulations, it can be seen from the lists of banned aggressive dogs published in various places, and relevant notices or announcements about permitted dog breeding in key management areas. The rules governing dog ownership and dog ownership restrictions vary. For example, Beijing stipulates that in principle, small toy dogs with an adult height of less than 35 cm (inclusive) should be raised in key management areas, and breeding of aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult height of more than 35 cm should be prohibited; Tianjin has clarified that key dog ​​management areas must Raising small ornamental dogs with an annual body height of no more than 45 cm is prohibited. It is prohibited to raise aggressive dogs and dog breeds with an adult body height of more than 45 cm. It is especially emphasized that after dog registration, dogs with a body height of more than 45 cm will not be registered; Qingdao requirements Violent dogs not included in the regulations, hybrid dogs containing the blood of ferocious dogs, or hybrid dogs with a height of more than 60 centimeters are prohibited from breeding, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/fd48e977c4b8123be445b7e2553a9449.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1564&quot; height=&quot;2860&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/fd48e977c4b8123be445b7e2553a9449.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254634&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Number of dog breeds banned in 15 cities (unit: breed). &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The breeds of dogs banned in different places are different&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;There are more than 4&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;0 breeds of dogs banned in Tianjin, Beijing and other places&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;After sorting through the lists of banned dogs in these cities, we also found that the number of banned dog breeds varies from place to place. Among the 15 cities included in the statistics, the number of banned dog breeds in Tianjin reaches 49; Followed by Beijing, Qingdao, and Changsha, each have 40 types of banned dogs. In contrast, the number of prohibited dog breeds in Shanghai and Chengdu is relatively small, with only 21 and 22 respectively. It is understood that among the cities not included in this statistics, Shenyang requires that 48 types of dogs are not allowed in key dog ​​management areas, including 39 types of aggressive dogs and 9 types of large dogs; Jinan has made it clear that individuals are prohibited from raising large dogs, There are 56 fierce dog breeds, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the names of prohibited dog categories in these cities, there are also some differences in the names of prohibited dogs. Some use full names, and some use abbreviations. For example, Japanese Tosa Inu, some cities prohibit dogs. The only ones on the list are called Tosa Inu or Tosa Fighting Dog; Italian Twisted Boliton, some are called Twisted Boliton, some are directly called Neapolitan, and so on. Judging from the list of banned dogs in the 15 cities included in the statistics, it is impossible to find a single category of dogs with the same name or all banned dogs. However, Tibetan mastiffs, bull terriers, Newfoundland dogs, Central Asian shepherd dogs, etc. are generally included in the prohibited list, but there are always cities that are not included in the prohibited list. For example, Newfoundland dogs do not appear on the lists of banned dog breeds in Shanghai, Suzhou, and Tianjin. Due to the large differences in the number of dogs in different places, there are problems such as a certain dog breed being allowed to be raised in one place but prohibited in another place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, some experts analyzed that because the power to formulate specific dog-raising rules is left to the people&#39;s governments of provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, this is also the reason why dog-raising regulations vary so much from place to place. It is necessary to keep pace with the times. Policy follow-up, as well as continuous and active improvement of the operating mechanism of the policy system, more standardized management, will close the gap of inconsistent standards for the prohibition of violent dogs, and prevent the recurrence of tragedies of violent dogs injuring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[他们关心大山里的孩子，那么谁来关心他们丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On December 10, 2013, Naituo Village Primary School, the lighting in the classroom was poor and The temperature is relatively low and students have classes outdoors. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/628c28081f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/628c28081f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254426&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On December 10, 2013, at Naituo Village Primary School, the lighting in the classroom was poor and the temperature was relatively low, so students had classes outdoors. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2013, as a volunteer, I rushed to the Daliang Mountains. During a charity event where we took family portraits for fellow villagers for free, I met Wan Chaohui, a local volunteer teacher. He was 28 years old at the time, from Sanmenxia City, Henan Province, and a typical northerner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wan Chaohui teaches in Naituo Village, Sedi Township, Zhaojue County, at an altitude of more than 2,600 meters. Naituo Village Primary School was built in 1990. It has dark brown tiles and yellow-brown mud walls. It has been in disrepair for a long time. The walls are cracked. There are three large cracks. The widest one can fit into Wan Chaohui&#39;s fist. There are more than ten small cracks. , can fit into the child&#39;s fingers. The windows were sealed with plastic film to prevent the whistling mountain breeze from blowing in. There are three rooms, with the teacher&#39;s dormitory in the middle and first and second grade classrooms on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As school was about to start, the primary school’s flagpole was broken by a pig. Three boys carried firewood daggers on their backs and went up the mountain to cut a 3-meter-long bamboo pole and carry it back to school. Wan Chaohui tied the five-star red flag with nylon rope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 1, 2013, the first class started. Class starts at 9 o&#39;clock. Wan Chaohui gets up at 7:30 and wipes his glasses repeatedly with a tissue. Standing on the podium, Wan Chaohui took out the roster and called the names, but after calling several names, no one answered. Some children grinned and laughed, while others stared at him with blank expressions on their faces. They couldn&#39;t speak Mandarin. Wan Chaohui was so anxious that he circled back and forth in front of the blackboard. Finally, he called Brother Jida, the village party secretary, and Jida came to act as his translator. A class lasts 45 minutes, all of which is used for roll call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the adobe house of the primary school has been transformed into a brick building. The school has toilets and shower rooms, a kitchen and a cement playground, as well as new desks and chairs, basketball hoops, flag poles, Dormitory beds and wardrobes. Worried that the fellow villagers were illiterate, Wan Chaohui specifically asked the construction workers to draw two little figures on the toilet wall to help the fellow villagers differentiate between men&#39;s and women&#39;s toilets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I met Wan Chaohui again in 2019. At the Yi Torch Festival in June, the school playground turned into a playground for students to light torches. More than 20 children surrounded Wan Chaohui in the center of the circle. The torches were lit, and Wan Zhaohui and the students ran around the school holding the torches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the blink of an eye, ten years have passed since my teaching career. In July 2023, I met Wan Chaohui again. He is 38 years old and nearly middle-aged. Over the years, another main storyline of his life has slowly emerged: returning to the secular world, getting married and having children. At this time, a specific topic that had been discussed every time I met him in the mountainous area gradually became important: as a volunteer teacher, his monthly living allowance was less than 3,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2017, Wan Chaohui, who had stayed in Liangshan for 5 years, met his first wife after being introduced by a Yi friend. From the first meeting to the marriage certificate, it only took A week&#39;s time. The boys in the class acted as relatives of the man. According to the Yi people&#39;s habit of marrying a wife, the villagers helped kill two pigs; the girls in the class ran to the mountains to pick Soma flowers, put them on the classroom podium, and wrote &quot; Happy wedding”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the marriage, his wife opened a restaurant in Leibo County, and Wan Chaohui still taught in Gujue Village. The two places are 150 kilometers apart and it takes more than 5 hours to drive. Due to their different cultural backgrounds and living habits, their relationship has become increasingly estranged. In May 2019, the two divorced. In September 2020, Wan Chaohui married a local kindergarten teacher, and their child was born the next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After having a family and having children, I realized the reality of oppression, such as diapers, milk powder, rent, water and electricity and other living expenses.&quot; Once, &amp;nbsp;Wan Sitting in front of me Chaohui told all this calmly. He has wanted to leave the mountainous area and return to urban life many times, but he is worried about his 38-year-old age. &quot;Many employers clearly stipulate that they do not accept jobs over the age of 35.&quot; Speaking of his parents, Wan Chaohui also looked helpless and guilty, &quot;I only go home every winter and summer vacation. Sometimes I feel that I am quite unfilial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He belongs to a special group among the volunteer teachers, not the mainstream, but still worthy of concern. How should teachers who volunteer to teach and are willing to take root in the mountains for a long time stay here? So this short film &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256942?source=131&quot; title=&quot;Standing in the mountains for ten years, with a monthly salary of less than 3,000: A support teacher&#39;s mid-life crisis &quot;How to explain&quot;>;Standing in the mountains for ten years, with a monthly salary of less than 3,000: How to explain the &quot;mid-life crisis&quot; of support teachers&lt;/a>;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While filming, I happened to meet a group of new college students who came to teach. Some have returned from studying abroad and some have graduated from teacher training. Most of them plan to teach for one or two semesters before leaving the mountainous area and returning to normal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿奇霉素上热搜，广东儿科专家紧急提醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the topic &quot;azithromycin&quot; became a hot search on Weibo. At the same time, the increase in children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in the respiratory departments of many hospitals across the country has also caused concern. Huang Huarong, director of the Department of Pediatric Respiratory Medicine at Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University, revealed in an interview with Southern+ reporters that about 90% of the patients she currently treats have respiratory infections, and about 80% of them are Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;593&quot; height=&quot;457&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7115b1ec97e19569a54369be370a8827.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254629&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As for the use of azithromycin, Huang Huarong said that it is indeed the main drug currently used clinically to treat Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. However, there are many clinical types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. Therefore, it is not recommended to take it by yourself, let alone trust the so-called &quot;strategies&quot; on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is azithromycin the main drug for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, macrolide drugs such as azithromycin, clarithromycin, erythromycin, and roxithromycin are the most popular clinical drugs. The drug of choice for the treatment of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. New tetracycline antibiotics such as doxycycline and minocycline or quinolone antibiotics can also be used for treatment, but caution should be used in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, azithromycin is the main treatment drug for Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia. Take azithromycin once a day, with three days as a course of treatment. It will take effect quickly and relieve acute symptoms. In addition, azithromycin is convenient to administer, can take into account children&#39;s medication compliance, and is conducive to improving the therapeutic effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Under what circumstances is it more appropriate to use azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Patients diagnosed by doctors as having Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can be treated with azithromycin. Generally, patients with mild symptoms will experience relief after taking medications. But that doesn&#39;t mean azithromycin will always work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, different children may have heterogeneous manifestations such as different symptoms, different onset conditions, and different physical indicators. The choice of drug needs to be determined by the doctor based on the specific situation. For example, children with mycoplasma pneumonia are more suitable for treatment with erythromycin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, if severe symptoms such as persistent high fever, wheezing, shortness of breath, and difficulty breathing occur, it may be severe or cause other complications. At this time, just using azithromycin is far from enough. It needs to be combined with other drugs and other treatment methods for comprehensive treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, patients may develop unresponsiveness to macrolide drugs due to self-drug resistance, abnormal immune-inflammatory response, and mixed infections. That is, taking azithromycin cannot be effective, and other drugs need to be identified, added, or replaced in a timely manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can I buy my own medicine and take azithromycin? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Azithromycin is an antibiotic drug and is a prescription drug. It should be used under the guidance of a doctor. It is not recommended to take it by yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Clinically, there are many types of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in children, and parents cannot judge the type and condition of the disease by themselves. In particular, children&#39;s physiques are different from those of adults, and some children have an excessively strong immune-inflammatory response and their condition progresses quickly. If the drug is not suitable for the disease, the best opportunity for treatment may be missed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When using medicines for children, special attention should be paid to the safety, rationality and effectiveness of the medicines. The doctor will determine the dosage, course of treatment, usage, etc. of the drug based on the child&#39;s weight, physique, age and other characteristics. Only by rational use of medication under the guidance of a doctor can children recover faster and reduce complications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many parents are worried about the sequelae of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, children with Mycoplasma pneumonia who receive reasonable and timely treatment rarely have sequelae. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to avoiding sequelae lies in early identification and diagnosis of intra- and extra-pulmonary complications. Some children may have intrapulmonary complications such as plastic bronchitis, pleural effusion, and acute attacks of bronchial asthma, as well as extrapulmonary complications such as damage to the nervous system, circulatory system, blood system, and skin and mucous membranes, and require prompt medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/81d7fd3207a47ea4e51255fc378cd269.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254628&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern+:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for the prevention of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Huang Huarong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly spread through droplets, and the pathogen is carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing and runny nose. Try to avoid going to crowded closed places as much as possible, and wear a mask when necessary. Pay attention to washing hands frequently, ventilating frequently, strengthening exercise, and improving physical fitness. Children with the disease should pay extra attention to rest and improve their immunity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, people have been wearing masks for a long time, which has reduced the occurrence of respiratory diseases and also caused people&#39;s &quot;pre-existing immunity&quot; to various pathogens to deteriorate. This is also one of the reasons why there are more infections with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and various types of bacteria and viruses today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents find that their children have persistent fever, cough, headache, sore throat and other symptoms, they should seek medical treatment promptly and do not blindly abuse drugs. Do not relax your vigilance after receiving treatment. You must continue to pay attention to the child, pay attention to severe warning symptoms such as persistent high fever and difficulty breathing after treatment, and return to the hospital in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老无所依丨昼夜有时]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbbQAs4OG6XJf5uUgM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/KlNGGnxk06oKgMlZ29wO2uHbbQAs4OG6XJf5uUgM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图） &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快她这只河豚就“嘭”的一声瘪了。一副病恹恹、生无可恋的模样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起初她还会想着我们，为妹妹还没结婚和我没有孩子感到遗憾。住在大姐家时，她会嘱咐大姐请父亲过去吃饭。她怕他不懂得照顾自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来她就只能想自己的事了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她想要活下去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了豪猪枣，她还相信文东姜能治好她的胆囊癌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我真是幸运，这么巧看到这个。”一天，她给我看一则关于姜能治病的报道。她很快就找到附近一个卖姜粉的女人。那女人把文东姜磨成粉，然后装在胶囊里。母亲买了五六瓶姜粉胶囊，还送了我一瓶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后是红毛榴莲的叶子。我们在医院听说红毛榴莲的叶子有神奇的功效，有人用它煮水，喝了几个月后，癌症竟然痊愈了。于是父亲搜集了一堆红毛榴莲的叶子。他把叶子存放在她的裁缝铺里。一天又一天，在阳光下，它们看起来脆弱又苍白。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最荒唐的是父亲出的主意。他从依约带回来一份宣传册，声称自己遇见了灵气大师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;粉紫色的宣传册上印着一个中年男人的照片。男人身穿黑色中山装，不苟言笑，双手举在胸前，仿佛在推着一个隐形的东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一个温和的自然疗法，带出了您最好的身心灵。当健康发光，财富将增长。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宣传册上还有灵气疗法和灵气大师的介绍及“灵气受恩人”的见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲拎着一只水桶和几个空水瓶去大姐家。他和灵气大师约定第二天在大姐家替母亲治病。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你们就信我一次，就这一次。”他在电话里说道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不知道。”当我反复问母亲究竟怎么想时，她这样说道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许她不敢对父亲说“不”，就像从前那样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不知道啦。”从前她总是惶恐或不耐烦地这样说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果是我们这几个孩子拒绝了灵气大师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后两周，弟弟请假回家照顾她。那时的她已经无法走路。忽然之间她的求生意志又回来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我一定要好起来，要能走路，不能让阿祥抱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们买各种保健品给她吃。弟弟还带她去吉隆坡见营养师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“怎么拖到现在才来？”营养师说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们带回来一堆瓶瓶罐罐。我们也顾不上它们到底管不管用了。但很快她就吞不下那些药丸了。在她死后，弟弟把它们退还给了营养师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后她依靠吗啡存活。护士说吗啡是止痛药。在她难受的时候，大姐用注射器喂她吗啡，喂的剂量越来越大。医生能做的只是减轻她的痛苦。喂吗啡，抽腹水，吸氧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的求生意志是多么地强啊，不像我，动不动就想放弃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最后我也看不见那道光了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她离世前三天，在去东京的飞机上，我和她视频通话，发现她的双眼是如此地空洞。没有光，也没有忧伤。仿佛无动于衷的样子。她望着我，没有说话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“上帝爱你。我为你祷告。”我没有让她看见我的眼泪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我为什么会说出那样的话？那些我甚至无法确定自己真的相信的话。在教会里，这是那些中产阶级信徒说的话。现在我也和他们一样了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她眼神空洞地看着我，什么都没有说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她疲惫吗？恐惧吗？她在想什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后那几天，我们几乎是仓促地为自己的行为寻找解释。我们找到了“姑息治疗”，刻意回避了“临终关怀”这个字眼。我们不是在为她的死亡做准备，我们是在与她的疾病共处，而且共处时间可能会很长很长，我们这样安慰自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实是我们只能照料、陪伴和安慰她。我们只能看着她疼痛，看着她一点一点地消亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;医生比谁都清楚。他打电话给大姐，要她请亲人们到病房看母亲，“来越多人越好。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我脑海里突然浮现那句话——“有时治愈，常常缓解，总是安慰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的弟弟妹妹们来了。他们陆续赶来，坐在床边陪她说话。她的精神突然好起来，兴致高昂，说了不少话。那时候没有人想到也许那就是回光返照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在几天前，她还会忽然迷迷糊糊的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一天晚上，在电话里，她大声对我说她有五个孩子，还逐一说出他们的名字。然后她问我为什么她看不到她的孩子们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无啊。无看着啊。按怎无啊？”她用闽南语对我说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有啊。没看到啊。怎么没有啊？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我对她说很快我就会回去看她。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大姐告诉我她在挂了电话后才想起刚才和她说话的人是我。 “刚才那个是阿虹啊。”她喃喃自语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她最后的时光，尽管她的丈夫和孩子们轮流照看她，她还如愿以偿有了一个女佣（人们似乎喜欢以此判断一个人的晚年幸不幸福），她的光景、她的样子，她那张被我埋藏在心底深处的独自一人坐在病床上的照片，都总是让我想起“老无所依”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从始至终，她都在独自挣扎，独自背负她的苦难与孤独。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年前，她曾经问我“老无所依”是什么意思。她告诉我有个邻居说她和父亲老无所依，因为五个孩子中，有三个在国外，不在身旁。那个女人是当着所有人的面说的，那时他们正在附近的体育馆晨运。母亲记下了“老无所依”这四个字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，当我看《无依之地》时，心里想的已经不再是她。我想的是夏木和我自己。偶尔我会暗自慨叹，因为她和夏木的病痛，我被抛入到这样的运命之中，早早地就要直面遥远又未可知的将来。仿佛我们的未来已经来到。我们跌跌撞撞，有时无所适从，有时隐忍，有时不为所动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许我应该这样安慰自己，在最后一天，她没有悲伤，没有痛苦，反而有所期盼。凌晨两点，她从床上爬起来，对女佣尤妮说她梦见她的父亲了，她要回家了。她说这话时一点都不忧伤和害怕。她想回家，她一直想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白天她就离开了。她去了我们所不知道的地方。也许她以为自己终于回家了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《无依之地》里，杰西卡曾问那些车轮流浪者有没有想过自己的未来。希尔维安妮说她唯一能做的就是像《末路狂花》里的塞尔玛与路易丝那样，继续前进，开着车冲过断崖。艾丽斯说她的尸体将永远留在沙漠里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不知道母亲去了哪儿。我也不知道我们会去哪里。我们从来都不知道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《无依之地》还有另一个名字——《游牧人生》。很久以前，在课堂上，说起游牧民族时，老师说他们“逐水草而居”，哪里有水和草，哪里就是他们的家。这是不断寻找、试探与尝试的生活。人们就是这样活着的，母亲也是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[联合国“近东救济工程处”：“加沙正被推向深渊”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258857]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原消失的海滩女童事件：警惕海滩的各种“隐形杀手”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258910]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 16:12:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[碧桂园辟谣“创始人父女已离境”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258869]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678022701523769&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;da5905d728f643fbae16817a69ac3075-ld-nbv1.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/5619700d5576678022701523769/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/5619700d5576678022701523769/MLInLoiOiu0A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/5619700d5576678022701523769/MLInLoiOiu0A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;10月19日早，碧桂园发布声明称，公司关注到有谣言称“创始人父女或已离境”，该谣言被别有用心地发布在多个网络平台，造成恶劣影响。我司创始人和集团董事会主席目前在国内正常工作。此外，10月18日晚间，碧桂园官微发布推文称，10月17日，中国农业发展集团有限公司党委书记、董事长曹江林一行到访碧桂园总部考察交流，并与碧桂园控股集团创始人杨国强进行交流。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上级检察院如何调用下级检察官？ 告别程序争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258851]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/F1rLuuMtXWdBWiMsht0c1wkLK6ROo21DlVVvzOlj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/F1rLuuMtXWdBWiMsht0c1wkLK6ROo21DlVVvzOlj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2020年9月15日，在湖北省秭归县法院，出庭公诉的检察官对12名涉“套路贷”恶势力犯罪集团成员进行指控。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明明是来自区县的检察官，怎么代表市级检察院出庭支持公诉？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月15日，河南新乡中院召开一桩受贿案的庭前会议，来自北京的辩护律师王兴对其中一名公诉人的身份提出质疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，根据异地调用检察官（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;简称“异地用检”&lt;/span>;）制度，上级检察院可以调用辖区内下级检察院的检察人员，代表本院办理案件，亦能将被调用的检察人员，指派到其他下级检察院办案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，根据相关法律，中国检察官具有地域属性，履职的前提是经过属地人大常委会任命。比如，市级检察院想调用A区检察院检察员到B区检察院办案，应通过市人大常委会，先免掉此人A区检察院检察员的身份，再将其任命为B区检察院检察员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前实践中，上级检察机关往往不经过同级人大常委会，就直接调用下级检察院检察官。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;律师们的普遍感受是，当他们对异地调用的检察官身份提出异议时，检方或是置之不理，或以“受上级检察院和当地人大常委会的双重领导，所以上级院有权调用”为由作辩解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这一次，王兴对面的检察官态度明显松动了。其明确表态，会遵照新规解决身份问题，“如果等到开庭，当地人大常委会任命流程还没有走完，那么他在法庭上就不说话。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新规是指最高检于2023年9月5日印发的《关于上级人民检察院统一调用辖区的检察人员办理案件若干问题的规定》，规定明确了被调用检察人员若要以检察官身份履行出庭支持公诉等职责，需要依法提请本级人大常委会按照法定程序任命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一规定的出台，意味着学界、实务界围绕异地用检制度的“唇枪舌剑”告一段落。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“合法身份”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2022年12月28日，全国人大常委会法工委在2022年备案审查工作情况报告中，已对异地调用检察官要求“须经本级人大常委会作出相关任职决定”，并表示“已向有关制定机关提出研究意见，建议予以考虑”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后到新规出台的9个月内，已有部分地方检察院采纳了律师关于异地用检的异议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，王兴在四川省宜宾市检察院公诉的一起诈骗案庭前会议上，也遇到两名来自区县的检察官。检察官本想发表意见，但王兴直接和法官说：“不同意，没有解决（他们的资格）问题前，就不要让他说话，以免导致庭前会议无效了。”2023年4月19日，宜宾市人大常委会公开任命这两人担任宜宾市人民检察院的检察员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“靴子”落地后，西南地区一市级检察院检察官告诉南方周末：“新规出台了，（异地用检）原则上都要遵循规定，若不遵守，一旦律师提出检察人员的身份问题，检察院这边就会很被动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体而言，新规规定了异地用检的适用情形，即在办理涉案人人数众多、案情特别重大复杂，且办案力量难承担的案件时，上级院就可以统一调用辖区的检察人员。其中，既可以派上级院的检察官到下级院办案，亦可以把下级院的检察官调到上级院，或者调去辖区内的下级院支援。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最重要的是，新规规范了异地用检的调用程序。第七条规定，案件一旦办结，或者上级院终止调用，则按程序免去其前述检察员职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于一些例外情形，新规也有考虑。上级院的检察官被调用至辖区的下级院；或者上级院调用本院的分院、派出检察院的检察官至本院或者本院的其他分院、派出检察院的，就可以不履行检察官任命程序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位基层检察官向南方周末表示，在此之前，上级院的一张调令下来，他就得去同级的兄弟院办案，调用期限通常为3个月，他也知道“办案人员借调到别处，没有人大常委会任命，我其实是没有合法身份的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于人大常委会通常两月才安排一次会议，不一定能满足检察官的办案时效要求。新规给出的补救措施是，在当地人大常委会作出任命前，被调用检察官可以以检察官助理身份协助办理案件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在云南红河陈某涉嫌寻衅滋事等罪一案中，红河州检察院就一次性将6名调用检察官全部转为检察官助理协助完成庭审活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照最高检专家组的意见，检察官和检察官助理间的最大区别在于，宣读起诉书、讯问、询问、质证、答辩及发表出庭意见等重要的出庭职责，应由前者亲自履行；而后者只能遵照指示从事宣读证据、协助进行多媒体示证等补充性、辅助性工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;屡屡陷入舆论漩涡&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;全国人大常委会法工委备案审查意见公开前，“异地用检”近年屡屡陷入舆论漩涡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，内蒙古包头市王永明涉黑案让异地用检成为焦点。王永明案一审开庭时，辩护律师当庭举报一位公诉人涉嫌索贿。随后，该案经由内蒙古自治区高院指定管辖，转到乌海市乌达区法院审理。其间，内蒙古自治区检察院从全自治区调集18名检察官、检察官助理组成公诉团队。有质疑者提出，自治区检察院的检察官进入公诉人团队、出庭支持公诉的做法，会导致控审失衡，有违程序正义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与王永明案类似，安徽芜湖“谢留卿等63人诈骗案”中，检察机关也曾组建“公诉团队”出庭。因该案一审判决其中42名被告人无罪，芜湖市繁昌区检察院提起抗诉。2021年10月，该案二审阶段，检察院出庭人员名单在网上流传。公诉人中，除了芜湖市各基层检察系统人员外，还包括省内合肥市、铜陵市等检察系统人员，共计11名检察官、2名书记员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一做法引发极大争议，“异地用检制度是否合法合宪”再次被置于聚光灯下，成为有关部门不可忽视的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在王兴的印象里，一些重大疑难或涉黑案件中，异地用检很“常见”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;异地用检的演变，最早是从统一调用辖区优秀公诉人开始。最高检2005年6月印发的《关于进一步加强公诉工作强化法律监督的意见》中，提到“上级人民检察院根据办案需要,可以选调优秀公诉人或者业务骨干办理重大、复杂案件”。2011年，最高检又出台《关于调配优秀公诉人办理重大公诉案件的规定（试行）》，规定必要情形下，可以调配辖区优秀公诉人办案。2018年新修订的《中华人民共和国人民检察院组织法》正式以立法的形式明确异地用检制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在四川大学龙宗智、韩旭等多名法学学者看来，异地用检制度旨在满足检察办案的需求，一是因员额制改革后，有办案权的检察人员数量和过去比大幅减少，另一方面，随着大案难案及社会敏感案件屡屡出现，基层检察人员难以完成指控任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在清华大学法学院教授张建伟看来，这一制度的出台则是应对辩护形态新变化：重大、敏感案件，以及许多贪腐或扫黑除恶案件中，外地辩护律师介入增多，特别是知名律师担当辩护明显增多，需要各地检察机关以更高公诉水平加以应对；另一方面，律师组成团队，为涉案共同被告人辩护，打破了过去各为其主、各自为政的辩护形态，给基层检察机关带来很大挑战。为了提高公诉水平，应对控辩局面的新变化，所以检察机关采取调派精兵强将来承担公诉工作，从而保证公诉质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对异地用检的合理性，并无争议，分歧在如何调用，检察系统内部亦一直有希望细化规定的声音。四川大学法学院教授龙宗智在一篇文章中提到：2019年《人民检察院刑事诉讼规则》修订期间，许多省级检察院希望对统一调用的范围、程序及检察官的职责等予以明确。但拟制者认为,“从目前来看,对于具体如何调用还需要进一步总结经验。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/YvHZdv9yPLrNkeO1GlGgHfunUjzyC8A8h76MYB01.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/YvHZdv9yPLrNkeO1GlGgHfunUjzyC8A8h76MYB01.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;最高检于2023年9月5日印发《关于上级人民检察院统一调用辖区的检察人员办理案件若干问题的规定》。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;有不同意见&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在韩旭看来，异地用检新规的出台，与人大监督、学界发声和律师们提起审查建议不无关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢留卿案确定二审出庭公诉人的前一年，律师干卫东给最高检写了封信，一开头就援引了《人民检察院刑事诉讼规则》第九条第二款规定：调用的决定应当以书面形式作出，被调用的检察官可以代表办理案件的人民检察院履行出庭支持公诉等各项检察职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我以为这一规定既违宪，也没有上位法依据。”他在信中直白地写道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这么做，意味着检察官可以突破人大常委会的辖区任命去非任命辖区办案，直接破坏了人民代表大会制度。”干卫东告诉南方周末。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年12月4日，最高检12309检察服务中心向干卫东做了细致的回复，明确表示，上级检察院调用下级院检察人员办案时，的确可以走当地人大常委会的任命程序，但实践中往往难以满足办案需要，甚至导致办案超期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，有的地方检察长将被调用人员任命为本院的助理检察员，这一临时身份属于检察官，但无需由人大常委会任免。随着检察人员分类管理改革和检察官员额制改革的推进，助理检察员这一职务被取消，调用检察官异地履职成了问题。为了解决异地用检的合法性，在2018年修订人民检察院组织法时，明确规定上级人民检察院“可以统一调用辖区的检察人员办理案件”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩旭表示，无条件限制的“异地用检”并不具有法理上的正当性。但是，既然法律和司法解释从制度层面确立了该项制度，“异地用检要尽可能少地使用，不要成为常态，只能成为例外”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月11日，在谢留卿案二审期间，律师王兴和沈亚川向全国人大常委会提请对《人民检察院刑事诉讼规则》中异地用检条款进行合法性审查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建议中，除了涉嫌违反各级人大常委会任命检察人员的规定外，两位律师还提及，异地用检还存在违反刑事审判级别管辖原则、导致刑事诉讼法规定的回避制度无法执行等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在收到备案审查建议一年多后，全国人大常委会法工委在2022年12月28日公开的备案审查工作报告中回应了律师们的建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位了解内情的学者透露：“全国人大常委会法工委关于调派检察官需要人大常委会批准任命的意见出来后，是有不同意见的，但法工委坚持异地用检要经地方人大常委会批准任命。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;遗留问题如何解决？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;随着最高检的新规出台，异地用检的程序已无争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实务界现在最关心的问题是，对于此前没有按照全国人大常委会法工委的意见，已经调用了检察官办理的案件，该如何处理？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“两高”也留意到了这一点。2023年9月15日，最高检发布新规10日后，“两高”又联合发布了《关于上级人民检察院统一调用辖区的检察人员办理案件有关问题的通知》，明确提到，对已经生效的判决，若申诉人以被调用检察官未经本级人大常委会任命为由提出申诉的，不符合刑诉法规定应重新审判情形的，要说服申诉人撤回申诉；坚持申诉的，则书面通知驳回。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通知还规定，对于已进入二审程序的案件，二审法院则不得以被一审期间调用检察官未经本级人大常委会任命为由，撤销原裁、发回重审。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩旭仍有疑问：被调用检察官受谁领导和监督？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他注意到，有些被调用至异地的上级检察院检察官，可能比调用地检察院检察长的职级还高，如此一来，本地检察院检察长很难领导上级检察院的检察官。他调研过参与“异地用检”的检察官，在实践中确实存在“对于被调用到下级检察机关的上级检察院检察官，因其职级较高而不敢监督或监督松懈的情形”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有，当被调用检察官不适宜继续参与案件时，其回避决定又由谁作出？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新规中提到，在办理案件中发现被调用检察人员具有法律规定应当回避的情形的，被调用检察人员应当自行回避，当事人及其法定代理人有权要求其回避。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但按照刑诉法，检察人员的回避应当由检察长负责。然而，被异地调用的检察人员通常是由上级检察机关决定的。如此一来，被调用人员的回避，到底是由上级检察机关检察长还是由调入地检察院检察长决定？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张建伟的观点是，因为调用往往由上级检察院决定，如果在调用的环节，出现检察官需要自行回避的情形，那么就是“谁调派，谁决定回避”；但如果被调用人员已经开始代表具体案件所属的检察院办案时，“出于办案效率的考虑，那么回避的问题就该由办案检察院的检察长作决定”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于未来有关部门会不会针对异地用检出台更详细的司法解释或相应规范，曾挂任最高检副厅长的张建伟表示对此有所期待，但目前还未听闻相关计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>