<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国产科幻剧，走向成熟的一次试错]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259515]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&quot;Mist Theater&quot; under iQiyi, Because it has produced a number of high-quality suspense dramas, it is highly praised by drama fans. Although there are occasional mistakes, the black texture and suspense atmosphere are in place, so that the series overall remains above the passing line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the new work &quot;The Bionic World&quot; launched by this column has attracted a lot of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1919&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd58ebed2554817389f53751808c24f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255883&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; &quot;The behind-the-scenes team is not bad. Chief director Chen Zhengdao has been quite active in recent years, and has directed film and television dramas with good reputations such as &quot;Love Is Delicious&quot; and &quot;Future Summer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1573&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/471722ecbc53445f4d068223ecef7c21.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255882&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other two Directors - Ke Zhennian and Xu Zhaoren, also have excellent works. The former&#39;s &quot;Silence&quot; directed in 2020 is a topical work focusing on the sexual assault of disabled people; the latter&#39;s &quot;Lifetime&quot; directed by Douban has a score of 8.9 , drama fans rushed to get into the trap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Weilong&#39;s good looks and Wen Qi&#39;s smart temperament also make &quot;The Bionic World&quot; look good. Coupled with the blessings of Liu Lin, Liu Dan and other veteran actors in the industry, it is difficult to let People believe that this drama will be so popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; is a science fiction theme. The background of the story is explained at the beginning of the series. In the near future, humans will make rapid progress in gene editing technology and create bionic people that are almost the same as humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;510&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/931322c2cf6df05f504e735eb747e9a4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255884&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only difference The reason is that the bionic person is implanted with an &quot;initial obsession&quot;, either to become a lover until death, or to become an obedient and sensible child. Only through special medicine can the unique eyes of the android be tested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3aef049b4f80dd281e3d9ab1d640eef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255887&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bionic human The large-scale appearance triggered a series of extreme events, forcing countries to change their strategies and recall the androids for processing. The only one with the ability to investigate and identify the identities of androids is the &quot;Bright Eyes&quot; organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main content of the series tells the story of the male protagonist Cheng Nuo, played by Song Weilong, who, as an investigator with &quot;Bright Eyes&quot;, continues to detect criminal cases related to androids. As a result, the series uses six unit stories to present the joys and sorrows between androids and ordinary people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d18b765ab70f48cab8152caa9e825840.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255886&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In narrative mode In terms of gameplay, it is similar to &quot;Crime Hunting Illustrated Book&quot; and &quot;Gate of Rebirth&quot;, using the protagonist&#39;s special skills to connect one strange case after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The undercurrent of the series is that androids encounter serial murders. During the investigation, Cheng Nuo also discovered that the case was related to his mother&#39;s accidental fall from the building, thus uncovering a shocking secret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simply speaking from the human tragedy reflected in each case, &quot;The Bionic World&quot; is remarkable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7928f4ed33e730c2e4fb5ca03e72b3c6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255885&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Played by Liu Lin Chen Xinhui, the mother of Chen Xinhui, lacked company for her son Fang Yuan, so she ordered a bionic person who looked exactly like herself to take care of her son when she was busy at work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I didn’t expect was that Chen Xinhui’s harsh attitude toward Fang Yuan was seen as malicious harm in the eyes of the androids. The latter began to deliberately imitate Chen Xinhui&#39;s speech and behavior, and eventually replaced Chen Xinhui and even imprisoned her in the basement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ed9902970e8c08b7afc15da444992380.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An accident, Chen Xinhui escaped from the basement and wanted to take her son back from the android, but she died at the hands of the android during the fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fang Yuan, who had been kept in the dark, finally realized that his mother, whose temperament had changed drastically, turned out to be a bionic person. In order not to lose this &quot;other mother&quot;, Fang Yuan asked Cheng Nuo and others He lied that he accidentally killed someone and the victim was an android. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradoxical case at the beginning of the chapter depicts Chen Xinhui&#39;s helplessness and desolation as a mother, Fang Yuan&#39;s struggle and loneliness as a son, and the kindness and extreme of the android as the middleman, all of which are tragic and moving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;463&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7198c3c26c616e055741ff27eb2369a6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255888&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Lin is here This person plays two roles without being overstretched. She skillfully grasps Chen Xinhui&#39;s psychological changes of being cold and then angry, and the personality differences of the android who is first calm and then crazy. Although her appearance is short, she leaves a deep impression on people. impression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emotional touch brought by this unit story is also reflected in the touching family bond between the bionic little girl and her adoptive parents, and also in the sweet romance between the lonely sailor and the bionic lover, but in the end In a story that ends in tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/2c9a2a556aeba45da6db1641c5f1b996.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255889&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course it is Domestic dramas are good at producing many popular dramas. It&#39;s just that &quot;The Bionic World&quot; only focused on forcing tears, forgetting to solidify the foundation of the science fiction setting, and also went out of its way to foreshadow suspense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a science fiction drama, in addition to the future background explained in the beginning, the persuasive style of the main film is close to that of modern urban crime dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting place inside the &quot;Bright Eyes&quot; organization is like a simply decorated office; the crime scene outside the city looks like a shanty town waiting to be demolished. It may seem excessive to use the &quot;cyberpunk&quot; style of &quot;Blade Runner&quot; to ask for it, but using slightly softer science fiction dramas such as &quot;Relative Universe&quot; and &quot;The Handmaid&#39;s Tale&quot; as comparison objects can fully highlight this The show&#39;s perfunctory attitude in setting up scenes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/7a42a0253179c920aab4f67ca67eafab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255891&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you zoom in to As for the details of the science fiction setting, &quot;The Bionic World&quot; also has many flaws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie &quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot; with a similar setting, we glimpsed the tragic experience of robots through Spielberg&#39;s lens. Discarded after use, they are slandered as murderers, treated as garbage, and put on the execution ground for humans to vent their hatred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Bionic World&quot; explains the smuggling activities in a few words, and in less than ten minutes of transition, it hints that ordinary people consume the flesh and blood of bionic people. But these pitiful black corners are mostly vague and obscure, unable to provide us with a clear perspective on the unknown world of bionic people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;445&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/0640ad6575323f3b716e67858042940f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255892&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you look If you don&#39;t understand the suffering of a group of people, how can you fully sympathize with and treat each other with compassion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it bluntly, the science fiction setting is just a certain strategy of &quot;The Bionic World&quot;. It uses elements that are extremely rare in domestic dramas to try to explore the human nature motif that has been repeated many times. This also explains that this drama is not only inconsistent in terms of science fiction, but also extremely difficult to grip people&#39;s hearts in the suspense section. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine An Qiu, played by Cheng Nuo and Wen Qi, investigates the serial murderer of androids. During this process, Cheng Nuo gradually discovered An Qiu&#39;s true identity, and the latter was gradually lost under the brainwashing of similar androids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/9fa39f3949d4688ae37ac9e055c55bbb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255893&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Nuocong An investigator who was prejudiced and jealous of androids finally revealed his true colors and turned into a gray figure who had accidentally killed androids. We can hardly see the changes in his personality and the contrast between before and after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Song Weilong&#39;s slightly immature acting skills prevent him from grasping the details delicately; on the other hand, there are problems with the plot setting. The arrangement and revelation of suspense rely too much on the villain Yin Tianhong played by Li Hongqi in the climax. Part of it is talking to myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for An Qiu&#39;s transformation from a seemingly ordinary psychologist to the most critical role in the whole drama, it was also revealed too early and too hastily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/afd4d7660d48d6afe60bd8f86db16bc4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth At the end of the episode, which is also the middle part of the whole drama, we learned the answer to the mystery from the rivalry between An Qiu and Yin Tianhong. Even in many scenes before this, An Qiu&#39;s true identity was clumsily revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You must know that the two biggest mysteries in &quot;The Bionic World&quot; are that Cheng Nuo accidentally killed someone and An Qiunai is a bionic human. These two mysteries involve the emotional tearing of the male and female protagonists, and also reflect the subtle complexity of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ed929dc9f100b6aa2d32f0b58009de0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the final Judging from the presentation effect, the reconciliation between Cheng Nuo and An Qiu is more like a &quot;love trick&quot; without the profound speculation brought by science fiction settings such as bionic man and initial obsession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The science fiction works of domestic film and television dramas have begun to show their talents. Whether it is the movie &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot; series or the live-action series &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, they are all outstanding works recognized by the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quality of &quot;The Bionic World&quot; is indeed poor, but I prefer to regard it as a trial and error for domestic science fiction dramas to mature. After all, without enough &quot;The Bionic World&quot;, how could there be more mature &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot; and &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小镇阿姨们想象着法国织的毛线比基尼，真的到了法国]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259464]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIygYcmW1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O7eoYOJsmylGZtTu62RB7REoLUC90XiaIyg YcmW1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255441&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2023, Hu Yinping went to Paris to participate in the Paris Internationale Art Fair (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;International Paris Art Fair &lt;/span>;), this is her third exhibition in France for Xiaofang’s art project. The piece she brought this time was a knitted woolen bikini, which came from the aunties in the small town in Sichuan where she grew up. Since 2015, Hu Yinping has been customizing wool fabric products from her mother and aunts in her hometown in the name of the fictional French company agent &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;. Nowadays, the aunts imagine a woolen bikini woven from an ocean in France, and finally arrived in Paris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this small Sichuan town, the &quot;French company&quot; is the source of imagination for the aunts. They selected their own yarn at the Xiaofang base, mostly green, and initially knitted hats of various shapes. They appeared in the exhibition hall on the Champs Elysées, at the anti-Trump parade in the United States, and at Ireland&#39;s &quot;Cuckold Festival&quot;... …Later, the fabrics became more and more diverse: “Dirty Word Shock Wave” (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;weaves out the curse words that want to scold bad people&lt;/span>;), Pork Shop Aunt The &quot;pig intestines&quot; weaved by each family, the flags of their respective families, and the &quot;banana peels&quot;, &quot;dogs&quot;, and &quot;cactus&quot; weaved to protect the family in the face of danger... In between the busy farming and taking care of the children , these aunts weave their understanding of life with wool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lEhg8qys4Ttx8DUc49utRHStOBvCmPe9XDs1Yqnp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255437&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Snow White Dove&quot; Paris Bikini Exhibition&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &quot;Stop it when it&#39;s good.&quot; In 2016, after Hu Yinping completed the first hat exhibition of Xiaofang&#39;s art project at Beijing Arrow Factory Space, a friend advised her because she was worried that the project would lose money. Hu Yinping graduated from the Sculpture Department of the Central Academy of Fine Arts with a master&#39;s degree. She used the income from sculptures sold as &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; as a commercial sculpture artist to subsidize Xiaofang&#39;s production. The original reason for all this was that she wanted to collect her mother&#39;s time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Hu Yinping returned to her hometown in Sichuan and saw that her mother was packed up by two large bags of hats in a year and purchased at a low price. She wanted to buy her mother&#39;s hat, but her mother refused. After returning to Beijing, she asked a friend to play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; and made up the identity of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; as &quot;the Chinese CEO of a French company&quot;. &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; would come forward to buy her mother&#39;s hat at a higher price. She knitted hats as she pleased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are no secrets in the town. The aunts in the town found Hu Yinping&#39;s mother and wanted to join the production of Xiaofang&#39;s project. In the 1990s, silk cutting was once a way for aunts in the town to make money to support their families. After experiencing collective layoffs from state-owned silk cutting factories, most of these aunts became the eliminated urban surplus labor force. Now knitting wool is a way for them to pass the time and earn pocket money. The way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now the Xiaofang project has expanded to more than fifty knitting aunts, including &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, &quot;Snow White Pigeon&quot;, &quot;Security&quot;, &quot;United Nations&quot; and &quot;Standard Configuration&quot; and other five stages of different years. Proposition creation. Behind the creation lies the complex work of the artist. In sharp contrast to the work utopia created by Hu Yinping, is the cruel art market with clearly marked prices that artists face. Until now, the aunts still don’t know the origin of this “French company”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/LT7q0TrkhxvWAsXZeC8f8crHUii9urnoWrVGYZky.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Yinping&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Hu Yinping&#39;s account: &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The aunt is very happy, the artist is very tired&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will be happier every time I go to Paris to organize an exhibition. Because Xiaofang’s project itself has something to do with France. Every time we have a project, we tell the aunties that the French company needs orders, invite the aunties to make it, and then pay the corresponding fees. This French company has always existed in the hearts of the aunties. At the beginning of production, we told our aunts that there was a beach in France and we were going to do a woolen bikini show on the beach. They imagined a beach and made a set of woolen bikinis for themselves and their families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang has a lot of such exchanges and work internationally. This French exhibition is aimed at There are more professional art professionals, corresponding to a large number of curators and museum directors. I also hope that Xiaofang will enter into a deeper and more international exchange and dialogue. To the public, Xiaofang may be a relatively warm story, but to me it is a very specific work. Behind Auntie, our entire team works very rigorously and professionally. Everyone can enter and understand this work in any way of their own, but it itself is the background of contemporary art works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The knitted works of the aunts are all placed in my warehouse in a village near Beijing. Aunts are very happy, but artists have a harder time. Xiaofang&#39;s team of six people needs to handle a lot of specific and trivial tasks. The aunties don&#39;t care. The time for their weaving is not fixed. They choose the threads and take them home to make them, and get some fees from it, whether it is to make money, kill time, or the so-called &quot;thinking&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before I called you just now, I was in contact with the art museum about the transportation and goods for this exhibition. Shan, to integrate all the work of Auntie, we need to do some very specific and serious work. In fact, the workload is quite heavy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For Xiaofang&#39;s project, there are too many times when the economy cannot sustain it. Yang Xiaofang spends every year It costs a lot of money, and I rely on selling sculptures of &quot;Qiao Xiaohuan&quot; to support Xiaofang, but last year it started to feel a bit flat. After Xiaofang had an exhibition in Shanghai last year, many people may have known more about Xiaofang. Last year, she actually made a profit of 800 yuan. If it could recycle itself, there would be no need to raise it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now Xiaofang’s new project is to open Xiaofang Bank in a shopping mall in Nanjing. Xiaofang&#39;s works themselves are extremely public. In addition to the dialogue in exhibitions in art museums and galleries, what feedback and possibilities it has when facing the real public is extremely important to us. Because the crowds faced by art museums and galleries are actually screened, but in shopping malls they face the real public and reality, without the protection of an incubator. The concept of this bank is that I hope that the banks of the future will be made of wool, I hope that the currency of the future will also be made of wool, and I hope that the weapons of the future will also be made of wool. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before the 1990s, the entire society was lacking in materials, and wool, as a craft of aunts, could make people The family was fed and clothed, and now the value of the wool had changed. Why are there so many people knitting now? When I held an exhibition in Shanghai last year, some people told me that they would do a lot of knitting during the epidemic. Small fabrics can actually bring you a lot of surprises and feedback, because handiwork itself has healing properties. What you exchange for time is a thing, which is an exchange of the most primitive labor force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s exhibition, I met a girl who imagined her belly when she was pregnant Knitting shoes and clothes for children. I met a diplomat in China who was making some woolen fabrics during the COVID-19 pandemic. She thought she had made an ugly mouse and an ugly little snake. When this silver-haired lady talked about her fabrics, she was as shy as a little girl. I like these things she made so much. , and can feel the warmth and healing in her heart. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang’s hat has a lifetime warranty. I don’t want it to break after I buy it back. hole, you just throw it away, which is a pity for manual labor. No matter what projects Xiaofang does in the future, it will always include the function of &quot;filling holes&quot;. We will also open hole-filling to the surrounding communities for free, hoping to form this kind of community. It’s not that we throw something away when it’s a little bit broken. I think we all do too much about abandonment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 510&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/riaaGVd4DuZUol0kkbugCr2XbQ9VVw91lGTBWkmH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Auntie knitting bikini&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Surplus labor force in the city, remaining time in the town&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In order to protect my eyesight, most of the wool I gave to my mother was is green. Because green hats don’t have a good connotation in the Chinese context, the aunts still had some doubts when they used green wool to knit various hats. Later, VICE (a new media in the United States) wanted to do an interview for Xiaofang&#39;s art project, and helped find a place to buy cuckolds - St. Patrick&#39;s Day in Ireland. The traditional color of this holiday is green, and ordered a lot of cuckolds for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Ireland, these people wear hats to participate in festival gatherings, and the aunties also see those live photos. very happy. The same thing may have completely different meanings in different cultural backgrounds. I also hope to help aunties realize that the world is very rich. But I think it is more important for them to be happy and make free choices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I returned to my hometown in 2015 and was timid about being close to my hometown. Because I don’t go home very often, I want to know what my mother does on a daily basis. When she placed two large packages of hand-knitted hats in front of me, I realized, oh, she had knitted these two large packages this year and had been purchased by others at a low price. Moreover, the raw materials are too hard on the hands, and the threads are very hard and extremely rough. She doesn&#39;t have the pleasure and happiness of knitting. She just kills time, and this is the only reason left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I think it’s better to collect it myself, but my mother won’t let me, so I invite friends Help me play the role of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; of the French company, ask her to make hats, and let her do whatever she wants. In 2015, WeChat was not so popular, and my mother did not have access to WeChat in her hometown. However, because she had to work with &quot;Xiaofang&quot;, WeChat became a work skill that she must master. Because of her work, she learned to surf the Internet and send express delivery. In the past, my father&#39;s name was written on the express delivery because of &quot;Xiaofang&quot;. Later, when she sent express delivery, she always wrote her own name on the express delivery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/x3FSl3sG3xKOWQPoibqOSdDBEyCe3TBRGPK6EPjf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, we have conducted research on the aunts who participated in the Xiaofang project. Almost all of them are eliminated urban surplus laborers. Women who work in cities are easily eliminated after the age of 55. Work as a delivery person or cleaner in the city. After a certain age, even if you are a nanny with many years of experience, it may be extremely difficult to find a job in a big city after the age of 55. This is the problem faced by these aunts in the process of urbanization. It is very common in the town for aunts who are almost in their fifties to return to their hometowns because they cannot find jobs. They take care of their children. Those with better financial conditions open small shops and knit with wool to earn pocket money in their free time. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since the appearance of &quot;Xiao Fang&quot;, the aunts have stopped knitting things for other places. In fact, the aunts all have their own jobs and things. Some aunts will definitely not be able to take care of making our things when the farming is busy. They only plant rice and harvest several times a year, with long idle time in between. Some aunts take care of their children at home. After school is free time. There are also some aunts who have their own small shops. When there is no business, she can do Xiaofang&#39;s business. Xiaofang actually fills up the remaining time of the aunts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In Xiaofang&#39;s third stage &quot;Security&quot;, the aunt at the pork shop first imagined Not sure what to knit. We would guide her step by step. When she was at her busiest, Xiaofang called her and said, &quot;If someone were to rob your pork shop at this moment, what kind of weapons would you use to protect yourself and yourself?&quot; Benefits?&quot; She was holding a large intestine in her hand and said that if he tried to rob me, I would throw the intestine to him. This is a very direct reaction. When she is not busy, we will repeat her own words to her and encourage her to knit this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;About Xiaofang, everyone is discussing the aunt&#39;s imagination, which is actually the artist&#39;s imagination supporting their work. Aunts are a group without imagination, but they can be guided. All they have to do is face their true selves and their own lives. I actually know what they are doing every time, but I am still surprised when I see what comes out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, Xiaofang sent me those hat packages made by my mother on weekends. I was very surprised every time I opened the package. This kind of surprise has never happened again. As I was very familiar with my mother, I suddenly discovered that she had a skill that I didn&#39;t know about. I knew that she had always been making hats, but I didn&#39;t know her. It was all fancy and messy and made so many fun things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The aunts still don’t know what’s going on behind Xiaofang. In fact, it’s not that clear whether they know or not. It&#39;s important because they don&#39;t care about it that much, but I don&#39;t want my mother to know. Some time ago, my mother went to Beijing and stayed for nearly two months. We emptied the entire studio of fabrics, leaving not a single yarn. My mother couldn&#39;t stay after playing for a week, so I asked &quot;Xiao Fang&quot; to come to the studio to give her some work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Actually, on my mother&#39;s side, I haven&#39;t given her too many themes. What I collected is not Representational fabrics, or requiring her to use her brain, did not require her to do so. I wish to collect a period of my mother&#39;s life. I want her to be more free and not want her daughter&#39;s business to become her business, which would be too tiring for her. It&#39;s good for her to live for herself. At this age, she should live for herself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moyQ2yFfHGz3h68l0on1SaaOqBZ7o6kpFHIpGGfV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;Frozen time, undulating waves&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 1990s, my mother and the aunts in the town were Work in the town&#39;s silk-cutting factory. But China&#39;s textile industry also underwent a major reshuffle in the 1990s. At that time, a large number of laid-off workers were formed, including my mother and aunts. Silk cutting means that after the cocoons are cooked in a high-temperature machine, the silk is separated one by one, and the eight silks are wound into a thread. The finished silk is finally shipped to other places. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The machines in the factory are always rotating at a constant speed, and people are changing. My mother is on this assembly line. Go to work. My childhood was spent sitting on the big machine in that factory. The aunts would change jobs. One would feed me a bite when eating, and the other would feed me a bite when eating. My entire childhood to elementary school was spent in that atmosphere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of familiarity between people and people is very good, and it is a very important memory for me , later Xiaofang had so many aunts involved, and I felt the familiar intimacy that I felt at that time. When I was a child, my mother’s workplace would give out various benefits, such as a thermos cup and some washing powder. I think this is very good and will make family members have a sense of recognition for her work. We keep this in Xiaofang. got this. In the past few years, we have distributed almost everything to aunties, from cups to fruits, washing powder, pots and pans to all small household appliances. Recently, because winter is coming, we have I bought a lot of quilts for my aunt, and now I don’t know what to give them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I held Xiaofang’s exhibition at Arrow Factory Space for the first time, my friend advised me to “see you soon.” Just take it.&quot; This suggestion is very sincere. As a friend, I advise me to stop the loss in time. But to me, this is not a work. To me, Xiaofang is a very real life scene between me and my mother, so it is not something that I can just accept, even though I know it will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/cLjTtqDH1TivdZIMNvYJXlVO1BGvhJyPtLxcRTBm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiaofang Universe Bank&quot; Nanjing exhibition scene&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the beginning, we all knitted them casually, and I worked hard to collect them. Later I found out that this was wrong. No matter how big a warehouse I rented, it wouldn’t be enough for these dozens of aunts to weave. If they make it, you have to pay. After paying, you have to help them sell the fabrics. Selling requires talent, and I don’t have it. With this talent, how many hats can several art museums sell? This is so cruel. We mainly work in the studio and rarely understand the operating rules of this world economy. In the process of Xiaofang, it was also interesting that we participated in this kind of work very realistically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiaofang&#39;s work is still a very important part of my life. Because actually, for an artist, ten years can produce a lot of works. But Xiaofang and I have a growing relationship together. Xiaofang is implanted into my aunt&#39;s life, and at the same time, she is implanted into my mother&#39;s life and my life. I have also calculated an account. For example, if I make other things, I will also pay the money to the factory and the production unit. But when I pay the aunt, it does not actually form an internal cycle of the art system. Investing this part of the expenses on my aunt, I think, is investing on my own people, which makes me happier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Next month we will go to Mexico to set up an exhibition. Xiaofang has achieved so far, and there are so many reactions from the audience. Some people like it, and some don&#39;t. I&#39;ve used that metaphor from the beginning to now, I&#39;m a toothpick and I&#39;m also an observer. The aunties are jellyfish. I poked the jellyfish with a toothpick, and the jellyfish swayed in different postures in the sea. Whether it is criticism, praise, interviews or exhibitions, they are all part of the butterfly effect in the sea. My job is to watch these reactions and their postures after taking the plunge. Regardless of the posture of the jellyfish or the waves and waves produced in the sea, in my opinion, it is an extremely beautiful thing because it reacts. , rather than something inherently conservative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;未来，我希望有很多人像那位驻华外交官一样给我看她的作品。我希望大家不要羞涩，勇敢面对自己，手工东西真的不存在丑陋，都是极度有质感的存在。我想重新定义毛线，我想重新定义小芳的文化属性。我现在主要在做这样的工作，也在持续推进。其实艺术家大部分时间都是在台下很安静地工作，至于被看到或是不被看到，引起什么样的反应和讨论，都是很外在的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;四川是个盆地，我们镇上那边有一条河，它跟中国所有的小镇一样，非常凝固的人群，非常凝固的时间。小镇上就是那么点人，但阿姨们想象着一个法国公司，去做这样的事情。我是觉得这个事情本身挺酷的，那个盆地里有一群阿姨一天到晚都在胡思乱想，然后又一本正经地去做她们胡思乱想的工作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违反一事不能二罚？TST庭秘密何以“脱罪”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259519]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/CYLszOgZEkf9sfTtZJimAURqgDipmPMe5iWOlRwx.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255901&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年10月，张庭与林瑞阳出席活动。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（TST庭秘密官方微博截图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月26日，TST庭秘密位于上海的总部来了一群人，她们是来自马来西亚、新加坡的代理们，“我们终于回来了”，有人激动地在社交媒体上宣布。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，早在8月24日，“大哥”林瑞阳就录了一段视频，宣布“我们的案子终于结案了，而且是非常正面的结案”，他提高了声调有些激动，“结案之后，大哥相信会有更多的人认为，他们本来就是这么好的公司。”他很抱歉这两年让大家受委屈了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到10月26日，中共中央政法委机关报《法制日报》主办的《法治周末》报道称石家庄裕华区法院已经作出民事裁定，宣布解冻他们名下96套房产及6亿元现金，这个消息才广为人知，之后林瑞阳两个月前在小红书上发布过的那段视频才冲上了热搜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据南方周末记者获得的民事裁定书，这96套房产均位于上海市浦东新区江耀路28号，即庭秘密总部。根据上海市房屋管理局的公开资料，这是他们2020年花了17.6亿元购买的，那时TST成立四周年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林瑞阳曾是台湾艺人，后与妻子张庭共同创办了微商美妆品牌TST庭秘密，这个品牌过去一直遭到涉嫌传销的质疑，直到2021年4月，石家庄裕华区市场监督管理局以涉嫌传销为由，向法院申请冻结了TST庭秘密关联公司的巨额财产，外界才确认其因涉嫌传销遭到了调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;眼下，在TST庭秘密一方看来，案件的结果给它正了名。那么，它到底有没有涉嫌传销？为何法院会解冻他们的财产？南方周末记者拿到的多份文件，给出了答案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;确有传销&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;TST庭秘密有没有传销？ The answer is yes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一份来自湖北省保康县市场监督管理局的行政处罚决定书，给出了清晰的答案：“保康县市监局认为……当事人针对红卡会员执行的奖金制度，要求被发展人员发展其他人员加入，形成上下线关系，并以下线的销售业绩为依据计算和给付上线报酬的行为属《禁止传销条例》第七条第（三）项&#39;下列行为，属于传销行为&#39;”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里的当事人正是TST庭秘密品牌的所有人上海达尔威贸易有限公司，法定代表人林吉荣，这正是“大哥”林瑞阳的真名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份行政处罚书的落款日期是2021年9月3日，也就是早在两年前，TST庭秘密就已被认定为传销，并受到了处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照国家相关法律规定，传销分为两种情形，一种是经营性传销，另一种是诈骗性传销。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经营性传销由市场监管部门根据《禁止传销条例》给予行政处罚，只是违法行为，如果没有吊销营业执照的处罚，接受行政处罚并整改合规之后仍可继续经营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诈骗性传销则是一种严重的犯罪，属于刑法中的组织、领导传销活动罪，要由检察院提起公诉。两者最主要的区别在于是否有实际的经营活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份行政处罚书显示，TST庭秘密属于经营性传销，认定的传销行为发生在上海达尔威贸易有限公司自2018年1月1日至2021年7月，没收违法所得并进行罚款，同时要求“限期改正”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，改了就能继续经营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年2月，TST庭秘密向保康县市场监督管理局提交了一份《关于恳请对上海达尔威贸易有限公司产品销售制度的整改情况进行指导评价的申请》，里面详细列明了自己的整改措施，认为“整改后的产品销售制度完全符合通常的商业惯例，不存在团队计薪的奖金方式，应不属于《禁止传销条例》规定的禁止情形”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者对比了整改前后的两份奖金制度，2021年4月的版本和2022年2月的版本，发现其中最大的差别是没有了团队计薪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奖金都分为三部分：一是销售折扣奖金，二是批零差奖金，三是自媒体教育推广奖金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是表格名称，过去叫“庭秘密经销商奖金制度-红卡”，后来更改为“庭直播会员折扣表”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;销售折扣奖金对应到新表中，就成为了“折扣”，差别并不大，这部分是个人业绩的提成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;变化比较大的是折扣差，也就是过去的“批零差奖金”，这部分是团队业绩的提成。比如，团队共卖出了10000元业绩，其中2000元是团长自己卖的，这部分按个人业绩提成，剩下8000元要和下级按照一定比例分配，这部分就是团队计薪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整改后的新规是“会员与其直属会员对应销售折扣的差额，在平台或系统以积分或代金券的形式积累，最终由公司制定兑换规则，在一定期限内兑换产品或抵扣购买金额（2%-24%不等）”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去以团队业绩按比例提取的“自媒体教育推广奖金”，如今变成了“推广服务费”，推广服务费增加了领取条件，要求“会员本人直播产品业绩大于0”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前这部分以团队业绩为计算基础的推广服务费，比例在4%-5%之间，现在都统一为3%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过整改后，庭秘密认为，“庭秘密销售业绩提成仅与直接关联的上级会员产生，均为一次性奖励，没有传递”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份整改报告也得到了当地监管部门的回复，表示“我局将及时组织有关人员进行研究”，之后TST庭秘密都在正常经营。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;一事不能二罚&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;也正是因为湖北省保康县已经在2021年5月25日对TST庭秘密进行了调查，使得2021年6月5日才立案调查的河北省保定市裕华区市场监管局陷入了被动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中华人民共和国行政处罚法》有明确的规定，一是“在先管辖”，二是“一事不再罚”，同时《工商总局关于进一步做好查处网络传销工作的通知》也明确了网络传销案件的管辖，有管辖权的机关对案件适用全案管辖的原则。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这一点上来说，管辖权到底归谁，是两个市场监督管理局首先要解决的问题。从后续的发展来看，湖北省保康县没有放弃自己的管辖权，立案四个月后就作出了处罚，TST庭秘密的整改也在2022年2月完成了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真正让此案广受关注的是，2021年12月23日，石家庄裕华区市场监管局以回复查询函的形式对外宣布，“因其利用金融机构转移或隐匿涉传资金，我局已依法申请人民法院采取保全措施”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终这一申请得到了裕华区法院的支持，冻结了TST庭秘密的96套房产和6亿元现金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份冻结财产的法院裁定书受到业内质疑。该案代理律师杨帆在社交媒体说，“裕华区市场监督管理局申请法院保全怎么会是民事裁定书？裕华区市场监督管理局至今一年没有作出任何行政处理决定，怎么可以在行政机关查办案件过程中去申请法院保全？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该案另一位代理律师、行政法学教授何兵也在社交媒体公开质疑，“这是民事诉前保全，还是诉讼保全？诉前保全只有30天，诉讼保全更不可能，当时和现在无人起诉，市场监督局不可能做原告”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石家庄裕华区市场监管局在接受上游新闻采访时则表示，该局成立了专案组，参与调查的执法人员达四百多人，“目前来看属于经营性传销，是否具备诈骗性传销特征还在调查”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到2023年7月26日，河北省石家庄裕华区人民法院作出了民事裁定书：“县、市级工商、市场监管部门查处网络传销案件，应在立案前或立案同时逐级报备至省级工商、市场监管部门。现该报备已撤销，本院对本案涉嫌网络传销资产继续实施保全措施的条件已不具备”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位参与本案的知情人士向南方周末记者解读了这段文字，他表示，“这里用的是撤销而不是撤回，意味着备案可能是被上级部门撤销的，而不是裕华区市监局的主动撤回。撤销报备之后，不排除后续较有可能会撤案处理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这位知情人士看来，按照《中华人民共和国行政处罚法》“一事不再理”的原则，如果裕华区市监局认为保康县已经生效行政决定认定的违法所得有误，则涉及行政行为的纠正，必须提请有权机关依法定程序予以撤销。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得关注的是，保康县的行政处罚书中给出了TST庭秘密的真实经营数据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;处罚书显示：2018年1月1日至2021年7月，TST庭秘密共发展会员约700万人，其中蓝卡会员约641万人，红卡会员约65万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;违法红卡主营业务收入约为91.7亿元，主营业务成本约为56.4亿元，主营业务税金及附加约为3744万元，实际发生的有关费用约为34.58亿元，所得税费用1046万元，获利约1927万元，上海达尔威贸易有限公司的获利应当认定为违法所得。最终处罚是没收违法所得1927万元并罚款170万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海达尔威贸易有限公司最后一次登上上海青浦区百强企业榜是在2019年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月，由于石家庄裕华区市场监管局的相关回复流出，张庭和林瑞阳都因为涉及传销，遭到了微博禁言，至2022年5月26日，张庭的微博再度更新，表示“达尔威公司遇到法律纠纷，寻求法律保护，充分证明达尔威公司尊重并相信祖国的法治环境”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奥纳·泰德斯：从朋克主唱到新晋画家]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv33dwOWYW8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/M5PEK9Zqmrdwlpq3WJEolkTcZ4PVGsv33dwOWYW8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（艺术家及泰勒画廊Gia Coppola/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在成为画家之前，奥纳·泰特斯（Honor Titus）是一支朋克乐队的主唱；在成为朋克乐队主唱之前，他是一位作家兼诗人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个路径或许可以颠倒过来再说一遍：因为奥纳·泰特斯是一位作家兼诗人，朋友问他:嘿，反正你写诗，为什么不干脆来替我们写歌词呢？于是，他成为朋克乐队Cerebral Ballzy的一员。接着，又因为乐队一炮爆红，知名艺术家雷蒙德·帕提伯恩（Raymond Pettibon）成了他们的粉丝，并为他们设计了其中一张专辑的封面。雷蒙德问奥纳：嘿，我喜欢你的歌，你为什么不来我的工作室帮忙呢？于是，奥纳成了雷蒙德的助理，在熟悉了艺术工作室的一切运作之后，他自己拿起了画笔，并且再一次，一炮爆红。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/wRIs9h63HVnEDSnKteQlhyBXor9w2yLe8a6Xcn2O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“奥纳·泰特斯：观赏距离”展览现场，2023年，Longlati经纬艺术中心，上海&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Longlati经纬艺术中心/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;亚洲令人兴奋&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;无论用什么顺序听这个故事，奥纳无疑都是令人羡慕的幸运儿。他几乎刚刚画出了第一幅像样的作品，就被泰勒画廊相中，带到纽约参展，他的画以并列之姿，与大名鼎鼎的亚列克斯·卡茨（Alex Katz）的作品挂在了一起。市场的反应也令人兴奋，虽然他是初出茅庐，没有任何成交记录做背书，但超过20位重要藏家都表示要入手此画。他也在他的画和卡茨的画中看到了相似之处：明快的色彩，简洁的轮廓线，平涂的笔触，“看到他们把我和卡茨挂在一起，我意识到人们是理解我的创作的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;的确是一幅令人眼前一亮的作品：一对男女以悠闲之姿休憩在落满花瓣的草地上，女人背对画面，看不清面部，男人就像南部雅痞那样穿着西装戴着巴拿马草帽，仰面躺倒，整个画面洋溢着一种怀旧的闲适，令人联想到修拉的《大碗岛的星期天下午》以及马奈的《草地上的午餐》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gaYOgkQcj7NCl425bcguB0rX24d8cbS2cSBmJoPX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《金贝拉》，2021年，布面油画，121.9cmx152.4cm 私人收藏， 图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我试着一边写这个人，一边听他的歌，三分钟后，已经被震耳欲聋的喧闹吓得关掉耳机。我意识到，画画的那个奥纳，跟作为乐队主唱的奥纳，也许是同一个人分裂的不同面相。他画面里流露出来的那种沉静、疏离，甚至古典，在他的朋克音乐里不见端倪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新近在上海Longlati经纬艺术中心的奥纳个展《观赏距离》，是他来到中国的第一场个展。在此之前，他刚刚结束了在高古轩的展览，亚洲令他有一种格外的兴奋，“两年前我有一幅画在拍卖会上，最终以估价的五倍成交，藏家就来自亚洲，这让我感受到了东方对我作品的接纳度，我也很好奇中国的观众会怎么评价我的画。”他的画面会令人不由得联系到印象派的气息，可能就源自那种二维属性——在这件事情上，正是日本的浮世绘深刻影响了印象派，而中国的水墨画又深刻影响了浮世绘——一条文化的隐线，让观看中的似曾相识成为可能，也提醒着这种观看上的距离。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;两位贵人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;是雷蒙德·帕提伯恩把他引进了绘画的大门，对奥纳来说，在雷蒙德工作室工作的那几年是他生命中“信息爆炸”的时光，雷蒙德是综合型的艺术家，他1957年生于美国，兼容了诸多美国标志性文化元素，尤其擅长将图像与文字融合在一起。文学、艺术史、哲学、宗教、政治、商业、时尚、体育，离经叛道的青年亚文化都是雷蒙德的灵感来源，这种庞杂极大地影响了奥纳。雷蒙德从没教他如何画画，却常常与他讨论文学，“雷蒙德有一个藏书室，几乎是小型图书馆，他常常从中抽出经典的小说，跟我谈论其中的故事。”威廉·布莱克、普鲁斯特、约翰·罗斯金和沃尔特·惠特曼……文学性构成了雷蒙德的视觉修辞，也深刻影响了奥纳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/8uYgnmSlVfIHSOEOD2IM55hztNR7Kjo48EFaSRTk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《AP的快乐》，2022年，布面油画，182.9cmx121.9cm Danjuma收藏，图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是在雷蒙德的工作室，奥纳得以接触大量的绘画经典。他发现自己对包括皮埃尔·博纳尔在内的纳比画派有兴趣，那种强调轮廓和色彩、取消透视的风格，天然降低了技术门槛，赋予素人画家一块简要而干脆的敲门砖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥纳在绘画上的另一位贵人是同样生活在洛杉矶的著名艺术家亨利·泰勒（Henry Tylor）。泰勒擅长描绘人物，活跃而高产。“之前有媒体把亨利·泰勒形容成我的导师，但他其实只是我的挚友。”亨利·泰勒在自己的工作室里为奥纳举办了一场展览，那是奥纳作为艺术家的第一次亮相。当时正值美国新冠疫情暴发，现场几百号客人挤在亨利的工作室中，来宾中的画廊主马上决定把奥纳的作品带去纽约，“那可真是一场轰动。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;852&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3spC5kJ7sm0AnHOTstxjpylLqCYuCEoK895VcZGC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《潜入湛蓝》，2021年，布面油画，214cmx183.5cm David与Indre Roberts收藏。图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;小说式绘画&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;得益于一双写作者的眼睛，奥纳最感兴趣的是人。在中国街头的每分钟，他都在观察四周的人群，见缝插针地学说中国话。他乐于画人，运动中的人、华服盛宴的人、闲栖而孤独的人，他固定了人在特定情境中的某个瞬间，而那个瞬间本身是带有叙事性的。当他流连在美术馆，也总是那些关于人的绘画紧紧抓住他的目光，比如霍珀或者安迪·沃霍尔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;跟那些平时积攒视觉资料、擅长摄影或速写的艺术家不同，奥纳的画面是小说式的，他喜欢画他脑中虚构的影像，胜过临摹生活中真实的瞬间，他的灵感也常常来自音乐或文学。“我画过一幅迈尔斯·戴维斯（Miles Davis）骑马的画像，纯粹是我设想出来的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;768&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v1ALTKi3JPH8Ma62koQLTw1QG3Ho1RuykZMp03mD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《道奇大厅的夏天》，2021年，布面油画，152.4cmx182.9cm Rony &amp;amp; Orly Grushka收藏, 图片致谢艺术家和泰勒画廊&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传奇音乐人迈尔斯·戴维斯是美国爵士音乐史上杰出的指挥家和演奏家，但后来一度陷入嗑药和破产，与困境缠斗。“迈尔斯从小在圣路易斯的绿色乡野间长大，还是个孩子的时候就会骑马，后来他来到纽约，进入朱莉亚音乐学院，经历了艰难的岁月。”奥纳画的迈尔斯，在纽约的中央公园策马狂奔，那是他心目中的画面，而绘画，就是要创造那些本来可能并不存在、但艺术家坚信其存在的画面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对奥纳来说，绘画是一场意外的成功，给他带来财富和一种全然不同的人生经历，但这延宕了他成为一个作家的理想。音乐、绘画、阅读、写作……他像个跳格子的人在不同领域之间跨跳，带着一种谐谑的身手敏捷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“接下来还想画什么呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“五年内要写出我的小说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么样的小说？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“绝不是自传，我希望是菲茨杰拉德和塞林格会写的那种小说。时候到了，我就会写的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特朗普用自己的音色讲普通话：AI正在取代配音、口译与英语老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259492]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我姐是专业语音工作者，之前在广播电台工作了近三十年，从事播音员、主持人等工作，现已退休。专业技术人员，很难界定退休概念，一般都是退而不休：广播电台建培训学校，请她去教播音、主持课；相关专业比赛请她去做评委、主持节目；商业机构请她配音、作广告……曾经整天忙忙碌碌，如上班时一样充实，挣得比退休金还多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但现在，基本真退休了，各种活计越来越少、劳动报酬越来越低。前些年每次劳务报酬在1000-1500元左右，后来降到500，再跌到每次200-300元。前些天，购物网站问：每条20-30元的商品广告播音，接不接？她感到身心俱疲，这个真没啥意思，算了，不去抢年轻小姑娘、小伙子们的生意了，自己好歹有退休金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我看了最近的AI配音，深感震惊，告诉她：不是你抢年轻小姑娘、小伙子们的生意，也不是有人抢你的生意。而是你们在AI的进击下，基本全要失业了。好在老姐还有退休金，那些寒窗苦读十几年、播音专业的年轻人，该咋办呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在的AI配音，能做到（在算法端）智能翻译、避免无厘头的低级错误；（在音频端）模拟对象音色、声线，赋予其口语表达性格特征；（在视频端）修正口型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结果是：霉霉、特朗普竟然用非常标准的中文说话了，而蔡明的小品则用英语表演。而且音色非常像他们本人所发出的，甚至特朗普所说的国语还可被设定为稍带南方口音的普通话。不仅声音可以假乱真，在视频方面，他们的口型被修得与所说语言高度吻合，要非常仔细观察，才能发现在很少环节有视频修改的痕迹。以现在AI发展速度估计，或许一年以后，这点微弱的修改痕迹也难以被发现了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在智能翻译方面，Animato公司推出的基于ChatGPT的智能交互式聊天系统Call Annie，已应用于苹果12以上的平台。其一推出，就造成了美国的教育平台Chegg的股价暴跌50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Call Annie不仅是聊天软件，而且是全AI教育系统。目前，其可提供英语、法语、德语、西语等大语种语言服务，且教学内容涵盖数学、物理、化学、生物、编程、金融等各学科专业知识。可以预料：在未来1-2年时间内，Call Annie很可能会发展到覆盖人类各种语言，包括大部分小语种甚至方言，其所能提供的教学内容将呈几何级数式增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更厉害的是：Call Annie不用约课、目前免费、24小时陪聊，而且不会像人类老师那样感到疲惫、烦躁、愤怒、需要下班，其更有耐心、态度好，也不批评和训斥，即便我基础很差、智力愚钝，其依然不厌其烦地教学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在如此强大的AI进击之下，估计很多语言老师、基础知识类教学老师、翻译，甚至大学的助教……只要是非原创研究类教授，都会面临被淘汰危险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如此强大的AI，仍在日以继夜地进化，我睡去时，其仍在学习、迭代、进步……不知是应该继续称其为“它”，还是得准备改称其为“他、她”了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI的进击，对人类现有工作的挑战，不是即将到来，而是“狼”已经来了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IBM最近表示：将暂停招聘未来几年可能被AI所取代的职位，大约2.6万个工作岗位。在未来5年时间里，这些职位30%将被AI和自动化取代，将涉及近8000人的工作，这只是IBM一家公司啊！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月，《Fortune》（财富）调查：美国1000家企业，其中48%正在逐步使用ChatGPT替代人类员工，这将涉及数万名白领的工作和生计。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高盛分析师Ben Snyder表示：“在未来10年里，人工智能每年可能将生产率提高1.5%。这可能会使标普500成份股公司的利润，在未来10年增加30%或更多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不光是美国，国内的各行各业，也受到了AI冲击。2023年4月，大批游戏公司原画师被裁员，有的公司甚至裁掉了超过半数的原画师。而自由职业者单次绘画的劳务报酬，从1500元降到200元左右。我们在之前的文章中预测：工艺美术类设计师将逐渐失去工作，仅仅是一年多之前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内知名广告公司“蓝色光标”全面停止文案外包，改用AI写稿。有电商公司创始人，用3个月培训GPT写带货文案，替掉了7名员工。部分淘宝商家已使用AI生成的数字模特，换掉真人模特。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，我姐失去了曾经的专业语音工作内容，并非个案，而是这时代大背景下，千百万专业技术人士的共同大命运中一个音符而已。AI的进击，已经从工程技术领域、发展到视觉艺术产业，再扩展到语言与表演艺术方面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就连百度前总裁陆奇都说：现在每周都有个脏话时间，就是被技术震撼到忍不住飙脏话。因为ChatGPT出现后，AI技术是以天为单位快速发展，在AI浪潮冲击下，无论理工科还是文科、艺术类，无论是基层生产人员，还是专业技术人员、行政人员，甚至到高管，无人能置身事外。科学和技术的发展，将会把人类未来推向何方？这恐怕已经超越了我们现有的认知能力和思维框架。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生态环境部答南周：对碳排放数据弄虚作假“零容忍”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 28/f7ffc589d7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255859&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 27, 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment held a regular press conference. Liu Youbin, spokesperson of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, said that the theme of this conference is to actively respond to climate change, promote green, low-carbon and high-quality development, and release the &quot;2023 Annual Report on China&#39;s Policies and Actions to Address Climate Change&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the launch of the national carbon market in July 2021, the quality of carbon emission data has attracted much attention. Xia Yingxian, director of the Department of Climate Change, made his debut after taking up his new post. When answering questions from Southern Weekend reporters, he said that overall, companies&#39; awareness of emission reduction has significantly improved, their regulatory capabilities have been significantly improved, and the quality of carbon emission data has been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the measures taken by the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism for carbon emission data quality plays an important role. After enterprises submit data and certification materials through the management platform every month, national departments are responsible for big data screening and regular spot checks, provincial government departments are responsible for technical review, and prefecture-level government departments are responsible for on-site spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian introduced that the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review mechanism follows the management idea of ​​&quot;using the day to protect the month, using the month to protect the year&quot; to ensure that every day , monthly, and annual data are stable and reliable, &quot;reflecting our cautious and cautious attitude towards data quality.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/09b6f3748b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255860&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian, Director of the Department of Climate Change Response of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. Ministry of Ecology and Environment | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Do a good job in daily supervision of data quality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has always attached great importance to carbon emission data quality management. There is &quot;zero tolerance&quot; for illegal and illegal activities such as data falsification. Especially since 2022, a series of measures have been taken to ensure that carbon emission data is accurate and reliable, focusing on comprehensively improving data quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, in terms of the construction of the legal system, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has actively cooperated with the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate to revise and issue judicial interpretations to criminalize the falsification of carbon emission data. Sanction scope. The accounting and verification guidelines were revised and introduced, reducing the formulas involved in carbon emission report verification from 27 to 12, optimizing the accounting methods, and effectively improving the pertinence, scientificity and operability of the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of supervision and law enforcement, since 2021, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has organized supervision and assistance, guided by problem clues, guided enterprises to standardize emission accounting reporting behaviors, and severely cracked down on Engage in deceptive behavior. Xia Yingxian said that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment will severely punish and reduce carbon emission quotas for emission-controlled companies that have verified data to be falsified in accordance with the law; it has exposed a number of third-party verification agencies that violate laws and regulations, which has a great deterrent effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of carbon emission management capabilities, Xia Yingxian introduced that the national carbon emissions trading management platform will be launched online in 2023, realizing inventory management, emission management, and data quality supervision. , verification management, and quota management are intelligent and digital, and big data means are used to enrich data quality management technical means. Since 2023, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has held 5 special training courses on carbon emission data quality management and supervision and law enforcement, with more than 5,000 trainees, and supervision capabilities have been significantly improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian also said that in the next step, we will continue to do a good job in daily supervision of data quality and make full use of the &quot;national-provincial-municipal&quot; three-level joint review working mechanism. Conduct spot checks and reports on data quality management work in various regions, establish and improve daily supervision and technical review systems for greenhouse gas emission data, clarify technical review standards and procedures, and consolidate the main responsibilities of key emission units. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Carbon price is in line with China’s current reality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the press conference , Xia Yingxian also mentioned the progress of the national carbon market construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A total of 2,257 key emission units in the power generation industry have been included in the second compliance cycle (2021 and 2022) of the national carbon market, covering annual carbon dioxide emissions of more than 5 billion tons. . The quotas for 2021 and 2022 have been distributed in August 2023, and payment and compliance are currently underway. Xia Yingxian revealed that the current contract fulfillment rate has exceeded 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian believes that the national carbon market has achieved the expected construction goals. &quot;After more than two years of construction and operation, the overall operation of the national carbon market is stable, the price discovery mechanism has initially appeared, and corporate emission reduction awareness and capabilities have been significantly enhanced, playing a positive role in promoting the goal of achieving carbon peak and carbon neutrality.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xia Yingxian said that the national carbon market has initially established an institutional framework system, breaking through the blocking points in key links such as reporting verification, quota allocation, market transactions, settlement and compliance, etc. Difficulties, and realize full-service intelligence through the national carbon market management platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Regarding the topic of carbon market expansion, Xia Yingxian stated that it is urgent to include more qualified industries into the national carbon emissions trading market to reduce the cost of emission reduction for the whole society. We will insist on making progress while maintaining stability, and prioritize the inclusion of industries that contribute significantly to achieving the goal of carbon peak and carbon neutrality, have serious overcapacity, have great synergy potential for pollution reduction and carbon reduction, and have good data quality foundations, and include each mature industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The expansion of the carbon market requires a good data foundation. Xia Yingxian introduced that the Ministry of Ecology and Environment conducts annual carbon emission accounting report verification work nationwide every year for petrochemical, chemical, building materials, steel, non-ferrous metals, papermaking, civil aviation and other industries, and collects data from more than 6,000 companies. The above-mentioned 7 industries The total direct emissions from the power generation and power generation industries account for more than 70% of the country&#39;s total. In addition, special studies were organized on quota allocation methods, accounting and reporting methods, verification points, and expansion implementation paths for seven industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of October 25, 2023, the cumulative transaction volume of carbon emission quotas is 365 million tons, and the cumulative transaction volume is 19.437 billion yuan. The carbon price after the launch of the national carbon market Maintained at around 50-80 yuan/ton. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recently, the quota price has shown an overall upward trend, maintaining at around 80 yuan/ton. The moderate increase in carbon price reflects the market nature of carbon price.&quot; Xia Yingxian believes that the carbon price is in line with China&#39;s current reality and basically reflects my country’s emission reduction costs. In the next step, we will study the establishment of a market adjustment mechanism and take measures such as early warning of contract performance risks to adjust market supply and demand, enhance market vitality, and ensure the healthy, stable and orderly operation of the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“三吠举报”到“恶犬法案”：美国人怎么养狗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is well known that many people in the United States love dogs. However, these Americans love and raise dogs to achieve a certain balance under the support of their specific natural conditions, social conditions and legal environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, in my opinion, the most important and overlooked point is that the United States is not a rabies epidemic area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 202 human rabies cases were reported in 143 districts and counties in China in 2020. Dogs in the United States hardly carry the rabies virus, and the few rabies cases are caused by wild animals (mainly bats). A total of five people died of rabies in the United States in 2021, the highest number of rabies deaths in the country in 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Differences in natural conditions will cause huge differences in social adaptation. When there are no worries about rabies, the intimacy between humans and cats and dogs will greatly increase, and dogs will not be too taboo about what they eat or lick. Even strange stray dogs don’t have to worry about rabies. This creates a close human-dog relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the living area and living pattern of Americans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the per capita housing area in the United States is 67 square meters, ranking first in the world. In addition to the large average area, there are also structural differences in urbanization rates. The overall average urbanization rate in the United States currently reaches 83%, and the urbanization rate in some metropolitan areas is close to 100%. China&#39;s urbanization rate in 2022 will be 65.22%. The problem of dog ownership is largely an urban problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calculated in terms of per capita housing area in domestic cities, especially large and medium-sized cities, it is about half that of the United States. This is just the living area, not the living pattern. Chinese people mostly live in high-rise buildings and share the green environment of the community, while Americans mostly live in suburban villas. Americans have far more outdoor space per household. Therefore, Chinese people use half of their living area and much less public outdoor area to raise dogs, which naturally creates more conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States also has another characteristic, that is, it is more diverse, has a large place, has many choices, and does not interfere with each other. It not only protects the rights of dog lovers, but also protects the rights of people who do not love dogs. There are many communities in the United States that prohibit pets. Not only are dogs not allowed in these communities, but dogs from outside are not even allowed to &quot;visit&quot;. Have a peaceful time together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Americans love dogs, and although the living area is large, the density is low, and there are many green spaces, it does not mean that American dogs do not bite people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the U.S. National Library of Medicine, approximately 1,000 people in the United States require emergency care treatment for serious dog bites every day, and more than 4.5 million people are bitten by dogs each year, with 30 to 50 People are killed by dogs. Injuries caused by dog ​​bites and attacks result in the need for 30,000 surgeries in the United States each year, including sutures and staples. In 2020, U.S. insurance companies paid $854 million for dog bites and attacks, with the average dog bite insurance claim amount being $50,245. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Humane Society of the United States estimates that 51% of dog bite victims are children, which means more than 2 million children are bitten by dogs in the United States each year. Among dog bite deaths, the highest proportion is among those aged 0-4 years. Since children under 1 year old are often unable to walk and are often looked after by adults, the rate of bites is the lowest. After the age of 4, as children get older, the likelihood of being bitten decreases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, although Americans love dogs, they also strictly manage dog ownership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For general harassment, take New York City as an example. If you are reported for not picking up dog poop while walking your dog, the police will issue a $250 (1,800 RMB) fine and may also require you to appear in court. The law also prohibits the harassment of pet dogs in all public and private places. If the dog is not kept on a leash, a fine of 200-400 US dollars will be imposed. For dog nuisance, follow the &quot;three barking report&quot; principle: if a dog of any family barks more than three times in a residential area, it will be considered a nuisance, and neighbors can report it. Under strict regulations, most dog walkers in the United States are self-conscious, and leash-free dog walking is rare. If a dog poops, most dog owners use plastic bags to collect the poop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the law stipulates that people who keep high-risk ferocious dogs must erect signs in conspicuous places in their yards to remind passersby to pay attention. In public places, high-risk ferocious dogs must wear a restraint leash and an anti-bite muzzle at all times. Otherwise, law enforcement agencies have the right to impound or execute the dog. Depending on the severity of the case, the dog owner may be held criminally responsible and may even be sentenced to 90 days in jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For higher levels of physical risk, some states have enacted so-called &quot;vicious dog laws.&quot; A dog is considered a &quot;vicious dog&quot; if it attacks or injures a human or their pet within a two-year period, or exhibits aggressive behavior that requires the police or animal control agencies to stop or drive away. Such dogs must be isolated, prohibited from contact with humans, and undergo mandatory training. If the owner refuses to cooperate, the dog may be euthanized. The Vicious Dog Act requires dog owners to take full responsibility for their dogs. If a dog attacks a person and the owner fails to take strict precautions and deal with it promptly, resulting in casualties, the dog owner must be responsible for all injuries and may even be subject to criminal penalties. If a dog attacks a human after escaping, the owner is still responsible for the dog&#39;s behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are very sound pet shelters and rescue stations across the United States, funded by the government and private organizations, to take in and rescue stray cats and dogs. In shelters, sheltered dogs and other animals are treated well. Americans love dogs, and there are always enough volunteers at shelters. Stray dogs in shelters generally have a 1-2 week deadline for adoption. Non-governmental animal protection organizations also try their best to allow dogs in shelters to be adopted. After that, if no one comes to adopt them, they will be euthanized. Statistics show that of the 8.5 million stray dogs sheltered in the United States in 2010, 82% were adopted and taken away by new owners, while the remaining 1.53 million old, sick, and unadopted dogs were euthanized. Although many civil organizations are trying to change euthanasia and replace it with sterilization, raising funds is still an unavoidable obstacle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All public issues are like this. Rights and obligations cannot be neglected or mentioned only on one side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年度佳作，没有人经得起剖析审视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 22:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;There are many movies about marriage. You can easily pull up a long movie list. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this topic is never out of date, and has different interpretations in the eyes of different people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;No, this year Cannes presents us with another blockbuster work - &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1060&quot; height=&quot;1442&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b19a76556aff12983f19e3d24aa140b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255204&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier is a female director. Her first two works were &quot;Victoria&quot; and &quot;Sibyl&quot;, both of which were self-written and directed, focusing on female expression. At the same time, Justine Trier is also the third female director in the history of Cannes to win the Palme d&#39;Or for this film. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/033b7143c76d1a17a561c001a6337809.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255201 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The starring role is German actress Sandra Wheeler. In 2006&lt;span>;, at the age of 28, she won the Berlin Film Festival for her performance in &quot;Requiem&quot; Film Festival Silver Bear Award for Best Actress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/902dd4cb99bb6f88fede51e39c7eb2b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255200 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talented female director teamed up with powerful actresses to present this masterpiece that cannot be missed this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The heroine Sandra is a well-known writer with strong creative power and very high productivity. Coupled with her androgynous temperament, she has accumulated many readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this day, while Sandra was being interviewed by a young female student majoring in literature, loud music suddenly came from upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reckless and rude interruption announced the existence of another person: Sandra&#39;s husband Samuel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2a233abb47c91b2b9aca1796fa31f56a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255202&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Samuel was originally a university professor and also wanted to write. However, unlike his wife, who was full of literary ideas, he seemed to always get stuck halfway and find it difficult to write. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The two have an 11-year-old son named Daniel, who is visually impaired. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, this disability is not congenital, but is caused to some extent by Samuel: One day a few years ago, Samuel was supposed to pick up Daniel from school. But he suddenly got inspiration for writing and hired someone to pick up his son. During this period, Daniel had a car accident and damaged his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0e5d5d53c24c303e43af529eef9a9e42.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255205 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The accident not only interrupted their careers, but also put this middle-class family into financial difficulties due to medical expenses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to reduce debt pressure, Samuel suggested moving his family from London, England to his hometown in the suburbs of France. For Sandra, she lost her stable life in London and entered an unfamiliar environment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3ec418927ff0374335b782d2fcc342db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255203 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra has no one here, and her interview with the female student can only end hastily after being interrupted by Samuel. Soon, Daniel, who was returning from walking his dog, found his father&#39;s bloody body in the snow. He shouted for his mother, and Sandra, who came in a hurry, quickly called the police. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/44b3b74826c847b3c87d02170b682e1f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255207 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After identification, the fatal injury to the deceased Samuel was a heavy blow to the head. Although it appears that he fell to his death, he was most likely murdered. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/01c5eb1595ccfd37e41b02780a6d80a9.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255208 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But their family’s residence was nowhere to be found, and there were no other outsiders present when the incident occurred. Samuel usually had no enemies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thus, the common conclusion in crime movies&lt;/span>; is readily apparent: the murderer is the wife Sandra, and she must be resentful of her husband. Is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was controlled as the first suspect, and Daniel was on the scene The only witness. To prove her innocence, Sandra must convince the judge that there is love but not hatred between her and her husband, and that she has no motive for killing. At this point,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;a death case has become a trial of a marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; also enters into the detailed &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;analysis of marriage relationships: When a person &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; dies In this case, how can the other party prove itself? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bf38fa94449b2a9fc2b78564bee0aa10.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255210 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, except for Sandra, everyone else was basically in the same blind&lt;span>; situation as Daniel. After all, except for the two parties involved, everyone is an outsider in this relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/259bf13f1bdeb716989d9140f58e3dcc.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255206 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So neither the psychiatrist’s testimony, which was heavily psychoanalytic, nor the defense provided by lawyers on both sides, could touch the real Samuel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is no way to reach the core of a living person or a love through words. But this trial has to find the truth through language. This is the contradiction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/d8365786989286236ed63fd6dfce40a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255209 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because she was in France, Sandra had to use her unskilled language to defend herself. Love&lt;/span>; is not like this: stumbling communication, but in the end it is inaccurate words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/847f1aa4b73a21a908d5b65926142342.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255211&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Words always have a certain performance quality, and &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; also presents this through a perfect recording. The film also completely enters the climax after the opening 80 minutes. . Samuel carried Sandra on his back and recorded the heated argument that broke out between the two on the day before her death. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the recording, Samuel accused Sandra of only caring about her career and ignoring her family, saying that she was always aloof, saying that she clearly blamed herself for causing Daniel&#39;s tragedy but refused to admit it. She plagiarized her own ideas and cheated on her physically...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/ 9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 24/9bd78f2696a3e569e9c4cdfb5db51903.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sandra was not to be outdone. From the beginning, she calmly advised Samuel not to complain and not to be self-motivated, but later she became unbearable. Gave him a slap...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a68b47fd728ab4de691984f854d41f16.gif &quot; data-key=&quot;255213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a quarrel must have been experienced by most couples and couples who have passed the passionate love stage. It is difficult for outsiders to say that the public is justified and the mother-in-law is justified. Determine right or wrong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But the problem is that this quarrel and physical conflict happened the day before Samuel&#39;s death, which undoubtedly pushed Sandra towards the angry wife who murdered her husband. image. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The troubled media are still chewing on Sandra’s book at this time, believing that her murder of her husband was premeditated. But is this really the case? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/c1015b22701e26ec628373b7019690b8.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255212&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; is a work that analyzes marriage as delicately as a scalpel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a middle-aged female director, Justine Trier has not only gotten rid of the male perspective, but also has passed the stage of young women&#39;s blind longing for marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is very creative in placing the marriage relationship in the court scene to analyze, on the other hand, she still has the unique tenderness and pioneering spirit of women. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, in the setting of the heroine Sandra, she has a strong androgynous temperament, which is different from common female images. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;454&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/16e460de70bbb0da317356adaee6a64a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255215 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, compared to common settings, the situations and personalities of Sandra and Samuel are also reversed: Sandra has a successful career, a peaceful personality, and is close to her children; while Samuel Not only did I encounter a career development bottleneck, but I also became more emotional and exhausted my creativity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This image and gender setting itself break through the stereotype of male narrative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the film uses calm and restrained lens language and narrative expression, trying to go deeper into the truth of the death case and give the audience a sense of clarity beyond the case itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two recordings in the movie, one is the interview of the female student that day, and the other is the quarrel privately recorded by Samuel. These two daily conversations were analyzed and interpreted word for word in public in court, and were even used as evidence of crimes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When the second quarrel started by Samuel appears in court, the gender balance begins to tilt, and Sandra needs to explain all of Samuel&#39;s dilemmas : Why does he have to choose between work and family? Why does he never have time to write novels? Why is his creativity exhausted while she publishes novels frequently? Why is he frigid and she cheats on her physically? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this time, the intimate relationship must be put on the table to experience the scrutiny of others, and then others will give the final conclusion. Sandra was extremely embarrassed. What she encountered was not only a discussion about gender, but also a trial of marriage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the age of only 11, their son Daniel has already experienced major events such as car accidents, disability, the death of his father and defending his mother. He is actually the avatar of the audience. After listening to the trial half-blindly, he finally chose his mother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1b3521e273bea7b3042a551243609361.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255214 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this choice itself, even Sandra&#39;s innocence itself, cannot achieve complete emotional catharsis, because when feelings need to be judged, it means that there will be no survivors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film&#39;s use of telephoto lenses, soft light, and close-up lenses makes the images presented in the film more cold and distant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b399ca425c211cb2ed16619ea2e2877a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255216 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the exquisite narrative of &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot;, the most commendable thing is the performance of the heroine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, she is a talented and famous writer, and on the other hand, she is a wife and mother who is troubled by intimate relationships. The emotions and gestures she expresses directly support her. Played the role itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/38212a67591cfbaa1d0dee9ea6af38ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255218 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the movie, Sandra is well aware of the complexity of language. She refutes others&#39; attempts to define Samuel again and again, and always uses negative statements to retain Samuel. beautiful image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;That&#39;s not him.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This denial itself is an expression of private love, but love cannot be declared to Mouth proves that love is so absurd. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So in the court that tried to convict her, she was the only one who loved the real Samuel. She did not kill him, but she did kill him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[色乡，一段关于救赎的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJInW9oBtSKF5N8j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/vsxsOobIv3x72l1YqXPbc1oLaJ InW9oBtSKF5N8j. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lodro Wolong Temple is built along the cliff, and the huts on the cliff are used for monks&#39; practice. The cave &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tawny and bare, this was my first impression of Luozha County. Luozha County is located in a mountain valley, and the county seat winds along the only mountain road in the middle. I chose to come to Luozha, Shannan City, to visit the Sakagutuo Temple with a history of more than 900 years in the Border Se Township. This is a pilgrimage road often walked by Buddhists. It has a long history and a mysterious place. As for the scenery, although I am not a Buddhist, I am also full of yearning for the beautiful scenery on the border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 9 o&#39;clock in the morning, I set off from the bus station in the northern suburbs of Lhasa and passed through the beautiful Yanghu Lake and rows of snow-capped mountains. When I arrived in Lozha County, it was about 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon. I immediately bought the only daily ticket at the station. A ticket to Sexiang. It still takes nearly two hours to drive to Sexiang. The road begins to narrow and there are more gravels. But I was still attracted by the barren and spectacular scenery outside the window. One side of the car is close to the exposed rocks, and the other side is close to the rushing river. The river is rushing forward happily, as if it is racing with the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/4CJwybPlikMf1N8rb8DErCaYsiUpV1g4HfqvdEr5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Loza County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were only five or six people on the bus An old Tibetan man, a young Tibetan man and me. The young Tibetan man comes from the Garze region and has been traveling to Tibet for more than half a year. This time he went specifically to Lapu Hot Spring in Sexiang. He wore a down jacket and carried a small plastic bag with him, but no other luggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already 7:30 when I arrived in Sexiang. I quickly found a place to stay before it got dark. The entire township is located on a flat land in the mountains. There are dozens of buildings built along the road. They are all occupied by local people. In order to welcome guests, some have been converted into hotels and some into restaurants. Hotels are either closed or full, and the owner is rarely there, leaving only a phone number. Finally, I finally found a bed at the Sakaguto Temple Hotel. There was a public bathroom, but I couldn&#39;t take a shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;702&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Zr1UWUXJhF4ejzye7gI0fYIs2ePDIci33DQAPxht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Saika Gutuo Temple in Sexiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;sai Kagutuo Monastery was originally a monastery of the Kagyu sect of Tibetan Buddhism, but later converted to the Gelug sect. It is a must-visit place for Tibetan pilgrims. The main building of Sakagutuo Temple, which has a history of more than 900 years, has been relatively completely preserved. The temple is located in the middle of Se Township, next to the cliff, and the sound of rushing river water comes from the bottom of the mountain, which is quiet and distant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a legendary and touching story of redemption behind the nine-story tower of Sakagutuo Temple. According to legend, in the 11th century, Marpa, the founder of the Kagyu sect, who was known as &quot;one of the seven great translators of ancient Tibet&quot;, had a disciple named Milarepa. He lost his father when he was young, his wealth was seized by relatives, and his family was enslaved. When he grew up, he learned magic and killed 35 people in revenge. Later, in order to atone for his sins, Milarepa came to Sexiang to become a disciple of Marpa. Marpa ordered Milarepa to build Sakagutuo Temple alone (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Means &quot;Nine-story Gongzi Castle&quot;&lt;/span>;). Day after day, year after year, every time he built it, Marpa asked him to overthrow and rebuild it, until it was finally completed the sixth time. The current Sakagutuo Temple was built at that time (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;later repaired and expanded&lt;/span>;). Ancient prayer wheels hang on the outside of the predominantly yellow temple, and murals from hundreds of years ago can still be faintly seen on the mottled walls inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pxdG2sSTqGXq9MC2LtS1A4lLkzoChetIoN1Fsd6t.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green space by the Sexiang River and a released calf&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There is a small suspended plank road on the top of the 9-story watchtower tower for people to pray for blessings. When I climbed to the ninth floor, a lama said that since I had come up, I should go around the tower. It is said that turning once can wash away all the bad luck in the past life; turning twice can pray for the health and happiness of parents; turning three times will prevent you from falling into hell in the next life. However, except for the steel poles that can be grasped by hand, there are no protective fences around the top of the tower. I was afraid of heights and dared not go up. Finally, I walked around in a circle under the leadership of the lama. The young lama chanted sutras while walking. He walked many times every day and it became a daily routine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sakagutuo Temple is very small and can be completed in less than half an hour. On the top of the mountain south of Sexiang, there is also Lodro Wolong Monastery, which is the birthplace of the Kagyu Sect of Tibetan Buddhism and was built by Master Marpa when he was 29 years old. According to the official website of Luozha County Government, &quot;Luo&quot; means &quot;south&quot;, &quot;Zhuowo&quot; means &quot;beginning of auspiciousness&quot;, and &quot;Long&quot; means &quot;prophecy&quot;. Luozhawolong Temple is where the master predicted and prophesied. place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes several hours to walk to the Luozhuo Wolong Temple on the top of the mountain, and there is no public transportation. I found a ride on the road and met a Tibetan family who drove up the mountain and picked me up. The family came from neighboring Cona County and came to Luozha County for pilgrimage for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/inSaPHeNkpXYh4IsTR42m20Z8b2IQG4o1WhqTgvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sexiang is dozens of kilometers away from Bhutan. Opposite the Sekhar Guto Temple is the Bhutanese commodity store, and the back of the mountain where Lodro Wolong Temple is located is In Bhutan, our ID cards were held at the checkpoint on the way up the mountain. The dusty gravel road was winding and difficult to walk. A couple from Guangdong decided to give up after driving for a short distance, but this Tibetan family did not. After half an hour, we successfully reached the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are only temples on the mountain, and the landscape is extremely open. Several huge crows are circling overhead, and the shadows of clouds are cast on the mountain. Lodzo Wolong Temple is built along the stone wall on the top of the mountain. In addition to the main temple, there are also many small hermitages scattered under the cliff. A lama who has been practicing for many years has long hair reaching his waist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lamas in Lodro Wolong Monastery are the most enthusiastic lamas I have ever encountered. They explained the story behind the temple to everyone who went up the mountain. Although I was the only Han tourist, after they finished telling a long list of Tibetan words, they would tell it to me again in Chinese. According to them, the old Lodro Wolong Temple was destroyed and was rebuilt in 1992. There is a sky burial platform at the top of the mountain. A lama in his twenties said that it was built based on a stone that Marpa carried back from India where he studied scriptures for 12 years. On the hillside at the foot of the temple, there is a flat area surrounded by prayer flags. The place where stones are piled is Shunyuantian. According to legend, this is the place where Marpa and Milarepa met for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We stayed on the mountain for more than half a day, during which time the temple held a Dharma ceremony and witnessed the Tibetan Buddhist Dharma ceremony. Finally, I went down the mountain with the Tibetan family, and the car went around the zigzag road back to Sexiang. We separated and continued our journeys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[好心多修120米路要拆除？公共资金不能这么造丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259415]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A long-awaited road has been built an extra 120 meters, becoming an illegal land occupation and will be demolished , wait until the procedures are completed before re-doing it. Why is it so fussy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Hunan Radio and Television Urban Channel, a new road in Changsha City that nearby residents have long awaited will be opened soon. However, a section of this road was suddenly surrounded again recently, and excavators were excavating the paved asphalt road. Street lights, street trees and other facilities on the roadside were also dismantled and removed, and garbage trucks were also brought in from other places. The loess was transported and poured on the road. What happened? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that the main part of this road is in Changsha Economic Development Zone, but it extends 120 meters to Furong District. When the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company was building the road, it built an extra 120 meters along the way without going through the construction application procedures with the relevant departments of Furong District. The Furong District Natural Resources and Planning Department determined that this was “illegal land occupation.” As a result, the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company responsible for the construction began to demolish the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, staff from the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company said that they agreed that the land was indeed being used illegally, but they were &quot;purely out of good intentions.&quot; Also, if we don&#39;t build more of these 120 meters, there may be no way to connect it with other roads, and there will be a section of &quot;intestinal obstruction&quot; in the middle, so it won&#39;t make much sense to build this road, so we &quot;kindly&quot; help and provide money and efforts to complete it. The more than 100 meters of road should be repaired. So when they were deemed illegal by the relevant departments of Furong District, they felt a little aggrieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Furong District, the extra 120 meters of road construction is within my jurisdiction. According to regulations, road construction should follow procedures and be submitted for approval in advance. It is of course illegal to build roads without approval. The competent department requires that the illegal status be eliminated and the construction be restored to its original state. The construction application procedures will be completed before re-repairing, which is completely &quot;in accordance with the law and regulations and in compliance with the procedures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There seems to be nothing wrong with both sides. However, after construction and demolition, demolition and construction again, a lot of money was wasted. What went wrong? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jingkai District Urban Construction Company that built the road built it without approval. Of course, there were violations of laws and regulations. However, the road has been repaired, and it is indeed a road that has been long-awaited by the nearby people and is necessary to be repaired. However, if it is forced to be demolished, the problem may be even greater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all this is a huge waste of public funds. Although the 120-meter road is not long, it costs a lot. The entire road is about 1 kilometer long and costs 60 million yuan. Calculating the cost of 120 meters is 6 to 7 million yuan, and dismantling it will also cost a lot of money. Once it was built or demolished, millions would disappear. This is a municipal road, and the Economic Development Zone Urban Construction Company responsible for its construction is also a state-owned enterprise. The source of its construction funds must be public funds of the local government, that is, public money. For Furong District, it is a good thing that the Economic Development Zone is willing to spend the money to build its own roads. If it is forced to be demolished and then rebuilt by oneself, although the cost of demolition will be borne by the Economic Development District Urban Construction Company, the cost of reconstruction will still be borne by Furong District. It is also incomprehensible to abandon existing roads that have been built with help from others and to dig up and spend money to rebuild them yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, a section of the repaired road is dug out, and the rest becomes a dead end road. It took three years to build this road, and the nearby people had been waiting for it for three years. It was finally opened, but a section was demolished, and its effectiveness was greatly reduced. If we have to go through the formalities and rebuild it again, I am afraid we will have to wait at least another year and a half. This will bring great inconvenience to the public&#39;s travel and will also damage the image of the local government in the public mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Requiring the Economic Development Zone to demolish the roads and then rebuild them themselves can be said to be harmful to Furong District and not beneficial to itself. So why do the relevant departments in Furong District do this? From the perspective of organizational behavior, perhaps one or two explanations can be given. For some departments, they must make the decision on their own territory. It is absolutely unacceptable for others to interfere with their boundaries without telling them. Even if you spend more money, you must maintain your authority. After all, if you want to spend money, it is also a financial expense, rather than having to pay out of your own pocket. Only consider issues from the perspective of one place and one department, from the perspective of maintaining the authority of the local area and this department, only consider legal compliance from the perspective of this department, and show your sense of existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether the decision made is reasonable from a higher level, whether it will waste financial resources and state-owned assets, waste local taxpayers&#39; money and public interests and perceptions, and consume administrative credibility, it is not considered. scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident shows the fragmentation and lack of coordination among relevant government departments, the lack of appreciation for the use of fiscal funds, and the lack of care for the waste of state-owned assets. Such things are not uncommon. In the past few years, roads in some cities have been dug up frequently. Today they are laying water pipes, tomorrow they are burying wires, and the day after tomorrow they have to repair sewers. Frequently digging and repairing, repairing and digging again not only wastes construction funds, but also doubles the construction period and brings great inconvenience to citizens&#39; travel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, after the media reports this time, the relevant departments of Changsha Furong District have urgently stopped the behavior of damaging the road surface, and have speeded up the relevant procedures to legalize the 120-meter road as soon as possible. This case has been solved. I hope there will be fewer such absurd things in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“软实力之父”约瑟夫·奈：“中美间的交流应该是面向所有人的”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Is there destined to be a war between China and the United States? My answer Yes, no.&quot; Joseph Nye, a professor at Harvard Kennedy School, gave a negative answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye is a representative figure of the neoliberal school of international relations. Before and after the Cold War, Joseph Nye was famous for proposing the concept of &quot;soft power&quot;. Soft power refers to a country&#39;s strength other than economic and military strength, and mainly refers to influence such as culture, values, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He served successively as Assistant Secretary of State in the Carter administration, Chairman of the National Intelligence Council and Assistant Secretary of Defense in the Clinton administration. He is also a leading figure in American politics. But he reminded that the history of mankind is full of situations where wars &quot;accidentally&quot; entered. As long as China and the United States strengthen cooperation and act cautiously, wars can be avoided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China-US relations are one of the most important bilateral relations in the world today. On October 27, 2023, U.S. President Biden met at the White House with visiting member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and Foreign Minister Wang Yi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since October 23, Joseph Nye has embarked on his first visit to China after the COVID-19 epidemic. Judging from the public schedule in just one week, the &quot;Father of Soft Power&quot; has successively attended speeches at many think tanks and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 25, in the Qiulin Lecture Hall of the School of International Relations at Peking University, Joseph Nye spoke with the topic &quot;Are China and the United States destined to have a war?&quot; Hundreds of teachers and students discussed &quot;The History and Future of Sino-US Relations.&quot; The conference was jointly hosted by the School of International Relations at Peking University and the Institute of International Strategic Studies at Peking University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye once proposed the &quot;20-year cycle theory of Sino-US relations&quot;, that is, since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States, the ups and downs of the relationship between the two countries have been based on a 20-year cycle. And change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the long run, China and the United States will have better relations. But in the short term, China and the United States still have differences to resolve.&quot; Joseph Nye told the South Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye believes that after 2017, Sino-US relations entered a cycle of great power competition. &quot;China-U.S. relations have gotten worse in the past. In a sense, I think we have seen the deterioration of Sino-U.S. relations, but I hope things will get better.&quot; Joseph Nye told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, discussions about the &quot;new cold war&quot; between China and the United States have been rampant in European and American public opinion circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Joseph Nye&#39;s view, the Cold War between China and the United States is completely incommensurable with the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union. “During the Cold War between the United States and the Soviet Union, although there was military and political competition between the two countries, their economic and social ties were very sparse. But now China and the United States are highly interdependent in many fields such as economy, society, and ecology. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, Joseph Nye wrote an article in the &quot;Wall Street Journal&quot; that the Cold War between China and the United States is completely avoidable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joseph Nye supports China and the United States in strengthening cooperation in public health, climate change and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Exchanges between China and the United States should be open to everyone. Exchanges at the cultural and scientific levels are equally important.&quot; Joseph Nye told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes The public&#39;s attention should not only focus on high-level people, but also exert soft power. Low-level contacts are also very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The following is an interview with Joseph Nye:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Sino-US relations have gotten worse in the past. In a sense, we have seen a deterioration in Sino-US relations, but I hope things will get better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unfortunately, during the COVID-19 epidemic, communication between China and the United States has not been sufficient. However, communication between China and the United States has begun to change. The United States sent important cabinet members to visit China, and Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi also arrived in Washington for a visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I think Sino-US relations are making progress. Two years ago, Sino-US relations were worse than they are now. What we&#39;re seeing today is some pickup, and I hope it continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among China and the United States, China not only has strong economic performance, but also has the attraction of traditional culture. I believe that a country’s soft power comes not only from government actions but also from civil society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The U.S. government often does some unpopular things, but despite this, America&#39;s civil society remains attractive to others because it is relatively free. Therefore, the soft power of the United States comes more from universities, non-profit organizations, and foundations, such as the Bill Gates Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is undeniable that people&#39;s views of the United States have gone up and down in recent years. In my opinion, the soft power of the United States has gone up and down. During the Vietnam War and when U.S. troops invaded Iraq, U.S. soft power was declining. The soft power of the United States returned again with the election of Obama as President of the United States in 2008, and fell together with Trump (who became President of the United States) in 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soft power does not decline linearly or rise linearly. It is often cyclical. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, the soft power of the United States is weakening due to internal divisions within the United States. On the other hand, if you look at the hard power of the United States, you will see that the U.S. economy is booming. The United States is a wellspring of innovation, leading in technological fields such as biotechnology and artificial intelligence. Looking at the situation in the Middle East today, (U.S.) military power is still very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Biden administration has been in power for three years and has a more balanced view (compared to the Trump administration). They still believe there are still benefits to working with China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In May this year, the G7 summit changed its focus on decoupling from China to de-risking on China. This expression means Countries outside the G7 will adopt partial decoupling from China, mostly in the security field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In other words, de-risking does not mean completely cutting off economic ties, but there are limits. U.S. national security adviser Jake Sullivan called it &quot;building a high wall around a small yard.&quot; We should not let this small yard grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To prevent deterioration, Sino-US relations should start with high-level contacts. Next, look for areas of cooperation between China and the United States, which can convey to the public of both countries that cooperation with another country is beneficial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I think this is an area where China and the United States can strengthen cooperation (position on the Russia-Ukraine conflict). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China and the United States can also strengthen cooperation in other areas, such as climate change and working with the WHO to respond to epidemics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Exchanges between China and the United States should be open to everyone. Obviously, people always focus on the president or the cabinet. Exchange on cultural and scientific levels is equally important. If we need to build trust and cooperation (with each other) and exert soft power, low-level engagement is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(Sino-US relations) have become increasingly complex and difficult to resolve in the short term. I tend to use &quot;short-term pessimists&quot; and &quot;long-term optimists&quot; to describe China and the United States as not posing a threat to each other. In the long run, China and the United States will have better relations. But in the short term, China and the United States still have differences to resolve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>