<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[小金眼中的大金丨人来人往]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260080]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDTusi9UKvZB3J0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDT usi9UKvZB3J0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jin Shenghua and Jin Yaoji at the translation seminar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin Yiuji, former president of the Chinese University of Hong Kong, has reached his ninth year and has been retired for nearly two decades. Ten years later, I am still strong and full of energy. While admiring me, I think of the past. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in 2004, between the administration building and the library of the Chinese University, everyone on campus unanimously called On the steps of the Central Steps, I met a colleague who was about to retire. She has served the school for many years. Starting from Li Zhuomin, the founding president of CUHK, she has worked with five presidents. She can be said to be a veteran of the past dynasties. Chatting with her, she mentioned her retirement and that Principal Jin Yaoji was leaving soon. She felt deeply sad to leave. She suddenly said: &quot;Principal Jin is such a nice person, I&#39;m not afraid of him!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not afraid of him? Who would be afraid of Principal Kim? However, if you think about it further, why are subordinates not afraid of their supervisors? According to common sense, isn&#39;t it common for subordinates to be afraid of their supervisors? This made me have an image of this &quot;member&quot; in my mind - affable, smiling, humorous, witty, and talented; treating everyone equally, from the school director to the co-workers; when running the school, Accept advice and learn from it, follow the good as a rule; smoke a pipe when you are free, and enjoy yourself. Such a gentle and kind-hearted supervisor will of course make people &quot;respect and love him&quot; rather than &quot;keep him at arm&#39;s length&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have known Professor Jin Yaoji for decades. At the beginning, there were not many teachers named Jin in the school. Since both of us were affiliated with New Asia, our colleagues mostly used &quot;Da Jin&quot; and &quot;Xiao Jin&quot; to distinguish each other, and we also called each other &quot;the family&quot;, adding Professor Jin&#39;s There is only one character difference between his name and my eldest brother&#39;s name, so I naturally regard him as an elder brother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met Professor Jin, it was still in the 1970s. I still remember that back then, this &quot;member of the family&quot; had just returned to Hong Kong from the United States. He was very handsome, young and promising. Not long after, he held important positions many times, and was later elected as the president of New Asia. At that time, Jin Yaoji was only in his early forties, and he was not from New Asia. These two factors may have caused him to encounter some obstacles when he first took charge of important tasks. However, with his outstanding intelligence and amazing courage, all difficulties were in his hands. , can all be easily solved. Since then, Professor Jin has been at CUHK for decades, and as he has moved up the ladder, he has more and more affairs and heavier responsibilities, but has anyone seen him looking sad and overwhelmed? In everyone&#39;s mind, Jin Gong always talks, laughs, and fights, and does everything lightly. Because of this, whenever the school has &quot;difficult and complicated diseases&quot;, they will naturally entrust them to him, hoping that he can &quot;prescribe the right medicine&quot; and rejuvenate them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2003, the CUHK Faculty and Staff Association held a Christmas dance, and Principal Jin was also invited. At the party, the host asked me to say a few words to pay tribute to him. I said: &quot;There are two kinds of leaders in the world: the first type, others respect and fear him; the second type, people respect and love him. Professor Jin certainly belongs to the second category.&quot; These words were recognized by everyone. That night, Principal Jin, who is usually not good at dancing, actually danced very happily surrounded by everyone. He is such a considerate and easy-going person. Over the years, whenever colleagues ask for advice, no matter how busy he is, he will put everything aside and listen attentively. This makes people feel that in Professor Jin&#39;s mind, you are the most important person and your affairs are the most important things. He is listening, he is thinking, he is sharing your burdens and resolving your worries. He is busy with everything, so he will stop time, accompany you, and protect you. No matter how bumpy the road ahead is, he will help you and solve your problems. How can such a supervisor not make people convinced? When colleagues work hard and serve the school wholeheartedly, he not only hears and sees them, but also expresses his gratitude through actions. On the eve of the degree awarding ceremony every year, colleagues in the public relations team are often extremely busy and stay up all night. One time, near midnight, Principal Jin actually visited the class in person and brought chocolates to express his condolences! Such a sincere leader can make the whole school work together as one, regardless of each other, to strive for a common goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin is most praised for his outstanding eloquence and excellent articles. He is a person who speaks well and writes well. On important occasions such as international conferences, commemorative celebrations, opening ceremonies, etc., as long as Jin Gong is present and he opens the mouth of Jin, both the guest and the host will be happy and everyone will be moved. Jin Yaoji&#39;s eloquence is not just about his brilliant tongue and spitting jade. What is unmatched is his humor, his wit, his ability to talk and laugh freely, as if everything in the world is ready at any time. As long as he waved and nodded, he would arrange the formation and send the generals out in formation. I remember one time, Professor Jin was going to the city to host a banquet. In the car, he asked me a few questions casually and got a brief grasp of the information about the guests. As a result, he used it vividly in his speech at the banquet. After my country&#39;s first astronaut Yang Liwei successfully launched into space, Principal Jin quoted the words &quot;feeling good&quot; on different occasions, but he used it just right every time and the effect was amazing. Another time, the Department of Translation held an international seminar and invited Jin Gong to preside over the opening ceremony. He asked me to draft the lecture notes in advance. On the opening day, Jin Gong came as scheduled and spoke according to the script. Halfway through the reading, he suddenly said: &quot;I did not write this elegant speech, it was drafted by Jin Shenghua.&quot; He was humorous, calm and comfortable, It can be seen. The most recent one was a speech at the launch of my new book (&quot;Heart-to-Heart-Eighteen Years with Brigitte Lin&quot;) on September 24, 2022. On that day, Shanheng College of Chinese University held a dialogue between Qingxia and I. During the meeting, Jin Gong was specially invited to make comments after the conversation. As soon as he came on stage, he asked the audience seriously if they could take off their masks. At that time, Hong Kong was still implementing epidemic prevention measures. Of course, it was not possible. So, he went on to say: &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if I don&#39;t take off the mask. Brigitte Lin wears a mask. Everyone will suffer a lot.&quot; .&quot; As soon as this statement came out, it immediately caused a roar of laughter and heated up the atmosphere of the entire venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also remember that at the dinner of the Second Global Chinese Youth Literature Award in 2003, President Jin once said that the stars were shining that night, and stars of both big and small literary genres descended on CUHK. , Bai Xianyong, Yu Guangzhong, Lin Wenyue and other famous artists, as well as many minor literary stars such as the young students who won awards in each group. In fact, President Jin himself is an out-and-out literary star. On the one hand, he writes books and lectures in the field of sociology to teach future generations; on the other hand, he writes narratives and expresses his feelings in the field of literature. During his visit to the University of Cambridge in 1975, Professor Jin was impressed by the aura and beauty of Cambridge. In addition to writing major works, he also began to write short prose pieces. During his one year at JNU, through rain, fog, snow, spring, summer, autumn and winter, Professor Jin’s inspirational words came out and he completed the book &quot;Cambridge Silk&quot;. Ten years later, when he was a visiting professor at the University of Heidelberg, he put his thoughts and feelings into writing and wrote the book &quot;Heidelberg Silk&quot;. The two volumes complemented each other and became a praised &quot;gold-style prose&quot;. In 2007, after Jin Gong retired, he made another trip to his hometown. One of them was a pilgrimage to Dunhuang, the desert art capital. After returning, he published the book &quot;Dunhuang Silk&quot;, which echoed and connected the previous two volumes of &quot;Yu Silk&quot;. It is the work of the three famous &quot;Yusi&quot; sisters. Looking at Professor Jin&#39;s life, he could not only use a huge pen like a rafter, but also use the dignity of a mountain to write large articles about governing the country and criticizing the current ills, which are very resonant to read. He could also hold a thin pen like a silk thread, and use the lightness of water to describe and express his feelings directly. , the true feelings of the world come from the heart, and it is deeply touching to read. No matter whether it is a masterpiece or a short piece, there is emotion in the theory, and reason in the emotion. The two blend together without leaving any trace. The author looks down at the heaven and the earth, travels between China and the West, traces the past, discusses the present, and explores the secrets. He can not only analyze and find out the clues in the vast sea of ​​knowledge, but also find new ways and write strange works in the literary world where hundreds of flowers are blooming. . The reason is actually closely related to his personal qualities, endowments, temperament and character. In addition to his professional field, Professor Jin has a profound understanding of literature, history, philosophy, and education. In addition, he is a reasonable person in life. As the saying goes, &quot;Knowledge of worldly affairs is knowledge, and understanding of human feelings is writing.&quot; Therefore, he can not only talk about poetry and art At that time, he was outstanding, and he was also good at twisting and turning in the intricate tangle of personnel and affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Kim Yao-kee has served at CUHK for a total of thirty-four years. During his two years as president, he has experienced many difficult and difficult moments under extraordinary circumstances, including the outbreak of SARS and the government-controlled Fortunately, Principal Jin worked hard and dealt with the accidents such as salary cuts due to capital cuts, and finally overcame the difficulties one by one. During his tenure, President Jin completed many tasks, not only established the School of Law, raised huge donations for the university, and introduced new mechanisms to improve the university&#39;s governance structure. When President Jin took office, he once humorously claimed: &quot;I have a long way to go but I still have a long way to go!&quot; Indeed, two years is not a long time, but President Jin&#39;s achievements in running the school are obvious to all and are highly praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of June 2004, on the eve of President Jin Yaoji’s retirement, CUHK held a farewell banquet. That night, the house was full of guests and the event was unprecedented. All the guests who were supposed to come came, and unexpected friends also came, including colleagues from all walks of life and departments in the school who usually do not like to have banquets. The dinner was held very successfully. There were no lengthy speeches or sensational scenes. Everything was simple and natural, just like Principal Jin&#39;s traditional style. The president said in his speech: &quot;I am the youngest dean and the oldest president in the history of CUHK. People ask me what I can do after retirement? I think, Ronald Reagan 71 I only became president at the age of 18, so I&#39;m probably qualified enough to be elected president!&quot; The fun and humor are still the same, this is Principal Kim&#39;s true character! In the middle of the dinner, there suddenly appeared a scene where everyone came forward to invite Principal Jin to take a group photo: one table after another, in good order, came forward spontaneously, with a look of reluctance in their eyes. This is A sight never seen before. From school directors to secretaries, from professors to clerks, it is hard to tell them apart. Regardless of high or low, at this moment, everyone only has in their minds the outgoing Principal Jin, the gentle, elegant and generous Principal Jin! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last program of the dinner was a choir formed temporarily by CUHK alumni to sing the song &quot;Blessings&quot; for President Jin. This famous song originally sung by Ye Qianwen, with lyrics adapted by the talented Professor He Wenhui, sings the voice of everyone: &quot;Ling Yun is talented, everyone sees it, and the principal Jin Gongyi banishes him to an immortal. He is funny, handsome, and very friendly to others. He has a large belly and can punt a boat.&quot; . People who practice benevolence can contribute, and their sincerity feels far away. Sincere and fraternal love nurtures talents without getting tired, and thousands of spring breezes blow gently and warmly. Ah! The spring breeze blows in my face again. I wave my hands gently, and the sadness of parting is still deep. Listen to me Tell me carefully, I will be happy in the future. I will have my beloved wife by my side, a pipe, and thousands of smoke rings...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Principal Jin retired, compared to the busy years in the past, his life was lighter. The wind is light, but still full and more elegant than before. In addition to his continuous writings, Jin Gong was also diligent in writing calligraphy. Jin Yaoji has worked hard to practice calligraphy under the supervision of his father since he was a child, but he never expressed his hardships. According to his self-statement, &quot;My exploration and pursuit of the art of calligraphy and calligraphy began after I retired from the Chinese University and was seventy years old.&quot; Therefore, Jin Gong, who was graceful and comfortable in his seventies, not only followed his heart&#39;s desires, but also enjoyed peace of mind. The joy of playing with grandchildren also continued the relationship between calligraphy and calligraphy that started in childhood, and carried it forward, becoming a &quot;golden calligraphy&quot; that has been praised for a while and is popular among the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Lin Qingxia kept hearing about Jin Gong’s name and various anecdotes from me, and she read his masterpieces and admired his calligraphy from Ming Pao Monthly. One day, this talented woman who was thirsty for talents, He offered to meet with Principal Jin and ask him for tips on writing and calligraphy. On September 24, 2021, I hosted a banquet at the Shanghai General Assembly. As a result, the leaders in academic circles and the entertainment industry finally got to know each other in a state of mutual appreciation. That night, although the two met for the first time, they felt like old friends at first sight. During the dinner, Qingxia talked about how not long after she started learning Peking Opera, friends asked her to sing a cappella song. The words were not finished yet, but she had already spoken cheerfully and boldly. He stood up and sang &quot;Su San Qi Jie&quot; (Hua Dan) and &quot;San Jia Dian&quot; (Lao Sheng) without any shyness. When Jin Gong heard this, he cheered and shouted &quot;You are so bold&quot; in a loud voice! When the whole audience heard this, they couldn&#39;t help but burst out laughing and applauded with great joy! After that, friends often used the term &quot;bold&quot; to describe Lin Qingxia, the &quot;desperate Sanniang&quot; who is now able to do everything with ease and go all out. Qingxia herself also thought that Jin Gong&#39;s gift was remarkable, even to Jin Gong&#39;s words. When I proposed to give a calligraphy treasure as a gift, I specifically asked him to mention these words and hang them high in the living room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after, Principal Jin presented Qingxia with a long calligraphy painting entitled &quot;The Wine Will Be Entering&quot;. This calligraphy was written with great joy, unrestrained and smart, and perfectly set off the famous work of the poet Li Bai. Qingxia asked the art master Zhang Shuping to help her frame it and hang it on the wall for viewing every day. Who knew that in July 2022, a &quot;fire&quot; incident occurred in the big house. Qingxia was far away overseas. At that time, what she was thinking about was not jewelry, clothes and other external objects, but Are you worried about whether the &quot;Will Enter the Wine&quot; hanging on the wall will be safe under the raging fire and billowing smoke? It&#39;s strange to say that&amp;nbsp;The third-level fire burned down famous paintings and furniture, but it stopped abruptly before &quot;The Wine Will Be Entered&quot;. It was separated by a wall,&amp;nbsp;but it didn&#39;t burn into Qingxia&#39;s room behind the wall. Paintings and clothes. Afterwards, Jin Yaoji sighed: &quot;I knew that Brigitte Lin was invulnerable to water and fire, Brigitte Lin is Brigitte Lin!&quot; Brigitte Lin believed that Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy treasure was a treasure of the house and had magical powers to prevent fire and disaster. Seeing the two of them admiring and boasting about each other, I couldn&#39;t help but feel how elegant and interesting the sympathetic friendship between them was! Nowadays, &quot;About to Enter the Wine&quot; has been moved to Qingxia&#39;s mid-level study. Whenever a scholar comes to visit, the hostess will definitely invite them to take a photo in front of Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy as a souvenir. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brigitte Lin and Kim Yao-kee took a group photo in front of &quot;The Wine Will Come&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new crown is raging, and the epidemic has been severe in the past three years, but Principal Jin is calm and calm, and his wife Yuan Zhen is even more angry After calming down, he said: &quot;Life and death are destiny, there is no point in being afraid!&quot; Principal Jin continued to pursue the aesthetics of life, saying: &quot;Food and wine are never deliberately avoided. In a dangerous epidemic, if you have good friends and confidants, you can share them with others.&quot; Drunk, a toast, it&#39;s life!&quot; With such a broad mind and such a state of mind, he is no less generous than the free and easy Dongpo layman! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Yaoji, as his name suggests, is like a golden glow in the eyes of his friends, shining warmly on everything around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[业委会成员向开发商索要好处费：监督业委会还需业主亲力亲为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260056]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two members of the owners’ committee of a residential area in Guang’an, Sichuan, demanded 130,000 yuan in benefits from the developer, suspected of illegal The crime of accepting bribes by a state employee was investigated by the public security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that Chen Moubing was elected as the director of the first owners committee of a community in Guang&#39;an with high votes, and Chen was appointed as the security coordination committee member and greening and sanitation committee member. At the end of May 2020, the government inspected the commercial buildings in the community and prepared to build a kindergarten. However, the developer of the community had set up some of the houses on the fourth floor as property offices and property committee offices. Chen Moubing found the developer of the community and asked for a benefit fee of 130,000 yuan, claiming that You can ask the property management committee, owners, etc. to agree to the office relocation. In June 2020, after the developer negotiated with Chen Moubing about the office relocation, he paid 80,000 yuan to Chen Moubing and 50,000 yuan to Chen Moubing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actions of Chen Bing and Chen have violated the provisions of Article 163 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China and are suspected of accepting bribes by non-state personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For 130,000 &quot;benefits&quot;, Chen Bing and Chen were able to turn a commercial building in the community into a kindergarten. This shows that as members of the property committee, they have considerable &quot;power&quot;. Several key points remain to be clarified in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, Article 30 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot; promulgated by Sichuan Province stipulates that the owners&#39; committee shall regularly announce the following information and information to the owners in the property management area: the use and operation of the common parts of the property Income and expenditure status. Has the owners&#39; committee announced relevant information to the owners&#39; meeting as soon as possible regarding the relocation of neighborhood committees and owners&#39; offices and the conversion of original houses into kindergartens? Have the owners reviewed this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if Chen Bing and Chen deliberately delayed or even concealed the report, it would be difficult to guarantee the community owners’ right to know about this important matter. This involves the second issue. According to the &quot;Guiding Rules for Owners&#39; Meetings and Owners Committees&quot; promulgated by the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the owners&#39; committee is elected by the owners&#39; meeting and consists of an odd number of 5 to 11 people. Why did the other members of the property committee, who accounted for the majority, not raise any objection to this decision and let Chen Moubing and Chen make the decision? This also reflects the inaction of other owners committee members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This points to a deeper question: Who will supervise the owners&#39; committee? The owners&#39; committee is the embodiment of community autonomy. Within the property management area, all owners form an owners&#39; meeting and elect the owners&#39; committee as the executive body of the owners&#39; meeting. However, the establishment process of the owners&#39; committees has been interfered with or even manipulated, and after the establishment of the owners&#39; committees, it has been reduced to a private area for a few members to seek personal gain. Such incidents have occurred frequently, making the independence and impartiality of some owners&#39; committees almost impossible. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as employment committee elections are concerned, some developers or property companies, in order to protect their own interests, interfere, block or even manipulate the elections of owners&#39; committees. The community where I live held a general election for the property owners committee this year. Unfortunately, the surrounding shop owners, who accounted for nearly 10% of the total property area of ​​the community, did not cast a single vote despite being notified and invited multiple times. This resulted in this The first general election failed to meet the requirement that &quot;owners accounting for more than two-thirds of the exclusive area participate in the vote&quot;, and the new property committee was therefore difficult to produce. Some owners who participated in the preparations for the new property committee reported that the property management company promised to reduce the rent to the shop owners in exchange for the other party not participating in the voting. The purpose was to hinder the election of the property committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if a homeowners committee is finally established through numerous obstacles, community owners will face more challenges. Since the owners&#39; committee exercises part of the power of the owners&#39; meeting, once it lacks professional ethics and sense of responsibility and only focuses on its own interests, regardless of the rights and interests of other owners, it will inevitably use public tools for private use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the ways in which owners&#39; committee members guard against self-stealing, there are roughly three types. First, turn public maintenance funds into your own “money bag”. According to a report by Beijing Evening News in 2018, owners of Zhujiang Junjing Community in Beijing reported that more than 4,000 yuan was spent on their public maintenance fund accounts as early as 2013 without any knowledge. Some owners also discovered that their public maintenance funds had been misappropriated. to the owners committee account. The owners&#39; committee said that this move was for everyone&#39;s benefit and investment, and it was not made public because it was afraid that someone would come to &quot;pick trouble.&quot; But this argument is unconvincing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second method is to &quot;expand financial resources&quot;, fully developing and commercializing various public facilities in the community, so that the profits that should be shared by all owners can be divided between the members of the property committee and the property management. &quot;Chongqing Evening News&quot; reported in 2010 that the property management company of Dibochundun Community in Shipingqiao, Jiulongpo District signed a contract with the property owners committee, and the public revenue was divided &quot;30-70&quot; (30% for the property owners committee and 70% for the property management party), but many The owner was unaware. In addition, the director of the owners&#39; committee also receives a monthly remuneration of 3,000 yuan from the property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third method is to reach out to the property company for replacement. Members of the owners&#39; committee use the excuse of changing the property to make the existing property company pay &quot;protection fees&quot; to them, or to replace it with a new property company that has an interest in them, thereby making a profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at many cases, we can conclude that the moral self-discipline of owners’ committee members is unreliable and third-party supervision is indispensable. According to Article 39 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot;, if the decisions made by the owners&#39; meeting or the owners&#39; committee violate laws and regulations, the sub-district office (township people&#39;s government) or county (city, district) people&#39;s government where the property is located shall Within thirty days from the date of receipt of the complaint or discovery, the urban and rural development department shall make a decision in accordance with the law and notify all owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, as the owners of the community, the majority of owners must also realize that autonomy is not only a right, but also a manifestation of responsibility and ability. Owners should spend more time and energy to actively participate in community governance and strengthen the supervision and management of owners&#39; committees through election of owners&#39; committees, participation in owners&#39; meetings, and formulation of management regulations. At the same time, for major community matters announced by the property owners committee, such as public benefits, etc., professional auditing agencies can also be hired to audit, so as to effectively protect their own rights and interests and improve the quality of the community with stronger public awareness and legal concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[入职两个多月，00后班主任留遗书自杀，班级管理该不该单独设岗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260099]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独居者老死在家中怎么办？用智能水表监测是一大创新]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260072]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;What to do when people living alone get old is a long-standing topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens said that some streets in Shanghai do this: collect information on elderly people living alone in the jurisdiction, and if the household has no water within a few days, they will come to check. This innovation is gradually spreading in aging communities. Other netizens added that Shanghai began to install smart water meters after a series of elderly people died alone in their homes and were found to be smelly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Their words caused a burst of sighs. Some netizens said bluntly that they were hurt in their hearts after reading the relevant content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement is not based on imagination, but is supported by news reports. Regarding the death of an old man without anyone knowing, here is an example: In December 2021, a news piece about &quot;an old man living alone in Shanghai died for many days and was discovered by firefighters&quot; attracted attention. According to neighbors, the old man is a native of Shanghai and is in his seventies. When the neighbor comes back from get off work every day, the old man will greet him, but he has not seen the old man for 5 days. I smelled a bad smell recently and called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of thing is not unique to Shanghai, it has happened in many places. For example, in November 2015, an old man surnamed Pei in Huangshi, Hubei Province, who had never been married and lived alone for many years, was found dead in the bathroom of his home. His body had turned into a pile of bones. According to media reports, the elderly man disappeared six years ago. Community workers and police worked with the deceased’s relatives to search for him but failed. The local Dongchu Evening News reported that “a 70-year-old man has disappeared from the world for more than a year.” Conducted special news reports on the topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This type of innovation is not unique to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the installation of smart water meters, CCTV&#39;s &quot;News 1+1&quot; reported in December 2020 that Jiangsu Road Street, Changning District, Shanghai, installed smart water meters for 6 elderly households living alone in the area. If the reading is less than 0.01 cubic meters within 12 hours, the neighborhood committee will immediately receive the signal and send someone to check it in time. It was on a pilot basis at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, such practices have appeared frequently in various places. For example, in May 2021, the Beijing Daily client reported that 25 elderly households living alone in the Red House Community in Nanyuan Street, Fengtai District used smart water meters with automatic alarms for free. If the water meter reading is less than 1 liter within 12 hours, the information will be fed back to the neighborhood committee, and someone will come to visit. In addition, smart mattresses, smart light sensors and smart one-button alarms can capture information about the daily activities of elderly people living alone. Once an abnormality is discovered, the back-end staff will promptly contact the community and the elderly&#39;s family members to provide safety protection for the elderly living alone and the disabled elderly. In July 2022, the website of the People&#39;s Government of Haishu District, Ningbo, Zhejiang published this news: &quot;Water Meter Butler&quot; to protect elderly people living alone is online. Abnormal water consumption will automatically alarm 24 hours a day to protect safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 16, 2023, Foshan Sanshui Foshui Water Supply Co., Ltd. launched the Sanshui District’s “Political and Public Conduct Hotline-Dialogue on People’s Livelihood” program. The company said: We have monitored that elderly people living alone use water When the data volume is abnormal, the grid staff of the village or neighborhood committee will be contacted. For example, if an elderly person used 0.5 cubic meters of water one day and no water the next day, we will recognize this change and notify the grid operator at the residence of the elderly person living alone to contact the civil affairs department and go to the scene to contact the elderly person. Make connections to see if there are any abnormalities in water use or other aspects. We hope that by monitoring water usage, the lives of elderly people living alone can be helped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s cryptic, but you know the meaning. News reports use suggestive and evocative language to describe objective facts. Relatively speaking, netizens’ vernacular is more shocking. But no matter how you express it, the core of the truth is indeed so bleak. For an elderly person living alone, it is not surprising that once his health has problems and no one is around to take care of him, his later life will be miserable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author has talked about the importance of having children in many articles. Whether you have children or not, the outcome is very different. That kind of blood and spiritual connection cannot be replaced by any instrument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, even if you have children, there may still be problems with the elderly living alone and the children not visiting the elderly often. The children of the aforementioned elderly people living alone in Shanghai live in the outer suburbs. The old man passed away, and the children didn&#39;t know about it. It can be seen that they haven&#39;t visited him for many days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many reasons why children and the elderly are separated and lack of care for the elderly. For example, some children are extremely busy at work or start a business in other places. As for the elderly who do not want their children to disturb their lives due to differences in interests, temperaments, and cognitions, there are many examples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But more importantly, the Chinese family structure of three generations and four generations living under one roof has long been impacted by many trendy concepts, such as &quot;separating children and the elderly is more conducive to harmonious relationships&quot; and &quot;children and children living together harmoniously.&quot; The elderly live separately but keep a bowl of hot soup away.&quot; In this context, it is an indisputable fact that more and more elderly people live alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what factors cause the elderly to live alone, it is indeed a worrying social problem for the elderly to live alone and be temporarily or permanently &quot;forgotten&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to solve it? It is a proposition worth examining that the elderly and their children should live together as much as possible. Of course, taking into account various practical problems, &quot;living together&quot; should include the option of &quot;living nearby&quot; for children and the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Singapore attaches great importance to promoting this &quot;project&quot;. For a long time, in order to encourage children to live with the elderly, the government has provided conveniences and discounts to families living with the elderly in HDB flats, such as when allocating government flats. Price discounts and priority arrangements will be given to families with three generations living under one roof. In addition, a series of subsidy programs have been launched to provide elderly care and medical subsidies to low-income families supporting the elderly to reduce their family burden. This move increases the enthusiasm of young people and the elderly to live together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order for family care to become the main way to provide for the elderly, policy promotion is essential. In November 2021, the &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening the Work on Aging in the New Era&quot; was released, emphasizing the need to improve the elderly care service system, innovate the home and community elderly care service model, and based on home care, through new construction, renovation, leasing, etc. Community elderly care service capabilities. Adult children are encouraged to live nearby or together with their elderly parents to fulfill their support obligations and assume care responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that relevant surveys show that 58.51% of adult children are willing to live with the elderly. This ratio gives people confidence. It is not difficult to realize the vision of &quot;living together&quot; for children and the elderly on a larger scale when they are trying their best to shoulder the responsibilities and obligations of providing for the elderly, and with the help of good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中产三宝拉夫劳伦不香了，年轻人开始走“没钱风”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260078]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/0d38a337b2acadb1e7320d558b846b73.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;952&quot; height=&quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/06/0d38a337b2acadb1e7320d558b846b73.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257148&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / picture）&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is said that the middle class has three treasures: Ralph Lauren, lululemon and Archaeopteryx. But recently, Ralph Lauren, one of the three treasures of the middle class, has begun to lose its sales. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The financial report for the first quarter of fiscal year 2024 shows that as of July 2023, Ralph Lauren’s sales increased by only 0.4% compared with the same period last year. North America performed poorly, with revenue down 10%, and growth in the European market also slowed. Overall, the performance in the past two years has been slightly weak. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Then the question is, as a classic representative of &quot;rich style&quot;, Ralph Lauren was once considered a must-have for the middle class. How did the miracle of Ralph Lauren&#39;s rise be explained? Created? How did it gradually come down from the altar? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Ralph Lauren and Old Money Style&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1967, Ralph Lauren was founded by Ralph Lauren was founded in the United States and is positioned as a designer brand full of American classics and British style. In the early days, by sponsoring popular films such as &quot;The Great Gatsby&quot; and &quot;Annie Hall,&quot; Ralph Lauren successfully bound itself to the &quot;American Dream.&quot; In countless American literature, &quot;models dressed like Ralph Lauren&quot; ” is another expression of becoming a superior person. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The classic polo logo and stand-up collar Polo shirt have conquered many middle-aged men, unified the aesthetics of elite men around the world, and established a firm foothold in their cloakrooms. Ralph Lauren&#39;s Polo shirt is as classic as jeans are to Reeves, and down jackets are to Bosideng. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, long-lasting Ralph Lauren classic items such as cable-knit sweaters and Oxford cloth shirts are popular all year round, which can be said to be an effortless way to look old money. A styling tool that sells well all over the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Speaking of the &quot;old money style&quot; that made Ralph Lauren out of the industry, why are the new middle class so attracted to it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Old money&quot; is a concept opposite to the &quot;new middle class&quot;. They are often people who were born in Rome and have been rich for several generations. They are known as the royal family. Most of them are nobles or wealthy businessmen, and they are in a class that is beyond the reach of ordinary people. And their dressing sense shows distinctive characteristics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The overall style is mostly basic, with silhouette-based clothing styles, classic and timeless designs, brand logos that are not deliberately displayed, and fabrics that look expensive. What matters is high-end and quality. The happiness of rich people is so unpretentious and boring. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The beauty of &quot;old money style&quot; is not piled up, nor is it created by luxury goods, but is enduring after time, calm retro and A solemn elegance, noble and unassuming, low-key but deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As Paul Fussell said as early as the 1980s in his sociological work &quot;Style: Social Class and Lifestyle&quot;: In appearance, housing , consumption, leisure, furnishings, spiritual life, language and other aspects of realization will reflect different social levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because machine-made consumer products are so perfect that their high-profile and cheapness can be recognized at a glance, and colors with grayscale components that deviate from the machine have become the center of attention. The favor of the upper class. “The softer and darker the color, the more classy it is.” “Low-key is a common tendency.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The behavior of being covered in luxury goods with logos, wanting to wear the most valuable possessions on your body, and showing off your money and power to others is what the old money do. Disdainful, with the aura of rich people and nouveau riche, too exaggerated and flashy, and appearing to be using too much force. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The unified and harmonious color system, clean and simple clothes, on the contrary, look noble and elegant, with a natural sense of relaxation, and show off effortlessly. sense of fashion. This is the essence of old money style, which is simple and low-key, but has texture and looks full of nobility without any effort. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ralph Lauren is at the forefront of this old money trend. At first glance, it looks ordinary among the crowd, but at a closer look, the brand&#39;s logo reveals its identity and status. It is conveyed in a low-key yet high-profile way, perfectly capturing the middle-aged people&#39;s preference for high-end brands. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;靠着与“老钱风”的密切捆绑，拉夫劳伦成功俘获了美国精英，然后，开启了全球的扩张之旅，也毫不例外地让中国中产为其竞相折腰。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/510edbfc3b41bdcca5acf9dfc0526a7d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1349&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/510edbfc3b41bdcca5acf9dfc0526a7d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257145&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;中产三宝，年轻人爱不起？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2007的国产剧《奋斗》里佟大为一件拉夫劳伦的Polo衫将这个美国精英品牌带入了更广泛国人的视野。此后，拉夫劳伦开启了属于自己的黄金时代。通过线下代理模式，在国内遍地开花，实现快速扩张。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但成也萧何败也萧何，大量门店为了销售额引入低端线拉低了品牌档次，频繁的打折破坏了消费者信任度，而山寨货的满街泛滥，也使得品牌形象一落千丈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;拉夫劳伦的财报由以前的高歌猛进变得接连下跌，并在2021年迎来了至暗时刻，营收相较于巅峰跌去40%，只有44亿元。并且因为疫情的影响，中国的线下门店关掉了一半。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在此之后，拉夫劳伦开始大刀阔斧的改革，中国市场彻底转化为直营，并开始高端化和数字化转型。营销上着重于KOL与社交媒体，也推出年轻化的子品牌。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如今Z世代流行着一股“how to dress like a rich girl”的风潮，富家千金妆容，富家千金服饰在国内外社交媒体上刷屏，引来模仿者众。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在对多巴胺穿搭、甜酷辣妹风、Y2K风免疫之后，时尚的轮回又到了“老钱风”穿搭上，年轻人开始沾染上了“老钱风”的怀旧情结，对于让自己穿得更贵气有了极致的追求，希望自己能够对外塑造一个低调、精致、考究的形象。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;也因此拉夫劳伦从收割中产的中年三宝，逐渐开始斩获年轻人，值得思考的是，年轻人短暂的偏爱并不能让拉夫劳伦有恃无恐。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本质上，“老钱风”也是一股新鲜的潮流，年轻人对于另一种生活虽不能至但心向往之，通过穿搭来感受下“老钱们”的世界，不失为一种可行之策。不过，往往试过之后也就失去了长久的兴趣，浅尝辄止又移情别恋，后浪们马不停蹄奔赴下一个时尚风潮。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;曾经作为老钱风的代表，拉夫劳伦被追捧为必备单品，而当“老钱风”褪去流行，五年涨价80%，年轻人实在是对拉夫劳伦爱不起来。毕竟在如今的风险社会，年轻人更加追求稳定性，在金钱的支出上，少了些随心所欲，多了些理性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;动辄三四千一件的基本款Polo衫，实在让人下不去手，这个时候回过头一看，优衣库联名款、无印良品真香。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当这届后浪开始走“没钱风”，消费降级伴随的是服饰降级，拉夫劳伦在中国还能火多久，我们不得而知，可以确定的是“前年全员北面，去年全员鸟人，今年拉夫劳伦”，在时尚的字典里，没有什么是永垂不朽。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;穿搭不仅是一种风格，更是一种个性的张扬，所以拉夫劳伦只是一个符号，年轻人不在乎这个符号到底是由哪个品牌所体现，重点在于，一种不被潮流左右的思考方式与生活态度。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[毕业生就业难，企业用工荒，创新国际化办学可破就业“悖论”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260104]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年1月29日，浙江海宁，某企业生产线上。（视觉中国/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/a8ac71dd93.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/a8ac71dd93.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年1月29日，浙江海宁，某企业生产线上。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“明明企业很缺人，为什么高校毕业生还是找不到工作？”2023年10月30日，在浙江省海宁市举办的第三届“浙大东方论坛·海宁分论坛”（下称“论坛”）上，浙江大学公共管理学院教授陈丽君提出一个关于就业的“悖论”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在分析了领英中国（LinkedIn）上百万条全球高校毕业生就业数据后，陈丽君发现，全球QS排名前100高校毕业生的首次就业率（初次毕业后选择就业人数）接近80%。而在中国的头部高校，这一数字为接近50%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈丽君认为，出现“悖论”的一个重要原因是人才链和教育链之间存在脱节，“学校培养的人才不是企业需要的人才，产业链跟人才链脱节，造成就业难和用工荒并存。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对县域经济而言，高端人才和企业的连接问题或许更为显著。在论坛举行地海宁，当地提出的一个解决思路是引进教育资源。早在2013年，海宁市政府与浙江大学达成合作，引进浙江大学国际联合学院，双方的合作目标是，建立一个以浙江大学国际联合学院海宁校区为主体，联动海宁全域的国际合作教育样板区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如今，浙大海宁国际校区招生已有七年。海宁市常务副市长王一鸣在论坛上提出，浙大与海宁的合作“渐入佳境”。“校地融合、科创融合、产业融合都越来越深，配套的人才就业服务也在跟上，”但他也承认，“引进人才、留住人才仍然比较困难。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;创新国际化办学&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;海宁是浙江省辖县级市，邻近省会杭州，距离上海仅一百多公里。这里曾被称为“皮革之都”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“人才资源问题是县域发展的一个突出问题。”浙江大学公共管理学院教授吴结兵在研讨会上介绍，2010年前，他曾对海宁的皮革产业进行调研，企业纷纷反映，“吸引一个名牌大学的本科毕业生都很难”，更多的毕业生选择留在了企业设有研发中心的上海或是杭州。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;摆在海宁面前的问题是，如何汇聚人才，创新发展高新产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;也正是在2010年左右，中国高校开启了一轮创新国际化办学的风潮。昆山杜克大学、上海纽约大学、温州肯恩大学等中外合作大学纷纷获批创立。有意思的是，结合此前的宁波诺丁汉大学和西交利物浦大学，经济发达的长三角地区集中了半数具有独立法人资格的中外合办大学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2013年，浙江大学与海宁市政府达成合作，该校国际联合学院落户海宁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国际化办学与地方经济发展需要息息相关。清华大学教育研究院教授李锋亮在分析了1997—2019年的省级面板数据后发现，无论是中外合作办学机构数还是项目数，中外合作办学规模与经济发展水平之间均呈现显著正相关关系。这表明教育对外开放的扩大能够促进经济发展水平的提高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016年9月，浙江大学海宁国际校区正式开学。同年年底，海宁决定建设一座以浙大海宁国际校区为依托的科技新城，聚焦泛半导体、生命健康、现代服务业三个产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;曾有学者提出，国际化办学是一把双刃剑，北京师范大学高教所常务副所长洪成文曾以装修房子来比喻中国的教育国际化，他认为是在用最好的材料装饰自己的家，但教育国际化的终极目标，应该是“如何服务别人的房子，做房屋的设计师”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;浙大海宁国际校区副院长屈利娟介绍道，“浙大海宁国际校区的主要任务就是引进先进的办学理念、教育模式和投资机制，通过国际联合学院广泛建立和世界一流学术的链接，再就是要通过教育、科技、人才赋能地方经济发展，相应的科技成果转化要在地方完成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月30日，浙江海宁，第三届“浙大东方论坛·海宁分论坛”圆桌会议，浙江大学公共管理学院教授陈丽君。（受访者/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/315958bd61.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/315958bd61.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月30日，浙江海宁，第三届“浙大东方论坛·海宁分论坛”圆桌会议，浙江大学公共管理学院教授陈丽君。（受访者/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;如何留住毕业生&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;论坛现场，陈丽君向与会者抛出了那个关于就业的“悖论”：一方面，高校毕业生找不到工作，百万大军纷纷前去“考公”；另一方面，处在转型升级期的企业，却招不到紧缺急需的人才。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她认为，“就业难”和“用工荒”同时出现，反映了人才链与产业链之间存在脱节，“企业太缺人了，之前参加杭州的一个人才座谈会，一家公司说，现在不缺设计师，缺的是高级技工，他们准备到南非去引进。高技能人才（招不到），应该说教育和产业链之间的脱节已经比较严重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除此之外，教育链和创新链之间也存在脱节，“我们国内高校的科技成果的转化率，大概只有6%，”陈丽君指出，“很多大学校园和产业园区之间是&#39;两张皮&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“在我国，各类创新要素之间的集聚还存在一定问题。”陈丽君提到，全球的科创中心里非常重要的一个特征是各类创新要素高度集聚、高度融合，包括了高校、科研院所、企业，还有各类中介机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如何解决人才链、产业链、教育链、创新链（简称“四链”）之间的融合问题？陈丽君指出，方法之一是围绕人才链来部署创新链和产业链，例如浙大与海宁合作的模式便是一种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在王一鸣看来，人才是教育链和产业链、创新链之间的媒介。他介绍，海宁与浙大的校地合作已初具成效，“校地融合方面，我们组建了校地建设委员会、国际教育合作办公室，为人才设立了科创母基金，提供制度和设计上的保障；科创融合方面，杭州湾北翼科创枢纽正在建设中，预计2025年初步成型；产业融合方面，与浙大共建了8个产教中心；人才的就业配套上，在校区周边，我们新建了国际学校和国际酒店”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;创新国际化办学能留住人才，破解就业悖论吗？据浙江大学国际联合学院公布的数据，学院前三届毕业生深造率达89.7%，境外深造率达66.2%。王一鸣提到，引进人才、留住人才仍然比较困难，“我们这么多深造的学生，什么时候能回来？如果能够回到中国来，那就是科技转化成功的结果，但目前看到的还不太多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;与之相关的背景是，经历过2018年前后一波中外合作办学机构和项目终止后，国际化办学回暖。根据中外合作办学监管工作信息平台公布的数据，截至2022年5月底，全国普通高校本科及以上层次在办的中外合作办学机构和项目已达1300余个，在校生规模已超70万人。从境内各省（区、市）规模分布来看，除西藏以外，其余30个省（区、市）均开设了不同类型的中外合作办学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“（留住）国际化人才不仅仅是浙江省的短板，也是整个中国的短板。”陈丽君表示，留学是全球人才流动最重要的途径，从现有数据来看，中国的优势大学中有50%的人想要深造，其中70%选择出国，就回流比而言，中国只居于全球100位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王一鸣坦言，未来双方在合作的广度和深度上还需进一步深化，他透露，“新一轮合作要投入100亿为人才提供要素保障，未来如何积极培养创新（人才），是对海宁市政府的能力和水平的考验。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[佳木斯体育馆坍塌背后：建设单位多次中标市政工程，涉事广场系省级重点项目]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260102]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 11:21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/FL9ZJRTyvyLXtiDcUFkgyB4RAlS5XKsule9kZFXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/FL9ZJRTyvyLXtiDcUFkgyB4RAlS5XKsule9kZFXn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;悦城广场。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（桦南县人民政府网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黑龙江齐齐哈尔34中体育馆屋顶坍塌事发不足四个月，悲剧再次上演，相隔六百公里的佳木斯桦南悦城体育馆也发生了屋顶坍塌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据桦南县政府通告，2023年11月6日19时20分左右，佳木斯市桦南县悦城体育馆发生部分坍塌，经现场初步确认，体育馆内3人被困。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;齐齐哈尔事发时曾连日暴雨，这一次事故中桦南县则连续6个小时内降雪量达15毫米以上，当地发布暴雪红色预警。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通告显示，事发地悦城体育馆为2层框架结构，建筑面积约2000平方米，坍塌位置为西侧2楼篮球区域，坍塌面积约为500平方米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个体育馆内共有三个场馆，坍塌的是篮球馆，还有一个位于一楼的乒乓球馆，及位于二楼的少儿体能训练馆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李志成是这家少儿体能训练馆的老板，他告诉南方周末记者，当天刚好是馆里休息日，用来打扫卫生和清洁，事发时他所在的体能馆没有人。位于一楼的篮球场和乒乓球馆应该是在正常营业，一般情况下到晚上九点才会关门，不过“周一应该没什么人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李志成得到消息后，配合警方拿到了整个二楼事发时的监控录像，当时警方也希望通过他的摄像头确认有没有人被困。监控视频显示，大约在19点20左右，整个屋顶突然坍塌，他原本在二楼增加了一道石膏墙，整个墙面被巨大的气浪冲倒了，摄像头也跟着掉了下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个场馆是李志成向朋友借了二十万元开的，“我们家在县里还是贫困户，原本想着前两年能回本，第三年、第四年就可以盈利了，现在啥也没了。不幸中的万幸，这天刚好我店里大扫除，如果说我的店里出现伤亡，我一辈子都过不去。家长反正也挺暖心的，都在问我有没有事”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;事发两个月前刚接受过检查&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;黑龙江省桦南县政府新闻办凌晨发布通报：11月7日0时35分，桦南县悦城健身体育馆部分坍塌事故现场完成救援。事故发生时，现场共有7人，其中3人自行脱险，1人轻伤，3人遇难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发生该事故的场馆隶属于桦南县新阳光健身俱乐部，俱乐部负责人已被警方控制。事故原因正在进一步调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者查询到，新阳光健身俱乐部的法定代表人是门雅男。11月6日22：52左右，南方周末记者曾多次致电门雅男，对方一直处于占线中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;门雅男曾在2021年4月8日开办了悦城体育健身俱乐部，但又将其注销，后在2022年7月20日重新在原地址注册了新阳光建设俱乐部。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桦南县官方媒体“大美桦南”报道显示，事发两个月前，2023年9月5日下午，桦南县县委常委董丽娟曾带队检查文化娱乐市场安全生产工作，悦城阳光健身、悦城好声音KTV就属检查地点之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/UfZ57TmF0Kxawz0rsT2wZfOXEqattzYkkFOiBRrB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;535&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/UfZ57TmF0Kxawz0rsT2wZfOXEqattzYkkFOiBRrB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月5日，包括悦城阳光健身在内的场馆进行了安全生产检查。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（大美桦南/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地媒体报道，“每到一处董丽娟都仔细排查各场所安全风险，查看消防设施设备是否符合规定，消防用具是否在有效期内，消防通道是否畅通，应急灯是否能正常运行，证照是否齐全。对发现的安全隐患，当场明确整改措施和时限，对现场不能明确整改措施的，列成问题清单，责成相关部门和责任人提出整改意见和方案，限期整改到位”，董丽娟表示，要抓牢抓实安全生产风险防控意识，“对突出问题、重大隐患盯住不放、一抓到底。持续树牢安全红线意识和法治意识，推动安全生产责任落实落细，确保安全生产形势持续稳定，群众文化事业稳步有序推进”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地媒体报道，7月24日，桦南县委副书记、县长程显峰也曾到悦城广场全民健身体育馆察看安全工作落实情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;两个建设单位均为中标大户&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者查询到，该体育馆属于悦城广场综合体的一部分，该项目开发商是黑龙江悦城房地产开发有限公司（下称悦城地产）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开招标信息显示，该项目共有两期。一期中标的建设单位是黑龙江海峰伟业建筑安装工程有限公司（下称海峰伟业），开工日期2018年6月30日，竣工日期2019年10月1日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二期中标建设单位是黑龙江省华优建筑工程有限公司（下称华优建筑），开工日期2018年6月10日，竣工日期2020年10月1日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者联系了海峰伟业的法定代表人岳城琪，对方表示已经知道了体育馆坍塌事件，但是不确定是不是自己修建的工程，“需要回去查一查资料”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;招标信息显示，海峰伟业是桦南县政府的招标大户，参与的项目也是五花八门。市政工程方面，承建了公共停车场、道路、高铁停车场等，医疗工程有县疾控中心、县医院的传染病区、120急救中心，还有桦南县美丽乡村基础设施建设、县供电局的物资储备库、桦南经济开发区的生猪屠宰厂区内黑土转运土方。此外，还中标了县里的保障性安居工程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悦城二期中标建设单位华优建筑的股东牟彦东，正是悦城地产的二股东。和海峰伟业类似，华优建筑也是政府项目的招标大户。除了悦城广场之外，它至少拿到了三个政府项目，分别是佳木斯市中医院的中医院修缮医疗用房项目、桦川县文化广电新闻出版局的文化设施建设项目、桦南县村镇建设管理中心的桦南县危房改造项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坍塌体育馆的所在地址，也注册了一家公司，名叫黑龙江省悦城体育文化发展有限公司（下称悦城体育），这家公司的法定代表人孙永军，正是悦城地产的监事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;颇为蹊跷的是，悦城地产、悦城体育相继在2021年和2022年注销。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悦城地产曾是当地的明星公司，据桦南当地媒体报道，“经县住建部门大力招商，北京得意音通技术有限公司投资3.8亿元，在县城原奥林新村三期棚户区建设城市综合体项目，并投资注册黑龙江省悦城房地产开发有限公司。项目于2016年5月开工建设，到2019年10月完工”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报道中表示，“悦城广场项目经理说，我们的项目在桦南县委、县政府及相关部门的大力支持下现在已完成的工程量有回迁楼两栋，面积是3.4万平方米，城市综合体商业面积是2.8万平方米，高档住宅小区的面积是1.6万平方米。2017年我们公司计划投资1.7亿元人民币，现已全部到位，施工的前期各项准备工作也安排就绪，现在商住这一块进行到内外装修阶段，预计八月份完工投入使用”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者查询到，悦城广场综合体项目位列黑龙江的省级重点项目，曾在2017年出现在桦南县政府工作报告中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至今，桦南县政府官网上还保留着当年盛况的报道。2018年1月22日，桦南县悦城广场开业，由县政府副县长致开幕词并宣布开业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悦城广场被介绍为，“集休闲、娱乐、购物、体验等多功能为一体的城市综合商业体，项目自身具备的业态优势、功能优势、品味优势、特色优势、规模优势、服务优势、品牌优势等使项目整体处于极具竞争力的主导地位，必将成为全县知名的城市综合体项目，提高城市品味，为全面建设活力、文明、生态、诚信、智慧、和谐、幸福的美丽桦南增光添彩”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位周边邻居向南方周末记者证实，事发的悦城体育馆已经封锁，可位于悦城广场商场内的KTV当晚仍正常营业。在大众点评上，网友评论悦城广场是这个县城最能消遣的地方了，“来这个小县城几趟，别的地方没记住，这商场还真不错，健身房用的都是国际大品牌器械，和哈尔滨一万多一年的健身房一样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中李志成为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江又有体育馆坍塌，天灾还是人祸？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260100]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 11:39:25&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;11月6日晚，黑龙江桦南县一体育馆发生坍塌。7日凌晨，事故现场完成救援，其中3人自行脱险，1人轻伤，3人遇难。三个多月前，黑龙江齐齐哈尔市第三十四中学体育馆发生屋顶坍塌，致11名师生遇难，事故原因为屋顶违规堆放珍珠岩，浸水增重致屋顶荷载增大。此次桦南县体育馆坍塌，也有声音将原因指向大雪天气。</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原佳木斯一体育馆坍塌瞬间，3人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260097]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 10:51:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江又有体育馆坍塌：形式主义安全检查难辞其咎丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260093]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 10:07:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At close to 11 o&#39;clock on the evening of November 6, 2023, the Huanan County Government Information Office announced through the official social media account , at 19:20 that day, the Huanan County Yuecheng Fitness Gym (full name Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym) partially collapsed. Currently, three people are trapped. The local government and fire department are doing their best to rescue them in the snow. Prior to this, this news had quickly become a hot topic across the Internet and attracted great public attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people were in the library at that time, how many students were among them, and what the casualties were are what the public is eager to know. According to the latest disclosure from the local government information office: at 0:35 on the 7th, the rescue at the accident site has been completed; when the accident occurred, there were 7 people on site, 3 of whom escaped on their own, 1 was slightly injured, and 3 were killed; the venue where the accident occurred It belongs to the New Sunshine Fitness Club in Huanan County, and the club leader has been controlled by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what caused the stadium to collapse? According to CCTV reports, the gymnasium is a two-story frame structure with a construction area of ​​about 2,000 square meters. The collapsed location was the basketball area on the second floor on the west side, with the collapsed area of ​​about 500 square meters. Video posted online showed that the roof of a building collapsed. The four walls were intact. The building was about two stories high. The scene was covered with snow and wall fragments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the gymnasium roof reminds people of the roof collapse of the No. 34 Middle School gymnasium in Qiqihar City in July this year. The accident killed 11 teachers and students of the school&#39;s women&#39;s volleyball team who were training in the gym. The cause of the collapse was that the construction unit illegally stacked perlite on the roof of the gymnasium. The perlite absorbed rainwater and gained weight, causing the roof load to increase and cause the collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the Huanan County Gymnasium this time was also a roof collapse, which is similar to the collapse of the Qiqihar Gymnasium. Therefore, there are also voices pointing to the heavy snow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the blizzard red warning signal issued by the Jiamusi Meteorological Observatory at 17:30 on November 6, the cumulative snowfall in the city in 6 hours has reached 15 mm. The snowfall is expected to continue until the morning of the 7th, with accumulated snowfall in the process. The amount can reach 25-35 mm. The Huanan County Meteorological Observatory issued a red snow warning signal at 16:47 earlier: The snowfall in our county has reached more than 15 mm within 6 hours and the snowfall is still continuing. Please pay attention to precautions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The collapse of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City was related to rainfall. It rained frequently in the area for a period of time before the incident. Perlite can gain three times its weight after absorbing water, and the water is not easy to dissipate. After repeated rains, the weight of perlite will increase a lot. Moreover, these perlite building materials are not laid flat on the roof, but gathered in one place, which increases the pressure on part of the roof structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The roof of the collapsed gymnasium in Huanan County was covered with snow. Judging from the video posted online, the snow on the ground is not too deep. Winter has just begun in the Northeast at this time, and there should be no snow before. The snow on the roof is mainly caused by this snowfall. Unlike rain, snow does not accumulate in one place, and the pressure is basically evenly distributed to the entire roof. Is 15 millimeters of snow enough to collapse the roof of a stadium? Converted into pressure, it is only 15 kilograms per square meter, or 147N/square meters. The standard live load value for roofs that are not accessible to people is 0.5kN/square meter (50 kilograms of force per square meter). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City, which is an old building with a history of more than 30 years, according to media reports citing eyewitness reports, the collapsed gymnasium in Huanan County was a newly built urban complex in recent years. If the entire roof cannot withstand a pressure of 15 kgf/m², does its construction quality pass the standard? How did it pass the inspection in the first place? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after the collapse of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City, Heilongjiang Province held an emergency video conference on production safety throughout the province that night and requested that the buildings of various schools and public welfare sports venues be quickly organized and inspected. Safety. According to the Hunan County Government website, on the afternoon of July 24, 2023, the day after the roof of the No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium in Qiqihar City collapsed, the Magistrate of Hunan County went to the Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym to inspect the implementation of safety work. . Just over three months later, a very similar roof collapse accident occurred in this gymnasium, indicating that Huanan County was probably just a formality at that time and did not conduct serious safety inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four months before the collapse of the No. 34 Middle School gymnasium in Qiqihar City, the Qiqihar City Education Bureau also conducted a school building safety inspection. This safety inspection also failed to discover the serious safety hazard of a large amount of perlite piled on the roof of the stadium, which ultimately led to the tragedy. Although the cause of the accident was rainfall, it was also a man-made disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real cause of the roof collapse of the Huanan County Gymnasium has yet to be identified. But in any case, the roof collapse shows that the building safety inspection 3 months ago was definitely not in place. How many more of these superficial inspections, official business matters, and formalistic inspections are there? How many more lives must be paid in exchange for a true emphasis on safety? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This stadium easily passed the safety inspection 3 months ago. How to explain it? More importantly, this stadium is part of the Yuecheng Plaza urban comprehensive commercial complex built in 2018 as a local investment attraction project. The total construction area of ​​this complex is more than 110,000 square meters, including commercial, residential and supporting public buildings. If the construction quality of the stadium is so poor, are there any quality problems or safety hazards in other parts of the entire complex? This is a much bigger issue than the quality and safety of gymnasiums. It should be clarified what responsibilities the construction unit, supervision unit, developer and local regulatory authorities should bear respectively; it should also be clarified whether the person in charge of the club has any responsibility in this construction process, and the operator should not be allowed to take the blame for the entire incident. Xia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public expects answers to these questions as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[史国威：打破摄影与绘画的边界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/xg0hnrzo0ZCiBuLzrU0BwZisyNWVwdgt8GSxiT6p.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/xg0hnrzo0ZCiBuLzrU0BwZisyNWVwd gt8GSxiT6p. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256520&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Several cats are patrolling on the two-meter-long glass table. One is black, one is white, one is completely brown from behind, and one is hiding. I don&#39;t want to see anyone on the second floor, it&#39;s gray. They have accompanied the artist and traveled around with respect as guests for more than ten years. The studio has been demolished again and again, and now it has retreated to the edge of the city and rents a flight attendant dormitory near the Capital Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The indoor space is getting smaller and smaller. When Shi Guowei is painting on the first floor, his cats stay on the second floor of the loft; sometimes even if he goes downstairs and jumps on the workbench, he still knows that he is always and at the same time. Keep a distance of one meter from the painting area. Looking at these aging pets is like witnessing an overly clear ending. After giving away several cats one after another, he no longer dared to raise new cats. Thinking of the scene of standing in front of the crematorium furnace again and again, he couldn&#39;t help showing a look of pain, &quot;My heart really couldn&#39;t bear it.&quot; He can only take things as they come. &quot;I don&#39;t dare to take them for a physical examination. They are all so old. If the problems are found, they must be treated. The energy, time, and expense are all beyond my reach.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Had he known that he would have to face this kind of torture again and again, he might have chosen to bypass it in the beginning. It was 2006, and he had just returned from studying photography at the Dortmund University of Technology in Germany. Like many young people who were excited and trying to become artists at that time, he built a large studio in Heiqiao and posed for photos in the studio. After completion, photos of people, real outdoor scenes and objects with Chinese elements were collaged and combined following famous Western paintings, washed into a huge black and white photo nearly two meters wide, and finally hand-colored into a colorful painting. His father, who was in the bonsai business, sometimes came to see Shi Guowei and brought a litter of newborn stray cats from Laitai Flower Market, which was once the largest in Beijing. He couldn&#39;t bear to banish them, so he had to accept these brothers and sisters with different colors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A soft-hearted bachelor with nearly ten kittens (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;after giving birth to two litters, the female cat disappeared. was able to give up&lt;/span>;) and began his fashionable and ambiguous artistic career. He hired an intermediary to search for Russian models for him. They should not be curvy or beautiful, but should focus on ugliness and conflict. Venus is no longer a symbol of peace and tenderness. The fat naked girl has her eyes closed and is sleeping soundly. There are many weird plastic dolls beside her, and the Old Summer Palace is on fire in the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/f9uPJOCXa1XpSg5L8Ld0W0Sh05Qv0tIp47Rq4sKA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/f9uPJOCXa1XpSg5L8Ld0W0Sh05Qv0tIp47Rq4sKA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256521&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Flowing Sunset&quot; 2023, laser silver salt on paper, liquid paint, 130cm×177cm, photo/courtesy of the artist and Magician Space&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hans· Holbein&#39;s &quot;Ambassadors&quot; has been transformed by Shi Guowei. The characters have changed from wool-clad nobles to blood-covered butchers. The astronomical observation equipment in the original work has been replaced with those from the 1960s and 1970s. Objects are thrown on a blood-red blanket, and a photographed Buddha head represents the skull at the bottom of the oil painting - neat irony and confrontation are ready to emerge in these works that combine photography and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By around 2010, this experienced boilermaker (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; had weak heating in his studio. In order to survive the long winter, The artists in Heiqiao wore black coats and shoveled coal constantly to prevent it from burning out. Their faces and hands were black every day. When the coal was weighed in their hands, they knew how much it cost per ton&lt;/span>;) They created nearly twenty visuals Powerful nude work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It takes a lot of time to color photos by hand. This method was first used in his master&#39;s degree graduation work. In order to graduate successfully in Germany, Shi Guowei thought for a long time and thought that he should make up for his lack of shooting hardware, The shortcomings in technology are highlighted while the strengths in art are highlighted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in college, he studied photography in the Graphic Visual Arts Communication Department of Tsinghua Academy of Fine Arts, but the courses for the first three years had no direct connection with photography. He trained in sketching, color, sculpture and other skills every day. I took basic sketching courses for two years and developed the same painting skills as an art student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creative method of photography and painting was determined. In terms of content conception, he still focused on the comparison between Eastern and Western cultures that he was busy with in the following years. He invited foreign models to wear Mulan costumes, and then asked Chinese models to wear Robin Hood costumes. He may be dressed like a pope, but his face is painted with Peking Opera facial makeup. &quot;This one is easier to operate, and you can use a large landline phone. At least the materials are better than others. After the black and white photo is developed, I will use hand coloring to paint it into color. In this way, it will stand out immediately. You and I All students are different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ie6zEu59X0Q9LUBcLXmXPMFJFaUZngiHbtNqhDUy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;873&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ie6zEu59X0Q9LUBcLXmXPMFJFaUZngiHbtNqhDUy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256522&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Wool&quot; 2021, laser silver salt paper base, liquid paint, 180cm×198cm Image/Courtesy of the artist and Magician Space&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&quot;Why is there always meat in my paintings? Is there blood?&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he completed his graduation project, the one-meter-wide photo paper table could not fit on it, so he had to lie on the floor of the rental house and sketch with his hands. Holding two brushes, I used the fine brushwork and heavy color blending method I learned in technical secondary school, dipped a dab of dog tag paint sent from China, and immediately changed it to water to dye it evenly. I relied on these eight single photos to &quot;get ready for graduation.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Curator and critic Karen Smith once summed it up, &quot;He observed and recorded scenes, creating black-and-white photographs in the traditional photographic style, which he then painted by hand over a long period of time. This The process not only requires eye-hand coordination behind the camera lens, but also requires precise control of the way the brush is applied. After returning to China after studying at the Higher School of Photography in Dortmund, Germany, Shi Guowei gradually formed his own unchanging and compelling vision. The way of expression is a delicate and exquisite fusion between photography and painting. The combination of many materials and techniques also makes the work carry more connotations than the literal meaning of the label &#39;hand-colored photos&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the early days of his return to China, he recalled that the large amount of bloody violence and pornography in his works came from &quot;many years of repression in society. When he was studying in Germany, he spent most of his time working to make a living, and had no choice but to wash dishes in restaurants and go to restaurants. I worked the night shift in the factory carrying bags, doing the lowest level of work. Art and other things didn&#39;t matter to me. The first goal at that time was to have enough food to survive, and the second goal was to graduate as soon as possible so that I could have an explanation for my family. Yes. Only with this diploma can I make a living and do what I want to do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The works from those years appeared in a number of exhibitions, large and small, but received little recognition. &quot;At that time, I wanted to do something related to the West, thinking that everyone could understand it, but in fact, through several exhibitions, I found that people didn&#39;t know what I was going to do, and they didn&#39;t know the source. Now it looks like I was there at that time I shouted as loud as I could and yelled very strongly, but it had no effect, so I might as well be quieter. If the treatment was superficial in the past, now it is internal injuries. Even if the treatment is calm, the Qigong has actually penetrated the body. It&#39;s through your body.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Hxm6eYLC2cSPba4i9gtCjIUwz3t9kP9wVFjNhQ6A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;795&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Hxm6eYLC2cSPba4i9gtCjIUwz3t9kP9wVFjNhQ6A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256524&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Roshan&quot; 2021, laser silver salt paper base, liquid pigment, 184cm×154cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（ (Photo courtesy of the artist and Magician Space)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since about 10 years ago, the content of his creations has undergone tremendous changes. &quot;I slowly changed because I started walking in the mountains and taking some photos related to nature. I felt more and wanted to return to myself. The previous works were all about society and other people, and exported some of my understanding of the outside world. I know, it has nothing to do with myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Shi Guowei first turned to nature, what he pursued was still the similarity of shapes. He painted very finely and obscurely meticulously. The grass itself is green. The painting is still green, but the degree of greenness may be slightly different compared to the color photo. What he hoped to hear at that time was the audience&#39;s perception when they took a quick look and said, &quot;Hey, isn&#39;t this a color photo?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, he has turned more and more inward. When he goes to Lingshan Mountain, he may only take one or two touching photos. In the solo exhibition at Magician Gallery in September 2023, some of the paintings are from his travels in Xinjiang, the Daxinganling and other places. He became more and more strict when selecting, &quot;You will wonder whether this scene is related to me, and whether it is worth it.&quot; .&quot; The traces of coverage are getting heavier and heavier, making it almost difficult to see the original appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rocks are painted with the texture of raw meat in his paintings. No matter how magnificent the scenery is, through his eyes, it is often transformed into a cruel product. The deaths of pets and relatives lingered in his mind. When he saw the wool piled up like a huge yurt, waiting for wool traders to come and buy it, dark brown, light brown and yellow were intertwined in the wind. The herdsmen were used to it, and he only felt cruel. ; Seeing an Ewenki hunter kill a deer in 20 minutes, he recalled how he handled hares alone after hunting with his father when he was a teenager (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hook The scene of putting on the doorframe, lifting the knife, and peeling the skin&lt;/span>;), &quot;It was familiar and uncomfortable at the time, so why is there always meat in my paintings? Is there blood? This kind of atmosphere is throughout, but now it is used It is more stable and not as bloody as the large area more than ten years ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of my wife, who is also doing art work, this dyed image is not a restoration, but more subjective than reality. , is doubt and dissatisfaction with the realistic picture. Coloring the fictitious landscape in reality means putting aside the training of restoring color cards and extreme precision in past photography classes, and completing denial and rebellion in &quot;turning a blind eye&quot;. He once said, &quot;Over the years, I have been trying relentlessly to break the boundaries between photography and painting, just like breaking a decaying wall. To be more precise, I am trying to keep myself free from the edge, like an acrobat walking on a tightrope. Maintain balance and never fall to any side, no matter photography or painting. Only in this way can I face the things around me more clearly and calmly, so that I don&#39;t get lost. Just like the edge of the river, there are always weeds that are fatter than elsewhere. , where the nutrients are the most abundant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>