<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[证监会再出“新招”规范上市公司分红强化制度约束和激励]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256974]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:30:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the common wish of investors to obtain higher dividends within a reasonable range. On September 18, a reporter from 21st Century Business Herald learned that the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to launch a series of measures to improve the normalized dividend mechanism for listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has introduced and implemented a &quot;linking&quot; policy between dividends and shareholding reductions. Listed companies have not distributed cash dividends in the past three years, or the cumulative cash dividend amount is less than 30% of the average annual net profit in the past three years. , controlling shareholders and actual controllers are not allowed to reduce their holdings of the company’s shares through the secondary market. According to the person in charge of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, it is planned to further strengthen institutional constraints on companies that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends to urge dividends, promote the optimization of dividend methods and rhythm, so that companies that pay dividends can get more incentives, and at the same time, strengthen the supervision of companies that exceed their ability to pay dividends. constraints, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the amount of dividends paid and the proportion of A-share companies ranked among the top in the world. Data show that in the past five years, the amount of dividends paid by A-share listed companies has increased year by year, with a cumulative dividend of 8.2 trillion yuan, and the amount of dividends has exceeded the amount of financing that year. In 2022, a total of 3,291 Shanghai and Shenzhen listed companies in my country&#39;s domestic market paid cash dividends, accounting for 67.1% of the total number of listed companies at the end of 2022. The total cash dividends for the year reached 2.06 trillion yuan, of which the amount of dividends attributed to A-share shareholders was 1.62 Trillion yuan. From an international comparison, the number of dividend-paying listed companies in the domestic market ranks first among the world&#39;s major securities markets, the total amount of cash dividends ranks second in the world, and the proportion of dividend-paying companies ranks second in the world. In addition, 163 listed companies announced cash dividend plans for their 2023 semi-annual reports, with dividends expected to be 203.01 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Mature companies with continuous improvement in dividends, and companies listed on the main board have a higher proportion of dividends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the sustainability and growth of dividends of listed companies in my country have continued to improve. Data shows that as of 2022, the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for five consecutive years has increased from 20% ten years ago to 48%, and the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for 10 consecutive years has increased from 8% to 31%; 412 listed companies have paid dividends continuously. The proportion of companies that have grown in three years has increased from 3% ten years ago to 12%, and the proportion of companies that have grown in five consecutive years has increased from 1% to 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dividend yield and dividend payout ratio also show a fluctuating upward trend. The dividend yield distribution range has gradually increased from 0.5%-1.5% before 2010 to the current 1.5%-2%. In 2022, the average dividend payout rate in my country&#39;s domestic market is 32.5%, and the average dividend rate is 1.97%, which is in the middle and upper reaches of major global markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which sectors and industries pay higher dividends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders believe that dividend features are generally in line with the company’s development stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of sectors, the dividend payout rate of main board companies is the highest, reaching about 33%, which is 8 percentage points higher than the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of industries, industries with stable performance and low investment demand tend to have higher dividend ratios. Judging from the average dividend payout ratio, energy, major consumption, and public utilities rank among the top three, with dividend ratios as high as 50%, 48%, and 45% respectively. Listed companies in these industries have low new investment needs and relatively stable cash flow. Hence the average dividend payout level is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, the real estate, industry, and information technology industries have greater investment demand, and the average dividend payout ratio is also lower, at 28%, 26%, and 25% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the dividend level of A-share companies in the start-up and growth stages is lower than that of companies in the mature stage. Due to their relatively weak financing capabilities and strong willingness to save and defend, private enterprises have slightly lower dividend levels than state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Whether a high proportion of dividends is reasonable or not needs to be viewed comprehensively and accurately&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dividends of listed companies need to comprehensively consider multiple factors such as profitability, cash flow, debt, growth stage, development goals, etc. Different types of The attitudes and demands of shareholders towards cash dividends are not completely consistent, and it is necessary to balance the interests of the company and shareholders, major shareholders and small shareholders.&quot; The interviewed experts believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this expert, whether a company can pay dividends and how much it pays are mainly affected by three factors: first, the undistributed profits accumulated by the company from its operations in the current year and in the past; second, the cash it currently has; It is whether the retained earnings can meet the company&#39;s future development needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dividend ratio needs to be determined comprehensively based on the company&#39;s profitability, development stage, and future development needs. According to industry insiders, whether a company pays dividends and how much it pays are not necessarily linked to the profit of the year. Although the dividend ratio of some companies in individual years is relatively high, it is still reasonable. This must be comprehensively analyzed and viewed accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, some companies have stable profits and cash flow and have little investment demand, so they maintain a high dividend payout ratio. On the other hand, some companies will keep the amount of dividends unchanged despite declining profits or losses, and stabilize investor expectations through continued dividend payments, which will lead to higher dividend payout ratios in certain years. At the same time, in order to reduce redundant funds, some companies will implement special dividends based on accumulated undistributed profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts interviewed believe that, of course, it is not ruled out that major shareholders may distribute dividends arbitrarily and hollow out the company regardless of the company&#39;s future development needs. This should be strengthened, but this should be a very small number. To judge whether dividends are reasonable, we need to start from three dimensions: first, we need to see whether the profits are real and whether there is fraud; secondly, we need to see where the cash comes from and whether it is borrowed money to distribute dividends; finally, we must make a comprehensive judgment based on the motivation of major shareholders to pay dividends. A high proportion of dividends cannot be equated with dividends beyond capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, we need to view high-proportion dividends comprehensively and accurately. On the one hand, we must identify dividends based on false profits at the expense of the interests of listed companies; on the other hand, we welcome dividends based on the company’s true profit level and development needs. A high proportion of dividends that can effectively return investors.&quot; said an industry insider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four aspects will be followed to further standardize dividends of listed companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to revise the &quot;Regulatory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 3 - Cash Dividends of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Dividend Guidelines&quot; ) &quot;Guidelines on the Articles of Association of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association&quot;) and other rules have been revised. On the basis of the &quot;linking policy&quot; between dividends and shareholding reductions that have been introduced in the early stage, we will continue to improve and optimize the cash dividend supervision system and strengthen information disclosure supervision. , conveniently optimize the mid-term dividend payment process, better play the role of investment side, and continue to enhance investors’ sense of gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the head of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, this policy adjustment will proceed from four aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen institutional constraints and urge companies to pay dividends that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends. The first is to strengthen information disclosure supervision. For companies listed on the main board that do not pay a certain proportion of dividends, they are required to disclose and explain the reasons. The second is to strengthen disclosure requirements for companies with large financial investments, and urge companies to improve the efficiency of asset use and better focus on the main business and return investors. The third is to strengthen inquiries and supervisory interviews. Strengthen regulatory inquiries to help investors make better judgments on dividend information, and urge more dividends through interviews and other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, promote further optimization of dividend methods and rhythm. Specific measures in this regard can be summarized in two points: First, simplify the mid-term dividend payment procedures to facilitate the company to further increase the frequency of dividends and allow investors to better plan capital arrangements. Second, guide the company to formulate a dividend policy for stable growth. Promote companies to amend their articles of association to improve the operability of dividend policies; guide companies to explore dividend distribution policies with stable growth and reward investors with more stable dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, let companies with good dividends receive more rewards and &quot;taste the sweetness.&quot; On the one hand, it gives more &quot;honor&quot; to companies that pay good dividends. The exchange will study how to further favor high dividend-paying companies in the evaluation of information disclosure; the Listed Companies Association will study and optimize the preparation method of listed companies&#39; dividend lists and increase publicity efforts to guide companies to establish a correct value orientation. On the other hand, promote the development of more influential dividend index products; encourage fund companies to issue dividend fund products, and guide market funds to increase their preference for cash dividends from listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, strengthen restrictions on companies that pay dividends beyond their capabilities. Although paying dividends beyond capacity is not a prominent problem in A-shares, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will still pay close attention to it and take multiple measures to strengthen prevention. The first is to work hard to ensure that the company&#39;s performance is true and the basis for dividends is solid, and to effectively prevent listed companies from falsifying their finances and financing dividends. Second, for listed companies that have high asset-liability ratios and insufficient operating cash flow, but continue to pay dividends at a high proportion, detailed disclosure of the rationality of the dividend plan and its impact on the company&#39;s production and operations is required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“杀猪盘”受害者决定复仇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D57PCasl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D5 7PCasl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The story of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is inspired by a large number of real cases of &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, decided to take revenge after being defrauded of 550,000 yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met for the first time, Zhou Dongyu asked Ma Yingxin in a joking tone, what do you think about me? Like a person who has been cheated? It was September 2021, not long after Ma Yingxin returned to China. In the first week after arriving in Beijing, she had a meal with Zhou Dongyu and talked about Zhou Ran, the heroine of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, a victim of emotional fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingxin felt that the real intention in the witty words was that she thought the audience would not be convinced if she played a deceived person. Ma Yingxin’s answer: When you think you will not be cheated, you are basically increasing your chances of being cheated. After hearing this, Zhou Dongyu did not refute or admit, &quot;But she did go back and think about it for two days and said, let me play this role.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I believe that after the movie is released, the first reaction of the audience will be, will Dong Yu be deceived?&quot; Ma Yingxin told the Southern Weekend reporter, but this was precisely one of the reasons why she chose Zhou Dongyu. &quot;I don&#39;t want to choose someone who everyone will think will be deceived when they see her. Then she acted in this story. I don&#39;t think she conveyed anything. It&#39;s precisely Dong Yu who is like this. Maybe in the audience&#39;s perception, they don&#39;t believe her. If you will be deceived, then it will be more interesting for us to read this story.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was early autumn in Beijing in September. In an office building near the China World Trade Center, Ma Yingxin wore a black knitted sweater and pushed Wearing a wheelchair, he entered the conference room neatly. After a car accident when she was young, she has been using a wheelchair. Stopping in front of the long white table, she did not say any greetings and only said softly, &quot;Let&#39;s get started.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creation of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is based on a large number of real cases. The background of the story is the emotional scam in telecommunications network fraud, commonly known as &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. After 2019, Ma Yingxin began to receive relevant news frequently. What puzzled her was that mainstream comments were belittling and blaming the victimized women. They were &quot;love-brained,&quot; &quot;stupid,&quot; and even the word &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; itself was a stigma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people, without thinking deeply about this problem, think how could I be deceived. But in fact, so many people have been deceived.&quot; When writing the script, in addition to online information, Ma Yingxin also Ask a friend to find the real victim and chat. She discovered that there were many more victims than she thought, and many of them were very smart and outstanding people. Emotional deception is different from ordinary financial fraud. The victim will feel humiliated and dare not tell others. Some people do not even call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emotional fraud usually refers to online fraud that induces victims to make &quot;investments&quot; based on opposite-sex online dating. The long-term process of establishing an emotional relationship is called &quot;pig farming.&quot; In recent years, as more information has been disclosed, people have discovered that the means of emotional fraud are highly specialized and even involve psychological knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman working in the financial industry in a big city in China also had doubts when communicating with scammers. The other party claimed to be a colleague. She asked some questions about the industry intentionally or unintentionally, and the other party could answer them appropriately. After being deceived, the woman did not tell her family, and only a few friends vaguely knew about it. She worries that if her colleagues find out, what she says in the company will have no weight in the future. When talking to Ma Yingxin, she always used a relatively relaxed tone, &quot;I thought everyone had passed the financial test, so there should be no problem.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, Ma Yingxin finished writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;. The heroine Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, is a female drifter from Beijing who was defrauded of 550,000 yuan. She followed clues to a small coastal town and met the con man Lin Zhiguang, played by Zhang Yu, and his friend Xu Zhao, played by Zhang Youhao. Emotional deception is based on imitation, performance, manipulation, and insight into and gaming of the subtleties of the human heart. Zhou Ran decided to retaliate in his own way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The filming location of the movie was Dongshan Island in Zhangzhou, Fujian. Maying hoped to find an island filled with fog. When writing the script, the first thing that came to her mind was the scene of three people meeting in the fog. She thought that this scene was like the state of a deceived woman - &quot;She was in the fog and couldn&#39;t see anything, but a male voice kept coming. She had been in a heavy fog for nine months.&quot; Until the source of the voice came out of the fog and a specific image of a man appeared, the fog began to disperse. &quot;From this moment on, Zhou Ran saw some things clearly. She wanted to take action. Finally, she was not in a place shrouded in fog and without anything. A situation that cannot be caught. I see you clearly, but you don’t know my situation or my mentality. She took the initiative.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China. She has loved watching movies since she was a child. After online paid movies became available, her father paid two to three thousand yuan in internet fees in one month. As an adult, Ma Yingxin went to Spain to study and study law, where she lived for more than ten years. She likes Almodóvar, has been writing scripts for the past ten years, and has made short films &quot;Dead Words&quot; and &quot;Man in the Chair&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is Ma Yingxin&#39;s first feature film. As a new director living overseas, this project was set up by accident. A few years ago, she met the writer Shuang Xuetao at a literature lecture in Spain. She introduced that she was engaged in film work in Spain and also wrote scripts. Shuang Xuetao said, if you want to hear other people&#39;s opinions, you are welcome to send them to me. At the end of 2020, after writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, she sent it to Shuang Xuetao on WeChat, &quot;I said that we exchanged WeChat messages when you came to Spain two years ago. Who am I? At that time, you said that you could give the script to Look, I now have a story that happened in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, they had a long phone call. Shuang Xuetao was on the sidelines preparing to play football at the time, but did not play until the end of the game. &quot;We didn&#39;t talk too much about the script on that phone call. He was actually trying to find out if I could be a director.&quot; Later, Shuang Xuetao became the producer of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, and Don He, who had collaborated with &quot;Fire on the Plain&quot;, served as the producer. Producer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the one-and-a-half-hour interview, Ma Yingxin occasionally needed to put her hands on the armrests of her wheelchair and lift her body to relax. Before becoming a director, she may face some labels, &quot;maybe a woman, followed by my personal physical condition&quot;, which she can accept, but in the final analysis, she wants to introduce herself as: an honest creator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; partly comes from parroting. The liar uses parroting techniques to help teach and complete the deception, which is essentially an act of imitation. She wanted to express, &quot;Women&#39;s appreciation of emotions is not a disadvantage of women, or something that should be eliminated.&quot; This is part of being a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China in 1986 and has lived overseas for many years. &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is her first feature film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;These women are ordinary people&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Very smart, even outstanding&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;You once said that you would not make a movie based on a certain social issue, but rather that a certain issue fits the issue you want to discuss and use this issue to develop a story. You think &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is very much like a fable. What does it contain to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was watching the news about &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;, the comments below kept discussing that the victim was stupid and must be It’s some very stupid, love-minded women who get scammed. After seeing these words, I have doubts based on my understanding of people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think it is impossible for a person not to have emotional connections with people in this life. It is not only limited to emotional love relationships, but also has emotional and trusting connections with your friends and people around you. . If this is the case, a group of people come here, and they are deliberately trying to deceive you. What can you do? It has nothing to do with whether you are a smart person, unless you don&#39;t relate to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I tried to find out what kind of people the victims were. I read online information and asked friends to contact me. I came to the conclusion that these people were ordinary women, just like me and the people around me. Nothing is different, have normal expectations for life and love. They are very smart, even brilliant women. So I&#39;m not going to create a typical or any kind of spectacle victim image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding why people are deceived, I had a communication with the producer Shuang Xuetao. He said that liars are an ancient industry, and cheating with feelings has been happening since ancient times. , but in a different form today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of being deceived involves many essential human issues, such as people’s eternal desire for true love, and the use of emotions to manipulate, deceive, and game between people. This is a very tense relationship. , which is theatrically intense. So this story has two levels. One is that the &quot;pig killing plate&quot; itself is an unfair or biased impression of the female victims, and the other is that this issue also contains other more essential issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You start from the emotional state and inner struggle of the victim after being deceived. , was this perspective formed from the beginning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I spent half a year to a year thinking about the script. I feel that the creation is not a complete representation of reality, and I don’t want to film it. I have so many news materials in my hands and then put them together in the form of a movie. Movies need to have a structure that puts in the things you most want to discuss. Later, I started writing the script after having two relatively clear ideas. One was that I wanted the victim and the liar to meet in reality, and the second was that I wanted to reenact the process of cheating and being cheated. I wrote it on and off for about half a year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xue Tao is very interested in many liar movies. He feels that this movie is a subversion of liar movies, because they usually focus on liars and describe how powerful liars are. How clever. He said that you did it from the perspective of a victim, which kept the genre of the con man movie and was subversive at the same time. In addition, he also said that liars have existed since ancient times, including big liars, small liars, and industry liars, so this is also a movie about trust. From both perspectives, this issue is worth pursuing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, he said that I provided a female perspective, because if a man were to make this movie, it might turn out differently. Don He has worked with female directors before and feels that this is a female expression, which is very precious and should be expressed like this. As a male, he could not understand every expression in it very accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The two male protagonists in the story are engaged in &quot;pig killing&quot; in a fraud park, and their true identities are confusing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Don&#39;t think this movie is going to teach women a lesson&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you choose Zhou Dongyu to play Zhou Ran? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After we promoted this project, the first thing we considered was who would play Zhou Ran, because it depends on an actress. Get up drama. At that time Don He recommended Dong Yu because they had collaborated on &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot;. Frankly speaking, I was hesitant at the time. Of course Dong Yu is very good, but in my heart I am a girl, and I think this character is exactly the opposite of her screen image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot; was shown to friends and family, and I went to see it. In the first half of the movie, Dongyu was still a girl, but in the second half, she showed another state. . Another more important reason is that I found that Dong Yu can handle very complex emotions, which is a very rare ability, because Zhou Ran has to constantly deal with complex emotions, not a simple &quot;I want revenge&quot; character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand the complexity of the character Zhou Ran? There are a lot of undercurrents and real and fake games in this story. Do you think she ever hesitated? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think her determination for revenge started from the moment she met the liar, even before she met the liar. Yes, but it was after she met the liar that she decided how to take revenge. Because this liar walked up to her and said, I am sincere, how many difficulties I have, what a special person you are, and he is still using words at this moment. She may have wanted to put him in jail before, and wanted to catch him, but after that scene, something deeper was aroused. She felt that just letting him go to jail was not enough, so she adopted a series of subsequent methods. Including the voices she heard from other female victims in the car, it also gave her a lot of strength and she must do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But you said whether she swayed and struggled during the process, I think she did. Because she is an ordinary person, not a well-trained liar, her doing this is beyond the scope of what ordinary people can bear. If she didn&#39;t struggle, it was a revenge, I came to act a scene, without any emotional fluctuations, and finally sent you in, it was not so powerful for me. On the contrary, she struggled a little bit and finally completed it, which I think is a very powerful act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Through the perspective of female victims, the expression you ultimately want to point to What is it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think we can understand the common experiences of women and the common intellectual and emotional struggles through the experience of this victim. Especially in recent years, with the emergence of the so-called &quot;love brain&quot;, I feel that it has been dwarfing women&#39;s natural appreciation of emotions, and has obscured the real problem in such an incident, which is the use of Those who seek benefits based on emotions are at fault, or this is what society really needs to be vigilant about. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not actually the core of this movie, but my own idea is that I hope that we can at least make a movie with a female protagonist. When the audience walks out of the cinema, they don’t just feel This movie wants to teach women a lesson about how women should not do anything. In the very few screenings we had before, female viewers could understand her way of revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Yingxin believes that the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is a fable that contains more essential issues such as trust and emotion. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is sincerity? He doesn’t know either&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your account at Station B There was a special episode about Zhang Yu in &quot;Weekend Movie Party&quot;. How did it feel to work with Zhang Yu this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course, the role of Lin Chiguang is very different from his previous screen image, such as in &quot;The Calm&quot; and &quot;Siberian Tiger&quot; In it, he is a reserved, restrained and even repressed character, or another very reckless, direct, and fierce character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Zhiguang is completely different. He is a person who thinks very, very much. He is constantly performing true and false performances. He is very good at using language to manipulate others and use language to game or win. deceive others. The same thing is that Zhang Yu himself is also a very good thinker. At that time, he read the script and found it very interesting, but at the same time he had some opinions, so he wrote a page and sent it to Don He. A screenshot of the Don River was sent to me. When I saw it, I was very unconvinced and asked why you had so many opinions. So I wrote him a letter to answer these questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Zhang Yu is such an actor. He has a lot of questions to ask you, but after getting the answers, he can communicate and he will be very happy. Moreover, Lin Zhiguang has a relatively gentle trait in dealing with people. This is also something Zhang Yu himself has. He is also a very gentle person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was written on that piece of paper? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For example, why should I kill an octopus? Is this directed at me? What is the purpose of this image? I say that movies should not explain things. The more you explain, the less things you will learn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did he himself create anything for this character? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The language he created most is Lin Zhiguang’s language. We have fought many times about this matter. He wants Lin Zhiguang to have A very soft, Southern and not-so-Southern accent. This character deceived people and said that he was in Southeast Asia. He should have a unique accent, not Zhang Yu&#39;s accent, and not a Mandarin speaker. This was something he felt was very important to this character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your image of these two male scammers How do you understand it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Lin Zhiguang is a person who does not believe in anything. He plays Achang online and Lin Zhiguang in life, so he basically He is a person who lives in acting. He is very good at manipulating others and emotions. He is an empty, helpless and hesitant person. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Zhao is a ruined person. He arrived at that place relatively young. He has no understanding of all this and starts doing these things in order to survive. He has not really experienced what love is and what sincerity is, and he is already using it to deceive others, which leads to him being in a very chaotic state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in reality when he faced Zhou Ran and a real woman, he was actually very confused and couldn&#39;t tell whether he loved her or cherished her. Lin Zhiguang has a line that says, I thought you really liked her. He said I really like her, you said it, you have to be sincere. But what exactly is this sincerity? I don&#39;t think he knows either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Yingxin was at the shooting scene. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Women’s way of revenge is unique&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;Powerful&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zhou Ran The scene where he and Lin Zhiguang were kissing in the car was not a very direct kissing scene, it was even a bit like a &quot;borrowed position&quot;. Why is it designed this way? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; This is intentional, because they are not a physical relationship, but a spiritual game, so I will try to keep the physical part as low as possible pressure. The most important thing about that scene was the game of language and emotion. Zhou Ran used words one after another to break down Lin Zhiguang and gain his trust. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Finally Lin Zhiguang returned to the carriage, he was real Was he captured, or had to come back? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Someone has asked me this question before. I don’t think Lin Zhiguang fell in love with Zhou Ran in such a short period of time. , especially for a person like Lin Zhiguang, it is almost impossible. I think that at that moment he was delusional about this woman being able to forgive him and possibly even build a future life with him. Even though he was a liar, he had a moment of delusion and returned to this carriage. There&#39;s also the possibility that he needed to get back to the car to get the money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Yu handled that scene very complicatedly. I am almost reluctant to interpret that scene in words, but my core understanding is the final confrontation. Dong Yu’s performance is very effective. Power, she even made a face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Was that her own reaction? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, she suddenly made that move at that moment. I think it was a very powerful reaction, and it was only her. will give a reaction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For you, Zhou Ran’s final revenge Is it a feminist expression? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think I am very honest in this movie. I am a woman myself, so it must be a female expression, but Is it an expression of feminism? Frankly speaking, I am still learning about feminism. But the film at least proposes a way for a woman to see things and how she acts. When it comes to revenge, you always think of it as a violent act, because the association brought by revenge was previously created by male movies or male-dominated movies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think this is a new impression, and the way women take revenge is unique. If you agree that emotions or lies can hurt people, then her way of revenge is powerful. Indeed, some viewers may feel that it is not satisfying enough and expect some more violent or more intense forms of revenge. But to me, this approach is really powerful, rather than something more violent and external. I think she really used how a person was destroyed to seek revenge or respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then do you think Lin Zhiguang has experienced this kind of harm, or received this Information? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Lin Zhiguang is at least surprised, something he didn’t expect. At least in terms of performance, Zhang Yu&#39;s character looked at Zhou Ran very hard in the last scene. He just wanted to see some answers, but he couldn&#39;t. I think at least this question will bother him. And besides being brought to justice, he might have a chance to truly reflect on what he&#39;s done in the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[211高校女硕士遭杀猪盘被骗138万：财务决策与婚恋决策分开是防骗关键]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，“211女硕士遭杀猪盘两周被骗138万”冲上热搜第一。当事人雪儿从江苏某211院校硕士毕业后，入职上海某银行。今年五六月份，她在某社交平台发布了择偶的帖子。一男性主动与她联系，称他住在上海杨浦区五角广场，毕业于上海财经大学，在互联网大厂工作，此时在北京出差。在网上交流一段时间后，对方给雪儿发了一个链接，让她点击下载一个名为“luno”的app，教她在上面买币，然后用币买涨买跌，赚点外快。刚开始雪儿赚了一些钱，随后，对方以各种理由让雪儿先后投入130多万，最终雪儿发现陷入骗局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;层出不穷的“杀猪盘”，对各类人群通杀，针对男性的裸聊陷阱，针对女性的婚恋陷阱，显示了骗子对两性心理差异的精准把握。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然拥有高学历、高收入、高颜值，但不少女性也深陷其中。究其原因，某些高知女性在婚恋中，往往没有做好财务决策和婚恋决策，尤其是混为一谈，使骗子有机可乘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓财务决策，涉及资金方面的支出、投资等行为，需对投资项目的合理可行性、投资规模、投资止损标准、投资失败带来的后果等，进行综合考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“杀猪盘”的变现套路，往往是以高息诱导受害人。然而，你图的是高息，骗子瞄准的是你本金。人们应建立一个投资常识，投资产品的预期收益与投资风险是正相关的。就如日常购买各类理财产品，理财产品会标注不同等级，预期年化收益率不高但标注低风险的理财产品，主要投资于高信用等级债券（如国债）、货币市场等低风险金融产品，而预期年化收益率高但标注中高风险的理财产品，则投资产品组合中股票、商品、外汇等高波动性金融产品的占比高。理财机构在客户购买产品时，还要进行个人投资风险评估，根据其填报的以往投资品类、收入状况等信息，为其推荐更符合其风险偏好的投资品种，避免其盲目投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，当女方听到对方介绍“包赚不赔、利息远超市场平均水准”的投资产品时，就应引起警惕。郭树清曾经提醒过广大金融消费者和投资者：高收益意味着高风险，收益率超过6%就要打问号，超过8%就很危险，10%以上就要准备损失全部本金。另外，就是不要轻信不明信息，不要随意透露个人信息，不要打开不明网络链接，不要轻易汇款转账。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但凡遇到大额资金投资，事先多了解一些投资理财专业知识，或者请具有相关经验的人士或机构提供建议，然后根据自身风险承受能力、资金面等，进行投资与否、投资金额、出现问题如何及时止损等方面的决策，应成为所有人具备的“财商”。尤其是作为高知女性，更应有起码的学习能力。上述案例的雪儿在银行工作，虽然从事IT工作，但找几个懂理财的同事请教并非难事，可她被男方尤其是“投资”最初的获利所惑，一步步深入陷阱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，男女还要做好婚恋决策。一般而言，在婚恋市场，男女双方的诉求排序不同。男性往往更看重女性颜值、年龄等，女性则将男性的财富、家庭背景等标准作为重点。对于高知女性而言，婚恋市场上某方面优秀的男性不少，但富人则很少，兼具外形和财富的高富帅，属于典型的稀缺人群，他们的选择空间极大，所以对“高富帅”的竞争其实是很激烈的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;骗子之所以打造高富帅人设，在于他们深知这一人群身处卖方市场，女性往往求之难得。一旦遇到，某些女性急于将白马王子牢牢抓住，有严重的依赖心理，易对骗子言听计从。部分女性过于追求爱情的完美和投资的高收益，忽视了现实中的风险和不确定性。在面对“杀猪盘”骗局时，受到情感和利益的双重诱惑，从而掉入骗子的陷阱，最终人财两失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论男性还是女性，进行婚恋决策，至少要做好三点事先评估：其一，客观评估自身条件，自己在婚恋市场的大致排序是什么？不要净想着买两块钱彩票中五百万。知人者智，自知者明，古人诚不我欺。其二，如果对方的言行与人身让你很舒服，如浴春风，那就不要太上头，应该吹一下冷风，用理智判断一下，对方就是这样的人品还是处处在迎合你？贪图情绪价值可以理解，但对方暗中的标价可能昂贵到你难以承受。其三，哪怕认定对方是真命天子，也别将婚恋决策和财务决策捆绑。越来越多走到婚姻这一步的男女，都开始强调婚后财产、生活开支“AA制”，你何以婚前就能将血汗钱交给对方帮忙投资？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 10:25:34 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳门街坊的横琴生活：粤澳合作区两周年记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/3IlYVTST4u7boDGwr3CZwE7hFkzeXhdwCKSbR0bN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎明破晓，伴随着旅客通关时发出的清脆提示音，伫立在横琴口岸的新旅检大楼，再度迎来了繁忙时刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天，约1.2万人次港澳居民经横琴口岸往返琴澳两地，澳门居民黄惠霞正是其中一员。差不多两年前，她迁居横琴粤澳深度合作区，成了一名“新横琴人”；如今，她长居横琴，每周会返回澳门三四次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“交通更便利了、房子更宽敞了、生活环境更舒适了、社区服务更完善了、来合作区的澳门人越来越多了……”谈到在横琴两年的生活感受，黄惠霞如数家珍。而未来，随着澳门轻轨延伸横琴线项目投入使用，横琴到澳门的交通将会更加便利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年9月5日，《横琴粤澳深度合作区建设总体方案》（以下简称《横琴方案》）印发，赋予横琴“促进澳门经济适度多元发展的新平台”“便利澳门居民生活就业的新空间”“丰富&#39;一国两制&#39;实践的新示范”“推动粤港澳大湾区建设的新高地”四大战略使命。12天后，横琴粤澳深度合作区管理机构正式揭牌，合作区建设驶入“快车道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自2009年《横琴总体发展规划》印发以来，国家相继出台了一系列创新政策，为横琴发展擘画美好蓝图。”中山大学区域开放与合作研究院院长毛艳华告诉南方周末记者，“横琴粤澳深度合作区具有区位条件优越、合作基础扎实、扶持力度大等多重优势，目前的发展势头正盛，而未来一定更加可期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;横琴的澳门街坊&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我原来在澳门的房子很小，只有六十多平方米，搬到横琴后，居住面积一下子增加到150平方米。”迁居横琴两年，黄惠霞对横琴的居住环境、交通条件、社区服务、医疗以及通关等方面的变化，有着最真切的感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初秋的天沐河水光潋滟，两岸绿树成荫，草木繁盛。沿着河边全长约7.2公里的生态长廊漫步，生态群落区、公园式社区等极具韵律感的城市滨水景观带渐次铺开，而一水之隔就是澳门塔、新葡京大厦、美高梅酒店等澳门地标性建筑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞两年前从澳门搬到横琴上村，那里有60%的住户都是澳门居民。上村距离天沐河步行只需要十分钟左右，每日闲暇的时候，她都会到河边散步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞还清楚记得刚搬到横琴时的情形，那时候由于人流量不足，公交线路很少，回澳门一趟要在路上折腾很久。“现在我每周都要往返澳门三四次，出了小区就有好几趟公交车可以抵达横琴口岸。”黄惠霞告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;横琴口岸位于横琴岛十字门水道西岸，与澳门一桥相连，处于“一国两制”的交汇点和“内外辐射”的接合部。目前，横琴口岸已经实现“合作查验、一次放行”，出入境人员只需“在一个大厅、排一次队、接受一次检查”就可完成内地、澳门双方出入境手续，人均通关时间只需30秒左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通关时间大大缩短，流程更加优化，让两地往返的澳门居民过上了更加舒适的双城生活。黄惠霞明显感觉到，每日通关到合作区的澳门居民越来越多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据统计，目前在横琴定居就业的澳门居民达7000余人，经横琴口岸出入境的港澳居民日均客流从2022年的5900余人次，增长至2023年的近1.2万人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了居住环境、日常起居和交通条件上的重大改善，横琴合作区的养老、医疗和社区服务也在不断向澳门标准靠拢。2019年，澳门街坊会联合总会在横琴设立服务中心，组成专业服务团队，为合作区内年满60周岁的老人提供澳门标准的居家养老上门服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“截至2023年8月底，我们已为琴澳两地居民提供服务逾96万人次。”澳门街坊总会一名负责人告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而得益于跨境执业政策持续推进，目前在横琴执业的港澳短期行医医师累计有67名。包括黄惠霞在内的“新横琴人”足不出区，就可以找熟悉的澳门医生看诊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们在横琴可以就地参保，享受和珠海市民同等的医保待遇，就医买药都很便利，而且个人花费也不高。”黄惠霞说，“后续&#39;澳门新街坊&#39;项目竣工后，将有澳门医疗团队进驻，还配备有大型医疗服务中心，以后的生活将更加便利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄惠霞所提到的“澳门新街坊”，是合作区首个为澳门居民打造的综合性民生工程，会配套各项澳门标准的公共服务和社会福利，将为超万名澳门居民打造优质宜居社区。目前，该工程已进入验收阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“未来在合作区的生活肯定会越来越好。”黄惠霞告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“四新产业”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;借着横琴合作区快速发展的东风，王瑞明来到横琴寻求发展。刚刚过去的几个月，他收购了一家澳资企业，计划成立新公司，主要从事金融和互联网产业，预计将于9月底正式开业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为从事合作区重点支持的金融行业，他的公司可以享受15%税收优惠政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王瑞明是一名“侨三代”。近几年，受粤港澳大湾区营商政策、环境吸引，他一直在湾区积极布局，先后在香港和深圳注册了金融公司，主营基金、信托和保险等业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“横琴的金融产业高度开放、跨境资本自由流动，是跨境人民币结算最活跃的地区，有很多世界五百强企业落户这里，未来很有希望成为中国金融业对外开放的新高地。”王瑞明告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年上半年，合作区内金融业增加值达88亿元，占&lt;span>;GDP&lt;/span>;近四成，同比增长2.9%，呈现出加速集聚的态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“合作区围绕&#39;四新产业&#39;扎实推进，不仅对产业定位更加明确，而且共商共建共管共享体制机制也已经初步搭建。”毛艳华指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澳门地少人多，不足33平方公里的土地上生活着逾68万人口，平均每平方公里超过2万人，是世界上人口密度最高的城市之一。土地资源不足、产业结构单一等难题，一直困扰着澳门发展。而与澳门一水之隔的横琴，面积达106平方公里，空间优势显著，为支撑澳门经济多元发展提供了充足空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2009年8月，国务院就批准实施《横琴总体发展规划》，明确指出要以横琴为载体，共同打造跨界合作创新区，为逐步改变澳门经济结构比较单一的问题提供新的空间。而伴随着粤港澳大湾区高质量发展逐步推进以及《横琴方案》出台，琴澳融合上升到新高度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自开发之初，横琴就被赋予了服务澳门经济多元发展的使命。十几年的开发建设中，这一使命不仅没有变，而且更加突出。”毛艳华指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自揭牌运作以来，横琴合作区聚焦“四新”战略定位，大力发展科技研发和高端制造、中医药等澳门品牌工业、文旅会展商贸以及现代金融产业“四大产业”，针对集成电路业、金融业、文旅会展业等推出一系列新政。两年的时间，一批批重点项目加快推进，琴澳一体化发展格局已初步建立，促进澳门经济适度多元发展的支撑作用正在逐步显现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅在2023年上半年，合作区实际运营的集成电路企业就超40家，初步形成涵盖知识产权（IP）、第三代半导体等领域的集成电路设计产业生态；粤澳合作中医药科技产业园一季度企业税收贡献近8000万元，同比增长59%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产业集聚以及政策红利之下，横琴粤澳深度合作区已成为澳人澳企投资创业的新平台和新高地。目前，合作区有澳资企业超过5600户，较合作区挂牌前增长22.3%，注册资本超1480亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《横琴方案》开启了粤澳深度合作区建设的新篇章。”毛艳华表示，“未来合作区建设要继续围绕服务澳门产业多元发展这一初心，从建设一流产业功能园区出发，大力发展实体经济，利用好创新体制，进一步吸引园区内外要素充分流动集聚，从而打造珠江西岸高质量发展的新增长极。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中黄惠霞、王瑞明系化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[接连停运，有轨电车真的没“出路”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256990]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8spu9Ts8vYeI5iLwBTHBFbpnaz72rSzHzGpQrZ3O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2019年8月，运行中的上海张江有轨电车，被市民昵称“铛铛车”。2023年6月，张江有轨电车停运。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;复古、高颜值、小清新……城市有轨电车曾带有这样的网红标签，但这几个月来，有轨电车停运的消息频出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月，网上流传的公告称，由于运营资金困难，云南红河州现代有轨电车将于2023年8月10日停止运营。8月11日，红河州现代有轨电车有限公司董事长回应该公告为假消息，目前当地有轨电车并未停运，正常运营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月，运营16年的天津开发区导轨电车一号线宣布停运并启动拆除项目采购。6月，运营13年的上海张江有轨电车1路停运并火速拆除轨道。两年前，2021年，广东珠海的有轨电车在开通运营3年多后，停运并计划拆除。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MFU4iCeil74t0PSJ2oM9bHP91GNq7BXwGV6rPpbL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月，上海张江有轨电车停运，工人正在拆除轨道。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（刘诗君/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，全国39条有轨线路已有3条停运。根据中国城市轨道交通协会发布的《城市轨道交通2022年度统计和分析报告》（下称《报告》），截至2022年底，全国23个城市共计39条有轨电车线路投入运营，运营里程达578.3公里，相当于北京到上海距离的一半。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;停运的首要因素是客流量低，此类新闻并非首次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年12月，成都有轨电车蓉2号线先通段开通后，由于线路未接入城市轨道交通网络，客流量低，导致社会舆论压力较大，遭受“有轨电车是鸡肋”的争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有轨电车为何屡遭停运？如何避免“运椅子”情况的发生？相较于客流量大的地铁，有轨电车属于“城市轨道交通低运能系统”，中国城市轨道交通协会专家和学术委员会副主任、现代有轨电车分会副会长李鸿春告诉南方周末，做好线网规划，实现多种交通制式高度融合，低运能系统可以系统健康发展，国内也有很多成功案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;客流量低是停运关键&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;客流不足、亏损严重是有轨电车停运的关键原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据界面新闻报道，到停运前，上海张江有轨电车日客运量已锐减到1000人次左右。公交爱好者、在张江上班的王青峰（化名）回忆，有时候“从起始站上车，一路上几乎没什么乘客上车”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7GRIEZBCekfhBuWMbwlWJsFG8aA4glabsEoy3T9I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年1月25日，工作日下午两点，上海张江有轨电车车厢内几乎没有乘客，仅有一名售票员。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;否认停运传言的红河州有轨电车的运营压力也不容乐观。据交通运输部发布的7月全国52个城市轨道交通运营数据，红河州有轨电车客运强度0.01（万人次/公里·日），在全国垫底。当月客运量仅有2.6万人次，平均每日不到900人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tmq4xCmR5RV33EHVVB48glNjtPxj5yA5Jau13Uos.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251206&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018年3月29日，云南红河，有轨电车进行联调联试。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;运营频次低是影响客流量的重要原因。发车间隔时间越大，客流吸引力越低，客流低又进一步影响发车间隔，形成了恶性循环。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张江有轨电车的班次停运前间隔为15到20分钟，对于通勤的乘客来说，等待时间过长。“与其等有轨电车，不如扫一辆共享单车。”王青峰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只共享单车，上海地铁2号线东延伸段、11号线、13号线等多条地铁线路的开通运营，都分散了有轨电车的客流。停运前，2023年2月，张江有轨电车减少了运行时间，从全天17小时运营调整为仅在早晚高峰开行4个班次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海浦东现代有轨交通有限公司在公告中称，近年来，张江地区公共交通体系不断丰富完善。多条城轨线路开通运营，地面公交线路多次优化调整，张江有轨电车1路客流逐年下降，将由地面公交替代衔接。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;技术适用性不足，维护成本高昂&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除客流低、发车间隔大外，天津开发区与上海张江的有轨电车均受制于车辆为进口产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二者均采用法国劳尔公司生产的Translohr系统，胶轮、单轨道、占地小，但全球使用该系统的城市并不多。随着劳尔公司被收购后逐渐没落，相关零部件产量大减，导致车辆维修费用高、维修周期长，部分零部件面临“断供”风险。零部件采购困难，也导致了上海张江和天津开发区有轨电车的维护困难、成本过高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王青峰回忆，以前乘坐张江有轨电车时，发现司机驾驶室里居然有一根粗木杆。轨道有时候会被杂物堵塞，驾驶员需专门下车用木杆清除杂物，非常影响交通效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于珠海有轨电车，李鸿春此前在接受采访时提到，其采用的TramWave地面供电系统缺少工程实践，建设方对该技术的适用性等认识不足，造成线路开通后系统故障率高、运营服务不稳定。同时，客流量低、维护成本高昂等原因直接影响了原计划续建的1号线剩余段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除频次低外，停运的有轨电车还被认为运行速度太慢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《报告》显示，2022年地铁的平均旅行速度为36.47公里/小时，全国有轨电车平均旅行速度只有22.3公里/小时，而张江有轨电车的旅行速度仅19公里/小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，张江有轨电车最高设计时速为70公里，运行速度慢是因为有轨电车没有专用路权——和所有车辆共享道路空间，仍然要受到红绿灯制约。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height=&quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MULPiJB1yaIIJktaDidZAsI5dHdXiQeen0UHbVz8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上海张江有轨电车没有专用路权，和所有车辆共享道路空间，仍然要受到红绿灯制约。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长长的有轨电车等红绿灯时，加剧了拥堵。比如张江有轨电车途经上海外国语大学附属浦东外国语学校，家长接送孩子时会把私家车停在路边，有轨电车开进来后会占住整个道路。一位市民表示：“要么借旁边的非机动车道超车过去，要么就只能跟在铛铛车的后面。”铛铛车为上海市民对张江有轨电车的昵称。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;规划问题，而非制式问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;放眼全球，有轨电车并非小众。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国城市轨道交通协会现代有轨电车分会发布的《中国有轨电车发展报告（2020）》显示，地铁和有轨电车是世界城市轨道交通的主流制式，其中地铁占47%，有轨电车占42%，轻轨占11%。在欧洲，有轨电车是不少城市的主流公共交通方式，如德国柏林，有轨电车在轨道交通里程中占比高达55.6%。而在中国，这一占比仅为5.71%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有声音提出，有轨电车来到中国之后“水土不服”。但李鸿春提醒，不少有轨电车项目运营得不错。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在超大、特大城市，有轨电车可以作为地铁等大中运能系统的延伸线和加密线。比如北京的西郊线，作为地铁10号线的延伸线，起于巴沟站，连接香山公园、国家植物园、玉泉郊野公园和颐和园等旅游景点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;西郊线的定位就是“以通勤为主，旅游观光为辅”，李鸿春补充说。西郊线是全国首条重联运营的有轨电车——两节车组连在一起，以增大客流量，在2019年“香山红叶节”期间最高日客流达到9.47万人次，成为全国单日进站客流最高纪录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/s3uq4s1bVWB4UFBFEPYKPTqk9SJPFsZy9Wmvy4UG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年“五一”期间，北京西郊线为降低车厢满载，采用重联运营模式，单列从5节车厢变为10节车厢，每日8组重联列车上线运营，最小发车间隔5分钟。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（中新社记者贾天勇视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在江苏淮安，有轨电车甚至作为城市的骨干公交，保证了客流需求。淮安有轨电车一号线是国内首条进入城市核心区的有轨电车线路，客流一直居全国有轨电车线路前列。据交通运输部发布的7月全国52个城市轨道交通运营数据，淮安客流量为58万，每日可达近两万人次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;665&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YZuUx67kFi1vu1dBrGUZDMvEdIKHCoUO5fyNCSws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2020年3月16日，江苏省淮安市，因疫情停运的现代有轨电车恢复运行。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在旅游区，有轨电车还可发挥特色旅游公交作用，比如福建南平武夷新区线路，连接了南平市高铁站至武夷山站，与武夷山景区无缝衔接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从成功运营的有轨电车经验看，与地铁等大运能系统不同，有轨电车作为低运能系统是在存量道路资源上再开发，具有一定难度，需因地制宜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李鸿春认为，部分有轨电车停运，反映的不是有轨电车制式本身的问题，而是在规划设计上存在问题。比如珠海有轨电车一期工程附近区域大多是高档社区，居民出行以小汽车为主，而且线路北侧以山体为主、沿线开发强度低、居住用地少、商业设施缺乏、线路为单边辐射，导致客流量低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何合理规划，李鸿春认为，有轨电车的定位是填补大运能地铁和常规公交之间空白的环保型交通系统，首先要保证公共交通规划层次清晰，加强与综合交通枢纽的衔接，要处理好有轨电车和常规公交系统的分工，线网布局考虑大运能系统与中低运能系统的融合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/DmwvK48RywdbQN78U7uYDMv8EtXxxxr81ofWHEj6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2020年12月26日，福建省南平市武夷山市首辆有轨电车缓缓驶出仙店车辆段，进入试运行阶段。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如三亚有轨电车设在最临近三亚火车站出入站的位置，嘉兴有轨电车车站与两侧新开发校区采用人行地道直接连接，这些设计都更加方便居民乘坐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;选址需要有一定的人口密度支撑。李鸿春提到，要精准预测线路廊道客流，避免出现实际客流量没有达到预估量的情况。在建设时序上，“要先考虑哪最需要建，而不是哪里更容易建”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都蓉2号线先通段开通时，由于还未接入城轨网络，客流量低遭到质疑，而后通段开通后，与地铁实现接驳，客流达到接近四万人，增长了几十倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在运营方面，针对有轨电车路权问题，李鸿春认为要为有轨电车提供优先通行信号，保障有轨电车运营安全、速度以及效率。比如淮安有轨电车1号线就配备三大系统：有轨电车信号优先控制系统、路口闯红灯电子警察和路段卡口系统以及路口视频监控系统，并安排交通协理员，实现有轨电车在路口优先通行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李鸿春认为，在我国城市化进程高速发展和私家车拥有率大幅度提高导致拥堵的双重影响下，发展公共交通是历史的必然趋势。而地铁的建设成本比有轨电车高至少十倍，有轨电车相比于公交车具有运量大、舒适度和准点率高的优势，在碳达峰碳中和的趋势下，有轨电车是公共交通建设的重要选项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[哈尔滨：黄昏缄默的时候，建筑在说话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;1909年10月26日上午9时30分，从宽城子（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;长春&lt;/span>;）乘坐专车抵达哈尔滨的伊藤博文走下列车，一位头戴鸭舌帽、身着洋服的矮小男人从容不迫地向其胸、肋骨、腹连开三枪，又向随行日本官员连开四枪，以俄语高呼“乌拉高丽亚！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发突然，众人犹在梦中。伊藤博文被抬上专列，30分钟后死去。那位面容决绝的男人——安重根，以一种近乎悲壮的姿态被俘；划过1899年始建、1903年定名的哈尔滨火车站上空的七声枪响，却急速而深刻地改变了20世纪初的东北亚局势——虽然火车站于1959年拆除后又重建，如今车站还有安重根义士纪念馆、事发站台仍有这一事件的鲜活痕迹：地面上的“∆”和“□”，分别为安重根和伊藤博文所站位置，两者相距约5米。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/BzUbpnhNJemtaGe2sadLVozJk7FY8TzRbmI4NHrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;哈尔滨火车站旧景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就如果戈里所说，“当诗歌和传说都已经缄默的时候，只有建筑在说话”——火车站周边，一切都与百多年前完全不同了，只有圣伊维尔教堂还静静地“倚靠”在站边。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;大街：“多元文化的交叉传播”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;没有城墙的“老哈尔滨”其实既不古老、也不现代——它是在火车的轰鸣声中成长为“现代城市”的。甲午战争中国的失利及沙俄以联合御日为诱饵、在中国东北攫取更多利益等诸多因素，催生了中东铁路的修建——1896年俄国得到中东铁路修营权，当年6月，俄国中东铁路建设总局由符拉迪沃斯托克（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;海参崴&lt;/span>;）迁到哈尔滨，与此同时，铁路以此为中心分东西南三线六端同时相向施工。作为西起满洲里、东接绥芬河、南到大连旅顺的全长2500公里的“丁”字形铁路的中心，这里迅速成为“楼宇冲霄、商贾辐辏、地价飞腾、尺土寸金”的国际化城市——“荒凉原野，瞬易为繁华大埠”。资本主义成为哈尔滨迅速成长崛起的“动力”，但同时外资又抑制、阻碍了民族资本主义的发展，使其成为中国传统城市与近代资本主义城市之间的“异类”；一条铁路，更对哈尔滨本土建筑文化构成巨大冲击，一股股带有强制性和取代性的建筑设计风潮——整合、附加、变异……在百多年前的缄默黄昏中，在这个拥有奇妙特质的城市里，开始不断“涵化”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/D2guwa6iQiMwc38cNPPYloIc751903YJ6dUZCGdE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;今日哈尔滨火车站与圣伊维尔教堂&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从哈尔滨火车站笔直冲射而出的红军街原名霍尔瓦特大街，是哈尔滨建城的起点与萌芽，以它为轴心向外扩散，显化出城市生长的年轮。龙门贵宾楼原址于1907年建成，另一端，曾是俄驻哈尔滨总领事馆和俄国外阿穆尔军区军官俱乐部，以及东北大地上“赫赫有名”的大和旅馆；1920年建成的华俄道胜银行，如今是黑龙江省文史研究馆，仍然保持着原有的法国文艺复兴风格；契斯恰科夫茶庄的古典主义、巴洛克和文艺复兴风格混杂的外凸窗、挑檐雨棚、露天阳台，掩映在绿树之中，看着“汇丰照相机商行”的招牌，让人难以联想到它是由侨居哈埠37年的俄籍犹太建筑师日丹诺夫设计的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;红军街与东西向的大直街，曾经在古哥特式木结构的圣尼古拉教堂相交。如今圣尼古拉教堂早已踪迹全无，建于1937年的国际饭店外形如同巨大的手风琴，与之对望的是原意大利领事馆、建于1919年的积别洛索高大楼，满布精美浮雕的八角形外墙层层向上叠加，形成巴洛克风格为主的折中主义可爱建筑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一组“庄重VS可爱”的建筑则在大直街上，著名的“大石头房子”哈尔滨铁路局办公大楼，1904年2月落成时为中东铁路管理局，形体宏伟，威仪端庄，宛如一座“巨大的城堡”；与之隔街可望的哈尔滨铁路博物馆，内部装饰古朴，外观则从它作为中东铁路俱乐部的时代开始，就保持着黄白相间的色彩，充满快乐气息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;圣尼古拉教堂所在之地“喇嘛台”，是哈尔滨地势最高点，松花江涨水时也能免受洪水侵袭，因而1899年起，俄国开始对此地所处的秦家岗地区（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今南岗区&lt;/span>;）进行大规模城市建设，五年内，中东铁路管理局大楼、莫斯科商场大楼（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今黑龙江省博物馆&lt;/span>;）等欧式建筑竣工，秦家岗东西轴线——霍尔瓦特大街、大直街和新商务街（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今果戈里大街&lt;/span>;）等主干街路建成。上世纪30年代，秦家岗地区“建筑宏壮，市街整齐”“空气清新，花香馥郁”，外国领事馆多集中在此地，成为哈尔滨的行政中心和外侨聚居地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/POHCoGfzXQASjZiCsl05TymX7339hGaP0MfzKjpW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;位于今日南岗区的秋林公司&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东西方文明的各个子系统在这里互相撞击、摩擦、渗透、交融，世界各族裔建筑文化的空前整合，呈现出一种“多元文化的交叉传播”。中东铁路带来了大量侨民——据统计，1923年哈尔滨总人口达40万，侨民近20万，国人18万余，日俄战争后哈尔滨开埠二三十年，已俨然一座国际都市，为这里带来了俄罗斯文化、犹太文化、日本文化、鞑靼文化……更带来了圣尼古拉教堂、圣索菲亚教堂、圣母领报教堂等近70座教堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日丹诺夫之于哈尔滨，就如邬达克之于上海。东大直街上“扎堆”的三座教堂中，日丹诺夫设计的圣母帡幪教堂（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;圣母守护教堂&lt;/span>;）最为惹眼。这座拜占庭风格的教堂据说保存了1899年在莫斯科浇铸的2600公斤重的大钟，只是今时无缘得见——可以看到的是教堂边竖着的告示牌：“请注意行为，上帝正在注视你”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;教堂：钟声回荡&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不像圣母帡幪教堂倚靠在车水马龙的城市主干道上，同样由日丹诺夫设计的鞑靼清真寺，隐藏在通江街居民楼间，红白相间的墙体富有拜占庭风格的静谧凝重气质，宛如一座“神秘的小城堡”，特别在黄昏时分，很有古朴之感。从1899年首位俄籍犹太人萨·伊·别尔采里来到哈尔滨，至上世纪40年代，无数犹太人曾经来到这“第二故乡”，在这里建起包括穹顶擎起大卫之盾六角圣星的犹太总会堂在内的众多犹太建筑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1HabQM6pie3ncVV0BRvXt7M6hTGjo46S3QHdSKxA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;鞑靼清真寺&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至少在百年前，雄浑的钟声曾回荡在哈尔滨上空，在钟声中，各国侨民、各色冒险家与流亡者都曾驻足聆听，在这个异乡找到故乡的片刻慰藉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈尔滨的象征——圣索菲亚教堂，在重要宗教节日奏响的悠扬钟声，可以说是老一辈哈尔滨人对城市深切的记忆。据说在冬天雪日中的教堂，拜占庭风格的外形能够让更多的雪留在建筑表面，风吹起雪花，纷纷扬扬，有如在水晶球中的极致浪漫；雪夜里，教堂又会化作金砖亮瓦的城堡，高耸的十字架犹如夜空中的繁星。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/V2YQMM3KsZcLyDiOizRXmYD6bVw7ZexK84FjSyq4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;圣索菲亚教堂雪夜，景致如水晶球般梦幻。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如若静观教堂细节，佳时则在黄昏。充满气势的饱满墨绿色穹顶被清水红砖的建筑主体托举得极高，金十字架熠熠生辉，呈现出次第升腾的动态美感；自侧面看，四个帐篷顶错落有致，斜照的光线在建筑细部投下神秘莫测的阴影，敦厚而古朴。步入教堂中，欣赏每日轮番上演的音乐会之余，还能品赏斑驳墙体与罗马风格的拱券窗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夕阳辉映在教堂顶部，让人联想到欧亚大陆那一端和它同名的姐妹，也让人重温城市过往的厚重历史。其实，这座教堂“出身卑微”，仅是沙俄东西伯利亚第四步兵师的随军教堂，1907年3月由俄商契斯恰科夫——他的家在红军街——出资翻新，1912年在原基础上包砌一层砖，1923年俄建筑师克亚西科夫在旧教堂东南角重新选址建造，1932年11月落成，遂成今日样貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/hdtifd6oogFdGgcFPgG8de1ZB92LWtDhnNDnlwJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;圣索菲亚教堂内的音乐会&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;圣索菲亚教堂的建筑样式与装饰风格借鉴了17世纪的俄罗斯砖雕艺术，而果戈里大街与士课街交角的圣阿列克谢耶夫教堂则把巨大的建筑体量与立面砖饰有机结合，赋予它浓厚的俄式乡音与独特情调。尽管这座原为东正教教堂、1980年改为天主堂的百年建筑亦有巍峨错落之美，甚至在东北响晴的蓝天下，堪称城市建筑的颜值担当，但少有索菲亚广场的那番热闹，日落之后绝少人迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;灯火&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：中华巴洛克&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;秋林格瓦斯打开瓶盖后沙沙作响，这种著名饮料看似啤酒，略呈红色，却只有1%的酒精量，极适合旅游徒步时“吹瓶”——比如从阿列克谢耶夫教堂，沿着果戈里大街一直走到1908年建成的L型淡绿色调的宏大建筑——秋林洋行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;果戈里大街有年头的建筑亦有不少，但在葆有当年荣光的同时，亦不可避免地没落破败了——一如道外区。从火车站向北，过江铁道之东，即是原称“傅家甸”的道外区，是山东、河北闯关东的移民聚居地。虽说亦是哈尔滨最早的市中心之一，但由于缺乏完备精细的规划，导致上世纪30年代的这里“街衢狭隘、参差错落”“一履其地，则令人作呕，掩鼻疾避矣”&amp;nbsp;——彼时民间俗谚曰“南岗是天堂，道里是人间，道外是地狱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里也曾生长出别具一格的“中华巴洛克”建筑。沿街一面沿用西方巴洛克式立面，同时融合了传统中式建筑富有吉祥寓意的装饰纹样，在凸出的挑台边缘设置铁艺栏杆或“观音瓶”式混凝土栏杆，步入内里，则纯然是北方四合院建筑形制，土洋结合，自有一番风韵。主要位于南二、三道街、已经修葺为景点的中华巴洛克街区却乏善可陈，青砖街道、宽阔院落，很多被改造成餐饮商铺，规整有余却少了当年的热闹繁华。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相形之下，还是街区以东靖宇街上的“中华巴洛克”最为原汁原味。始建于1890年的这条长街原名正阳街，亦是哈尔滨民族商业的发祥地：正阳楼、老鼎丰、世一堂、大罗新百货、亨得利、同记商场……寸土寸金的老街曾经商家鳞次栉比。在靖宇街与南头道街交口，1920年建成的四层砖木结构建筑纯化医院，前身为同义庆货店，是“中华巴洛克”的代表作之一：蔓花摇曳的浮雕从爱奥尼亚柱式和柯林斯柱式的建筑外墙一路蜿蜒而下，富丽奢华之风令人难忘，尽显当年民族工商业者对名望的希冀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/H2HaomUi40Tfp1di33htXnYLR2z81FDQEy5p4fNF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251179&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;位于老道外的纯化医院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一切盛名、繁华与热闹都有终点。如今的老道外因大规模施工，人气不再，颓势尽显：沿街危楼举目可望，楼顶长满衰草，仿佛老建筑正在发出的叹息；街上游荡的小猫小狗看起来都充满沧桑感；在废墟边，偶尔可见打着“织补”招牌的小电动车，那是东北中老年妇女常做的营生——缝穷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在老哈尔滨，如果说“中”的窗口是“正阳街”，“西”的缩影就是中央大街——在萧红笔下，市街像一张“繁繁杂杂颜色不清晰的地图”，今日哈尔滨也具有类似特质——同样是商业街，道外的靖宇街成为大工地，而道里的中央大街，在早上七点，就有游人拎着格瓦斯瓶子四处闲逛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Jt6BaNZEvKBbBo0gbLrmB46GwPl3f8A6k8AsvD8z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;老道外街景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“夜，春夜，中央大街充满了音乐的夜。流浪人的音乐，日本舞场的音乐，外国饭店的音乐……7点钟以后，中央大街的中段，在一条横口，那个很响的扩音机哇哇地叫起来，这歌声差不多响彻全街。”萧红在《春意挂上了树梢》中曾经写到中央大街，不乏讽刺与戏谑；不过，她记录的“渐渐数不过来”的“像扯在太阳下的长串的黄色铜铃”一般的璀璨灯火，仿佛还挂在北起松花江防洪胜利纪念塔、南至经纬街、全长1450米的中央大街之上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在一些横的街上，是较为清静一些，路灯的光把树叶的影子印在路上，衰老的俄国人，正在絮絮地说着已经没有的好日子。……在日间也许以为是丑恶的，可是美丽的夜，把美丽的衣裳披在一切的上面，什么都像是很美好的了。”靳以笔下的那些短一些的街，和中央大街组成了类似鱼骨状的街道布局，撑起了1903年中东铁路贯通后，这条大街洋行云集、店铺棋布的“妖娆”样貌；特别是1924年俄国工程师科姆特·拉肖克负责设计并监工，铺设了长方形状如面包的花岗石路面后，面包石路代替了泥泞土路，大街容颜大改，富丽华贵起来，上世纪30年代，中央大街已成为建筑艺术长廊和万国建筑博览会，街道两侧多是巴洛克、哥特、文艺复兴诸式风格建筑，创造了优美的天际线；洋行商店、舞厅影院、餐馆酒吧林立……彼时的中央大街成为商品拜物教的朝圣之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;454&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cCg5StykNWAWuSug1zFc7uhbhVW0nLaG8gUXJHD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;初具规模的中国大街（今中央大街）&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方石铺就的街路上，维多利亚式马车发出的辚辚车声早已驶进历史的暮霭，只有一块块被流逝的岁月磨蚀得亮泽光洁的面包石，还在向今天步行街上的游人讲述长街的如烟往事——在夏日的傍晚，灿烂夕阳斜照在70余栋欧式、仿欧式建筑上，它们仿佛也拥有了自己独特的性格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;音乐：北国灵魂&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当然还有逛中央大街必不可少的马迭尔冰棍——在松浦洋行大楼改建的松浦1918西餐厅斜对面，即是马迭尔的冷饮厅。如今全国各地都能吃到价格不一的“马迭尔”，但据说都“欠点意思”，还是得在这里买5元一根、前店后厂制作出来、不带包装纸的最为正宗：在冬天这里日售一万根起步，元旦销量通常大爆发，一天能卖三至四万根——在哈尔滨的旅游旺季，“北风中的裸体马迭尔”是中央大街的特色之一，人人都想将自己“冷却到底”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;啃完冰棍，转身就能在马迭尔西餐厅品尝热乎乎的红菜汤、奶汁桂鱼和味道极美妙的罐虾——自从1898年俄国人在田家烧锅院开办铁路食堂，俄式西餐就在中国大地开始生根发芽，光中央大街区域就有塔道斯、华梅（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;原马尔斯西餐茶食店&lt;/span>;）与马迭尔等30余家西餐厅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美食佳肴令人回味无穷，特别是还有音乐相伴——不论在松浦、华梅，还是马迭尔自家一层的西餐厅，夏日里每每能听到马迭尔宾馆二楼阳台音乐秀的小提琴曲、萨克斯演奏或者美声独唱。轮番上阵的看似来自中东欧的艺人们卖力献艺，引得游人纷纷驻足，为中央大街平添许多热闹，更让人联想起他们的“前辈”，那些20世纪上半叶云集于此的外国音乐家：1936年，歌唱家亚历山大·威尔金斯基、费多尔·夏里亚宾来哈举办音乐会；1938年，10岁的赫尔穆特·斯特恩与父母来到中国，14岁在哈尔滨举办音乐会，后加盟成立于1908年、一度号称“远东第一交响乐团”的哈尔滨交响乐团，1948年远赴以色列后，他成为柏林爱乐首席小提琴家……上世纪20年代开始，在哈外侨先后创办了近30所音乐学校，百年未散的浓厚音乐氛围，成为哈尔滨被联合国授予“音乐之城”称号的重要基石。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Pww276vsMjnYQx0VjT6gEc7pijLlfoy5G7WMWdzP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251180&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;马迭尔宾馆旧景&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张亚萌/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马迭尔的阳台音乐秀仅是“音乐之城”的一个小小音符。 “在马迭尔宾馆，就是那家有大舞台和豪华大厅的宾馆，在电影放映场次之间组织了剧目演出并开始加演舞蹈节目……我愉快地放下了剧团枯燥的排练，专门去他们那里了。”舞蹈家、诗人拉丽萨·安捷尔曾在中国生活了34年，常常在1906年由俄籍犹太人约瑟·卡斯普创立的马迭尔宾馆演出，她的倩影和夏里亚宾、威尔金斯基的照片，以及餐具、灯具、电器、饰物、马迭尔电影院的宣传海报，一起组成了宾馆内的“历史文化长廊”；在她活跃于哈尔滨的岁月里，这座中央大街极古老的建筑被目之为“拥有最豪华的舞厅及餐厅、最现代、最舒适的客房”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时马迭尔宾馆的风光一时无两，直到1933年震惊哈埠的“卡斯普绑架案”戛然而止。那年8月24日晚，在马迭尔西餐厅用餐后，老约瑟·卡斯普之子西蒙被哈伪警察厅督察长马丁诺夫和15名匪徒绑架；12月3日，西蒙的尸体在哈尔滨附近的小岭被发现，舆论大哗。转年，伤心的老约瑟带妻儿远走法国，不久于巴黎病逝，马迭尔亦从风光走向没落，往昔辉煌，只有卡斯普留在宾馆“历史文化长廊”里的皮包，可以聊作见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1948年11月25日，中共中央代表与在哈的沈钧儒、章伯钧等民主人士在马迭尔宾馆一号会议室达成《关于召开新的政治协商会议诸问题的协议》。那时73岁的“衡老”沈钧儒住在宾馆，常到松花江边散步，见到江水冰封后又重新解冻的罕景，遂作诗云：“江心冻后见奔湍，雪意连潮亦欠酣。地气也随人事转，从今北雁不须南。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MeUDNfEc5bjBva429SBk5G5VHfqoybUYFksExSJs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251183&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;文化公园内的圣母安息教堂&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孟慧忠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央大街走到尽头的松花江南岸，即是斯大林公园，一个既窄且长的“江沿儿”，自这里可以览尽时而湍急、时而平缓的江水景致、触摸到北国都会的灵魂，又可以在夏日感受已逾六十载的“哈尔滨之夏”音乐会的狂欢氛围。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;江水与歌声向远方流淌，百年岁月沉积，哈尔滨就像一块海绵，吸收所有的声音，而那些斑驳古旧的建筑，则成为城市历史变迁的见证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西省人大常委会原副主任龚建华一审被判有期徒刑15年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 19, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province publicly announced the verdict of the original party group of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress In the case of member and deputy director Gong Jianhua accepting bribes, the defendant Gong Jianhua was sentenced to 15 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 5.5 million; the bribery income of Gong Jianhua and his The interest shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/1a1520b066a1634f1e305ec1762a147c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251237&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2004 to 2020, the defendant Gong Jianhua used his position as deputy secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, executive deputy mayor, leader of the Nanchang Municipal Planning Land Operation Leading Group, deputy secretary of the Yichun Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, and municipal Chairman, Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, Secretary of the Nanchang Municipal Committee, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial People’s Congress and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers or status, provide relevant individuals with land listing, project contracting, and project development. Provided assistance with matters such as job promotion and job promotion, and illegally received property equivalent to more than RMB 83.61 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhangzhou Intermediate People’s Court held that the defendant Gong Jianhua’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes, and the amount of bribes he accepted was particularly huge. In view of the fact that Gong Jianhua truthfully confessed his crime after voluntarily surrendering to the case, and voluntarily confessed some bribery facts that were not yet known to the case-handling agency, he had the circumstances to surrender, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribery proceeds and their accruals have been sealed, detained, and frozen in the case, which is legal. , determine the circumstances of lenient punishment, and he may be punished leniently in accordance with the law. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次本不公开的学术不端自查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256962]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3nh27B3yxPJUsd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/l2wuCqI3gXizKDKZ0fxN0vyIVL3 nh27B3yxPJUsd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, during an academic conference, Li Wei (pseudonym), a professor at the School of Physical Education of Shihezi University, casually agreed to a friend’s request for a paper name. It was a paper related to swimming. In 2021, a third-party agency discovered that the paper was suspected of being synthesized by reverse translation software and reported it to the Ministry of Education for confirmation, and the Ministry of Education fed back the situation to Shihezi University. The school launched an investigation and sent a letter to the other school, and found that Li Wei, the corresponding author, had not previously known about the existence of this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei was punished and could not participate in various project applications and evaluations for three years. During the ongoing self-examination of academic misconduct in college theses and the cleanup of false claims, Li Wei was reported again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in late May 2023, many universities have successively announced the launch of self-examination and cleanup of academic misconduct in papers, requiring self-examination and cleanup of academic papers since January 2018. Previously, on April 27, 2023, the General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a self-examination notice, requiring universities and scientific research institutes to self-examine and clean up common academic misconduct including plagiarism, plagiarism, forged peer reviews, ghostwriting and investment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main purpose of self-examination is to reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers and strive to curb the increase. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: line-through;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a self-examination operation that was not intended to be made public. Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the notice only became known to the outside world because two universities posted the notice as an attachment online. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The self-examination document is “not public &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the notices issued by each school, the main objects of this self-examination are These are all academic papers published by teachers and students of the school as the first signed unit. The focus areas of self-examination are basically the same, and they are all relatively common academic misconduct. It mainly includes six categories: plagiarism, plagiarism, and duplication of publications; forging corresponding authors, forging or manipulating peer reviews; forging, fabricating, and tampering with experimental data and pictures, using one picture for multiple purposes, and selective use; buying, selling, and ghostwriting papers; and purchasing experiments. Research data; nominal phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the notice of the Ministry of Science and Technology, universities and scientific research institutes in all provinces should carry out self-examination and clean-up work. However, according to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, only nearly 30 universities, including Shihezi University, Qinghai University, and Beijing University of Civil Engineering and Architecture, have issued this notice on their official websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology that the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice was originally a non-public document, but it became known to the outside world after two universities posted it online as an attachment to the notice. In fact, the notice documents issued by the Jiangsu and Anhui Provincial Science and Technology Departments did state &quot;This matter will not be made public&quot; at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a top-down campaign to investigate academic misconduct. Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact nearly 30 universities that publicly released the notice. Among them, Shihezi University, Qinghai University, Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University were interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, different universities have slightly different self-examination methods. However, they all adopt the method of teachers filling in forms and reporting by themselves. The content of the form mainly contains the personal information of the self-examination teacher, such as position, school, research direction, etc., as well as paper information, including paper title, DOI/PMID, publication time, publication journal, author category, academic violations, etc. The college’s statistical researchers are required to screen academic papers published within the verification period, identify academic papers with the above six conditions, put forward rectification suggestions, and form a self-examination work summary report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specific inspection methods can be roughly divided into focused spot inspections and comprehensive inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University and Yanshan University adopted a comprehensive inventory approach. A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University told Southern Weekend reporters that they had comprehensively checked 8,671 papers signed by teachers at the school within the time limit. The school organized an investigation team. The teachers first filled in the self-examination form, and then the college compiled and submitted it. Finally, the school&#39;s scientific research office reported it to the XPCC Education Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Social Sciences Office of Yanshan University said that after the announcement, the secondary college organized teachers to conduct self-examinations and submit self-examination forms and commitment letters. The college issues a self-examination report based on the self-examination situation, which is finally summarized and reported by the Social Science Office. Southern Weekend reporters contacted some colleges of the school to inquire about the implementation status. Among them, a staff member from the office of the School of Construction Engineering and Mechanics confirmed the statement of the aforementioned person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinghai University and Southwest University of Science and Technology adopt focused spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that the school&#39;s Science and Technology Office takes the lead and adopts a two-level system. First, the college&#39;s professor committee organizes self-examination, and then the school inspection office conducts random inspections. Specific to different disciplines, the degree of rigor varies. For example, due to the subject characteristics of medicine, which is prone to academic misconduct, the school conducted a census of more than 150 papers published by teachers from the clinical medical school between January 2022 and May 2023, while other disciplines were Spot checks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the requirements in the notice are from January 2018 to May 2023, the aforementioned teacher in charge said that Qinghai University has two inspections every year, at mid-term and at the end of the year, so this time it will be from 2022 to the present. Check the thesis again as a key point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why he adopted the method of focused spot checks was that Qinghai University’s strong disciplines are mainly agriculture and forestry. “Due to the plateau specificity, many papers do not have experiments and data, and cannot be copied from other places. Therefore, The probability of academic misconduct will be relatively small.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spot checks are conducted on a proportional basis. He gave an example, based on the total number of papers published by the college within the period, for example, 50 papers were published, and 10 papers were randomly checked, including the original data of the scientific research and whether the person named on the paper was a member of the research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology said that they mainly screen key papers, and others mainly rely on feedback and reports from school teachers and other staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Almost no problems were found&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of large-scale self-examination has little impact on This is the first time for many universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant officials from Southwest University of Science and Technology and Yanshan University stated that similar large-scale system self-examination work had not been carried out before. The person in charge of Southwest University of Science and Technology emphasized that issues such as academic misconduct and pseudonymity were previously mainly investigated and handled through reports from others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in most notices, the self-examination time left for teachers is about one month. At present, the self-examination work has basically been completed at the school level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some self-examination window periods are shorter. The Science and Technology Office of Shijiazhuang Railway University issued a notice on July 26, 2023, requiring each college to complete the self-examination and cleanup work before July 30. If problems are found, a summary form should be filled out in a timely manner and submitted to the Science and Technology Office, and remedial measures such as corrections and retractions should be taken, and &quot;no feedback after the deadline will be deemed as a paper without academic misconduct.&quot; They gave each college only four days for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the four schools interviewed, the result of the self-examination was “almost no problems.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers at Yanshan University said that the self-examination work was completed at the end of July and &quot;no problems were found&quot;, and emphasized that the relevant results have been reported to the Provincial Department of Education. Teachers from the Science and Technology Development Department of Southwest University of Science and Technology also said that the school has completed a preliminary screening and found no relevant violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for whether a self-examination report needs to be issued, a staff member from the office of the School of Architectural Engineering and Mechanics of Yanshan University said, “The school only requires us to fill in a self-examination form and issue a report if there are any problems, but our school should no problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, the teacher in charge of Qinghai University said that since inspections were organized twice a year before, no serious academic misconduct was found this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only exception is Shihezi University. They self-identified three illegal articles. The violations were improper naming, purchasing data, and repeated publication. They belonged to the School of Physical Education, School of Medicine, and School of Animal Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the improper listing and purchase data are illegal articles that have been investigated before this inspection. Although notices from the science and technology departments of many provinces stated that papers that have been investigated and dealt with may not be included in the scope of this self-examination. However, the teacher in charge of the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University believes that it &quot;still serves as a warning.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to punish after investigation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The General Office of the Ministry of Science and Technology stated that if problems are found during self-examination and cleanup, scientific researchers must report them to their units in a timely manner and take remedial measures such as corrections and retractions. Those who comply with the lenient treatment circumstances specified in Article 34 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; may be given lenient treatment in accordance with the regulations; those who conceal or make false reports shall be punished in accordance with Article 3 of the &quot;Rules for the Investigation and Handling of Untrustworthy Conduct in Scientific Research&quot; Article 15 and other relevant regulations will be dealt with seriously and publicly announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University explained that the school has criticized and educated the teachers involved and required them not to apply for projects within three years. They are not allowed to be prioritized and receive talent titles, nor can they apply for science and technology projects. award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shihezi University will take lenient treatment for those who took the initiative to report in this self-examination. Zhang Xiaoqian and Li Jie of the School of Animal Science and Technology published the article &quot;The Effect of Culture Temperature on the Test Results of Streptococcus Thermophilus Inhibition Method&quot; in 2019. The teacher involved submitted papers to two journals, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; and &quot;Chinese Dairy Cow&quot;, of which &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; was the core journal. In May 2019, &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; took the lead in publishing the paper, and four months later, &quot;Heilongjiang Animal Husbandry and Veterinary Medicine&quot; published this article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discovering the duplicate publication, the author of the paper repeatedly negotiated with the person in charge of the journal &quot;Chinese Cows&quot; and asked the other party to withdraw the paper, but was rejected. It was not until July 2023 that the author of the paper negotiated with the relevant notice from the Ministry of Science and Technology, and the other party finally agreed to withdraw the paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher from the Scientific Research Office of Shihezi University said that because the author of the paper took the initiative to report it and contacted the magazine several times to withdraw the paper, the handling was lenient and only criticized and educated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why self-examination? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why is there this large-scale top-down self-examination? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The explanation in the aforementioned Ministry of Science and Technology notice is to consolidate the main responsibilities of each unit, reduce the stock of academic misconduct papers, strive to curb the increase, and guide scientific researchers to strengthen their awareness of scientific research integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the core of self-examination is to eliminate the stock and curb the increase. The aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology explained that for example, a scientific researcher bought an article ten years ago and either published it to apply for a professional title to make a profit, or it has never been used. If it doesn&#39;t work, I can only hold it in with all kinds of severe crackdowns now. Once it is published, it may explode one day. Either way, they will be uneasy. Self-examination and clean-up is a good opportunity, &quot;It is to give these scientific researchers who have made mistakes a chance, whether they were ignorant or lucky at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it also gives scientific researchers an opportunity to self-examine and sort out. &quot;It is always a good thing to sort it out, to enhance the awareness of integrity, to find out the family background, and to avoid the situation of being named but not knowing it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for curbing the increase, &quot;If you know that everyone is watching this matter , they will never do it again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the aforementioned person close to the Ministry of Science and Technology mentioned that since it is a self-examination, there are mitigating circumstances. &quot;If there is no profit from it, you may not even be held accountable, but criticism is definitely required.&quot; He believes that self-examination serves more of an educational and deterrent role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not the first time an inventory has been carried out. Southern Weekend reporters learned that this work was also carried out at the ministry level in 2022, with the purpose of letting relevant departments and local levels understand the importance that ministries attach to scientific research integrity work, but it was &quot;not made public&quot; at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the possible concealment of reports, the aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that if there are no problems during the self-examination, but problems are found in the future, and they are within the time period from 2018 to the present, then the punishment will definitely be aggravated. , &quot;This is equivalent to confronting integrity checks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you look at it over a longer period of time, behind the self-examination are the increasing number of retractions of papers and the tightening of scientific research integrity management measures in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 20, 2017, academic publishing giant Springer issued a statement stating that 107 papers published in &quot;Tumor Biology&quot; had been withdrawn due to suspected peer review fraud. The papers involved are all from China and were published between 2012 and 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Association for Science and Technology expressed its opinion at the time, hoping that Springer Publishing Group could improve the internal control mechanism as soon as possible, strengthen the management of journals, and deal with problematic papers before publication instead of withdrawing them after publication. At the same time, we are highly vigilant about &quot;predatory journals&quot; that seek financial gain and collude with &quot;third-party&quot; institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 15, 2023, Healsan Consulting LLC of the United States released the &quot;2022 SCI Paper Retraction Briefing&quot;. The briefing shows that as of December 31, 2022, a total of 41,642 SCI manuscripts have been withdrawn worldwide, including 19,421 from China. Specifically, from January 1, 2022 to December 31, 2022, there were 5,488 SCI manuscripts retracted around the world, of which 2,879 were retracted in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also an increasing emphasis on scientific research integrity. In May 2018, the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued &quot;Several Opinions on Further Strengthening the Construction of Scientific Research Integrity.&quot; The opinions emphasize the need to severely crack down on behavior that seriously violates the requirements of scientific research integrity, establish a lifelong accountability system, and investigate and deal with it at any time once discovered. This is the first time that the central government has issued a document raising the importance of scientific research integrity to a very high level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, in 2020, the Science and Technology Progress Law was revised to further clarify the relevant punitive measures for breach of trust in scientific research. In 2022, 22 departments including the Ministry of Science and Technology revised the &quot;Rules for Investigation and Handling of Scientific Research Integrity Cases (Trial)&quot;, which resulted in more specific handling rules for the investigation and handling of scientific research dishonesty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, starting from 2018, the Ministry of Science and Technology has successively announced the results of investigations and treatment of untrustworthy conduct in scientific research every year. There are one batch of results from 2017 to 2019, two batches in 2020, and two batches in 2021 and 2022. Four batches were announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There will be follow-up after this round of self-examination. The aforementioned people close to the Ministry of Science and Technology said that, in particular, problems that have not been found at all are precisely within the scope of focus. &quot;This time I came with the red seal of my unit, and there was not a single problematic article. However, if the articles are frequently withdrawn later, or problems arise during the investigation, then the unit&#39;s main responsibility will definitely not be fully implemented, and it will be seriously investigated and dealt with.&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生频频被举报，“飞刀”为何难合规？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257002]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsPsrAMQWtq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/nJ5K8okIndVjOpZzD0Ym5yrulOaiEvsP srAMQWtq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Currently, consultation and multi-point practice are two ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot; The main path, but the remuneration standards of both should be consistent with the remuneration system in the main practice institutions. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the disease is not cured, should the surgery fee be refunded? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, Mr. Ma, a family member of a patient in Qixian County, Henan Province, said that his father &quot;had a bump on his face&quot; in July, so he came to Qixian Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital for treatment. The hospital informed me that a specialist from Kaifeng would perform the surgery and that a cash payment of 3,000 yuan would be required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The surgery was performed by experts from outside hospitals, the surgical fee was higher than the market price, and the cash payment was all reminders that Mr. Ma&#39;s father had undergone a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery. &quot;Flying Knife&quot;, as the name suggests, &quot;hits the flying knife to open the knife&quot;. Doctors leave their hospitals to visit other places in their spare time, mostly performing surgical operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s interesting is that the patient’s condition was not good, and Mr. Ma wanted to repay the 3,000 yuan surgical fee charged by the surgeon. This was based on the “Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians’ Out-of-Home Consultation” issued by the former Ministry of Health in 2005. Regulations regarding consultation fees should be paid uniformly to the consulting medical institution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident was reported by Henan Metropolis Channel, it immediately attracted attention in the industry: Should &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery exist? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some doctors believe that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery currently lacks institutional protection, brings risks to both patients and doctors, and should be banned. Some doctors also hold objections, believing that &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery helps experts earn income, patients receive convenient treatment, grassroots hospitals gain technical experience, and local medical insurance funds can stay local, so it should be supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, &quot;throwing knife&quot; surgery remains in a legal gray area. Policies that can make &quot;flying knives&quot; comply have encountered many obstacles in the hospital&#39;s internal management and institutional processes. Under the huge market demand at the grassroots level, private &quot;flying knives&quot; have always existed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Income issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For doctors, the core reason for the long-lasting success of &quot;Flying Knife&quot; is &quot;increased income.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, consultation and multi-site practice are the two main ways to formalize &quot;flying knife&quot;, but the remuneration standards for both must be consistent with the salary system within the major practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Provisions on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; mentioned that the consultation fees involved in the consultation shall be subject to the regulations of the location of the inviting medical institution, and additional fees may be charged as appropriate on the basis of local regulations. The increase will be determined by the provincial price department in conjunction with the health administrative department at the same level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The range of &quot;discretionary&quot; is destined not to be too high. Cheng Sheng, the department director of a secondary hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of inter-hospital consultations in Beijing is about 300 to 300 yuan. 500 yuan, &quot;Which expert is willing to waste time and energy by making such a trip?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the salary of multi-site practice, the former National Health and Family Planning Commission issued the &quot;Regulations on Promoting and Standardizing the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; in 2014. &quot;Notice of Several Opinions&quot; stipulates that the salary of multi-site practicing physicians is determined by consultation between the medical institution and the physician at the place of practice based on factors such as actual working hours, workload, and work performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the income that doctors who perform daily surgeries in our hospital can earn, a respiratory doctor in Shanghai once revealed to a Southern Weekend reporter that his remuneration for each operation is about 300 yuan. A hard-working doctor Two or three operations are performed every day, and the monthly performance bonus income is about 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Corresponding to this is the income from &quot;flying knives&quot;. Wang Gui, who works as a &quot;flying knife&quot; agency, revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the cost of a &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery for a patient ranges from 3,000 yuan to 9,000 yuan, with the agency taking a 10% commission and the rest going to the doctor. The main factors that determine the cost are the doctor&#39;s level, the difficulty of the operation, and the distance of practice. An operation priced at 10,000 yuan may require the support of multiple doctors across provinces, and the operation lasts 7 to 8 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Agents tend to stratify experts. Top experts are generally subject leaders, master&#39;s and doctoral tutors, and department directors of top hospitals in their cities. These doctors are the first choice for foreign aid in large hospitals in provincial capital cities. The seniority and popularity of ordinary experts are low, and the general location of &quot;flying knife&quot; is county-level hospitals. “There are quite a lot of surgeons in general surgery, ophthalmology, gastroenterology, hepatobiliary surgery, thoracic surgery, and orthopedics,” Wang Gui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without an intermediary like Wang Gui, &quot;throwing knives&quot; mostly occur between doctors who have personal relationships. Most of the inviting doctors come from district and county hospitals, or have studied in the expert&#39;s department, or have studied under the same discipline. &quot;Both parties must know the basics.&quot; said Cheng Lei, director of thoracic surgery at a tertiary hospital in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, regardless of the form, compared with the above-mentioned &quot;Regulations&quot; and &quot;Notice&quot;, &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Formalization efforts have never stopped&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of some doctors, in addition to economic benefits, &quot;Flying Knife&quot; can also showcase their skills and improve &quot; Jianghu status&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Lei told Southern Weekend reporters that he once went to overseas hospitals to demonstrate technology under the organization of a surgical instrument manufacturer, helping a tumor ablation surgery to be implemented nationwide. “It’s more like a flying knife than a flying knife. It’s about teaching.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even as the chief physician of thoracic surgery, Cheng Lei has to ask for help from colleagues who can handle difficult surgeries. Cheng Lei&#39;s father was diagnosed with aortic dissection in a hospital in Jiangsu and suspected aortic aneurysm. The local hospital did not have the conditions for surgery, and it was hundreds of kilometers away from Shanghai for treatment. Once the tumor ruptured on the way, it would be life-threatening. Finally, Doctor &quot;Flying Knife&quot; solved the urgent problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, given the reality of uneven distribution of medical resources, governments at all levels have never stopped trying to bring &quot;flying knives&quot; onto the formal track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 &quot;Interim Regulations on the Management of Physicians&#39; Out-of-Home Consultation&quot; proposed an inter-hospital consultation system, and the 2009 &quot;Notice of the Ministry of Health on Issues Concerning the Multi-site Practice of Physicians&quot; responded to the concerns from all walks of life about allowing multiple sites. The call to practice. Since 2020, the construction of medical consortia has accelerated, and the consultation, training, and referral systems of hospitals within the same medical consortium have become increasingly mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be understood that if an expert wants to perform surgery in the same hospital for a long time, he will usually apply for a multi-site practice registration. If it is a one-time operation, a consultation method will be used.” Senior Jingheng Law Firm Partner Zhang Li, who has been a doctor for six years, explained this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the multi-site practice system, there was a restrictive rule that &quot;a doctor is not allowed to practice in more than three medical institutions.&quot; However, the &quot;Physician Practice Registration Management Measures&quot; promulgated in 2017 allowed doctors to Practice in multiple locations across provinces. It also stipulates that doctors who practice in multiple locations within the same provincial administrative region of their main practice institution only need to register with these practice institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change from a registration system to a filing system means that doctors can practice at multiple locations without permission from the main practice institution and the local health department. With the support of such policies, a set of data released by the National Health Commission in October 2020 showed that the number of multi-site practicing doctors in the country has reached 260,000, four times that of 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Hospitals don’t want to see their doctors flying around”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are still many obstacles to the promotion of multi-site practice, which also provides “ Throwing knives&quot; creates the soil of reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees mentioned soft discipline in hospitals. The Southern Weekend reporter obtained the &quot;Multi-site Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; implemented by a well-known hospital in Southwest China, which requires doctors to complete the multi-site practice registration, but also to register with the local health bureau and submit it to the hospital. Photo, physician qualification certificate, practicing physician license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cumbersome in-hospital approval process is not an isolated case. According to public reports from the self-media &quot;Seeing Medical Circle&quot;, in 2020, the &quot;Measures for the Management of Multi-site Practice of Physicians (Trial)&quot; issued by Changsha First Hospital stipulates that doctors who practice multi-site must have intermediate professional titles or above, and their departments must be above. The department&#39;s year-end KPI assessment results for the first year rank above the average level, etc. The document also states that non-commandatory activities in medical institutions outside the hospital must be approved by the department director, reported to the medical department and the leader of the hospital in charge, and can only be registered after approval by the hospital office meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Multiple Practice Management Standards for Physicians&quot; of the above-mentioned Southwest Regional Hospital requires that multi-site practicing physicians should sign a labor agreement with the multi-site practice institution on the practice category, scope of practice, employment period, work tasks, Medical responsibilities, time arrangements, assessment methods, salary, insurance benefits, etc. are clarified, and the agreement is filed with the Medical Department of our hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pang Liang, a surgeon at a private hospital in Beijing, told Southern Weekend reporters that some hospitals have banned doctors from practicing outside their homes. One of the reasons is that they are worried that patients will be diverted to other hospitals, which will affect their income. Xie Rushi, honorary president of the Shenzhen Non-Public Medical Institutions Association, analyzed from a purely managerial psychological perspective, &quot;Hospitals don&#39;t want to see their doctors flying around. This is normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Flying knives&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Controversies continue, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The people will not hold the officials accountable&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Flying knife&quot; surgeries performed without permission may be classified as illegal medical practice and subject to severe punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the technical appraisal of medical malpractice determines that it constitutes a medical malpractice and bears the main responsibility, at the administrative level, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be suspended from practicing or even have his physician&#39;s practicing certificate revoked; if he violates criminal law, the doctor may also Prosecuted on suspicion of medical malpractice. If the medical malpractice is of equal liability and below, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor may be held administratively liable. As for the civil compensation part, the law stipulates that the subject of compensation is medical institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a large extent, disputes related to &quot;throwing knives&quot; still belong to the category of &quot;people do not complain and officials do not investigate&quot;, and the patient&#39;s will has a great influence on the development of the case. In one case that Zhang Li represented, when a &quot;flying knife&quot; expert performed a chest nodule operation, the patient suffered from massive bleeding and &quot;could not get off the operating table.&quot; Afterwards, the doctor came to apologize. The family also believed that it is not easy for the country to train a doctor and chose to give up administrative complaints and criminal reports. Therefore, the &quot;flying knife&quot; doctor did not involve administrative or criminal penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in another case, the doctor performed a breast plastic surgery, and the patient also suffered from massive bleeding during the operation. After recovering, he reported it to the health authority of the hospital where the expert worked. In the end, the expert was administratively dismissed, transferred from his job, and fined to suspend his practice for three months. This is the &quot;throwing knife&quot; case with the most serious punishment that Zhang Li has ever come across. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if no medical accident occurs, doctors may be &quot;troubled&quot; by patients. A well-known example is that in 2019, a Shanxi patient asked doctors from Beijing Tiantan Hospital to perform neurosurgical stent implantation. According to China Youth Daily, the patient&#39;s family secretly videotaped and reported the incident while paying 10,000 yuan in cash for &quot;throwing a knife&quot;. As a result, the doctor involved and the doctor who helped collect and transfer the money to the hospital were suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another concern is that &quot;flying knife&quot; doctors will leave after performing the surgery, leaving post-operative care to grassroots hospitals, but the latter may lack relevant knowledge, posing hidden dangers to patients&#39; well-being. Pang Liang mentioned a medical accident in 2019: a male patient underwent gastric volume reduction surgery in a hospital, which was performed by a foreign doctor who participated in academic exchanges. Five days after the operation, the patient died suddenly. The autopsy report showed that the patient suffered from secondary gastric leakage, acute purulent peritonitis, and peritoneal pus and blood effusion after surgery, leading to infection, toxic shock, and death from multiple organ failure. This may be the result of a lack of appropriate post-operative care in local hospitals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The patient feels that the effect is not as expected, and wants a refund. If you don&#39;t refund the money, I will sue you. I will sue you for sure.&quot; Cheng Lei said that the gray attribute of &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery is the natural instinct of doctors. The weak point is that high fees are not on the table. When encountering disputes, most grassroots hospitals that issue &quot;flying knife&quot; invitations will not go to the trouble of experts, but will quietly pay to &quot;settle the matter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Legal and compliance problems need to be solved&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The seemingly beautiful &quot;flying knife&quot; has not yet come out of its non-compliant nature, which means that The ability of patients and doctors to resist risks is extremely fragile. For example, some hospitals will insure doctors with medical malpractice liability insurance to help reduce economic losses after an accident, but unregistered &quot;flying knife&quot; surgeries are obviously not covered by claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors have also gradually figured out a &quot;semi-compliant&quot; out-of-hospital consultation operation path. Before visiting a doctor, ask the primary hospital to issue an invitation letter and complete the registration in your own hospital. After the consultation is completed, an additional amount of money will be charged on top of the normal income. The latter is not included in the financial process, nor is it paid directly by the patient to the specialist, but changes hands through the inviting hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is what is done in daily life. There needs to be a certain amount of supplementary income so that people are willing to go for consultation.” Xie Rushi told Southern Weekend reporters that in this way, the behavior of “throwing knives” itself is legal. If it has been reported, it is a legal medical behavior, but part of the income is a red envelope, which is still shady and may face investigation and punishment by the disciplinary inspection department within the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For self-protection, doctors will also screen &quot;flying knife&quot; cases to avoid participating in &quot;flying knife&quot; surgeries that are too risky. Wang Gui said that after a patient requests an expert from outside the hospital to perform the surgery, the doctor in charge of the hospital will evaluate whether the patient&#39;s family members are &quot;relatively sensitive&quot;, prone to finding faults, and whether the financial conditions are sufficient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Pang Liang&#39;s vision, in order to let the &quot;flying knife&quot; income come into the light, large hospitals should establish a public expert database and clearly mark the price of each expert according to department and level for patients and Primary hospital selection. This price can put a gap between the salary of daily practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is more important is to let &quot;Flying Knife&quot; truly gain status. Wang Gui&#39;s institution has complete diagnostic and treatment business qualifications and controls private hospitals. Experts are registered in this hospital to practice in multiple locations, and are then dispatched by the hospital to provide consulting services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Li&#39;s view, this way doctors can bypass the public medical institutions in their main practice areas and legally conduct out-of-town consultations. In an article teaching doctors how to legally &quot;throw a knife&quot;, he called this practice &quot;long-range missiles&quot;, while &quot;intercontinental missiles&quot; are founding or joining a doctor group or clinic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The doctor group mainly connects the supply and demand sides of consultation and dispatches group doctors to primary hospitals to provide services. However, the doctor group does not belong to a medical institution. The doctor is still affiliated with a main medical practice institution-either the doctor&#39;s old employer or a private hospital within the doctor group. In essence, doctor groups are just intermediary platforms, and doctors still follow the path of multi-site practice or consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Rushi, who has participated in the establishment of several doctor groups, said that the doctor group can sign a notification agreement with the patient or the hospital where the patient is dispatched to determine the price of &quot;flying knife&quot; surgery, and charge in the name of the doctor group. This operation makes the &quot;flying knife&quot; fee in the gray area compliant. However, the problem faced by the doctor group is that it is very difficult to reach a cooperative relationship with the dispatched hospital through bidding, and it is impossible to form a business model by negotiating cooperation with patients one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even with complete qualifications, Wang Gui’s organization is still very cautious. Their declared business model is to provide doctors’ consulting services, including preoperative evaluation, postoperative rehabilitation plan formulation, etc., but does not include surgical performance. &quot;In fact, we can hold a knife, but we can&#39;t say so because there is no document allowing us to do so.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Interviewee Requirements, Cheng Lei, Wang Gui, and Pang Liang are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新冠疫苗：每年秋天来一针？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6pdVq7qDbnD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/Tsc8wnKvCrJ8AxgwNj3kCNxQHmvTU6 pdVq7qDbnD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some countries, the new coronavirus vaccine may be recommended every year like influenza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued a recommendation that everyone over six months old should get a shot of the new coronavirus vaccine this fall and winter. A few days ago, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved two new versions of the vaccine from Moderna and Pfizer. The new version of the vaccine targets a variant of the Omicron virus called XBB.1.5. , this strain is widespread in most countries around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vaccination remains the best way to prevent hospitalization and death from COVID-19. Vaccines can also reduce long-term COVID-19 effects. According to recommendations issued by the CDC, anyone who has not received a COVID-19 vaccine in the past two months can receive this new version of the vaccine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have more tools to prevent the serious consequences of the new coronavirus.” said Mandy Cohen, MD, MPH, director of the US CDC. The reason for issuing this recommendation is that the new coronavirus is still mutating, new subtypes are emerging one after another, and the protective effect of the vaccine has declined sharply over time. Vaccination with the new version of the vaccine can better protect public health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The CDC&#39;s independent advisory committee voted 13:1 to recommend universal vaccination of this vaccine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the supporters, Dr. Sandra Fryhoffer, associate professor at Emory University School of Medicine in the United States, believes that severe COVID-19 may occur in people of all ages, including people without underlying diseases. , coupled with the fact that many people have not received booster shots before, this means that the overall immunity to the new coronavirus is declining, so vaccination should be recommended for all people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Should ordinary people take the vaccine or not?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It has been more than three years since vaccination was encouraged, but the vaccine strategy is quietly changing. Most countries have not done so like the United States. Likewise, booster shots are recommended for everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, the British government announced that the new version of the booster shot would be provided free of charge to seniors over 65 years old, frontline medical staff and vulnerable groups. France does not recommend booster shots for non-vulnerable groups. Germany has no plan for a booster shot in the autumn, although it has previously recommended that high-risk groups should receive a dose of the new crown vaccine every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers generally believe that because the main role of the new coronavirus vaccine is to prevent severe illness rather than infection, high-risk groups will benefit the most from vaccination. There is still controversy in the scientific community as to whether low-risk groups and minors should be vaccinated again. “It makes a lot of sense to get booster shots for the elderly, people with underlying diseases and immune deficiencies,” said Amesh Adalja, an infectious disease expert at the Johns Hopkins University Center for Health Security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;In the past three years since the spread of the new coronavirus, many people have gradually become numb to the virus infection, and the number of people choosing to be vaccinated has also gradually declined. But in fact, whether in the United States or China, there are many people who are repeatedly infected with the new coronavirus. CDC scientists report that hospitalizations for COVID-19 have been increasing since mid-July, and while most of them are young children and older adults, half of children under five hospitalized do not have underlying health conditions, a reminder that Even otherwise healthy people may be at risk of severe illness from COVID-19. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the upcoming autumn and winter virus epidemic seasons, influenza viruses, respiratory syncytial viruses and new coronaviruses are likely to be cross-infected, which will cause serious consequences for vulnerable groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Prepare before winter&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In our country, the overall epidemic situation is in a state of sporadic sporadic spread, but the new coronavirus has not disappeared. The phenomenon of transmission still exists, and there are many people around us who experienced &quot;two positives&quot; a few months ago and are now experiencing &quot;three positives&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Based on the fact that COVID-19 is extremely contagious, antibodies naturally attenuate after being infected with COVID-19, and there is no absolutely protective COVID-19 vaccine, most people will be infected 1-3 times a year.” The Third People of Shenzhen City Professor Lu Hongzhou, director of the hospital, explained, “It will not have a particularly big impact on people with normal immune function.” However, for people with low immune function such as the elderly, diabetes, and underlying cancer diseases, Lu Hongzhou recommends regular vaccination with the new crown vaccine every year. Vaccination strategies can include combined immunization with nasal spray vaccine and subcutaneous injection vaccine, and multivalent COVID-19 combination vaccine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 25, 2023, the &quot;Recent New Coronavirus Vaccination Work Plan for Key Populations&quot; issued by the Comprehensive Group of the Joint Prevention and Control Mechanism of the State Council proposed that targeted new coronavirus vaccination be implemented for key populations such as the elderly. It is clear that during the epidemic period of the XBB variant strain of the new coronavirus, focusing on the autumn and winter of this year, vaccination containing the antigen components of the XBB variant strain is recommended as a priority. Experts call on people who have been infected and have not completed basic immunity to receive one dose of vaccine 3 months after infection. This will help provide better protection for people at high risk of severe illness and death in possible subsequent epidemics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some experts predict that the number of new coronavirus infections will increase after the start of school in September. According to the immunity cycle, the next wave of the new crown epidemic may appear around November this autumn. At this time, it is also the flu season. The superimposition of COVID-19 and influenza may lead to an increase in severe respiratory infections. Therefore, it is recommended to receive both influenza vaccine and COVID-19 vaccine at the same time. This is also recommended by the WHO - superposition of the two vaccines can maximize the prevention of severe illness. and mitigate the risk of viral cross-infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The increase in hospitalizations and deaths shows that coronavirus disease is here to stay and the world still needs tools to prevent, detect and treat COVID-19.” Dr. Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, Director-General of WHO, in September 2023 Emphasized at the media briefing on the 6th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天降烟头烫伤女婴，DNA比对锁定嫌疑人：胜于住户连坐多矣！丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256968]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Some time ago, a baby girl in Zhengzhou was burned by a cigarette butt falling from the sky in a community. The police collected blood from all the residents upstairs and compared the DNA on the cigarette butts, and successfully identified the suspect who threw the cigarette butts. This is another case of using high-tech means to identify the suspect of throwing objects from high altitude. It also reminds you again that throwing objects from high altitude is extremely harmful and the probability of police intervention to solve the case is greatly increased. Don’t take chances and try the law yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, at the end of August, Ms. Huang was taking her 4-month-old baby for a walk downstairs when an unextinguished cigarette butt fell from the sky and burned the child&#39;s shoulders and neck. Although the surveillance cameras in the community only cover one floor and there is no high-altitude surveillance, it is impossible to find out who threw the cigarette butts through the video. However, the police successfully found the suspect who threw the object at high altitude by collecting blood from all the residents upstairs to test DNA. Not only will this person be liable for civil torts, but he is also likely to be subject to criminal penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tall buildings provide us with more living and working space and have become a symbol of modernization. However, they also bring the risk of throwing and falling objects from high altitudes. Carrying high-speed kinetic energy converted from high-altitude potential energy, even an egg weighing tens of grams may cause serious injury, not to mention other dangerous items. In recent years, there have been constant news about vehicles being damaged by objects thrown and falling from heights, killing and injuring people. In 2016, an iron fitness ball fell from the sky in Suining, Sichuan, killing a baby girl under one year old; in 2020, another 14-month-old baby in Shaoxing, Zhejiang was hit in the head by a brick thrown from upstairs. Causing brain death...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is unlikely that an unextinguished cigarette butt will injure someone, the risk of causing a fire or scalding someone is not small. In addition to the recent case in Zhengzhou, a similar case occurred in a community in Luzhou, Sichuan in 2021. A cigarette butt dropped from a high altitude burned through the roof of a baby car and almost burned the baby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, casualties or property losses caused by falling objects from high altitudes were usually dealt with as civil infringements, and the victims had to collect evidence on their own to prosecute. Unless the impact was extremely serious, the police generally would not intervene in the investigation. The individual&#39;s ability to collect evidence is naturally very weak, and in most cases the perpetrator cannot be found. What to do? The previous law stipulates that in this case, all &quot;possible perpetrators&quot; will be compensated. That is to say, once an incident involving a high-altitude object injuring someone occurs and the perpetrator cannot be found, all residents upstairs (except those who have evidence to prove their Those who are not the perpetrators (for example, if the building is vacant and no one lives in it, etc.) will be &quot;sitting together.&quot; Although this provision allows the victim to receive compensation, it is very unfair to those who did not throw things downstairs. It may even condone the perpetrators, because the consequences of the evil are shared by many people. This legal provision and related court decisions have caused great controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to solving the problem is to find the perpetrators and punish them severely. This aspect relies on technological progress, such as high-altitude video surveillance, DNA comparison and other technologies, which can help identify the perpetrators. On the other hand, there are changes in legal provisions. If you still let the victim collect evidence on his own, it will basically be impossible. Because individuals do not have the right to collect DNA from others for identification, there are no legal provisions, and properties have no incentive to install high-altitude surveillance systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Civil Code and Criminal Law Amendment (11), which will be implemented in 2021, has changed this rule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the civil side, although the &quot;simultaneous sitting&quot; provisions still exist, the Civil Code requires the police to investigate in a timely manner in accordance with the law and identify the person responsible. The &quot;continuous sitting&quot; rule applies only when the police are unable to find out. As a result, it has become the legal duty of the police to identify the person responsible for falling objects from heights. The police have greater power and ability to conduct investigations. For example, they can narrow the scope of investigation based on the mobile phone signal at the location of the incident, and can force &quot;possible perpetrators&quot; to provide biological samples for DNA comparison. Through these technical means, the police can basically make the perpetrators invisible. Especially the DNA comparison is extremely shocking. In the case of a cigarette butt falling from the sky in Luzhou, Sichuan, which almost scalded a baby, the perpetrator voluntarily surrendered after the police completed the DNA analysis on the cigarette butt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Civil Code also stipulates that property management companies and other building managers should take necessary safety measures to prevent infringement incidents of falling objects from high altitudes; otherwise, they will bear tort liability for failing to perform safety guarantee obligations. In this way, the property management company will have the motivation to do a good job in prevention, monitoring and other tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of criminal liability, the judicial interpretation issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2019 stipulates that intentional throwing of objects from high altitude and negligent falling of objects from high altitude can be classified as &quot;crime of endangering public safety by dangerous means&quot; and &quot;negligence causing casualties.&quot; Convicted and punished for crimes such as &quot;serious accident crime&quot; and &quot;major liability accident crime&quot;. The Criminal Law Amendment (11), which took effect on March 1, 2021, has added the crime of &quot;throwing objects from high altitudes&quot;. Although the penalty for this crime is lighter than the penalty for &quot;crime of endangering public safety&quot;, the police must open a case to investigate the crime regardless of the severity. This also means that under the new criminal law, the threshold for criminal offenses for throwing objects from high altitudes has been lowered, and the police have greater legal responsibilities to conduct criminal investigations. In this way, the probability of the perpetrator being discovered will be greatly increased, the possibility and intensity of punishment will also be greatly increased, and the deterrence of high-altitude missiles will also be greatly increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Use technology to let the law grow teeth and form sufficient deterrence. Those who throw objects from high altitudes will be caught and severely punished. Those who throw objects from high altitudes will have nowhere to hide. With fewer people daring to test the law, the sky above our heads will be safer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>