<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[朱哲琴：见山还是山]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259472]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi8FeyCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;703&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/xImYvF42LqnE84TiURg1nhOxRFSDZshfHi 8FeyCC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhu Zheqin was a teenager, he dreamed of becoming a traveler. A few years later, she won the second prize in popular singing in the professional group of the Youth Singing Competition. If she embarks on the path of an acting singer, she can choose from many record companies, performance opportunities, and gain both fame and fortune; she can also leave everything behind and pursue what she really wants to do, but she doesn&#39;t know what she wants to do at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1991, the year after participating in the Youth Singing Competition, 23-year-old Zhu Zheqin left Guangzhou for Chengdu, still determined to be a tour guide. Her collaborator at the time and for many years to come, the composer He Xuntian, was a little angry and said it was a pity that she didn&#39;t sing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although she failed to become a traveler, she later went to India, Bhutan, Nepal, Tibet, Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, Guizhou, and Xinjiang to collect music. Her singing has also gone far. Her first album &quot;Yellow Child&quot; (1992) showed artistic qualities in addition to popular singing. &quot;A Sister&#39;s Drum&quot; (1995) was published in 56 countries, becoming the first A Chinese album released globally, with &quot;Yangjinma&quot; (1997), the scope expanded to 65 countries. In the wave of New Age Music that emerged at the end of the 20th century, Zhu Zheqin is a representative figure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes she attributes herself to the laws of history - her popularity in the 1990s coincided with people&#39;s pursuit of spirituality after their material life was abundant. Sometimes she just said that people are really strange. What is a living thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took her a long time to figure out what she wanted to do. During this period, he released 6 albums, including a live recording album, held a world tour, served as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program, and initiated goodwill actions and original design platforms based on the protection and inheritance of Chinese traditional music and handicrafts. Then, by chance, I started sound art and have been creating it happily ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, social activities and artistic creation caused her to become relatively quiet in the field of music performance. After not giving a concert for nearly ten years, on September 30, 2023, she performed new music and sound art works, including a small concert, at the Aranya Jinshanling Community in Chengde, Hebei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I haven&#39;t sung for you for a long time.&quot; I saw her on the second day of the performance. We walked into a meditation room at the foot of the mountain. She took off her shoes and coat, and her black body disappeared on the gradually dimming tatami. Most of the lighting in this room comes from a floor-to-ceiling window. Outside the window is the dry landscape, only a sliver of sky is exposed, and dusk is approaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/t1U27X2z1WbK5TikYw6d0l9KQIox47yu50D2XHb2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;A long-lost slightly impromptu concert&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from July, at the invitation of Aranya, Zhu Zheqin stayed in Jinshanling for three months to create music and sound art. It is located at the junction of Beijing and Hebei. The ridge is dotted with ruins of the Great Wall of the Ming Dynasty, which are ruined and mixed with rubble. To the southwest is the capital city, where the forests are gradually dyed in autumn. The Jinshanling area is inhabited by aboriginal mountain people, and real estate development has attracted many &quot;new mountain people&quot; to buy homes or travel with their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Intentionally or unintentionally, Ma Yin, the founder of Aranya brand, wants to create a paradise here. First of all, transportation here is inconvenient, and secondly, it is extremely close to nature. At a dinner party and a conversation, Ma Yindu said: In the next ten years or more, we will spend more time in pain than happiness in our lives, so warming people&#39;s hearts may be a mainstream thing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin’s exhibition will be completed in two landmark buildings in Aranya Jinshanling. One is the upper courtyard designed by architect Liu Yichun. It is built according to the mountain and is composed of a courtyard, a terrace and a hall. It is the spiritual highland of the community. One is the Valley Concert Hall designed by architects Li Hu and Huang Wenjing. It looks like a boulder and an alien object from the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three months of residency, Zhu Zheqin visited the concert hall and upper courtyard at different times, early morning, dusk, midnight, windy, rainy or foggy. &quot;It&#39;s like you get to know a very strange person.&quot; Friend, you have to know his character, know when he is the softest and most moving, and also know when he is the strongest. This is my working method.&quot; Especially the Valley Concert Hall, contrary to conventional concert halls, it does not There is no condition to completely purify the sounds of human voices and musical instruments, because its roof reaches the sky and the four walls are cut out, connecting the inside and outside. Sitting on the concrete seats of the concert hall is like sitting in a hollow boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is completely opposite to the concept of a standard concert hall. It does not block ambient sounds, but hopes that you can hear ambient sounds in an open state, feel the changes in light, and know that everything wakes up in the morning. .&quot; For musicians, these are unique and rare performance venues that burst the imagination, but they also have great limitations. They make people rethink, what kind of performance is a good performance? What kind of listening experience does this performance bring to the audience? Why do these two buildings appear here? Why do people come here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On several occasions, Zhu Zheqin went mountain climbing with Bai Chunxiang, the local Great Wall protector. Once she saw the back of Bai Chunxiang sitting on the Great Wall. She looked at it for a long time and thought, how should we as contemporary people deal with themselves in these cultures? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lbaQoHgExHNiEcG259bwKpOzStLmFWBm1CmnzTHh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Mountain Questions·Secrets of Nature&quot; live performance&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;She seemed to be embarking on a new journey, with old experiences falling off like frozen leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Zhu Zheqin spent 15 days in the mountains to collect various sounds, downloaded sounds from other planets from NASA’s official website, and used ambient electronic music editing throughout. She decided to compose in a minimalist way in three sections. The melody has only five notes, do re mi so la, and the lyrics only have three sentences - &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, Seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still mountains, and seeing water is still water.&quot; She invited Jinshanling aborigines and &quot;new mountain people&quot; to form a choir, and also successively contacted other musicians, including arranger Meng Ke Zhuolan, guzheng Chang Jing, and wind blower Wang Hua and percussionist Chen Shijie, all of whom participated in her tour ten years ago, are now reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete performance design is as follows: in the afternoon, the audience follows the guide silently throughout the entire process through the four performance locations along the upper courtyard building complex, using their &quot;hearing&quot; to experience nature and the musicians&#39; understanding of natural sounds. The performance of the performance was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;; in the evening, I entered the Valley Concert Hall to listen to the concert, which was &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall structure of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; is strictly arranged, and each paragraph is mainly improvised. The day&#39;s weather, audience interaction, and the sounds of flora and fauna in the valley will all become part of the improvisation. Therefore, except for the chorus, which is composed, the other parts are improvised, and each rehearsal and performance will be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final rehearsal and recording was going on in the concert hall the night before the official performance. At 8 o&#39;clock, the mountain breeze passed through the hall, and the recording tube was full of whistling wind. Meng Ke Zhuolan&#39;s curly hair was blown all over her head. She stood at the mixer at the top of the back row and shouted to Zhu Zheqin at the bottom: &quot;Aren&#39;t you scared?&quot; Zhu Zheqin looked at her happily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Later we thought it was actually good to have wind, because if your music is open enough, it can accommodate this.&quot; Meng Kezhuolan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the night, the rehearsal was over. The next morning, Zhu Zheqin got up and turned on the recording to listen again. Suddenly, he kept crying. &quot;I feel extremely happy. I have never shed tears because of a good meal, but I may have read a poem, stood in front of the sea, watched a movie, and listened to Dupree&#39;s Elgar Cello Concerto in E minor, It makes me feel like my life has been turned into gold.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;166 cushions were squeezed into the originally 140-seat Valley Music Hall, and people were still coming in. Many people had to stand at the entrance to listen. At 6pm, the show starts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert hall was very dark at first, with only a beam of white light shining in from the roof, scanning the entire venue back and forth. In the center of the sunken stage, Zhu Zheqin’s long hair was tied up in a bunch, with his eyes closed, like an immortal sitting in a cave. middle. The sound of 432 Hz always surrounds this fairy cave. This is a soothing and healing sound frequency that Zhu Zheqin specially used this time. It is superimposed with the sounds of streams, frogs, chimes and alien planets to create a space far wider than a concert hall. Zhu Zheqin&#39;s voice has a long breath and a wide range, from far to near, from humming to singing. She was so happy with the performance that she clapped her hands and danced, swaying her three-meter-long costume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Derek Bailey discusses the concept of free improvisation in Improvisation: Its Essence and Musical Practice, he considers it to be a celebration of the moment. Li Jianhong, a musician who is keen on improvisation and the translator of &quot;Improvisation&quot;, regards improvisation as a channel. He believes that for a conscious musician, improvisation is always a way to explore the true self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhu Zheqin, all these are true, and can be interpreted in another way. Improvisation is also a coexistence between everyone and nature, and is a humble and great part of it, like flowing water, frogs, wind, and trees. Like crows, they live for a short period of time, but they also create enduring arts such as music, poetry, and painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the three-part singing was over, the musicians were supposed to be introduced, but that night she felt that anything she said in the middle of the performance was superfluous. So she performed all the way to the impromptu &quot;Finale&quot; that was originally prepared for everyone to leave at will. Halfway through the &quot;Finale&quot;, people still stayed where they were. Then she introduced the choir and performing members, thanked many people, and then said: &quot; It&#39;s been a long time since I sang for you.&quot; She paused and continued, &quot;We are already at the age when we are about to go down the mountain, but we climbed up a mountain together. This is rare in life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the time Near 8 o&#39;clock, Zhu Zheqin was worried that a strong wind was coming, and finally told the audience who were unwilling to leave, everyone should go back. People stood up one after another, but she was reluctant to leave. Amid the rustling footsteps leaving the concert hall, her singing voice suddenly sounded again, with a broad and clear voice: &quot;Seeing mountains is mountains, seeing water is water. Seeing mountains is not mountains, seeing water is not water. Seeing mountains is still water. Mountains, water is still water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/O1EkFns46Ibu19yVyHZzEqdLs92RMmfbED2Z0a6c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255462&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;World Hear·Ethnic Music Discovery Tour&quot; Guizhou Station, Zhu Zheqin led a team to record Miao girls singing &quot;Soul of Rice Flowers&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A week later, I met Guo Rong in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin has been working together for 11 years. Guo Rong found that every time there was a new art project, Zhu Zheqin would always leave a place for the &quot;old people&quot; who had worked together. Zhu Zheqin is surrounded by collaborators who have worked together for more than ten years, and she has become close partners in life with many of them. Guo Rong said that Zhu Zheqin maintained his enthusiasm for people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large part of the reason why Zhu Zheqin was so moved at the end of the concert and later at the dinner was that many friends came, including Xi Chuan, Li Xianting, Xu Bing, Zhang Xiaogang, Wu Ershan... &quot;It&#39;s too luxurious.&quot; She choked up when talking about these names, &quot;Their works have been with me for many years, and the spirit, energy, touch, and encouragement released by their creations have been useful to me for life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After (New Crown) I miss these friends very much during the epidemic. I feel that life is meaningless. They come and go naturally, but they are the scenery of my life. If they need my voice, I think I should sing to them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dinner As usual, let the guest of honor say a few words during the ceremony. Zhu Zheqin took the microphone and said he had nothing to say. Everyone said, &quot;Let&#39;s sing.&quot; She said, &quot;Come on.&quot; &quot;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot;.&quot; It&#39;s too long ago. &quot;Return.&quot; Just right, this is the theme song she wrote and sang for the movie &quot;Feng Shen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Christmas Eve 2019, Zhu Zheqin received a call from Wu Ershan and asked her if she wanted to go to Qingdao for Christmas. When I arrived in Qingdao, I discovered that it was a huge studio with thousands of people busy every day. Wuershan has been preparing for 10 years and spent 3 billion to make a trilogy of mythological epics. He hoped that Zhu Zheqin would write a song for &quot;Fengshen&quot;. They met as early as the 1990s. Zhu Zheqin watched Wu Ershan move from contemporary art to advertising shooting and then to film director. She felt that she did not have the courage to target a wider audience like Wu Ershan, and subconsciously refused: &quot;This is For a commercial blockbuster, I am not a traffic star and cannot bring you traffic.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our first choice is Teacher Zhu, and he is also the only choice. We want to write an art song with a melody Full, and at the same time the voice span is very large, because if you want to express very full emotions, it will involve a very large span between notes. No one (except her) can sing.&quot; said Meng Kezhuolan, who is Wu Ershan&#39;s wife , is also the music director of &quot;Fengshen&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guests fell silent, there was no accompaniment, and the sound was dry and dull, not suitable for singers to sing. But the three-part song was sung melodiously and stretched by Zhu Zheqin. It tells the story of the young Ji Fa who was sent to Chaoge as a hostage, and then escaped from the control of the tyrannical Shang King Yin Shou and returned to his hometown. The song was still being recorded during the COVID-19 epidemic. She had to return from abroad. According to epidemic prevention regulations, she was quarantined when she was in transit in Hong Kong, and then quarantined again after arriving in Beijing. Zhu Zheqin said that this is Ji Fa&#39;s homesickness, and it also embodies some of her nostalgia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11 o&#39;clock during the dinner, the brightly lit restaurant suddenly lost power and became completely dark. The staff found real and fake candles for lighting, and the guests were happy and cheered softly. Then someone said, let’s go see the moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The moonlight is bright and clear, the mountains are silent, and the cold night makes people shrink their necks and stamp their feet. A small group of people filed out through the narrow glass door and gathered on the platform to sing again, &quot;The moon passes through the white lotus-like clouds&quot; and &quot;You ask me how deeply I love you/How much I love you.&quot; / My love is true / My love is true / The moon represents my heart”... Sometimes it is a solo, sometimes it is a chorus of three or three, and someone brings a piano, and the echoes are like ripples. spread among the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They will definitely lose power when they are together. The spiritual energy field is too strong.&quot; Zhu Zheqin also remembered during the interview, &quot;It was like that in the 1980s and 1990s. There were no exhibitions at that time. There were no paintings to sell, no records, no concerts, all of this was nothing. Zhang Xiaogang was still painting stage sets for the Sichuan Opera Troupe as a living profession. But what he loved most was painting. He painted hard, and he had no money. No reason. In recent years, it seems that people paint just to go to auction, and how high the price is, and how good it is. In fact, it is not true. In my opinion, those are just projected phenomena. There is a powerful spiritual power behind it. I What I cherish is that kind of thing. I think that kind of thing will change the world and heal myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, the narrow door that everyone passes through from the restaurant to the terrace seems to have become a door to time and space. , outside the door is their spiritual hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;I think people of every era are the masters of this era. The history of this era is created and left by us, so what do we want to create? If we are dissatisfied with reality, Then why don&#39;t we do some ourselves? I&#39;m not one to complain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was singing &quot;A True Story&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Red-Crowned Crane&quot;&lt;/span>;) and became famous after winning the Youth Singing Competition, a fan appeared at the door of the hotel in the middle of the night and said to her, I think you are the Red-Crowned Crane. She was scared away because &quot;it impressed them so strongly that they stayed there forever.&quot; She didn’t know what she wanted at that time, but she knew what she didn’t want—not to become a singer, not to be packaged, not to enter a paradigm. &quot;Someone in my heart said, no, no, no. But, what are you going to do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;468&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /yQeEdjBF1wJS0Ud62RZkcYfqakKALJiTfhyn62F3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Double CD &quot;Moonrise&quot; by Zhu Zheqin and ethnic singers&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, the market economy developed rapidly and social trends moved away from single collectivism. Zhu Zheqin recalled That feeling of liberating the mind, &quot;Actually, people are quite confused, and they don&#39;t know where they are in this coordinate.&quot; She did not sign with any record company, nor did she join an art troupe, and disappeared from the public eye. She went to Chengdu from Guangzhou, and a year later, &quot;Yellow Child&quot; composed by He Xuntian and sung by Zhu Zheqin was released. Later, historian Luo Xin wrote about a detail when he was reflecting on and criticizing racial thinking. On a winter night when he was working on his doctoral thesis, he heard &quot;Yellow Children&quot; being played on the radio, &quot;that empty and desolate feeling of loneliness and hopelessness.&quot; &quot;It tells the loss of the East in front of the West.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, &quot;A Sister Drum&quot; was released. This was the second collaboration between Zhu Zheqin and He Xuntian. They took a trip to Tibet, which they regarded as a spiritual holy land, and returned many times. But no matter how impressive the natural scenery, humanities and art in Tibetan areas are, what makes Zhu Zheqin most unforgettable is still the &quot;people&quot;. It is &quot;the scenes of their lives in poverty that made me have to re-evaluate the weight of my life.&quot; She got a new name, Dadawa. Dadawa is reminiscent of Dadaism, which was later basically annexed by Surrealism. Dadawa is the Tibetan word for the moon. Dadawa is neither the East nor the West. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ajie Drum&quot; and &quot;Yangjinma&quot; two years later form a complete expression of their Tibet, which is mysterious and strong on the one hand, and everyday and light on the other, bringing Zhu Zheqin to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten years later, she also made a physical journey across Asia. From Kashmir to the Himalayas, I sweated and sneezed while clicking the shutter in the spice markets of India, and took a tricycle to look for gypsies. Gypsy Bopa played the music on a very simple folk violin. Zhu Zheqin was fascinated by it. It took him a while to come back to his senses and said that it was like hearing real music for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also during that trip, she saw Hindus waiting for death by the Ganges River, and the cremated corpses rolled down to her feet. &quot;Journey to the Ganges is another starting point in my life, where I realize the meaninglessness of life. Our life is redefined by our values ​​and culture, which celebrates the greatness of life. A person&#39;s birth must be celebrated, and a person&#39;s death must be commemorated. . But if you imagine that a fish is born and dies, it is a natural thing, nothing more. The truth of the universe is that you are like a leaf, yellow today and withered tomorrow.&quot; She thought, if life is like this, what will happen to people? Life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/moHob6dSTD1sdob5xq1BTDB9wa38LRzdGOEyxrht.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ask the Mountain·Theme Concert&quot;, Zhu Zheqin and musicians performed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Asking is the beginning of Tao&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, the first year of the new coronavirus pandemic, Zhu Zheqin entered a &quot;dormant state&quot;. She spent most of her time at home, cooking, taking care of the yard, and thinking about nothing. &quot;I rarely have such a stage where I shut down my phone. Suddenly I felt how fragile the world is and how vulnerable human civilization is to an invisible virus.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second year, she began to I thought, if there are no recordings, no exhibitions, no concerts in the future, what else will I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Zheqin was admitted to the Guangzhou &quot;Little Skylark&quot; Chorus at the age of 7 and performed at the Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hall. At the age of 13, she recorded children&#39;s singing teaching materials. She can sing any type of opera. During school, she worked as a singer in a karaoke hall, and then she became famous. , hold concerts, explore your own expression and style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the trip to India shattered the meaning of life, Zhu Zheqin felt that he had reached a point in time where all expressions seemed pale and feeble, and he had to look inward to find something more essential. &quot;When you find yourself weightless or confused, only by daring to throw yourself out can you have a chance to regain your life.&quot; In 2009, she accepted the appointment as the China Goodwill Ambassador of the United Nations Development Program and launched the &quot;World Sees-China &quot;Ethnic Culture Protection and Development Goodwill Action&quot;, conducting field research on folk music and handicrafts in ethnic minority areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, she realized that she and the entire generation had a very weak understanding of their own culture. Zhu Zheqin said: &quot;In modern China, a &#39;modernity&#39; suddenly appeared, but this &#39;modernity&#39; may have nothing to do with its own culture and is a collage. From the time we started to imitate to the time we realized that imitation was not It is not ourselves, and then we have to find and construct it. The first stage is to create something from scratch, and then we have to take root, grow up, be local, and reflect the face of the people of this land and water.&quot; She deliberately made young people Many musicians participated in the project to organize and adapt folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, she released her last album to date, &quot;Moonrise&quot;, a double CD. One is a collection of original ethnic minority music, and the other is a musician&#39;s work that has been arranged and sung. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the creative team of &quot;Moonrise&quot; held a world tour with ethnic singers and young musicians. Meng Kezhuolan served as composer and arranger. She was less than 30 years old at the time and mainly wrote chamber music. Before a performance, Zhu Zheqin asked Meng Kezhuolan to come and listen. That was the first time she heard a singer and musician singing Miao Fei Song sitting in front of her. As soon as the other person opened his mouth, she got goosebumps all over her body. &quot;I was suddenly photographed there. His earthy, tanned look no longer existed in front of me. I thought to myself that if he were in a Miao village, all the girls would fall in love with him.&quot; Until a few days ago, wind player Wang Hua still remembered that tour during the rehearsal of &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and said that it was the best performance he had participated in in so many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;World Seeing&#39; thing seems to help others, but it actually saved me.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said frankly, &quot;After the meaning of life was shattered, it gave me a stage to learn and do something. Specific things. At that time, I had a very big feeling. I thought I was a drop of water, but I was also an ocean. Only when I became a water drop could I be an ocean.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But after that, Zhu Zheqin never released an album and had only a handful of public performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As a singer, I use singing to express my thoughts and feelings, but apart from that, I have always been more interested in inner energy.” Along this path, she entered sound art, “I want to Know what else is inside me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it didn&#39;t go well at first. In 2014, Gao Peng, then director of Today Art Museum, approached Zhu Zheqin and asked her to create a sound art work. After two visits, her reply was pending. Guo Rong hoped to persuade Zhu Zheqin to start a new attempt. She said: &quot;Teacher Zhu, I came to your team because I like your music and your voice.&quot; Something seemed to be touched in Zhu Zheqin&#39;s heart. A few days later, she flew abroad. Before leaving, she left a note for Guo Rong, which listed 20 issues, including time points, production schedules, and problems faced... Guo Rong was relieved when she saw it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, I think the process of her asking these questions is also a process of self-answering. If I didn&#39;t answer her at that time, someone else would answer her. If no one else answered her, she would answer these questions herself. Question.&quot; Guo Rong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, the Sound·Jue Zhu Zheqin sound art exhibition opened. Today Art Museum was painted into a dark box, with a pool on the ground. Zhu Zheqin recruited dozens of people to walk back and forth beside the pool, making sounds and playing chimes. She did not sing, but stood in the crowd, and all the sounds turned into ripples, reflected on the wall, turning the invisible into something tangible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The mystery of all things lies in the combination of things. The world is a temporary combination of consciousness, and music is sound. The essence of sound is waves and vibrations. So I think vibration is a very direct way to approach consciousness. . I am very lucky to be on this road.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;It was only when I became aware of my voice that I fully understood myself. I want to create a field and let everyone enter, so that people can realize that everyone is actually affected by something. Driven by an inner energy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you are at the scene, as both Meng Ke Zhuolan and Guo Rong have described, it seems that everyone has come to another time and space, temporarily breaking away from external forces and moving inwards. Zhu Zheqin tried to create this feeling in his seven subsequent sound art works, including &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot; and &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three lyrics in &quot;Ask the Mountain&quot; are also a portrayal of her journey back to her inner self. In the beginning, people looked at things through the universal laws of phenomena. The saying goes: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; When superficial phenomena are denied, solid and perfect things become vulnerable, and perfection is just a fantasy. This is: &quot;Seeing mountains is not mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, &quot;After the first year of the COVID-19 epidemic, I thought, when I was 6 years old, no one said that I would have concerts, wouldn&#39;t I still sing every day? I just love this thing, it is Bringing me joy in life, helping me grow and perceive the world, isn’t it more real than anything else? When you reach this point, you will see your true nature. Just like birds singing in the sky and fish swimming in the sea, if I have wings, I will Fly.&quot; Zhu Zheqin said, &quot;In such an era, I think it is more important to maintain an imagination, maintain poetry, and maintain free thoughts about reality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this a mountain or a mountain? . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the concert &quot;Asking the Mountain&quot;, everyone will get a small guide card at the entrance of the Valley Concert Hall, which reads: Creation stems from the perception of the mountains, and does not seek to understand the mountains and the world. Any definition of &quot;mountain dwelling&quot; nor explore any answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the performance, I walked up the mountain along the path connecting the Valley Concert Hall and the Upper Court. There was a small dark green sign hanging on a tree on the roadside, with a black arrow pointing to the depths of the mountain. There is a line of small words attached to the arrow: There will be answers in the mountains. Continuing in the direction pointed by the arrow, the same arrow guide appeared one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sign ends in front of an old cave. This is a small house built against a shallow cave, with three real people enshrined inside. There was a kang built against the wall. There were traces of fire underneath, but now the window paper was broken and air leaked from all sides. There was no sound for a while. Am I the only one in this world? &quot;Will there be answers in the mountains&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While listening to me talk about this experience, Zhu Zheqin looked at a certain place on the roof. The meditation room fell into silence, and became darker as the sky darkened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, she said, when you start asking, that is the beginning of the Tao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to Huang Yao for his help)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>; Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[她研究在美中国本科留学生，发现高远志向下的挣扎和迷茫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259545]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QRIdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1226&quot; height=&quot;817&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o0I00cNuZ36LrUM9459x0QR IdqPX4WLh5Jn3Kh8n. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 17, 2022 local time, New York University graduates celebrated their graduation ceremony. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The annual application season for international students is here again. According to the &quot;2023 Study Abroad in China White Paper&quot; released by New Oriental, more than 50% of people intend to study abroad with a bachelor&#39;s degree or below. The situation of studying abroad is picking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, two other reports are also worthy of attention. On September 25, 2023, the National Student Credentials Certification Center in the United States released a report &quot;Completing College&quot; that showed that the undergraduate dropout rate for Chinese students in the United States was as high as 25%. In the same month, WholeRen, a Pennsylvania-based education consulting company, released the &quot;2023 White Paper on the Current Situation of Chinese Students in the United States.&quot; According to statistics, 70% of Chinese students who have been dismissed from the United States are undergraduates, and more than half of the students are studying in the top 50 schools in the United States. The top two reasons for being dismissed were academic dishonesty and poor academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The data only presents the tip of the iceberg. In the seemingly distant American education system, many Chinese students are indeed experiencing struggles under the glamorous impression&lt;/span>;. Ma Yingyi, a professor of sociology at Syracuse University in the United States, wrote the book &quot;Ambitious and Anxious: The Success and Struggle of Chinese College Students in American Higher Education&quot; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ambitious and Anxious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;How Chinese College Students Succeed and Struggle in American Higher Education&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;) &lt;/span>;, describes the status of Chinese students in the United States as &quot;ambition and anxiety coexist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She found that whether they came from wealthy families or ordinary families, these international students began to experience this contradiction before arriving in the United States, and it intensified after entering college. They have big dreams, but in pursuing their dreams, they experience academic and social struggles and feel confused about their futures. They worry about whether they will be able to earn enough money after graduation to pay off their parents&#39; investment in education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this takes place against the background of the rapid development of Chinese society. All these anxieties forced them to think about the ultimate question: Is it really worth studying in the United States? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The samples surveyed by Ma Yingyi included 507 Chinese international students from 50 American undergraduate colleges and universities, all born in the 1990s. The survey period was from 2011 to 2019. The book won the 2021 American Association for Comparative and International Education Higher Education Best Book Award and the American Sociological Association’s Bourdieu Book Honor Award. Recently, Ma Yingyi accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The increase in undergraduate international students is not due to the financial crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How did you pay attention to the group of Chinese international students in American undergraduate education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingyi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My research began in 2011. At that time, major universities in the United States began to have a large number of Chinese undergraduates. Prior to this, most Chinese students studying abroad in the 1980s and 1990s studied in China for graduate school and then went to the United States to study for Ph.D., or they completed their undergraduate studies in China and then went to the United States for graduate school, as was the case for me. Twenty years ago, I first came to the United States after earning my bachelor&#39;s degree in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But around 2007, a large number of students came to the United States to study for undergraduates after completing high school in China, and some even went directly to the United States to study in high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that most of the previous generation of international students either relied on scholarships from the United States to study for master&#39;s or doctoral degrees, or were sponsored by the Chinese government to study in the United States. As for the generation of undergraduates I follow, 90% are completely self-funded. For in-state students, tuition at public universities in the United States is very cheap, but international students have to pay extra, which is higher than out-of-state students, and private universities charge even more. Therefore, whether applying to public or private universities, the cost for Chinese international students is very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, this is a brand new phenomenon, reflecting the rise of the middle class and the accumulation of wealth in Chinese society. Then during the research process, I gradually discovered the duality of ambition and anxiety among this generation of international students. Whether it is academic or social life, or planning for the future, this contradiction is reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在市场上的留学中介会建议家长为孩子去美国留学准备一年一百万的巨额费用，相比英国、加拿大、澳大利亚、新加坡等地区花费更高。为什么还有那么多中国家庭愿意支付？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;美国本科留学的费用成本相比其他地区可能是最高的，所以很多人误认为，赴美留学的中国学生都是企业家的子女，但其实那样的人只是少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社会学里，收入和财富是两个不一样的概念。收入是你的工资，仅从收入来看，中国的中产阶层或许无力承担赴美的学费。但财富不一样，财富可以包括房产、股票等，在中国主要是房产。从2000年代开始，中国城市化发展迅猛，房市腾飞，许多并不算富裕的家庭也积累了一定的财富。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我收集到的样本中，有些父母是中学老师，有些甚至是基层工薪阶层。因为有房子，他们选择变现这个财富来支持孩子出国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;美国大学的老师们怎么看这种变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我曾遇到一位普渡大学的行政官员，他说学校在2008年金融危机以后出现了财政危机，恰好这个时候中国本科生来了，也有了支付高昂学费的能力。他形容这是一个“完美的婚姻”。我当时发现这是一个非常系统的现象，这背后不仅有双方的需求，于是开始着手研究。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;赴美本科留学生的增加是因为美国的金融危机吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多人说中国留学生的增加是在2008年金融危机之后，那时美国大学缺钱。但我的调查数据显示，中国赴美留学生人数年增长率最高的年份是2007年，是在金融危机之前。所以并不是美国大学的需求导致中国留学生迅速增加，更多是因为中国中产及以上阶层对于子女教育的需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时中国经历了经济发展迅速、中产阶级崛起，居民收入也迅速增加。我在书中提到的另一个因素是2006 到2014 年人民币升值，到2014 年，人民币升值了大约37%，中国家庭的支付能力更强了。另一方面是中国的好大学仍然非常难进，而美国目前为止仍然是世界上好大学最聚集的地方，所以很多人来到美国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;三个阶段都有“志向和焦虑并存”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的研究是如何展开的？又是怎样观察到“志向和焦虑并存”的情况？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的调查从2011年开始，最开始是用抽样法在线调查，再挑选出愿意参加深度访谈的学生。我们收到了来自50所院校的507 份调查问卷，最终对65名2013年到2016年在美国读本科的中国留学生做了深度访谈。我让学生选择英语或中文，几乎每个人都说中文。之后三年，我在中国六个城市的九所高中进行了实地调查，还采访了一些学校辅导员、校长和老师。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我把他们的经历分为三个阶段。第一个阶段是学生来美国之前，需要准备申请、考试、择校，整个过程充满焦虑，这很大程度来源于他们的抱负，因为他们就想进排名前30、前50的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个阶段是选专业。要选一个满足自己兴趣又好找工作的，这里开始出现与父母的矛盾。在社交阶段也焦虑，中国学生很不熟悉美国学生的社交方式和娱乐方式，导致难以融入。很多学生出国的目的就是想接触多元文化，接触不同的圈子，所以这也带来很大的压力和落差感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后一个阶段是对未来的规划。我做调研的时候，就业市场还不像现在这样，但也有各种问题。比如想留在美国就有签证的问题，回中国又有难以融入国内圈子、如何使用国内社会资本以及择业的问题。他们也迫切希望自己的学历和经历能够获得满意的回报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这三个阶段中都可以明显观察到这种“志向和焦虑并存”的二元性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相较于其他国家留学生而言，中国学生身上这种二元性会更突出吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;任何一个留学生都会面临这种状态。具体到中国留学生，不少人家里卖房或借贷供养孩子留学，这一代又大多是独生子女，很多人需要回到父母身边。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然从哲学的眼光来看待，志向本身就能产生焦虑。但中国留学生在这一点上更加突出，我在写作的过程中意识到，理解这一代留学生，其实非常重要的是理解他们背后的中国社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去二十年，中国社会其实也是一种志向和焦虑并存的状态。没有哪个国家像中国变化这么大，各个阶层的人都感受到很多变化，很多人实现了富裕，很多人有很大的抱负和野心。人们视野开阔，收入增加，同时也总在担心自己错失了什么机会，他们迫切希望获得国际视野，但这需要很多资源，人们也开始担心，自己的投资是否能获得足够的回报，这一切都带来焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来自这个环境的中国留学生自然也如此。而且留学生在任何社会里都不是一个随机的人群，他们都是有志向、有一定特权的一群人。在社会学上，流动人口相对不流动人口是更具野心和目标性的。留学生要读书拿学位，要见识更大的世界，他们甚至背负着整个家族的期待和目光，承载着社会变迁带来的压力和机会，机遇和挑战并存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，中国的社会虽然发生了巨大的变化，但教育变化相对没有那么大，主要还在于高考仍是指挥棒。中国孩子和美国孩子接受的中小学教育差异非常大，中国留学生是带着中国教育的烙印到美国的高等教育去的，这个变化本身也给他们带来很大的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之，中国留学生可能在全世界留学生群体里面，或者说流动人口里，是最具备“志向和焦虑二元性”的群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1007&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/K6zJfahPg7LyzIdrNINGBRE3Bv747eqJGNgtyTJY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左：《雄心勃勃与忧心忡忡：中国大学生在美国高等教育中的成功与挣扎》。右：美国雪城大学社会学教授马颖毅。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;遭遇“落差感”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在书中还提到，一些中国留学生到美国后，会因学校在“村里”而震惊？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最有名的案例是伊利诺伊大学香槟分校，大家说它是一片玉米地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这和中美高等教育发展的历史有很大的关系。中国大学集中在大城市，而美国其实大城市没几个，但有很多大学城镇，就是在大农村建的学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个州都有自己的旗舰学校，QS排名靠前的学校不一定在大城市里。当然大学排名是一个片面的、容易误导大家的信息。美国的大学非常多样，公立学校里有非常好的学术类院校，也有社区大学，不同的学校有不同的使命，它们没有严格意义上的优劣之分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么留学生那么看重大学排名？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;一个原因在于，美国的招生制度很不一样，它不是只看分数，你都不知道分数会占有多大比例，没有办法定量地判断是10%，还是5%，还是90%，每个学校都不一样，每个专业也不一样，每个学校不同年份也不一样，没有人会告诉你。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国学生也许因为这个学校的某项运动取得过很好的成绩、学校离家近，甚至风景好等各种五花八门的原因而选择。但中国学生不了解这些，大学排名就成为他们背负的压力和焦虑的其中一个来源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在你的访谈对象中，这种“落差感”还出现在哪些方面？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;生活上的落差感，包括人际交往。他们此前可能认为美国人热情开放，后来才发现交朋友没有想象的那么容易。比如，有些学生刚开始雄心勃勃，希望能交到很多美国朋友，但很快受挫。美国大学生非常重要的社交娱乐方式是周末聚会，聚会上很多人都要喝酒，同时玩一些喝酒游戏，比如在一个啤酒瓶上放个乒乓球，大家一起吹，球击中了谁，谁就喝酒。很多中国孩子没办法加入其中，很多人觉得喝酒游戏难以忍受。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人就觉得很挫败，回到中国学生的圈子。这个圈子的娱乐可能是大家一起吃饭，去KTV唱歌，女孩逛街，男孩打游戏。很多中国学生会觉得，我出国不应该还是跟中国人在一起玩，甚至他们的父母会督促他们交美国朋友，说“不交美国朋友的话，你英语都还不如出国以前”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一位中国留学生，英语说得非常好，性格外向，有很多美国朋友，大家都以为他是在美国长大的。但他融入美国大学生圈子后，挺失望，没有像此前想象的那样享受多元文化，所以又回到了中国人的圈子，在中国留学生群体里承担领导职务，主持春晚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个很有趣的回归，出去转了一圈，想象破碎，再回来。在哲学意义上，这种回归是一个寻找自己的过程，尽管他表面上最后又回到中国学生当中，但他出来看过了、交往过了、感受过了不一样的世界，那和他当初没有走出去的状态，是完全不一样的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他们都是如何去适应这种“落差感”的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这种落差感会影响他们对留学的满意度，会影响他们整个状态，包括学习、社交、日常生活等，其实是很难适应的。但时间本身能带来习惯，一直不习惯的学生有可能会选择离开，比如说有些学生本科学校在美国的大农村，那他们毕业以后，就会申请去纽约、波士顿之类的大城市读研究生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总而言之还是要加深对自己和新环境的理解，留学之前，先了解自己到底想要什么，学校能够提供什么，尽量减少一些误解，才能减少之后因为误解带来的不满意和焦虑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做一些准备工作对于适应环境很有好处，比如一位学生，家里条件比较好，父母在Twitter上给他找了一个美国朋友，专门陪他练口语、交流生活，还有一些学生会提前到美国学校附近适应环境。我还做了一些统计分析发现，多参加社团活动、参加学校组织等都可以提升学生的留学满意度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了生活，留学生不在课堂上发言，难以很好地融入课堂和学术活动其实也一直是个问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;他们可能非常想表达、想参与，但很难参与。这种求而不得的状况，其实带来很多心理负担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于课堂讨论我有切身体验。我经常上课让同学们讨论，讨论不完全是对英语交流的挑战，语言是最基本的门槛，很多英语很好的同学同样难以参与讨论。我的调研显示，60%的学生都认为自己的英语很好，但所有学生里只有20%-30%的同学认为自己经常上课发言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是什么因素阻碍了他们？我认为，一个非常重要的原因是基本思维模式的差异，学生不能勇敢充分地表达自己。大多数中国课堂一直在寻求标准答案，学生总担心自己说出的话对不对。而美国大学课堂是开放式的讨论，没有正确答案，这是一个相当大的差异。中国学生需要改变思维模式，才能够有效地参与讨论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;扬长避短，而不是补差补缺&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这本书2020年出版，之后这3年间，我们都经历了更多变化，你有没有观察到一些新的情况？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;全世界的留学生在新冠疫情期间都很困难，旅行不便，远离家人，中国留学生应该说是处境更困难。我的基本结论没有改变，但这三年显然让“忧心忡忡”变严重了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;怎么理解“忧心忡忡”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;具体的挑战是不确定性，这体现在留学生活的方方面面。航班什么时候能增加？回国能不能容易一些？学生签证、工作签证怎么这么难办？美国的政策、舆论趋势等，都会增加中国学生的心理压力。这都是10年前的中国学生所没有的压力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，写这本书时，选择美国好像是非常一致的倾向，但现在有很多学生选择了欧洲、日本包括中国香港等，这是一个比较大的改变。近期发布的数据显示，在美的印度留学生已经超过了中国留学生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你如何看待留学低龄化的趋势？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;越来越多家庭选择送年龄小的孩子去留学，这可能是出于结构性的原因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在标准化考试的淘汰体系里，大多数人都不是优胜者。有一些学生虽然成为了优胜者，但在这种竞争的环境下，他没办法获得比较平衡的身心发展，或者他不开心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以很多家庭选择低龄留学，显然大家都知道是有风险的，相比于大学生而言风险更高，但他们分析了风险和回报之后觉得利大于弊，才会做出这种选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对于中国留学生和家长有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;马颖毅：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;最重要的就是通过各种方式多去了解自己。比如通过父母、朋友，或者通过参与各种活动去更全面地认识自己。留学其实只是打开了一个窗口，来了以后要做出很多选择，包括选什么课、参加什么样的社团、选择怎样的未来道路等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国高等教育一个很大的优势，就是提供了很多选择。一个人要做出适合自己的选择，非常重要的前提就是自我认知。所以要了解自己，了解自己优势是什么，弱点是什么，对哪些东西有热情，哪些能力是培养不出来的。一个人不可能擅长所有的东西，现代社会最重要的是，要做自己擅长和感兴趣的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不够了解自己的话也没有关系，我觉得这是一辈子的功课。但是学生现在要有这种意识，从现在就开始关注自己的兴趣特长，扬长避短，而不是去补差补缺。我觉得学生和家长都需要做出思维上的调整。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以舆论战开打，以色列缘何撤销公共外交部？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259553]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, 2023 local time, the Israeli cabinet decided to revoke the country’s main responsibility for public diplomacy through a telephone vote. , the Ministry of Information for External Propaganda Affairs (generally referred to as the &quot;Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs&quot; in news reports), and said that the ministry&#39;s budget will be transferred to the recovery and reconstruction of communities around the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a gesture by the Israeli government directed at both its domestic public and the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Abolish the so-called inaction departments internally, find scapegoats, and try to homogenize domestic public opinion. It has demonstrated its determination to burn its boats to the outside world, and any attempt by the outside world to interfere with Israel&#39;s will will be rejected. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs mean? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The term &quot;public diplomacy&quot; was first proposed by Professor Edmund Glean of Tufts University in the United States in 1965. He believed that public diplomacy is to ensure that one&#39;s own country maintains effective relations with foreign countries. Thought connection”. More generally speaking, public diplomacy is a strategic plan to carry out national marketing and create a positive and good international image. It is a &quot;popular project&quot; to win the hearts and minds of the international people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Israel directly announced the immediate dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs. It is obvious that it has deeply felt the changes in international public opinion. Israel’s external propaganda department cannot escape the blame for this, although Israel is doing a positive job The battlefield has an overwhelming advantage, but the corresponding situation is not shown on the battlefield of public opinion. The reasons behind this are worthy of scrutiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, global public opinion has embarrassed Israel, which not only seriously interferes with Israel&#39;s upcoming retaliatory actions, but also has the potential to further weaken Israel&#39;s internal unity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this atmosphere, Minister of Public Foreign Affairs Atbaryan&#39;s voluntary resignation not only gave herself a step down, but also showed her support for the Netanyahu government. She said, &quot;Put aside Self-deprecation aside, running a ministry in such a horrific time of war is an expensive problem and the Israeli people need every shekel.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the latest opinion poll conducted by the &quot;Jerusalem Post&quot; showed that nearly four-fifths of the people believe that the Netanyahu government needs to deal with this large-scale Hamas infiltration and Responsible for the massacre of Jews, the Israeli government must not only unite internally and externally at this moment, but also consider a potential post-war political reckoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Israel’s internal struggles remain complex and changeable, which has profoundly affected Israel’s security environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israeli media pointed out that the Ministry of Public Affairs not only failed to fulfill its obligations, but even interfered in Israel&#39;s internal affairs for a long period of time. This minister from the Likud Party has used his power to vigorously promote the government&#39;s judicial reform and made a series of inflammatory remarks. For example, in April 2023, Atbaryan directly pointed out that the military, police and media composed of The deep state network is working hard to overthrow the government, which is reminiscent of how the Turkish government described the Gulen movement before the attempted coup in 2016, highlighting that the Israeli state and society are gradually being torn apart. In addition, she has launched scar-revealing attacks on her political critics, underscoring her right-wing conservative ultra-hardline political stance, which runs counter to Israel&#39;s desire to be diplomatic in its international propaganda matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on October 12, before the department was disintegrated, she issued a resignation statement, saying that the power of her department had been weakened, and there was an overlap of powers between the Ministry of Expatriate Affairs and the Ministry of Public Affairs. The Ministry of Foreign Affairs only received its budget six months after the new government was formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first cabinet member to resign after a new round of conflict between Palestine and Israel broke out. This is just a microcosm of Israel’s domestic struggle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Palestinian-Israeli conflict, analyzed only from a technical level and from an absolutely neutral political stance, has greatly shocked Israel. It is comparable in form to the Fourth Middle East War and in terms of psychological trauma. Compared with the &quot;9·11&quot; incident in the United States. This is not unrelated to the division of domestic public opinion caused by Israel&#39;s promotion of judicial reform in the past year. The root cause is the long-standing dispute between left and right, religious and secular disputes in Israel&#39;s internal affairs, as well as the frequent changes of governments in recent years. hidden fundamental crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, fortresses are breached from within. Israel’s recent political chaos has seriously affected its military and intelligence systems, giving Hamas room to take advantage of the situation. In addition, the peace process between Israel and Saudi Arabia About to enter its final chapter, Hamas urgently needs to give the international community a heavy blow and prove to the world that Middle East reconciliation that bypasses the Palestinian-Israeli issue is putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the dissolution of the Ministry of Public Affairs heralds the imminence of a larger-scale bloody operation. Israel is consolidating all resources and preparing for war. Israel&#39;s domestic thinking in fighting Palestine urgently needs to form a united front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel’s move is also preparing for the worst for the safety of the hostages, that is, it ignores the hostage weight in the hands of Hamas, ignores domestic and foreign voices in favor of reconciliation negotiations, and treats Hamas the possibility of a complete liquidation. But this is undoubtedly a difficult decision. Hundreds of thousands of soldiers on the Israeli border are hesitant. During Biden&#39;s visit, he issued &quot;Advice to Israel&quot; and so on. These all prove that the large-scale ground war against Gaza will not only affect Israel&#39;s The international image is more likely to cause further division within Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The situation on the battlefield of public opinion is tense&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a medium for public diplomacy and a window for understanding the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the importance of public opinion is self-evident. With the many conflicts that have broken out in recent years Similarly, the public opinion field is the second battlefield opened by all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, various advanced technological means, such as 5G, streaming media, artificial intelligence and mobile-based social media networks, have made the battlefield of public opinion mixed, making it difficult to distinguish between true and false, and the situation is changing rapidly, which has brought about The &quot;information tide&quot; has a strong ability to induce and differentiate positions and values ​​and create opposing emotions for the public who lack certain professional knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the public opinion war in this Palestinian-Israeli conflict, it has the following three major characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the mature development of streaming media and online live broadcast technology has given global audiences a stronger audio-visual impact on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. The timeliness and impact of information dissemination have greatly increased, and it has also provided opportunities for the proliferation of false information. It has provided a breeding ground for various conspiracy theories, historical-realistic information confusion and propaganda, and fake accounts and robot trolls have emerged one after another on social media. While expanding attention, it has also set off a confrontation between the two factions around the world. These include positional opposition (supporting Israel or supporting Pakistan), religious opposition (Judaism and Islam), ethnic opposition (Arabs and Jews), and intra-sect opposition (moderate factions exist within both Arabs and Jews). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Hamas launched its attack, it used heavy bulldozers to break through the Gaza separation wall and carry out bloody killings inside the Israeli border posts. The video was broadcast live on the Internet. This video set off a new wave of sectarianism in the Arab world. , nationalistic sentiments, but also directly angered groups sympathetic to Jews. It is precisely because of the popularity of the Internet and mobile devices that war has achieved a certain form of visibility and transparency, and has become a hotbed and soil for breeding public opinion wars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, when the Western media reported on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the wording was the Israel-Hamas War, not the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. This highlights the asymmetric nature of the conflict and is a precautionary endorsement of a potential high-intensity Israeli military strike. Hidden behind this is the challenge to the loopholes in international law and the laws of war. Because the laws of war are applicable to sovereign states, the Israeli Defense Forces&#39; attack on Hamas is most likely to be a &quot;police-like war.&quot; Such a narrative will also separate the public from the perspective of ethnic and religious conflicts. The legitimacy of the war on terrorism is obviously greater than the battle for territory. It can be seen that the inclusion of stance in narrative strategies is an eternal pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the public opinion war in this conflict has typical sinking and spillover effects. This conflict has transcended the conflicts between Palestine and Israel and Kazakhstan and Israel, and has shown a trend of spillover and camp formation. Currently, both sides are working hard to seek legitimacy for the war, and have moved from the level of international authoritative media to the level of mass entertainment media. The two sides are competing for the right to speak across the air in other countries. This is not common in previous war conflicts, but it is inevitable for the vigorous development of modern information technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, after Israel announced the dissolution of its Public Ministry of Foreign Affairs, it has in a sense reaped the consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Hamas publicly released two old Israeli women. A video of them shaking hands with masked Hamas members and saying goodbye went viral on social platforms, and they later faced dozens of reporters. , the released elderly people said that Hamas treated them very friendly and responded to their requests. The accounts of those who have witnessed it are extremely impactful, which has compressed the public opinion space in Israel now and even for a long time in the future, and also caused doubts in the Israeli media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The game between Palestine and Israel has never stopped when narrating the war. The mutual siege is not only a portrayal of the real battlefield, but also a manifestation of online public opinion. This is a microcosm of the structural contradiction between Palestine and Israel in the field of international political communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(The author Yang Fuxin is an assistant researcher at the Institute of Environmental Studies at Zhejiang International Studies University; Ma Xiaolin is a professor at Zhejiang International Studies University and an environmental Director of the Mediterranean Institute)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[难以推开的石门，看完很扎心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 22:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;In recent years, female-themed works have exploded, but most of them Focusing on the plight of urban women, there are still very few films with small town women as protagonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which was recently released on streaming media, is a precious image of the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/24e847a87b538a5e8d415b57418b1a23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255861&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;The directors of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; are rising independent film stars Huang Ji and Otsuka Ryuji, who are a husband-and-wife team. The two co-produced the &quot;Women&#39;s Trilogy&quot; &quot;Eggs and Stones&quot;, &quot;Stupid Bird&quot; and this &quot;Stone Gate&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;391&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/fce83c6651e3d60eb39ae2261db8f6df.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255863&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in Hunan In the small town, Huang Ji&#39;s perspective mainly focuses on the survival plight of rural women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Eggs and Stones&quot; focuses on the left-behind girls who were sexually assaulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;850&quot; height= &quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d22f211bf6810a183841027b8696a85f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255862&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stupid Bird&quot; &quot;Through the carrier of &quot;mobile phone&quot;, it shows the growing confusion of left-behind girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height= &quot;400&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/14965ab1cecd4dfa8b029de7324b7cbb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Stone Gate&quot; It takes the experiences of female college student Lin Sen as a slice to reflect reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ages of the heroines in the trilogy are consistent, they are 14, 17 and 20 years old respectively, and the same actor Yao Honggui was chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is more mature than the previous two films. The film style is very similar to the early works of domestic sixth-generation directors that we are familiar with. It uses non-professional actors, talks about marginalized groups, and prefers extreme Life-like scenes and an objective and calm perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/8fa8ab8a6e1614c11be8c2dab955b11d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the kernel , with Huang Ji’s own characteristics and personal experience, his friend and work partner Otsuka Ryuji can also make some observations about the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The narrative of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; relies on the three identities of a 20-year-old girl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, she is Lin Sen, a beautiful female college student, studying as a flight attendant at a vocational school. She has a stable relationship with her boyfriend Liu Long, who even paid for her to enroll in an English training class. With the unexpected pregnancy, Lin Sen&#39;s life also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/bbb1a402d88da00e34082b137825c904.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen&#39;s My parents run a small clinic. The father is disabled, the mother is addicted to micro-business, and a medical accident that caused a female patient to miscarry made the family worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;718&quot; height= &quot;367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d833696ed0f76cd31ec4acf654dba8c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sensible Lin In order to help his family pay off debts, Sen started working crazily to earn money. She worked as an opening welcome model and also went to shopping malls to sell milk powder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height= &quot;451&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e17fb61902a96dc28f20b9864de8a1e1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpected pregnancy and Family debt caused Lin Sen&#39;s originally peaceful life to plummet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen has no intention of becoming a mother, her boyfriend cannot be held responsible, and her creditor wants a child. With the help of her parents, she agreed to an incredible plan to give birth to a child to pay off the debt to the poor woman &quot;Yinfang&quot; who unfortunately had a miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pregnancy is a unique life experience for women. The difficulties unmarried young women face when they have an unexpected pregnancy, whether to have an abortion or not, are common themes in feminist films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Romanian film &quot;April, Three Weeks and Two Days&quot; and the French film &quot;As It Happens&quot; are both set in the last century when abortion was not accepted by most countries. Due to the complex social status quo, women Uterine autonomy is often not possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/4112b28ce818aff9c36aa10b4cb47ec6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American movie &quot; &quot;Juno&quot; and the Norwegian film &quot;Ninja Babies&quot; focus on the physical changes and mental stress that pregnancy and childbirth bring to women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/560cc0b6ed6d037a1c8f5a5754c790f6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255870&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In domestic movies , Li Yu&#39;s &quot;Beautiful Beauty&quot; also reproduces the various pressures faced by women after unexpected pregnancy, mainly due to the relatively conservative social public opinion environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference in &quot;Stone Gate&quot; lies in the alternative way of handling the heroine Lin Sen&#39;s pregnancy - not having an abortion but abandoning her for adoption. ‍‍‍‍‍‍Children are also used as a commodity to solve her immediate life problems. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, this is Lin Sen’s active choice, but the film also pays attention to the soft coercion she suffered. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like at the beginning of the film, her boyfriend took her to an English speaking training venue. Others were communicating freely, and the topic revolved around the country they wanted to go to. After Lin Sen found that she couldn’t fit in, she went to the Start playing with your phone on the sofa. She has no strong desire to improve her English. She came here because her boyfriend took the initiative to make the choice for her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;842&quot; height= &quot;375&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/d9438d13ec636201a492d203efd6438b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍This one , we can clearly feel the girl Lin Sen&#39;s numbness towards life and new life, the lack of vitality and confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high frequency of static shots in the film further exaggerates this sense of silent despair. ‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/1ef6b320b255e6460e3af6748f2b2bc5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255871&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen She rarely showed her emotions. Even when her boyfriend asked for an abortion, she didn&#39;t make a fuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the pain in her breasts during pregnancy and the tearing during childbirth, as well as Lin Sen’s unbearable expression and voice, tell us that her pain is indeed real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/dfe1e9a335889ec1e3d9fb2d86323882.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In pain and In confusion, she gradually lost control of her destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The plot of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is not complicated, but the film is 147 minutes long because the director placed many shots on the social landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many scenes, Lin Sen does not participate in the main narrative, appearing as a background board and becoming a silent observer. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, she would watch her boyfriend shoot a Douyin wedding promotional video, and watch underground industry managers openly interview young girls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/59e3f267b96f037451638fa307fa95c5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255873&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Sen’s mother Obsessed with selling three-no products and telling his story at the organization&#39;s annual meeting. ‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b4dd97b8e56ff0a3faba40627712dca9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255874&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outbreak Later, crowds of people gathered at medical equipment institutions to buy medical masks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b610ca468e29f05f07ee6fe14a850d6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is &quot; The biggest feature of &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is also the film&#39;s problem. On the one hand, the unrestrained display of shots greatly affects the rhythm of the narrative, and too many idle strokes make the movie long and boring. On the other hand, it also leads to the heroine becoming a tool, making the entire story biased towards curiosity and lacking the power to move people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although film and television works showing women in small towns have been relatively scarce in recent years, they were not uncommon in previous years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excellent works can maintain an excellent balance in grasping female narratives and social and cultural landscapes. Let’s not mention the classic representative works of the fourth and fifth generation directors, such as &quot;Qiu Ju&#39;s Lawsuit&quot;, &quot;The Love of Humans and Ghosts&quot;, &quot;The Beginning of Spring&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here is an example of an unpopular masterpiece - &quot;The Crying Woman&quot;. The director and screenwriter of this film, Liu Bingjian, used the story of Wang Guixiang, a Guizhou woman who made money through mourning, to show the public that China has a long history of funeral culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e041e619ee4d45eb63a62f887f45b33c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wang Guixiang Her strong vitality, her shrewd and kind feminine charm, and the warmth and warmth of people in rural society can all leave a deep impression on people. &quot;Stone Gate&quot;, which failed to do this, also formed a contradiction, with its novel subject matter but bland plot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth mentioning that &quot;Stone Gate&quot; is almost the same as a documentary in terms of realism. It is a story that grows out of the shooting environment and the actors&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors who play Lin Sen’s parents are director Huang Ji’s biological parents. They run this clinic in reality, and their home is also the real residence of the director and his wife. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/16048330511b15c4fd902365660c13e4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This movie Filmed over a ten-month period following the pregnancy cycle, and with a limited budget, it didn&#39;t have a set designed in advance like many films, and the actors were thrown directly into real space. ‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha is the main filming location. The lens captures its glamorous and prosperous side, as well as its chaotic and dark corners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/3e41d5118d476d174812674e0747a397.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255880&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;‍‍In addition to the director The camera strives to be close to reality, and also tries its best to show the living conditions of girls in non-developed areas. ‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍‍&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original setting of the heroine Lin Sen was an imaginary image of a proactive female college student. But this was completely different from the state of actor Yao Honggui at the time, and it was also different from the current situation of many young college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director and his wife rewrote the character design, and the protagonist’s story is a mixed experience of female college students obtained from interviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the unexpected pregnancy experience of a small town girl, the film reflects the structural dilemma of this group. It originates from many constraints such as patriarchy, commodity society, and power class. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/e3ba2cfb0a66e49d2831ae5de02d63df.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255879&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The heroine was The oppression does not occur openly, but it does not mean that multiple exploitation does not exist. This complex structural dilemma creates a low margin for error in women’s choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, it seems that Lin Sen can make different choices, take the initiative to have an abortion, not pay off the debt for his mother, or give birth to a child and raise him, but no life path will become easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are too many stone doors in her life that are difficult to push open, and she can only avoid falling by climbing hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/b3b1f6c550e80ffe730f5b4c5fc7f3b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255881&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ending of the film It is open-ended, and we have no way of knowing the final fate of the child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the audience can see is that the male employer hopes to postpone the adoption date due to the epidemic. The heroine Lin Sen, who is waiting for the handover, was triggered by the child&#39;s cry and got chest pain and got out of the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it hurts and there is no escape. Escape, the pain is still there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lack of hope in her life made her breathless. However, instead of floating helplessly in the ocean of life, it is better to fight hard and push open the stone door to try to welcome new life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“上海警察上门抓德牧”成事件：警犬军犬的谣言为何大行其道？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news about &quot;Shanghai police came to arrest German Shepherd&quot; triggered a &quot;storm in a teacup&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was first reported online that on October 24, the police from Wusong District, Shanghai came to the door and seized a 16-year-old German shepherd. The owner surrenders the dog. In the videos and texts circulating on the Internet, the dog has become a &quot;retired police dog&quot; or even a &quot;retired military dog.&quot; The words &quot;18 special police officers in three vehicles broke down the door and caught a 16-year-old dying old dog&quot;. Hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, the Shanghai Wusong Subdistrict Office issued a notice on this matter. The report stated that a resident of Haibin San Village was raising large and aggressive dogs (wolfdogs with hybrid blood) without a license, and had repeatedly walked dogs without leashes and large dogs without muzzles and other illegal dog-raising behaviors. After receiving reports from surrounding residents, police officers from the police station, staff from the Dog Breeding Office, comprehensive law enforcement officials and the district&#39;s special police detachment jointly came to rectify the situation. The dog owner took the initiative to open the door and cooperated with the work, and took the initiative to hand over the dog to the relevant departments for containment and disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After careful review of this incident, there are many contradictions and inconsistencies between the information transmitted online and the official report. Even after the report was released, many people expressed &quot;disbelief&quot; and need to be analyzed one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;bloodline&quot; of the dog involved. Someone on Weibo said it was a retired police dog, but the &quot;uniform&quot; in the video posted online only had &quot;POLICE&quot; in English and no Chinese &quot;police dog&quot;. This is obviously inconsistent with the &quot;standard dress&quot; of domestic police dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the first batch of retired police dogs in Shanghai were opened for adoption on September 5, 2022. The eight police dogs announced at that time were all from the police dog training base of the Songjiang Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau. Bradford, Malinois, Rottweiler, Springer Spaniel, German Shepherd, Doberman, etc., but only one Springer Spaniel and two Labradors are open to the public for adoption, and the remaining five including the German Shepherd are retired Police dogs can only be adopted by units. At the same time, adoptive citizens also need to receive follow-up visits every three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, there is indeed a German Shepherd among the retired police dogs open for adoption in Shanghai, but it was not given to citizens for adoption. Therefore, the rumors that the dogs involved were just &quot;retired police dogs&quot; and &quot;German shepherds&quot; are self-defeating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;retired military dog&quot; theory, there is a lack of any supporting information, and it directly conflicts with the &quot;POLICE uniform&quot; in the online video. China&#39;s &quot;Interim Regulations on the Work of Military Dogs&quot; defines military dogs as special combatants and an integral part of the military&#39;s combat effectiveness. After military dogs retire, they will generally enter military dog ​​breeding and training bases to &quot;live out their old age&quot;. Military dogs with meritorious service will also enjoy recuperation treatment. Even if adoption is open, adopters have very high requirements, including &quot;must love dogs&quot;, &quot;must have experience raising large dogs&quot;, and &quot;cannot be a living environment in an urban community&quot;. Some units will also require adopters to have Military personnel will vouch for them, and they must have a stable income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Zhengzhou 10 million reward for finding retired military dogs&quot; incident on July 9, 2023, the &quot;retired military dog&quot; gimmick instantly proved that this is a &quot;starting picture, the rest are all It’s fake news, because the description in the “reward notice” is completely contrary to the regulations for the adoption of retired military dogs. In this incident, the terms &quot;retired police dog&quot; and &quot;retired military dog&quot; are inconsistent and can be proven to be pure rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether the dog owner’s dog-raising behavior is legal and compliant, and the truth behind the door-to-door rectification actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 12, paragraph 3, of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; passed in 2011 and revised in 2016, prohibits individuals from raising aggressive dogs. Violators of this provision will have the aggressive dogs taken into custody by the public security department. The &quot;Shanghai Catalog of Prohibited Individual Breeding of Violent Dogs&quot; stipulates 24 types of ferocious dogs, including German Shepherds, French Wolfdogs, and Kunming Wolfdogs. Therefore, whether the owner of the dog involved adopts a German shepherd or a hybrid wolfdog, it is undoubtedly a violent dog breed that is prohibited from personal breeding, and dog registration, annual inspection and dog management fees are out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the official report, the owner of the dog involved also engaged in illegal dog-raising behaviors such as walking the dog without a leash and without wearing a muzzle. This is also consistent with the &quot;20 reports from surrounding residents&quot; in the online information. The statement is consistent. Articles 21 and 30 of the &quot;Shanghai Dog Breeding Management Regulations&quot; also clearly stipulate that dog owners shall abide by public order and shall not interfere with the normal lives of others. Residents&#39; committees also have the right to formulate and supervise dog breeding conventions or regulations in their residential areas. Management, dog owners should comply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that the illegal dog-raising behavior of the dog owner involved has been confirmed, surrounding residents naturally have the right to report and request the public security department to take in the dog. This request is reasonable and reasonable, and the joint door-to-door rectification by various local departments is also in line with current laws and regulations. Judging from the live videos and pictures, &quot;18 special police officers&quot; is also false information, and relevant social media bloggers have deliberately exaggerated it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this incident also shows that relevant public issues have lost focus, which may not be a blessing to the public interest. Faced with the public issue of &quot;how to regulate dog ownership,&quot; some people are willing to mobilize by creating fake news and create traffic and attention with &quot;tragic narratives.&quot; Similar behavior is no longer a public discussion, but an out-and-out &quot;information war&quot; and &quot;public opinion war&quot; method, trying to blur the focus and muddy the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, laws and regulations regulating dog breeding have been implemented in various places for many years, in order to better protect people&#39;s rights. Dogs are not civil subjects and are the private property of their owners. &quot;Conflict between humans and dogs&quot; is a false issue that does not exist. The real issue is how to regulate dog breeding: only when the premise of protecting human rights is established can we talk about protecting people&#39;s property rights to dogs. Protecting people from being hurt by dogs and preventing &quot;dog bites&quot; should still be a real issue that public opinion pays attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报深圳欢乐谷过山车碰撞事故救治情况：目前17人留院诊治]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259549]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 21:08:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;821&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/icPBcDeRPzTXeytRVvcAgxDLzedBlJx77ZIA0HT2. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社会总要“毒打”每一个准社会人丨 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259535]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/29/o2oKFU2EiDUXRbLqoSU8L1WMxan6W8ITAbEXeCc5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;880&quot; height=&quot;658&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/o2oKFU2EiDUXRbLqoSU8L1WMxan6W8ITAbEX eCc5. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, Guangzhou, the theme of the South China University of Technology was &quot;Shenzhen It is a double-selection meeting of the &quot;State-owned Enterprises 2024 Campus Recruitment&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ke Yule/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Details of relevant reports See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/258798?source=131&quot;>;&quot;Who is in the cold?&quot; Who&#39;s popular? The first job fair for the Class of 2024&quot;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a journalism student, when interviewing job fairs, I pay special attention to the situation of media units. However, after the four double-election meetings, I only saw one news website from Foshan, which was on September 28, 2023, at Guangdong University of Foreign Studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The HR of this news website used the pseudonym Huang Li in the manuscript. After a brief introduction, I was allowed to sit aside and ask questions or observe on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a form on the table to record the basic information of job-seeking students. Nearly three hours have passed since the double selection meeting, and about twenty names have been filled in. The next column is &quot;Education,&quot; almost all of which are master&#39;s degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I heard that Guangzhou Foreign Studies University (graduated this year) has 150 master&#39;s degrees in new communication.&quot; When she said this, Huang Li had a subtle smile on her face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven minutes ago, she just rejected a girl&#39;s resume on the grounds that &quot;the resume was not suitable.&quot; A girl wants to apply for the social media platform operation of a news network, but she only has user operation experience in an ordinary company. It’s hard to tell what the essential difference between the two “operations” is, but it doesn’t prevent Huang Li from thinking that they don’t match each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I speculate that what she meant was that there were many students applying for jobs and she could choose as much as she wanted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In media reports, the number of graduates has been rising year after year - 9.09 million in 2021, 10.76 million in 2022, and 11.58 million in 2023 - making each year replace the previous year and become a new &quot; The most difficult employment season.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following interview with Xu Yang, the organizer of the double election conference, confirmed this point. He told me that in recent years, the supply and demand for jobs at the double election have become increasingly asymmetric. On the one hand, students&#39; enthusiasm for employment is actually increasing and the number of participants is increasing; on the other hand, the number of participating companies and the number of jobs released is decreasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiamin, a master’s degree student in materials science from Sun Yat-sen University who has been mentioned in many reports, was someone I met at South China University of Technology. At that time, she was sitting outside the venue and resting against the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Across the wall, countless red posters hang low, and there are one or two nervous-looking HRs in front of each booth. The aisles were narrow and cluttered, leaflets scattered everywhere, and it was dark and stuffy, like a trench. Li Jiamin smiled bitterly: &quot;Looking for a job requires physical and psychological torture.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Employment is indeed like a battle, and everyone is prepared. But after each battle, it seems that everyone has lost their armor and lost their armor, with no victory or defeat in sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the bathroom of the same double election meeting, I also saw a young HR with a childish look on his face. She was still breastfeeding and asked me in a low voice to help close the outer door of the toilet. I was secretly surprised by how hard he worked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the manuscript was released, Li Jiamin’s demands for salary were considered by some readers as “having not withstood the severe beatings of society”. Like a motto of the times, society always wants to “beat” every (quasi) social person. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn’t it normal for job seekers to want higher wages and better jobs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, companies also have their own grievances. When Huang Li commented on today&#39;s young job seekers, her dissatisfaction could not be concealed in her words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For those of us who were born in the 1980s and early 1990s, our family conditions were not that good when we were young, so we all consciously cherished our jobs. But today’s young people have good family conditions, have no worries about food and drink, and have many choices of work. A lot. For them, the boss doesn’t fight against the west, right? As long as there is something that doesn’t fit the idea, just leave.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to improve the so-called recruitment retention rate, the job seeker’s hometown It became a question she repeatedly asked. From whether she is from Foshan, to whether she has relatives and friends living in Foshan, to her identification with the city of Foshan, she did not let go of any clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Feng, who was at the same double selection meeting as Huang Li, is the head of the Guangzhou branch of a public examination training institution. On this day, his booth was almost always surrounded by people. This is very unusual for a small and micro enterprise with less than 50 employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is difficult to tell whether the crowd who gathered around him was attracted by the several &quot;Guangdong Written Examination Questions for Selected Students&quot; on the table or by the institution itself. Wu Feng seemed not to think about this problem. Before the interview, he gave me a set of real questions with the same enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 5 pm, the interview came to an end and I was ready to leave. But he stopped me and asked about the end time of my internship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There&#39;s still one month left.&quot; I said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Then after your internship is over, you can sign up for an internship with us.&quot; Wu Feng said that they are short of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弃养致死，那些变相杀害孩子的父母]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/QxImREUiIkRx7hQBSB6y1vFdwO3z0acGg8wkGHnx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/QxImREUiIkRx7hQBSB6y1vFdwO 3z0acGg8wkGHnx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 5, 2022, children watched carp streamers in Koshigaya City, Saitama Prefecture, Japan . Today is Children’s Day in Japan. On this day, people hang carp streamers to pray for their children &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do parents do this? Becoming the murderer who personally caused the death of a child? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than 20 years, Japanese writer and journalist Haru Sugiyama has continued to investigate cases of parental abandonment in Japan. In many cases of abandonment that shocked society, young children eventually starved to death because they had no ability to take care of themselves. Or die of illness. These cases are driving the revision of Japan&#39;s Child Protection Act, but the situation of deaths due to abandonment remains serious. &quot;Most of the parents who have lost their children seem to be young people, prejudiced people or people with disabilities.&quot; In October 2023, 65-year-old Haru Sugiyama told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; in an email interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After children are born, does the world provide them with a safe and protected growth environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022 alone, 77 children died of abuse in Japan. Data from the Japan Children and Family Agency show that the number of child abuse consultations in Japan in 2022 has set a new record for 32 consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 23, 2023, a case involving the death of an abandoned baby was opened in Japan. 33-year-old Narumi Taniguchi, who works in a custom shop, gave birth to a baby girl alone on a street in Osaka City on January 30. She put the baby in a bag and abandoned it in a coin-operated locker. The baby eventually died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the South Korean police discovered the remains of two infants in a refrigerator in an apartment in Suwon City. This incident attracted great attention in South Korea. South Korea&#39;s Ministry of Health and Welfare stated that as of July 18, there were more than 2,123 unregistered &quot;ghost babies&quot; in South Korea, and 249 of them were confirmed dead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What initially led Haru Sugiyama to investigate the phenomenon of &quot;child abandonment&quot; was a death case of a girl that shocked Japanese society. On December 10, 2000, a girl died in Aichi Prefecture, Japan. A pair of young parents put their 3-year-old daughter Mana Murata in a cardboard box at home for nearly 20 days. During this period, Mana barely ate, she eventually starved to death. At that time, Masami Murata, a mother, was pregnant and raising a 1-and-a-half-year-old son with her husband Tomonori Murata. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugiyama Haru graduated from the First Faculty of Literature of Waseda University. He worked as a magazine editor and later became a freelancer. He writes reportage about parenting and parent-child issues, parents killing their own children, etc. His works include focusing on women. The poverty-stricken &quot;Documentary·Abuse - The Case of Two Children Abandoned to Death in Osaka&quot;, &quot;Thoughts from Child Abuse: How Society Pressures Families&quot; which explores the seriousness of family relationships in Japanese society, and &quot;Parenting Abandonment - Trapped Mothers&quot; The Chinese version of &quot;With the Neglected Daughter&quot; will be published in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SLJxrzToY7rJMxC11QGsHQ2fvLN081Dr1nnwGzrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SLJxrzToY7rJMxC11QGsHQ2fvLN081Dr1nnwGzrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255435&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugiyama Haru met the Muratas while they were serving their sentences and continued to correspond with them. Sugiyama Haru&#39;s child is one and a half years older than Mana. During the investigation, Sugiyama Haru &quot;the closer he came into contact with the case, the more unable he was to escape from his mother&#39;s perspective.&quot; After three and a half years of interviews and research on this case, Haru Sugiyama finally recorded this tragedy caused by the parenting environment in modern society in a way that is close to line drawing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother who abandoned her daughter was also a daughter who was abandoned since she was a child. In Japanese society with structural gender inequality, women&#39;s own needs are always ignored. When her daughter Mana&#39;s health condition worsened, Masami turned to her husband Tomonori for help. After being treated indifferently, the frustrated Masami no longer cared about her daughter&#39;s condition, but turned to her own mother Hideko, and flattered her husband who had already remarried. The mother expressed her love passionately and tried hard to imitate a &quot;well-behaved daughter in her mother&#39;s eyes.&quot; The 24-year-old Yamei was afraid of her haggard child and did not dare to touch her daughter, waiting for her child to die in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a society where mothers assume the main childcare responsibilities by default, lack of social awareness of childcare, and economic inequality, the tragedy of young children dying due to abuse and abandonment is not an isolated case. The circumstances and details in the &quot;Mana&quot; case have appeared repeatedly in subsequent &quot;childcare abandonment&quot; cases. The parents of these children often suffered violence or abandonment when they were young. They grew up in isolation. As adults, they still face tremendous pressure to survive and lack the ability to live stably in society. Haru Sugiyama said: &quot;Twenty years of continuous interviews have given me the feeling that cases of death by abuse are also affected by the contraction of social functions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BBiMfnmVj1JPaa4U1MSOG6MhKdmSSDILBNSDxy9o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/BBiMfnmVj1JPaa4U1MSOG6MhKdmSSDILBNSDxy9o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255439&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is an interview between &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; and Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unable to Why don’t parents raising children seek help? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the 1990s to the present, Japan’s &quot;childcare abandonment&quot; &quot;How has the phenomenon changed?&quot; What kind of fluctuations have the incidence rate shown, and what are the social and temporal reasons behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, about 70 cases of killing children occur in Japanese society every year. Of course, in the period of social chaos after the war, children suffered even more. In the second half of the 1970s, there were approximately 200 cases of child abuse-related death each year. In the first half of the 1970s, in Japan, which was experiencing rapid economic growth, cases of babies being thrown into lockers at train stations often occurred. That was an era when a large number of young people moved from rural areas to cities. Such cases occurred frequently, probably because the society at that time did not provide cultural and institutional support for families. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have been paying attention to &quot;nurturing&quot; since the 1990s Children” topic, especially the phenomenon of “parenting abandonment” or improper parenting in Japan. What is the general appearance of the families you met during your research, such as their economic status? Are they all from the bottom of society? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Haru Sugiyama:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I interviewed six families that were torn apart by child abuse. Some of the children in these families were abused to death, and some were on the verge of death. . Some of the interviews involved me meeting directly with family members, while others I simply attended court proceedings. Objectively speaking, the families I interviewed were all facing financial difficulties. Even if they do not fall into the low-income group defined by society, these families are still in considerable financial difficulty. In addition, parents who lose their children seem to be more likely to be young, prejudiced, or disabled. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Childcare requires an investment of resources. British urban anthropologist Sandra Wallman believes that there are six types of necessary resources for family life: structural resources; land (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Residential&lt;/span>;); labor (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Services&lt;/span >;); Capital (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Money&lt;/span>;); Organizational resources (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Resources that put structural resources into actual use&lt;/span>;); time, information, self-identity (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sense of belonging, self-esteem&lt;/span span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary for people to realize that they are eligible and have access to these resources, otherwise it will be difficult to use rescue services. People who are living in difficulty should not kill their children, but should actively seek help and find ways to get out of their predicaments. It is important to prepare social resources, but I think it is more important to solve the problem of society clearly providing resources, but people are unable to take the initiative to ask for help. We must let everyone realize that if there are difficulties, we must use social resources and society to make adequate preparations for everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In these families, the mother is often the one who receives the most attention. What state are they usually in? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the cases I participated in, every mother suffered from mental trauma and serious psychological problems. Mothers who are physically and mentally healthy can use a variety of resources to get over the hump. The formation of psychological problems is related to the mother&#39;s lack of care in childhood and repeated violence during childhood and marriage. The experience of sexual violence can be particularly deeply traumatic. The mothers in many cases appeared to have experienced sexual violence in a situation where their self-esteem was not protected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in these cases, the aiding party failed to fully play its role. Clients often lack relevant knowledge and do not know that they can receive help. In 2010, a case occurred in Nishi-ku, Osaka City. The mother of the child is a full-time housewife. Although she received full social assistance when raising children, she did not even receive child support allowance after the divorce, and she never thought of seeking any social assistance. This really surprised me. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reporter&#39;s note: In 2010, a mother in Nishi-ku, Osaka, Japan abandoned her 1-year-old boy and 3-year-old girl for 50 consecutive days. Causing them to starve to death. The mother left home, leaving her two children at home, and never came back.&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the differences among mothers with different education levels and social classes regarding seeking help? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have not investigated how differences in education and class affect families. But even mothers with outstanding knowledge and high education may not be able to seek appropriate assistance if their self-esteem is taken away and they no longer believe in their own worth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are also people who overcome difficulties with the help of wisdom. When difficulty intensifies, knowledge is even more needed to overcome it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A survey shows that about half of single mothers have difficulties in living. Even if women are eager to work, they often can only enter the workplace by doing part-time jobs and cannot become regular employees, which means that they cannot receive normal income. Sometimes, the mother&#39;s income alone is not enough to support her children. This is a problem that needs to be addressed as a society, not just mothers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many specific cases, I found that men’s fear of leaving the social class in which they grew up seems to have gradually become the reason why they are violent towards family members and violent towards their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese society is currently experiencing an economic downturn and social functions are gradually shrinking, which adds to the worries of being a parent. Continuous interviews over the past 20 years have given me the impression that cases of child abuse deaths have also been affected by the retrenchment of social functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Z4NhPACsTexDnNlEpygQrFeZAvgbSuBzce4y7338.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Z4NhPACsTexDnNlEpygQrFeZAvgbSuBzce4y7338.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 23, 2023, in Kobe City, Hyogo Prefecture, Japan, a 6-year-old boy was tortured to death and his body was dumped. People presented flowers and snacks in front of his residence&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Absent husband, absent society&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your extensive research, is the family structure of &quot;men taking charge of the outside world and women taking charge of the house&quot; common? Has the proportion of husbands’ participation in family childcare changed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Haru Sugiyama:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At present, Japan’s economic development is in a period of stagnation. I think society’s requirements for women are no longer limited to protecting the family. Probably only those who marry men with very strong financial ability are allowed to &quot;maintain the household&quot; - there are also a few families where the husband does not allow the wife to work outside the home even though the family is very poor. However, patriarchal values ​​are still very strong, and everyone still believes that family values ​​are in the hands of men, and women only provide assistance. This view also binds many people unconsciously. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the past, the proportion of fathers participating in child care in Japanese society should have increased. Twenty or thirty years ago, very few fathers went to kindergarten to pick up and drop off their children, but the situation now has improved a lot compared to that time, and everyone has begun to think that it is normal for fathers to pick up and drop off their children. More companies allow employees to take parental leave, and men&#39;s participation in childcare is much more common than before. The maternity leave system for men in large companies has gradually improved, and the success rate of men applying for maternity leave has also become higher. This means that a reform of society&#39;s consciousness is underway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a &quot;separated generation parenting&quot; in Japan similar to China (by Grandparents raising children) phenomenon? Is there a problem of &quot;left-behind children&quot; in Japan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Skip-generation parenting&quot; has also happened in the past, but in today&#39;s Japanese society, grandparents and maternal grandparents often lose their jobs due to insufficient pensions. If you can&#39;t make a living, you still have to work in society. The situation may be different in each region, but the number of families that the previous generation could comfortably help with childcare was probably limited. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About the issue of &quot;left-behind children&quot;. In today&#39;s Japanese society, the number of young people going to work in big cities from small areas has decreased compared with before. The phenomenon of migrant workers used to be very popular, but now things have changed. In addition, most young people with financial difficulties seem to choose not to get married or have children. The declining birthrate is a major problem that Japanese society needs to face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Separate-generation parenting&quot; and &quot;left-behind children&quot; phenomena are also reflected It explains some Chinese people&#39;s understanding of childcare - childcare is a &quot;public matter&quot; for a family or even a family. This is different from the cultural understanding of childcare in Japan and South Korea. How do you understand this difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It turns out that in China, childcare is a &quot;public matter&quot; of the family. This is very interesting. It turns out that parenting has a public nature, which moved me very much. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, the nature of childcare is private. It gives me the impression that childcare is basically centered on the small family. In other words, the small family is not actually &quot;private&quot; but A minimalist “public” with responsibility. The restricted &quot;family&quot; is burdened with everything. The parent-child relationship is very close, and some children are controlled by their mothers. The problem of underage caregivers in Japan also needs to be solved urgently. In some families, parents lack basic abilities or have behavioral disorders or mental illnesses, and they have to be cared for by their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether it emphasizes the rescue of abused children or the treatment of abuse There is a lag in judicial punishment of behavior, and the damage has already been done. Is the socialization of childcare responsibilities important? What is Japan’s current progress in this regard? What support should be provided but is not? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You are right. The family system in modern society has become increasingly difficult to maintain with the development of economy and capitalist society. In the past, people relied on their family&#39;s industries to make a living, but in today&#39;s society, people have to spend money to buy labor, and the intergenerational nature of the family is no longer available. Although the era of having children for the family still has a certain influence on the present, the concept and form of family have changed. If society is not aware of this problem, people raising children may be in pain forever. In my opinion, Japan currently lacks awareness of socialized parenting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/1BOnhzrjk82P9hZmXn1pzMruYmoidjR9Xi1UPhsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 956&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/1BOnhzrjk82P9hZmXn1pzMruYmoidjR9Xi1UPhsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Nobody Knows&quot; directed by Hirokazu Kore-eda. The film is based on the 1988 Nishisugamo infant abandonment incident in Japan: a mother abandoned her four children to live with her new boyfriend &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(&quot;Nobody Knows&quot;/Photo)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Are young people gradually becoming a vulnerable group? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In June 2023, the &quot;Suwon Freezer Dead Baby Case&quot; occurred in South Korea &quot;, what do you think of the childbirth environment in South Korea? South Korea&#39;s &quot;prohibition on abortion&quot; will only officially expire in 2021, and the price of contraceptive pills is high and the related contraceptive procedures are still cumbersome. What is the birth environment like in Japan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the reason why children are killed by their parents is because women cannot choose whether to have children or not in the current society. Society should make changes so that women can take charge of their own lives. In addition, the power of society is also very important, and it has the responsibility to carefully care for and nurture every life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s contraceptive pills, especially emergency contraceptive pills, also require a doctor’s diagnosis before they can be prescribed. They are also expensive and not readily available to women. The current situation is that the pregnant woman herself cannot decide whether to give birth to the baby. Society lacks awareness of raising children together, and individual women cannot make the decision for themselves when it comes to having children. This interview made me realize that Japanese women have to bear the burden of childcare, but there is a lack of social assistance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;South Korea will become the country with the lowest fertility rate in the world in 2022. What is the current mentality of people behind the low fertility rate? What kind of social reality does it reflect? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Haru Sugiyama:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Inequality in Japanese society is expanding rapidly. People with financial means get married, have children, and raise their children like people in the past. People who lack financial resources will have to work hard to raise children and find it difficult to feel happy. Because society does not provide them with support. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In order to alleviate the low fertility rate, the Korean government After intensively introducing a series of fertility &quot;patches&quot;, such as raising subsidy standards and adding more nurseries, how does the Japanese government deal with the problem of low fertility? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is very important to improve the subsidy standards. Society should at least not let any child go hungry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the number of nurseries in Japan increased, the number of children who met the requirements but were unable to enter kindergartens decreased rapidly. This is achieved at the expense of lowering standards of care for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has also adjusted its education system so that children can receive free education. Children from poor families also receive free scholarships to further their studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, the school&#39;s facilities are still imperfect. Or some old facilities could be easily updated before, but now they have not been able to do so. The actual budget spent on children is pitifully small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government has already invested money in institutions such as children&#39;s canteens. Although these institutions are of varying quality, they have all received government funds. However, the state cannot guarantee the quality of children&#39;s canteens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we want children to grow up truly happy, we should start from the country, pay attention to the growth of each child, and strive to improve the parenting environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;How can I have a child if I am not living well?&quot; ——Deteriorating economic conditions, increasing education costs, etc. are problems that many young people have to face when considering having children. What is the mentality of young people in Japan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sugiyama Haru:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Among Japanese young people, those who can think objectively to a certain extent also tend to think that &quot;I can&#39;t live well. Why have children?&quot; However, there are also some young people who lack love from their parents or society and try to make up for it through sexual relationships. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of young people who do not want children continues to increase, reflecting the fact that young people are gradually becoming a vulnerable group in society. Young people are not treated properly and do not think that they should be the main force participating in social construction. It is worth thinking about how aware the elderly are of this current situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[14只猫咪非正常死亡背后，警惕“踢猫效应”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259539]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/29/b8f04c2e41.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 29/b8f04c2e41.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, 2023, the Bonsai Garden of Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area, Two kittens strolling in the sunshine. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang |&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For several days, Dahuang, Xiaohei and Xiaohuang did not show up, and the cat food placed in the corner remained untouched. This made the tea house in Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area untouched. The waiter Han Xue clenched her heart. She was worried that the three kittens would also die from poison given by &quot;bad guys&quot; as reported on the Internet. This guess was immediately corrected by the colleague next to him, &quot;None of us saw it with our own eyes, so we can&#39;t talk nonsense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 20, 2023, Weibo netizens broke the news that a large number of stray cats died of poisoning in the Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area in Suzhou, and attached photos of the cat corpses. This information has been fermented on multiple platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, adding a new dimension to the controversy over stray animal management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 22, Liu Fang, a staff member of the Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area Management Office, confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that 14 cats were found dead in the park between October 10 and 16. However, after checking the surveillance, no evidence was found that the cat died of poisoning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, a Rottweiler dog bit a girl in Chongzhou, Sichuan. Some netizens linked the deaths of stray cats in Huqiu to dog bites of girls. However, Southern Weekend reporters found that most of the deaths of stray cats in Huqiu occurred before dogs bit girls, which means it is more likely to be an isolated incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the number of topics about killing stray animals on social networks has increased sharply recently. Qian Yefang, a professor at the School of Law at Zhongnan University of Economics and Law, also noticed the &quot;dog-hating and cat-hating&quot; sentiment on social media. In her opinion, behind it is both the incitement of practitioners in the dog meat industry chain and a manifestation of the &quot;cat-kicking effect.&quot; : &quot;If you don&#39;t dare to express negative emotions to the strong, you vent them to the weak. They are passed down layer by layer, and finally passed to animals that cannot speak.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perennially calling for the introduction of the Companion Animal Protection and Management Act &quot;In addition, Qian Yefang conducted an experiment that lasted for more than three years in Haitian Community, Qiantang District, Hangzhou. Regarding the management of stray animals, the solution she gave is not novel, but there is still a long way to go: improving legislation, advocating civilized dog breeding, eliminating street culling, rational disposal, and more cooperation with private forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The scenic area has alerted the police&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area is located in the west of Suzhou. The main body is a hill with an altitude of 34.3 meters. There are two entrances and exits at the foot of the mountain in the north and south. Ji Jie, who works in the bonsai garden in the scenic area, told Southern Weekend reporters that the density of tourists at the north and south entrances and the bonsai garden is small and the terrain is flat, so they have become the main stronghold for stray cats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the feeding of Ji Jie and his colleagues, there are already more than a dozen cats living in the bonsai area. The scenic area management office also discovered the traffic potential of cats. In a short video released by the official Douyin account of Huqiu Mountain Scenic Area in April 2020, an orange cat named &quot;tiger&quot; appeared, whose name means the &quot;tiger&quot; of Huqiu. This video received 482 likes, which is more than ten times the number of likes for the flower and scenery video released in the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This sudden death made many employees feel sad. Ji Jie recalled that a colleague who had participated in the &quot;Small Animal Protection Association&quot; found that a cat that had been raised since childhood was convulsing and foaming, and he tried to rescue it by pouring water. But the kitten failed to save him in the end and bit him while struggling. In addition to the one that died in front of his colleagues, Ji Jie estimated that there were two or three cats missing from the bonsai area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Tiger Hill Scenic Area, most employees are on duty during the day, but cats often come out to be active in the evening when there are few tourists. Some cats die after nightfall, and their bodies are collected by cleaners in the early morning. Most people have not seen the corpses with their own eyes, but intuitively feel that the number of cats has decreased, and then they hear about &quot;poisoning&quot; on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Mei who runs a stall near the south gate of the scenic spot also feels that the number of kittens has decreased. In the past, when I went to work every morning, the sound of Aunt Mei&#39;s trolley on the road would attract five or six cats begging for food. Shortly after the National Day holiday, the number of kittens in this batch was reduced to two or three. After that, she asked the cleaners every day if they had picked up the kitten corpses. After receiving consecutive affirmative answers, she was very sad and angry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Fang said that the places where cats died were mainly concentrated in the South Gate, Xixi Huancui (West Garden), and Wanjing Villa (i.e. Bonsai Garden). From the map, these three areas are adjacent to each other and concentrated on the south side of the scenic spot. Ji Jie and other employees in the bonsai area mentioned that a few days before the cat&#39;s death, tourists complained about being scratched by cats in the bonsai area. Could there be a connection between the two? Apart from deliberate revenge, Ji Jie couldn&#39;t think of any reason to explain all this. Of course, he had no proof. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Fang said that the scenic spot has called the police and the police station has intervened in the case. The park also called in surveillance cameras and checked the ground, but no poison was found. &quot;If another cat is found dead later, we will ask the public security department to conduct a physical inspection immediately to determine whether this is a man-made incident.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, the scenic spot further strengthened the strength of on-site security inspection personnel, and promptly Clean up food residues scattered on the ground and discourage visitors from feeding small animals at will. On October 26, Liu Fang said that the scenic spot has organized a cat care volunteer service team to install smart cat boxes at points where cats come and go frequently, with dedicated management, remote monitoring, and fixed-point feeding to create a safe living environment for cats. At the same time, animal protection advocacy videos are played in scenic spots and cat care signs are produced. &quot;In the future, we will continue to pay attention to the living conditions of cats in the scenic area and provide them with necessary help and protection as much as possible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rumors verified, whether true or false&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the dog bite girl incident , public opinion about hurting dogs and cats continues to ferment. Southern Weekend reporters verified some of the revelations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Hangzhou blogger broke the news that on October 18, his Schnauzer and Shiba Inu were stolen and killed by the landlord’s father. Among them, the Shiba Inu was skinned and chopped into pieces. Dog meat”. Three days later, the person involved deleted the relevant notes about the incident originally published in Xiaohongshu and canceled his account. The person involved declined the Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s interview invitation, saying that the matter was over and he did not want to be disturbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person close to the blogger revealed that the two parties in the incident have been mediated by the Public Security Bureau, and the other party has publicly apologized and compensated for the losses. The parties involved will donate the compensation to charity projects for stray cats and dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The authenticity of another revelation is controversial. On October 20, a Weibo user broke the news that the property management of Phoenix Garden Community in Wuhan beat to death &quot;three 4-month-old puppies and a pregnant cat mother&quot; on the evening of October 19, with the caption &quot;The murderer&quot; &quot;Photos of security guards and several dead cats and dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 25, a staff member of the Phoenix Garden Community Property told a Southern reporter that the dog beating incident was a rumor. The real situation is that many community owners complained that stray cats and dogs were barking and disturbing the residents, so the property management organized security to drive away the stray animals instead of culling them. The property management company called 110 on the morning of October 20 to report the incident to the police at the Canglong Island Police Station in Jiangxia District and reiterated that no stray animals were killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being &quot;exposed&quot;, the community property management received a large number of calls in a short period of time. Some of them &quot;cursed and said we are not human beings&quot;, which affected the normal development of property management work. Southern Weekend reporters called some of these numbers, and most of them said they saw the breaking information on Xiaohongshu and WeChat groups rather than on Weibo. At present, Xiaohongshu cannot find relevant information, and the post may have been deleted by the person who broke the news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some Weibo bloggers used image recognition software to identify the news that many reports of stray dogs being hunted and killed online were in fact “old news” or were copied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some news of harm to stray animals has been confirmed. On October 21, Sichuan Science and Technology Vocational College reported the killing of stray dogs in the student dormitory: two students were given detention for probation, and the police were transferred to the public security organs for processing; Sohu Clairvoyance reported that a resident in Zhenjiang, Jiangsu Province discovered that the lawn was being eaten while walking his dog in the community. A large amount of &quot;poison ham&quot; suspected to be stuffed with pills was released, and stray cats in the community died after accidentally eating it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beware of the &quot;kicking cat effect&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Qian Yefang believes that in the complicated news about the death of stray animals, in addition to distinguishing the authenticity from the false, it is also necessary to define the nature of the behavior: Government The capture, containment and subsequent harmless disposal organized by the competent authorities are incomparable with the &quot;lynching&quot; and execution of stray animals by individuals or even the cruel killing of stray animals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Yefang began to pay attention to the problem of stray animals in 2018. In her observation, whenever there is a dog biting incident, there will be a wave of support for culling stray animals on the Internet. In addition to the differences in the opinions of various parties, Qian Yefang believes that there are still some practitioners in the cat and dog meat or animal cruelty industry chain in the public opinion field who are muddying the waters and setting the pace, allowing voices that encourage extremes to gain the upper hand from time to time. This is actually the strong bullying the weak - the manifestation of the &quot;kicking the cat effect&quot; in social emotions. For example, if a person is criticized by his boss at work, he vents his depressed emotions on his wife when he gets home, and the wife vents on his children. The child had nowhere to vent his anger. When he saw a cat when he went out, he went up and kicked it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/9c19b8a38a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/29/9c19b8a38a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 18, 2022, in Zhengzhou, Henan, the 32nd &quot;Zhengzhou Adoption Day&quot; offline charity event was held. Volunteers found new homes for stray cats and dogs. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike food animals, cats and dogs, as companion animals, have received special legal protection from slaughter in some countries and regions. The two seemingly incompatible groups on the issue of stray animals also have a consensus. For example, Qian Yefang has been calling for the introduction of the &quot;Companion Animal Protection and Management Law&quot;, in which the focus of management is civilized dog breeding, which can not only reduce conflicts between humans and dogs, but also reduce the occurrence of stray animals from the source, which is beneficial to animal welfare. If you compare stray dogs with stray cats, the specific disposal procedures are different. Compared with stray dogs, the risk of stray cats injuring people is relatively low. &quot;So the act of killing stray cats has no legal system support, nor moral or traditional support. It is a naked atrocity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, stray cats have strong reproductive capabilities and may pose a threat to small wild animals such as birds. The Trap Neuter Release (TNR) model is currently being promoted. In Qian Yefang’s TNR practice, she also found a low-cost way to sterilize stray cats: working with nearby pet hospitals Cooperate to promote the hospital among pet parents in the community. In return, the hospital can perform two sterilization surgeries for free every month. For more than two sterilization surgeries, the hospital charges 100 yuan for female cats and 50 yuan for male cats, which is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;（文中除钱叶芳外，其他皆为化名。南方周末记者黄思琪对本文亦有贡献。）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[斡旋巴以人质危机，卡塔尔凭什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259537]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 17:03:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has lasted for three weeks, and both sides have continued air strikes. News about the release of hostages came one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 23, 2023, local time, at the Rafah Port, two elderly Israeli hostages detained by Hamas were handed over to the Israel Defense Forces. They had been held in Gaza for 17 days before being released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second batch of hostages released by Hamas. On October 20, also on the Gaza border, Hamas released a mother and daughter from the United States, Judith Lanan and Natalie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hostage issue puts Netanyahu in a dilemma. Israel wants to completely eliminate Hamas and establish a new order in Gaza, while Hamas The hostages were used as bargaining chips in an attempt to interfere with Israel&#39;s ground offensive plan.&quot; According to Zou Zhiqiang, a researcher at the Middle East Studies Center of Fudan University, the two sides are still in an ongoing game and compromise is extremely difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth mentioning that Qatar mediated the release of two consecutive batches of hostages. U.S. President Joe Biden publicly expressed his gratitude to Qatar after two American hostages were rescued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 25, Qatar Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Mohammed once again responded to the progress of hostage negotiations. He said that negotiations are still actively underway and both sides have made some progress and breakthroughs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the ever-changing Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the small Gulf country of Qatar is walking in the flames of war and mediating on the hostage issue. People can&#39;t help but wonder: Why is it a &quot;small country&quot; like Qatar? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The released hostages are targeted&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the deep night, accompanied by Hamas soldiers, two female hostages were Handed over to staff wearing ICRC uniforms. Two Hamas soldiers covered their faces with black veils and held steel guns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before leaving, one of the hostages turned around and shook hands with the Hamas gunman in farewell, saying &quot;Shalom.&quot; In Hebrew, &quot;Shalom&quot; means &quot;peace.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of October 23, 2023, Hamas shared a video of the release of hostages. The two hostages released in the video are 79-year-old Nurit Cooper and 85-year-old Yochiri Lifshitz. They live in Kibbutz Nir Oz, Israel, close to the Gaza border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 7, Hamas launched the &quot;Aqsa Flood&quot; operation. 1,200 Hamas armed gunmen crossed the border and launched attacks in southern Israel. And took away a large number of hostages. Cooper and Lifshitz were also among the hostages kidnapped, along with their husbands, who are still being held in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Israeli military said that there are 222 hostages held by Hamas in the Gaza Strip, &quot;most of whom are still alive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In fact, through the raid on Israel, Hamas&#39;s main military goal has been achieved. The kidnapping of hostages is mainly to make Israel have concerns and facilitate future bargaining. &quot;Zou Zhiqiang analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Lifshitz&#39;s account, after being kidnapped, she was taken into a vast network of tunnels under Gaza that &quot;looked like a spider web.&quot; They ate the same food as the Hamas guards - pita bread, cheese and cucumbers. To ensure the hostages are healthy, a doctor will check on them every two or three days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When asked why she shook hands with the gunman, Lifshitz said the hijackers were nice to her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Hamas, the hostages were released for &quot;humanitarian reasons.&quot; However, in the opinion of the interviewed experts, Hamas&#39;s release of the hostages has the dual purpose of exerting pressure and showing a compromise posture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Under the dual pressure of Israel&#39;s continued air strikes and the pressure of its soldiers, Hamas is looking for opportunities to threaten the release of hostages in exchange for Israeli military concessions. &quot;Zou Zhiqiang pointed out, &quot;So far, the hostages released are all non-combatants and women.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the first hostage released by Hamas The hostages are dual American-Israeli citizens and are from Chicago. The two were visiting relatives in Israel when they were captured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The hostages Hamas chose to release are targeted.&quot; Yu Guoqing, a researcher at the Institute of West Asian and African Studies at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Hamas sent We hope that the United States will put as much pressure on Israel as possible to allow it to retain a certain amount of leeway in ground military operations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 18, Biden visited Israel. Brigade, in addition to expressing his staunch support for Israel, Biden also discussed the hostage issue with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Biden emphasized that ensuring the safe return of American hostages is his top priority. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But to this day, dozens of foreigners, including 11 Americans, are still detained in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, hostages are the most valuable bargaining chip in the confrontation between Hamas and Israel. In the case of asymmetry in strength between the two sides, Hamas will make full use of it. This card opens up the situation.&quot; Yu Guoqing analyzed, &quot;When to release the hostages and how many to release at one time, Hamas will not obey Qatar&#39;s orders.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt; strong>;Suitable&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Mediator&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gaza since Hamas raid on Israel Encountered ruthless rocket bombardment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the evening of October 25 to the early morning of October 26, the Israel Defense Forces launched a large-scale ground attack on the Gaza Strip and conducted approximately 250 air strikes within 24 hours. Netanyahu said in a televised speech, &quot;We are pouring the fire of hell on Hamas... and this is just the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;And Qatar, thousands of miles away from Gaza, has become lively after the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, with dignitaries from various countries arriving in droves. Among those hurriedly visiting Qatar were US Secretary of State Antony Blinken and French President Macron’s special envoy for Lebanon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Dignitaries from various countries gathered in Qatar, and the hostage issue became an unavoidable topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gaza is the stronghold of Hamas, which hides hostages in batches in huge underground tunnels. &quot;We don&#39;t have specific data on every house and street in Gaza.&quot; Michael Milstein, who has worked in the Israeli military intelligence system for 20 years, warned, &quot;This is the most difficult hostage situation that Israel has ever encountered in its history.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Rescuing hostages is extremely difficult, and mediation has become an important way for hostages to gain freedom. In this context, Qatar’s unique role as an international mediator has become increasingly prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hasni Abidi, director of the Geneva-based Center for the Study of the Arab and Mediterranean World, pointed out that &quot;there are not many mediators, and Qatar is the most suitable mediator. This small country has no regional agenda of its own and does not care about the political uses of mediation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Qatar has deep pockets, extensive contacts, and a good rapport with the United States. It maintains close contacts with Hamas, which provides it with a unique advantage in mediating the hostage crisis,&quot; Yu Guoqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qatar is one of the 18 &quot;important non-NATO allies&quot; of the United States. Al Udeid Air Base, located 35 kilometers southwest of Doha, the capital of Qatar, is one of the largest U.S. military bases overseas and the forward command center of the U.S. Central Command, with approximately 10,000 U.S. troops and 100 military aircraft deployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2021, the United States hastily withdraws its troops from Afghanistan, and Al Udeid Air Base will assume the role of a &quot;transit hub.&quot; According to statistics, the United States has withdrawn 123,000 people from Afghanistan, of which about 57,000 were transited through Qatar. In fact, the withdrawal agreement between the United States and the Taliban was originally reached in Doha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In addition to relying on the United States, Qatar also has close contacts with Hamas, Hezbollah and other &#39;radical organizations&#39; in the eyes of Western countries.&quot; Yu Guoqing said . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qatar is an important economic supporter of Hamas and has provided a large amount of aid, investment, humanitarian and infrastructure construction to Gaza. Didier Billion, deputy director of the French Institute of International Relations and Strategic Studies, pointed out that Qatar provides $30 million in monthly financial support to Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qatar not only maintains close economic ties with Hamas, but also provides political asylum. In 2012, Qatar’s Emir Hamad bin Khalifa Al Thani visited Gaza. This is the first head of state to visit Gaza since Hamas seized control of the region in 2007. Also starting in 2012, Hamas leaders began to reside in Doha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Struggling between the United States and its hostile forces, Qatar&#39;s role seems contradictory, but in fact it is inseparable from the &quot;tolerance&quot; of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The United States&#39; Middle East strategy has inherent flaws. On the one hand, the United States hopes to rely on its alliance system to achieve its Middle East intentions, but on the other hand, it pulls one faction to fight against the other. It has created all kinds of enemies, especially various sub-international organizations and non-state armed groups.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang analyzed, &quot;When the United States cannot use force to suppress it to achieve diplomatic goals, it must find a middleman to mediate, and Qatar plays the role of Such a key role.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Qatar&#39;s ambitions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qatar is surrounded by sea on three sides, with its southern land bordering Saudi Arabia, like a small boat docked On the west coast of the Persian Gulf. Similar to the shape of its land, Qatar is like a &quot;fast and flexible boat&quot; in international diplomacy, balancing among different forces and playing the role of messenger and mediator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Actively mediating the Palestinian-Israeli hostage crisis is just a microcosm of Qatar&#39;s role as an &quot;enthusiastic&quot; international mediator. In just over a month, Qatar has made three consecutive attempts to act as an intermediary for hostage rescues, prisoner exchanges and other activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 16, 2023, the Qatari government announced that after months of mediation, Russia agreed to release four Ukrainian children. Embassy in Moscow, taking a different route back to Ukraine. Qatari officials said in a statement that the repatriation of the four children was &quot;only the first step.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 18, the United States and Iran officially exchanged five prisoners detained in the United States and Iran, and the prisoner exchange took place in Doha. In fact, the success of this negotiation is inseparable from Qatar&#39;s mediation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to public reports, negotiations between the United States and Iran were held in Doha. During the negotiations, representatives from both sides did not meet each other and stayed in different hotels, while Qatar, the middleman, ran on both sides and acted as a sounding board. After at least eight rounds of airborne talks, the United States and Iran finally reached a prisoner exchange agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qatar has a land area of ​​only about 11,500 square kilometers and a total population of 3 million. How can such a small country be frequently active on the international stage and play a role far beyond its own capabilities in major conflicts? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the 1990s, Qatar wrote the &#39;diplomacy&#39; strategy into its constitution. Since then, it has been adopting a multi-faceted strategy to deal with various forces. Balance. At the same time, Qatar is extremely rich in oil and natural gas resources, and its strong financial resources provide strong support for Qatar’s diplomatic strategy.&quot; Yu Guoqing analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The interviewed experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Qatar&#39;s &quot;small country, big diplomacy&quot; strategy is not only based on the needs of its own survival, but also conceals huge diplomatic ambitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Middle East is intertwined with contradictions and conflicts are frequent. &quot;Caught between regional powers, Qatar is unwilling to be passively controlled by others and choose sides among different forces. For security reasons, Qatar hopes to use high-profile diplomatic mediation in exchange for protection from relevant countries to ensure its own national security. and political security.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang said, &quot;In fact, the reason why Qatar is not afraid of getting burned is largely because it has the big tree of the United States on its back.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;More importantly, using a &#39;grand diplomacy&#39; attitude to mediate in geopolitical crises can further highlight Qatar&#39;s regional importance and international influence.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang further said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Qatar is not entirely following the lead of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the United States has supported Israel, but Qatar has not completely followed the footsteps of the United States. On the contrary, Qatar&#39;s Ministry of Foreign Affairs condemned that Israel bears full responsibility for the continued escalation of the situation and that the international community urgently needs to stop Israel&#39;s violations of international law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Qatar has its own considerations and will not completely follow the interests of the United States.&quot; Zou Zhiqiang pointed out, &quot;adopting a multi-sided bet strategy to balance between different forces , rather than one-sidedly surrendering to major powers or following allies, is an important basis for Qatar to play the role of a middleman. Only by being good at dancing can Qatar have greater room for mediation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But such balanced diplomacy is not without risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 2017, several Middle East and North African countries, led by Saudi Arabia, accused the Qatari government of &quot;supporting extremist forces, intervening in other countries&#39; internal affairs, and creating regional instability.&quot; It suddenly announced the severance of diplomatic relations with Qatar and imposed embargo and blockade measures on Qatar, including closing borders and airspace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The crisis of severing diplomatic relations lasted for nearly four years before it ended. It was not until January 2021 that Saudi Arabia and other countries announced that they had reached reconciliation with Qatar and officially restored comprehensive diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[应该关掉各种班级群，给家长“减负”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259533]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-29 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a seventh-grade teacher from Zhuge Liang Middle School in Xiangyang City, Hubei Province commented to his students &quot;the best in the class&quot; while correcting homework. Oops, are you an orphan?&quot; He then took a photo and posted it in the &quot;Grade 7 Class 9&quot; WeChat group. Subsequently, the local education bureau issued a notice of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course it seems that the teacher has no teacher ethics when he said this. The real problem in this matter is that the teacher really thinks that it is the parents&#39; business to correct students&#39; homework and teach students cultural classes. She was really angry at the parents: &quot;Why don&#39;t you teach your children or grade their homework?&quot; The reason why she scolded her was not to scold the students, but to scold the parents and put pressure on them. In fact, in today&#39;s education, she is by no means the only teacher who thinks so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the inevitable factor behind this accident, and this is the real problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still remember that when I was a child, the teacher would assign homework. It was always after class. The teacher would write on the blackboard, and I would circle it with my book or memorize it in my notebook. This is something every student can accomplish. Do your homework as soon as you get home. If you don&#39;t know how to do it, you may be asked, or you may leave it alone. Your parents may sign it, but they will definitely not check whether the homework is done correctly one by one. Submit your homework the next day and the teacher will correct it. If you are wrong, ask for correction and hand it in with the next day&#39;s homework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now everything has changed. Tutoring and correcting homework have become the responsibility of parents. The teacher assigns homework in the group every day, and parents see it and help their children complete it as required. Although the Ministry of Education has repeatedly warned not to assign homework to parents, the effect is not great. Teachers still give assignments, and parents still need to help with homework, correct homework, and attend class. Among these, Internet-based home-school contact plays a big role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are of course many benefits to using the Internet and smartphones to communicate between home and school. Teachers and parents can communicate at any time without being restricted by time and location, which is convenient and fast. Teachers can assign homework in the group to prevent students from forgetting, and can also publish students&#39; learning status, homework completion status, test scores, etc. Parents can also keep abreast of their children&#39;s learning status and provide timely feedback to the teacher. In short, through WeChat groups, QQ groups, DingTalk groups and other platforms, parents and teachers can interact better and participate in their children&#39;s education process together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the advantages and disadvantages of anything actually lie in the purpose. If the purpose is changed, the advantage may become a disadvantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In various home-school groups, privacy issues such as sending wrong messages are not a big deal. The key issue is that these Internet channels are a channel that effectively distributes pressure and work from teachers to parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that love in the past was beautiful. You had to wait repeatedly to send a love letter. Although it was backward, it was romantic. Nowadays, WeChat contact is constant, making many people feel that they have no space of their own. It is said in the movie &quot;Mobile Phone&quot;: Mobile phones are originally for convenience. Without them, people are quite free. With them, people become kites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Channels will affect content, and tools will affect behavior. Efficient electronic channels have forced parents to have nowhere to escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, parents could say: The child didn’t tell me when he got home, so I don’t know. Now that parents no longer have this space, teachers will shift all the pressure onto parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher is the group leader, to some extent the leader of a small organization. When teachers communicate with parents one-on-one, they are relatively equal, but when communicating in a group, teachers will have many supporters. . Whoever the teacher praises or criticizes in the group will create pressure in the class, and then this pressure will be transmitted to parents and children. In this incident, the teacher also took photos and posted them in the group to unscrupulously put pressure on parents. This will force parents to tutor their children, increase the pressure on their children&#39;s studies, and ultimately form a heavier academic burden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, when there are too many WeChat groups and QQ groups, it will also put a lot of pressure on teachers, add some extra work to them, and increase their workload. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reducing the frequency and convenience of home-school contact can reduce the tasks and pressure teachers pass on to parents. Obviously, if there were no electronic channels and groups, it would be impossible for teachers to call parents one by one to assign homework. These tasks and pressures return to the teachers, and the teachers cannot complete them. In the end, the students&#39; academic burden is reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people may worry that without efficient communication and interaction channels, what should we do if our children&#39;s learning declines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, from a large policy level, this choice has been completed. Some people believe that in the process of implementing the &quot;double reduction&quot; reform, on the one hand, it is necessary to &quot;reduce the excessive academic burden&quot;, have more outdoor activities, and have less homework; on the other hand, it is necessary to &quot;study well&quot; and let children learn in their interests. You can learn more, faster, and better in a state of exuberance. &quot;Load reduction&quot; cannot be simplified to &quot;reducing academic work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of strategy of having both fish and bear&#39;s paw is very safe in terms of attitude. Neither side is offended, both sides want it, and they do not bear any responsibility for the consequences. Children&#39;s burdens are still heavy because they have to &quot;study well&quot;; children do not learn well because they have to &quot;lighten their burdens.&quot; There are changes because we need to &quot;reduce the burden&quot;; there are no changes because we need to &quot;learn well&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is impossible to have your cake and eat it too. For most people, learning requires high-intensity brain operation. The more you learn, the less time you have for this high-intensity operation. The only way to reduce the burden on primary school and junior high school students is to lower their academic standards. In fact, the high school entrance examination in many places has lowered the distinction, and everyone&#39;s scores are about the same. This is lowering academic standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people believe that this will drive parents to let their children continue to answer questions and improve their proficiency, but this may not be the actual situation. Some people&#39;s strategy for reducing returns is to invest less. For example, in the past, people who ate from a big pot and worked hard could be promoted and become model workers. However, most people would choose to lie flat in the face of such disproportionate input and output. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having a group to establish close ties can indeed enhance academic performance, but at the same time, it will cause the problem of overburdening parents. Since the main goal of the policy is to &quot;reduce the burden&quot;, it should not &quot;increase the burden&quot; on the children by &quot;adding burdens&quot; to parents. At this time, the advantage of establishing close ties between home and school through groups becomes a disadvantage. Then, it is a logical choice to reduce the frequency of home-school contact, close various class groups, or even prohibit Internet-based home-school contact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>