<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[从入园难到关停潮，高速增长15年的幼儿园数量迎来拐点丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会顺利闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261168]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 21:24:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 23, the closing event of the Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was held in Shenzhen International, Guangdong Province Held at the Convention Center. Yu Jiadong, deputy director of the conference organizing committee and deputy minister of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, and Lin Tao, deputy director of the conference organizing committee and vice governor of Guangdong Province, attended the closing event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484000c0413bb5e94fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;392&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/e7256484000c0413bb5e94fbda6f7503.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259427&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At the closing event, the conference announced the final winning projects of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition and the list of winners of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Skills Competition. Representatives of the final award-winning projects of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition roadshow display, 12 human resources services On-site signing of supply and demand projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a68f9ac859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;426&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a68f9ac859a8b26aa764953b2ec6461c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259429&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98abfa2c995c1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/406a98abfa2c995c1722300d15389278.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23f95df018807535855354580dccd1fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/23f95df018807535855354580dccd1fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference achieved fruitful results. 144 leading human resources service companies and key employers in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area participated in the exhibition. 294 human resources service cooperation projects were negotiated and docked during the conference, with an intended amount of 20.7 billion. Yuan, the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area youth talent recruitment activities provide more than 50,000 high-quality jobs online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/96af7e89af02ae54faad37f372086e58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/96af7e89af02ae54faad37f372086e58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259432&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713b5a21840ece0263755c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/252fdfbff713b5a21840ece0263755c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c1500f0af88.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/afe1e648209885cba36c6c1500f0af88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259436&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837f66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cf8ba12e1b2f837f66778518904eadd7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259433&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770bc55b77c916a267369fc81.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/ec7bb39770bc55b77c916a267369fc81.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259434&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human Resources Society Responsible comrades of the Ministry of Security, relevant units of Guangdong Province and Shenzhen City, responsible comrades of the Human Resources and Social Security Departments (Bureaus) of all provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, experts and scholars, representatives of human resources service agencies, key employers, and media reporters Attend the closing event of the conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636e4adbd5a23072100e910fbbe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a4349636e4adbd5a23072100e910fbbe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259435&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[瓦依那乐队：哪段水域都不能代表这条河流]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261164]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/RCWqUthWT9bwFoGh9mNh9XvHssFluG0f7YPvWT8s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/RCWqUthWT9bwFoGh9mNh9XvHssFluG0 f7YPvWT8s. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture from Honor 100 series Photography/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage of the third season of &quot;Summer of the Band&quot;, the song &quot;Big Dream&quot; made the Waina band popular, and there were many invitations to perform. This debut has been for more than 10 years The band has become a very popular new face this summer. The lives of the three members are filled with various schedules, which are far more intense than the busy schedule of farming. Before they stand on the stage, they live in the ground. Ban farmers are busy planting in spring. Passers-by work as bricklayers on construction sites all year round, and occasionally go to the streets to sing and sing. Shiba was farming in his hometown and working as a street singer in Guilin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to maintain the order of life as much as possible in Vaina&#39;s busy life, the three members have agreed to spend half the month wandering outside and the other half living at home. For now, they are still looking for a new rhythm. Lu Min and Shiba have not yet adapted to the sudden increase in cameras and flashlights. They feel uncomfortable facing the camera, their eyes flicker, and they don&#39;t speak much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, Shiba went to the streets to sing, spending half the time singing and the other half taking photos with the audience. He made a promise to himself: go there at least once a month. &quot;After all, it&#39;s been 18 years since I first started singing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, &quot;Big Dream&quot; - using age as a node, written from birth to death, has every age Duan&#39;s Dilemma - Before the stage broadcast, we conducted an exclusive interview with the Waina band. They detailed the beginning and end of the establishment of the Waina band and the lives of the three individuals. But at that time, there was still a short period of time before they really became popular, and they belonged to the &quot;former Waina&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will they change? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Real creation is a portrayal of people’s sense of distance on the land of this era&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You performed outstandingly in &quot;Summer of the Band&quot;. Although it has been 10 years since your debut, you are a new face to the public. What do you think of this “newness”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The reason why we went to participate was just for a stage. I have loved writing songs for a long time, but I haven’t had the opportunity to communicate with everyone. This stage allows us to freely express our original attitudes. Sing the songs we want to sing authentically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of Lumin and Shiba, they are indeed young and new. And I (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Editor&#39;s note: Banong&lt;/span>;) have been singing for many years, and I just want to say that this is the first time everyone has heard it. Some of our songs have a different angle from the songs that everyone often hears, and (the audience) has a new feeling. But it is not new to us. We have always been ourselves. What is new (in the eyes of the audience) is something very old about us. It has always been some of our emotions and states of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjPeNhz0AExO9YK8KzSq2BkFbY9EhfybgPc3kk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/wrdjPeNhz0AExO9YK8KzSq2BkFbY9EhfybgPc3kk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ban farmers inspect old rice varieties in their fields&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After getting on this stage, will the invitations and performances that are pouring in come to me? Destroy your rhythm of life and affect your original attitude? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If we don’t have a clear direction, we will be destroyed, but if we have a good direction, it is not destruction; To help us build the state we want, it mainly depends on how we grasp it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We still pay more attention to our own lives, and now we have agreed to spend half a month living at home and half a month doing more communication outside. Of course, this half-month plan is a regular plan. If you are busy with farming or have something to do at home, you can adjust it slightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will your creations be affected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s still land, it’s the relationship between land and people, it’s something real (things) related to life, coming from experience A little more stuff. We prefer to express some emotions from contemporary real life, rather than purely creating or imagining something. This kind of thing derived from reality also has artistic modification techniques. But man is a thing on the land and has a close relationship with the land. Many of people&#39;s sorrows today may be a sequelae of a certain separation between people and the land. People must be inseparable from a relationship with the land and life as a whole, including the countryside and the city. If your creation is real, it must be a portrayal of a person&#39;s sense of distance on the land in this era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have no limits on what we want to create, but there may be a starting point. The Wayna band wants to retain the style of Wayna, but we all have other creations privately, some very different creations based on personal hobbies. But in Waina, it is better not to go off topic. Like when we sing now, we have a little interaction, but in fact I (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Editor&#39;s note: Banong &lt;/span>;) Make some pure music, which is not very similar to Waina’s songs. I have also tried a lot of electronic music. Therefore, we limit our vision to the countryside and describe some changes in people and nature, people and society in contemporary rural areas. This is the main style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A song like &quot;Big Dream&quot; is not considered traditional Waina style, but it has attracted many people now. Will your future creations be biased? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is still close to a portrayal of real life, like &quot;Grandma Returns&quot; written by Lu Min. That song is Hakka. But Waina is from the Zhuang ethnic group, so that’s fine. It’s still a very rural and authentic creation. The so-called reality means that it is like something growing out of the ground. It does not mean that we just make a flower. Of course, that is also a kind of beauty and a kind of consciousness, but Wayna prefers this aspect (reality). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(Everyone likes &quot;Big Dream&quot;) It&#39;s okay, everyone likes it. Let&#39;s just sing &quot;Big Dream&quot; three times first and then sing country. Good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you satisfied with your current life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It mainly depends on how to design. Everything has to be redesigned. There is no fixed life or a satisfactory life for you. , you should (adjust) it based on comfort and realism at any time, and don’t drift. We are quite free and can allocate our time as much as possible. If you want to go out and sing tonight, you can go out. If you don&#39;t want to go out, you can&#39;t go out. Take the initiative to do things without getting tired. It’s a bit hard to be regulated and do it. It was difficult for me to eat because I was probably trying to sleep at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Waina Band was not a banker at the beginning , Lu Min and Shiba 3 members, will you stick to the current lineup in the future? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is sometimes like asking whether you will get divorced after getting married? I feel like it&#39;s flowing, don&#39;t try to kidnap a band. I hope that everyone will do something with their heart wherever they go, instead of just doing it for the sake of making money. Regardless of whether we stay together or not, everyone can continue to sing and live life truthfully. This is the most important thing. If the three of us get tired of our relationship and want to break up, then we will break up. But it doesn’t matter. From now on Shiba can continue to write good songs, I can continue to make music, and Lu Min can continue to sing the songs he wants to sing. This has nothing to do with whether we break up or not. The important thing is to always maintain the expression and experience of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You enjoy the feeling of being photographed in front of the camera ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Shakes his head&lt;/span>; )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you usually like to take pictures? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wayna:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;岜农&lt;/span >;) Usually I can take pictures if I want to. I still like to take pictures of picking wild fruits and pricking them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think is the standard for a good photo? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Waina:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes I look through my hard drive and find some photos that I thought were interesting at the time and beautifully posed, but in fact they are not. use. What&#39;s really useful? I did it, I filmed it. It reminded me of the actual experience and feelings of doing that thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you define a perfect life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Vayna: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Everyone should be different. He should find his most comfortable state, live freely, and be able to realize the meaning of life. Everyone is looking for that spot in him, and I found it early on. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The word &quot;full marks&quot; divides life. From the perspective of the whole life, every stage is a part of your life, just like a river. Which section do you like best? Waters? In fact, no stretch of water represents the river. I think every individual is a perfect score. If you can love yourself and let go like this, you will be a perfect score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨曾志平：坚守正确就是意义所在]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping, the first doctor of military law in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1966 in Yudu County, Ganzhou, Jiangxi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1984-July 1988, studied at the Nanchang Army Academy of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army , received a bachelor&#39;s degree in military science. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1988-1995, successively&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as an officer of the People&#39;s Liberation Army stationed in Zhangzhou, Fujian and an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1995-July 1998, studied at Xi&#39;an Political College and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2004, he served as an instructor at Nanchang Army Academy and a military lawyer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 2004-January 2007, studied at China University of Political Science and Law, receiving a bachelor&#39;s degree in law Ph.D. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From January 2007 to August 2018, he served as professor and senior professor of Nanchang Institute of Technology Professor, Dean and Vice President of the School of Political Science and Law. From July to August 2010, he served as a visiting scholar at the China Research Service Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;April 2012-April 2013, at the University of California, Hastings He served as a visiting scholar at the School of Law (now the University of California, San Francisco School of Law) and the U.S. Institute of Military Justice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 2018-January 2019, served as the Faculty of Law, Xiamen University Kah Kee College professor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2019 to January 2022, he served as the Wenzheng College of Soochow University/Suzhou City Professor of the Department of Law and Political Science of the college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From February 2023 to present, he serves as a professor at the Law School of Guangzhou Business School. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zeng Zhiping is China&#39;s first doctor of military law. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/23/ba4c195b53.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Zhiping is China’s first doctor of military law. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the PhDs interviewed, Zeng Zhiping may be the last to obtain a PhD. In January 2007, he graduated early from China University of Political Science and Law and became China&#39;s first doctor of military law - 24 years had passed since the first batch of doctors trained after the reform and opening up were awarded degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, as a secondary discipline under the category of law, the process of military law becoming a discipline is relatively late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1984, legal scholars Zhang Youyu and Pan Nianzhi first proposed that military law is a branch of the legal system in the &quot;Encyclopedia of China·Law Volume&quot;; three years later, in May 1987, the former State Education Commission Military law was officially listed as a branch discipline of law; in 1993, the Military Law Department of Xi&#39;an Political College (now the Xi&#39;an Campus of the Political College of the National Defense University of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army), the country&#39;s first teaching institution specializing in military legal education, was established, marking the establishment of the Department of Military Law. Military law professional education is officially on the right track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, Xi&#39;an Political College became the first school with the right to award a doctorate in military law; in the same year, China University of Political Science and Law opened a military law research center. In 2004, China University of Political Science and Law began to recruit doctoral students in military law. Also in this year, Zeng Zhiping, who had the rank of lieutenant colonel, transferred from Nanchang Army College and was admitted to China University of Political Science and Law in September of the same year, becoming the only doctoral student in military law enrolled that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Zhiping studied under Professor Zhou Jian, a well-known expert in the field of military law and the first director of the Military Law Teaching and Research Office in China. Zhou Jian once pointed out in an article: &quot;Among the top ten legal disciplines identified by the Ministry of Education, military law (030110) can be said to be the one with the least talents and the most difficult to research.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with law Among other majors, military law is a relatively mysterious and niche subject. Before changing careers, Zeng Zhiping worked in the army for 21 years. In a sense, it was his status as a soldier that gave him the opportunity to specialize in military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zeng Zhiping’s view, today’s “openness” of military law is related to the atmosphere of the rule of law and the society’s demand for military legal talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Military academy, army, and then to military academy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1984, you were admitted to Nanchang Army College (now the Army Infantry College of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army) as an undergraduate student. Why did you choose a military school at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our time, especially in rural areas, everyone’s life was not guaranteed. The ones with relatively better treatment were the military. . When I graduated from high school, I participated in the military draft. At that time, I was recruited to be a pilot, and the requirements were relatively high. I was rejected during the physical examination. When Nanchang Army Academy came to recruit students, the head teacher recommended me. I didn’t have any particularly strong ideas at the time, but my father thought it would be good to be an officer, so he went for it. If you want to say that I have any strong (ideas) towards the military or officers, I don’t think I have any. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is special about undergraduate education in military academies? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Before I went to the military academy, I didn’t know much about the military or the military academy, but physical training was the most beneficial thing for me in the military academy. When I first went to school, I couldn&#39;t do any pull-ups. The school organized physical training, and during the training process, I made the fastest progress. Later, I became an all-around athlete in school and also participated in military sports competitions. Some of the teachers are from the army and will teach tactics, shooting, military fitness, formation and the like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating from Nanchang Army Academy, what did you do Which jobs? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduation, I was sent to the front-line army in Zhangzhou, Fujian. At that time, I was a platoon leader in a regiment. After a few months, I was transferred to the agency. During the training of all division cadres, the instructor of one training subject did not demonstrate accurately, so the regiment leader &quot;picked&quot; me out. Later, I became an instructor for many projects. This (experience) made me stand out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been in the front-line army for four and a half years. I have served as an officer in the Organizational Section of the Political Department and as an instructor. After the Lantern Festival in 1993, I was transferred to Nanchang Army Academy to teach, which I applied for on my own initiative. At that time, I went to the Marxist-Leninist Teaching and Research Office, and the director of the Military Teaching and Research Office asked me: &quot;Why don&#39;t you come to me?&quot; He was my instructor when I was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In school, I taught Introduction to International Politics when I first arrived because there were relatively few teachers taking this course at that time. I was also interested in the introduction to law class, and after one semester, I was teaching introduction to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Discipline Positioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why will you continue? Study law on your own? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s a bit of a coincidence that something happened in the spring of 1993 that had a great impact on college students across the country: the International College Debate Competition , the one Jiang Changjian and the others participated in. It was really interesting for us to watch this competition at that time. Jiang Changjian majored in National Politics, so I wanted to go to Fudan to study for a graduate degree in International Politics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But later at school, I learned that several young men we hung out with were preparing to take the bar exam. I felt that this matter was definitely the right thing to do. After weighing it, I said that I would study law instead of international politics. International politics is a &quot;dragon-slaying art&quot; and law is more practical. In 1994, I began to study law on my own in accordance with the requirements of the bar qualification examination syllabus. In October of that year, I ranked first in the military and qualified as a lawyer. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Note: The national judicial examination system had not yet been established at that time, and you could obtain lawyer qualifications by passing the bar qualification examination.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When I took the postgraduate entrance examination, I was not afraid of majors related to law. Because I had already passed the bar exam and my brain was good at that time, I thought I could pass the exam for any major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You already teach in a military academy, why do you want to study for a master&#39;s degree? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I had not thought about leaving the army at that time, but I did want to leave Nanchang Army Academy. Many professors in the school are older. I feel that if I don’t leave the school, I may not be as good as them when I get older. However, it is still relatively difficult to transfer to the army. The postgraduate entrance examination is a means of leaving school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to take the international law major at Wuhan University, but someone told me that if you study as a graduate student at a local university, you have to go back to your original school after graduation, because it is impossible for local universities to You stay. So I chose Xi&#39;an Political College, which is also a military school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that I think about it, if I had gone to Wuhan University from the beginning, my academic foundation might have been more reliable. If I received systematic academic training when I was young and read a lot of books, then my most source knowledge would be complete and my academic research would have a beginning and an end. My current knowledge cannot reach this level, which is a lifelong regret of mine. Now I mainly feel that my years have been wasted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you were studying for a master&#39;s degree, what did you know about military law? Do you have any idea about what kind of disciplines and what kind of problems are to be solved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is true because I have a background in law. I have read a lot of materials before and also studied military law. In my master&#39;s degree, my direction is military justice, mainly studying the military prosecutorial system. What impressed me most was that I read a lot of English materials at that time and discussed with some famous professors the structure of criminal theory of the three levels of German and Japanese criminal law. This also had a great influence on me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You developed a love for military law during your Ph.D. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I can’t say it’s love. I just accumulated knowledge to a certain extent and have an understanding of this subject. On the other hand, I see a lot of work that is poorly written. I feel that my participation in this subject may make it better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Let’s go back to discuss the positioning of the discipline of military law Question, do you think it belongs to the branch of military science or the branch of law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It depends on how you treat belonging. This issue can be discussed from the subject management of the Ministry of Education, from the professional fields involved in the subject, and from the classification of knowledge. I only recognize the classification of knowledge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In June 2022, Wenzheng College of Suzhou University, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) is with students. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cb781e6727.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022 In June of this year, Zeng Zhiping (fifth from left) was with students at Wenzheng College of Soochow University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I am also a product of the times”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you graduated with a master&#39;s degree, your original plan was to continue on the academic path? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, before graduation, I want to go to the Shanghai Military Procuratorate or leave the original school. At that time, I returned to Nanchang and took an introduction to law class at school. Because there were several teachers taking the same course, I could only attend a few classes in one semester. In addition to taking classes at the military academy, I was also teaching part-time at several private universities. It can be said that teaching has nourished my psychology. In private universities, many students look at you with hungry and passionate eyes, which is different from what I encountered at my original school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then why did you go to China University of Political Science and Law? Where&#39;s Beau? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a bit of a coincidence. I had always wanted to change my job before the Spring Festival in 2004, but at that time the unit leader had not announced our job. There is news that I can change my job, I am just applying. At that time, I saw the information about various schools recruiting Ph.D.s, and I was thinking, &quot;Will it be approved (for career change) this year?&quot; Around January 10, 2004, after my application for job change was approved, I quickly checked the admissions information of various schools. I had always wanted to go to Wuhan University, but the registration had closed at that time. However, that year, because the Chinese Political Science and Law added a new doctoral program in military law, its registration period was extended, so I signed up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When looking at school admissions information, I will also consult some teachers. I met Teacher Zhou Jian when I was studying at Xi&#39;an Political College, and I called him. I originally wanted to major in criminal law, and I have been teaching criminal law. Then teacher Zhou Jian said, you don’t want to major in criminal law. I teach military law in China’s political and legal field, so you can study military law with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also told Teacher Zhou, &quot;I have changed careers, why should I study military law? I am still more interested in criminal law.&quot; Therefore, military law is really a product of the times, and I am also a product of the times. It is a coincidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Was the competition fierce to apply for a doctorate in military law at China University of Political Science and Law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, China University of Political Science and Law had three professors who could teach PhD students in military law, but that year only Professor Zhou Jian enrolled students, and the quota only one person. I was particularly impressed. There were 10 people who signed up at that time. I also checked the scores of other candidates using the score checking rules. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rule for checking scores at that time was to just enter your admission ticket number. According to the numbering method of the admission ticket number, the first digits are the same, and the difference is in the last single digits and tens digits. Based on where we were in the exam room at that time, I could probably guess how many people were in front of me and behind me. After I checked my scores, I guessed their numbers, and I actually found out my scores. Seeing that the second place was 20 points lower than me, I felt more relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How will it be for you to get a doctorate from China University of Political Science and Law? Something more important? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this is a very important turning point in life. At that time, I changed my career and had a doctorate in military law. Teacher Zhou said, China’s political and legal affairs will definitely keep you, so my life plan at that time had a general direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for my master&#39;s degree, I once went to Beijing. While reading in the Beijing Library, I met an old gentleman. He went to an event at Peking University and we had a brief chat. He said something to the effect of &quot;If I can go to Peking University to be a professor in this life, I can do whatever I want.&quot; I had a very imaginary idea at that time: It would be great if I could become a professor of political science and law in China, so sometimes life is very strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there were some changes later, and I did not stay at China University of Political Science and Law after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cognition is the core of personality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You Studying for a master&#39;s degree is to leave the original school; studying for a doctorate is to stay in a new school. So these choices you made were not based on professional choices? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I have always wanted to teach in a better university, but people are like duckweeds of the times. My current thoughts may be more mature thoughts, because my career is nearing the &quot;end&quot;. I think it is like this: you need to go to school, your school, the teachers and classmates you meet should work together to help you find your interests in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think an ideal society should be one where everyone is encouraged to do what you want to do and find your interests and passions. If every young person&#39;s growth is to learn based on his own love, then this will enhance his love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The first doctor of military law after the founding of New China&quot; label, for Has it had a big impact on your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I didn’t realize this when I graduated. In 2007, my son was going to take the college entrance examination. My simple thought was, can I graduate early? If I stay in China Political Science and Law, it will be very convenient for my son to go to school in Beijing. But my son didn&#39;t think it was necessary. He got good grades and was admitted to Wuhan University. But I finished my thesis and graduated half a year ahead of schedule. I didn’t mean to be the first. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I passed the graduation thesis defense in the morning, and the &quot;Legal Daily&quot; reported it in the afternoon. Later, some foreign media also followed up and reported the matter. It still seems very interesting now. I don’t know if the foreign media paid attention to the first doctorate in other disciplines, but at that time many foreign media reported on me and even mentioned the title of my thesis &quot;On Military Power&quot; and said that I was interested in Such a major theoretical issue is well researched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t told anyone about this label myself. Now that I have to say it has brought me any special benefits, I don’t think it has. After all, I haven’t used it to apply for a job. Or do some publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., you applied for Nanchang Institute of Technology and were ordered to establish Nanchang Institute of Technology Department of Political Science and Law, College. Compared with the “five colleges and four departments” in the legal world, what do you think the law department of a private university should look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I came to Nanchang Institute of Technology in 2007 and received the National Social Science Fund in 2008. At that time, there were only a dozen colleges and universities with law departments and law majors in Jiangxi, so it had a great impact. For a long time, the school regarded me as a signature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of undergraduate education, I am very conscious. I have not included military law in the professional courses of law undergraduates. I have only made it a public elective course for the whole school. It would be very shameless if you become the head of the department or the dean of the law school and then turn your own courses into professional courses, compile textbooks, and ask people to buy your books. Until now, I have not compiled a textbook on military law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I started the courses based on the most basic law undergraduate major. If there is anything special about it, it can be said that I taught several very important general courses: general logic, grammar and rhetoric, introduction to political science, introduction to sociology, etc. At that time, these courses were not available in law schools. universal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, we became the construction unit for the master&#39;s degree awarding project in Jiangxi Province, which was issued by the relevant units. I want students to receive a good education, which can also be regarded as a relatively direct achievement at work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the sense of accomplishment I get from teaching also gives me the motivation to continue. Why do I keep teaching? It&#39;s because I think there are many mistakes now, and teaching is also wrong teaching. Sometimes I say it very negatively, even though I am definitely not popular, I can at least eliminate those false popular ones, because I occupy a position, so that there is one less false popular person. Location. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I stick to what is right, that’s what it means to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have any experiences or ideas that you would like to share with current college students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zeng Zhiping: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is true that people cannot escape the fate of duckweed, but whether they care about knowledge or not is always different. After all, cognition is at the core of personality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[起底缅北电诈头目祝寿视频背后产业链：有明星报价一条14万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261143]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Which celebrities can be invited to record blessing videos for less than 2,000 yuan/5,000 yuan/10,000 yuan?&quot; &quot;Backstage private message recording of celebrity blessing video&quot; &quot;can be released in 3 days!&quot; Many celebrities were exposed to have filmed birthday videos for the leader of telecom fraud in northern Myanmar, causing an uproar. Recently, reporters from Nandu and N Video found on some e-commerce and social platforms that there are still an endless stream of merchants hyping and selling &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;birthday boy&quot; who caused the controversy is Bai Yingcang, the son of Bai Suocheng, one of the four major families in northern Myanmar. Bai Jiaci is recognized as the head of the &quot;four major Kokang families&quot; in northern Myanmar. Zi, who is also the deputy director of the Kokang Finance Bureau and the captain of the Kokang Autonomous Region Militia Brigade, controls Cangsheng Science and Technology Park, an electronic fraud park. Even though some celebrities said that filming a birthday video for them was &quot;out of favor&quot; and they did not know them, it still failed to dispel netizens&#39; doubts. The &quot;Celebrity Blessing Video&quot; industry chain has once again entered the public eye. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is it illegal to make a birthday video for a scammer? &quot;Celebrity blessing videos&quot; have been around for a long time. How is the trend now? Why are consumers so keen on buying, and how do celebrities view this phenomenon? Reporters from Nandu and N Video interviewed entertainment company agents, buyers and sellers of blessing videos, lawyers and experts, etc. to get to the bottom of the industry chain behind &quot;celebrity blessing videos&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/2e15988619c628888801adc6292903f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259403 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Someone promotes celebrity blessing videos on social platforms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Controversy: Celebrities send video of birthday wishes to Dian Toutou&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Here, I I wish Bai Yingcang a happy birthday and a bright future...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After several leaders of telecom fraud groups in northern Myanmar were arrested, a message &quot;Many celebrities paid tribute to the four major families in northern Myanmar. The news that Cheng&#39;s son Bai Yingcang recorded a video to celebrate his birthday caused an uproar in public opinion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At this birthday party, the large screen in the center of the stage played congratulatory videos from many stars, including Hong Kong artists Eric Tsang, Wong Yifei, and Charlie Chao, as well as actor Du Xudong and crosstalk actor Hou Yaohua. wait. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eric Tsang, known as the eldest brother of the Hong Kong film industry, explained to the outside world, &quot;It may be that friends help each other by saying, &#39;This is my good friend&#39;, and then record it. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;After this, some unfamiliar people will try to avoid it.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Actor Charlie Cao released an apology video He said that he came back from Canada in August last year. &quot;When the manager sent this thing over, I asked why it seemed to be a dialogue from Jiang Hu, and I didn&#39;t want to shoot it. He said it&#39;s okay, many celebrities have filmed it, so I filmed it.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He said that he didn’t know where the manager put the video. Many celebrities did it for money. “I made this video just for money, because I want to live and live. I have no choice but to eat, but I have never interacted with people who scam people in northern Myanmar.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Nandu reporters found that before this incident, there had been similar &quot;overturning&quot; of celebrity blessing videos. Artist Yang Di once fell into a whirlpool of public opinion for filming a promotional video for a P2P platform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July 2020, a large number of investors reported on social networks that the loans on the &quot;Lili.com&quot; platform had not been paid after they expired, and posted on Yang Di&#39;s Weibo account , calling on him to speak out about the &quot;Yiwang Fraud&quot; incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Subsequently, Yang Di issued a statement on Weibo, stating that he recorded the video for the promoter during the movie promotion period and was not the spokesperson of &quot;Yiliwang&quot;, nor did he record the video. Charge any fees. &quot;I will help the users who were deceived in this incident to pursue the case to the end, and I deeply apologize to the viewers who suffered losses due to the video recommendation.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What is the reason why celebrities record blessing videos? For favor or for money? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In July this year, Hong Kong media reported that Luo Jiaying and other actors shot exclusive blessing videos to endorse online club groups. Some people were deceived and transferred tens of thousands of yuan to stock trading platforms. Afterwards, the money cannot be withdrawn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Afterwards, Luo Jiaying admitted, &quot;I read the script according to the arrangement of the manager. I don&#39;t know this person.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Quotes: Someone has to collect an intention fee of more than four figures before making an inquiry&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 22, a Nandu reporter used keywords such as &quot;celebrity blessing video&quot; A search on some e-commerce and social media platforms found that many users with the words &quot;celebrity agent&quot; and &quot;media culture&quot; in their names have posted multiple celebrity blessing videos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Click on the user&#39;s homepage, and the introduction will have a prompt of &quot;backstage private message celebrity blessing video recording&quot;. Several sellers showed the Nandu reporter a quotation list, which included the celebrity&#39;s name, avatar, masterpieces, and the price of recording blessing videos for personal and commercial purposes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Most of them are singers, &lt;/span>; actors, hosts, and Chinese and foreign athletes from the Mainland, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. In the same quotation, the price difference is huge, as low as 100 yuan, and as high as 140,000 yuan. There are also celebrities who appear in the alternatives without price tags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/a3af588330a155a751f2020852648a91.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259401&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The price of a celebrity shooting blessing video shown on a quotation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A seller introduced&lt;/span>; that the price quoted by such celebrities is more than 100,000 yuan. If you want to name them to record a video, the seller will need to charge more than four figures. Only if you need an intention fee, you are willing to contact the star company to inquire about the quotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen &lt;span>;Jian (pseudonym), who claims to work in the media circle, admitted to Nandu reporters that the prices of celebrities are naturally different depending on their status. Faced with doubts about the higher prices compared with peers, he said, &quot;The difference lies in the service.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He recommended a Taiwanese actor’s blessing video service with a quotation of 30,000 yuan. On the quotation sheet of Zhang Yong (pseudonym), the actor’s quotation was 23,000 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I offer low prices without any additional fees.” Zhang Yong claimed to be an artist manager and a first-hand general agent. “I can not only connect with media companies, but also You can connect with artist managers, or even directly contact the celebrities themselves.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Chen Jian said that the duration of celebrities&#39; blessing videos is generally controlled within 30 seconds, and in addition, the specific details need to be The content is reported to the star, and an accurate quote can only be given after confirming that it can be recorded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another seller, whose name is from a media company, made it clear to Nandu reporters that the video length is generally about 10 to 15 seconds, &quot;the normal speaking speed is 20 to 25 seconds.&quot; Between the words.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for the production time, it is generally determined according to the star&#39;s own time. &quot;It usually takes about 7 days, if faster, 3 to 5 days.&quot; Some sellers also write that &quot;it can be released in 3 days.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Yong revealed that his quotation list marked a group of celebrities who often record blessing videos because they are &quot;highly cost-effective, fast, and highly cooperative.&quot; Be recommended to buyers first. Some lesser-known celebrities will take the initiative to ask him to help recommend and record them first. The blessing videos of such celebrities will be &quot;packaged&quot; and sold at a uniform price. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some sellers told Nandu reporters that although some &quot;top&quot; names appeared in the quotations, in fact they did not accept orders specifically for A-list celebrities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for which celebrities are “top-tier”? &quot;Let&#39;s put it this way, you feel that celebrities or athletes who have endorsed many brands will basically not record blessing videos.&quot; Chen Jian said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Regulations: Some companies have clear regulations&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Why are celebrities recording blessing videos so popular? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai (pseudonym) once spent more than 200 Australian dollars (over 900 yuan) to purchase and customize two clips of English football legend Michael Owen on Cameo, an overseas video customization website. blessing video as an encouragement to myself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;603&quot; height=&quot;933&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/aa0ac2a14de88d8f77c4e782e3fa4489.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259400 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Maimai received a blessing video recorded by Irving. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She fell in love with Owen when she was young and started to play football. It has been 17 years now. She recalled to Nandu reporters that when she decided to buy the video, she was going through a divorce and ended a seven-year relationship. She needed encouragement. &quot;When words of encouragement come from the mouth of an idol, it feels different.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Maimai got the video&lt;/span>; within about a week after paying. And the moment she saw the video, she felt it was all worth it. &quot;This video gave me strong strength and belief at the lowest and saddest time in my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Guiping, associate professor of the Department of Audiovisual Communication, School of Journalism and Communication, South China University of Technology, analyzed to Nandu reporters, like The recording of videos by celebrities is a satisfying and public presentation of their mimetic intimacy, but there is another situation as well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individuals have profit-seeking appeals to the appeal of celebrities. &lt;span>; In layman&#39;s terms, it can be understood as &#39;traffic&#39;, that is, using the celebrity&#39;s popularity to increase one&#39;s visibility and discussion. Some even It can be directly converted into fans and platform revenue on social media platforms,” she said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters saw from Zhang Yong’s “Buyer Show” that there were many enthusiastic orders from various companies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;The psychological demands of companies for celebrities to record videos are more pure. There is no relationship demand, but mainly interest demands.&quot; Huang Guiping explained that in fact, it is to take advantage of the celebrity&#39;s popularity and Public trust endorses one&#39;s products, brands, and company image, reducing the public&#39;s doubts and uncertainty when purchasing its products. &quot;This kind of &#39;bringing goods&#39; is relatively risky for celebrities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Peng (pseudonym) is the manager of a well-known domestic female talent show team. He told Nandu reporters that he usually tells the artists directly that the company has clear regulations that do not allow recording of these blessing videos. &quot;In my opinion, these incomes are not scientific.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At work, he will strictly distinguish the nature of video recording. &quot;For example, for holiday greetings or cultural promotion, we will charge &#39;travel fees&#39; for recording as appropriate. &lt;span>;But if you record a video for an enterprise, it is a proper business behavior. Our requirements will be higher and we will not just record it easily.&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nandu reporters found that sellers who sell celebrity blessing videos often do not only engage in this business. Celebrity business endorsements, rummage videos, commercial performances, group photos... In the profiles they showed, various celebrity-related businesses emerged one after another. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/0a3fdad9e43324b8f07be87f08edae13.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259402 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The seller shows a business case of celebrities recording blessing videos. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“They often have commissions.” Sun Peng revealed to Nandu reporters, “In fact, the fixed salary of artist agents is not high, and sometimes they all earn commissions by doing work for others. Or rebate. But everyone has their own life, and it is difficult to evaluate the quality of this phenomenon.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Risk: Celebrities may be held legally responsible&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Celebrities recording blessing videos may seem like a business deal that can be concluded with just a few words, but in fact there are hidden risks that cannot be ignored. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If it is a birthday occasion, celebrities record blessing videos out of favor or for a fee, which generally does not violate public order and good customs, but if it involves platform, &quot;endorsement&quot; and other properties, it cannot be easily understood As &quot;if one party is willing to give money, the other party can shoot&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiaxin, a lawyer at Guangdong Guangxin Junda Law Firm, analyzed to Nandu reporters that providing blessings to individuals can be regarded as an economic behavior for fans. This form is not a civil legal act and does not actually infringe legal interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if a celebrity shoots a blessing video for a company or product, due to the celebrity&#39;s celebrity effect, such videos are actually using advertising language &lt;span>; and positive statements to imply or express the outside world&#39;s view of the company or product. Enterprises and products should be widely promoted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Therefore, this type of video is an act of advertising endorsement. If the company involved in the video blessing is suspected of illegal business, and the star has knowledge of the business, the star is also suspected of breaking the law and will be held liable. Responsibility.&quot; Wang Jiaxin said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When it was revealed that many celebrities had recorded birthday videos for telecom fraudsters in northern Myanmar, many netizens questioned, &quot;Why did the telecom fraud leader harm so many innocent people? Is he celebrating his birthday?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;But if these blessing videos are later exposed to congratulate the leader of the electronic fraud, the netizen&#39;s report is actually not valid, because they are personal blessing videos and are not It’s not targeting the company.” Wang Jiaxin further explained that if a celebrity’s blessing video emphasizes an electronic fraud company, it must also be proven that the celebrity is aware of the company’s suspected electronic fraud, such as whether the celebrity participates in the company’s operations or holds shares in the company, but It is generally difficult to prove. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As the manager of a well-known domestic talent show girl group, Sun Peng also feels that &quot;irregular forms of cooperation&quot; such as recording blessing videos will increase the risks to the artists themselves. . At the same time, he also admitted that sometimes companies spend millions of yuan to invite artists to participate in brand promotion and endorsement. During the promotion process, it is actually difficult for artists to refuse the company&#39;s request to take photos or record videos. Once you agree, how the subsequent photos and videos will be used by the other party is uncontrollable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Before relevant laws, regulations and policy provisions are introduced for control, the transaction of celebrities shooting congratulatory videos will indeed be in a gray area, which will lead to what we call&#39; There is a hidden worry of recognizing money but not people.&quot; Huang Guiping, a communication expert, told Nandu reporters that in the absence of regulations and controls, celebrity individuals, companies, and consumers are all in a state of lack of protection, which is likely to lead to a situation where everyone loses. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Therefore, when relevant departments take action, celebrities realize the consumption of their own image and turn back, or companies realize that the efficiency of benefit conversion is low but the risk is high, this If any of the three situations occurs, it is possible that the &#39;celebrity blessing video chaos&#39; can be alleviated.&quot; Huang Guiping said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄乌电子战，矛与盾的游戏丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQgEpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQg EpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, in the Donetsk region, unmanned troops of the Ukrainian army Aircraft operators are training not far from the front line &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Ukrainian military claimed that it had Soldiers drove out their positions on the east bank of the Dnieper River in the occupied Kherson area and established multiple bridgeheads. Russia also admitted for the first time that the Kiev army had crossed the Dnieper River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is of course a result worthy of attention, because the establishment of a bridgehead on the east bank of the Dnieper River poses a great threat to Crimea. If Ukraine can deploy long-range weapons on the east bank, Crimea may It’s hard to stick with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General Zaluzhny, Commander-in-Chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, emphasized in an interview with The Economist that Ukraine needs to develop and deploy its own advanced technology to regain the upper hand in the war. Behind the establishment of the bridgehead It is the tactical advantages brought about by a series of technological updates, especially in electronic countermeasures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the outbreak of the Russo-Ukrainian War, Ukraine has been engaged in invisible electronic countermeasures with Russia. The battle in the Kherson area is the forefront of this confrontation, because the two sides can often only use it across the river. Long-range firepower exchanges, so drones become the key to victory, because both sides rely heavily on drones to find targets and correct artillery. Whoever can use electronic countermeasures to suppress the opponent&#39;s drones will gain an advantage in the battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the most efficient way to fight drones is to suppress them through electromagnetic interference, which will directly cause the drone to crash. It has been previously reported that the area near the Dnieper River has become a no-fly zone for drones, because both sides will use electronic jamming methods to suppress and interfere with the flight of drones. On this invisible battlefield, the two sides have been engaged in a very complex and cruel battle. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For nearly a century, electromagnetic interference has been an important part of warfare. Traditional electronic warfare methods are to find the radio frequencies being used by the enemy and create overwhelming noise on the same frequencies, making it impossible for the opponent to attack use. In World War II, electronic warfare mainly targeted radio communications and radar. As long as the opponent was unable to communicate and detect, the mission was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern communication technology has developed various means to combat electronic interference, but the main reason is not just for electronic warfare, but because there are a large number of electromagnetic signal sources in human society. During World War II, a 50-watt radio could easily carry out point-to-point communications in China and even East Asia. However, now it is difficult for a 50-watt radio to cover even one province - this is not because the radios back then were more advanced, but because the radios were more advanced. It was because the electromagnetic environment was good back then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electromagnetic communication can be regarded as a conversation between two parties. If the room is very quiet, the two parties can hear what the other party is saying without making a loud sound. If there are not only many people chatting in the room, but also people watching movies, shooting balls, playing and singing, then the two parties must raise their voices or be very close to each other when communicating. The reason why modern communication technology attaches great importance to anti-interference is because the electromagnetic background environment is too complex, making it impossible to complete communication simply by increasing power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Software technology is also improving. For example, in the past, changing the frequency and signal characteristics of a radio station required replacing hardware. However, with the softwareization of radios, only changing the encoding can completely change the spectrum of the equipment. In other words, problems that in the past required major repairs after being interfered with can now only be solved by adding a patch to the software, or even reusing the software to replace the encryption method. In the past, to change the encryption method, each receiving end needed to change the machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;UAVs used in the military generally use more complex control methods to combat interference. For example, frequency hopping is used to connect back-end control, which can skip the interfered frequency band. This is commonly used in radio communications. Anti-interference means; you can also use inertial navigation in the case of interference, continue to execute the original flight path, and then connect satellite navigation and rear control when the interference weakens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, as the ability to resist interference becomes stronger, the ability to resist interference will also become stronger accordingly. Spears and shields compete with each other and develop with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, as long as your electronic warfare capabilities are strong enough, you can construct an electronic golden bell that prevents all drones from flying in and prevents precision-guided weapons from hitting targets in the golden bell. If the interferer&#39;s equipment reaches 100% power, anti-interference methods are often difficult to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the reality is that interference means cannot provide full-level signals in all areas, which depends on the location of the interference source, the orientation of the antenna and its own power. The drone is a mobile platform that can continuously fly for reconnaissance and interfere with weak signal locations to find better flight routes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And sometimes the problem can be solved in less &quot;electronic&quot; ways, such as using radio triangulation to directly find the approximate location of the interference source, and using long-range firepower to cover the opponent, even if it misses the target. It can force the opponent to shut down temporarily to avoid the blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, there are many tactics in actual combat that can weaken the effect of the opponent&#39;s electronic interference, and these tactics themselves are also an important part of electronic warfare. Therefore, there is no omnipotent secret weapon. On the invisible battlefield of electronic warfare, only by continuously strengthening technology and constantly changing and updating countermeasures can we gain an advantage in action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省人大常委会原副主任李春生受贿案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:08:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the Chenzhou Intermediate People’s Court of Hunan Province held a public hearing of the first instance against the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress The bribery case involving Li Chunsheng, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The Chenzhou Municipal People’s Procuratorate alleged that from the second half of 2001 to May 2022, the defendant Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County, Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security, director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province, and provincial Director of the Public Security Department, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress, etc., and provide convenient conditions for the formation of authority and status to provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc. , illegally accepting property from others, equivalent to a total of more than 79.4 million yuan in RMB. The procuratorate requested that Li Chunsheng be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the procuratorate presented relevant evidence, and the defendant Li Chunsheng and his defender conducted cross-examination. The prosecution and defense fully expressed their opinions under the auspices of the court, and Li Chunsheng made a final statement. He also expressed his guilt and repentance in court. At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 30 people including NPC deputies, CPPCC members and people from all walks of life attended the trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘红兵任广东省副省长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261150]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:33:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the afternoon of November 23, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress voted , decided to appoint Liu Hongbing as deputy governor of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A·S·拜厄特：“即便我死了，春天还会继续到来”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261141]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/23/y6qQYTfj2g7DgTOzkyJwXOlLmaHQGdT151yVDL2i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/y6qQYTfj2g7DgTOzkyJwXOlLmaHQG dT151yVDL2i. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;AS Byatt&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps no novelist has made as important a contribution to expanding the boundaries of English fiction as she has.&quot; (Philip Henschel)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On November 16, 2023, local time, British writer and scholar A.S. Byatt passed away peacefully at home surrounded by his relatives at the age of 87. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Byatt won the Booker Prize for his novel &quot;Possession&quot; and made a sensation in the literary world. In the same year, she was awarded the Order of the British Empire, and in 1999 she was awarded the title of Dame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The almost obsessive research ethos prevalent in contemporary English writing owes a great deal to Possession’s majestic, engrossing demonstration, a work of romantic literature from the archives; at the same time, The science fantasy of &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot; has powerfully proven its immense instructive significance for young writers... No one can write about both Darwin&#39;s theory and the ancient inexhaustible theme of love. &quot;So brilliantly.&quot; Philip Henschel, a reporter from &quot;The Paris Review&quot; who once interviewed Byatt, recalled, &quot;Few writers have such strong intellectual curiosity; except for her, perhaps no one can view spiritual life so decisively. It is a pleasure to be enjoyed, and it is equal in absorption and release.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 60-year writing career, Byatt also published &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, &quot;The Children&#39;s Book&quot; and Her representative works include the tetralogy of female growth (&quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot;, &quot;Still Life&quot;, &quot;Tower of Babel&quot; and &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot;), as well as short story collections such as &quot;Eye of a Nightingale&quot; and &quot;Matisse Stories&quot;. Her works have been It has been translated into 38 languages ​​and won many world-class literary awards. Confidently moving between literature, religion, science, art, and theoretical insights, Byatt is recognized as &quot;one of the most important writers and critics of our time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/muZTpXilvlTUurXYtz23y4l913KVOooAqwbWUI04.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1030&quot; height= &quot;1542&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/muZTpXilvlTUurXYtz23y4l913KVOooAqwbWUI04.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021, Byatt&#39;s last book , the short story anthology &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&quot; was published. &quot;These stories are charming and sparkling, intoxicating and trembling. They comfort you and awaken you.&quot; The famous British novelist David Mitchell commented in the introduction: &quot;If you compare &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&quot; to For an artist’s retrospective exhibition, the museum does not need to provide a tour guide, nor does it need to place exhibition labels next to the works - because these stories are just there, so perfect and bright.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I don’t like it. Spiritual Director&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“A lot of what I write has to do with the need, fear and desire for solitude.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A. S. Byatt was born Ann Antonia Susan Drabble was born in Sheffield, England in 1936. Her father was a judge and her mother taught Victorian poetry. Byatt graduated from the University of Cambridge and the University of Oxford. He taught English literature at University College London in 1972. He resigned from his teaching position in 1983 to focus on writing. In the same year, he became a member of the Royal Society of Literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt is the eldest daughter in the family. Her parents and three younger siblings are also Cambridge graduates. &quot;I was lucky in Cambridge. A university English degree often makes people discouraged from writing. Graduating the degree greatly suppressed my desire to write and made me feel embarrassed. But at the same time, it greatly strengthened my desire to write. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DOKvCJtmvmkSaQNItA7o6YMTBOWPfG8k5ZkQ6iQI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DOKvCJtmvmkSaQNItA7o6YMTBOWPfG8k5ZkQ6iQI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Possession&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the publication of the novel &quot;Possession&quot;, Byatt&#39;s reputation was once shrouded in the shadow of his sister Margaret De La, who is also a writer. Under the aura of Boole, Byatt once admitted in an interview with &quot;The Paris Review&quot;, &quot;Let&#39;s put it bluntly: the response to my first few books was all confused...No one paid attention to what I was doing...She wrote I wrote a lot, and I wrote fast. In the long run, it had a positive effect on me. I didn’t have the anxiety most writers have about repercussions, I just had this simple fear of being thought of as someone’s sister.”&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In his 1967 novel The Game, Byatt tells the story of a pair of competing sisters (just two years earlier, Drabble had published a novel on a similar theme). Byatt explained that the inspiration for &quot;The Game&quot; came from a board game that her friend&#39;s sister used to play with imaginary fragments, &quot;much like Henry James&#39;s game of climbing stairs to find fragments of information.&quot; The novel is also a reference to Brown. &quot;I found the Brontë sisters&#39; solitaire imagination to be extremely terrifying.&quot; &quot;The Game&quot; also points to people&#39;s creativity in childhood. According to Byatt&#39;s recollection, when she was a child, she wrote about men in disguise sneaking into Adventures in a girls&#39; school, but &quot;most of those exercises were burned before I left boarding school.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1958, Byatt married British economist Ian Byatt (first husband, divorced in 1969), and the two lived in Durham, a city in northeastern England. It is a place where the legacy of the Middle Ages still exists. In that era, if you were a woman, they would take away the benefits they gave you for getting married, but if you were a man, they would increase it. So, there I lost my benefits, and from some hidden In a sense, I am secretly happy about it, because I actually want to be a writer rather than a scholar.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt gave birth to two children after marriage, during which she gave birth to her first child. The manuscript of &quot;The Shadow of the Sun&quot; that had been put in the drawer was taken out and &quot;rewritten over and over again in a slow and unpleasant way...At the same time, one or the other baby was placed in a small chair on the desk and rocked gently with one hand. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, Byatt published her first novel &quot;The Shadow of the Sun&quot;. In her own words, &quot;a novel about a young woman at a university who wants to write a novel.&quot; In this debut novel, Byatt writes about a girl trying to escape from her controlling father. Tense family relationships and women&#39;s independent growth have since become important issues in many of her works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“I don’t want to belong to any group...I don’t like a spiritual guru, someone who asks you to follow or worship him. I like someone who asks you to think for yourself.”&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Is he &quot;possessing&quot; her, or is she &quot;possessing&quot; him&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Possession&quot; was conceived by me for 15 years. I gave up UCL for 11 years I wrote it in two months after I started teaching. It&#39;s the only novel I&#39;ve ever written that was generally coherent, with no one getting sick, no disasters, no awards, no book promotions. It had a terrible energy, and from the first sentence to the last, the whole book was in my mind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to Byatt, &quot;early writing&quot; means Works before &quot;Possession&quot;. In 1990, when this work became a best-seller and won the Booker Prize, Byatt finally &quot;occupied&quot; an important position in the literary world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The creation of Possession began with the title of the book. I was sitting in the old-fashioned round table reading room of the British Museum, watching the great Coleridge scholar Catherine Coburn in the circular catalog area Walking around, round and round. I suddenly realized that her whole life was dedicated to this dead poet. I thought: Did he &#39;possess&#39; her, or did she &#39;possess&#39; him? Then I thought, This could be written as a novel, about the &#39;possession&#39; relationship between the living and the dead. It would be a fascinating story of possession.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Possession&quot; revolves around two contemporary people. The scholar&#39;s research unfolds: a pretentious young academic and a reserved feminist. While tracing the letters exchanged between Victorian poets, the two unearthed a secret love affair of that era. Falling in love in the process...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The word &#39;possession&#39; also has a very direct interest level that can be discussed: who &#39;possess&#39; the manuscript of a dead writer? Moreover, &#39;possession&#39; also applied to sexual relations. At that time , I was studying the letters of Browning and his wife, and I thought of two pairs of lovers, one modern and the other ancient - the Victorians, and having them embody &#39;possession&#39; in these senses.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The publication of &quot;Possession&quot; (full title &quot;Possession: A Romance&quot;) heralds the emergence of a &quot;new Byatt&quot;. She has great narrative talent, and the novel is full of humorous satire on the academic circle. , like a suspenseful detective story, or a touching (as its subtitle suggests) romantic legend. &quot;I originally planned to write an experimental novel, about literary theory and an ambitious biographical text... What changed everything was my reading experience of Eco&#39;s &quot;The Name of the Rose&quot; and its ironic medieval detective story... The secret I found in it is: a great story that can put whatever you need to put in it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the text of &quot;Possession&quot;, Byatt also boldly inserts herself Poetry imitating the style of Victorian poetry. &quot;The novel required real poetry in form, but I don&#39;t write poetry. My editor at the time said: Don&#39;t be ridiculous, write it yourself! So, I went home and wrote a Victorian poem about spiders... I have always been fascinated by the poetry of Tennyson and Browning. I read it as a child because my mother was a Browning expert. Their rhymes sang in my head, and those Victorian verses just clicked in my novel. came out of nowhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the time Byatt completed Possession, publishers on both sides of the Atlantic were deeply troubled and almost sceptical. &quot;They begged me to cut out those poems and writings about the Victorian era. The only American publisher brave enough to accept it reminded me: &#39;You ruin all the suspense with these cumbersome words.&#39; Early in the morning, I cried. . Later, the novel won the Booker Prize, to everyone&#39;s surprise (including myself), it became a bestseller, and people wrote essays using my imaginary poet. &quot;Possession&quot; was translated into thirty Multiple languages. I owe Eco a huge debt.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/lVwV5oiE7YyAk81DJaL91Dxb3tBmm8PecdppoaHu. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/lVwV5oiE7YyAk81DJaL91Dxb3tBmm8PecdppoaHu.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;259392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matisse&#39;s story&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Still Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Byatt once said in an exclusive interview with the New York Times: &quot;I am not an academic who accidentally wrote a novel. In fact, I happen to be a moderately academic novelist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt&#39;s early literary creations were modeled after George Eliot and Iris Murdoch. Like the former, she regards novels as an ideal art form because &quot;you can absorb the whole world from them&quot;; influenced by the latter, she tries to portray characters who are entangled and struggling with various ideas; at the same time, following the example of her two predecessors, she admires Utter writes dense, detailed novels that are challenging to read even for her smart, patient fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The difficulty lies in the fact that sentences like this can be seen everywhere: a dense collection of unknown knowledge and the author&#39;s delicate and rigorous subjective feelings; specialized terms in the fields of classics, mythology and art are randomly picked up... ...long sentences contain alternating long and short clauses...familiar words have long-abandoned meanings or obscure meanings.&quot; Yang Xiangrong, the translator of Byatt&#39;s works, once &quot;complained&quot; that the translation of &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; was difficult, But I was impressed, &quot;When I read it for the second time, I gradually fell in love with the complex and regular language style, the unremitting capture of subtleties, and the almost aristocratic style of writing in which the writer never creates simple sentences. Restraint.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/HOQMyggc4ie4BhAyeJxX1TyLYm626qhZpLHfTrPc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;428 &quot; height=&quot;616&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/HOQMyggc4ie4BhAyeJxX1TyLYm626qhZpLHfTrPc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Virgin in the Garden&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1978, &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; was published. Byatt inscribed on the title page - &quot;Dedicated to me&quot; The son of Charles Byatt (1961.7.19-1972.7.22).&quot; &quot;I came up with the idea of ​​​​creating &quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot; around 1961, when my son was born. I suddenly realized that I had experienced a certain period. History.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt set the background of &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; in 1953, when Queen Elizabeth II ascended the throne. In the very short time span from rehearsal, performance to completion of a historical drama, Bo The three children of the Te family have undergone fundamental changes. The eldest daughter Stephanie got married and had a child, the 18-year-old second daughter Frederica lost her virginity, and the youngest son Marcus was deceived and became insane... They all experienced dangerous growth. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the novel, Byatt begins with &quot;National Portrait Gallery: 1968&quot;, &quot;I experienced the early 1950s. I lived in the 1960s, and I don&#39;t regard the 1960s as A time for a revolution, but as a time when I can look back on the history in which I lived... What is personal is not political, although the participants in politics are individuals. Politics is not personal at all.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In 1972, Byatt&#39;s son Charles, who was just over 11 years old, died suddenly in a car accident on his way to school. After losing her beloved son, she experienced landslides and ice cracks in her life. She wrote a sentence at the end of the prologue of the novel. A woman whose son was seriously injured in the collision said, &quot;That woman used to be a good teacher, but not anymore. She used to have many friends, but now she doesn&#39;t have them. She used to have a lovable body, but now she doesn&#39;t. She was scared and angry. Exhausted, I can&#39;t let go for a moment...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/uuSqPK3CD0KxF4AfyCabNroUPI4TaeGozkVUYusl.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/uuSqPK3CD0KxF4AfyCabNroUPI4TaeGozkVUYusl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259393&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still Life&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1985, Byatt published &quot;Still Life&quot;. The scene in the first chapter of the novel is set in obstetrics and gynecology. In the hospital, while waiting for a prenatal check-up, Stephanie witnessed the miscarriage of another woman beside her. The little life ended, &quot;motionless and silent&quot;... Stephanie gave birth successfully, but when she was looking forward to a new life, she was accidentally electrocuted. Death. The English title of the novel &quot;Still Life&quot; is interpreted literally - &quot;still life&quot; - that is, death. In the book, Byatt once lamented through the mouth of a character: &quot;Perhaps, we can also look at still life in this way. The so-called still life painting is synonymous with natural death.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have already conceived it. Stephanie&#39;s death in 1961. I thought I was going to write a series of novels in which I would make that death a central awareness, so that readers would feel the pain of a real death, as you did, rather than having to deal with a real death. A fictional death. Every two or three months I get a letter from a reader saying, how dare you do this to me. I sit down and cry all night long. You know, you have no right to kill in a novel like Real people kill people like that. That&#39;s not fair.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Resisting &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;——What&#39;s the point of surviving one day and another? What kind of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——The lives of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt&#39;s &quot;Female Growth Quartet&quot; which took 30 years to complete has a certain autobiographical color. Among them, the obvious main line is the growth and awakening of the intellectual woman Frederica. This series of novels explores almost all the confusions and issues that women face throughout their lives. &quot;I don&#39;t want to write about little women, but I want to write novels that are liberating to people&#39;s minds.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/23/ehzmAdk2KOaeQaXp0gRWIWnCCMTJlENqAEk9qTLm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 23/ehzmAdk2KOaeQaXp0gRWIWnCCMTJlENqAEk9qTLm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Children&#39;s Book&quot; original English version&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DfygYILTg42wQEqb7uMgNau9wkx9zHeW16kmUs5H.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;605&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DfygYILTg42wQEqb7uMgNau9wkx9zHeW16kmUs5H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259394&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children&#39;s book&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continued After &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; and &quot;Still Life&quot;, Byatt continued to write about Frederica&#39;s various struggles after studying in Cambridge, getting married, and becoming a mother in &quot;The Tower of Babel&quot; in 1996. &quot;People &quot;Always marry with your own yearning for marriage.&quot; After experiencing several domestic violence from her husband, Frederica decided to run away. &quot;The place we longed for and tried our best to beautify may be the place we will escape from.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cOlUEd2YPcSKnURCwtx52nKi4nOPXBWHnLcB3sDE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;556&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cOlUEd2YPcSKnURCwtx52nKi4nOPXBWHnLcB3sDE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Whistling Woman&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the tetralogy finale &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot; (2002) , Byatt continues to tell the story of the lives of free women in the whirlpool of social change. In the 1960s, the emerging television media occupied the forefront of popular culture. The 33-year-old single mother Frederica began to look for new ways to satisfy her intellectual needs. She whistled in the exquisite box of television and became the star of the talk show &quot; The sharp and knowledgeable host of &quot;Through the Looking Glass.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Images of survival and innovation permeate the entire novel &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot;. The work is based on the cultural academic circle dominated by psychoanalytic thought from Cambridge in the 1950s to the 1980s, and involves difficult and complex topics. In the novel&#39;s acknowledgments, Byatt records exchanges with scholars in different fields: snails and genetics, physiology and cognition, the possibilities of television, the ethnology of birds, religious culture, etc. Together with her heroines, she explores new worlds beyond literature and art. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9dAAI9mIPjzGJqN11hUrf64NO8ee2Xg70zTnOaGk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;435&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9dAAI9mIPjzGJqN11hUrf64NO8ee2Xg70zTnOaGk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tower of Babel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I read an article that asked:&#39; Is there no support for rationality? &#39;I guess I&#39;m a rationalist. But I don&#39;t think our description of the world is appropriate.&quot; Byatt once expressed his distaste for astrology, &quot;I think the zodiac represents The most absurd and arbitrary poetic imaginings of mankind... They are not at all - God help us - a ram or a virgin, they are just a series of dots... I don&#39;t understand why humans need these systems, but They just need it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/xgcQwvEkzA0lbpfpVTnRnRSmESBFazHUIXBYJELo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/xgcQwvEkzA0lbpfpVTnRnRSmESBFazHUIXBYJELo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Angels and Insects&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/NTjZvRwzCLL6SQKYbUonukZnTHRRAcsgJCjxxj9x.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/NTjZvRwzCLL6SQKYbUonukZnTHRRAcsgJCjxxj9x.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nightingale Eye&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The novella &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot; published in 1992 (collected together with &quot;The Engagement Angel&quot;) In &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, Byatt tells the story of William, a naturalist who studied ants and butterflies in South America. After returning to England, he married Eugenia, the daughter of a squire, only to discover that his wife was involved in a terrible relationship with her half-brother. In the end, William broke with the decadent aristocratic life and returned to the primitive Amazon forest...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the publication of &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot;, critics praised it one after another. Some say that Byatt, through William, put together the fragments of evidence of true evil. God and science, humans and insects, Amazon and England... Byatt uses her intelligence and imagination to weave everything into this gentle and poetic comedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt once recalled that after the death of her youngest son Charles, she began to pay attention to comedy, &quot;When you are in a lonely and desolate world, those great comedies - Shakespeare or Jane Austen&#39;s Comedy - is strangely becoming more and more important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that interview, she mentioned what happened to the heroine Hermione in Shakespeare&#39;s late comedy &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale&quot;: She was The jealous husband, King Leontes of Sicily, suspected adultery and ordered his death. He survived the catastrophe and was hidden in a sculpture in the cellar. After 16 years, the injustice was overturned and the family was finally reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have spent most of my life writing to resist &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale.&quot; That kind of deception is so bad! It takes away a woman&#39;s most fertile and sexually demanding years. Lock her in a cellar and say it would be nice if she came back as a sculpture, that would be a comfort. It pissed me off.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt admitted that when she was 30, she had I feel scared because &quot;spring comes carelessly, and I will grow old and die&quot;, &quot;But now that I have reached such an age, this fact makes me more gratified: even if I die, spring will continue to come... still There are rocks and trees... As long as we don&#39;t destroy this planet, spring will continue to come; even if we destroy this planet, maybe spring will continue to appear on other planets...&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(References: &quot;The Paris Review·Writer Interview 6&quot;, &quot;Possession&quot;, &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, &quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot;, &quot;Still Life&quot;, &quot;Tower of Babel&quot;, &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot; &quot; &quot;Eye of a Nightingale&quot;, &quot;Matisse Stories&quot;, &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles: Selected Stories&quot;, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对周建琨涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:09:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on November 23 that Zhou Jiankun, former deputy secretary and vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, was suspected of The bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, it was reviewed and prosecuted by the First Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate. Recently, the First Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chongqing Municipal No. 1 Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ notified the defendant Zhou Jiankun of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Zhou Jiankun, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecution charged: The defendant Zhou Jiankun used his position as deputy secretary, mayor and municipal party committee secretary of Duyun Municipal, Guizhou Province, deputy director of the Economic and Information Technology Commission of Guizhou Province, deputy secretary-general of the Guizhou Provincial People&#39;s Government, deputy secretary of the municipal party committee and municipal committee of Anshun, Guizhou Province Mayor, Secretary of the Municipal Party Committee, Secretary of the Bijie Municipal Party Committee of Guizhou Province, member of the Guizhou Provincial Political Consultative Conference Party Group, Deputy Secretary of the Party Group, Vice Chairman, etc., seeking benefits for others and illegally accepting property from others, with a particularly huge amount , he should be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes according to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>