<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[常州通报“企业家约谈后坠楼身亡”事件：正核查案件办理情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260490]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 09:54:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it has been reported online that Changzhou Holley Chairman Cheng Yong fell to his death after being interviewed, which has attracted public attention . On the evening of November 12, Changzhou Radio and Television Station’s WeChat public account “Zhongwu.com” issued a briefing on the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c09c94ce96d15a229789fd7f86242d29.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1448&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c09c94ce96d15a229789fd7f86242d29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258050&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the legal representative of Changzhou Huali Hydraulic Lubricating Equipment Co., Ltd. fell to his death after being interviewed. The Changzhou Municipal Party Committee and Government attach great importance to it and are organizing relevant departments to carry out investigations and disciplinary inspections in accordance with the law. The supervisory authorities are conducting in-depth verification of the handling of relevant cases, and adhere to the principles of seeking truth from facts and handling them conscientiously in accordance with rules, disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to previous reports from Nanduwan Financial Society, at noon on November 11, Changzhou Huali Hydraulic Lubrication Equipment Co., Ltd. (referred to as &quot;Changzhou Holi&quot;) posted on the official WeChat public account that at 4 o&#39;clock in the morning that day At 36 minutes, the company chairman Cheng Yong jumped to his death. On the afternoon of the 11th, the relevant article was deleted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to an article published on Changzhou Holley’s official WeChat public account, the suicide note was signed at 0:24 a.m. on the 11th. At 4:36, Chengyong posted the last message in his life before jumping off the building. Screenshots show that jumping off the building was related to his recent interview with the Changzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon of the same day, Changzhou Holley staff confirmed the news of Cheng Yong’s death to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News, and said that the above-mentioned article was indeed officially released by the company, and the contents were the true expression of the company’s intentions. The person in charge of the company is handling related matters and does not have any more information at the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, staff from the Propaganda Department of the Changzhou Municipal Party Committee also told reporters from Nanduwan Financial Society that they are currently understanding the situation and may issue a notice on the matter in the future. Reporters from Nanduwan Financial News repeatedly called the Changzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and the Changzhou Tianning District Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, but there was no reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆市政府原党组成员、副市长熊雪严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260492]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 10:17:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission investigated Xiong Xue, a former member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Mayor of the Chongqing Municipal Government. Serious violations of discipline and law were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Xiong Xue lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original intention and mission, had a weak political consciousness, disagreed with the Party Central Committee on major principles issues, engaged in &quot;seven things&quot;, formed cliques, and had a negative view of political achievements. Distortion, engaging in formalism, making false reports, resisting organizational review, and engaging in superstitious activities; violating the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepting banquets and services that may affect the fair execution of official duties; being disloyal and dishonest to the party, and not responding to organizational interviews and inquiries Explain the problem truthfully and conceal personal matters; accept gifts and gifts in violation of regulations, and obtain large returns through private loans; perform duties incorrectly; have a bad family tradition and ignore your spouse; be greedy, corrupt, and associate with unscrupulous businessmen Working together with others, they transformed public power into a tool for personal gain, engaged in power-for-money transactions, used their position to benefit others in terms of project contracting, land approval, etc., and illegally accepted huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiong Xue seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of bribery crime, and did not restrain himself after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Hands, serious nature, bad influence, should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Xiong Xue from the party; The treatment he enjoys shall be canceled in accordance with regulations; his illegal gains shall be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues shall be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved shall be transferred together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[常识的落脚地丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260476]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/0xtfslDmpgxIvEKPX7E3ucKcQTiHdKpooVdd1BPN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0xtfslDmpgxIvEKPX7E3ucKcQTiHdKpo oVdd1BPN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2023, girls confided and comforted each other on the playground of Ugly Duckling Middle School &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Related reports For details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/259838&quot; title=&quot;The Growth of the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;: Exploration and Thoughts on Preventing and Treating Teenage Depression in a School&quot;>;The Growth of the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;: 1 Exploration and reflections on the prevention and treatment of adolescent depression in one school&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is impossible for one school to cure adolescent depression.” A reader left a message after reading this magazine’s report on Ugly Duckling Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True. This was not Zhan Danian’s original intention when he founded this school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; originally accepted so-called &quot;problem children&quot; that ordinary schools and families were unable to take care of. Zhan Danian discovered that the rate of depression among students has increased in recent years and was determined to help them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, he hopes to use the forum to arouse more people&#39;s attention to the phenomenon of teenage depression. A month ago, I heard Zhan Danian talk about this topic for the first time on the phone. I admired this middle-aged educator for his sense of social responsibility - but also secretly thought: a private school aimed at helping &quot;problem students&quot; , do you have enough professionalism and experience to share (on dealing with student depression)? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three or four days I went to Yiliang, my doubts were solved bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on the day we arrived at the school, a small book-sized window at the gate was opened, revealing the smiling faces of several children: Auntie, we will ask someone to open the door for you. After entering the door, Zhan Danian was standing by the playground. When they saw me, they started introducing me directly from the teaching building. When he walked into the psychology room, several children greeted him with a smile, &quot;Zhan Zhan, do you still remember me?&quot; In the painting room inside, two boys were quietly drawing mandalas without raising their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During those days of &quot;ugly duckling&quot;, students were all at ease wherever they went. Except for military training and physical education classes, which require gathering on time, at other times, these children cannot see the tension of being disciplined, the exhaustion after excessive homework, and social numbness. It was the &quot;Class Culture Week&quot; and there were many children drawing in the stairwells and dormitories during class. During the interview, looking at their relaxed expressions as they chatted easily, and greedily taking a few deep breaths of the warm air on the mountain, I really felt: This is a normal campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you get closer to these children, you will find that many of them are &quot;ridden with holes.&quot; A colleague read the manuscript and said, &quot;Today&#39;s children, aged fourteen or fifteen, have so many things on their minds...&quot; In fact, every child has an interesting soul. &quot;Things on the Heart&quot; are related to their tortuous experiences and are also their normal reactions to this weird world. It would be strange if all the excitement, curiosity, and attempts are constantly broken, misinterpreted, and &quot;formatted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to my doubts at the beginning of the interview. Xu Kaiwen, a Ph.D. in clinical psychology at Peking University, followed up on 10 families who lost their only child during the fifth anniversary of the Wenchuan earthquake. He found that families that recovered well from the trauma had “improved living conditions and localized emotional regulation, like playing mahjong. This kind of down-to-earth social support system may be more effective than psychological counseling.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is no different for teenagers. In addition to children with symptoms of severe depression who should be treated through medical means, most teenagers need nothing more than understanding and listening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plenty of sunshine, regular physical exercise, teaching that is not aimed at cramming or exam-taking, time for daze, opportunities to express without fear, and equality between teachers and students. Whether it&#39;s a teacher, a classmate or a parent, there is always someone who understands you. When you feel down, use him as your tree hole or &quot;handrail&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These should be the growth atmosphere that every school-age child and teenager has the right to enjoy. Now it has become a luxury and even consensus cannot be reached. Rather than visiting the Ugly Duckling Middle School in search of a cure for children’s depression, it would be better to see how a shielded educational common sense is put into practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before publishing this article, Zhan Danian received another WeChat message from the parent of a first-year high school student. The latter told him that another student in his child’s school chose to leave in a decisive way. &quot;As parents, we are all frightened.&quot; This parent&#39;s child was also diagnosed with severe depression through a scale when he was in seventh grade. The child&#39;s parents have been committed to changing their relationship with their child. The family atmosphere is very good now. &quot;But we are in a county, and we are very scared when such a situation occurs. How should we accompany our children?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, they are not alone. After the forum, in addition to the WeChat group of 500 participants who continued to share various mutual aid information, a new WeChat group was added, and everyone discussed establishing an alliance to prevent and treat youth depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We need to look for technologies and methods, hoping that the group will get better and better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马伯庸回应拒签盗版书：精神产品生产者的声誉有多重要？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260486]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some netizens posted that they saw this scene at the Nanjing offline meeting of writer Ma Boyong: An uncle asked a writer to sign a book, but &quot;he was scolded by the staff&quot; that the book was pirated. &quot;Anyone with a discerning eye could see his embarrassment.&quot; This netizen believed that the staff were &quot;arrogant&quot; and that the writer &quot;didn&#39;t do anything to support the staff&quot;, &quot;made me feel like I was about to lose the house&quot;, &quot;very disappointed&quot; and &quot;held hundreds of book signings a year&quot; In a writer I see only his substance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen expressed the battle between reason and emotion. On the one hand: understanding that genuine editions protect the rights of writers. On the other hand, he said: Just like Teacher Yu Hua said, &quot;My books should be pirated.&quot; He is not supporting piracy, but he really hopes that at that moment he can stand up to protect a reader&#39;s love for him; the more he thinks about it, the more sad he becomes. , the more I admire Teacher Yu Hua. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Ma Boyong himself responded: I really can’t sign pirated books. After all, I haven’t reached the level of Teacher Yu Hua. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident is undoubtedly a storm in a tea cup, but there is indeed something to interpret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it is normal for different writers to have different views on their books being pirated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The occurrence of piracy is often a reflection of &quot;book sales&quot; and &quot;popular works&quot;. In this sense, piracy is a writer&#39;s medal. It can even be said: How can one be called a &quot;writer&quot; if he has never been pirated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, writer Yu Hua’s words are contextual and cannot be understood as support and endorsement of piracy. He said this on at least two public occasions. Once he said: &quot;I never fight against piracy. There is mainly such a poor consumer group. They also want to read, so they buy a few cheap pirated books... If this problem is not solved, my books will be pirated. It should be&quot;; another said: &quot;It is right that my book should be pirated, because at least it is better than food safety. You solve the food safety problem and then solve the piracy problem.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time Yu Hua said this, the focus was not on piracy, but on a specific social issue. The first time was &quot;poor consumer groups&quot; and the second time was &quot;food safety.&quot; In fact, if the losses caused by piracy are not huge but the cost of settlement is high, expressing your attitude and gaining reputation in this way is also the right choice. After all, a good reputation is a very important asset for a producer of spiritual products. Moreover, he believes that the &quot;piracy problem&quot; needs to be solved, and does not believe that &quot;piracy is justified&quot; or &quot;piracy is justified.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s understandable even if the author himself hates his books being pirated. Pirated copies are far cheaper than genuine copies. On the one hand, this allows people who cannot afford genuine copies to afford them and satisfy their intellectual and spiritual needs. On the other hand, it also makes some readers who would otherwise buy genuine copies buy pirated copies instead. Piracy with typos has long been a thing of the past. Today’s authentic photocopies, electronic versions, or electronic print versions have almost no difference in reading experience from the original version. This will affect the sales of the original version and harm the interests of publishers and authors. There are even some sales channels that mix genuine copies with pirated copies, and the latter is more profitable. Many readers spend the price of genuine copies to buy pirated copies. This is essentially a form of fraud, and it also infringes upon those who were kept in the dark. Reader Rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, on this basis, how to clarify the right and wrong of this incident? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For an extremely successful best-selling author like Ma Boyong, he has no problem with being averse to piracy. In his response, he said that he felt sorry for the readers who unknowingly bought pirated copies. In the past, he would spend his own money to buy more than a dozen books to keep. If he found out that the readers had pirated copies, he would give them a genuine copy, but later the pirated copies were really It is so rampant that sometimes nearly 1/3 of the books brought by authors on site are pirated copies. It was embarrassing and burdensome, so I changed the method and set up on-site genuine sales. Readers who accidentally bought a pirated copy can buy a new one. &quot;You don&#39;t have to queue up again, just come to me to sign it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Readers who spend time and money to get autographs from authors should do so because they particularly like the author and his works, and generally do not intentionally buy pirated books. Therefore, most of the readers who brought pirated books thought they were cheated by the channels and bought pirated copies with genuine money. Therefore, both arrangements before and after are decent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the on-site staff really &quot;scolded&quot; the uncle who signed the pirated book, then the only thing worth improving is the attitude issue. This type of signing event is usually organized by publishing houses. It is possible that the staff of the publishing house will be angry when they see such a high proportion of pirated books and the interests of the publishing house being infringed upon. In this sense, even if Ma Boyong is particularly generous, it is inappropriate to accept pirated books and sign them all, because this is generosity to others and detrimental to the interests of the publishing house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, how do you view writers as producers of spiritual products and their pursuit of material interests? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A gentleman loves money and gets it in a wise way. In theory, this principle applies to any profession, but producers of spiritual products are indeed very different from producers of material products, and reputation and reputation are much more important. Readers as consumers have two special psychological expectations for the former. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, especially for an author who is a spiritual mentor, readers will expect him to conform to the image of a wise man or a saint: the best image is to be immortal, with a transcendent and elegant air, and in moral terms You are a lot higher than the world, at least you can&#39;t show your love for money or greed for material benefits, because if you are as &quot;tacky&quot; as me, what else do you have that I can admire and look up to? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Boyong’s response obviously understood the reader’s psychology. He did not explain why he disliked piracy, nor did he clarify whether there was any “scolding”. He only said that “it is inevitable to be negligent in doing things, and there will always be mistakes.” A satisfactory place&quot;, and spend a lot of space on empathizing with the reader, telling how he enjoys the interaction with the reader, &quot;treating the reader as a friend&quot;, and demonstrating that he is not materialistic. This is an effective way to protect his reputation. Act of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, for producers of spiritual products, readers will expect their behavior to be consistent with the values ​​expressed in books or in public. If a writer promotes a high moral standard or expresses a certain value tendency in a book, but fails to achieve it or does not do it consistently in practice, or is perceived as such by readers, then the reader may turn from love to hate, or from fans to fans. black. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen said, &quot;The writer who likes little people the most and is good at portraying little people has also become a big shot after becoming famous.&quot; &quot;I bought an umbrella on the road, but my heart was already wet.&quot; He knows the truth of &quot;piracy is wrong&quot;, but whether it is true love no longer or misunderstanding or wrong love, this feeling is extremely real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[五星评分打底的宣传，就这？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260484]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;If you are a director and the screenwriter writes How would you shoot a rape scene? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Should we use a large aperture to focus on the victim&#39;s painful face and the perpetrator&#39;s twisted body, or should we use a blurred lens to express violence with a line of blood, a cry of pain, and an angry and struggling hand? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you were a director, how would you show the pain of a single mother who lost her only daughter and did not hesitate to die with her enemies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Should I express my mother’s feelings without any elaboration and use a few sensational lines and music, or should I express my anger at my daughter’s stigmatization, my despair at the distorted truth, and my sudden uncertainty about my future life? Hopelessly complicated mentality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you think about these two questions for a moment, you can understand the problem of the new film &quot;Rescuing Suspect&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/76d97e67a4f527fd1014fe0ec6ed7492.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/76d97e67a4f527fd1014fe0ec6ed7492.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This film is produced by Directed by Zhang Yimou&#39;s daughter Zhang Mo, it is a remake of the Korean movie &quot;Seven Days&quot;. The original work was not a good work, and the remake failed to make the story interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movie is about a gold medal lawyer played by Zhang Xiaofei. After her daughter is kidnapped, she receives a mysterious phone call asking her to defend a criminal suspect. If she wins, her daughter will live, and if she loses, she will be killed. In order to save her daughter, she had no choice but to get involved, check the suspect&#39;s information, explore the life of the deceased woman, and then the entire case came to light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that the choice of this subject was driven by female directors aiming at female stories. It’s a pity that we don’t see tenderness and empathy for female characters in the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, the intertwining of light and dark aspects of human nature and the gaps between love and hate in interpersonal relationships are where the tension of the story lies, but in this film, these are all ignored. The director likes to focus the camera on the emotional reactions of the characters, making them gasp, cry, anxious, have tears in their eyes, or have gloomy eyes. They like to use slow motion to show the somatic characteristics of people in pain. However, as for the undercurrents beneath these waves, But he didn&#39;t care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c8e979e942e077ea8429669a3b1036ae.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c8e979e942e077ea8429669a3b1036ae.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years There are a large number of female creators who constantly surprise us, such as Phoebe Waller-Bridge in &quot;Fleabag&quot; and Shao Yihui in &quot;The Myth of Love&quot;. They are all good at listening to the footsteps of their characters. Next, they bring their insight into the character&#39;s heart, their subtle description of desire, and their empathy for pain and separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These perspectives are subtle and gentle, illuminating the hearts of the audience. Therefore, I am particularly looking forward to a female director remaking this story. Coupled with the constant positive reviews from the pre-release publicity, I expect her to be able to show the grief and indignation of a mother who is stunned, painful, resentful, regretful, and helpless, and finally goes to despair. This is a tragedy taking shape, and it also allows the audience to step on the edge of the protagonist&#39;s heart and resonate with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, the film did not record the footsteps of the tragedy. Without the sound of footsteps, the movie lacks the power to evoke emotions and thinking, just like a small cool drama mass-produced on a short video platform. However, it is also doubtful whether this film can really achieve the purpose of pleasing the audience like these low-cost, fast-produced dramas, because its pace is slow, and the twists are cliched and lack logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/fc2bc6cfbeff05c167b9868cf15b736e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;492&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/fc2bc6cfbeff05c167b9868cf15b736e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this The narrative completion that only stays at the visual excitement and superficial twists is almost a kind of surrender by the director: I can&#39;t understand the characters, I can&#39;t figure out the story, this is the only way I can go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know whether this is the director’s lack of confidence in his own expressive ability, or his habit of shooting movies as short videos: plots that do not ask for logic, emotions that are not patiently laid out, all the effort is spent on Play with various camera moves and reversals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have heard more than one person complain that movies in recent years, including Hollywood blockbusters, have become more and more short videos. There is a group of people who no longer want to film real stories, abandon the core &quot;people&quot; of the story, and choose to fill the audience&#39;s stomach with potato chips, popcorn and Coke. Therefore, popular hot words, amplified emotions, and reversal techniques are their operating formulas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/8cc113799c717260831859c21a4d1fb7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;489&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/8cc113799c717260831859c21a4d1fb7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trend There are of course practical factors behind it. For example, viewers who are anxious about survival have reduced mental strength, no longer have the ability to empathize with others, and only desire quick emotional satisfaction. The creators followed suit, and film and television fast-moving consumer goods became very popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, responsible creators will still try to pull the tired audience out of the small world and tell them that Coca-Cola potato chips cannot provide real nutrition, and they will ultimately not be able to fill the empty hearts of adults. We need to go into the broader story and identify the emotional antidote that suits us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing this, I originally wanted to avoid discussing the family background of the director of this film, but when I thought about it, it had close to 10% of the film schedule at the beginning of its release, the promotion of a five-star rating, and Hui Yinghong, Actors like Zhang Xiaofei can&#39;t help but think of the words of supermodel Victoria Ceretti against Depp&#39;s daughter:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Please don&#39;t compare yourself to me. I don&#39;t have a rich father. We Ordinary girls in this industry have to use their own efforts to gain everyone&#39;s respect. It doesn&#39;t mean that you can succeed by lying on the sofa of a mansion in Malibu.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being born in Rome is a blessing, not a mistake. . But after enjoying resources that most outstanding creators cannot enjoy, only handing in such an answer sheet will inevitably make people feel complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专家解答：得了支原体肺炎需要输液、“洗肺”吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260480]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, mycoplasma pneumonia in children has attracted widespread attention. When is a child contagious? Do I need infusion or &quot;lung washing&quot;? Worried about whether the hospital can be self-administered due to the large number of people in the hospital? On the occasion of World Pneumonia Day on November 12, the reporter interviewed relevant medical experts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After being infected with Mycoplasma pneumoniae, there is an incubation period of several days before the onset of fever, at which time the patient is contagious to a certain extent.” Zhou Wei, deputy chief physician of pediatrics at Peking University Third Hospital, said that wearing a mask can It can prevent infection to a certain extent, but it is not realistic for children to wear masks strictly and regularly. Going less often to crowded closed public places, ventilating the house frequently, regularly cleaning and disinfecting schools, and increasing outdoor activities are all helpful in preventing infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is infusion the best treatment for mycoplasma pneumonia? Zhou Wei said that some parents believe that intravenous infusion is better than oral treatment, but in fact there is no such conclusion. Treatment should be selected based on the child&#39;s condition. Children with severe pneumonia can choose intravenous infusion, while most children with mild illness can be treated with oral medications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the &quot;lung washing&quot; operation that parents are worried about, Zhou Wei said, &quot;This year, more children with mycoplasma pneumonia are indeed undergoing lung lavage treatment. Lung lavage has strict operating indications, such as patients with If the child develops atelectasis, local consolidation, or even very serious inflammatory reactions such as necrosis and sputum plug formation, lung lavage may need to be performed under a bronchoscope to unblock the airway, and it can also be seen under the microscope. To the extent of lung disease.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to mycoplasma, bacteria and viruses can also cause pneumonia. Ye Huan, director of the Respiratory Department of Beijing Chest Hospital, reminded that pneumonia patients often have typical symptoms such as fever, cough, and difficulty breathing, and young children and the elderly should pay special attention to precautions. It is recommended that people over 65 years old and children get the pneumonia vaccine. Although there is currently no vaccine against Mycoplasma pneumoniae, the pneumonia vaccine can prevent a variety of pneumococci. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts remind that for pneumonia caused by different pathogens, the medication choices are also different. For example, for mycoplasma pneumonia, penicillin and cephalosporin antibiotics are ineffective, and macrolide antibiotics are the most commonly used. Patients who are suspected of being infected with pneumonia should seek medical treatment in a timely manner and receive targeted treatment after diagnosis, and avoid blind medication such as &quot;self-administration of antibiotics&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为何总有体育馆塌顶：暴雪之下掩藏多少行业沉疴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260478]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 20:27:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 7, 2023, Yuecheng Stadium after the roof collapsed. Xinhua News Agency reporter Photo by Chen Yichen&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/17c0044e7c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/17c0044e7c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258044&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;On November 7, 2023, Yuecheng Stadium after the roof collapsed. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Chen Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within more than a hundred days, two stadium roof collapse accidents occurred in Qiqihar City and Jiamusi City, Heilongjiang Province, killing 11 and 3 people respectively, including 13 minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 23, 2023, the night of the Qiqihar accident, Heilongjiang quickly organized and carried out safety inspections of various schools and public welfare sports venues. The main leaders of Jiamusi Huanan County went to Yuecheng Gymnasium the next day Observe on the spot. 105 days later, on November 6, Jiamusi ushered in the first snow before winter. In the gymnasium where the leaders had implemented safety production requirements, tragedy happened again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are not the only two cases of large-span roof collapse. Southern Weekend reporters found that there have been many steel structure roof collapse accidents in recent years: In April 2022, the roof of a swimming pool collapsed in Zhengzhou, Henan, causing 3 deaths and 9 injuries; in November 2021, the light steel structure roof of a project in Jinhua, Zhejiang collapsed, causing 6 deaths and 6 injuries; in March 2021, a grid roof collapsed at a construction site in Qingdao, Shandong, causing 1 death and 7 injuries; in May 2019, the roof of a steel structure building collapsed in Baise, Guangxi, causing 6 deaths and 87 injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not unique to China. Wang Luchuan (pseudonym), an expert in engineering accident research and former chief engineer of Beijing Urban Construction Group, told Southern Weekend reporters that roof collapse accidents of large-span structures are a common problem in buildings around the world. According to the cases he knows, stadium collapses have occurred in France, the United States, and Canada. ACCIDENT. “Currently there are relatively few cases of stadium collapse in China.” Wang Luchuan emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many stadium roof collapse accidents point to the design form of fragile long-span steel structures. How did it change from a popular architectural style to the &quot;Sword of Damocles&quot; hanging above people&#39;s heads? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reduce costs, reduce loads&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2023, netizens focused their attention on the roof of the Jiamusi stadium that collapsed just five years after it was built. According to Xinhua News Agency, The roof structure of the stadium is an H-shaped variable-section steel beam structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yonggang, chief engineer of Chengdu Southeast Steel Structure Co., Ltd., has 19 years of relevant experience. He told Southern Weekend reporters that this structure is called a portal steel frame structure in the industry, that is, doors made of H-shaped steel The structure can form a span of 20 to 30 meters, so there is no need to set up many columns. It is usually used in the design of small gymnasiums and factory buildings. &quot;The gymnasium in Jiamusi covers an area of ​​675 square meters, and the portal structure still matches the overall structure.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This structure itself has no problems, it is simple and simple, and it is a relatively mature structural system.” Liu Yonggang explained that the steel structure has good toughness and high strength, and it can be built like building blocks. It can be built quickly and achieve good architectural effects. &quot;It is excellent in itself, but if it is not used properly, problems will occur.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yonggang introduced that the first step to make good use of steel structures is design, and the first step in design is selection. There are many structural forms that can meet the long-span function, such as portal structure, grid structure, truss structure, etc. Among them, the portal steel frame structure uses the least amount of steel, and its processing and installation technology is relatively simple, so it is also one of these three structures. The cheapest among the structures. The stadium that collapsed in Jiamusi this time was a portal structure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the type is selected, the next step is to calculate the load. Different load values ​​determine the amount of steel used and the compressive resistance of the building. In the Northeast region, in addition to the conventional wind loads, live loads, seismic loads, dust loads, etc. that need to be considered, the building design codes have additional provisions for the frequent heavy snow weather, that is, increasing the snow load. At the same time, in order to make it easier for snow to slide down, the roof slope is usually designed to be larger, but the increase in slope also means an increase in the cost. Photos of the interior of the Jiamusi Yuecheng Gymnasium circulated online show that the roof supported by H-shaped steel beams has a smaller slope, which means that the roof is easier to accumulate snow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether a building is designed safely is related to the designer’s personal expertise and experience, as well as the owner’s budget and requirements. Liu Yonggang introduced that designers from large design institutes will be more professionally persistent. For example, if they want to design a satisfactory and strong building, they will superimpose and evaluate all unfavorable factors, and then the designed plan will be relatively conservative, and the amount of steel used will naturally be higher. Increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For some owners who pursue maximizing profits and repaying their capital as soon as possible, &quot;obedient&quot; small design institutes are their first choice. &quot;Some owners are looking for costs. They will say, save me a little more, reduce the amount of steel used, and laymen will guide experts. Some small design institutes also want to survive, so they will try to figure out the load and meet the specifications. The limit.&quot; Liu Yonggang said. Yuecheng Gymnasium was designed by Jiamusi Architectural Design Institute. Liu Yonggang said that this design institute is a relatively small design institute. “It’s just that the design institute is small and it is not clear whether the design experience is sufficient.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The redundancy of this kind of stadium building design is too low. If you pile something on it, it will collapse. If you spend 100 yuan to keep it from collapsing, then you are willing to spend 101 Yuan, or are you willing to spend 200 Yuan?&quot; Wang Luchuan said frankly that he could understand, &quot;It is unlikely that the redundancy of such a long-span roof will be particularly high, so the cost will be too high. Like a bridge, an additional 10 % redundancy may increase the cost by 50%. But it cannot be given too low. It is really unjustifiable if it collapses in 5 years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 7, 2023, the person in charge of Yuecheng Sports Club and others have been controlled by the police. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Chen Yichen&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f18e03de13.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f18e03de13.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258045&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 11 On March 7, the person in charge of Yuecheng Sports Club and others were controlled by the police. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Chen Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“People don’t know goods, money knows goods”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, even having a perfect design plan does not guarantee the safety of the building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Ruoqiang, a professor at the School of Civil Engineering of Southeast University, wondered why a gymnasium that had just been built five years ago collapsed. &quot;The first five years are the best period for the house. It is impossible not to consider the snow load when designing. But if it collapses at this time, the problem is still quite big.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters that if there are no problems with the design drawings, then Is the construction quality strictly controlled: &quot;For example, does the purchased steel meet the strength requirements, is the construction section strictly in accordance with the drawing requirements, and is the weld quality qualified?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the industry situation, in the steel components Quality risks may also exist in the processing and manufacturing process. Liu Yonggang introduced that some small processing plants only have two or three machines and can invest hundreds of thousands of yuan to process, but they often do not have standardized management structures, quality management systems and safety production systems to control product quality. &quot;For example, after the factory buys the steel plate from the steel factory, it cuts it into pieces with a flame, and then welds it to form each steel component. During processing, if the hole is punched out of place, it needs to be cut larger with a flame. This will damage the steel and shorten its original service life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regular enterprises have a complete management system. Liu Yonggang took his own company as an example, &quot;When we buy steel plates, we need to detect and inspect them. After they are processed into steel components, we have to inspect them ourselves and ask a third party to inspect them before they can leave the factory.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On-site installation also requires attention to quality control. During the installation process, if the operation is not standardized, it will also cause quality defects and the designed service life will not be reached. &quot;Installation is equivalent to the final assembly of a car, which means bringing the processed steel components to the site for installation. It is best to have professionals do professional work.&quot; Liu Yonggang said that some irregular construction units bring a group of migrant workers to work, &quot; I was still farming yesterday, and I will install the steel structure tomorrow. If the accuracy of one place is not adjusted well, I will start the next step of installation, and it will be cut again and again, and errors will accumulate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Optimization&quot; is also a common problem during the construction process. Feng Ruoqiang said that in order to make more money, a construction unit that won the bid &quot;optimized&quot; the design height of the steel beam from 600 mm to 400 mm and the wall thickness of the steel beam from 20 mm to 12 mm during construction. In order to save labor in the welding process, low-level welders are used to replace good welders with high wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yonggang believes that winning bids at low prices is the direct cause of the &quot;optimization&quot; trend in the industry. He found that the bidding prices of large companies are about 20% higher than that of small companies, mainly reflected in management costs, raw material costs and installation costs. “Our industry association also makes suggestions to the general contractor and the government, hoping that the price will not be lowered again and again. If the price is too low, if a small company does it, there will be problems such as &#39;optimization&#39;, cutting corners, etc., and ultimately it will be &#39;profitable&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is difficult to change. &quot;The difficulty now is still money. In order to put into production as soon as possible, the owner requires you to rush for work hours and save costs. Including government investment, it is also reducing costs. As long as you don&#39;t choose the cheap one, you have made a mistake. People don&#39;t know the goods. , money knows the goods.&quot; Liu Yonggang sighed with emotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Don&#39;t kill yourself&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sports venues designed and constructed in accordance with national standards cannot &quot;sit back and relax.&quot; In the specific use stage, safety mainly depends on the owner&#39;s consciousness, and there are no national mandatory standards. &quot;If a sports venue cannot be used correctly, it is prone to problems. During use, do not use it indiscriminately. People cannot go on the roof but you have to go up. There are no other loads on the roof but some additional loads are added.&quot; Many interviewed experts told Southern Weekend reporters The collapse of Qiqihar No. 34 Middle School Gymnasium was caused by more human factors. Its roof structure was called a bolted ball grid structure. Due to the illegal stacking of water-absorbing perlite, the load was excessive and suddenly collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Qiqihar Stadium is a typical example of improper use.” Feng Ruoqiang believes that during the blizzard weather when the Yuecheng Stadium collapsed, “As an operator, you either close the stadium or pay extra attention. During the use phase Operators must have sufficient safety awareness, which is very important.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among building materials such as concrete, steel structures, and aluminum alloys, steel structures have a fatal weakness, which is its corrosion problem. It is more susceptible to oxidation. After oxidation, the performance of the material will be greatly reduced. Many collapse accidents are caused by corrosion of steel structures. Therefore, the maintenance of steel structure houses is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The steel structures we build need to be repainted every 10 to 15 years, and the bolts must be checked to see if they have fallen off. We will recommend that owners perform annual maintenance, or conduct major inspections every few years, and deal with problems as soon as possible if they are found. Liu Yonggang said, but now many steel structure buildings are difficult to maintain after they are repaired. &quot;Either it is covered by the suspended ceiling or wrapped in the wall, making it impossible to repair some places. If a rod is bent, it is difficult to notice. Some rods are force-bearing rods. If they are suddenly broken, the force will be distributed If the other members cannot bear it, they will suddenly collapse.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Ruoqiang visited many gymnasiums in a city in East China. Out of professional habit, he noticed that the steel structure roofs of some swimming pools were corroded. It&#39;s amazing, the paint is peeling off, but no one pays attention to this problem. Some poorly maintained badminton courts install heavy chandeliers and suspended ceilings on the roof for the convenience of playing, which will make the venue unsafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an ordinary person, how can we judge whether the steel structure gymnasium we are in is safe? Liu Yonggang introduced the key points of observation: &quot;We mainly look at a few places, first to see how it transmits force. For example, the roof receives the load, and the roof transmits the force to the beams, the beams to the columns, and the columns to the supports and embedded parts. Etc. Therefore, we look at it from the other side, whether the column bolts have fallen off, whether the column has deformed, whether the column elevation has settled, and looking further up, whether the supports between beams have fallen off, whether the beams have deformed, whether the purlins have Is there any bend?” However, when these problems can be seen with the naked eye, it means there is an imminent safety risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the collapse of the Qiqihar Stadium, Heilongjiang requested a comprehensive investigation of public welfare sports venues in the province; after the Jiamusi accident, the local government once again conducted a thorough investigation of long-span spatial structures including gymnasiums, requiring &quot;no discounts, Leave no blind spots and don’t go through the motions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Ruoqiang believes that regular inspections by government departments are still necessary, but a solid inspection team must be formed. He suggested that the government could invite professionals in architecture and structure to &quot;focus on the inspection targets. First, check the stadiums with longer service life. If rust is found, apply anti-corrosion and anti-rust paint. Secondly, check the stadiums with lower design standards.&quot; Small and medium-sized gymnasiums”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our construction in the past 20 to 30 years has been a bit too fast. Many times everyone is rushing for work. After the accident, we were also discussing that many steel structures have been repaired for more than 30 years. , especially some venues built in the early stage, should be maintained or demolished.&quot; Liu Yonggang said, &quot;The dividend period of our industry has also passed. In the remaining time, we need to think carefully about the development of this industry, and don&#39;t kill ourselves. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot; >;(Hui Ze also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[没点中仇家的死穴，却点到观众的笑穴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260444]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&quot;Acupoint Storm&quot; is the most recent comedy I have seen The most effective episode. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist of the story, Numakura Koichi (played by Ryuhei Matsuda), was a child when his father owed a huge debt and disappeared, leaving him and his mother to depend on each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gangster leader who keeps collecting debts keeps an eye on my mother and will punch and kick him when he is unhappy. In order to prevent her son from being beaten all the time, her mother agreed to fly away with the underworld leader, leaving him and his elderly grandmother to depend on each other. But my grandma also passed away not long after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b079fe836d8c04e3c58ab8866954c5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/b079fe836d8c04e3c58ab8866954c5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Left from mother From the day he wrote the note and left, Numakura Koichi secretly made up his mind to seek revenge from the underworld leader one day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to realize his revenge plan, he picked up the comic book &quot;Fist of the North Star&quot; at home and studied and practiced diligently, just because the protagonist in the comic knew a unique skill of tapping acupuncture points to cause death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Numakura Takashi studied this skill day and night, and finally succeeded ten years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/534d93e3a2ec461d120d409d1ebfb37a.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;591&quot; height= &quot;313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/534d93e3a2ec461d120d409d1ebfb37a.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He found the underworld The boss, just hit him with acupuncture points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the leader not only escaped unscathed, but also asked the younger brother next to him to beat him half to death, while beating him and cursing &quot;Where did you come from?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eea3597e823ed4b614c62fbea496c506.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/eea3597e823ed4b614c62fbea496c506.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1421919e0da17db59191276939089fa4.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1421919e0da17db59191276939089fa4.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257963&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Numakura Koichi suddenly realized: It turns out that comics do not depict the human body He gave an accurate description of the acupuncture points, which led to him not completing his revenge plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, he determined to delve into more professional acupoint knowledge, and at the same time learned from others&#39; strengths, integrating Chinese acupuncture points, Thai massage, finger techniques, etc., and finally became a nationally awarded qualification certificate through hard study. masseur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Killing for revenge and growing up to be a professional masseur is the first layer of reversal in &quot;The Storm in the Acupoint&quot; and also the tone of its storytelling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it has the chubby and passionate style of a Japanese drama, and talks serious nonsense, it can make you want to watch it. As the audience said, &quot;This plot is like a wild horse running wild, unable to find the direction to go in the next second.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/11/dc978e304182538322770b4844d86e7c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/11/dc978e304182538322770b4844d86e7c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257962&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, after finally getting an opportunity for the underworld leader to ask for a massage, Numakura Koichi was about to execute the acupuncture revenge plan, but unexpectedly It was discovered that the other party had a spinal tumor, and it was still in an advanced stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to common sense, you should be happy to learn that your enemy is about to die. But Numakura Koichi was in great pain, because in the revenge plan he had planned as a child, the leader could only be considered complete if he died in his hands. Any other way of death could not eliminate Numakura Koichi&#39;s heart. hate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, the planned revenge plan turned into a rescue plan in an instant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/bd85aa9868d5d13eff856364568d854f.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/bd85aa9868d5d13eff856364568d854f.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it The leader&#39;s spinal tumor was about to be cured and he could immediately carry out his revenge plan. However, the leader was suddenly hit by a car accident and was knocked face down to the ground, sliding for several meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a last resort, Numakura Koichi took action again and pulled him back from the gate of hell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one was killed, no revenge was taken, but his life was saved several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/f27646daa8eb00976e979c113228e36b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;591&quot; height= &quot;329&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/f27646daa8eb00976e979c113228e36b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of reliance Delays and contrasts, as well as the narrative method of constantly dissolving the plot of revenge, are the basic operations of &quot;The Storm in the World&quot; to stimulate the audience to laugh. To put it bluntly, it relies on the occurrence of a series of unexpected events to disintegrate the serious proposition of revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among all film and television genres, comedy is the most deconstructive genre. It liberates us from a certain serious state and also liberates the protagonist from the weight of meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like Koichi Numakura in &quot;The Legend of the Underworld&quot;, he is full of revenge plans, but what he actually does is to save the life of the underworld leader. Before Koichi Numakura even realizes how ridiculous his behavior is, we as the audience have already realized the ridiculousness of him betting his life on revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ad631b60f27814fcb3c4adb8aa08e54.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/7ad631b60f27814fcb3c4adb8aa08e54.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comedy is not here To construct meaning and to paint it, we need to dig out the walls of meaning and make it appear somewhat powerless when it collapses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This dissolution of meaning is comprehensive, and the objects it wants to mock include even us as the audience. It just sets a safe distance for us, allowing us to get a kind of psychological comfort from ridiculing the protagonist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After seeing that Numakura Koichi started to practice &quot;Fist of the North Star&quot; diligently at the age of ten, and ten years later, he performed acupuncture on the underworld leader under a streetlight, and was beaten until his face was covered with blood. , the pain of being scolded as crazy also coincides with our feelings of working hard but not getting anything in return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d660e6b365ee5cd4d9b0329432df8966.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d660e6b365ee5cd4d9b0329432df8966.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comedy, use A sudden escape method brings the audience into some common experience or experience, and thus resonates with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Storm in the Cave Realm&quot; obviously understands this well, so most of its plot settings are deduced on this basis. For example, the acquaintance between the heroine Rika Sakamoto (played by Nishino Nanase) and Koichi Numakura is full of a sense of escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sakamoto Rika was originally a young woman who was interested in a massage career. However, due to her father&#39;s high paraplegia in a car accident, she had to work several jobs to support her family. She works in a custom shop at night, and Numakura Koichi met her when he went to the custom shop. She showed her massage skills to Numakura Koichi, but Numakura Koichi had a very bad experience. In turn, he gave Sakamoto Rika a massage, hoping to show her what a real master is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d905a0f491c7c617ebb8567812affaeb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/d905a0f491c7c617ebb8567812affaeb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result is, Sakamoto Rika kowtowed and became a disciple on the spot. But at this moment the alarm clock rang. Sakamoto Rika held the alarm clock seriously and asked the newly appointed teacher Numakura Koichi if he wanted to add another clock. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ca53ed503071fc99c7904e30254fca19.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/ca53ed503071fc99c7904e30254fca19.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Acupoint World&quot; The brilliance of &quot;Wind and Cloud&quot; as a comedy lies in this. It removes the fig leaf and allows you to discover the absurdity behind serious things and the emptiness behind persistence. And all the hard work and dedication sometimes seem like a ridiculous daydream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This ubiquitous comedy makes Numakura Koichi&#39;s determination for revenge turn into a joke in the face of his actual actions to save the underworld leader again and again. The more serious Numakura Koichi looks and the more he swears, the more he looks like a clown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/180acc554311c286ce8487972fb043ed.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/180acc554311c286ce8487972fb043ed.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257967&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a drama It is a collection of ridicule on the great contrast between Numakura Koichi&#39;s spirit and behavior. It is also a sigh about being too persistent and getting into trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is why, when he thought of the underworld leader lying dying in bed due to a car accident, Numakura Koichi suddenly felt that he had lost the motivation to live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gambled his youth and life, letting hatred and anger fill his mind, but what he got in exchange was that he saved his enemies again and again. This joke that fate and character played on him was a bit too absurd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[费滢：巴黎黑户、旧货商人与10年博士生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260360]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/lYKOEf6757VvmHrJPllfLZTZ2olhGCkPT9umLjv8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/lYKOEf6757VvmHrJPllfLZTZ2olhGC kPT9umLjv8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Literature Defended&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 24, 2023, the 6th Blancpain Utopia Literature Award Ceremony was held in Beijing. Fei Yinghe The other four nominees sat in the audience. She was shortlisted for her novel collection &quot;The Legend of Dzi Beads&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the finalists, her identity is relatively complicated. She has published three books, the first is &quot;The Girl Who Often Gets Wandered&quot; written in middle school, the second is &quot;Dong Ke Lou Jing Bian&quot; published nearly 20 years ago in 2020, and the third is 2023 The novella &quot;Legend of Dzi Beads&quot; was published in 2011. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you search for her name, you can also see information about her failure in the college entrance examination more than ten years ago. She won the gold medal in the &quot;Global Chinese Youth Essay Writing Contest&quot; and her article was included in high school Chinese textbooks. But she left Nanjing, where she grew up, with everyone&#39;s speculation that her college entrance examination essay would score 25 points, and went to France to study. She earned a Ph.D. while running her own small antique business (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The &quot;occupation&quot; written on the French visa is &quot;second-hand goods dealer&quot;&lt;/span>;). She travels around exhibitions in various places, always carrying a magnifying glass (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;often lost&lt;/span>;), a purple light and cash (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Putting it aside when setting up a stall can attract wealth - a kind of metaphysics in the antique circle&lt;/span>;) three-piece set. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her doctoral major is &quot;Buddhist Philology&quot; and she has not graduated after 10 years of study. She is called a &quot;missing person&quot; by her tutor. Due to various mistakes in administrative procedures, he was forced to become a gangster for nearly four years. During this period, she wandered around Chinatown in the 13th arrondissement of Paris, reading and picking up leaks... Based on the principle of eating more than one fish, or &quot;striving for the maximum reward for labor&quot; - just like her &quot;The Classics of the East Classroom&quot;, won She received a bonus once for the award, a royalties for reprinting it in journals, and it was published once in traditional Chinese and simplified Chinese. She wrote a novel (by the way) based on everything she saw and heard, which is mainly reflected in the third chapter &quot;The Legend of Dzi Beads&quot;. The first &quot;Xing Zehuan&quot; takes place in her hometown of Lixiahe River Basin, and the content is pretty much the same. It&#39;s always about a small antique dealer with little money in his account, showing off his arms. The middle piece is called &quot;Reverse Scene&quot;, which combines drama, supernatural, suspense and science fiction - a very cyberware mashup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7iuJKfhv5ryqGZAEj3FSP0Iuq48pMiJ8v0yN5hoT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;673&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7iuJKfhv5ryqGZAEj3FSP0Iuq48pMiJ8v0yN5hoT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rich life experience , writing books became a less visible part of it, although it was the part that brought her wider fame. Her novel &quot;Bird&quot; won the United Press Literary Award Short Story Grand Prize, and &quot;East Class Building Jingbian&quot; won the first prize of the Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company Literary Award. She didn&#39;t even spend much time writing. &quot;Bird&quot; only took one or two hours to write, and the three novellas in &quot;Legend of Dzi Beads&quot; were all completed within half a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writer Tang Nuo said: &quot;I have met many excellent novelists and some talented novelists. Fei Ying is one of the best ones I have seen. I shouldn’t have met more than three people... She has relatively few works, which is her trouble. I’m not sure if the novel world can get this person. She may have something she finds more interesting and interesting to do. Do it.&quot; Just like at the Utopia Literary Award Ceremony, no one paid more attention to the sponsor&#39;s products and speeches than she did. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a second-hand dealer, Blancpain&#39;s watch may become her single product. She has done some research on antique watches and knows the two impacts that quartz watches and electronic watches have brought to mechanical watches. While listening to the speech, scattered memories flashed through my mind: French women always like to buy a small lip watch to match their fashions, the soaring price of Italian Vetta, and the fact that Le Jour is a Swiss brand with a French label. She specializes in antiques business, and the knowledge she occasionally learns about clocks and watches is just used for talking with clients, &quot;to look a bit stylish.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage, the spokesperson of the sponsor gave his own definition of &quot;defending complexity&quot;: a simple and bright surface, but a very complicated movement; and a watch with 800 parts is difficult to operate. Very simple. Fei Ying suddenly understood the meaning: &quot;Perhaps what mechanical watches and literature do are consistent to some extent, they are both efforts to make time visible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She recalled some auctions or private exchanges Meeting, suspension, exaggeration, strong commercial flavor, but with a special thoughtfulness, which is the product of the mature stage of capitalist development, making people feel a little sincerity of a convention. Like Eliot in Somerset Maugham&#39;s &quot;Blade&quot;, he is keen on hosting parties and even takes care of arranging seats. While being sarcastic, he also sincerely and tolerantly supports everyone&#39;s conversation (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Even vulgar American taste&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This feeling is so complicated that I even think that those of us who are engaged in literature have inherent (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; or intentionally The aloof ignorance and ignorant aloofness displayed&lt;/span>; were also gently lifted up. No, they were protected. After all, in comparison, we are the unprofessional group.&quot; She said in wrote afterwards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fei Yingwen is like a person, with a generous expression, eight teeth exposed when speaking, and eyes narrowed to a slit. She laughed brightly, her clothes were loose and loose, and her sleeves dangled when she walked. When she spoke, she often played with her green peaked cap, on which a duck was raising its head and saying &quot;yeah&quot; with its wings. The antiques, anecdotes, legends, and secrets of the underworld come one after another in her mouth, and they are clearly organized. If she didn&#39;t do this business, she could probably still be a storyteller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said that she is a &quot;social cow whose business personality has been transformed.&quot; She was laughing and joking as if nothing in the world could trouble her - except taking pictures. Fei Ying&#39;s expression in front of the camera lost her joyful expression, her condensed expression was scattered all over the floor, and her lively face suddenly became stiff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The publisher said that &quot;Legend of Dzi Beads&quot;, especially the chapter &quot;Chinatown&quot;, seems to be &quot;world literature written by Chinese people&quot;, and it is up to the readers to judge whether it is accurate or not. Anyway, Fei Ying is dancing with joy She was very &quot;worldly&quot; at that time - she was cynical, but she took the injustices she saw seriously - by analogy with the book reviews she wrote, such a straightforward definition may be a bit offensive, and it also seems not very advanced. If you have read her Douban, you can somewhat feel the literary concept hidden in her dense complaints broadcast: presentation, statement, and ending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the way, until now, she has not graduated with a Ph.D. From this, we can expect that this actively or passively extended academic career will lead to more possibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sjPrjtBofroQcW5jkI4XrPNVwchuHiunjfInemM6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sjPrjtBofroQcW5jkI4XrPNVwchuHiunjfInemM6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fei Ying participated in the domestic antiques &quot;Bed Rendezvous&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;Old school&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September 2013, Fei Ying went on a trip with her mother. At the end of the trip, her mother gave her the remaining 2,000 euros in cash and said earnestly: &quot;You are old and want to be independent. There is not much money left in your account. You can take these 2,000 euros.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Back in Paris, 2,000 euros were quickly replaced by one month’s rent (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;700 euros&lt;/span>;) and a year’s subway ride. Tickets (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;700 euros&lt;/span>;), one semester&#39;s tuition ( ;&quot;>;400 euros&lt;/span>;) was dismembered, leaving just over a hundred euros. She was struggling to make a living, and she happened to see Faye Wong and Guo Degang wearing Tang Baleng in news photos. At that time, one piece sold for 10,000 yuan on the market. She knew the origin of this bead: it was a kind of agate bead produced between the Han Dynasty and the Tang Dynasty. It was basically imported from Central Asia and was available all over the world. It was large in quantity, similar in appearance, and had limited specificity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She thought of Wang Zengqi&#39;s &quot;Running Alarm&quot;: If someone brings gold, someone will throw away the gold. If someone throws gold, someone will pick up the gold. I am a human, so I can pick up the gold. &quot;I&#39;m a human being, why can&#39;t I pick it up?&quot; She downloaded relevant materials, borrowed books, and researched on jstor (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Academic website&lt;/span>;) The circulation of ancient beads. &quot;I collected all the research materials in this area as if I were writing a doctoral thesis outline.&quot; Fei Ying said, &quot;With some of the original knowledge, it is easier to identify roughly the age and scope, and the purpose of the research. See where it is most likely to be found in the market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A month later, she began to collect scattered Tang Baleng in a larger area. She went to French antique markets and some trade fairs, and flipped through a thousand pages on eBay (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;online auction and shopping website&lt;/span>;), and finally I found a 16-piece Tang Baleng bracelet for $100. It was during Thanksgiving, and the seller had no idea, &quot;It&#39;s only $100. I&#39;m not an artist. I can&#39;t use your iPhone to take clear photos for you.&quot; She had to beg the seller to take a picture of a bead under the light. After taking a close-up photo to confirm the authenticity, I spent US$100 on shipping to get this string of beads across the ocean, and then resold them to a domestic merchant for 5,000 yuan a piece, and I got 80,000. Since then, he has entered the industry and officially became an antique dealer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She concluded that her small antique business mostly provides a service to help customers find what they want. For most collectors, antiques are a kind of consumer product that shows their taste in life. They basically follow the trend in type selection and look for whatever is popular on the market. In recent years, in addition to jade of various ages, she has also helped people find white tea that is more than 30 years old and Moutai liquor that has aged well. &quot;Is Maotai considered an antique?&quot; &quot;Even Cordyceps Sinensis counts.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These are all unexpected needs. There are still many things to do, including helping them arrange dishes and banquets. For example Talk about interesting games, what kind of things I will show in this game, I will help you arrange it.&quot; Fei Ying said, &quot;Generally, some enjoyable, exquisite, artistic, and luxurious things can be planned in advance.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Antique dealer) is a very nostalgic profession. Of course there are many pitfalls and tricks, but there are also moral principles and rules. Speech at the checkout is essential. Exchange knowledge with them and guide their taste. Sometimes, there is also the exaggeration and persuasion part. A customer trusts you, and he puts all his investments in this area to you, asking you to help him find the items he likes. You must keep it true and you can return it. But you are them Are you a friend? You are just a businessman. They will also invite you to attend some occasions as a cultural bargaining chip. You charge a fee, but you are their old friend. It is very interesting. This is a kind of tradition that has existed since ancient times. , old-school social relationships.&quot; Fei Ying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old-school communication requires not only the professional ability to distinguish between true and false, but also human sophistication. Most of the top antique dealers Fei Ying came into contact with abroad graduated from prestigious schools, received systematic training, mastered multiple languages, often dealt with the upper class, had excellent eyesight, and treated people professionally and appropriately. &quot;Overseas, collection is a symbol of cultural taste for the middle class and above, and it has too much cultural value.&quot; The domestic antique industry is not yet mature, and it is unlikely to form hierarchies. Fake goods account for 99% of the market, and those selling old goods Most of the antique dealers have a background in land shoveling, &quot;They all love reading.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The class of domestic antique buyers is uncertain and their origins are unknown, which poses a great challenge to the social skills of antique dealers. One of Fei Ying&#39;s friends facilitated a million-dollar business. When delivering the goods, the other party pointed to the collection at home and asked if these items were good. The friend said honestly: &quot;Some of them are fake.&quot; The other person&#39;s face suddenly darkened, and he didn&#39;t mention the transaction from beginning to end. He drank the tea politely and sent him off politely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Antique exchange meetings are held almost every day, and antique dealers with good physical strength can attend the exhibition 360 days a year. We must save money on food, clothing, housing and transportation. Instead of taking planes or high-speed trains, we use long-distance buses, green trains and other old-fashioned means of transportation. The traffic and horses are slow all the way. You won’t necessarily stay in a hotel when you arrive. “Isn’t the 75 yuan a night bathing center delicious? There’s breakfast when you get up.” Fei Ying was running an exhibition in Germany. A few people rented a small van and went with the big truck the next morning. Drinking coffee in a container. But it was also this group of people who bought expensive emeralds at the trade fair in a blink of an eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the trade fair, they start &quot;fighting&quot; after they like each other. They don&#39;t reveal the bottom price and bid each other, &quot;mutually creating GDP.&quot; Fei Ying has watched the highest transaction volume once was 1.5 million. After nightfall, only the companions were left. A few of them ordered a late-night snack, bought a few bottles of wine, and began to express their feelings. Even though he was drunk, he still kept on business: &quot;Let&#39;s talk about that thing during the day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The world of antiques is full of deceitful economic behaviors, but it is also in this circle that very innocent and straightforward things will come out. .&quot; For example, there is an antique dealer who thinks that you are my friend. Today you brought other friends to my stall, so I will give you a hundred yuan for them all. &quot;I must give you face when you come.&quot; Again. For example, I know you, we met in this place, and you said that you are not doing well recently, then I must &quot;open&quot; for you (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Buy you a thing&lt;/span>;). &quot;This is morality. If you are polite, I will be more polite than you. If you are particular, I will be more particular than you.&quot; Fei Ying said, &quot;There is a comfort in this relationship. Now it is no longer an altruistic society, but this industry can still Give profits to others, leave room for others, and every chain can turn.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /08/Xp8FoKbddQAKQztmWaWEkVjZ8s9jQ3ae645vlDHi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Xp8FoKbddQAKQztmWaWEkVjZ8s9jQ3ae645v lDHi.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;257452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fei Ying sets up a stall at the 200th Antique Market in Hangzhou&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Background color&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Fei Ying’s antique enlightenment came from a Henan man who met on the street selling fake goods when he was 10 years old. People (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t mean to say anything bad about Henan people.&quot; she added&lt;/span>;). She visited street stalls in Nanjing and was attracted by their fake goods. They offered her snacks and told her they were fake. She was invited to their small workshop and learned a lot of counterfeiting techniques. &quot;Because the technology of counterfeiting is real, all the knowledge surrounding counterfeiting is the knowledge you need to identify the authenticity.&quot; They even taught Fei Ying how to behave, quoting many stories of receiving goods, such as the goods worth 5,000 yuan, the owner of which was in prison because of drug addiction. Yes, I&#39;m willing to sell it for 2,800 yuan. This is a warning: Don&#39;t get involved in pornography, gambling, and drugs. Once you get involved, you will be dead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why she likes antiques also comes from this experience. &quot;Antiques are the accumulation of a person&#39;s spirit and a very concentrated expression of the aesthetics of an era. For example, everyone says that the aesthetics of the Song Dynasty represents a peak of Chinese aesthetics. If you look at a porcelain bottle, it has the lines of blue and white porcelain. , can we say that this is the highest peak of Chinese aesthetics? This itself is something that makes me think it has more meaning. Antiques can be 100% authentic, but the judgment is moving and there are evolutions in various senses. The whole thing is more attractive to me . It is not like a text. The text does not know whether it is true or false at all. The meaning is completely fluid. Even the meaning of a word is very unstable. It is too easy to be used by many people and then determined to have another meaning. But The object is already a thing of the past. It has its truth and falsehood, and it is a kind of correctness. But on top of that, it has many additional meanings, and this meaning is changing. There are many conflicts and conflicts in between. Pull. I really feel something very futile or meaningless. These aesthetic changes have affected my life and turned me into a cynical person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cynicism is Fei Ying Her background makes all the anxieties presented in the novel and born out of life seem to be incapable of hurting her. The portrait that fits her is probably always wandering the streets of all sizes with her arms swaying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mehZunkXety5GUzBzrgzkmuuVrCMKFKDHyp7sNK7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/mehZunkXety5GUzBzrgzkmuuVrCMKFKDHyp7sNK7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fei Ying started learning at Yongle Auction&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In November 2016, Fei Ying went to renew her residence permit for the next year as required. French administrative processing is very slow, there are too many applications backlogged, the system often crashes, and online appointments cannot be made. She can only queue up at the immigration office in her living area to grab the 50 numbers every day. After two or three failures, she waited in line at 4 a.m. on a snowy night until dawn, and finally sat in front of the immigration staff. The staff arranged for her to submit the materials six months later. One month after submitting the materials, the other party sent a letter telling her that she applied too late and the information was stuck in the police station&#39;s system. It was suggested that she return to the country and apply for a study visa again. She queued up again to appeal, but was rejected. At the same time, because she had made an appeal, her materials were locked by the system and could no longer be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She just became a gangster. She found a lawyer who specializes in litigating cases for Algerians, who told her that she could go through the process of regularizing her status after two more years of blackmail, which would give her 10 years in law. The lawyer charged 1,800 euros. Fei Ying was shocked by the fee. The other party said: &quot;Because I&#39;m not sure whether I can help you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lawyer had two suggestions: &quot;First, take the current paper I tore my passport and applied for a new one. Anyway, the police station and immigration are not connected to the Internet. Secondly, change to another police station. This police station is well-known in the industry for its bad attitude. Let’s change the area.&quot; So she moved to Paris 13 94 Province, a subway station away from Chinatown in the district, started a gamble without a residence document for more than two years. Then there is the story of &quot;Legend of Dzi Beads&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many things that you cannot do as a gangster, such as working legally. Many people would be anxious for Fei Ying when they saw her doing nothing, but she was really not in a hurry. &quot;Perhaps a personality formed since childhood, I think it is all bad, or it will be like this anyway. Why are you anxious? Life is just like this. Look at your age at the age of three, you don&#39;t know how you became such a person Yes, but I have never been anxious about any problems of my own. If I am anxious, it may only be about social fairness and justice.&quot; She said, &quot;Just like I have a serious and honest attitude towards antiques. , what should this item look like, what era is it from, whether it is real or fake... I will be very serious. I also have the same attitude towards many things in this world, what should this thing be like? In this way, whether everyone gets what he deserves, or even how a book should be evaluated, I may even make a misjudgment at the time, but at that time I was very serious, and it is what it should be. So. But I don’t care enough about a certain material thing that I like, because I think the things I like are fluid after all.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world seems to be getting worse and worse, indeed. It&#39;s hard to make people feel relaxed, and perhaps this is one of the reasons why Fei Ying has made so many comments on Douban. &quot;Because you can&#39;t handle everything. If you want to express some opinions, you have to bear the consequences. I hope you will be able to bear the consequences in the future, but you may not be able to now. Sometimes your attitude and voice will be misinterpreted. I have seen too many things, and the consequences of too many actions, all happened like this, even if the starting point is good. Even in history, there are too many individual voices that will speak out for some social phenomena, but after speaking out, the entire incident In fact, the direction of the epidemic and the great consequences it will cause cannot be borne by one person. Just like you build a nuclear bomb. Every individual must be responsible for his own words and deeds, just like when I make antiques, I am responsible for what I sell. Every thing is responsible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最早发明指南针的确是中国，但不是司南]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260460]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As for the compass, one of the four great inventions, like the other three great inventions, there are also many debates in the public. Among the more important ones are &quot;Sinan is a fake, so the compass is also a fake&quot; and &quot;Europe invented the compass one step earlier than China in 1190&quot;. These claims are specious. There is indeed a need to re-examine the invention, spread and significance of the compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;True and fake compasses&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;First of all, the &quot;Sinan&quot; we saw in the history books &quot;puts a magnetic spoon on the plate, and no matter how you turn the handle of the spoon, it always points to the south&quot;, It is constructed, and there is no such thing from documents to physical objects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The literature basis for the view that &quot;Si Nan&quot; is a compass mainly comes from &quot;Han Feizi&quot; of the Warring States Period and &quot;Lunheng&quot; by Wang Chong of the Eastern Han Dynasty. However, this is a misunderstanding or distortion of the documentary records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Han Feizi·Youdu Pian&quot; states: &quot;The invasion of the master by ladies and ministers is like the terrain, and they gradually pass by, causing the master to make mistakes and change faces from east to west without knowing it. Therefore, the king established &quot;Si Nan means day and night.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Si Nan&quot; here is not a compass, but marks the north-south direction on the court. It means that the king sits north and faces south, and uses magical instruments and rituals to consolidate the dignity of the emperor and the inferiority of his ministers. political landscape. It is very easy to find out where the south is when it is stationary. Just identify it according to the direction of the sun rising in the east and setting in the west. It does not require high technology or instruments such as a compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Lunheng·Shiyingpian&quot; states: &quot;The ancients were simple, and when they saw the movement of grass, they could refer to it, and if they could refer to it, they could refer to the sycophants. When Sinan&#39;s ladle was thrown to the ground, it was &quot;Guide.&quot; Fish and flesh insects gather in the ground and travel north, so the nature of insects is the same. Today&#39;s grass can refer to it, and it is also nature.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chong&#39;s purpose in writing this article is to oppose the influence of heaven and man in the Confucian classics of the Han Dynasty This concept believes that the characteristics of natural things are their own nature and has nothing to do with human affairs. The two examples cited are &quot;Sinan&#39;s Ladle&quot; and &quot;Fish and Flesh Worms&quot;. &quot;Lao&quot; refers to the Big Dipper, not a spoon. The meaning of the sentence &quot;Sinan&#39;s ladle, thrown to the ground, is a guide&quot; means that the Big Dipper (like a spoon shape) with guiding properties is projected to the ground, and the handle of the spoon is The direction it points to is south, but this is just a characteristic of the Big Dipper itself and has nothing to do with personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that whether it is &quot;Han Feizi&quot; or &quot;Lunheng&quot;, the &quot;Si Nan&quot; mentioned has nothing to do with the compass. So, why can the &quot;Sinan&quot; with a spoon on the plate, which was constructed due to misinterpretation of the literature, really be a guide? Because this thing is artificially magnetized using modern technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, Wang Zhenduo made the so-called &quot;Sinan&quot; with a spoon on the plate based on the record of &quot;Sinan&#39;s ladle, throw it on the ground, and guide it&quot;. He claimed that no matter how the magnet rotates on the plate, it will It will eventually point to the south, so I successfully copied &quot;Sinan&quot;. The truth is that because the spoon is too big, the friction when rotating on the plate is too great. The magnetism of the natural magnet cannot restrain the friction. Wang Zhenduo put the natural magnet into the magnetic field to magnetize it to achieve the effect of always guiding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ancients did not have magnetization technology, so it was impossible to make &quot;Si Nan&quot; that did not exist in the literature. It is untenable to regard &quot;Si Nan&quot; as a compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people also believe that based on the records of magnets in the ancient Chinese books &quot;Lu Shi Chun Qiu&quot; and &quot;Huainan Zi&quot;, China has recognized the magnetism of magnets in ancient times and was able to create compasses at that time. This statement is also specious. Recognizing that magnets have magnetism to attract iron does not mean that they also recognize that magnets naturally have the characteristic of pointing to the South Pole. The polarity of magnets was not recorded until the Song Dynasty, so it is impossible to have invented it in the Warring States, Qin and Han Dynasties. Compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Heng of the Eastern Han Dynasty, Ma Jun of the Cao Wei Dynasty, and Zu Chongzhi of the Southern Dynasty invented the compass car. However, the compass car did not use magnetism to indicate the direction, but used gear friction to keep the wooden figure on the car pointing in one direction. Although this invention has its value, factors such as wheel size errors and uneven road surfaces will cause deviations in the direction of the wooden man. Secondly, it cannot be used for navigation, so it is of little use. Therefore, it will be lost and reinvented many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The controversy between water compass and dry compass&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, although Sinan was constructed and the compass is not that amazing, the compass was indeed invented by the Chinese first. The evidence is strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the reign of Emperor Renzong of the Song Dynasty, Yang Weide, an official of Sitiantai, mentioned in the &quot;Fuyuan Zonglu&quot; that the &quot;Bingwu needle&quot; pointed at a constant point was used to survey Feng Shui, and the &quot;Wu Jing Zong Yao&quot; mentioned that giving iron pieces a certain Magnetism made a &quot;guide fish&quot;, which floated in the water bowl and used the guide method. This was about the 1040s AD. In the Song Shenzong era that followed, the compass had achieved greater development. Shen Kuo&#39;s &quot;Mengxi Bi Tan&quot; mentioned four forms of compasses, including the water float method, the bowl-lip spiral method, the nail spiral method, and the thread-suspended method. And think that the wisp method is the best. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest record of the use of compasses in navigation can be found in Zhu Yu&#39;s &quot;Pingzhou Ke Tan&quot; in the late Northern Song Dynasty. It is said that &quot;the boat master knows the geography, observes the stars at night, observes the sun during the day, and observes the sun when it is dark.&quot; Observe the Compass” (1120s AD). The &quot;earth snail&quot; mentioned in Zeng Sanyi&#39;s &quot;Yin Hua Lu&quot; in the early Southern Song Dynasty (1170s) was a compass designed by Feng Shui masters to improve the equipment for observing Feng Shui. The compass still used a floating needle guide with water, but Subdividing the azimuth scale allows people to grasp the direction more accurately. This is also the earliest recorded compass in the world, but there is no evidence that the compass was used for navigation at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is some controversy as to whether the dry compass was invented in China or Europe. Because according to existing documents, Europe may have mastered the dry compass before the Arabs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1190, the British theologian Alexander Nicham mentioned in &quot;On the Nature of Nature&quot; that &quot;a needle placed on a fulcrum will point out the direction of navigation after the rotation stops&quot;, which is very descriptive. It&#39;s like a dry compass, and the earliest Arab document recording a compass was Muhammad Ofi&#39;s &quot;Collection of Stories&quot; in 1232, after the Europeans, and it recorded a water compass rather than a dry compass. Some foreign scholars believe that the Chinese invented the water compass and influenced the Islamic world, but the Europeans independently invented the dry compass and were the first to use it for navigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the earliest Chinese classic that clearly records the dry compass is the &quot;Yin Hua Lu&quot; in the 1170s. In 1985, it was discovered in the tomb of Song Shaowu Zhijun Zhu Jinan (buried in 1198) in Linchuan, Jiangxi Province. The &quot;Zhang Xianren&quot; pottery figurine holding a dry compass indicates that the dry compass should have been born in China first. However, its age is too close to the year 1190 when the dry compass was recorded in Europe. It is difficult to determine that the dry compass was spread from China to Europe based on these alone. It is still very possible that China and Europe independently invented the dry compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there were some vague records of suspected dry compasses in China before this. The &quot;Jiutian Xuannv Qingnang Haijiao Jing&quot; written by Guo Pu of the Eastern Jin Dynasty is believed to be a Tang Dynasty classic, which records that it was used as a guide. Regarding the heaven and earth, Wang Ji&#39;s Feng Shui work &quot;Compass Yijing&quot; in the early Northern Song Dynasty also used the phrase &quot;the needle is clear between virtual dangers and dangers, and the three-way south is open; it is difficult for people to distinguish the right position, but it is indistinguishable.&quot; A poem like &quot;Spirit&quot; records a compass-like device. It is very likely that China invented the dry compass much earlier than the Southern Song Dynasty, so it had time to spread westward to Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in China, the dry compass has been used in geomantic omen, and in Europe it was quickly used for navigation. By the Jiajing period of the 16th century, the Chinese were inspired by the Europeans coming from the East and used it to The dry compass, which has been used for navigation for hundreds of years, has been used to read Feng Shui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the ancient people who believed deeply in religion, new inventions were often religious items first and then put into practical use. The evolution of the function of the dry compass also conforms to this law. However, Europe was the first to put the newly acquired dry compass into practical use, and its technology was converted into productivity faster than China. This also shows that the social vitality of Europe in the High Middle Ages was even better than that of the Song Dynasty, the most dynamic dynasty in Chinese history. At this time, it is no longer important to argue about who invented the dry compass first. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The compass is one of the important navigation technologies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Song Dynasty was a rare era in which China allowed its own merchant ships to operate at sea. Therefore, after the invention of the compass and the water compass, within a few decades, 12 It was passed to the Islamic world in the late 13th century. In the 13th century Muhammad Offi&#39;s collection of Persian anecdotes, &quot;The Encyclopedia of Stories,&quot; records the story of using iron pieces similar to Chinese guide fish to find paths, which is enough to prove that the technology was passed from China. Europeans were the first to put dry compasses into navigation, but their ability to use the compass&#39;s guiding properties was probably also influenced by China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compasses are indeed a great help to world navigation technology, especially in the Mediterranean region. There are many cloudy days in the Mediterranean. The traditional navigation technology of positioning oneself based on the sun, moon and stars will be greatly reduced or even completely ineffective on cloudy and rainy days. At this time, the role of the compass is extremely precious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the long run, the compass is only one of many important navigation technologies and should not be overly deified. The statement that &quot;without the compass, there would be no Age of Discovery&quot; is even more inconsistent with the facts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Neolithic Age, the primitive people of Oceania already had very outstanding navigation technology through the observation of ocean currents, celestial bodies, animals, and clouds, so they only used simple canoes, or at most they had outboards. The pallets were used to load supplies and transport people, but they were able to colonize the Pacific islands from Southeast Asia all the way east to Easter Island, which is not far from South America. To the west, they crossed the Indian Ocean to the African island of Madagascar. Such a magnificent ancient &quot;Age of Discovery&quot; did not require a compass to be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1st century, the Greek Hipparus discovered the pattern of the Indian Ocean monsoon. From then on, the ships of the Roman Empire could take advantage of the monsoon to reach India directly without having to detour along the coast, which greatly shortened the voyage. The connection between the Eurasian continent has been significantly strengthened, and the technological content is only above the compass, not below it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 8th century, the Vikings have used simple segmented wooden sticks or even raised an arm or a finger to observe the declination with the corresponding celestial body to determine their position. There was no compass when sailing from Scandinavia to Iceland, Greenland and even the Americas. From this we can see that even without a compass, Columbus could still have discovered the New World, but it was just more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, before and after the compass, other civilizations also possessed many important navigation technologies, but these technologies did not promote navigation under the compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in the astrolabe of ancient Greece, sailors could arrange the relative positions of celestial bodies in the sky at a specific time. If the sailor could determine the date and time, he could adjust the copper rings representing different latitudes. When the aligned celestial bodies are aligned with the projection position of the celestial body you are currently seeing, you can determine your latitude. This position indication function for sailors is still better than that of a compass, but observing celestial objects requires clear weather and is subject to climate restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is the quadrant invented in the 17th century and the sextant invented in the 18th century. You can determine your latitude by measuring the height of celestial bodies, and the operation is easier than an astrolabe. During the day, measure the angle between the sun and the horizon. At night, measure the angle between Polaris and the horizon in the northern hemisphere, and measure the angle between the Southern Cross and the horizon in the southern hemisphere. Just move the indicator arm to align the sun, Polaris or the Southern Cross with the horizon. You can get your latitude on the indicator arm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Determining the longitude of a sailor is much more difficult than the latitude, but by 1736, the British carpenter John Harrison invented the sea clock, which solved this century-old problem. As long as the sea clock is set to Greenwich Mean Time in the UK, no matter where the sailor is sailing, as long as he looks at the time on the sea clock at noon when the sun is highest, he can deduce how far he is from Greenwich and thus determine his longitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of the above important inventions have any impact on navigation. The progress of world navigation technology is the result of the joint efforts of various civilizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The compass stagnated in China but progressed in Europe&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether or not the European dry compass navigation was influenced by the Chinese compass, the compass is undoubtedly a Chinese invention. But it is a pity that China invented the compass and that was it. Europe continued to improve the dry compass, and through the study of the compass, it inspired the development of cartography and magnetism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 13th-century French scholar Peregrinus, based on his research on compasses, wanted to use magnetism as a power device for weapons. In a letter to a friend, he talked about a more comprehensive understanding of magnetism. Zhi, pioneered the study of magnetism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the 14th century, the Italian Amalfitani invented the &quot;compass card&quot;, a land compass that rotates with the needle, making the direction of the magnetic needle clearer. At the same time, the Italians also used compass bearing lines to draw nautical charts, making the nautical charts much more accurate than the TO world maps of the European Middle Ages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the age of iron ships, European and American sailors realized that the magnetic force of the iron ship itself would interfere with the compass. They installed a piece of Flinderston iron on the compass to offset the compass error caused by the magnetic field of the iron ship. , which became a common practice for iron ships in the 19th century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1906, the German H. Anhuiz invented the gyrocompass. The rapidly rotating gyroscope will use the rotation of the earth to find the true north direction of the area, and will not be affected by the geomagnetic field and nearby metals. Impact, ideal for use inside metal carriers. Gyroscopic wheels were quickly adopted by European and American navies, and were later used more extensively in the aerospace field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1932, the radio compass was put into practical use in the Air Force. The radio compass determines the direction of the aircraft by calculating the angle between the aircraft and the released radio waves, providing the pilot with clear directions, which is another big step forward in compass technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology can only develop through continuous use. During the Ming and Qing Dynasties, the country was generally closed to the outside world, and no one was allowed to enter the sea. Although the private smuggling industry was quite prosperous, under the attack of the imperial court, the navigation industry in East Asia was still greatly affected, and it was natural for science and technology to stagnate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Zhou and Qin Dynasties, China has had the idea of ​​​​&quot;celestial empire&quot;. It regards its neighboring countries as barbarians and has little enthusiasm for exchanges. The Song and Yuan dynasties were rare exceptions, so the compass was invented. However, in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, along with the ban on sea policy and the decrease in exchanges with overseas countries, the arrogance and arrogance intensified, which also prevented the people from spontaneously improving the compass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even in the Song and Yuan dynasties, which were relatively loose and socially dynamic, there was still an upper limit under the control of the Qin system. With the freight volume at that time, there may not be an urgent need to improve the compass, so although the Song Dynasty The compass was a rare invention, but there were not many further improvements. Therefore, only in a society with relaxed systems, open ideas, and active society can science and technology flourish. This is what the history of Compass has taught us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被检出兽药残存，明治召回4.4万瓶牛奶！客服回应了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260470]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Remnants of veterinary drugs were detected in Meiji milk, a well-known Japanese dairy brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 11, according to the Japan Broadcasting Association (NHK), the famous Japanese dairy brand Meiji Milk announced the recall of 44,000 bottles of bottled milk that have been on the market due to the detection of veterinary drug residues in the products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/9c973624a99c1a9fc552d3637d344bcc.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/9c973624a99c1a9fc552d3637d344bcc.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258011&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that this veterinary drug residue is called sulfamethoxazole, which is commonly used to prevent or treat infectious diseases in cattle or pigs. Since this substance will remain in the milk and have adverse effects on the human body, in accordance with production safety regulations, this drug must not be used on animals within 72 hours before milking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Japan Broadcasting Association (NHK), the milk with residual residue was produced by Meiji Dairy&#39;s Kansai factory in Kaizuka City, Osaka Prefecture, and is mainly 180 ml bottles for home delivery. On the 6th, the local government discovered veterinary drug residues during an inspection of the factory and ordered Meiji to recall the problematic products in accordance with relevant food safety regulations. So far, about 44,000 bottles of the product have been recalled. However, since the shelf life of this batch of problematic products ends on November 13, the products have been sold in many regions such as western and central Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Meiji Dairy Group issued a product recall announcement and stated that it would conduct a thorough investigation of the raw milk and production process to prevent similar incidents from happening again. The company argued in the announcement that there is currently no evidence to prove that residual sulfamethoxazole is obviously harmful to the human body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding this matter, a reporter from Nandu Wancaishe asked the customer service of the Meiji flagship store on major e-commerce platforms. The Meiji customer service on the JD.com platform stated that the milk and other products sold by the store in China, except for the use of Except for the raw milk raw materials produced in China, all dairy products are made from dairy products other than Japan. Moreover, the acceptance of raw milk is strictly in accordance with the regulations of the Chinese government, so please feel free to eat it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/66b60fd49e7eb2d4cee80761f61c7d0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/66b60fd49e7eb2d4cee80761f61c7d0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258010&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Meiji customer service on the Taobao platform stated that the chocolates and biscuits sold in the store are produced in China, and there are no milk products sold in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/94007c36a82c2c134b41e0abe37bd10d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/94007c36a82c2c134b41e0abe37bd10d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258009&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>