<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[怀念奶奶丨到此的路程]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261493]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Art history scholar Xu Xiaohu. Data map &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/2ae42d43a2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259891&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Art historian Xu Xiaohu. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;When my parents got married in Nanjing, the capital of the Republic of China, in May 1933, my grandmother invited some Chinese ladies who she thought were not decent. Come and stand with the bride during the ceremony. This is because grandma was shocked when she saw the 20-year-old German girl chosen by her doting third son: brown loose hair, thin and long face, eyes that fell into her head, and was squashed The raised nose is so ugly and perverted! How could this happen? Grandma was frantic, trying desperately to find some uglier ladies to reconcile the horrific situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1933, Xu Daolin and Barbara Schuchard held a wedding in Nanjing, and Jiang Fucong was the witness. Data map&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a6271c87ed.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259892&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;1933 Xu Daolin and Barbara Schuchard held their wedding in Nanjing, and Jiang Fucong was the witness. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The introducer at that time was Mr. Jiang Fuchong, my father’s senior student in Germany, who was cheerful and progressive. Mr. Jiang later became the director of the National Central Library. There are many advanced and effective management measures, and it is advocated that all books should be digitized and permanently preserved for the public. Later, Uncle Chiang became the first director of the National Palace Museum in Taipei, where he implemented many new initiatives. Out of consideration for the benefit of employees, he provided dormitories and welfare facilities for everyone near the museum, which was still a suburb at the time. and other facilities. In 1933, he served as a witness at his parents&#39; wedding ceremony in Nanjing. He later told me that he &quot;ate the little tiger&#39;s red egg.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My mother took a boat from Germany, which fell to Nazism, to China to marry Xu Daolin. She found that this ancient country had many traditions that were very difficult for her. At first she refused to kneel and kowtow in front of her grandma like her father did. Growing up in Berlin, Barbara Schuchard had never kowtowed to anyone or any god in her life. In front of many curious viewers, her spine became an unbendable iron bar. At first, the poor father could only run back and forth between mother and wife to explain, and became a master of &quot;diplomacy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The next spring, a huge typhoon hit Nanjing. The young bride went to the Central Hospital to give birth to their first child, and found that the windows of the hospital ward were also covered with debris. Broken by the typhoon. She thought excitedly, ah! This must be a &quot;presidential-level&quot; boy! The father is also waiting for his son, and they have prepared many names - all for boys. When they saw a red and wrinkled little girl, they were completely stunned, indescribable surprise and disappointment. They looked at each other, not knowing what to do. One day passed, two days passed, and I couldn&#39;t think of any girl&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the third day, grandma spoke. She explained to the new parents the ins and outs of the baby. Feng Conghu and Yun Conglong, this descendant is obviously my father&#39;s favorite big cat named Xiaohu when he was a child. The cat was suddenly run over by a car one day. The &quot;three bald boys&quot; of the Xu family (my grandfather shaved the heads of all his sons and refused to wear Manchu pigtails) were so sad that they didn&#39;t eat or sleep. They just felt sad. . Grandma comforted Dad and said, don&#39;t cry, Santuer, your little tiger will fly back to you as soon as possible and stay with you for the rest of his life. Dad felt relieved and slowly returned to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma hugged the new little girl and said: Look, isn&#39;t this the little tiger you have been waiting for so many years to come back to accompany you? Who did you say? This is the little tiger who came back. My parents had nothing to say, so my grandma looked at my mother’s face and gave her daughter-in-law a title for the first time——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;You say Isn&#39;t it, Hu Zi Niang? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In the summer of 1934, Xu Xiaohu and his parents were in Guling, Lushan. Data map&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3fb66ea181.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1089&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/28/3fb66ea181.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259893&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the summer of 1934, Xu Little Tiger and his parents in Guling, Lushan Mountain. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight years later, we spent the most beautiful time in Geleshan, the suburb of Chongqing, the capital of Chongqing, where azaleas bloomed all over the hills and pine trees danced in the wind. time. From 1938 to 1941, my father served as the Charge d’Affaires of the Republic of China in Italy for four years. When World War II broke out and China and Italy broke off diplomatic relations, my parents took my sister Xiaoyu and me back to China. Grandma also came to Geleshan from her aunt&#39;s house in Chengdu to welcome her third son after four years of separation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Our plane landed in Chongqing, and the welcome crowd gathered next to our parents, speaking adult Chinese. I walked down the gangway and stepped onto the land of China. I was extremely moved. This is my motherland! My eight-year-old heart nearly burst. My elementary school classmates in Rome once asked me, Uncle! (This is the pronunciation of Xu Xiaohu by foreigners)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Uncle Stop shouting! Why is your face so flat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I thought about it and answered: This is because I come from a very far away and very ancient country. The Chinese Embassy you saw on Viale Pola has strong guards in front of it wearing beautiful uniforms and tall feathered helmets. That is my ancient and luxurious motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now I kneel on the land of my motherland, bend down and lower my head, passionately kiss the place I have dreamed of for four years, I am happy and moved, and shed tears. Tell the motherland softly, great land, the tiger cub is back, your child is back. I will learn Chinese as soon as possible and become a Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The land at that time was so dirty, not as bright and clean as Rome. I saw dirty children with tattered clothes and scabs on their heads, standing there with bare feet and a runny nose, staring at us. Like adults, they spit out phlegm from their mouths and spit it on the ground. Xiaohu was very sad when he returned to China, but he insisted on thinking that this is my favorite motherland, that far, far away, very ancient motherland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After several hours of climbing up the hillside in a sedan chair, we finally arrived at the small, dark mud house at No. 15, Bakuaitian, Geleshan. Someone was carrying the luggage in, and my mother and sister went into the house and rummaged through the luggage for something. I stayed on the balcony and watched my father kneel down next to my grandmother who had her head and feet bound. Mother and son hugged each other, and grandma burst into tears, her thin and high-pitched voice reaching to the sky. Dad cried silently, and they held him and cried like this for a long time. I felt sad after reading it. I didn’t understand a word, but I fully understood the emotion in their hearts. I left quietly, walked into the door, climbed on a chair next to the big round table, and saw a pot of tea and a few unattended cups on the table. Don’t know what that drink is, but it must be a drink from my home country. I just poured myself a drink and watched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bitter. Adult taste. taste of China. I love it, I want to love it. Have another drink and taste it. Another glass. I have never tasted this taste in my life. A flavor not found in Italy. I am Chinese and I can drink Chinese taste. Cup after cup, I took in this ancient flavor with love and breathed it into my soul. Xu Xiaohu and her motherland gradually became one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It is starting to get dark. The crying and complaining outside hasn&#39;t stopped yet, but it&#39;s hard to see clearly inside the house. Someone placed a lamp on the big table. It was a green long-handled oil lamp made of ceramics. There was a white wick floating on the bowl of oil, and it was burning with its head exposed on one side, emitting very little light. Is this the only lighting in our entire large room (dining room)? The newly returned Chinese found that she could not see anything, and it was nothing like the light of a Roman electric chandelier. She suddenly felt very ashamed. This is the ancient lighting of my motherland. No matter how bright it is, I will still love it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I don’t remember how I fell asleep on the first night in Geleshan. I just remember that I insisted on going to school right away, learning my mother tongue again, and becoming a Chinese primary school students. I didn&#39;t expect that I was sent to the first grade to learn how to speak Chinese when I expected to continue studying in the fourth grade of elementary school. I went to school happily. I still remember the first class saying &quot;Come, come, come to school, everyone come to school.&quot; All Chinese characters did not have any phonetic symbols - we went directly to understand the ancient Chinese characters. On the way home, my classmates chased me and threw stones, shouting &quot;foreign woman!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My hair is not black and straight. It is brown and curved. When I got home, I scrubbed hard with water and a brush, trying to get it straight and black. No matter how wet it is or how you brush it, it will curl up again as soon as it dries. I had no choice but to face these classmates myself, fight with them, and beat them to the ground one by one. After all, I am already eight years old, a little taller than my first grade classmates. Xiaohu, who never behaved negatively when getting along with his Italian classmates, began to release an inner energy and felt very proud. It turns out that the children of the motherland during the war used physical strength to persuade each other. Well, start learning to speak Chinese and start becoming a Chinese hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Get down from the tree, Hutouer . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;Grandma said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;I will not come down from the tree. This tree is my home. &lt;/span>;I answered happily and mischievously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma asked you to get down from that tree immediately . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;No, grandma, I’ll sit down at my place. I see the world from here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hutou&#39;er, you are right away Get down from that tree. Grandma tells you to come down from that dirty tree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;No. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;We will not be unfilial now Come on, little tiger, good boy, come to grandma. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why don’t I leave my own Tree? Why do I have to go to grandma&#39;s place? I like living in this tree. Here I can count the enemy planes flying above! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At that time, I already spoke Chinese well. On the pine tree near the dark mud house in Geleshan, I remembered I remembered the free big fig tree that no one had observed or searched for in the large garden of the elegant embassy residence in Rome. My bedroom in Rome had a very high ceiling, and the ceiling to the walls were covered with colorful frescoes of classical mythological characters... There was a two- or three-story dollhouse in the bedroom, and I could play with the furniture inside, a doll&#39;s bed and cabinets, chairs and tables. , and several puppet dolls that can sit and stand. None of this means anything to me. After my nap, I would sneak outside into the garden, find the tallest fig tree, climb up, and hide among its rich leaves that oozed milky white liquid. No one could see me, and no one would come there to find me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the fall months I get to pick the juicy fruits from this huge tree. Even if there are no fruits, I can sit on its big branches and enjoy the breeze, the height and the blissful solitude. For a child with a family nanny, this is a rare blessing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;My lovely little sister Xiaoyu is three and a half years younger than me. She has been in the doting arms of a French-Swiss nanny we call Mademoiselle. The Roman years between the ages of 4 and 8 were very free and devoted more to exploring unknown solitude rather than chatting with servants or dolls. In the ever-changing world of trees with cool breezes passing through, I would listen to the sounds of people talking on the ground from a higher vantage point and feel the movements of adults. That perspective allowed me to interact with adults from a wonderful distance. The world is separated by a buffer zone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On those generous branches, everything loses the persuasiveness of &quot;adults say&quot;. From an arboreal perspective, everything happening on the ground becomes less urgent and threatening. Observing them from a higher perspective than adults reveals that adults often undermine the bounds of worldly wisdom or common sense. Surprisingly, they are often like this, spending a lot of time engaging in unnecessary words and deeds; making many unnecessary actions, untrue behaviors, and developing a hypocritical mentality. Adults spend days and nights thinking about issues that may seem unimportant or even ridiculous to us (children). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For example, they created clothes that were very difficult to put on. My mom&#39;s outfit for going out had a long row of buttons - but they were all in the back! Walking behind her, I could see that one of the buttons wasn&#39;t buttoned correctly, tilting her head to the side, causing all the other buttons to be wrong, creating a funny-looking sight. The adults would pretend not to notice but would giggle behind her back all day long. No one pointed this out to her, and no one helped her rebutton the row of buttons properly. I could only walk behind and look at them, thinking how stupidly and needlessly all this time was being spent, yet we kids were not allowed to point it out, giggle or laugh; Left to themselves and chalked up to adults&#39; love of spending time talking nonsense, children suffer in silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma tells you to get out of that dirty tree right away Get down from the tree. Did you hear it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why, grandma? Why should I leave my beloved habitat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because I have to teach you now embroidery. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Embroidery? With needle and thread? Piercing my finger? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now you must learn embroidery. Time to learn something useful! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;For what? What&#39;s the use of embroidery, grandma? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;All girls learn embroidery. This is an absolute must! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why? I had never heard of embroidery in class! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The thought of sitting in a closed room, holding a thin needle, pricking a piece of cotton stretched in a hoop, in and out Being outside, cutting off all the sounds of the breeze, the fresh air from the sun, the songs of birds, or the voices of people, was to me like cutting off life itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition to sitting on the pine tree at home, I also like to sit on a small square stone under another pine tree. On my way home from school, I passed through the valley. At the corner of the winding mountain path, under the big stone mansion of General Chen Cheng, I slid down a few steps to reach that habitat. I sat there for a long time and stared at the distant plains of the Shapingba Valley. , the Jialing River meanders into the distance under the sunshine. There is the Central University there, and my father teaches there and also works for the Chongqing Central Government. In that habitat, I would listen to the voices of the people living in the plains, selling goods, parents shouting at their children, and the children shouting at each other, and I would think of my dad, working alone with his head like me, for all People serve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Every Sunday, he would take the &quot;double rickshaw&quot; to leave our black mud house and go down the thousands of steps to Shapingba below. The riverside plain, entering his Chongqing and his lonely room, I have been thinking like my dad, I think about my dad&#39;s inner world... He is alone, content with everything he can, making our country a better place Some. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This was at the start of World War II, and Japan was mercilessly bombing Chongqing on a daily basis in hopes of wiping out important government targets. But Chongqing has been in haze, with dark clouds, making it difficult for Japanese aircraft to bomb their targets. Every few days we&#39;d hear sirens whining overhead, and everyone, even those of us on the Gele Mountains, would rush out and squeeze into those dank, dark air-raid caves dripping with condensation. water vapor. Every time I would sneak out alone, sit on the rock under my favorite tall pine tree, count the enemy planes, and try to identify the different brands of the planes based on the black and white photos - those photos were taken from the police station by my classmates and I. Got it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Stop everything now, Hutouer, Come to me immediately. Come and learn embroidery, start today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why? What good was embroidery when the Japanese were bombing us with planes overhead? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because you will get married, You have to get ready to be a bride! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;That’s terrible, grandma! Is this really the case? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Of course, fool. Of course you want to get married! Get married and have kids! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;——&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Grandma, please tell me, Is our childhood life also about getting married and having children? ——That is such a painful life, grandma! Each of you has given birth to a baby! Mom and Dad have done it too! Grandma’s baby’s baby has been born and is standing in front of Grandma! Now that our group of children has finally arrived, we must start living interesting lives. We are here to live our special, child-only lives! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;I suddenly became crystal clear. The reason we are born is to be born! Become the children of our parents in marriage. Now that we are finally born, our purpose of growing up has been fulfilled and we no longer need to get married and have children! The life Grandma explained was completely unacceptable to my broad, arboreal way of thinking. Is this really the life everyone talks about? So it seems like adults are completely ignorant! The real purpose of life cannot be just for human existence. I saw clearly at that time that humans have obviously not asked this question. The meaning of existence - why we live - this is the question! What did we come to this fun place for? Of course I am here to appreciate this life and play with it thoroughly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Play it to the end - this is what we are here for - isn&#39;t it? This most basic and important test has taken root in my heart since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma told me many stories. There was a large, round metal barrel on a high shelf in her room. Grandma swayed her little feet back and forth, and was able to walk to the elevated shelf, take down the particularly bright bucket, mix it up, open it, and take out the maltose she made. There is nothing in the world that tastes better than the maltose rolled by grandma herself. They are round and flat, with white powder on the outside to prevent them from sticking together and being difficult to separate. Therefore, eating maltose can certainly be considered one of the main goals of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Listening to grandma telling stories is also one of the wonderful purposes, so charming! Grandma’s stories always include our family’s great heroes. For example, my grandma’s surname is Xia, and the Xia family comes from Yue Fei’s hometown. Grandma&#39;s voice was as sweet as honey and as high as a bird, and the stories she slowly told in her Xuzhou accent were all delicious. Xiaohu sat next to Grandma&#39;s knees and listened, forgetting everything else. The whole village loved Yue Fei, who helped the emperor return from the Jin Kingdom to restore the emperor&#39;s throne. However, Gaozong was unwilling to return the throne he had already occupied to his father. This unfilial son called Yue Fei and Yue Fei&#39;s eldest son. , was convicted as a national enemy and beheaded. The little tiger would burst into tears when he heard this, with tears and snot flying everywhere. The villagers who loved Yue Fei were too sad to speak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Grandma also likes to tell the story of grandpa’s trip to Mongolia——&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tiger Head, one day, the country wanted the Mongols to stay in China and not be able to leave the motherland and go out independently, so they invited your grandfather to persuade them. So your grandfather, General Xu at that time, ran to Mongolia alone without any troops or weapons, taking only his flute master and the old lady from Xuzhou who made pancakes with him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In this way, the three of them arrived in Mongolia , found a small hill, went to the top and sat down. Grandpa planted his big &quot;Xu&quot; military flag on the ground and sat there writing lyrics, singing songs, admiring the moon, eating pancakes, and calmly waiting for the Mongolian chief to appear and surrender. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;After a while, the Mongolian chieftain really coming. He looked up and wow! I heard the sound of Kun Opera. I was shocked when I saw the big military flag with the word &quot;Xu&quot; in it. I immediately climbed up respectfully. As soon as I saw my grandfather, I knelt down and kowtowed desperately to apologize. &quot;Oops! The president has come in person. I am so ignorant and incompetent that I dare not take it! I have no intention of disturbing the uncle!&quot; He regretted that it was too late to kowtow and apologize. The confused chief thought that your grandfather was Mr. Xu Shichang, our president at the time, so he surrendered directly. . Hahaha! You see, grandpa brought Mongolia back without saying a word. You say how capable your grandpa is. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This is how my grandma narrated the story of the three grandfathers taking back Mongolia, and it has become one of our private family history jokes. Now when the great-grandchildren scattered in various countries gather together, they will perform multiple versions of this story as a &quot;historical drama&quot;, showing the story of General Xu Shuzheng&#39;s recovery of Outer Mongolia from various angles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Of course Dad has never heard grandma say this. In front of dad, no one dared to mention grandpa&#39;s name or past events. Dad would shed tears just thinking about his beloved father. Xiaohu actually liked hearing grandma&#39;s story very much, it was much more enjoyable than Yue Fei&#39;s story. I laughed every time I heard the part where the chief was covered in sweat and had no time to kowtow and surrender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At this time, various ideals of country, struggle, self-sacrifice, integrity, and serving the public took root in my heart. I began to think repeatedly about the purpose of our existence; I felt how important it is and how vast the world of time and space is. But in the deepest part of my heart, I began to have an overwhelming doubt...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“我想当大明星”：地下偶像疯狂在2023年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261515]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“营造女友感”：追地下偶像的男人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261499]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 12:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“蓉漂之后，再无漂泊”：年轻人与成都的双向奔赴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 10:57:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the afternoon of October 20, 2023, &quot;Chengdu Marathon &amp;amp; World Science Fiction Conference City Walk &quot;The flash mob event was held at the main venue of the World Science Fiction Conference on the Greenway around the Lake. Chengdu Commercial Daily/Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/228de3a407.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/228de3a407.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 259913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 20, 2023, the &quot;Chengdu Marathon &amp;amp; World Science Fiction Conference City Walk&quot; flash mob event was held at the World Science Fiction Conference The main venue of the conference was held on the greenway around the lake. (Chengdu Business Daily/Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 5-day 81st World Science Fiction Convention was held in a city that has not changed its name for more than 2,000 years - —Chengdu&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>; has come to an end. This is the first time that China has held such a science fiction event. In October 2023, more than 20,000 science fiction fans and more than 1,200 guests from 35 countries and regions around the world gathered in Chengdu to talk about the future in this modern city with a long history. Imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the conference, 27-year-old science fiction writer Bai Ben stayed in a hotel in Pidu District. On the 19th floor of the hotel, through the window, he saw a shopping mall not far away, which happened to be the one he participated in the design and construction of when he was a real estate company at his former employer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bai Bi could not describe his feelings for a moment: it was a sense of time and space intertwined in Chengdu, where the past and present, ideals and reality merged. He just came to Chengdu in 2021 and worked as a designer in a real estate company. After 9 months, he was too busy to &lt;span>;home&lt;/span>;; but it was also in Chengdu that he got closer and closer to his science fiction dream, and he successively won several projects in China The Science Fiction Galaxy Award for Best Newcomer and the Chinese Science Fiction Nebula Award for Best Short Story Silver Award. Now, he also has his own book signings at science fiction conventions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As one of the millions of young people &quot;floating in Chengdu&quot;, Bai Bi from Jiangsu has a reason to stay in Chengdu. At present, he is mainly engaged in the Internet industry and works part-time in science fiction writing. There are few cities that can simultaneously host good Internet companies, embrace the vision of building a science fiction industry, and also create a comfortable, livable and smoky urban atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu attracts Bai Ben, and young people like Bai Ben also attract Chengdu. For years, this rapidly rising megacity in the Midwest has struggled to recruit and retain young talents. I don’t know who was the first to say the words, “After Chengdu, there will be no more wandering.” This has become the essence of Chengdu’s talent work branding and the pursuit of the city’s builders. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Beside Xinglong Lake, look up and meet the doctor&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After five years, I faced the computer screen with a picture of Aba, Sichuan Province in 2018 Huang Ying is still quite moved by the high-altitude aerial view of Aerzhai, Wenchuan County, Prefecture. That year, a landslide suddenly hit Aerzhai. Half of the village collapsed &lt;span>; and half of it was buried. Fortunately, no one died. The geological disaster monitoring and early warning platform developed by Sichuan Zhongke Chuanxin Technology Co., Ltd. played a role. Villagers moved in advance and escaped this natural disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying is now the deputy general manager of this company. However, going back to 6 years ago, Huang Ying was still confused on the eve of changing careers. At that time, the 24-year-old was working in a survey and design institute in a province in Central and South China. The industry was gradually declining. A colleague asked: &quot;Should we transform into high technology?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Huang Ying is somewhat tempted, but where to settle is a problem. He thought of Chengdu, where he spent four years in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, major cities across the country have increased their efforts to attract young talents. Chengdu also needs more young people to participate in urban development and construction. Li Rong, a talent worker in Chengdu, told Southern Weekend reporters that Chengdu has launched version 1.0 of its new talent policy around the idea of ​​“gathering people to prosper the city”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Settlement first and then employment&quot; is a policy initiative that has led to a nationwide trend of settling down and attracting talents. &quot;Those under 45 years old and with a bachelor&#39;s degree or above can directly settle in Chengdu with their graduation certificate.&quot; Li Rong said that in the past six years, Chengdu has attracted more than 710,000 college students to settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying took a fancy to the convenience of settling down and joined the trend of &quot;Peacock Flying Southwest&quot;. He and his partners founded a company in Chengdu High-tech Zone, focusing on geological disasters and Environmental disaster prevention and reduction platform construction and product research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Everything is difficult at the beginning. Huang Ying&#39;s new company encountered obstacles in financing, human resources, sales and other aspects. Initially, he traveled to almost every county in western and southern Sichuan to introduce himself to the local land and resources departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu gave him a hand. Huang Ying remembers that when the company first settled in Chengdu High-tech Zone, the government provided policy support of halving office rents. At the end of 2017, the company sold the first batch of prototypes to a county in western Sichuan. Half a year later, the machine successfully warned of landslides twice, and since then it has gradually opened up the market in southwest China. However, government assistance has not stopped. Three years after the epidemic, the company has also received financial subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying said that currently, the company has applied its equipment and platforms to water conservancy dams, mine safety, foundation pit support, transportation, etc., and has Go nationwide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Huang Ying’s career is developing, and Chengdu’s talent policy is also iterating. In 2020, Chengdu launched the New Talent Policy Version 2.0 around the construction of the Western Science City, focused on technological innovation, launched and implemented Tianfu Laboratory&#39;s global high-end talent recruitment plan, created Chengdu&#39;s characteristic professional group, and supported high-level platforms to open to the society. In 2022, The Chengdu Innovation Index ranks 29th in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three years have passed, and there are many scientific research institutions in the Chengdu Science City located in Tianfu New District, Sichuan. Liu Hongyan, a 34-year-old assistant researcher at the Institute of Urban Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, joked, “If you walk around Xinglong Lake, you might just look up and meet a doctor.” In 2019, she came to the institute as a postdoctoral fellow to work on functional Food development and other work, becoming a member of Xinglong Lakeside&#39;s army of doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shi Jian, the 36-year-old assistant director of the DC Research Institute of Tsinghua Sichuan Energy Internet Research Institute, is also a Ph.D. from Xinglong Lakeside. Looking back on his two years in Chengdu, he felt that he had achieved what he had hoped for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shi Jian is pursuing the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. He once worked for 7 years in a research institute affiliated to a state-owned enterprise in a southeastern province, focusing on research on ultra-high voltage DC engineering and new energy power generation. He has always been troubled by the fact that the cycle of transferring scientific research to application is too long. After arriving in Tianfu New District, Sichuan, he was able to flex his muscles. Right now, the Shijian team is developing the most critical projects in the power industry such as series of power equipment and power chips for DC projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 22, 2023, Peking University Qiu Deba Gymnasium, the scene of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Peking University special event. Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6490cf2092.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6490cf2092.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259914&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 22nd, Peking University Qiu Deba Gymnasium, the scene of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Peking University special event. (Talent Office of Chengdu Municipal Party Committee/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why did the six million &quot;Rong Piao&quot; come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of October 2023, a group of students from Tsinghua University At a job fair, a doctor of medicine expressed mutual interest in a state-owned enterprise in Wenjiang District, Chengdu. State-owned enterprises do not &quot;go round and round to make appointments&quot;. Instead, the person in charge directly reads the resume, interviews, and talks about job content, remuneration and benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a scene from the Beijing special event of the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; series of events. Li Rong introduced that as the most important series of talent recruitment activities in Chengdu in recent years, the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; has held more than 1,000 talent recruitment activities in key cities at home and abroad, and signed more than 200,000 contracts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, Chengdu has focused on leading the city’s talent work with branding strategies. &amp;nbsp;The slogan &quot;Rongpiao&quot; has been shouted out, but there has been some controversy in society as to whether the talent brand should continue to use this name. After all, like Beipiao and Shanghai Piao, there is still the word &quot;piao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, Chengdu has been a typical immigrant city since ancient times, with cultural characteristics of openness, tolerance, generosity and friendliness. According to talent workers in Chengdu, the genetic inheritance and cultural core of &quot;Rongpiao&quot; have long been rooted in the urban development trajectory, and have become Chengdu&#39;s endless driving force, changing the original meaning of &quot;piao&quot; and enriching the meaning of &quot;piao&quot;. &quot;Connotation. Chengdu respects every individual&#39;s dream, cherishes every upward force, and uses the greatest sincerity to help &quot;Rongpiao&quot; realize their personal value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has fully launched the practice of talent work branding strategy, creating a deeply rooted &quot;Rongpiao&quot; brand, and is also the first country in the country to apply for trademark registration The city&#39;s talent work brand has created a series of flagship products and a series of derivatives, such as the &quot;Rongpiao Plan&quot; to attract talents, the &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; to recruit talents, the &quot;Rongpiao Cup&quot; to gather talents, and the &quot;Rongpiao Cup&quot; to educate talents. Talent Development Institute”, Jingcai’s “Rongpiao Talent Day”, Licai’s “Rongcheng Talent Green Card”, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has been exploring ways to solve practical difficulties for young college students who have just entered society. &quot;Thinking about it from a talent perspective, what does a newly graduated college student lack when going to a city to find a job? It must be a place to live.&quot; Li Rong said that based on this idea, Chengdu has created 26 &quot;Rongpiao&quot; cities in recent years. &quot;Youth Talent Station&quot; provides short-term free accommodation for fresh graduates who come to Chengdu to find jobs, as well as a series of value-added services such as employment guidance and urban integration. &quot;As long as they hold the interview notice and pass the online application, young college students can stay in the apartment for free for up to one month.&quot; So far, more than 80,000 young college students have been accommodated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that in the past, when enterprises and institutions in Chengdu went to first-tier cities and well-known universities to recruit, the results were not good because they worked alone and lacked visibility. not good. Later, they changed their approach and maximized the effectiveness of talent introduction by building a collaborative talent introduction model of &quot;government guidance, employer leadership, and broad social participation&quot; to unify publicity themes, unified promotion processes, and unified logos and slogans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking this year&#39;s &quot;Rongpiao Talent Gathering&quot; Tsinghua University and Peking University as an example, Chengdu mobilized 26 public institutions and 16 municipal state-owned enterprises to come up with For high-quality positions, university research institutes and Fortune 500 companies are invited to participate in recruitment. According to statistics, this event released 782 recruitment positions and attracted more than 1,800 young college students to participate. The activity includes city promotion, opportunity list release, job promotion, doctoral and postdoctoral policy promotion, etc. Each recruitment unit &quot;can add their own creativity&quot; and set up stalls to recruit talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recruiting young talents is only the first step. In order to retain talents, Chengdu also spent real money. From the city level to the district (city) and county level, there are a series of talent project applications and talent level assessments. Liu Hongyan recalled that after she achieved certain scientific research results, she was evaluated as a senior talent category C in the &quot;Tianfu Talent Plan&quot; of Sichuan Tianfu New District in 2022. The new district will provide a subsidy of 500,000 yuan within five years. The following year, she applied for scientific research funds from the Chengdu Agricultural Science and Technology Talent Cultivation Program. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Right now, a laboratory in the institute is filled with freeze-dried fruit and vegetable solid drinks developed by Liu Hongyan’s team, and a whitening and moisturizing set containing phloretin. and other technological transformation achievements. This Inner Mongolian native has bought a house and settled in Chengdu. &quot;Currently, Chengdu is the city that best coordinates my work and life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Chengdu Youth Development Report (2022)&quot; released by the Chengdu Municipal Committee of the Communist Youth League and the Chengdu New Economic Development Research Institute shows that the population of &quot;Rongpiao&quot; reaches 6.8349 million. Among them, the proportion of young people from outside Sichuan Province is 21.85%, and the proportion of young people from &quot;Rongpiao&quot; who come from outside the province is 32.9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Rongpiao Youth Talent Station, Jinjiang District, Chengdu. Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /28/c8611cc39a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/c8611cc39a.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;259915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rongpiao Youth Talent Station, Jinjiang District, Chengdu City. (Chengdu Municipal Party Committee Talent Office/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Camping in the city, looking at the snow-capped mountains on the rooftop&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is little research in Hu Peng’s life dictionary Such lofty words as institute and laboratory. He is just an ordinary person who loves life. In Chengdu, he felt another attraction of this city for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;30-year-old Hu Peng is from Leshan, Sichuan. He works as a tour guide in Chengdu, taking tourists to appreciate the different flavors of the city, including city gates, city walls, streets, and museums. , listen to historical stories and observe the lifestyle of local residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He developed two niche routes, one from Shaocheng in the west of the city to Fuqin, and the other from Xiner Village in the north of the city to Caojia Lane. In Fuqin, he had seen a cup of tea costing 3 yuan, and a bowl of noodles costing 89 yuan. The old man went out to eat noodles and drink tea in the morning, and sat there all day, feeling relaxed and happy. In Xiner Village, &quot;the size of the community is the size of the market.&quot; The market men and women lingered in the market in the morning, and he felt a vibrant beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Young people can always find the livable side of Chengdu. Science fiction writer Huo Zhongwu came to Chengdu in 2005 to study at university and settled here after graduation. He enjoys the pleasant cost of living here. Similarly, renting an apartment near the city center is about a quarter of that in Shanghai. A &quot;Rongpiao&quot; young man admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that one of the important reasons why he came to Chengdu to work three years ago was that Chengdu&#39;s housing prices are extremely cost-effective among provincial capital cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Have fun&quot; is a business card of Chengdu. Huo Zhongwu’s observation is that life in Chengdu is much slower than in first-tier cities, and there are always people in the teahouses and cafes on the roadside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bai Ben was deeply impressed by a salon at the World Science Fiction Convention. A writer mentioned that he had seen a netizen post asking: It will be rare to have sunny weather in Chengdu tomorrow. Does anyone want to go to a high-rise building to watch the snow-capped mountains together? The writer went to the roof before dawn the next day, and there were already many people rubbing their hands and waiting. “This kind of thing is hard to imagine in other cities,” Bai Ben said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu has also captured the needs of talents for urban environment and quality of life. In 2022, Chengdu will launch the &quot;Talent New Deal 3.0&quot; version with excellent platforms and ecological management, attracting more young talents to take the initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When the water accumulates, fish gather&lt;span>;, and when trees grow thicker, birds gather.&quot; The relevant person in charge of the Talent Office of Chengdu Municipal Party Committee introduced that Chengdu has been We strive to protect the value attribution of talents with the highest quality services and create a value ecosystem where everyone is seen, respected and cared for. What can be proved is that Chengdu has been ranked first in &quot;China&#39;s happiest city&quot; for 14 consecutive years, ranked first in &quot;Fortune&quot; magazine&#39;s &quot;Attractive Cities for College Students and Young Job Seekers&quot;, and won &quot;China&#39;s Best Talent Attracting City&quot; for 4 consecutive years. &quot;prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Talent work is ultimately inseparable from improving the quality of the city.&quot; For example, in order to cater to young people&#39;s fun-loving and quality-of-life mentality, Chengdu continues to optimize its environment , a 100-kilometer first-level greenway of the Ring Ecological Park has been built inside and outside the city ring expressway, with billowing green wheat fields, lush grassland, and swaying woods; while building a park city, Chengdu has opened up a large number of wetlands and green spaces As a camping site, &quot;everyone goes camping and basking in the sun on weekends&quot;, creating a new picture of urban life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 3, 2023, a unique &quot;underwater bookstore&quot; next to Xinglong Lake, a famous internet celebrity check-in place in Chengdu. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/238c595079.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/28/238c595079.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9, 2023 On March 3, Chengdu’s famous internet celebrity check-in place was a unique “underwater bookstore” next to Xinglong Lake. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Resonance among young people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chengdu’s life scene that attracts young people also includes abundant public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The streets and alleys here hide &lt;span>;three&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;thousand&lt;/span>; more than one bookstore, far more than any other city in the country. It is difficult to count the number of public activities that are closely connected to it - reading clubs, movie viewing parties, script screenings, and sharing by scholars and experts. Some active spaces can host hundreds of events a year. The event was small in scale, with only twenty or thirty people at most, but it provided an opportunity for connection and resonance for countless young people eager to express, share, and see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 2015, Wang Miaomiao worked as an account manager for a brand company in Chengdu. At that time, she fell into depression for a time due to family reasons. She began to participate in a large number of offline public activities and spent three or four nights a week in various sharing sessions. Although most of the time, she couldn&#39;t understand what the sharer was saying, she liked the friendly and warm atmosphere, which allowed her to temporarily escape the pain in her life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Product manager Di Hao came to Chengdu to work in 2016. At the beginning, he couldn&#39;t find anyone he could play with, whether at work or in life. A year later, he saw the activities of the Toastmasters Club in the same city on Douban and tried to participate. Since then, he has been hooked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He has vivid memories of many activities. During the reading party, they read Tolstoy to understand human greed; after the movie viewing party, someone explained Plato&#39;s Allegory of the Cave. Once, scholar Wang Di came to a tavern in the suburbs of Chengdu to share. More than a hundred people came and &lt;span>;Wang Di&lt;/span>; talked until midnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Di Hao felt that the young friends who participated in the event gave him a sense of belonging. These activities also opened up a new world for Di Hao. In the past, when facing big figures, he had a sense of order based on distinction between superiority and inferiority. The egalitarian atmosphere of public activities gradually made him accustomed to dealing with others as an equal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After 2018, Hu Peng also often went to Chengdu to participate in public events. In his early years, he met a Polish man and a British man at a sharing meeting. They worked for a few months a year, teaching English and doing project planning, and the rest of the time was spent traveling around. This way of life surprised him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Peng prides himself on being a young man from a small town, having graduated with a bachelor&#39;s degree. Many people in his hometown have nothing to do in their spare time except playing cards. These activities made him realize that there was another possibility in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Also in 2018, Wang Miaomiao, who has participated in numerous public activities, became the director of Xunlu Library. This is a community library, but it aspires to become a &quot;humanistic beacon&quot;. Wang Miaomiao discovered that people lacked general education, so he invited professors from Sichuan University to come to the library to teach general education courses about Du Fu and visual culture. She listened to lawyer Zhang Ying&#39;s &quot;Bright Dialogue&quot; series of public debates and thought it was good, and invited Zhang Ying to the library for a discussion on psychology. Some participants said that these discussions responded to the rising enthusiasm for psychology since the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Miaomiao feels that these public lives have reshaped her life. She likes to study people and society, and is curious about where strong vitality is born, and the sharers &lt;span>;also&lt;/span>; responded to her questions in their own ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2023, she will become busier. Offline activities in Chengdu are very prosperous. In addition to creating more in-depth public activity content, she also needs to run a &quot;reclamation community&quot; that unites participants with reading as the core. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this corner of the southwest, public space is so prosperous, and Hu Peng connects it with the characteristics of the city. Chengdu has a tradition of chatting in teahouses and cafes. In addition, perhaps many busy young people are heading to first-tier cities such as Beijing, Shanghai, and Guangzhou. The young people who come to Chengdu are more pursuing spiritual enrichment and yearning for a better life. They find resonance in Chengdu and at the same time inject new vitality into Chengdu&#39;s public life. People and cities always choose and nourish each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Rong and Di Hao are pseudonyms, Bai Ben and Huo Zhongwu are pen names)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[360万种改造成都的方式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 10:57:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73772&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70563&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/160a2e749d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;During the National Day, people ride on the central axis of Chengdu city on the greenway around the city .Visual China Map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;During the National Day, people ride on the greenway around the city along the central axis of Chengdu. Visual China Map&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/160a2e749d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259909&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the National Day, people ride on the greenway around the city on the central axis of Chengdu. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ji Ying will appear at the Jinsha Heritage Museum every Thursday morning. She is a volunteer guide here. Usually, after gathering seven or eight tourists, the team sets off. Along the way, there will be more and more listeners behind the red volunteer uniforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This 51-year-old Chengdu native was originally a manager of a foreign company. He traveled around the southwest and was busy and exhausted from work. After a serious illness, the doctor warned &quot;not to be too tired from now on&quot;, so the museum at home became a new choice. The company organized groups to come and listen to it several times. They were surprised by the colleague in front of them who talked about the ancient Shu civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more than 3.6 million people like her with dual identities in Chengdu. Zhang Zimeng, a student at Sichuan Conservatory of Music, is a volunteer in the &quot;Song is the Sweetest Medicine&quot; project. She goes to the hospital every week to serve as a vocal teacher for fifty or sixty &quot;Teletubbies&quot; suffering from severe spinal deformity; 37-year-old Express Member Tang Jian is the captain of the &quot;Maverick Pioneer Drivers&quot; volunteer service team. His team is a &quot;mobile probe&quot; that walks through the streets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are volunteer service stories that happen every day in every corner of Chengdu. Wei Na, the relevant person in charge of the Volunteer Service Department of the Propaganda Department of the Chengdu Municipal Party Committee, told Southern Weekend reporters that they have built a volunteer service platform &quot;Civilized Xingrong&quot; to use information technology to record all volunteer service information. Since the entire platform is in operation, there are nearly 40,000 registered volunteer teams in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chengdu is becoming a model city of &quot;City of Volunteers&quot;. Wei Na feels that this is a &quot;process of gathering glimmers of light&quot;: &quot;Looking at them separately, they are all small and microscopic, but together they are dedicated to the governance of the city and its happiness.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;“It’s so troublesome to be a volunteer”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is Ji Ying’s sixth year as a volunteer at the Jinsha Heritage Museum. “Without a strong belief, there is no way to persevere.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more than 60 volunteers in the museum, and the recruitment assessment of Ji Ying’s explanation team is recognized as strict. This &quot;novice on historical knowledge&quot; stumbled all the way. He passed the group interview, completed the first round of the relics museum&#39;s interpretation test, passed the written test, and passed the entire museum&#39;s interpretation interview, becoming a trainee volunteer. The entire assessment process lasted nearly seven months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first lesson of the volunteer training is to visit the museum, and the second lesson is to learn the team rules and regulations. The service hours are required to reach 120 hours per year, and in principle, they must come once a week. Ma Nong, a volunteer in the service group, was not used to it when he first arrived: &quot;I didn&#39;t expect that being a volunteer would be so troublesome, but it is so strict.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id =&quot;73774&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70565&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/0bf8bd712f.jpg&quot; img-title =&quot;ffa8c2a263ca7831b29090f0159f916.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Volunteers in red uniforms are explaining to tourists at the Jinsha Heritage Museum. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;729&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/0bf8bd712f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259910&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Volunteers in red uniforms are explaining to tourists at the Jinsha Site Museum. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who manages this volunteer team is Lu Lu, a staff member of the museum’s Department of Public Service and Social Education. &quot;We often call her King Lu or Little Leather Whip.&quot; Manong joked, &quot;King Lu&quot; is very strict. If you don&#39;t bring a work permit, you won&#39;t be allowed in, and the service time will not be counted. As time went by, she discovered that this strict compliance with the rules was equivalent to blocking out &quot;those who were not determined&quot;, leaving only those who really wanted to be volunteers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Lu told Southern Weekend reporters that she &quot;stated the rules and regulations upfront&quot; in the hope of conducting a double selection with volunteers. &quot;Without management, there is no cohesion. If you can accept it, we will happily work together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cohesion of the team is not only reflected in the system. Lu Lu will try her best to remember each volunteer’s birthday and lead everyone in the group to send blessings. At the end-of-year commendation meeting, she will contact the departments the volunteers have worked with and request them to issue certificates of honor to express respect and gratitude to the volunteers. &quot;Volunteer partners are not here for material things, so I hope to satisfy them in other ways that they are respected and needed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For museums with limited manpower, volunteers are important supplementary strength. Lu Lu mentioned that the museum has more than 30 docents, and during winter and summer vacations and popular holidays, the supply far exceeds demand, and volunteers can fill the seats. They announced the designated time for volunteers to give lectures, three in the morning and one in the afternoon, &quot;which can alleviate the demand to a great extent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The English translation volunteers in the translation team have a &quot;full schedule&quot; of work. The museum had tried a translation company, but it involved archaeological terminology and was more difficult. Instead, the museum&#39;s volunteer translation team was more competent - they had all passed CET-8 in English, and their academic qualifications were basically at least a master&#39;s degree. &quot;We have a lot of professional training, including the curator who will explain to us the excavation and historical origin of cultural relics, and we all understand them very clearly,&quot; said Lei Lei, the head of the translation team. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Overall scheduling from city to district&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the aforementioned &quot;Civilized Rong&quot; platform, there are an average of more than 500 various activities like this every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first intelligent platform in the country to fully support the practice of civilization and the development of volunteer service activities in the new era. It is understood that this smart platform can realize the complete record of volunteer service information. At the same time, it is also an important reference for award evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yi, deputy editor-in-chief of the Chengdu Volunteer Network, who is responsible for managing the platform, said that volunteer service activities in all districts and counties in Chengdu can be seen on the platform. “Its biggest function is to facilitate citizens to find activities and sign up to participate. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, there have been particularly many ecological and environmental protection activities on the platform. Liu Yi told Southern Weekend reporters that during the National Day holiday, the Chengdu Municipal Civilization Office linked 14 volunteer service stations on the greenway around the city to carry out cycling check-in activities. Chengdu’s city-ring greenway is a holy place for cycling enthusiasts, with a total length of 100 kilometers. &quot;The needs of citizens prompted us to extend civilized practices and volunteer services to the greenway scene.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 14 stations cooperate with each other and each has its own actions. Zhang Ying, chief of the Creation and Volunteer Service Section of the Propaganda Department of the Wenjiang District Party Committee, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that at that time, she was most worried about not attracting citizens to stop. The organizer put together the civilized blind box of the station into a map of China. Cyclists passing by would always stop and ask questions, which was very eye-catching. “Every day, our check-in points are crowded with people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from the projects in the Jinsha Site Museum, this is a network of volunteer activities woven by government departments at all levels in Chengdu. An event lasting several days requires the cooperation of multiple departments. In the greenway station activities, civilized units at all levels play the main role, guiding and coordinating social organizations to participate in the assistance, and civilized units at the provincial, municipal, and district levels pair up to jointly build greenways. In the Wenjiang section of the Ring Greenway alone, the participating departments include the Wenjiang District Health Bureau, the District Culture, Sports and Tourism Bureau, and the District Education Bureau, with a total of more than 100 people from at least 12 units and enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The specific activities of the greenway station every day are also carried out by the responsible unit. Zhang Ying gave an example. The district health bureau is responsible for free TCM clinics, which provide health consultation services to citizens, teach first aid knowledge, and deal with sudden accidents such as cycling injuries and hiking sprains. The Wenjiang District Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital also dispatched medical team volunteers. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Zhang Ying, it is not difficult to connect various departments to participate in volunteer activities. The entire event is coordinated by the New Era Civilization Practice Center, and the district party secretary serves as the director of the center to implement the work. Before the start of a large-scale event, the Civilized Practice Center will hold a scheduling meeting, and all departments that need to cooperate with the event must attend the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to her, Wenjiang District is among the first batch of new era civilized practice center pilot projects in the province and the second batch in the country. A district-level center, nine towns and sub-districts, and 95 villages and communities have jointly built a three-level position where the Civilized Practice Center is located. It also has 8 professional volunteer service standing teams and multiple special volunteer service teams. “When we need it When the time comes, we can coordinate.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our volunteer service model in Chengdu is well coordinated from top to bottom. The civilized practice centers in each district and county have standardized systems, activities and organizational structures, which can promote this kind of service very well. Civilized practices and volunteer service activities are carried out on a regular basis.&quot; Zhang Ying concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73771&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70562&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/69306910a6.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;839b8378c9c405b613355b1a9cb0de4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wenjiang District carries out activities at the Greenway Station during the National Day in 2023. Photo provided by the interviewee &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/69306910a6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 259911&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the National Day in 2023, Wenjiang District carried out activities at the Greenway Station. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Volunteer service in &quot;Taobao Mall&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Establishing a points feedback incentive mechanism is an important part of building a city of volunteers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Volunteer time exchange for points and services, and related selection and recognition are common options for each project, and it is a top-down design. The &quot;Chengdu Volunteer Service Incentive Measures (Trial)&quot; launched by Chengdu City in 2019 is the country&#39;s first systematic volunteer service incentive system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, the framers wanted to link education, employment, settlement, etc. with volunteer services. Wei Na admitted that there are difficulties at the practical level, such as extra points for employment interviews or public examinations. Due to the lack of upper-level system support, it is difficult to clearly correlate volunteer service experience with the degree of extra points, and the basis is also difficult to quantify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are some areas where quantitative bonus points can be gained. For example, in the residence permit point statistics, volunteer service is worth 10 points. &quot;The previous policy was to add 100 points to get a household registration, and to participate in volunteer services, you can add 10 points. The points are still very impressive.&quot; She added that the Municipal Civilization Office has a dedicated person responsible for the points recognition of volunteer services, which has been changed to Normal operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, volunteer service is closely related to the comprehensive quality evaluation of primary and secondary school students in Chengdu. If you participate in the &quot;Civilized Rong&quot; volunteer project, the platform will automatically generate an official certificate, which will be used as a reference for school evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the &quot;Civilized Xingrong&quot; platform, volunteers can exchange points for corresponding rights and interests. Liu Yi nicknamed it the &quot;Taobao&quot; of volunteer service. The online points mall can be redeemed for items, training and services. Some communities will also upload incentive items, such as a pack of washing powder, a bag of rice, or a haircut card at the doorstep. &quot;We are actually using the concept of crowdfunding to provide courtesy and help for volunteer services.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Niushikou Street, which gave birth to the &quot;Maverick Pioneer Drivers&quot; volunteer service team, has created its own points incentive system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jie, a staff member of the Party and Mass Affairs Office of Niushikou Street, said that one point is equal to one yuan, which can be exchanged for mobile phone holders, ponchos, power banks and other items in the points mall, or you can choose coupons donated by caring companies. . The most popular redemption items are Hongqi supermarket chain cash coupons, which can be used directly for consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the volunteers of Jinsha Heritage Museum, the biggest incentive to give back is intangible. The suggestions they put forward always received support from the museum: inviting sanitation workers into the museum, accompanying nearly a hundred visually impaired friends to visit, and bringing the story of the &quot;Sun Bird&quot; into the community...these ideas that sprouted in practice, It has become a representative project of the museum’s volunteer activities, making the volunteers quite proud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The audio program &quot;Xiao Zhi Hua Tian Fu&quot; led by Ji Ying was also born under this kind of autonomy. In the program, the &quot;Jinsha Maidens&quot; will use Chengdu dialect to explain the ancient Shu civilization and Tianfu culture in the 31st Universiade. &quot;We hope that through this program, more people will have a deeper understanding of Chengdu.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The seeds planted in 2008&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wei Na found that the soil had become thicker, and volunteering had gradually become a way of life for Chengdu people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Day holiday in 2023, a staff member of the Volunteer Service took his son to ride on the greenway around the city. When they arrived at the Baiye section of Jiaozi in Wuhou District, they saw that the volunteers were very busy. My 16-year-old son stopped, signed up on the spot, and worked as a volunteer at the inn for two hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her parents have also spontaneously joined the elderly volunteer association in the community. Various volunteer services are often announced in the association group. My father will participate in chorus programs to celebrate festivals for residents; my mother will participate in river patrols every week, walking with friends in the same unit to check whether there are any fishing issues during closed seasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than ten years ago, two old people came to this strange city to help take care of their children. By participating in volunteer service activities in the community, they got to know the elderly people around them and established their own social circle. At present, I have sold my house in my hometown and chose to settle in Chengdu. She smiled and said, &quot;Because they love this city very much, and they are also very active in community activities after settling here. They are really super backbones.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wei Na&#39;s view, Chengdu people have a strong sense of belonging in their hearts. Philanthropic sentiment: &quot;The year 2008, when the earthquake occurred, can actually be called the first year of volunteer service in Chengdu. We were the place where the disaster occurred, and there were NGOs from all over the world, and many volunteers came to help us.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;For philanthropist Xu Zhen, the seed of volunteering was planted in 2008. At that time, many rescue teams and volunteers from all over the world poured into Sichuan, and those helping hands left a deep impression on her. Four or five years later, when she was in college, she wanted to join the school&#39;s volunteer association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, as the person in charge of the &quot;Song is the Sweetest Medicine&quot; project of Cloud Public Welfare, she has been serving &quot;Teletubbies&quot; with volunteers for nearly seven years. When she first saw these patients with severe spinal deformity, their heads and waists were covered with steel rings, which were connected and fixed by four support rods above their heads. This physical condition gave Xu Zhen a very strong intuition. impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, volunteers will take patients to do vocal exercises, exhale to make a rhythm, and make a &quot;hissing&quot; sound on their mouths to exercise their breath. This is a part of the treatment process and is customized by the director of the orthopedics department of the hospital. From admission to discharge, &quot;Teletubbies&quot; will grow an average of 20 centimeters in height and usher in a new life. Xu Zhen was especially pleased when she saw someone in the group changed the note to &quot;discharged&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More volunteer seeds are being planted continuously in the &quot;One Hour a Week&quot; project carried out by the Chengdu Volunteer Network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Hong, leader of the &quot;One Hour a Week&quot; project team, introduced that they advocate citizens to participate in at least one hour of volunteer service every week. In the four years since the project was launched, there have been more than 170 online and offline activities, more than 80,000 volunteers participated, and more than 5 million people have been served. During the Chengdu Universiade, citizens were encouraged to upload moments of civilized viewing of the games. After the Universiade, a micro-story collection was launched for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For her, &quot;one hour per week&quot; is a habit-forming task, so she tries to lower the threshold for volunteer service participation and increase the number of participants and coverage. The &quot;shoot as you go&quot; activity, which is being vigorously promoted, can be participated in anywhere in the city. As long as you take photos of civilized behaviors and upload them five times, you can get electronic certificates, volunteer service hours and points. “The ultimate goal is to inspire our citizens to identify with volunteer services, identify with the friendly atmosphere of the city, and be willing to contribute to the civilization and friendliness of the city.” Liu Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Micro-governance of “two-way running”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this city of volunteers, volunteers serve others and are also served. This &quot;two-way rush&quot; is already a kind of urban public governance on a micro level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Hongjixin Road in Jinjiang District, a conspicuous courtyard has a sign reading &quot;Brother Xiao Niu·Sha Yi Jie&quot;. This is a 24-hour love station and a resting place for new employment groups such as express delivery, takeaway, and online ride-hailing drivers. Gao Linya, the person in charge of the &quot;Little Niu Brother&quot; project, said that there are already 35 sites like this in Jinjiang District. From replenishing water and charging, to psychological consultation, labor safety protection, employment guidance services, vocational skills training, holding free clinics, etc., they are all options at the station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early demand survey, the &quot;Little Niu Brother&quot; team found that what couriers and delivery people needed most was charging services, so they specially coordinated with a company to set up six charging stations at the entrance of the community opposite the post station. Set charging cabinet. &quot;&#39;Brother Maverick&#39; has not only served these groups from the beginning, but also guided them to participate in social services, forming a closed-loop logic of two-way services.&quot; Gao Linya said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73773&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70564&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/0e329f974d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;79c93e56795144985b1569ca6447dd5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Brother Maverick·Shake Kick&quot; Station. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;729&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/0e329f974d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259912&quot; style =&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Brother Maverick·Stop&quot; Station. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also motivating citizens to participate in urban governance is Zhang Haibo, secretary-general of the Chengdu Urban and Rural Community Development and Governance Promotion Association. He unites universities and communities, and college students independently launch refined volunteer services. The communities list their needs, and students in corresponding majors provide professional services. &quot;Let students see the value of their own subjects during the process of volunteer service, which will facilitate subsequent life planning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the scope of stimulation has gradually expanded. Zhang Haibo built a youth volunteer service innovation laboratory to organize service projects based on problems. Zhang Haibo was deeply impressed by the &quot;Breaking Action&quot; launched in the summer of 2023 to prevent left-behind children from being addicted to mobile phones. College student volunteers also invited players from the Chengdu AG e-sports team to play games with the children. &quot;Our idea at the time was , we’ll talk about it after we’re convinced.” He smiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such micro-governance occurs in every corner of the city. Takeaway riders travel through the streets and actively upload social governance clues while delivering food. Gao Linya introduced that governance clues are divided into eight categories, including accident emergency and damage to public facilities. The street has dedicated personnel to review and deal with the clues, and feed back the problems to the corresponding departments at the grassroots level. If they cannot be solved, they will continue to be reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For some things within their capabilities, volunteers are encouraged to &quot;find and solve them by themselves&quot; and actively participate in grassroots governance services. Discovering the problem of random storage of shared bicycles and sorting them out is equivalent to gaining points for two clues. For more than two years of the project operation, there are more than 500 people in the background, and more than 3,000 social governance clues collected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Our group of people may feel embarrassed to do (volunteer). With encouragement and promotion, there are additional rewards after finishing, and the enthusiasm will get up. In the end Come inside. &quot;The courier Tang Jian sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;brf = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://https://https://https://https:/ /feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社区营造师：“我们在链接中产生价值”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261509]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 10:57:51 src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/05731d75e3.png&quot; IMG- Title = &quot;Picture 1.png&quot; Alt = &quot;Yang Yingqi. border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;731&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/05731d75e3.png&quot; data- key = &quot;2599088 &quot;STYLE =&quot; &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Yang Yingqi. The interviewees confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Starting in September 2023, Yang Yingqi and her team made a bold attempt in Chenghua District, Chengdu: 23 of the 83 communities were selected for gradual participation planning. The only criterion for screening is attitude, &quot;the community secretary must be changed from the inside.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is one of the series of the fourth series of &quot;Chengshi · Cheng Painting&quot; Chenghua District Community Planning and Design Festival. Yang Yingqi explained to the secretary of the community party committee who participated in the competition that the gradual participation plan was to continue to try and correct errors to make a community gradually move towards a better direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a community creator, this is the fifth year of &quot;post -95&quot; Yang Yingqi. Cheng Cheng, who is active in the public governance atmosphere in the community, is not a small number of &quot;professional players&quot; like her. They are responsible for formulating community action plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Yang Yingqi&#39;s view, community builders are more like the companion and deep cultivators of the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Yingqi accompanied the participating team to complete the entire process. From the training ability of the preliminary secretary, to the discussion of round tables with the backbone of the secretary, and then to the backbone call for residents to do participation and voting, and select community issues. Then perform two -way blind selection to match the volunteer designer team. &quot;All are controlled by small physical quantities, 100,000 yuan, but we have to solve a problem or contradiction in the community, or let the community have a point to glow.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; For Yang Yingqi The results of the game are not the most important. More importantly, in the process of participation, people&#39;s awareness of the community and inspiring the enthusiasm for public governance of community residents, &quot;grassroots governance should be seen most.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of the contestants, Zhu Xiangling, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Shuanglin Community, is particularly impressed. At the discussion stage of the round table that week, there were almost 100 people who participated in almost every day. Most of them were residents, as well as community builders, planners, grid members, community and street office staff. &quot;Before we didn&#39;t know how to leverage various resources, it seemed that everyone felt that this was a cross -border thing. It was actually not. Everyone had a common goal to make this environment better.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p >; Following the possibility of solving the problem, the &quot;wall competition&quot; is at this time into the attention of the participants. Master Jiang, who was repairing the car for a long time, occupied a public space in the community. Zhu Xiangling said that like Master Jiang, the entire community is also distributed a lot. They provide personalized services and survive in public contradictions. However, residents have denied this method of banning. &quot;People have been here for two or three decades here, and the craftsmanship is good, and it provides good services. Why do people ban people?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; They started thinking, can the two be symbiotic? As a result of the &quot;shared wall and surface&quot;, it gradually became full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Yingqi appreciates the temperature and flexible treatment of the Shuanglin community. In order to solve a community contradiction, there is no new contradiction. The car repair master who works hard can still maintain a living, and can also provide services to the community residents. Sharing ladders, hammers, pliers and other tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhu Xiangling was also impressed by Yang Yingqi&#39;s team. In the contact at the beginning of the event, Zhu Xiangling observed that the team ran through the entire Chenghua District to visit the investigation. She recalled that the little girl also brought the secretary and the &quot;special forces&quot; visited the friendly community of the people created by the team before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is an important project that Yang Yingqi took the team to take root in Chengdu, and it was her &quot;reason for Chengdu&#39;s entire confidence.&quot; Three years ago, the project landed on the Bilei community. She met the community in charge for the first time and talked to 11 o&#39;clock at night, and decided to cooperate immediately. Yang Yingqi felt that the managers of this community were tolerant and appealing, and they were also willing to continue to introduce youth forces. &quot;I think this is the most needed energy for community secretaries. I call it endogenous power.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She likes Beilei communities. She is a shop when she is on the street. The residents are living on the street. The shop provides the service of the entire community. The price is cheap, the life is comfortable, there is no large viaduct, and there are no wide highways. It is more suitable The dominance scale of urban residents. She is willing to return to such a place and inject new vitality into the old town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the Beilei community, in response to the contradiction between people and dogs who are more concentrated, Yang Yingqi team helped formulate a friendly convention and complete the construction of the community&#39;s pet community. The spontaneous operation of the community has no longer needed coordination and guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months ago, she was building a basketball court for a village, and her funds were insufficient. A wonderful thing happened: friends in the friendly community of people learned about this and took their children to raise funds on the street. The merchants in the community also deliberately contributed their own products as a gift for fundraising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She sighed: &quot;If in the grass -roots governance, when we make people and people have value recognition, when condensed into some strength, they can help people in other places. This good will continue to expand And glowing. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Time clockwise allocated for another five years. The new Chengdu native of Chengdu who moved with his family since his childhood, with the sense of weakness of the public welfare industry, chose this profession. She wants to find a link between people in the urban community. In her understanding, the &quot;community&quot; is not an administrative division or a community concept. It means the community. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So in the early days of each project, Yang Yingqi was looking for such links, looking for the community of this place, and exploring the real needs of the community. In the south, there were projects for villagers&#39; courtyard renovation with 700,000 yuan. Before the Yang team took over, five sets of courtyards had been transformed. The designer entered the venue directly, did not negotiate and respect, and the effect was counterproductive. The owner was very dissatisfied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After Yang Yingqi took over, she told the villagers that she could not obtain the decoration fund for free and need to pay 2,000 yuan, which is the fee paid to the young designer. She asked each household to participate in the entire construction process, and the designer and the owner lived together for 15 days. She also asked each family to reduce the height of the garden wall and try to be transparent. &quot;The entire village does not have high walls, and it is not the appearance of small households. It will form the concept of a large family in the entire community.&quot; This common creation model was promulgated by the Asia -Pacific Office of the United Nations Agency in 2021. &quot;2021 Asian Metropolis Landscape Award&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This creation concept has been running through. In this gradual participation planning action in Chenghua District, the core theme is community motivation, which is inseparable from &quot;community cultivation&quot; and &quot;community growth power&quot;. Yang Yingqi&#39;s &quot;community cultivation&quot; is to combine &quot;from bottom to bottom&quot; with &quot;top -down&quot;. When the community ability is still insufficient, it is appropriately incorporated into external forces. A degree of intervention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Out of interest, Zhu Xiangling also participated in the training course of the community creator. In her understanding, the key step of &quot;building&quot; is to dig out the owner&#39;s consciousness of the community residents: &quot;I think community construction should be the participation of diversified subjects, reaching a consensus on a public problem, and more resources to solve the corresponding problems. After the solution, it is also necessary to empower it. In the end, the two -way change of people and the environment. It is not only a change in hardware, but also changes in everyone. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[共享菜园主理人：带领都市中产感受农田]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261505]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 10:57:58 src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6b8675029d.jpeg&quot; IMG-tital = &quot;Yang Chuangshi in Shu Yue Park. jpeg &quot;alt =&quot; Yang Chuangshi is in the shared vegetable garden. The interviewee confess &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1080 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias /Image/23/11/28/6b8675029d.jpeg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259906 &quot;style =&quot; &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; In the shared vegetable garden. The interviewees confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In Pengzhen, Shuangliu District, Chengdu, this is a manor that is easily missed. On the side of the highway, a section of sand and stone roads leading to the door of a few thin wooden stakes, with a sign hanging under the wooden stakes, &quot;Shu Yue Farming and Reading Garden&quot;. In the garden, the white hut is covered with straw, the fence is divided into small pieces of vegetable fields, and the side of the vegetable field is also stood up with a simple shed made of wood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At 3 pm on October 10th, the weather was gloomy, and the founder of the farming and reading garden was squatting in the field and grabbing bugs in the vegetable field. He said that now the vegetables in his garden do not take pesticides, and sometimes they have to catch insects and strikes accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; 2023 is the fifth year of Yang Chuangshi&#39;s march to agriculture. This year, he opened a 30 -acre small manor on the land rented by Shuangliu District and named it Shu Yue Garden. After people pay as members, they can claim small pieces of land in the park. They can grow vegetables and rice from planting or entrusted the park to harvest crops and participate in the construction of the manor. Yang Chuangshi called him a shared vegetable garden. In Chengdu, where the culture was prosperous, he was naturally a shared vegetable garden manager. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The first side of the 28-year-old Yang Chuangshi, it is difficult to associate him with agriculture. His face was right, wearing glasses, clean clothes, and seeing Sven, there was no old farm&#39;s soy sauce skin and deep gully on his face. However, as long as he said a few words to him, it is easy to detect his enthusiasm for the field. When it comes to extinguishing insects and weeding, he has the head of the head, and there are many local farmers who only understand the earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is after seeing the farm gate. In his hometown in Mangshi, Yunnan, his parents have planted sugarcane for 20 years since he was two years old. After growing up, Yang Chuangshi walked out of the border town and wandered around. In 2014, when he drifted to Shanghai for a year, he consciously bought a house and settled in hope. Suddenly he remembered that his father had worked as a soldier in Chengdu and searched the introduction of &quot;the Kingdom of Tianfu&quot; and &quot;Panda Culture&quot; on the Internet, so he bought a train ticket for Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; When he came to Chengdu, Yang Chuangshi studied undergraduate and did business while doing business. Beginning in 2015, he has developed human resources company and APP development. Later, the app was acquired, and he made a fortune and was in Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Life suddenly leisure. Yang Chuchi spent more than half a year think about it, what to do next. After inspections across the country, in May 2018, he made up his mind -the state advocates rural rejuvenation, and agriculture is worth trying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Many friends advised him to do the risk of agriculture. Yang Chuangshi also knew that he could not prepare all his net worth without preparing. By the team of APP in the past, he first worked for the development of software for large farms, agricultural companies and agricultural travel projects. More than thirty projects followed, and he touched the whole process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2020, Yang Chuangshi decided to do his own farm. He chose the location in Pengzhou City under the jurisdiction of Chengdu, rented dozens of acres of land, and &quot;order agriculture&quot;, which specializes in vegetables. After the customer pays 10,000 yuan a year as a member, he can receive 400 pounds of organic vegetable blind boxes every year. The category depends on the season. Onions, garlic, and vegetables are diverse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Relying on the media to do publicity and promotion, Yang Chuangshi quickly recruited the first batch of about 20 customers. This experimental version 1.0 manor operated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The difficulty of organic agriculture is beyond imagination. Vegetables such as corn and lotus white are easy to grow worms and need to grasp manpower; vegetables cannot be used, and they must be artificially plucking. Live &lt;nS CITE = &quot;Mailto: Hu&quot; Datetime = &quot;2023-11-28t07: 18&quot;>; Child &lt;/ins>; A person is endless, and the employee is 200 yuan a day. Almost half of his expenses were spent on manpower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The number of customers that can be supported by dozens of acres of land is limited. Once excessive, they must open up the fields and hire extra people. The cost is too high. Two years later, Yang Chuangshi rented another 130 acres of land in Wenjiang District. This time, he started a shared vegetable garden -per person paid for dozens of square meters of fields, or herself, or hosted, and maintained the pastoral experience without guaranteeing output. This greatly reduces the cost of manpower and has also attracted more customers who truly love rural life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The number of customers has slowly risen, and Yang Chuangshi encountered the common problems of entrepreneurs-the cooperation with the partner has obstacles. He shifted his position again, but still did not leave Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This is because Shu land is not only suitable for climate, but also convenient logistics and transportation. He told the southern weekend that the land rent of his hometown was much cheaper, but the transportation was inconvenient and the transportation was consuming. In Pengzhen, even in the highest temperature in the summer, the harvested vegetables and ice cubes were put into the foam box. It can be sent to Chengdu area in a few hours. There are several large logistics centers near the manor. He is quite convenient to buy large items to transport items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In June 2023, the farming and reading garden officially started. The factory was set up on the original site. In two or three months, Yang Chuangshi and the other three partners repaired the land suitable for farming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The wasteland ends, and 300 people have claimed the land one after another. Yang Chuangshi said that most of the claimers are the middle class of Chengdu. If you pay 999 yuan a year, you can replace the smallest land -15 square meters. Seeds, agricultural tools, and hydropower are provided by the manor. They cultivate themselves on it. The reasons for people to claim are different. Yang Chuangshi remembers that pregnant women prefer organic foods. Eat eggs only eat soil eggs. The manor does not need pesticides and chemical fertilizers. Considers can grow naturally cooked tomatoes, slightly sour, and can also harvest farm fatal development and non -ripe lettuce. Only one -third of the market is thick. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are also parents who are tired of the education of the &quot;grain without distinction&quot;, and also want to escape the rest day around the mahjong and hold the mobile phone tablet. They will choose weekends or holidays to take their children to the manor to do a few hours of farm work. Spring eggplant, planting pumpkin after the clear and clear, peas in the Mid -Autumn Festival, garlic in October, rotation of four seasons. The claimers are not here on weekdays. Yang Chuangshi and the employment union helped to catch insects. The rest were given to the sky. Tiangong sometimes does not make beauty. In the fall of 2023, the sky was raining, and the vegetable garden was soaked in one -third of the rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; More important is a state of mind. Yang Chuangshi felt that he had developed software in the past, and he did not say the whole words. He did not wash his face and was extremely depressed. He also had high cholesterol and low hemoglobin. Later, when he was drinking tea in the manor, his depressed heart was released, and the indicators of medical examinations returned to normal. He also remembers that a client used to suffer insomnia in the past. After claiming the vegetable land, even if there were mosquito bites, he often went to the manor to work in the afternoon, and his insomnia left him soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are more and more customers, which also gives Yang Chuangshi&#39;s feeling of returning to the countryside. Not only do you help with each other, sometimes you will bring some special -products of sausages and bacon to share, and sometimes you also invite a picnic, &quot;very harmonious&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the basis of &quot;farming&quot;, the manor gradually adds the element of &quot;reading&quot;. Yang Chuangshi invited the academy specializing in Chinese education to try to integrate traditional cultural courses into agriculture. If you have children to grow rice, you can start a class at the field to tell the poems depicting rice in the Book of Songs; they have also done traditional tie -dyeing, wrap the leaves of the plant with flowers, knock on the hammer, slowly slowly, slowly slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly, slowly knock on the hammer. The color is left on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now, Yang Chuangshi has begun to imagine to copy his shared vegetable garden model to the whole country. However, before that, he had a trivial matter to do. Not far away, there is a small piece of white fence surrounded by a small cluster of rose. Yang Chuangshi said that it was a piece of land that built a scum, which could only be transformed with rose. After the rose withered this season, he planned to plant peas. By next year, he is convinced that the vegetables on the ground will grow well. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[酒体设计师：与酒共舞的人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261507]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 10:58:02 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img img-id = &quot;73695&quot; group-id = &quot;0&quot; asset-id src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ab106ca461.jpeg&quot; img-tital = &quot;Jane is doing wine design. alt = &quot;Jane is doing wine design. The interviewee confess&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1080&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/28/ab106ca461.jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259907 &quot;style =&quot; &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Design work. The interviewee confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the 11th year of the job, Jian He found the cup of old brews in Chengdu in Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 11 years ago, Jian He&#39;s occupation had no official name, and the industry was called a hookr. Simply put, he needs a glass of white wine one by one, and 40 glasses of wine is his lowest cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is also one of the secrets of Jianhe to grasp the destiny of the liquor industry, so that it can maintain the perception of liquor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 23, 2023, a wooden table on the Chengdu Office of the Chengdu Office of the Sichuan Provincial Institute of Breeding Research Institute was placed with three rows of glass bottle with white wine. Label. &quot;Fragile incense ... Chen Xiang, Cellar, Qu incense, Honey Fragrance, Baked Fragrance, Grass Scent ... Sweet and delicate, mellow and plump&quot;, the label of one bottle is so written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is the teaching aids when Jane is still becoming an apprentice. He must turn himself into a liquor database, the aroma and style type of thousands of white wine stored in his head, and learn to evaluate the quality of the Chinese. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In most drinks, it can be prepared with &quot;technology and hard work&quot;. Behind liquor is still a complex aroma world that cannot be completely penetrated by equipment and data analysis. The taste is far satisfactory according to the material components and white wines prepared by the equipment. The &quot;design&quot; of liquor, relying on the light of Jian He and his peers, tongue, tongue and incense memory in the brain, determine the ratio between the original wine and the seasoning wine, and &quot;flash rotation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2021, the fourth batch of new professional directory released by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security gave Jian He&#39;s occupation with an official name -wine body designer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jane He is quite deep with this career. More than thirty years ago, his father served as a technical person in charge of a winery in Sichuan, and he grew up next to the factory&#39;s cellar pool. Although his first occupation was in the automotive industry, he still couldn&#39;t give up his love for liquor. In 2012, he entered the Sichuan Provincial Institute of Brewery with the idea of ​​learning white wine in all directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Institute of the Institute in Guanghan, Sichuan, there is an area of ​​20 acres of scientific research bases. Jian He&#39;s first errand is the warehouse of the management base. The small liquor samples prepared by the Technology R &amp; D Center will produce dozens of hundreds of tons in the warehouse, and make the final fine -tuning before the installation. This is called &quot;magnifying the sample&quot;. Even the apprentices are not simple, just taste the adjusted samples in the warehouse, and then push the designer’s matching scheme and design concept. Taste. If you don&#39;t understand, I will go to the technology research and development center to communicate with them. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2014, Jian He passed the assessment and entered the R &amp; D center. In this master&#39;s obvious tradition, a group of young people who just came in worshiped under the door of the deputy director of the supervisor technology and began to learn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a process of assembling a liquor database in the brain. At first, the masters would only tell the characteristics of all kinds of original wines to mix a sample, and finally rely on the apprentices to go to the sample and appreciate it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jane He said that now the equipment analysis has been able to detect almost all the flavors in liquor. It is known that the dance of alcohol, ester, acid, aldehyde, phenol and other substances produced during the brewing process dedicated the complexity of liquor, but the type, content and proportional relationship of the substance cannot Sensory indicators correspond to. Most of the time, apprentices need to call more, with five senses and brains. A glass of white wine, after smelling and tasteing, you need to remember its aroma, taste and style. The best way is to find approximation in your familiar taste and name it. The flavor is near banana, which is recorded as a banana aroma, like pineapple, which is pineapple aroma. First remember the single aroma, and then slowly remember the composite aroma of liquor after the preparation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After passing the assessment, Jian He became a wine designer. In the next 7 years, most of his jobs provided various technical services for winery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most of the small and medium manufacturers need to be designed by wine. Jian He said that before accepting the delegation of the wine body, the designers need to do a survey. If the customer is an unfamiliar winery, he will buy some customers&#39; products from the low to high order, and conduct the evaluation within the institute. Familiar wineries can directly post the other party to post wine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the survey is over, everything is inspired by the designer. They will retrieve the aroma memory of the liquor in the brain, supplemented by the means of physical and chemical analysis, and determine the ideal fragrance, aroma, taste, and style. While taste and blend samples, adjust the proportion of raw wine and seasoning, and gradually approach the taste of expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is like being crossed in the dark, the other side is very close and far away. Jian He remembers that he has designed a five -grain incense wine for a big winery in 2021. At that time, his thinking was to highlight the fragrance of grain, Chen Xiang and mellow. But in the first 8 days, he never achieved the effect. No matter how you tune or combine all kinds of liquor, the aroma is either or the taste is not good. The more you tune, the more you feel in your heart. &quot;I think it may be too tired, the sensitivity of the nose and tongue has decreased&quot;, and then people become irritable. The ideal aroma has been vaguely in my mind, it is almost a little bit, but it is never enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Until the 12th day, Jian He touched his head with a few designers, and some people talked about the aroma that he had brought up when bartender. He flashed his spirit, joined the aroma, and finally achieved his achievements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The wine designer cannot stop in the design of the wine body, but also knows the entire industry chain of liquor production. Jian He said that although they do not directly participate in processes such as raw materials screening and brewing, they have a profound impact on them. When the designer found that the wine made of wine had a odor, he found that there was a problem with the raw material, or the temperature, acidity, and starch content in the period of a certain period of time. After they checked the records and determine the reasons, the manufacturer can optimize the technology of grain selection and brewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Sichuan Guan News, in 2021, there are already 100,000 alcohol design practitioners in Sichuan alone. It was also that year, Jian He was transferred back to Chengdu, who had been gone for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chengdu is obviously the city of his opportunity. Jian He has participated in two studies as the main researcher. One is the research and development and application of the fragrant white wine loss of yellow water. As a result in Chengdu, they passed the review of the provincial scientific and technological transformation results. At the same time, after the epidemic passed, Chengdu also held a series of high -standard wine design competitions. Jian He found that this specifications are the first time in the industry, and he has also won in some competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because of the technical experience that has accumulated throughout the chain for many years, Jian He has also been demanded more to develop a new market. Some customers want them to recommend high -quality original wines in Sichuan, and people who have made steel want to bring capital into the liquor industry and find research institutes to seek plans. Jian He and colleagues have to circle everything. It is best to choose a factory in the five major production areas of Sichuan liquor; it is best to determine where the water sources and microorganisms are determined by the production area; if you make a strong white wine, you must stare at the cultivation of the cellar mud and microorganisms; make sauce wine, and The layout is very important. The high -temperature accumulation process requires enough venues to pile up steamed grain and ingredients ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; to do such a job, Chengdu is undoubtedly the best place. On the one hand, customers from other provinces come to Sichuan, Chengdu is the most convenient point. In addition, the customer needs him to take into account the five major production areas, and the distance between Chengdu and the five major production areas has the most broad radiation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He also has a different feeling for Chengdu. The city grew up almost with him. When I first arrived in 2007, there were still many fields around Chengdu Third Ring Road, and they were still a student. Today, Chengdu has a high -tech zone and Tianfu New District, and with the second round of the city, he has also become a senior wine designer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When in Guanghan, Jian He put his family in Chengdu, but he got together with his family. Back to Chengdu, he can pick up the child home for 10 minutes after get off work. In recent years, many friends in the buildings and sales industries have also returned to Chengdu to start a business. &quot;Chengdu is my blessing.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黄仕忠丨人生真味几悲欢：忆蔡义江老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261477]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 11:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ Image/23/11/28/de2c4257a0.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 709 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/ms/medias/23/11/ 28/de2c4257a0.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259874 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &lt;span style = &quot; Color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Cai Yijiang, born in 1934, Ningbo, Zhejiang. After graduating from Hangzhou University in 1954, he stayed in school to teach. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Laohang University in the early 1980s, everyone said that Teacher Cai Yijiang was a real talent. profound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Cai is from Ningbo, Zhejiang. His respected Cai Zhuping &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (1904-1982) &lt;/span>;, the pen name is deep, and the genius is deep. span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (Zhejiang People&#39;s Publishing House, early edition of 1958, 1982 replica) &lt;/span>;, I have also bought one. His brother Guo Huang also studied classical poetry. Under the guidance of his father, the two brothers co-authored &quot;The Chronicles of the Campaigo&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (1979) &lt;/span>;, etc. Published an article. Such a scholarly door, his brother Ke Shaoqiu, is really enviable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Cai tells us the poems of the Tang and Song dynasties. He wore a pair of black -frame glasses, his skin tone was dark, and when he laughed, his teeth were very white. His voice was bright, the laughter was particularly hearty, and he was very infectious. Everyone said that listening to Teacher Cai&#39;s class is a kind of enjoyment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, Teacher Cai&#39;s academic reputation was mainly from &quot;The Review of the Dream of the Red Mansion&quot;. This book was written in 1974. The following autumn was printed as &quot;Teaching References&quot;. Comrade Cai Yijiang wrote. &quot;&amp; Nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ae3b8da361.png &quot;&quot; &quot;&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1576&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/ae361.png&quot; data- key = &quot;2598755 &quot;>; &lt;img alt =&quot; &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/181559a3c1.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1775 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/181559a3c1.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 259876 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The first edition of&quot; Red Mansion Dream Poetry and Moistus Comment &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the next few years, Teacher Cai adopted multiple suggestions and opinions, and made a great addition and deletion and modification. In October 1979, it was officially published by Beijing Publishing House, and it returned to his personal name &quot;Cai Yijiang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot; has a special position in contemporary China. In the Cultural Revolution, it is one of the few classic masterpieces that are still allowed to read. However, it is not easy to read this book. A large number of poetry and poetry are very embarrassed. At that time, many units organized people to comment. Teacher Cai used the accomplishment of classical poetry to comment on the rhyme in the novel. Since the light car is familiar with the road, this book also stands out from a lot of note. status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1978, he was borrowed in Beijing to participate in the creation of the &quot;Red Mansion Dream Magazine&quot; and the establishment of the &quot;Red Mansion Dream Society&quot;. He has published papers in the &quot;Hangzhou University&quot; for several consecutive years. In 1979, there were three even three articles. In addition, there were many influential papers, which were scattered in the well -known of the &quot;Social Science Front&quot;, &quot;Literary History and Philosophy&quot; and &quot;Literature and Art Research&quot;. publication. At that time, the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; had just ended, and many young and middle -aged scholars had not seen academic paths, and he had stepped forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Mu Xiu Yu Lin, the wind will destroy it. His nature is bold, informal, and identifying this, so he will never return, and even again, and then the three places are on the cusp of the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6407fa6b30.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;Height =&quot; 1455 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/6407fa6b30.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259877 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Mr. Cai Zhuping (1904-1982) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mr. Cai Zhuping, who is 22 years old, joined the Kuomintang at the age Captain Secretary. Later, he served as the secretary of the 6th Division of the 26th Army and the head of the Political Training Office to participate in the Northern Expedition. In 1932, he went to Hangzhou and served as the secretary of the Central Airlines School &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti;&quot; (Honorary President Chiang Kai-shek) &lt;/span>;. In 1936, he went to Nanjing and served as the Secretary of the Central Airlines Commission &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (Secretary-General Song Meiling) &lt;/span>;. In 1938, he transferred to civil affairs and successively served as counties and counties such as Wenling, Huangyan, Yuyao, and other counties and counties. In May 1945, he reported that he was arrested by the National Government in June and was detained in Lishui Prison. He was released from prison in the winter of the following year and went to Shanghai Watson Electric Factory. He also served as the honorary main author of Ningbo&#39;s &quot;Current Affairs Bulletin&quot;. In early 1949, the &quot;Ningbo Morning News&quot; was founded. In April, Chiang Kai -shek, who was in Fenghua, was furious and ordered his alarm. He personally ordered the seal. After the founding of New China, he still works in Shanghai. In June 1951, he was arrested in the &quot;Town Anti -&quot; movement. Although he had long been separated from the Kuomintang, he had a close relationship with Jiang Zhengzheng before, and it was difficult to get rid of suspicion. In 1952 and 1953, the release of innocence was announced twice, all of which were unacceptable. In the summer of 1953, he was in critical condition and he was admitted to the hospital for treatment. In winter, investigators of the East China Bureau of the Communist Party of China believed that he should restore his freedom; at the end of the year, the judge of the Yuyao Court said: &quot;No sin has been found yet, first sentenced for five years; continued to find sin.&quot; After that, &quot;executed by the disease because of the disease&quot;. In 1956, the police station announced that the sentence was over, but there was no judgment. In the summer of 1957, he went to Hangzhou to recuperate. He met Xia Chengzhang through his second son Cai Yijiang. Xia Weng recommended him to edit the &quot;Selection of Lu Fangweng Poems&quot; as the Zhejiang People&#39;s Publishing House. Since then, he has been committed to classical literature research, but the drafts in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; have been copied. In January 1982, he served as a member of the 7th CPPCC of Ningbo City and died in February. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The genes and resumes of the parents often affect the child&#39;s future destiny in the meditation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The young and vibrant Cai Yijiang has always been indispensable: During the liberation of the liberation, his father risked the danger of killing the killing. Being trapped? He heard that his father encountered some uneven things in the detention center, and he actually wrote a letter to the Zhejiang Daily. In the summer of 1954, Cai Yijiang stayed in the school with the first grade of the grade and served as a missionary member of the Teacher&#39;s Youth League branch. Soon, the school received an official letter from the Yuyao County Detention Center, and believed that &quot;Cai Yijiang completely lost the revolutionary position that a young member should have, and suggested to give serious education sanctions.&quot; As a result, Cai Yijiang, who had just won the title of &quot;Excellent League Member&quot; in the school, was &quot;seriously warned&quot;. His father was also allowed to reduce his sentence because of &quot;leakage the secrets of the detention center&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1958, the requirements of college entrance and political trials were strict. The situation of Cai Zhuping affected her children&#39;s advancement. Cai Yijiang, who was qi, sued again, claiming that his father was &quot;retaliated with people and did not give a judgment for many years.&quot; The general branch of the party&#39;s branch organized all the teachers of the department to criticize it &quot;standing on the reactionary position and repeated cases for his father&quot;; In the written report decided by the branch, Cai Yijiang had to sign, but he still believed that &quot;since the judgment was not made, he could not be called a case.&quot; Subsequently, he was decentralized to &quot;labor exercise&quot; in Huantan in Xiaoshan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This incident made Cai Yijiang discriminated against politically. He himself was still acceptable, but the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; ended and resumed the college entrance examination. So he rejected his father and became the knot of Teacher Cai Yijiang again. After the Third Plenary Session, most of the cases of &quot;unjust, false and false&quot;, and &quot;right&quot; have been corrected, but the case in the &quot;town&quot; was generally not reviewed. Unless it is a key united front object of the Provincial Party Committee of the Democratic Party, it can be required. To this end, he applied to join the &quot;Civil Revolution&quot;, and soon added to the Provincial Party Committee of the Revolutionary Revolution, and then wrote to his brothers and sisters to write to his father. He also thought about it: in case of any responsibility to bear it, he stated that he was his personal behavior. Fortunately, everything was smooth. Soon, the Yuyao County Court rehabilitated the wrong case of Cai Zhuping&#39;s &quot;town against&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3243b56d2c.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1376 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3243b56d2c.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259878 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; Mr. Cai Yijiang is in front of his father&#39;s tomb. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Cai immediately reported the situation to the organization, demanding that the two serious warnings on him and the disposal of the group membership. One week later, the secretary of the general branch said: &quot;I can&#39;t find any recorded records or materials in the file. Since I have not been punished, how can I cancel it now?&quot; Teacher Cai said with a smile: &quot;Since there is no, then,&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What is ridiculous is that when Teacher Cai thought about rehabilitation for his father, someone also gave him a lesson in a book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the second half of 1981, the first graduate student he recruited was about to graduate, but the distribution process was a bit long. In order to stay in school, some students made &quot;targeted arrangements&quot; through school leaders and department leaders, which caused the resentment of the ancient literature and teaching room, and then collectively decided to &quot;not leave one person.&quot; The student was quite uncomfortable and wrote anonymous to the newspaper, and slandered a paper published by Cai Yijiang in 1980 to plagiarize the results of a graduate student. For Teacher Cai, who is clear, it is like a head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I don&#39;t believe that Teacher Cai will do such a thing at all, but people are awesome. Vaguely heard that the reporter claimed to be upset as a classmate, and sent a &quot;internal reference&quot; through the alumni of the newspaper in the newspaper, the purpose was to make Teacher Cai embarrassed. Most of the graduate students were more than thirty years old when they entered school. They just experienced the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, and they were familiar with such operations. At that time, the Chinese Department also intended to use this to rectify the wind discipline, so it was a bit of wind and crane. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I later read the letter written by Mr. Guo Zaiyi to his brother Guo Lianyi in November 1977. Speaking of the editorial department of the &quot;Hangzhou University&quot;, he originally planned to post two papers in a row. It is required to postpone another article to the following year. He wrote: &quot;The Chinese Department is the right place. Some people never write articles and cannot write articles, but they are afraid of writing articles. This generation has a means. Kaita, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (The original text is so, when it is&quot; wrong &quot;&lt;/span>;.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The newspaper issued three texts, and others may not have seen it. I have also heard some people discuss: &quot;Red Mansion Dream Poetry and Moisty Comment&quot;, since &quot;organizational discussion&quot;, others have also had credit, but now they are all attributed to one person, so they have made someone unique. Although Teacher Cai explained the work of writing the process with others in the &quot;Postscript&quot;, some people want to think so. It is not only a &quot;rumor&quot;, and it is to make you unable to argue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the study of research, I obviously felt that Teacher Cai was different, and it was no longer as open as before. He gave us three lessons for our graduate, all of which finished the rules, the content was informative, but there was no passion for the past. It may also be the impression of my preconceived. I always feel that he intentionally avoids contact with graduate students, and has the taste of &quot;unable to afford to hide&quot;, which makes me feel faintly painful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, I learned that Teacher Cai was slandered because of slander, and Zeng Gong declined to enroll. The department asked him to bring Wu Xionghe Teacher and temporarily appeased. The two graduate students were recruited. The teacher also seems to alienate the students. After this session, he did not enroll again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In July 1985, I graduated to stay in school. In the winter, a teacher meeting conveyed the &quot;Internal Reference&quot; at the &quot;Guangming Daily&quot;, which was a matter of obituary Cai Yijiang&#39;s theft of student results a few years ago. &quot;Internal reference&quot; said: The manuscript made by Comrade Cai Yijiang was originally &quot;attached&quot; after the text, indicating that the students checked the information by the student, but when the publications were on board, they felt that there was no need to do more. &quot;Knowing&quot; deleted. ——Who knows this delete, it is a &quot;teacher morality&quot; incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At that time, in order to explain the situation, the graduate student Li Mengsheng was invited to record the incident in writing. Thirty years later, Li Mengsheng&#39;s &quot;situation description&quot; and two letters to Teacher Cai spread to Confucius to &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (June 2012 19th) &lt;/span>;. Li Mengsheng wrote that Teacher Cai had gone to the student&#39;s bedroom to talk about the idea of ​​this topic, and sighed that there was no time to check the information. At that time, several classmates were present. Later, a graduate student he instructed to consider the information. The paper was written and published, and was deleted by the editorial department for &quot;Consciousness&quot;. Teacher Cai felt a little sorry. When he received the manuscript fee, he repeatedly said that he would be distributed to the students half. The teacher to check the information is the student&#39;s duty, and he resigned. This kind of humility has repeatedly made the graduate students knowing and led to the use of people with the intention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, even though the facts were clarified, they were &quot;vindicated&quot;, but the scars were still there, and the inner depression could not be resolved. It is both a &quot;internal reference&quot; and the conversation object is limited to the teachers of this department. It can be imagined that he cannot explain to all those who have heard rumors one by one. This slanderous book directly affected his academic research. I observed his post since then: Although it was published from 1982 to 1984, it was mostly submitted before or appreciated. In 1985 and 1986 No articles. Teacher Cai said that from his father&#39;s death, &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (February 1982) &lt;/span>; In fact, this is also overlapping with his slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Around 1986, the Central Organization Department of the Communist Party of China transferred academic reputation and justice from various places to work in the central government of the democratic parties. Professor Cai Yijiang was also selected. Teacher Cai joined the Democratic Revolution, and his ability and influence made him a selection object. Teacher Cai also intentionally changed the environment because the barrier block in the chest was not disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I went to Sun Yat -sen University to study. After hearing that Mr. Cai went to Beijing, he served as the member of the Standing Committee of the Central Committee and the Minister of the Propaganda Department of the Central Committee of the Revolution. . In the new environment, Teacher Cai recovered its vitality again, wrote a lot of papers, published the &quot;Chronicle of Xin Qiji&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1987, and Cai Guohuang cooperation) &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>;, &quot;On the Draft of the Red Mansion&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; (1989) &lt;/span>; and other works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the autumn of 1993, I did a visit to Peking University and went to visit No. 84 Gennan Street, Donghuang City. Teacher Cai enthusiastically introduced his recent Red Study Research, saying that he would re -order the Dream of Red Mansions, the practice is to collect the masterpieces and complete a new comment book. ——The published comments will be published shortly after, and the response is very good. Recently, the Business Press issued a revised version, &quot;Cai Yijiang&#39;s New Relution of Red Mansion Dream&quot;, which is a haircut collection, which is loved by readers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/20FBed5431.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1128 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/20FBed5431.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 259879 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; The new version of &quot;Cai Yijiang New Rights Red Mansion Dream&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I felt the excitement when he was talking about academics, and noticed his loneliness. Because I have left colleges and universities for many years, these can only be regarded as &quot;amateur&quot; work. His red studies are &quot;unique&quot;, but it also means that even the two -three &quot;heart people&quot; are difficult to find. He was angry with the bad atmosphere of the red academic community at that time, and believed that &quot;the most evil -three -not -style style of academic articles&quot;, that is, regardless of common sense, whatever means, and irresponsible. In order to correct the time and disadvantages, he wrote continuously and discussed with others, offending many people. I thought it is not necessary, because &quot;academic&quot; and &quot;non -academic&quot; were in the original line of the original line, but looking at the teacher is so true, I dare not say much, I just remembered the popular words at the time: after all, it was a scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since then, Teacher Cai is still active as a red scientist, but the talented classical poetry research experts have since voiced. As a disciple of a generation of poetry sect, Xia Chengzheng, he also published &quot;Three Hundred Songs of Song Ci&quot; after retirement &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kai style_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; (2007) &lt;/span &lt;/span >;, &quot;Song Ci Selected Complete Solution&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2013) &lt;/span>; -Family: Kai style, Kai style_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (2020) &lt;/span>;, etc. In addition, the study of ancient poetry, which he was most powerful that year, had only one &quot;Song Poetry Essence Records&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot; (1999) &lt;/span>;, is Li Mengsheng The proposal and cooperation; another book &quot;Selection of Huang Zhong&#39;s Poetry&quot; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2011) &lt;/span>; Planning was planned, and it was only completed after 30 years. These are popular readings, and some are revised and expanded by the same content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking back at Teacher Cai&#39;s academic experience, I found that their generation has almost no stable time to lay the foundation and study academics. Two sueds in the 1950s made him hit and was distributed to the farm for many years. In the early 1960s, shortly after returning to school, he encountered the &quot;Four Qing&quot; campaigns. The &quot;social education&quot; had not ended. In the early 1970s, when most of the ancient literary works could not be read and studied, he was fortunate to find a small oasis in the desert. At the beginning of the peers. Who knew that when he was full of pride and soaring his wings, he was folded by a dark arrow and folded his wings. Although the official duties continued to cultivate the territory of the Red Studies, the home of classical poetry was deserted. After leaving Hangzhou University, he never recruited graduate students, nor had he had the opportunity to bring doctoral students, and his mantle had not been passed on. Besides, the years are ruthless, and suddenly the old realm! Many ideas have not been implemented, and the talents have passed silent at any time. This is not only his own unique sadness, but also the common subject of a generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Boy is not sensitive. He thought that Teacher Cai was a temperament, and he was interested in the waves, but in the turbulence of the times, he encountered the reef from time to time. Following forward, there is no real time. This life is stunned! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this point, I can&#39;t help but think of Mr. Qu Chan, the teacher of Teacher Cai&#39;s &quot;Shi Tian · Show Zhejiang University Cong Tour in the Disease&quot;, Word Cloud: &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: Kaita, Kaiti_GB2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Listen to the cuckoo in the night and night. The annual belongs to the river ship. When Hua Wei faithful, the depression was cold first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Laugh in the same language, also front. Life is really sad. Friends of the lamps are painted, and they are good at younger brothers and sisters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xia Laohui&#39;s eyes have already seen through the world. For teachers and students, but also the front. &quot;Life is really sad and happy&quot;, indeed! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3FF79782c.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 898 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/3FF799782c.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 259880 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; November 13, 2023, when the author of the Japanese in Japan met Teacher Cai. Photo by Zhao Yanfang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (this article refers to &quot;Mr. Cai Zhuping New Year&quot; and Cai Yijiang&#39;s &quot;Search memory residue&quot;; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[报名人数一增一降，考公还是考研？回顾20年上岸大数据丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261464]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老房子卖给国企当保障房，多地跟进“以旧换新”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261483]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-29 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;Aerial Paida Taicang Tianjing Lake Scenic Area. Visual China/Figure&quot; src = &quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/570ed3992e.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot;//images.infzm. COM/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/28/570ed3992e.jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 259882 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Taicang City Tianjing Lake Scenic Area. Visual China/Picture &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 24, 2023, the second batch of commercial houses in Taicang City, Jiangsu Province, &quot;replaced the new with the old&quot; registration ended. According to the official official of the Propaganda Department of the Taicang Municipal Party Committee, the citizens can sell the eligible second -hand housing to the state -owned enterprise, and then set up a new house designated by state -owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Taicang is the county -level city -level city in Suzhou. In 2022, GDP was 165.357 billion yuan, ranking sixth in various cities in Jiangsu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Taicang Release&quot; has explained the policy intention of changing the old new policy. On the one hand, it supports improvement of the demand for house purchase, and on the other hand, it is to enrich the types of talent apartments and affordable housing supply. &quot;After the old house purchased is transformed into a talent apartment or the affordable house, the distribution of the listing will be wider, and there will be more room for citizens to choose.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Except for Taicang, since 2023 More than ten cities have been promoted to change new commercial houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Initially, it was initiated by developers in Yangzhou, Jinan and other places; after that, industry associations such as Zibo, Nanjing and other places organized developers and intermediary agencies to &quot;sell old and new&quot;; , Combine with affordable rental housing. During the evolution of the model, the participation of local governments and urban investment platforms became higher and higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Old House&#39;s Byset Payment&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the old -fashioned new plan of Taicang, second -hand housing is sold to state -owned enterprises, and new houses replaced are also developed by state -owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Taicang Release&quot; introduced that the first batch of optional houses included 3 communities, all developed by Taicang Urban Development Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Chengfa Group). The second batch of extensions to 8 communities, Taicang City Construction Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Urban Investment Group) also participated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The company&#39;s investigation shows that the two companies are controlled by 100%of the State -owned Assets Supervision and Management Office of the Taicang Municipal Government. Southern Weekend reporters consulted in the name of home buyers, and many of the buyers who participated in the old real estate introduced the replacement process: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chengfa Group or Urban Investment Group will conduct price evaluation of second -hand housing. New house models are deducted from 60%of the total price of the new house. The new houses purchased were developed by these two state -owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;It is equivalent to using the old house to the first payment.&quot; One of the positions of the industry said. Suppose you want to replace a new house of 3 million yuan. The maximum old house can reach 1.8 million yuan, and the remaining 1.2 million yuan can be loan to the bank. If the old house is worth more than 1.8 million yuan, state -owned enterprises will not be cash back, but it can be replaced with a new house worth more than 3 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this process, the acquisition of second -hand housing for state -owned enterprises does not need to invest additional funds. 60%of the deduction ratio restrictions to ensure that they still have cash to account for new houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This also means that the new house changed by the owner must be more expensive than the old house, but compared with selling old houses and buying new houses, it is greatly shortened with the old replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A real estate agent in Suzhou told Southern Weekend reporters that the average sales cycle of local second -hand housing is 89 months. A real estate agency in Taicang said that if you want to sell a house, the listing price is 100,000 to 200,000 yuan lower than the market price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Participate in the old replacement of the new. According to the two state -owned enterprises&#39; real estate consultants, all processes can be completed in just two or three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The one -location consultant of Chengfa Group also reported. The real estate she was in charge was on the designated list of the policy. The old house on her hand was not easy to sell, and she decided to try to replace the company&#39;s new house directly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(replacement of the old) is suitable for old communities that are difficult to sell.&quot; She told the southern weekend that the old and poor second -hand houses are currently not sold on the market, but as long as it is a 70 -year property residential house The construction area is below 144 square meters, and the old can be replaced by the old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the &quot;Taicang Release&quot; report, most of the first batch of residents who signed the &quot;replacement of the old&quot; mostly lived in the old communities in the old town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter of the Southern Weekend called the 8 communities designated as a new home. It was learned that 6 of them were regular housing. Most of them were newly opened improved real estate. Two or three years later, the house was concentrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Follow up in many places &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In fact, Taicang, which has been released earlier, is not large with the old and new scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The first -level industry consultant of Taicang City Fa Group introduced that the first batch of only 100 places for the old replacement, 200 people participated in the registration, and finally sold only thirty or forty sets. Because after registration, many owners have given up because of unsatisfactory listings and prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The second batch of quota expands to 800, 500 Cityfa Group, and 300 Urban Investment Group. In the 8th communities, there are only dozens of new houses in each community, most of which account for less than 1/10. As of 5 hours before the registration, the number has not been reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Multi -location consultants told the south weekend reporter that second -hand houses that want to replace must settle loans. After the replacement, if the new house has not been delivered, it is necessary to pay the rent to the state -owned enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Following Taicang, Lianyungang City, Jiangsu Province has also launched similar policies. The Local Housing and Urban Construction Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Further Promoting the Real Estate Market in the Real Estate of the Housing Consumption&quot; on October 17, 2023, and proposed to explore &quot;selling old and new&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The specific policy is to develop a development project that has not been constructed and contains affordable housing. Use of housing or talent room. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; A staff member of the Lianyungang Housing and Urban -Rural Development Bureau introduced to the reporter from the south weekend that the specific participating state -owned enterprises were Lianyungang Urban Construction Holdings Group Co., Ltd., and second -hand housing was acquired by the company. &quot;The replacement new house is estimated to be developed by the company.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; But the current policy is still in the exploration stage, and specific details such as replacement methods and existing house transformation have not been drafted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Haining and Lishui, Zhejiang Province, will be directly subsidized by finance and encourage housing companies to acquire stock housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, Haining proposed that the financial subsidy of 2%of the total purchase funds to the housing company purchased the stock house, and Lishui gave the old house transaction taxes for 100%subsidy. Among them, individuals purchased second -hand housing. The transaction tax subsidy subsidy and house purchase subsidy is high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Haining requires that the main body of the purchase and new commercial housing sale must be the same real estate enterprise. A reporter from the Southern Weekend consulted in the name of buyers. A staff member of the Local Housing and Urban Construction Bureau said that the government did not designate which housing companies could replace it and did not limit it to state -owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Specific developers&#39; selection and replacement prices are negotiated by owners and enterprises. The second -hand housing acquired by the developer is also handled by itself, and there is no notice as a affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; The real estate enterprise undertakes the secondary sales profit and loss &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The earliest, the old replacement is mainly based on the marketing of industry associations and private enterprises as the main body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On September 6, 2023, the Zibo Municipal Real Estate Development Association, the Municipal Real Estate Broker and Evaluation Association jointly launched a new signing ceremony of the old replacement. The first 12 developers and intermediary agencies signed a cooperation agreement. According to the list released by Zibo Daily, the participating subjects are mainly private enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A staff member of the Zibo Real Estate Development Association told the Southern Weekend reporter that this measure is more accurate to say &quot;selling old and new&quot;. It is mainly to help customers sell houses through additional push and drainage, and then replace the new houses that deliver the deposit and lock the house after the old houses are sold. If they are not sold smoothly, the deposit will be refunded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mainly shorten trading time and save transaction costs.&quot; The staff member said. In addition to Zibo, this model has also adopted this model in Nanjing, Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before that, there were also private developers replaced the old way by acquiring second -hand houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiangsu New Energy Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as New Energy Real Estate) at the end of September launched a new event. Its official micro -introduction, the company provides two modes of direct replacement and commissioning. The latter is similar to Zibo that the company commissioned an intermediary agency to help the owners sell old buying new. The former was directly acquired by the new energy real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Southern weekend reporters consulting in the name of home buyers, a staff member of the company said that this event is still ongoing. The replacement new house must be developed by new energy home ownership, and second -hand housing can be a product of other developers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She introduced that the company had launched the old replacement as early as 2016, mainly to promote the sales of new houses. In the direct replacement mode, the old house is valued and acquired by the company, and then resold to the market. The company is borne by the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The key is that the new house required for new energy home ownership must be twice the price of the old house. It has requirements for the age, location and elevator of the old house, and the loan must be basically settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jinan Greenland Lansing Mansion also launched similar direct replacement activities in August 2023. Real Estate Real Estate Consultants introduced to the South Weekend reporter that the owners participating in the replacement must pay the house to the company in accordance with the evaluation price of Greenland Group (600606.SH), and then buy a new house developed by the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like new energy home ownership, Greenland Group has higher requirements for the quality of old houses acquired. In addition, when the owner receives the old house repurchase, it is necessary to pay the company&#39;s purchase of new house purchase funds, and the new house they purchase is about 40%higher than the total price of the old house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Qilu Evening News, about two months after the activity was launched, the Greenland Lanting Mansion replaced more than 30 houses. Greenland Group also copied this model to some projects in Qingdao, Weifang, Linyi and other cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A senior real estate practitioner in Jinan analyzed the reporter from the southern weekend that under the current market conditions, it is not cost -effective to transfer the rent after acquiring second -hand houses. Acquisition at a lower price, and then selling more likely to the market. But the essence is still to promote the sales of new houses, and second -hand housing is not the focus of profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Xiaoling, the research director of the company of Kerry Research Center, wrote a new report with the old replacement. She told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why localities were intensive to launch new measures for the old replacement were mainly due to the current poor liquidity in the second -hand housing market, which limited the release of improving the demand for house purchase, and provided a path for breaking this dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to her observation, there are also differences in the new effects of different modes in different modes. With the current difficulty of refracting the new house and the large number of second -hand housing listings, many urban effects that implement the intermediary -to -sell model are not obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The effect of direct replacement is more intuitive, but the acquisition of second -hand housing has certain requirements for the amount of funds of developers. There are not many real estate companies that choose this model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>