<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[划着轮椅，出门去]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259854]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvVquGUPdTNq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvV quGUPdTNq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tianye in his Chuanchuan store picture/provided by MYBank Charity Store Alliance&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sea is blue and you can&#39;t see the edge at a glance. To the outside is a beach filled with vacationers. Further outward is the main road, which is flat and wide. A wheelchair is coming from a distance and is moving from the asphalt road to the seaside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Sanya, Hainan. The soft and fine sand shows high quality, but it is a challenge for wheelchairs. The wheels of the wheelchair sank easily, and Ye Ye sat on it. Someone had to pull him backwards and forward so that he could move slowly. Little by little, and then little by little, the beach and the sea came to the young man at a slower speed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most difficult situation when going out is that you often have to wait, &quot;waiting for someone to help you show up.&quot; Tian Tian recalled the journey with me several times. For example, from the main road to the beach, a half-meter-high iron railing blocked his eyes. Others could step over it in one go, but he could not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Skating, playing, and driving, before the age of 17, the young man from Xi&#39;an was very active in the fields and saw a future that was &quot;omnipotent.&quot; In 2004, an accidental car accident caused him to become a high-level paraplegic and he could only sit in a wheelchair since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While waiting passively, he and other &quot;injured friends&quot; in wheelchairs encouraged each other and went out to draw a map of barrier-free facilities within the third ring road of Xi&#39;an&#39;s main city. Mark the existing problems and open the way out. It took 3 months, 4 wheelchairs, and 15 hours a day to create a barrier-free map of 597 square kilometers. Thousands of marks were made in three color categories, covering all the main roads in the Third Ring Road of Xi&#39;an. The relevant departments cleaned up accordingly. Obstacles, more ways out appear in the eyes of people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Along the way, they have encountered a lot of criticism, &quot;Why can&#39;t we just take a detour? Why do we have to take this road?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t want to take a shortcut, I just wanted to Take the original path.&quot; Tian Ye sat in a wheelchair and repeated this answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Injured Friends&quot; push wheelchairs together on the barrier-free passage Picture/Microfilm &quot;Hey, Come Out&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Precise physical needs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;One wheelchair met another wheelchair, more and more, five or six people driving wheelchairs gathered in the open field, &quot;Hey , come out!&quot; After a simple greeting, they started the competition - wheelchair racing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The track is very long and needs to go through some barrier-free passages. Slight irregularities on the road may cause the wheelchair to slow down or even pause. This is the road they have driven on countless times in wheelchairs. Irregularities were marked, fed back, and resolved one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the race is over, they will meet for a meal at a Chuanchuan restaurant in Tianye. There, people with disabilities receive a 50% discount on dining, and it is a regular gathering place for &quot;injured friends&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for several days, I never waited for such a scene. In mid-September, it was the rainy season in Xi&#39;an. The rain lasted for more than ten days, separating the previous summer from the following winter. &quot;There is no autumn in Xi&#39;an,&quot; the locals say. The weather turned from hot to cold in the blink of an eye, leaving no time for preparation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even after living in Xi&#39;an for decades, the &quot;injured friends&quot; still feel uncomfortable even with slight changes in the weather. When the rain comes, they can&#39;t get out even more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s not easy to get together. They are slowly getting used to it, just like many details in life, they need to adapt again and find a new order in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They need precise control over their physical needs. For example, drinking water, the simplest thing, needs to be done regularly, quantitatively, and managed accurately. Otherwise, it will be impossible to control the timing of defecation and defecation, which will make it more difficult to go out. It is impossible not to drink water. Some people have tried it to treat bladder system infections and urinary tract infections. Problems will ensue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the filming of the micro-film was completed, Tian Ye and the crew took a group photo&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the Online Merchant Bank Charity Store Alliance)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speed of drinking water must also be controlled. If you drink too fast or too hard, the water will flow from the throat to the bladder too quickly, and errors will occur. A five-minute time difference will be enough for a wheelchair when going out. It could mean an accident lasting more than two hours. The two-hour trip was compact: find a suitable spot, clean yourself up, then open the door and walk onto the street, pretending that nothing had happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Developing a tacit understanding with the body requires coping with seasonal changes. For example, in summer and winter, people sweat differently, and the corresponding drinking patterns are naturally different. The exploration of every tiny pattern comes from the fact that &quot;injured friends&quot; cannot resist the temptation to go out deep in their hearts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 50% discount skewers shop opened by Tian Ye is also one of the temptations for &quot;injured friends&quot; to go out. When he was 17 years old, he suffered an accidental car accident and became paraplegic. He relied on a wheelchair to travel and became a member of the &quot;Injured Friends&quot; circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I saw Tianye was at his home. Urinary tract infection is one of the common diseases among injured people. Tian Tian has just returned from the hospital for infusion. He is sitting in a wheelchair, his body tilted to one side, and the tail end of his speech hangs on the ground, with the exhaustion of struggling to maintain his strength. He has sneakers on his feet, and he needs help from time to time to move him, making sure he is on the pedals of his wheelchair. When chatting for a long time, he needs to move. The effect of gravity will make his feet more and more uncomfortable until he asks the people around him for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time, this person is his father. &quot;Dad, drink water.&quot; &quot;Dad, Coke.&quot; There is no need to thank you, explain, or any other reason. A long time will reduce such a conversation to the most direct expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ye Ye lives in Qujiang New District, Xi&#39;an City, where there is an average of one public restroom every few hundred meters, equipped with barrier-free restrooms. Tian Ye sat in an electric wheelchair and drove skillfully to a public restroom near his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Open the door of the barrier-free bathroom. The facilities inside are complete. There are facilities where babies can be placed on horizontal boards while they lie down to change diapers, and there are facilities where babies can be fixedly seated on one side for parents to use the toilet. There are also facilities with handrails for people with disabilities to use the toilet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, only those who actually use it can feel the subtle differences. Tian Ye pushed his wheelchair and walked to the mirror. He couldn&#39;t see himself in the neat and clean half-length mirror. Tian Tian explained that the mirror needs to have a certain tilt so that you can see your face from a low position. I tried to bend down and lower my head so that my line of sight was at the same height as his head in the wheelchair. I no longer dare to call it a &quot;slight&quot; difference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two sides of the barrier-free passage leading from the main road to the bathroom are not smooth, but standing aside, you can&#39;t tell the abnormality. &quot;Both sides are uneven,&quot; Tian Ye&#39;s father measured it with his hands. The relevant road regulations stipulate that the error cannot exceed 2 centimeters. &quot;Within 1 centimeter (error) does not affect the wheelchair going up and down, but there is at least a 5 centimeter error on this road.&quot; Until Tian Ye&#39;s wheelchair slowly moved up, it pushed hard several times. If I don&#39;t get up, a sudden acceleration may cause it to roll over. Only then do I realize what the slightest difference in sight means to a wheelchair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Ye then explained the classification of the blind walk he just walked through: there are two types of blind walk bricks. The strip-shaped ones are guide bricks, which guide the blind people to move forward safely and securely. These are called marching blind walk bricks; the other kind They are dot-shaped reminder bricks that are used to remind blind people that there are obstacles ahead and they should make a turn. These are called blind trail bricks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t understand anything before,&quot; Tian Ye smiled and began to recall the point where he &quot;understood&quot;, which was an accidental car accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tianye’s Chuanchuan shop has become a gathering place for &quot;injured friends&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the Online Merchant Bank Charity Store Alliance/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A show for everyone&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The gray-white Santana passed by, and the license plate number stayed in Tianye’s heart, and he could still blurt it out many years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the car passed by, life in the field was &quot;moving&quot;. He was born in 1987, and his ancestors have lived near the Big Wild Goose Pagoda in Xi&#39;an for generations. Tian Ye has been naughty and active since he was a child, and likes to watch martial arts movies. The famous scene of &quot;The Lion King&#39;s Fight for Hegemony&quot; in &quot;Once Upon a Time&quot; starring Jet Li left a deep impression on him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, he went to a martial arts school and practiced martial arts for two full years from the age of 13 to 15. When he was young, he loved roller skating. He was always the best and fastest skater. At that time, there was a popular game called &quot;train driving&quot;. A group of people were dragged forward and backward, sometimes straight, sometimes diagonally, changing formations. The person driving first was called the &quot;locomotive&quot; and asked whether the train was fast or not. &quot;It all depends on the head.&quot; Tian Tian always plays the role of the locomotive. With a background in martial arts school, his speed, balance and strength are outstanding, &quot;like autumn leaves falling in the air&quot;, he can do side flips and splits easily, and he can pull more than a hundred people while pulling a train. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I stopped studying and learning martial arts. I drove a bulldozer and repaired cars in the field. At the construction site, except for tower cranes, he has driven all other &quot;cars&quot; that can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This speed stopped when I was 17 years old. In 2004, Tianye was involved in a car accident. After saving his life, he stayed in the ICU (Intensive Care Unit) for 21 days, which cost him no idea how much money he spent. Then he lay in bed for another eight months, becoming skin and bones. It was the most painful period in his life. Tian Ye recalled that at that time, he was over 1.7 meters tall and weighed only 70 to 80 kilograms. His ribs were clearly visible, and he could be seen clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next 10 years, his parents took him to seek medical advice everywhere, including specialist hospitals and charlatans. I don’t know how many folk remedies and secret recipes have been tried, money was spent, and hardships were endured, but the person failed to stand up. &quot;Kaizi (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;local dialect, meaning &#39;fool&#39;&lt;/span>;) was deceived, and Dangdang was different,&quot; Tian Ye lamented the state of the family at that time , unwilling to accept the facts, always feel that I can still stand up, and I should be able to stand up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unable to find an exit in reality, Tianye kept a dream in his heart. In the dream, he entered a temple. Many monks were meditating and knocking wooden fish. He knelt in front of the Buddha statue. Suddenly the door of the Main Hall opened, and with a golden light, an old monk came in. He said to Tian Tian, ​​&quot;You should have gone to hell.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Tian was puzzled and asked crying, &quot;I am so kind, why not What terrible bad things have you done? Why do I have to go to hell? Why do I have to sit in a wheelchair?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The monk replied, &quot;Sitting in a wheelchair is already very good. You were going to hell.&quot; The monk was in the air Drawing a circle, it looked like a TV. In it, Tianye saw that he was a prince. He ran into a temple during the fighting and knocked off the head of a Bodhisattva statue with a wooden stick. After reading it, Tian Ye cried loudly in his dream and continued to cry when he woke up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After crying, although the dream was illusory, Tian Ye seemed to have found some reason for comfort outside of reality. He was no longer confused, no longer felt targeted by fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about the node of change, Tian Ye pondered for a while and talked about &quot;mission.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What is your mission?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I am performing a play, and the audience is everyone. I used to be a very naughty child, and I had an accident. Some people say that it is retribution, or karma, because I was too naughty before, and others would use me to educate their children. At first I felt disgusted, but later I was happy, and my experience became the opposite of what parents should do to educate their children. Textbook - &#39;Don&#39;t learn from Tianye&#39;. From here, I slowly found the direction of my life and was no longer lonely.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianye decided to open a skewers shop. It was first opened in a community. In May 2013, from eight briquette stoves, an umbrella, and a few benches, to sixty or seventy stoves, sheds, and prefabricated houses, it &quot;became stylish.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the summer of 2021, Tianye and &quot;injured friends&quot; experienced barrier-free facilities at Qujiangnan Lake in Xi&#39;an&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewees/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2021, the store moved to a shop about 1 km away from home. &quot;That was the best time for business.&quot; The 120-square-meter store can accommodate hundreds of tables every day, and there are so many people that it can&#39;t accommodate them. Half a year later, the store expanded again, and Tian Tian changed the lease to a 300-square-meter store next door. In the middle of the month after the move, cases of new coronavirus pneumonia appeared in Xi&#39;an. In November 2021, Tianye&#39;s Chuanchuan store closed just after it opened. For the entire year of 2022, the store was closed for 180 days and suffered a loss of hundreds of thousands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By 2023, Tian Ye thought that the epidemic was gone, policies were relaxed, and everything would get better, but business has slowed down. In mid-September when we met, the store was being renovated, and Tianye wanted to use a new look to welcome back its former prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Should the new store install a barrier-free bathroom?&quot; I looked at him and asked at another rice noodle shop in Tianye. This rice noodle shop may not be able to open anymore. Tian Tian wants to alleviate some of the financial pressure so that he can start it again in the future. The rice noodle shop&#39;s rent expense is about 90,000 yuan a year, and its business is not doing well. He analyzed that it is because the location is not good. While we were chatting in front of the store, light rain fell from time to time. This store is sandwiched behind an office building. There are several fast food restaurants nearby. The business is not very good. There are few pedestrians on the street on rainy days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that he had considered installing a barrier-free bathroom, but it was still unrealistic. Fortunately and conveniently, there is a public restroom about 100 meters away from the Chuanchuan store. There are barrier-free facilities there to facilitate &quot;injured friends&quot; to solve toilet problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the store opened, people with disabilities will receive a 15% discount when they come to the Chuanchuan store in Tianye. In May 2021, the MYbank Charity Store Alliance was established, and Tianye’s Chuanchuan store joined. With the support of MYbank, it launched a set meal activity for people with disabilities to eat skewers at half price. Wang Ye is the initiator of this charity store project. She introduced that the main users of the platform are small shop owners. While doing this charity project, she wanted to know who the “shopkeepers” were. During the epidemic at that time, Wang Ye first came into contact with the owner of a dumpling restaurant in Xi&#39;an. Some people came to Xi&#39;an to look for jobs but could not find jobs and had spent all their money. The boss posted a piece of paper at the door to the effect of &quot;It&#39;s no big deal if you have difficulties. Come in.&quot; Eat a bowl of dumplings for free.&quot; The charity shop project gave the dumpling shop owner a subsidy of 10,000 yuan. &quot;How can there be such a sincere person? He is obviously very difficult.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Wang Ye discovered Tianye&#39;s Chuan Chuan shop and also gave him 10,000 yuan in support. &quot;Injured friends can eat Chuan Chuan at 50% off.&quot; ” activity is online. Wang Ye&#39;s task is to find 1,000 such stores across the country. &quot;1,000 is our upper limit. We don&#39;t look for people who are determined to do charity from the beginning, because it will be difficult to persist. We look for people who are already in the normal business.&quot; run.&quot; After contacting many such small charity shops, Wang Ye lamented that charity does not rely on emotional impulse. It requires a sense of purpose and values ​​​​in the heart. It cannot be a temporary passion, but must always be a belief, &quot;I Know what I&#39;m doing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256497&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the filming of the micro-film, director Wang Ye (first from left) and the injured experienced wheelchair travel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Photo provided by MYBank Charity Store Alliance)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Leave it to time to present&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to Chuan Chuan store, Ye Ye and the wounded friends’ charity territory “It’s also about creating an accessibility map. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2018, Tian Ye and six people with disabilities he met jointly raised funds to establish the &quot;SCI Wingless Flying&quot; charity center. &quot;You want to fly even if you don&#39;t have wings&quot; is their original intention of establishing &quot;Wingless Flight&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the establishment of &quot;Wingless Flying&quot;, Ye Ye and the wounded friends spent three months conducting a road barrier-free environment survey within the third ring road in Xi&#39;an. The idea was originally proposed by &quot;wounded friend&quot; Huang Yuan of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yuan, 52 years old, was involved in a car accident in July 2011. The 9th to 12th ribs of his chest were injured. Since then, he has needed to use a wheelchair to travel. In a wheelchair, he ran a half-marathon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to going out with &quot;injured friends&quot;, he feels less pressure. The most difficult thing may be the problem of temporary toileting. For example, if you cannot control your bowels and bowels well, especially stool, you have to return home or clean yourself little by little in the accessible toilet, which can take an hour or two. &quot;Injured friends&quot; can completely understand each other with a look or a word. They can give full understanding without explanation, because they have &quot;equal bodies.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most serious problem with his body is that he has no feeling. His thigh swelled three times its original size after going out once, and the injury was not discovered until then. The scar on the right leg was left in May 2022 and is still not healed. He rolled up his trouser legs, and there were deep and shallow scars on his uneven calves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to going out, Huang Yuan is always full of smiles. &quot;Injured friends&quot; drove wheelchairs on the road to observe, and if they found any problems with barrier-free facilities, they took photos and sent them to Huang Yuan, collecting tens of thousands of photos. Huang Yuan finally selected the 5,000 available photos and made them into an electronic map. This requires a lot of behind-the-scenes work, such as reversely reading the coordinates from the GPS, then mapping the photos to the corresponding locations and marking them with markers of different colors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This electronic map is distinguished by different layers: one is divided according to administrative regions, and the other is classified according to reasons, including irregular design, inadequate construction, and later damage and loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Huang Yuan’s experience, most of the design plans are in place because there are standard drawings. However, during the construction and supervision and acceptance processes, problems sometimes occur and &quot;look-alikes&quot; appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After three months of research, Huang Yuan compiled the &quot;Investigation Report on the Status of Accessible Facilities in Xi&#39;an&quot; and produced a special electronic map of the distribution of accessibility problems in Xi&#39;an, clearly marking every existence Location, image representation, cause category, etc. of accessibility issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results of the investigation were sent to the relevant road administration departments by email, and some of the problems were corrected. The map and report are still kept in Huang Yuan&#39;s computer, even though the &quot;Public Welfare Center&quot; is currently unable to maintain due to insufficient funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete investigation was not there at the beginning. It was initially a sporadic &quot;love post&quot;. Liu Sifang took out a pile from under the coffee table. The pink post-it note had the words &quot;I am a disabled person and your vehicle blocks the barrier-free passage&quot; printed on it. He also had a pile in his wheelchair backpack and took it with him when he went out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Sifang is 60 years old this year. When he was 50 years old, he suffered from a vascular attack and leaked his carotid artery. The doctor told him that there were no more than 50 cases of people suffering from this rare disease worldwide. In 2014, he underwent surgery at Xi&#39;an Medical College, and his life since then has been inseparable from crutches and wheelchairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Sifang keeps several parrots at home. They fly around the room, sometimes landing on their shoulders and sometimes on their heads, adding a bit of life. He gave these birds names, which was a lot of fun at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about making love stickers and barrier-free access maps, Liu Sifang mentioned, &quot;It is to find a reason to go out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was originally a sporadic love sticker, but later it hurt Friends thought, &quot;Forget it, just run by yourself and be a whole person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The people who check and accept are not disabled.&quot; When talking about the problems encountered in using barrier-free facilities, Liu Sifang has more options Understand: You will encounter non-compliant &quot;slope problems&quot;, and some make barrier-free passages into gravel roads, maybe for the sake of appearance, but small-wheel wheelchairs cannot go there, so you have to use large-wheel wheelchairs, which limits some wheelchairs. Travel... Such details can only be truly understood by sitting in a wheelchair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acceleration is addictive. In order to let more &quot;wounded friends&quot; go out and to encourage themselves, for 3 months, 4 wheelchairs, and 15 hours a day, the &quot;wounded friends&quot; of the small shop walked out of Xi&#39;an. A barrier-free map of 597 square kilometers, with 3 colors and thousands of markers, covering all the main roads in Xi&#39;an&#39;s third ring road. The &quot;injured friends&quot; are called the &quot;little princes of wheelchair racing&quot;. They often meet in the suburbs of Xi&#39;an to compete in wheelchairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going out is a dilemma and a temptation. The farthest place Tian Ye has ever been was Sanya, which was five or six years ago. Facing the sea, with the sun on his head and the beach at his feet, drinking ice-cold watermelon juice and wearing sunglasses, he seemed to be in a new world. It was the Spring Festival, and it was the middle of winter in my hometown of Xi&#39;an, thousands of miles away. The wind was blowing and the snow was shining. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is not good at expressing himself. How can he describe the sound of the waves? Speaking of that kind of remoteness, Tianye&#39;s gaze lengthened and became farther and farther, passing through the wall in front of him. A faint smile appeared on his face, and he seemed to hear it again, that &quot;like the spring in Xi&#39;an&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Waiting for someone to help you appear&quot; is the good luck you may need when going out. Just a few days before our interview, it rained heavily in Xi&#39;an. There was something going on in the store that had to be checked. Tian Ye drove his electric wheelchair out and accidentally fell into a puddle on the side of the road. He didn&#39;t notice it because the rain was so heavy that the puddle was covered. The mother saw that he hadn&#39;t left for a long time, so she came back to look for him along the road, only to find her son kneeling on the ground, half of his body soaked in water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were not many pedestrians on the rainy day. A woman wanted to help, but she was not strong enough. Later, a man came and several people worked together to rescue Tianye. The wait took half an hour. &quot;There were also people who passed by but didn&#39;t help,&quot; Tian Ye added lightly at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you go out, you will hear voices of opposition, &quot;Disabled people can&#39;t do anything, just stay at home. Why go out? It will only cause chaos to society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianye is not satisfied with this. He felt angry when he said, &quot;A normal society should be an inclusive society. It should not only tolerate people, but also small animals, flowers and plants on the road.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the contact, Wang Ye felt the affection of Tian Ye Optimism has a sad undertone. &quot;He is not heartless or painless. He will have many moments of contemplation. The difficulties he encounters are all business-related. Physically, he is used to it.&quot; In Wang Ye&#39;s eyes, Tian Ye is a store owner who operates with heart. &quot;I would rather introduce him as a hard-working person and a store owner, rather than introducing him as a person with a disability first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 years Before, I had the idea of ​​writing a book. Sitting in a wheelchair, Tian Ye talked about the past intermittently. He wanted to write about his life. The window was behind him, and the rain was pattering outside, making the room a little cool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have not thought about the beginning and the end,” Tian Ye answered my question about the book “A Lifetime”. “Maybe life is meaningless, but it does not mean that it should be spent casually. I know my own No matter what the script looks like, I will still act it out.&quot; In this book, he wanted to tell it step by step and use time to present it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黄仕忠：怀念郭在贻老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDVbVt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDV bVt. png&quot; data-key=&quot;256610&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi (1939-1989). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo Zaiyi is fundamentally a very proud person. More than thirty years after his death, I read a long letter he wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi on November 21, 1977. He talked freely about calligraphy schools and famous calligraphers at that time, and criticized Fang Qiu. in this way. The depth of calligraphy attainments seen in the handwriting astonished me. Because he knew what he said, it flowed out naturally from his mind. To him, it was just a normal conversation with his brother. Since it was a private letter, there was no need to be restrained, so he spoke frankly and heartily, rather than pretending to make shocking remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256609&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Zaiyi wrote to his brother Guo Lianyi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1988, Teacher Guo worked with students to complete the first draft of &quot;Review of the Dunhuang Bian Anthology&quot;. A friend wrote in a letter: &quot;This manuscript is devoted to our own opinions. We are confident and not without inventions. There are many unique secrets in the research and interpretation of common words and proverbs.&quot; It is also full of confidence rather than boasting. This tone can be seen or heard in his letters and conversations with friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo and I only exchanged words occasionally. He is not tall and his eyes are not big, but they are bright and bright. When he glances past with slightly squinted eyes, he seems to be condescending, which makes me feel uncomfortable. Health shrinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, he had just passed his forties, and his body seemed to be condensed with infinite energy, shining so brightly that it was impossible to look directly at it. Especially in the field of Chinese history, he is the person who carries the banner after Jiang Liangfu and Jiang Lihong. In July 1986, with the approval of the Discipline Review Group of the State Council, the Chinese Department of Hangzhou University welcomed a new group of doctoral supervisors after Mr. Jiang Liangfu. They are: Shen Wenzhuo, Jiang Lihong, Xu Shuofang, and Guo Zaiyi. The first three are all over 60 years old, and Mr. Guo is only 47 years old. He was the youngest doctoral supervisor in the field of humanities and social sciences at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was an undergraduate (1978-1982), he offered elective courses for the 1978 and 1979 students. I didn’t choose them at the time, but I have looked up to him for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, several students in Grade 77, influenced by Teacher Guo’s ancient Chinese class, spontaneously formed an interest group to carry out research on word exegesis. One of them is named Bian Xincan, who is from my hometown, and we are the same age, so we have a lot of exchanges. He said: &quot;Teacher Guo is knowledgeable and humorous in class. One of the sentences touched me very much: &#39;Discovering a new meaning is like discovering a planet.&#39; It can be said to illuminate my soul.&quot; So he dived into ancient books. In the pile, I made cards and copied words. By the fourth grade (1981), I published papers in &quot;Hangzhou University Journal&quot; and &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. He was only 21 years old that year. His graduation thesis was also supervised by Teacher Guo. I have read his paper published in &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;. The words he explained are well-documented and convincing. They are exactly the same as Mr. Jiang Lihong&#39;s &quot;Explanation of the Meanings of Dunhuang Bianwenwen&quot;. He said that after the article was written, he cautiously submitted it to Mr. Jiang Lihong, and received enthusiastic guidance and recommendation to &quot;Hangzhou University Newspaper&quot;; the article in &quot;Chinese Language&quot; was accepted by his own submission. At that time, many teachers were struggling to write papers and therefore could not be promoted, so this incident left a deep impression on me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yimin, Zhang Yongquan, and Ji Weiqiang in the interest group also published papers in influential professional journals when they were in college or early after graduation. Yimin said that he was slightly excited when he saw his name listed with Mr. Ni Baoyuan, a teacher from Hangzhou University, in the catalog of &quot;Chinese Language&quot;. Yongquan re-entered Hangzhou University two years after graduation and studied for graduate school with Professor Guo, opening up a new world in the field of Dunhuang colloquial word research. Behind this, you can see the figure of Teacher Guo Zaiyi. They were just undergraduates, but under Teacher Guo&#39;s guidance, they achieved such outstanding results. As a student at the time, I admired him very much and could not imagine how great he was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was in the autumn of 1982 that I was admitted to the graduate school of ancient literature at our university after graduating from my undergraduate degree. Teachers Guo Zaiyi, Zhu Hongxi and others recruited six graduate students in ancient Chinese, including Fang Yixin, Chen Baiye, Jin Xiaochun, Guo Xiaowu, Wang Yunlu and Ye Qing. The boys&#39; dormitory is next to each other. Yixin, Baiye and I are undergraduate classmates, so I often visit them and listen to their discussions. Teacher Guo asked me to read through the paragraph notes of &quot;Shuowen&quot; first with punctuation. At that time, there was a photocopy of the notes, with a purple cover and a large format. Each of them had it open on the table. It was very solemn and quite showing off, because &quot;our Teacher Guo&quot; believed that this was the right way to get started, and Teacher Guo himself ordered it. Read it three or four times. This made me very envious, and I bought a copy. However, I hesitated repeatedly on whether to read it through, and finally gave up, because at that time I was working on &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Han Dynasty&quot; under the guidance of Master Xu Shuo. There is not enough time for comparison of books. In the second academic year, I returned to opera from &quot;History&quot; and &quot;Han&quot; and systematically read through the basic literature on Yuan and Ming opera. In fact, I was indirectly influenced by Teacher Guo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave his graduate students a course on &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, and I also took the course. This was the first time I walked into his class. It was an eye-opener and I was hooked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256607&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;When Teacher Guo was young, he was full of sunshine. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Guo Xianyu)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo is from Zouping, Shandong, and has a strong accent. For me, a Zhejiang native, it sounds a bit strange. The pronunciation of the characters is quite difficult to distinguish. Even so, his lectures were engaging. He first put forward examples and listed different theories, and then laid out his evidence, one, two, three, four, as if he were doing vertical arithmetic problems for primary school students, with clear layers and a clear view. In fact, it is extremely difficult to select examples for exegesis. Unless you are very familiar with the semantics of words and their origins, you will not be able to find accurate examples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, I only thought that it was enough to understand some &quot;methods&quot; of exegesis. I only had a superficial taste of Mr. Guo&#39;s thesis, and my understanding was not deep enough. Teacher Guo is based on his own years of research and combines the results of his predecessors to provide supplementary extensions and demonstrations in class. The core content has been published. One article is &quot;Exegesis of Chu Ci&quot;, published in &quot;Literary History&quot; (6th and 14th series, 1979, 1982); the other is &quot;Explanation of Vernacular Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, published in &quot; Chinese Language, Issue 6, 1983. In 1984, with these two papers, he won the second prize of the first Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences (a total of three people won the award, the other two being Li Jiahao and Jiang Shaoyu from the Chinese Department of Peking University). This award was established after the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; by Mr. Lu Shuxiang with a donation to commend young scholars (limited to those under 45 years old). There was no first prize in the &quot;first edition&quot;, so this is the highest award. Two years later, he was approved as a doctoral supervisor. It is said that Mr. Xu Fu greatly appreciated his research and strongly recommended him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have mostly forgotten many of Mr. Guo’s incisive explanations, but some of the “methods” he taught played a real role in my subsequent academic research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Teacher Guo introduced the concept of continuous words, which are mostly double-sounding rhymes that must emphasize their sounds. There are different writing methods with similar sounds, and they cannot be broken into single characters for explanation. He also said that some of them were discovered by Mr. Jiang Liangfu. Mr. Jiang&#39;s famous work &quot;Collation and Annotation of Qu Yuan&#39;s Fu&quot; was completed when he was only 29 years old (originally written in 1929 and completed in 1931). I looked through the &quot;Chu Ci&quot; and found that dozens of words are continuous words. However, most of the annotated versions of contemporary scholars still use split words for explanation. In other words, just relying on &quot;continuous words&quot; as a trace gave the young Jiang Liangfu many new insights. His graduation thesis at Tsinghua University, &quot;An Examination of Shi Sao Lian Mian Zi&quot;, was supervised by Wang Guowei. Wang Guowei keenly listed the discussion of Qing Confucianism as a special topic. He only pointed out the problem in one article and gave the topic to the students. The students followed this and expanded it to open up their own fields. This allowed me to see the necessity of mastering &quot;academic principles&quot; and &quot;criteria&quot;, and at the same time I also learned the importance of &quot;family law&quot; and &quot;teacher-to-teacher inheritance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Guo gave a wonderful explanation in class on the difficult words in Chu Ci, as well as the words that scholars in the past considered &quot;unexplainable&quot;. From Wang Yi, Zhu Xi, Hong Xingzu, to Guo Moruo and other contemporary Chu&#39;s famous masters, they all revealed some weaknesses in front of his exquisite &quot;solution&quot;. He stood above the high platform in this field and pointed out Jiangshan. In addition to the solution, it will also tell us some tidbits, and the words will be proud. He said that he would buy one of the new Chu&#39;s notebooks and checked it again. Most of them were thrown through, because there were no new opinions. At the same time, he will write a letter to some bets, showing that I have read your book, and also given a hint: &quot;You use Guo Moruo and Wen Huaisha, you will specify; Instead of talking, I actually know! &quot;After that, he closed his lips tightly, sideways slightly, raised his chin, leaving a freeze in my mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; —— I then know that a scholar is recognized and requires a process of accumulation of qualifications. This allows me to face the same thing calmly in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Guo Zaiyi was the most dazzling of young scholars at that time. This also made us very curious. How did he stand out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is said that in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, he is a &quot;Xiaoyao School&quot;, and he brought the book &quot;Chu Ci&quot; related books in the data room. His &quot;Chu Ci Jie&quot; was written after reading hundreds of relevant information. In the meantime and fans, there is a self -described story to testify: one time I went to buy meat and lined up, he could read the book with a book, and when he woke up, he found that the sky was dark. , He was alone, standing there and read the book for a long time. But at that time, &quot;the more knowledge, the more reactionary&quot;. Reading these things only had negative effects, so many people joked to him. And one of his old classmates, on talent, or not under him, &quot;Smart&quot; is far more than him. He actively invested in the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and once became a &quot;three kinds of people&quot; after the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;. When he returned to his teaching position, Guo Zaiyi had shined in the academic community. He only felt pain and started. From this to form a consensus, scholars should stay away from &quot;exercise&quot;. At the same time, there are also rumors that Teacher Guo is not very good because he is too hard -working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the summer of 1985, after graduating from graduation, my graduate stayed in school to teach, distributed the dormitory of teaching workers, and lived in a room with her classmate Hui Xiaochun. Xiaochun&#39;s graduation thesis was directed by Teacher Guo. In the following year, I heard many stories of &quot;our teacher Guo&quot; from him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I have to say that I have a story related to Teacher Guo. In the fall and winter of this year, Teacher He Chunhui and I went to Shanghai to send the review materials promoted by teachers in this department, involving teachers such as Wu Xionghe, Cai Yijiang, Guo Zaiyi, Ni Baoyuan. I am responsible for the experts in literature, and Chunhui is responsible for the experts in language and literature. She said that when she saw Mr. Shi Cunzhi of East China Normal University, she was very enthusiastic and had high evaluation of the teachers of Hangzhou University, especially Mr. Guo. I have been promoted to the titles of my respectable division. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xiaochun got married a few years ago. His wife was from Hangzhou. The family was very good. He moved to live in a new house, and he rarely returned. But when I come back, I will always share the story of &quot;Teacher Guo&quot; with me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Spring and summer in 1986, due to the promotion of the title, Teacher Guo improved the treatment and added some new furniture. He was very happy and fiddled with Xiaochun&#39;s newly purchased objects. Xiaochun and the teacher are between the teachers and friends, and sometimes deliberately fight with the teacher. I remember Teacher Guo was proud of his newly bought double sofa, and Xiaochun teased: My family is a three -person sofa! Teacher Guo said with a moment, saying, &quot;Hey, I won&#39;t compare with you.&quot; Just looked left and right, appreciated himself, and couldn&#39;t hold back the joy of his heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Listening to Xiaochun Dao to say such small stories, our common feelings are a kind of indispensable bitterness. Fortunately, all this will become the past. The teacher&#39;s vision is full of sunlight! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This fall, I was admitted to the PhD in Sun Yat -sen University. Soon after Xiaochun also went to the United States to do academic exchanges, and I rarely heard the news of Teacher Guo. More than two years later, in mid -January 1989, the news of the death of Teacher Guo Zaiyi suddenly came, and I was stunned! Is it ordered? It is nothing to say, he can only pray silently, and I hope he is good in heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many years later, I learned about Mr. Guo&#39;s final situation from Zhang Yongquan&#39;s article. On the afternoon of the B-ultrasound, the afternoon of the liver cancer, Teacher Guo endured the great pain of spirit, and wrote a suicide note to the students: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style_ GB2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Yongquan, Huang Zheng: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; hurriedly farewell. You have to work hard to complete our scientific research plan, and strive for all three books to comfort me in the spirit of heaven. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Please ask you: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span stylele = &quot;FonT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Please collect the articles that I have not included in the &quot;Training Draft&quot;, compile a sequel, and strive to publish it in a few years (of course it is impossible now), for the case, for it, for a few years, for a few years (of course), for a few years (of course it is impossible), for it, it is not possible. I earn some manuscript fees to make up for my family members, but I personally have nothing to do. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: right;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbbb sp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaiti, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; November 5, 1988 &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What a proud person, at that moment, I did not forget his&quot; &quot;Scientific research plan&quot;; for the sake of family members, I can only say humblely that I hope to &quot;earn some manuscripts to make up for my family members&quot;, and I still have to declare: &quot;I personally ask for nothing.&quot; Reading this &quot;will&quot;, Why not make people cry! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Guo endured the pain and entered 1989, but in the end, he was unable to return to heaven. One day away from his 50th birthday! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I later read the memories written by Fu Jie: &quot;In the last days of life, there are fewer and fewer words of Yi Master -both have no spirit and because of melancholy. Lying on the same way, the lost eyes did not look at us around us, just looked at the ceiling, and suddenly sobbed, making our young us Zhang emperor. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; also confirmed the day of confirmation, He said to Yongquan: &quot;The situation is not good, I have made thoughts, but pity their orphans and widows ...&quot; But even two days before his death, he also said to Yongquan: &quot;Fang Yizhi &quot;Tongya&quot; is a good book. If you come, buy one for me. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; How nostalgia he is! Because he has too many things to do, there will be a plan of &quot;Dunhuang Three Books&quot; recently. It is implementing with his disciples. There is a pair of children who are still studying in middle school. Unwilling, but helplessness, and no one can say with the complaint, only the eyes of the loss of God only look at the ceiling &quot;,&quot; more than once &quot;,&quot; suddenly sobbing &quot;... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG SRC = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/tq1a69pfkbbm4sznlJCFH0LD3EWP1R0BJZZFOS3I.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 960 &quot;height = &quot;652&quot; data-src = &quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; This photo, or the last summer, frowned slightly, without melancholy. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Guo Xianyu&#39;s picture/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Guo Zaiyi left the world, it is more than thirty years in a blink of an eye. This year is only eighty -four years old, but what kind of world will it open for the research of Chinese history! His classmates later accumulated and made their scores academically, and now they are healthy. If life can be selected again, how will people choose? Xia Chengzhang said to his friend Wang Jisi: &quot;Ji Si, learning is not desperate by his life.&quot; However, life is alive, and he has nothing to do with the times and society. Moreover, &quot;articles hate their lives&quot;, even if they are proud of them, they will not be able to fight for fate! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“无级别”5年后，国家消防救援指挥机构明确为副部级丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259954]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-03 23:06:50 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/03/VDVT8TLSJA7WV8VICSDRRSCSPHIA2SNVY6PXV3HQ.jpg &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1126 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;674&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm/medias/i Mage/23/11/03/VDVT8TLSJA7WV8VICSDRRSPHIA2SNVY6PXV3HQ. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 256986 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; On the morning of August 29, 2023, the National Fire Rescue Bureau Zhejiang Mobile Team added The presence ceremony was held in Tonglu. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (People&#39;s Visual/Picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After 10 months of listing, the &quot;Three Plan&quot; of the National Fire Rescue Bureau was finally announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 31, 2023, the preparation of the establishment of the establishment of the Chinese institutions clearly stated that the National Fire Rescue Bureau is the National Bureau Managed by the Emergency Management Department, which is the deputy ministerial level; There is a political member; a total of 275 administrative establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to the Emergency Management Department, since October 2023, the Central Committee&#39;s Office densely announced the preparation and adjustment information of the responsibilities of multiple other ministries and commissions, involving the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, and the National Health and Health Commission , People&#39;s Bank of China, the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One of the important reasons for the &quot;three -fixed plan&quot; of the National Fire Rescue Bureau is that the Fire Rescue Bureau of the Emergency Management Department and the Forest Fire Bureau of the Emergency Management Department of the Emergency Management Department before the integration was established in October 2018, It has not been clearly clear. The two institutions merged in January 2023 to form a National Fire Rescue Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this way, the leadership command agency of China&#39;s fire rescue team has been in a &quot;levelless&quot; state in the past five years until it is clearly explicitly become the deputy ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The management system and institutional settings of the fire team have changed several times. In October 2018, the Public Security Fire Force and the Armed Police Forest Forces withdrew from the active service, the construction system was placed under the emergency management department, and the national comprehensive fire rescue team was formed. Among them, the management agency of the Public Security Fire Force was changed to the Fire rescue bureau of the Emergency Management Department, and the management agency of the Armed Police Forest Force was changed to the Forest Fire Bureau of the Emergency Management Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One year later, in November 2019, the Central Office of the Central Committee issued a notice to clarify the fire rescue bureau and the Forest Fire Department of the Emergency Management Department. Unclear team administrative level. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Notice also shows that since August 22, 2018, there are three years of &quot;trial running periods&quot;; during the running period, timely regulation of the number of leadership positions in accordance with the running situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;磨合期满之后，2022年2月印发的《“十四五”国家应急体系规划》则进一步明确，要“将消防救援队伍和森林消防队伍整合为一支正规化、 Professional and professional national comprehensive fire rescue team &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After that, another year later, on January 6, 2023, the National Fire Rescue Bureau, which was integrated from the Fire Rescue Bureau of the Emergency Management Department and the Forest Fire Bureau, was officially listed. It has passed for another 10 months from the listing of the National Fire Rescue Bureau to a clear administrative level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The &quot;Three Plan&quot; of the National Fire Rescue Bureau clearly states that the National Fire Rescue Bureau has the first political commissioner and the main responsible comrades of the Emergency Management Department will serve as concurrently. The political member of the National Fire Rescue Bureau is also the director of the Political Department of the Emergency Management Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, news from the website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security showed that Wang Xiangxi, Secretary of the Party Committee and Minister of the Emergency Management Department, has also served as the first political member of the National Fire Rescue Bureau. Xu Ping, a member of the Party Committee of the Management Department, served as a political member of the National Fire Rescue Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the &quot;Three Plan&quot;, the sign of the National Fire Rescue Bureau Command Center will also be added to the Emergency Command Center of the Emergency Management Department. Concurrently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the same time that the &quot;three -fixed plan&quot; of the National Fire Rescue Bureau was announced, the functions of the Ministry of Emergency Management also adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The responsibilities of the Fire Rescue Bureau of the Emergency Management Department and the Forest Fire Bureau, and the national comprehensive fire rescue team assigned by the Education and Training Department for education and training related responsibilities are transferred to the National Fire Rescue Bureau; The bureau also increases the duties of formulating firefighters withdrawing and resettlement plans and organizing implementation to establish and improve the responsibilities of emergency joint command platforms. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At the same time, the Emergency Management Department continues to fulfill the relevant work of the national comprehensive fire rescue team&#39;s duties, deployment, commendation, rewards, punishment, martyrs&#39; assessment and other related work in accordance with the principles of the first -level management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Personnel movement &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; The Ministry of Civil Affairs changed coaches, Lu Zhi was the secretary of the party group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs, and Tang Dengjie was transferred to the Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Xinhua News Agency on October 28, 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China decided: Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Before the new performance, Tang Dengjie served as the secretary of the party group and minister of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. The Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee was previously held by the Blue Buddha An, and he has replaced Liu Kun as the Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After Tang Dengjie was new, Lu Zhiyuan was the secretary of the party group of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. Lu Zhiyuan has worked in Shaanxi Province for many years, served as deputy secretary and mayor of Yulin Municipal Party Committee, Secretary of the Weinan Municipal Party Committee, etc. In January 2018, he was promoted to deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. Minister. In September 2021, Lu Zhifang was transferred to the Standing Committee of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee, and later served as Deputy Secretary of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Qingdao Municipal Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Zheng Zujie adds new positions of the National Development and Reform Commission] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; November On the 1st, the news of the network showed that the 21st issue of &quot;Seeking&quot; in 2023 published Zheng Zujie&#39;s signature article- &quot;Deep Cultivation for Jiu Jiu for a long time to advance the&quot; Belt and Road &quot;high -quality development&quot;, the author&#39;s introduction at the end of the article shows that Zheng Zujie, director of the National Development and Reform Commission, has served as the director of the Office of the Leading Group of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; construction work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Olympic champion Chen Ruolin to adjust the general swimming management center of the accessories] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; Recently, the Personnel Department of the State General Administration of Sport issued a public announcement saying that according to work needs, Chen Ruolin was assigned to work from Beijing to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Ruolin, female, born in December 1992, a bachelor&#39;s degree, is currently the coach of the Swimming College of Nanjing Institute of Physical Education. Chen Ruolin entered the Jiangsu Diving Team in 2000, and was selected as the National Diving Team in 2005. He won the 2008 Beijing Olympic Women&#39;s Single and Double 10 -meter Championship. Olympic women&#39;s doubles 10 -meter champion. She is also a coach of Quanhong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Supreme Law: Liu Shaoyun is a first-level judge of the People&#39;s Republic of China] &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; On October 28, 2023, the Supreme Law issued an announcement that according to relevant regulations such as the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, Liu Shaoyun was the first -level judge of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Anti-Corruption Chronicle &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; From January to September 2023, a total of 405,000 people were disposed of in the country] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection on October 29, from January to September 2023, the national disciplinary inspection and supervision organs received a total of Letter and visits reported 2.617 million times, of which 819,000 reports were reported in reporting and complaints. The disposal of the problem clues was 1.283 million, including 266,000 conversations. 470,000 cases, including 54 cadres in the case, 2480 cadres at the department and bureaus, 20,000 cadres at the county office, and 65,000 township -level cadres; the current or former village party branch secretary and director of the village committee 46,000 people. 405,000 sanctions, including 331,000 party disciplines, 108,000 government sanctions; 34 provincial and ministerial cadres, 2,244 cadres at the department and bureau, 16,000 cadres at the county department, 54,000 township -level cadres, generally, generally There are 56,000 cadres, 277,000 people such as rural and enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [still does not stop after retirement, He Zehua, former deputy director of the National Tobacco Monopoly Bureau] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the WeChat public account of the &quot;Procuratorate Justice Network&quot;, the former deputy director of the National Tobacco Monopoly Bureau He Zehua was suspected of accepting bribery and using influence and bribery. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Dalian City, Liaoning Province was reviewed and prosecuted. Recently, the Dalian People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution to the Dalian Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He Zehua was the deputy of Ling Chengxing. In May 2013, when Ling Chengxing served as the party secretary and director of the National Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, He Zehua had been a member of the National Tobacco Monopoly Party Group and deputy director for nearly 10 years. On October 23, 2023, the website of the National Commission for Discipline Inspection issued a notification that Ling Chengxing, the former party secretary and director of the National Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, were suspected of serious disciplinary violations and were undergoing disciplinary review and supervision investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Hunan&#39;s children&#39;s children asking children to take care of each other] &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, Hunan, Hunan The Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision held the provincial leading cadres to use their powers or influence to promote the special rectification work promotion work of relatives and friends. The meeting emphasized that it is necessary to focus on the supervision focus, and we must focus on the three categories of key content of 3 categories such as illegal business -oriented enterprises, &quot;playing!&quot;, &quot;Basketball&quot;, and including the children of leading cadres. Typical performance, strengthen education management and supervision, and resolutely stop the crooked wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hunan information shows that cases such as Yi Pengfei, former vice chairman of the Hunan Provincial Political Consultative Conference, exposed the problems such as the children of leading cadres asking each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Bringing nearly 50 million yuan, former Secretary of the Political and Legal Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee Wang Xinghua for 13 years] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 31, 2023, the first instance of the Rizhao Intermediate People&#39;s Court publicly sentenced the former Standing Committee of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee and former secretary of the Political and Legal Committee Wang Xinghua to accept bribery. It is also fined RMB 4 million; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Ministerial information &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; National Health and Health Commission: Promote the addition of infant childcare services such as secondary vocational and higher vocational colleges] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 1, 2023, Wang Bin, director of the General Office of the National Health Commission At the press conference, it will promote the major of infant care services in secondary vocational, higher vocational colleges, and high vocational colleges, and promote the development of childcare support services for medical institutions, and gradually improve policies, standards, standards, and service supply for childcare services. , Further promote the continuous optimization of population policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Ministry of Cultural Tourism: Elimination of some national non-heritage representative project protection units] &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to CCTV news reports, recently, the protection unit self -inspection, inspection and evaluation of various localities and soliciting procedures for the project inheritance of the project, the review of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, have 2981 protection units who have passed the assessment; If the evaluation is unqualified, the qualifications for the application of national intangible cultural heritage protection funds will be suspended, and rectification will be rectified within a time limit; the three protection units will not perform their duties in their due diligence, relieve their protection units, re -identify the protection unit; Major changes, do not have the basic conditions of the protection unit, re -identify the protection unit; identify the three protection units with vacancies before before; 12 application areas or units do not identify the protection unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Rule of rule of law &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; Since 2017, there have been more than 4,200 cases of cultural relics illegal cases] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 30, 2023, the Supreme Prosecutor and the State Administration of Cultural Relics stated at the joint press conference that since 2017, since 2017, since 2017, since 2017, There are more than 4,200 cases of cultural relics in the country, and more than 650 people are held accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot;&quot; Women Married Girls &quot;land acquisition compensation and resettlement standards are not uniform, procuratorial agencies have issued procuratorial suggestions] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In response to the problem of incompatible resettlement standards during the compensation of the &quot;marrying girl&quot;, the procuratorial organs have issued procuratorial suggestions to promote the formulation of unified compensation standards for administrative organs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Supreme Procuratorate said that whether &quot;marrying a woman&quot; should be compensated for resettlement and whether the compensation resettlement standards are consistent, it is related to the personal interests of women. In the land acquisition compensation and resettlement, the &quot;marrying girl&quot; registered by the rural collective organization separately should enjoy the right to resettlement compensation, and use a separate household to compensate for resettlement in accordance with the unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Debug was sentenced to innocence for 902 days, and the former richest man in Hubei won 590,000 yuan in compensation] &lt;/&lt;/ SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On October 24, 2023, Lan Shili received the Criminal Compensation Decision made by the Guangzhou Procuratorate. &amp; nbsp; On December 17, 2021, the Guangzhou Intermediate People&#39;s Court tried that the charges of alleging Lan Shili could not be established, and Lan Shili was not guilty. Three days later, Lan Shili was released. The &quot;Criminal Compensation Decision&quot; determined that Lan Shili was detained to restrict personal freedom for a total of 902 days, and it should receive more than 590,000 yuan in state compensation. &lt;br>; &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Public reports show that Lan Shili, born in 1960, was born in Wuhan, Hubei, and appeared on the Forbes rich list with a net worth of more than 2 billion yuan in 2005 to become the &quot;richest man in Hubei&quot;. He is also Dongxing Group Group And the founder of Dongxing Airlines. In 2008, the global financial crisis broke out, Dongxing Airlines was also affected and eventually went bankrupt, and Lan Shili fell into a lawsuit. In 2010, Lan Shili was sentenced to 4 years in prison for evasion of the tax owed by the recovery office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Science and Education News &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; Hangzhou Education Bureau: The risk seminars will be carried out in the school&#39;s cultural and sports activities] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the news of the Hangzhou Municipal Party Committee and the Hangzhou Government website on November 1, the Hangzhou Education Bureau recently replied to Hangzhou Twelve No. 146 CPPCC No. 146 recommends that &quot;ensure that the school dares to implement sports education from the court&#39;s decision&quot; and &quot;multiple guarantees to prevent parents from excessive accountability&quot;. Volunteer principles, advocate parents to purchase comprehensive insurance for students (children). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Guangdong Provincial Education Department: It is strictly forbidden to enter the campus such as &quot;radish knives&quot;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p >; &lt;p>; Recently, a new type of toy called &quot;radish knife&quot; has become popular in elementary and middle school students (young children) groups. Recently, the Guangdong Provincial Department of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Management of Harmic toy Education&quot; (referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;), requiring all primary and secondary schools and kindergartens to prohibit such dangerous and harmful toys entering the campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Internet transmission Wei Dongyi was fired, Peking University rumor] &lt;/span>; &lt;p>; Recently The information about Wei Dongyi, an assistant professor of Peking University, was circulated on the Internet. On November 1st, Chinanews confirmed to the above -mentioned information from the School of Mathematics and Sciences, where Wei Dongyi was located. The staff of the College Comprehensive Division stated that Wei Dongyi is still working. The staff of the college&#39;s propaganda office said, &quot;No news from receiving any changes.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At present, on the official website of the Department of Mathematics at the School of Mathematics of Peking University, Wei Dong Yi&#39;s resume information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Local political conditions &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&quot; The Xinjiang Free Trade Zone was established] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 1, 2023, the 22nd Free Trade Zone in China -Xinjiang Free Trade Zone was established, becoming China in Northwest China The first free trade test area established along the border area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Kunming: cancel the sales of commercial housing restrictions] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &quot;Kunming According to the &quot;news, on November 2nd, the official website of the Kunming Municipal Government issued the&quot; Notice of the Office of the People&#39;s Government of Kunming City on the abolition of a batch of real estate policy documents &quot;, which decided to abolish the relevant real estate policies issued in 2017 and 2018, which means that the previous releases were released in the past. All commercial housing restrictions on purchase restrictions are canceled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [Changchun Three-child parenting subsidy plan for landing: require local household registration, one time subsidy of 10,000 yuan] &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to recent news from the Changchun Municipal Government&#39;s website, the husband and wife will have a one -time subsidy of 10,000 yuan per child. The conditions are: both husband and wife are household registration in Changchun (including the husband and wife of the husband and wife, the other party is an active military person, or both the husband and wife are active soldiers). Three -child and above children are settled in the city of the city, and have been registered for fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;strong>; Sound &lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&amp; nbsp ; Lou Yangsheng: Henan today pays attention to innovation than ever, and is threatening talent than ever before.] &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 27, 2023 At the opening ceremony of the 3rd China · Henan Open Innovation and Transnational Technology Transfer Conference, the Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, Lou Yangsheng, said: &quot;Henan is an important birthplace of the Chinese nation and the Chinese civilization. The talents are emerging, the invention creates shining, and the love of respect is the wind. &quot; FAMILY: Kaita, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (Comprehensive from Xinhua News Agency, CCTV News, Shangguan News, Central Discipline Inspection Commission State Supervision Commission website,&quot; Kunming Release &quot;WeChat public account, CCTV, Chinanews, Guangzhou Daily Client, surging news, etc.) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃货文人”梁实秋丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259949]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-03 22:31:22 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男性没有情绪价值需要”是偏见：互相取暖才能行稳致远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259842]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-03 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Among the many values ​​that one person can provide to another, emotional value is the most reflected &quot;interactive nature &quot;One of them. If the two are interacted and lost the &quot;courtesy&quot; about emotional value, and make the emotional value only become a supply of one party, then it must show that the power and status between the two people are not equal. Continuously provide emotional value, the so -called &quot;low low&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The relationship between the sexual relationship should generally be a peer relationship. It is a normal relationship to respect each other and please the other party. In this sense, men&#39;s needs for emotional value are often ignored, which is a problem that cannot be avoided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A blogger said that men actually need emotional value very much. He mentioned a typical example: an Internet old man complained on Weibo, talking about his middle -aged crisis, his emotional collapse For a moment. Old Internet men usually appear as &quot;friend of women&quot;, so they have accumulated a certain amount of female fans. As a result, when he began to complain, he did not get the sympathy and comfort of his female fans, even if he always provided emotional value to his female fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The blogger said with emotion: Some women seem to think that men must be very happy and should not complain and complain. And they are complaining all the time, even if many times they are very happy to outsiders, but they can always find some complaints. These women seem to have a collective consciousness. &quot;Do not make men feel happiness, and must not make men get emotional value. As for why, I can&#39;t understand it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is the words of my heart. Of course, a couple can always raise a lot of examples of respecting each other or pleasing each other. However, according to my observation, men are always more likely to be frustrated in the process of getting emotional value from women. What Fang Hongjian met in his wife in &quot;Siege City&quot; was this sense of frustration. When not married, the relationship between the two was okay. Sun Roujia gave him a special psychological satisfaction in the adversity. But after the marriage, Sun Roujia seemed to change a person, making readers feel a little incredible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Blogers believe that men are not all for sex with women. If a woman hangs the emotional value every day to play the limit, all men who have a little self -esteem will eventually leave -for example, Fang Hongjian has intended. Of course, the way to leave is different. Many men find that &quot;the emotional value that women can&#39;t give, brothers can give, games can be given, and even fishing can be given.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is a &quot;straight man&quot;, which not only explains the reasons why there are many &quot;fishing guys&quot; gathering in front of the river in front of my house, but also explain some middle -aged men. The principle of always playing games before getting home or staying downstairs for a while before entering the door: They know that there are endless complaints and endless mental loss in the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is the case, as the blogger said: In the past many years, men&#39;s demand for emotional value has been suppressed. So many women think that men only need to pay. The reason why this deformity is barely maintained is because a kind of ideological steel seal called &quot;responsibility&quot; is bound to men -whether it is to society or family. Traditional thoughts and values ​​tell men that you must settle this baby. And should endure any value, including happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This must have hit the hearts of many men who can&#39;t feel happy in marriage. Many ladies say that they have to find a &quot;emotional stability&quot; when they get married. Why? The main reason for such a choice is not just to eliminate those men who are emotionally unstable, but also in a deeper and more practical scene to make &quot;emotional stable&quot; men work hard for their families and endure tolerance as the highest pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The question is, who is born as a person, who should be more emotional than who? This is a pseudo -proposition. Whether emotional stability is always relative, no life is a &quot;emotional stability&quot;, there is no time to be unstable -if such a person exists, it must be made of plastic and steel. It is worth noting that when this requirement becomes of course, it will inevitably lead to an unfair situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What is the marriage for marriage? I am afraid that everyone has their own ideas, but in general, it is nothing more than these points: continue to write love, get stable sex, and raise offspring. Mentioning the responsibility after marriage, in most cases, men often become the main or even sources of income from the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The discounts between Fu Shiger and Lao Liu fully show that emotional value is affected by family economic relations. Once a man brings children at home, it is often not optimistic. Because society is not the same for full -time wives and full -time husbands. If men want to maintain dignity, they are not discriminated and not suffered from being angry. After all, a man who flows into the world is more likely to be lightly seen by public opinion than a woman who only brings a baby at home, and even regarded as a &quot;waste of a soft rice&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It stands to reason that in the external mode of the male lead, men have a great hope of getting emotional value in the family. But it is interesting that theoretical connotation is often broken in reality. Some men are exhausted and died, and they have to be said to be said: if they know that playing games, they do not know how to do housework. Sometimes it is also labeled with the &quot;Paramilia Parenting&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The so -called emotional value is &quot;persuasion&quot; in the final analysis, women are sad, men are coax, and in turn should be the same. If a man is always forcibly given &quot;strong&quot; and &quot;hard&quot;, it is created as a role that is insulating with emotional value, and paid blindly in a wider range; It wo n’t be able to come over. Even men can only solve them by themselves, so this relationship has changed, and it also loses the emotional foundation of suffering from the chief and common. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is there no emotional needs for men, or shouldn&#39;t they seek emotional help? Of course not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Men and women should be equal on the issue of emotional value. It is a normal way to get along with emotional values ​​like men and women, and to give respect and care. Based on this, it is the way to balance each other and solve each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A family must not be a quagmire that has absolute power and the other party can only be checked. No one will be willing to marry or marry a &quot;slave master&quot; for confession. Therefore, no matter whether men and women want their rights and spirit to be respected by the other side, they refuse to kneel and lick and endless unilateral efforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The current marriage rate has plummeted, the divorce rate rises, and the increasing number of unmarried families will explain to a certain extent that the connotation of &quot;home&quot; is more rational and stricter to a certain extent, so as to take the initiative Escape from an invisible shackle. This cold fact tells us that marriage and family are the &quot;intangible&quot; subjects that two people operate with love and sincerity. For a long time for marriage and family, if you want everyone to have more confidence in marriage and family, you must look at the emotional needs of both parties fairly and create a kind of love relationship, especially abandoning the prejudice of &quot;men without emotional value&quot;. , So that we can maintain each other&#39;s consciousness to the greatest extent, and warm each other can be stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (&quot;>; ( This article is only the personal point of view of the author, does not represent the position of this newspaper) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戛纳金棕榈获奖影片，一场对亲密关系的审判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影中，丈夫坠楼死亡后，法庭展开了对谋杀还是自杀的审判，同时也揭开了对家庭关系的剖析。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国阿尔卑斯山下的小木屋中，一场采访正在进行。女作家看起来擅长回避问题，一度反客为主成为提问者。坐在她对面的年轻记者显得有些招架不住，只得顺着她的意愿闲聊起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;突然，楼上传来作家丈夫播放的音乐声，震耳欲聋，他的不满表现得很明显。采访被迫终止，女记者离开。而在她离开后不久，作家的丈夫被他们的儿子发现坠死在小木屋外的雪地上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题来了，谁是凶手？如按以往的悬疑叙事策略，剧情总要经过多重反转，真相才会水落石出。 2023年刚获得戛纳电影节金棕榈奖的影片《坠楼死亡的剖析》却提供了另一种解法，导演茹斯汀·特里耶似乎并不在意剧情是否反转，甚至凶手是谁也并unimportant.拨开悬疑的外衣，特里耶更感兴趣的是人们如何用各自的叙述完成对一场死亡的剖析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片巧妙地设置了庭审环节，于是，本应该为私人领域的亲密关系被赤裸裸地摊开来呈现在众人眼前。一方想证明谋杀，另一方想通过证明丈夫自杀以彰显自己的无辜，双方都在尝试用自己的叙述去接近真相，所有蛛丝马迹都有可能成为呈堂证供。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为小说家，桑德勒∙沃伊特的写作成为控方审视的对象，“她的生活就在书里面，尤其是她的关系”。小说中妻子对丈夫的厌恶、脑海里萌生的有关丈夫死亡的可能性，以及如何杀人的想象，这些虚构内容都被理解为是对现实杀人动机的映射。在这种审视下，书里的叙事不再完整，它们被切割成片段，甚至句子，再以人的意志在脑海中与现实联系起来，进行叙事的重构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片中的关键证据之一还有丈夫塞缪尔死亡前的录音。塞缪尔之前是一名教师，同时也喜欢写作。由于塞缪尔对儿子丹尼尔的永久性视力受损存有部分责任，出于愧疚，他将自己大量的时间花在各种家庭事务，以及对丹尼尔的陪伴中。他看上去无怨无悔、心甘情愿，但录音却展现了这个家庭亲密关系的另一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;录音中，塞缪尔要求妻子重新考虑家庭分工，认为自己已经牺牲了太多个人时间在家庭事务上，他想要有更多的时间去写作。听完后，桑德勒冷漠地嘲讽他，作家不会因为有了孩子和家务就停止写作，没有人逼他，自己也并不欠他。导演似乎是有意将性别进行对调，塞缪尔经历的其实是现实中众多处于婚姻关系中的女性处境，无奈且挣扎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接下来，录音中两人的争执愈加激烈。桑德勒的双性恋身份、出轨等私密信息在塞缪尔的口中被一一揭开，落入庭审内众人的耳中。在控方看来，这些都是夫妻关系失衡、妻子谋杀丈夫的动机和理由。在此处，原本只是记录人与人关系中某一个维度的录音，也被用以指代全貌，帮助控方完成对真相的推演和重构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桑德勒企图否认这种一直被重构的叙述，她对作为证人之一的塞缪尔的心理医生说，“你说的只是整个情况的一小部分，一对夫妻就像是一团乱麻……”她认为，这不能证明自己就是凶手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矛盾的是，桑德勒自身也在有意无意地对真相进行自我叙述，丈夫在离世六个月前吃药的异常举动、看心理医生、写作上的郁郁不得志等，都成为她在辩护过程中重构他自杀的理由。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使控辩双方呈现的证据片段都是真实存在的，但或许没有人敢确认依据这些片段重构出来的自杀或他杀故事就是真相本身。正如导演茹斯汀·特里耶说的，“这是非常现代的，这就是我们今天的生活。在审判中，各种事物都会发生变化，并被赋予额外的分量，从而产生新的虚构。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证据不仅呈现在控辩双方的面前，也在儿子丹尼尔面前徐徐展开，他也因此重新开始审视自己的父母。一开始他对母亲深信不疑，而随着双方在庭审上的叙述，他的态度也慢慢变得摇摆，脑海里甚至出现了母亲用力击打父亲并将他推下楼的画面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一边，他也尝试给狗喂药，以验证母亲所说的父亲曾吃药呕吐的事实，他也想起父亲在送狗狗去看病时跟他的谈话，他认为这流露出了父亲的自杀倾向。从种种摇摆到审视后自己对事实片段的选取，丹尼尔最终也在脑海中构建出自己对于真相的叙述版本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《坠楼死亡的剖析》（又译《坠落的审判》）剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导演茹斯汀·特里耶曾在采访中提到，“这些审判对人们来说是一种噩梦，因为你自己的生活被剥夺了。每个人都在创造一种虚构的故事，并没有真正试图达到真相。我对真相和试图通过故事寻求真相非常着迷，我觉得这非常有趣。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，导演也想将观众拉入对真相的寻找和叙述的建构中。在悬疑的外壳下，作为观众的我们从塞缪尔坠楼起也自然而然地一直在思考凶手是谁。在控辩双方的争锋中，每当他们列出新的证据，进行新的陈述、辩解，我们也如丹尼尔一样，不由自主地将审视的目光投向塞缪尔和桑德勒，试图从双方提供的事实证据以及他们的叙述中找到属于自己的叙述，推演死亡的真相。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但片外的我们更为被动，一切叙述始终是建构在片中人物对真相的阐释之上的，这也意味着我们对真相的感知更具不确定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片最终以桑德勒被判无罪作为结尾。既然双方都有虚构的因素在，那为何一种叙述能战胜另一种呢？或许还是因为其中的情感力量——丹尼尔讲述的有关父亲的那段独白打动了法官，从而成功帮自己的母亲赢得了胜利。在桑德勒回家之后，丹尼尔抱住并亲吻了她。在一室寂静中，一股难得的温情萦绕其间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真相难道就是如此吗？ Not really.在此前各方的叙述中，导演已成功地将怀疑的种子埋到观众心间，即使桑德勒被判无罪，人们对真相的犹疑与不定却并未消失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;女主角扮演者桑德拉·惠勒曾就剧本问题问过导演，她演的角色是有罪的还是无辜的，特里耶告诉她，“我不知道，但我希望你表现得好像她是无辜的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她可能有责任却没有罪，或者她可能有罪却没有责任。她可以负有逼迫他自杀的责任，却没有杀死他的罪过，或者她可以在不想杀死他的情况下杀死他——无论是以冲动的方式，还是以我们可以尝试想象的方式。真相是存在的，但它太复杂了，在这里无法把握。”导演茹斯汀·特里耶在一次采访中这样说道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但回过头想想，真相如何或许早已不重要。虚构是人的天赋，只要乐意，借助几个关键词便能建构出属于自己的叙述。只是，如若人与人之间的关系都像这场死亡一样，被抽丝剥茧般进行审视、重构，那实际上，没有任何一种关系经得起如此严苛细密的剖析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚太安全专家谈：中国发展红利被周边国家共享]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;冷战结束后，尽管有一些地缘政治紧张或者地区的热点问题，但亚太地区仍然维持了和平Stablize.而欧洲、中东地区则陆续燃起战火。如何解读这样一种国际局面？为什么亚太地区能够维持数十年的和平稳定？ How to continue to maintain prosperous and stable Asia Pacific? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月29日，在北京香山论坛“中外名家对话”会上，多位中外学者围绕“中国在维护亚太安全中的作用”等议题进行深入探讨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中华人民共和国外交部前副部长、国际安全策略清华研究院创始人傅莹在会上表示，冷战之后，亚太地区抓住机遇，迅速对外开放，快速进入区域一体化。过去几十年，亚太地区没有大的战争和政治冲突，同时也没有重大的社会动荡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“亚太地区有四十多年的和平发展。这个过程中，中国发挥了核心作用。中国区域快速发展的红利被周边国家共享，中国也是大部分亚太国家第一大国际贸易合作国。”傅莹说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月29日，多位中外学者围绕“中国在维护亚太安全中的作用”等议题进行深入探讨。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3e0785ae47.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月29日，多位中外学者围绕“中国在维护亚太安全中的作用”等议题进行深入探讨。 （姚忆江/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“经济发展奇迹”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“不知道大家是否记得，（上世纪）80年代，当亚太地区开始多边合作，中国也加入区域一体化时，很多国家都还在发展和贫困的边缘行走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;傅莹在发言中表示，在过去很长的一段时间中，亚太区域获得了极快的经济发展，超越市场中很多国家和地区。她列举亚洲银行数据称，在过去42年间，亚洲GDP增长7倍。而这一现象也被叫做“亚太地区的经济发展奇迹”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;傅莹认为，和平稳定、区域注重合作对话及经济全球化是促成亚太经济发展的重要原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚太地区数十年的稳定和安全背后，究竟有什么独特的驱动力？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为了维持亚太长期稳定和安全，我们需要发现一种独特的&#39;亚太模式&#39;。”上海国际问题研究院院长陈东晓表示，“开放的区域主义”是重要的驱动因素，而这一理念又包含诸多内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“首先经济发展合作是重点。它超越了意识形态，以及政府方面的分歧。其次，在区域开放主义下，不管大国或者小国，都需要遵守相关的规章制度，都应该以平等的方式遵循社会规则。我们不应该有双重标准，这一点非常重要。”陈东晓说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与亚太地区和平稳定相对照的是，欧洲、中东地区近年来陆续燃起战火。在论坛讨论中，两名欧美学者也表达了对“中西差异”的思考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为什么亚太地区和欧洲有所不同？背后的原因是非常多的。”美国昆西国家事务研究所东亚项目首席主任迈克尔·史文认为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯国立高等经济大学世界经济与国际事务学院院长谢尔盖·卡拉加诺夫同意史文的观点，称“现在还处在早期阶段，我们仍要保持谨慎态度” .同时，他也强调与亚洲不同的欧洲“文化因素”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“欧洲历史上充斥着很多战争。欧洲的和平或者战争总是与欧洲内部的问题紧密相关。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;美国领导的风险正在变大&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;对于美国在亚太安全中的角色，韩国外国语大学国际研究中心主任黄载皓提出，“虽然世界上没有完美无缺的领导（模式），但美国领导的风险越来越大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他以美国对华政策举例称，从特朗普政府到现在的拜登政府，美国在全局战略和经济细节上发生多次改变。 “美国没有看清全局，战略和战术都不明确。所以美国缺乏一致性的愿景与政策，这造成了当前国际秩序不稳定。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会上，美国昆西国家事务研究所东亚项目首席主任迈克尔·史文在发言中提到“中国在亚洲的最终安全角色是什么仍然不确定”等观点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，傅莹直接予以反驳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不太同意这种类型的观点。迈克尔·史文先生的逻辑让人非常疑惑。”傅莹表示，中国积极推动了亚太地区经济发展，美国也从中受益良多.这种“缺乏说服力”的逻辑，大概源自于国际社会几百年来的权力更迭论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但是，你知道中国的发展背景完全不一样。”她表示，中美之间有很大的不同。但是它并不影响中美追寻各自发展的脚步，彼此支持获益。 If the power of China has become a &quot;threat&quot; in the Asia -Pacific region, how do you look at the rise of emerging countries such as India and Indonesia in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;傅莹还指出，当前美国对于自身全球影响力下降而感到焦虑，但这不是中国产生的问题，而是因为“经济全球化和美国自身犯错太多”的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国自己的问题让它举步维艰。看一下贸易战中，美国获得了什么好处？贸易战造成了美中贸易赤字不断加大，但它减少了中国对美国出口吗？实际上并没有，相反数据还在增加。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她提出，美国应该成为该地区发展的积极贡献者，而不是试图用竞争来优先定义该地区的议程，“劫持”了亚太地区成功的合作、对话及经济发展的长期议程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;寻找平衡、危机管控&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在发言中，多位学者不约而同地表示，国际秩序中旧平衡可能被打破，新变化即将发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢尔盖·卡拉加诺夫表示，随着美国和西方社会开始施加影响改变全球化，此前所谓的全球化时代已经结束。他说，我们必须要有一个新的理论或者新的全球治理模式，而这种模式必须要通过所有合作伙伴来决定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“过去这么多年中，我们一直在说要实现双赢，我们要让所有的相关方都受益。但不幸的是，我们并不是生活在理想世界，有时候需要震慑，需要和不同的国家达到平衡。”谢尔盖·卡拉加诺夫说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迈克尔·史文表示，任何国际体系都要平衡不同国家的需求，在平衡之下再合作。 （国家间）要寻求共同的利益点，相同经济发展的诉求，有没有相同的历史遗留问题要解决等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他坚持认为，当前不确定性仍然存在于国家之间，且无法得到管制。大小国家都会受到权力更迭的影响，其间毫无疑问会有不确定性产生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不能说中国认为各国大同，我们就能够做到这一点。它无法解决很多基础性的问题。而且，这并不是由美国造成的，而是由于结构的变化所引起的，它还会引发国际秩序的变化。”史文说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，在新的国际秩序形成之前，如何维护亚太地区的安全与和平呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈东晓提出了“三不”原则——即不分立集团阵营、不发起军事战争特别是核战争、不使用双重标准。 “过去几年，中国政府在很多场合一再重申，战争并不是处理各国分歧的好方法，相反它带来更多危机。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈东晓认为，中美关系是地区安全的重要因素。同时，亚太地区小国的作用不容忽视，不应该把它们分入哪一个派系。 “一些中立的国家可以发挥重要作用，比如东盟国家，他们能在亚太地区应对分歧，并实现相关的合作。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄载皓提出，相较于别的地区，亚太地区比较稳定，中美之间可以维持相对平衡。当前有外界声音称中美两国已经进入到“新冷战”，但他认为这更像是一种“复合竞争”。而且，现在已经是两个大国开始进行危机管理，并设置了沟通渠道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“但是，现在没有战争只有战斗，所以还可以管控。”黄载皓说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[九名市州长“进京检讨”：自然资源部组建以来首次高规格集中、公开约谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259895]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZylf9D.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/kcNAdYfHnmy6jaVIfdtcKIgbeorhtPCG5wZylf9D.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256894&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，在殷联盆花市场，土地的边缘还放着售卖的盆栽。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者李桂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为亚洲最大的鲜切花交易市场，云南省昆明市斗南花卉市场一年四季都人潮涌动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在斗南花卉市场北侧，一路之隔的是另一个和花卉有关的市场——殷联盆花市场。 Different from Dounan&#39;s main fresh cut flowers, most of the Yinlian Penpertflower markets built in 2012 are green plants and potted plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10年过去，大棚里曾种着各类苗木和多肉植物的盆花市场，如今也部分种起了蔬菜。这和自然资源督察有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月15日下午，在北京市阜内大街，自然资源部对2023年例行督察发现的违法违规主要问题进行了通报。 Among them, the issue of &quot;large shed houses&quot; in Yinlian Pen Flower Market was named. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了通报典型问题，自然资源部同时还开了一场约谈会：受国家自然资源总督察委托，国家自然资源专职副总督察陈尘肇对2023年督察发现违法违规问题突出9个市（州）政府主要负责人进行当面约谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9个市（州）分别是河北省石家庄市、黑龙江省哈尔滨市、浙江省温州市、安徽省滁州市、山东省临沂市、广西壮族自治区河池市、贵州省黔西南州、云南省昆明市、甘肃省兰州市。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了代表这些市（州）政府参加约谈会的市（州）长，这些市州所在的省（自治区）政府副秘书长，省、市两级自然资源部门“一把手”也被要求出席。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家自然资源总督察办公室公布的文章显示，此次约谈是“面对面指出督察发现的突出问题，督促地方政府加大整改查处力度，坚决遏制耕地违法行为，牢牢守住耕地保护红线”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是自然资源部2018年组建以来，首次举行的大规模、高规格的集中、公开约谈会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;违法占用耕地&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;77亩&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从殷联盆花市场的1号门进去，首先映入眼帘的，是各类印着“花卉”“苗木”“园艺”字样的店铺。到了10月，有的店铺门口还摆着正在开放的桂花、三角梅和各色茶花。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些店铺大都以大棚的形式存在：屋外露天的地方和透明薄膜搭成的屋顶被盖上了黑色的遮阳网；屋内地面少有水泥和瓷砖，大都是抹平了的黄泥土——种着植物的花盆放到地上，根系从盆底钻出来，泥土会给它们提供水分和营养。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沿着主干道一直往西北方向走约300米，店铺、大棚和遮阳网都消失了，道路两侧变成了空旷又开阔的空地。空地上丢着不少鼓鼓囊囊的白色编织袋，袋子外侧印着“饲料”字样，凑近还能闻到粪便的臭味。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;戴着遮阳帽的工人们把袋子扯开，黑色的肥料被铺到了黄泥地上，又有人拿着锄头把它翻开。远处的挖掘机正在另一块空地上作业，传来轰隆隆的声音。倘若不是地处城市，这里的景象看起来和农村的秋播没什么两样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在变成空地前，这里也曾是售卖绿植的大棚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大约一个月前，2023年9月，昆明市呈贡区委领导视察之后，大棚被拆了。 2023年10月25日，一位曾在此开过店的大棚主表示，在拆棚之前，2023年8月，他就搬到了现在的大棚，两地相距约500米，都由殷联社区成立的昆明仡顶经贸有限公司（以下简称昆明仡顶）负责出租。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该大棚主表示，虽然双方的租赁合同是一年一签，但他在原来的大棚已经经营了近十年。谈及搬店的原因，他认为是“政策调整”：“那一片地当时没有批成商业用地，所以就拆了。”此前在签合同时，昆明仡顶“也搞不清楚”土地的性质. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，在自然资源部的通报中，前述空地被定性为耕地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通报显示，2019年2月，昆明市呈贡区殷联盆花市场被纳入“大棚房”问题整治范围并通过整改验收；2022年7月，殷联社区将已复垦的农业大棚又出租给76户商户用于售卖盆花、农资、农药等经营性活动，违法占用耕地77亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;严格来说，“大棚房”问题的重点不在于建房形式，而在于建房位置所处的土地性质。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由农业农村部主管的《农业工程技术》杂志曾在文章中解释，“大棚房”问题是指一些工商企业、个人及组织借建农业设施或农业园区之名，违法违规占用耕地甚至永久基本农田，用于非农业建设的行为，其本质是改变土地性质和用途、改变农业生产功能，触碰耕地保护红线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“呈贡区自然资源局”微信公众号发布的信息显示，2023年5月，国家自然资源督察成都局对昆明市2019年“大棚房”清理整治情况进行督察，其间发现涉及呈贡区的2宗“大棚房”反弹问题，其中之一为殷联盆花市场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月26日，昆明市自然资源和规划局呈贡分局一名工作人员告诉南方周末记者，涉事“大棚房”问题“整改的责任在街道”，可以向街道了解相关情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;殷联盆花市场位于斗南街道，2023年10月25日，斗南街道办事处的一名负责人介绍：“以前（棚里面的东西）腾空了，但是去年因为疫情和村庄拆迁，就摆了一些销售的绿植在棚里面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该街道负责人表示，在2023年5月的督察中，国家自然资源督察成都局指出了该地存在的问题：“按照（督察）要求，（棚）里面要求见黄土，但是这个土上面摆着东西，它就视为违规。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月，呈贡区自然资源和规划分局与农业农村局对多家用地主体联发责令改正违法行为通知书和限期整改通知。前述街道负责人表示，按照整改通知的要求，他们需要在2023年9月底之前，将存在问题的大棚“恢复到2019年的状态”，即把棚内物品腾空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了具体执行阶段，整改要求被一再细化。该街道负责人记得，2023年6月，棚内东西腾空后，土也翻松了，但相关部门“每一次不同的检查，都会提不同的要求”，“所以我们反反复复的，今天要把门牌号撤掉，明天就说门上还有个广告要把它拆掉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了2023年8月底，大棚只剩下空壳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/s1YruHxfKE3KYlsmm4kD2GMkegXzl5ryT78fz4fl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256895&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;昆明市呈贡区委书记陈净（左二）在斗南街道殷联盆花市场“大棚房”整改工作现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（“呈贡发布”微信公众号/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;多个共性问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大棚腾空近一个月后，2023年9月15日下午，包括昆明在内的9个市（州）被自然资源部约谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然资源部共有北京、沈阳、上海、南京、济南、广州、武汉、成都、西安等9个自然资源地方督察局。约谈会上，9个地方督察局的局长，分别通报了督察发现的违法违规问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然资源部官网公开的信息显示，此次督察发现部分地区耕地保护责任落实不到位，耕地“非农化”“非粮化”等冲击红线的突出问题依然存在，各类园区、开发区、城市市政道路未批先建等非农建设问题比较突出，违规占用永久基本农田和一般耕地种植草皮问题在部分省份不同程度存在，“大棚房”问题禁而未绝，违法侵占耕地挖湖造景问题在一些地方仍有发生，有些地方违反生态保护红线管控要求违规批矿、非法采矿严重破坏生态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;情况通报则披露了更多详细情况。综合来看，被约谈的9个市（州）出现违法违规用地问题的数量，在所在省份均排名靠前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，石家庄、哈尔滨、温州、滁州、兰州存在违法违规问题“全省排名第一”，临沂、贵州黔西南州，“全省排名靠前”，昆明“问题个数排名全省第一、耕地面积排名全省第二”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，此次督察亦发现多座城市存在多个共性问题。如耕地“非农化”“非粮化”等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通报显示，哈尔滨存在“非农化”问题51个，涉及耕地900.68亩；临沂存在“非农化”问题111个，涉及耕地1065.56亩；河池存在“非农化”问题150个，涉及耕地2629.55亩；黔西南州存在“非农化”问题207个，占用耕地1649.65亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;耕地“非农化”更具体的表现则包括“大棚房”问题、农村乱占耕地建房、部分工程项目和基础设施未批先建等。不仅是昆明，哈尔滨、温州、河池也出现了“大棚房”问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，被通报的9个市（州）中，石家庄、哈尔滨、滁州、临沂、黔西南州、兰州等6地均存在非法采矿的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，哈尔滨代管的五常市对英泽砂石有限公司自2022年1月至2023年5月持续非法开采建筑用花岗石行为监管不力，未及时立案查处制止。将非法采矿行为上报为“伪变化”，不实上报，应付检查。哈尔滨市对五常市不如实上报行为监督不力，审核把关不严。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9个市（州）中，浙江温州是唯一被通报存在“自然资源领域信访持续多发”的城市。通报显示，2021年以来，温州市自然资源领域信访事项数量全省排位一直靠前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;会外整改&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在地方督察局局长通报9个市（州）的违法违规问题之后，市（州）长们分别发言，“逐个表态”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国之声报道，昆明市市长刘佳晨表示，昆明市耕地“非农化”“非粮化”问题十分突出，为此“深感自责与愧疚”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在表态环节，多位市长亦表示，部分问题已得到整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对滁州市来安县政府违法征地，用于建设金陵水乡小镇项目配套景观水系，侵占耕地400.4亩挖湖造景的问题，滁州市市长吴劲表示，来安县政府违法征地建设金陵水乡小镇项目配套景观水系的重点问题已于2023年6月30日全部整改复垦到位，并按照“人事并处”的要求提级办理，移交市纪委监委追责问责. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约谈会结束后，多个市（州）长召开会议，部署了相关工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二天，2023年9月17日，河池市长王军主持召开政府常务会议，要求坚决守住耕地保护和粮食安全底线。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月19日，温州市长张振丰在全市耕地保护和粮食安全工作会议上强调，要攻坚督察反馈问题整改，按照“一个问题一个方案，闭环推进一抓到底”要求，针对性制定整改方案，限期推动问题销号清零，同步开展已整改问题“回头看”和举一反三问题同标同质整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同日，昆明市召开全市违法用地和耕地流出问题整改工作会议。昆明市委书记刘洪建主持会议并讲话，市长刘佳晨传达自然资源部集中公开约谈会议精神。会上，昆明市自然资源规划局汇报全市违法用地和耕地流出问题整改情况并作检讨发言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5天后，2023年9月23日，昆明市呈贡区委书记陈净率队实地调研“大棚房”整治、耕地流出问题整改等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“呈贡发布”微信公众号发表的文章显示，在斗南街道殷联盆花市场“大棚房”整改工作现场，陈净详细了解了全区“大棚房”整治工作整体情况、工作推进情况及存在的困难问题等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“呈贡发布”公开的文章中，配有一张陈净站在大棚内的照片，他身后是拆到只剩框架的大棚。就在陈净调研后不久，大棚的框架也被拆了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前述斗南街道负责人表示，此前，他们已经有了拆除大棚的计划，“主要是有些细节和标准（没确定），刚好赶在领导来了之后就制定了，我们就快速彻底地整治了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈及拆除大棚的原因，该负责人表示，是为了避免问题再次反弹。 “如果棚还在，下一次谁又把东西搬进去了，检查的时候又会说（有问题）。”他解释，“到最后，我们是做通了社区和群众的工作，就是为了一次性整治到位。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，盆花市场所处位置的土地都由殷联社区负责管理。 “大棚房”问题反弹后，由于“社区监管不到位”，目前这七十多亩土地已经收归街道。现在大棚拆除后的位置种地的，是街道委托的第三方公司。该负责人补充：“我们街道干部也不会种地，工作也很多，所以目前是委托给第三方先来完成种植任务，然后再谈以后。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该街道负责人还表示，2023年5月，发现“大棚房”问题反弹后，街道相关干部也被调离了原岗位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/iAC6qJLe4TweMpYZNXW426OfjztTk55xazXpnjme.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256896&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，殷联盆花市场内，工人们正在处理运来的肥料。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者李桂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;核心职能，仍和土地相关&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自然资源部约谈地市级政府负责人，与自然资源督察有关，这是上级政府对下级政府行政监察的形式之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家土地督察是国家自然资源督察的前身。为了遏制土地违法、落实耕地保护，2006年，国务院正式出台土地督察制度，主要督察对象为省、自治区、直辖市、计划单列市政府。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年3月，自然资源部成立，“随着自然资源管理职能的转变，为适应自然资源管理需要”，国家土地督察转型为国家自然资源督察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年6月，中共中央办公厅、国务院办公厅发布《中央生态环境保护督察工作规定》，以党内法规形式明确了中央生态环境保护督察的制度构成、程序规范、权限责任等内容，同时确立了中央和省级两级督察体制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在武汉大学环境法研究所教授陈海嵩看来，即便自然资源部整合了多个部门的职能，但和土地相关的职能，仍是核心。 “自然资源的核心是土地资源”，陈海嵩说，因此，自然资源督察应该聚焦于最为成熟的土地督察业务，不断深入发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年9月1日起施行的《土地管理法实施条例》则首次明确了自然资源督察的范围和工作方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;条例规定，国家自然资源督察机构根据授权对省（自治区、直辖市）人民政府以及国务院确定的城市人民政府的耕地保护情况、土地节约集约利用情况、国土空间规划编制和实施情况、国家有关土地管理重大决策落实情况、土地管理法律、行政法规执行情况、其他土地利用和土地管理情况等进行督察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家自然资源督察机构还可以约谈被督察的地方人民政府有关负责人，并可以依法向监察机关、任免机关等有关机关提出追究相关责任人责任的建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和此次9个市（州）长被叫到北京约谈不同，此前，国家自然资源督察机构的约谈大都在地方进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年10月至11月，国家自然资源督察机构对31个省（自治区、直辖市）和新疆生产建设兵团开展了耕地保护和矿产资源实地督察，发现了一些违法违规问题.针对督察发现的突出问题，经国家自然资源总督察授权，派驻地方的国家自然资源督察机构对部分违法违规严重的地市政府进行约谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，成都局约谈云南大理，北京局约谈河北邢台、山西晋中，南京局约谈江西九江，广州局约谈广东清远、广西南宁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次在北京约谈地方政府主要负责人的深意，在陈海嵩看来，依然和粮食安全有关，“接下来很长一段时间内，耕地保护、粮食安全都是非常重要The problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在约谈会上，国家自然资源专职副总督察陈尘肇表示：“耕地保护任务没有减轻，而是更加艰巨了。要采取坚决有力的措施，持续加强耕地保护，牢牢守住18亿亩耕地红线。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部：中小学校要确保学生课间正常活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:11:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近期，一些地方中小学生“课间10分钟被约束”问题受到社会广泛关注，新华社“新华视点”记者就此采访了教育部有关负责同志。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位负责同志表示，中小学校安排课间休息十分重要、十分必要，有利于学生调节情绪、放松身心、增强体质和防控近视。 The Ministry of Education attaches great importance to students&#39; recess. The &quot;Regulations on the Protection of Minors in Schools&quot; (Ministry of Education Order No. 50), which will be implemented on September 1, 2021, clearly states that legitimate exchanges between students during recess and other non-teaching time are not allowed. Unnecessary restrictions are placed on the freedom of speech and behavior such as games, activities outside the classroom, etc. In actual work, primary and secondary schools are required to arrange 30 minutes of physical activities between classes every day, and students should be arranged to go out of the classroom for appropriate activities and relaxation during each class break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位负责同志指出，教育部将进一步督促地方和学校严格落实国家有关规定，遵循教育规律和学生身心发展规律，坚决纠正以“确保学生安全”为由而简单限制学生Necessary recess breaks and activities will be implemented; localities and schools will be guided to scientifically implement management and safety precautions, strengthen inspections of outdoor facilities and personnel on duty, strengthen students’ safety knowledge education, minimize the risk of safety accidents, and make children happy Activities with confidence. At the same time, schools will be required to work closely with home-school communities, strive for parents&#39; understanding and social support, and work together to ensure students&#39; normal activities during class and promote students&#39; healthy growth and all-round development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[安徽武校投毒致7死案开庭：“26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;事发后，七家死者家属合照。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/3f463a8261.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;事发后，七家死者家属合照。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我心里想，这个案子破不了了，没想到破掉了。”2023年10月31日下午，61岁的刁山云在电话里告诉南方周末记者。 26年前，他的儿子钱敏在11岁的年纪被投毒致死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平是在2023年6月得知凶手被抓获的，她的弟弟杨长伟死于同一起投毒案。 “26年了，总算对弟弟有个交代了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发于1997年6月30日7时许，安徽马鞍山和县南北少林武术学校约130名师生吃过早饭后出现呕吐、抽搐等症状，包括钱敏、杨长伟在内的7名学生因抢救无效死亡，经公安机关调查发现，均系毒鼠强424成分中毒死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;26年过去，2023年10月29日，马鞍山市公安局召开和县南北少林武术学校集体中毒案件通气会，宣告抓获该案的两名犯罪嫌疑人付某阶、朱某林。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月1日早晨9:00，该案在马鞍山市中级法院开庭审理。 The Ma&#39;anshan Procuratorate asked for criminal responsibility for investigating Zhu Moulin and Fu Mou. More than forty people and relatives of the defendants and victims listened to the trial, and they were not sentenced to court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;投毒130余人报复馆长&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;午间休庭时，杨习平告诉南方周末记者，“上午审的是姓付的，他就说自己收了姓朱的500块钱投了毒，自己脑子稀里糊涂，还有话要说。”杨习平称，法庭下午将继续审朱某林。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据上游新闻报道，在法庭上，两名被告人否认预谋作案。公诉机关建议判处两人十年以上有期徒刑、无期徒刑或死刑，7名遇难者的家属提出近770万元民事赔偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开庭前一天，杨习平把随身带的弟弟照片拿出来看，一个身穿红色运动服的小男孩，长相清瘦，永远定格在了11岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平姊妹四人，杨长伟是家中幼子，也是唯一的男孩。杨习平作为家中的老大，为了供弟弟上学，早早出去打工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她疼爱这个弟弟，在家里干活时，走到哪儿带到哪儿。弟弟爱打闹，家里就让他去和县南北少林武术学校学习打拳，杨习平只记得学费不便宜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们一次性交七八千。”刁山云说，以前自己和丈夫钱发荣做生意，顾不上照顾小儿子钱敏，就安顿在武校，计划等儿子到18岁就去当兵，“上了不到两年，最后抱回来了个骨灰盒”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时那个打击太大了，承受不了。”62岁的钱发荣至今还在用钱敏的照片做微信头像，他记得，事发当天接到儿子中毒的消息后，自己急忙赶到医院，已经来不及了。 1997年7月1日下午3点钟，钱敏浑身抽搐，离开了人世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;钱敏在木桩上蹲马步。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/839f6a4929.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钱敏在木桩上蹲马步。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但钱发荣夫妇没想到，凶手就是在武校任教的教练付某阶。 “那个姓付的教练最喜欢我儿子了，他们住一个房间，我们每次去看儿子都要感谢他。”刁山云说，儿子时常念叨付某阶的好，“他不喜欢我儿子干嘛叫我儿子跟他住一个房间，我当时听儿子说这个付老师很好的，人品还是不错的，他咋能干这个事？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;马鞍山市检察院的起诉书显示，这起投毒案发端于两家武术馆之间的竞争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1994年左右，被告人朱某林和彭某伟在和县乌江镇卜集镇经营和县少林武术馆，朱某林任馆长、彭某伟任主教练。在经营过程中，二人发生矛盾。彭某伟离开了该武术馆，并在西埠镇重新开设和县南北少林武术学校，还带走了大部分师生，朱某林因此对彭某伟怀恨在心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1996年8月，被告人付某阶到彭某伟经营的和县南北少林武术学校任教，在任教期间，因琐事逐渐对彭某伟心生不满。朱某林和付某阶二人经他人介绍后认识，在相处过程中，两人都表达出对彭某伟的不满，遂决定一起报复彭某伟，把彭某伟的武校搞垮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年6月，付某阶、朱某林商议决定使用投毒的方式报复彭某伟，付某阶实施后由朱某林支付给付某阶5万元，朱某林当场支付付某阶500元。月底，付某阶从武校辞职，回到湖北监利老家购买了两包老鼠药。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发前夜，6月29日晚，付某阶从和县南北少林武术学校南边窜至武校厨房内，将两包老鼠药投放在厨房南侧桌上红色塑料盆内的咸豇豆上，搅拌后从原路逃离，离开和县。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二天早晨7时许，武校130余名师生吃过早饭后发生呕吐、抽搐等症状，杨长伟、王俊、邢涛、刘文宝、田丹、汤玉叶、钱敏等7名学生死亡。现场勘查提取了咸豇豆、纱罩网罩纱等物品，均检出毒鼠强424成分。另对7名学生死因进行鉴定，经鉴定，7名学生均系424鼠药中毒死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而付某阶、朱某林已经不知所踪，警方一时难以破案。马鞍山市公安局在通气会上介绍，案件发生后，公安机关成立专案组，围绕案发现场周边开展走访排查，分析付某阶、朱某林有重大作案嫌疑。 1997年7月14日，公安机关将付某阶、朱某林列为网上逃犯，悬赏通缉，持续追捕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;付某阶与学生游玩的合照。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a9145252bf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;付某阶与学生游玩的合照。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“总算可以给个交代了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我们也不知道该找谁，下毒的人已经跑了，你说咋整？”杨习平接到邻居的消息已经是事发半个月之后，回到家就看到院里摆一口棺材，她记得很清楚，“我当时跪在地上那一刻，看我老爸头发全白了，瘦得都不像样子了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刁山云至今都想不通，儿子怎么就被自己最喜欢的教练毒死了。夫妻俩把儿子下葬后，买了一座墓碑，上面写：“爱子钱敏，九七年不幸发生6.30血案含冤致死。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直至2022年下半年，这起沉寂多年的投毒案有了突破，专案组在贵州发现了朱某林的踪迹，并于2023年年初基本锁定其藏匿地点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月初，福建晋江警方利用大数据分析，发现在一皮革厂打工的男子与嫌疑人付某阶存在相似体貌特征，经两地警方反复比对确认后，立即将其控制。专案组于5月6日晚赶赴福建晋江，经初步审讯，付某阶向公安机关交代了犯罪经过。 5月9日，付某阶被押回和县。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;抓获付某阶同时，5月7日清晨，专案组前往贵州贵阳市，在当地警方协助下，将隐匿身份并在当地开办桶装水生产企业的朱某林在厂内成功抓获。见到前来抓捕的民警，朱某林僵在原地、惊讶不已，想不到过去这么久民警还会找上门。 5月8日凌晨，朱某林被押回和县。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月，在武校投毒案新闻通气会上，马鞍山市公安局专案组介绍：经审讯，付某阶交代，作案后，他一直东躲西藏，居无定所，先后流窜到江西新余市、福建德化县、莆田市、晋江市等地，以打零工为生。因害怕身份暴露被公安机关查处，他不敢登记身份信息，在疫情期间不敢打疫苗、做核酸检测。在应聘工作时也从不挑岗位、谈工资待遇，只为有一处藏身之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据朱某林交代，为逃避公安机关打击，潜逃期间他隐匿真实身份，独自漂泊在外，先是在江西鄱阳县躲藏了2年，后又窜至浙江杭州市打工，先后在江西上饶市、贵州贵阳市开办桶装水生产企业，这么多年始终过着提心吊胆的生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“6月份，我老爸接到通知说凶手找到了，我立马回来了。”杨习平称，听说找到凶手时，自己和父亲都在电话里哭，“总算可以给弟弟一个交代了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平时常想，如果弟弟还在，这个家一定是另一番样子。她要求妹妹们不能远嫁，“因为没弟弟了，老妈身体也不好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨习平称，母亲因丧子大病一场，父亲受打击后神经衰弱，三妹也因此再无心念书。 “我老爸经常夜里都找不到人，要么跑到弟弟坟上哭，要么跑到河里和砖坯子里，我们到处找。”杨父一直自责害了儿子，走不出来。因为当初是他不顾家人反对，将小儿子送到了学费昂贵的武术学校。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚，杨习平带着家人赶到和县，准备参加第二天的开庭。她希望付、朱二人受到应有的惩罚。 “我弟弟要是不出事，今年就是37岁，该成家了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访俄专家安德烈·科尔图诺夫：俄乌冲突越早结束，对大家都越好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>