<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“3元羽绒服”上热搜：不是买不起还是感冒药更有性价比]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, discussions about down jackets have become heated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When will down jackets sell for five figures?&quot; &quot;Domestic down jackets sell for 7,000 yuan&quot;... Thousands of thousands of down jackets are frequently on the hot search list, slowly becoming a &quot;luxury product&quot; in winter &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;3 yuan down jacket&quot; attracted the attention and discussion of netizens, showing that low-priced down jackets costing 3 yuan but actually selling for only 35 yuan were given to ordinary people in the cold winter. The warmest gift, for them, is more than enough for them compared to big-name luxury goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the light snow season has arrived and major cities have entered winter, many people have dug out the down jacket that has been at the bottom of their boxes for a year. Statistics show that more than half of netizens buy down jackets when needed. , during the Double 11 period, down jackets became a hot-selling product on major e-commerce platforms. Many domestic down jackets appeared on Tmall’s best-selling list and received a lot of praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the rise of domestic down jackets is inseparable from the improvement of the comprehensive production strength of the manufacturers behind them, and the Yangtze River Delta is the main force in down production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiangsu, Zhejiang, and Shandong, the number of down-related companies exceeds 10,000, and many domestic down jacket brands are gradually starting to transform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the wide variety of down jacket brands and types, many netizens said that they are in urgent need of a scientific selection guide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it depends on the filling of the down jacket: goose down is more expensive than duck down due to factors such as large and full velvet, good fluffiness, strong warmth retention, and long use time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, it is the down that really plays a role in keeping warm, and the down content more intuitively reflects the quality of the down jacket. It is worth noting that thicker and warmer is not the case. The higher the fill power of a down jacket, the more air it insulates and the better its thermal insulation effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the data point of view, there are still a small number of netizens who choose thousand-yuan down jackets, and most netizens pursue cost-effectiveness. As a saying often seen on the Internet: It’s not that down jackets are unaffordable, but that cold medicine is more cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What price range of down jacket would you choose? Today, &quot;Know&quot; will show you how to choose a cost-effective down jacket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/586c1b2150.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/586c1b2150.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259897&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/135e6eaeff.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/135e6eaeff.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259898&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tytIIT1Ze3ZYW31QaU8DrhSJeQ8Tm4SvtKxe7GWc.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tytIIT1Ze3ZYW31QaU8DrhSJeQ8Tm4SvtKxe7GWc.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/a2e0996720.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/28/a2e0996720.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259899&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/28/f6fba97f3a.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/28/f6fba97f3a.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259900&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/28/9a1cf85f82.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/9a1cf85f82. PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;259901&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dc54f1e8f9. PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/dc54f1e8f9.PNG&quot; data-key= &quot;259902&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与南方周末读者交换一本书，请查收]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261587]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;From Xinjiang Sayibak, Inner Mongolia Hohhot, Heilongjiang Qiqihar, Sichuan Aba Tibetan and Qiang Autonomous Prefecture, from Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen, Hangzhou, Wuhan, Chongqing, Xi&#39;an... A book met in Yangcheng across time, space and geography, and was sent to another person&#39;s hands through exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who in the clouds sent a brocade book? The answer is hidden in the package. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/5A8ODADrJeJEAcfRuyYc7NbiN6vdtzKWG9svp2Bq.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;2182&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/5A8ODADrJeJEAcfRuyYc7NbiN6vdtzKWG9svp2Bq.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Good reviews from readers. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an era of cluttered information, we firmly believe that reading is a kind of concentration, so we have this book exchange event. It lasted for a week, and the conference room was filled with books. The courier boy became a mature person, and the name &quot;Xiao Nan&quot; became a high-frequency word in Cainiao Station&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ZSuV1QftTAdicJDCDmy7KX0wGMQzySclizpmZteN.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height= &quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ZSuV1QftTAdicJDCDmy7KX0wGMQzySclizpmZteN.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Packages are waiting to be opened. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/UvzQU6uLvkEZqtFtqb8FF4Ihn3CTp3SKihJNRbEk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/UvzQU6uLvkEZqtFtqb8FF4Ihn3CTp3SKihJNRbEk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260203&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;Categorize books. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was surprised and moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opening the package, each book attempts to convey a series of experiences. The words and pictures, whether virtual or real, converge into the tastes and interests of each Southern Weekend reader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We received &quot;Letter from a Strange Woman&quot;, we took a &quot;Submarine at Night&quot;, we explored &quot;The Right Bank of the Ergun River&quot;, we met &quot;The Kite Runner&quot;, and we also followed Lao She, Mo Yan, Liang Shiqiu, Peter Heisler, Woolf, Camus, and Ryunosuke Akutagawa feel the personal emotional memories and the pulse of the times in which they live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/L8IUlatz6O6KMCwD6iBkAMfFfENlLy132bXjUkp1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;8000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/L8IUlatz6O6KMCwD6iBkAMfFfENlLy132bXjUkp1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260204&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;The books were passed around in the hands, and the battle continued until 2 o&#39;clock in the morning. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What touched us even more were the letters that came with the books. Some are as long as a page, and some are just a few sentences. Different words have the same heart-warming power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/WGgAC6icKNJBPsXemUizqGLavoSpezBZZPzkriRx.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/WGgAC6icKNJBPsXemUizqGLavoSpezBZZPzkriRx.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tCeYIaIVqz74XQhMn04FkERO0WtsBHZzvEri3ObE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/tCeYIaIVqz74XQhMn04FkERO0WtsBHZzvEri3ObE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260208&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/DinWciWR8LWNRVulrj7D9pxeHwfE5hBCgbpAU5sn.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4000&quot; height=&quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/30/DinWciWR8LWNRVulrj7D9pxeHwfE5hBCgbpAU5sn.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260205&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/30/svVVFShmqHbDtRxoLC2eYO5UqwYjuExRSr1AZUFn.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/svVVFShmqHbDtRxoLC2eYO5UqwYjuEx RSr1AZUFn. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260211&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/67Y1856tkQlaZxaGqnqXvEIXj648hdnXCPV1PW8X.jpeg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height=&quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/67Y1856tkQlaZxaGqnqXvEIXj648hdnXCPV1PW8X.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260210&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/lG2eB62YslIBISUWqEKrA5SvmDmytU08KlwJhz4s.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;6000&quot; height= &quot;4000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/lG2eB62YslIBISUWqEKrA5SvmDmytU08KlwJhz4s.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260209&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The text is fireworks , gives people the courage to ponder and question, which is hard to express in words. It also allows us to resonate with the world and find answers to the ever-changing world. &lt;strong>;The books participating in this event have been exchanged and shipped on November 28th&lt;/strong>;. We look forward to your excitement in opening the &quot;blind box&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But please don’t stop reading. After receiving the book, &lt;strong>;you are welcome to share your reading experience&lt;/strong>; in the comment area of ​​this article and communicate with the original owner of the book. &lt;strong>;During November 30th to December 10th&lt;/strong>;, we will draw one person every day to leave a heartfelt message and &lt;strong>;give away a signed book by Southern Weekend columnist and poet Chen Nianxi&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/RjwQmdKcZOdOZc5a47a6CKddLHNu4fWPHh7cOugQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;8000&quot; height= &quot;6000&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/RjwQmdKcZOdOZc5a47a6CKddLHNu4fWPHh7cOugQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260212&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xiao Nan is always careful when matching books, hoping to satisfy you. If the book you finally receive is different from what you imagined, please forgive me. After all, the meaning of exchange is more about encountering the unknown. &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Welcome to add Xiaonan Enterprise WeChat to share your event experience and suggestions. &lt;strong>;If you participated in the event and have not received the express delivery from us after December 4th&lt;/strong>;, please give us feedback. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/OdX0yHMcXD1ggRXcqxgTLlYMGq4661lHibwuT3Q2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 273&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/OdX0yHMcXD1ggRXcqxgTLlYMGq4661lHibwuT3Q2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260213&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国前国务卿亨利·基辛格去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 09:55:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 29, local time, former US Secretary of State Henry Kissinger was at his home in Connecticut Died at the age of 100. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨童兵：理论的价值是推动实务的进步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261562]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tong Bing, the first doctor of journalism in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;A native of Shaoxing, Zhejiang, born in November 1942 in Shaoxing, Zhejiang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1958-1963, studied at Shanghai Middle School in Shanghai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963-1968, studied in the Journalism Department of Fudan University, and was assigned to participate in After hard work and training, one year later he was transferred to &quot;Jintie News&quot; as a reporter and editor of the newspaper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1981, he was admitted to the Chinese Department of Peking University and became a graduate student after the resumption of the college entrance examination. The first graduate student soon moved back to Renmin University of China with the journalism major, and stayed at the school to teach after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984-1988, studied for a doctorate at Renmin University of China, becoming a Chinese-trained The first Ph.D. in journalism, he taught at Renmin University of China after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In December 1990, he was promoted to professor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;He has been a doctoral supervisor since 1993 and enjoys special allowances from the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2001, he was transferred to the School of Journalism, Fudan University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2012, he was awarded the title of Contributor to Chinese Journalism Education by the Journalism Professional Committee of the China Higher Education Commission and China Journalism Education Award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a senior professor of liberal arts at Fudan University, a doctoral supervisor, and a researcher on the Marxist view of journalism at Fudan University Director of the Center and Dean of Zhide College of Fudan University. He once served as the convener of the Journalism and Communication Discipline Evaluation Group of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council and a member of the fifth, sixth and seventh expert groups of the Postdoctoral Management Committee of the Ministry of Human Resources. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tong Bing, born in 1942, is the first doctor of journalism in New China. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ce49eaf0b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/29/ce49eaf0b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260107&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tong who was born in 1942 Bing is the first doctor of journalism in New China. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Become a reporter,&amp;nbsp; It was a child soldier&#39;s wish in middle school. But in more than ten years of study experience, he found that his ideal is still to &quot;engage in academics and do research.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating from the Journalism Department of Fudan University in 1968, the child soldiers were assigned to participate in labor training in Horqin, Inner Mongolia. In 1970, the &quot;Jintie News&quot; accidentally discovered their writing skills to become a journalist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The tide of the times is carrying budding journalism students drifting in unknown directions. In 1977, news came that the country had resumed the college entrance examination. The child soldiers who were far away from the border regained their fighting spirit to study, and the following year they were admitted to the postgraduate degree in the Chinese Department of Peking University. This year, a full ten years have passed since the child soldier graduated from college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;His mentor during his master&#39;s and doctoral studies was journalism educator Gan Xifen. Following in the footsteps of his mentor, Tong Bing devoted himself to the research of Marxist journalism concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Opening up a new research direction requires a lot of basic reading support. Within one year, Tong Bing read through more than 4,000 papers with the word &quot;horse&quot; in them, and also read through all 50 volumes of the complete works of Marx and Engels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The complete works of Marx and Engels were published in batches. After the first 39 volumes were read, the last 11 volumes were not published until 1985.&quot; Tong Bing said that at that time, the most complete new books could only be seen at the former Central Compilation and Translation Bureau. The child soldier who was still a &quot;poor student&quot; often brought two steamed buns and a cup of boiling water to read in the Translation and Compilation Bureau, sitting there all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After graduating with his doctorate in 1988, Tong Bing stayed at Renmin University of China to take up a teaching position. In more than 40 years of research and teaching career, he has published more than 700 academic papers, published and edited more than 50 books, textbooks, dictionaries, etc., and successively published the &quot;History of Marxist Journalism Thought&quot; and &quot;The History of Marxist Journalism Thought&quot;. Academic monographs such as &quot;Classic Course of Marxist Journalism&quot;, &quot;Introduction to Theoretical Journalism and Communication&quot;, &quot;Journalism Theory&quot;, &quot;Comparative Journalism and Communication&quot;, &quot;Subject and Mouthpiece - An Examination of the Trajectory of News Communication in the Republic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is how I have been through these years. It can be said that there is no time to breathe and no chance to sleep peacefully. I am constantly breaking through new tasks. Although it was tiring at the time, looking back now, I think it was worth it,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the first doctorate in journalism independently trained in China, Tong Bing has experienced the process of graduate education in journalism from scratch and witnessed the development of Renmin University of China, The development of journalism at Fudan University, one of the two famous universities in the north and the other in the south. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Do knowledge simply and plainly, but don&#39;t do simple learning&quot; and &quot;Don&#39;t dare to waste a day in life&quot; are the creeds he mentioned many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Already octogenarian, Tong Bing is currently a senior professor of liberal arts at Fudan University, still standing on the three-foot podium teaching journalism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Truth&quot; is a key word for Tong Bing&#39;s academic studies. He once used the four &quot;truths&quot; of &quot;true learning, true understanding, true belief, and true application&quot; The words summarized his lifelong academic insights. His pursuit of truth in learning also allowed him to repeatedly speak out about the shortcomings of the journalism community and the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Journalism research has entered a new era. He directly stated the shortcomings of the development of the discipline, &quot;Among various disciplines, the discipline construction of journalism has developed slowly.&quot; In his It seems that in order to solve the development problems of journalism, &quot;it is necessary to calmly spread out the problems and conduct in-depth analysis. This may be good.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;My ideal is not here. Place&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; When taking the college entrance examination in 1963 , why did you apply for the Journalism Department of Fudan University? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; I wanted to be a reporter when I was in middle school. At that time, I was a student cadre and the president of the student union. I was no stranger to news. . Student cadres who want to take the liberal arts major usually choose the Department of Politics, the Department of International Politics, and the Department of Journalism. At that time, the universities with the best journalism departments in my country were Renmin University in the north and Fudan University in the south. My parents didn’t want me to leave Shanghai, so I took the Fudan exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;It took ten years between graduating from undergraduate degree and applying for graduate school. Can you talk about this experience? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; When I graduated from my undergraduate degree, it was at the end of the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and I was assigned to participate in labor training in the Northeast. I started out as a road maintenance worker building railroads. At that time, all major railway bureaus in our country had enterprise newspapers, and Jinzhou Railway had an enterprise newspaper called &quot;Jintie News&quot;. More than half a year later, they found out about me and transferred me to the newspaper as an editor and reporter. The newspaper office often holds correspondent training classes. Since I major in journalism, I often give lectures and have a relatively harmonious relationship with everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After staying there for a while, our country resumed the college entrance examination. At first, the railway didn’t want to let me go because I had already graduated from my undergraduate degree. But later, the Jinzhou Railway Bureau heard that both Renmin University and Fudan University were recruiting master&#39;s degree students (there were no graduate students in the journalism major before) and agreed that I would try to take the exam. I passed the exam right away and was the first batch of master&#39;s students recruited in our country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Reform and opening up on your personal destiny What is the impact? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; The changes in my personal destiny are closely linked to reform and opening up. Sometimes I often say in meetings or classes that I am very grateful to Deng Xiaoping. If the college entrance examination and university admissions are not resumed, I may still be a reporter at the Jinzhou Railway Bureau tabloid for the rest of my life. If I do well, I may be promoted to deputy editor-in-chief or editor-in-chief. However, my ideal is not in this place. I still want to engage in academics and theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; During graduate school, Professor Gan was How did that guide you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; Mr. Gan Xifen is also recruiting graduate students for the first time, and his requirements for me are relatively strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There were pilot projects before the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot;, but they could not be carried out after a while, so there was no master&#39;s degree in journalism before 1978. The lifelong wish of these old gentlemen is to push forward journalism research. The National People&#39;s Congress and Fudan University were the first to do relevant work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mr. Gan Xifen emphasized two points when guiding me. The first point is to read the original works. He believes that graduate students in journalism should learn more classic works; the second point is to practice. I always insisted on these two points while studying at Renmin University, and I persisted relatively well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;How do you insist on these two points? required? What are the specific methods? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; I had classes during the day, read in the afternoon, and went to the journalism department office around 4 o&#39;clock to read the day&#39;s newspapers. , we poor students could not afford to subscribe to newspapers at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I come back from the classroom and library at 9pm, I review the day&#39;s newspapers in the dormitory, including the day&#39;s &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; and &quot;China Youth Daily&quot;. The review is conducted 5 nights a week, each person is responsible for one week, and several people take turns. The students responsible for reviewing the newspaper should take notes and write a report every week, which should be sent to the newspaper. The newspaper also attaches great importance to our opinions and will reply to us every once in a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This arrangement is very helpful to our study. After a 3-year master&#39;s degree, I stuck to this method for almost 3 years. We also have many contacts with news organizations and have a relatively close relationship. I did the same thing until I stayed in school to become a teacher after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Continuously opening new courses and recruiting new students&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;In 1983, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council agreed to establish a doctorate in journalism. Under the background of that time, if you graduate with a master&#39;s degree and work as a university teacher, your academic qualifications are enough. Why do you continue to study for a doctorate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Child Soldier:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;One is because of the need for theoretical study , studying for a doctoral degree will give you the opportunity to audit courses in many other majors at Renmin University. For example, I have listened to history, scientific socialism, and international politics. When I went to attend classes, none of the teachers refused. They saw that I was not too young and still eager to learn, so they generally allowed me to enter their classrooms, and I often asked questions in class. In this regard, they really treated me. Very considerate: When I go to ask questions after class, other teachers or classmates will stop and let me (ask questions first). In the process of my study, it can be said that many teachers from relevant majors at Renmin University have helped me a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, my supervisor and other teachers in the journalism department hope that I can take the lead in helping the school establish a doctoral program in journalism. Later, the State Education Commission agreed that journalism would have a doctoral degree. At that time, China began to have doctoral programs (in journalism), and two schools were approved, one was the Journalism Department of Fudan University, and the other was the Journalism Department of Renmin University of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;After graduating from the Ph.D., you stayed He taught at the National People&#39;s Congress and returned to his alma mater, Fudan University, in 2001. What did you think at that time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>;After completing my master&#39;s degree at Renmin University, I stayed in school because of the needs of school work. At that time, our journalism industry was in great need of talents, and young people wanted to join it and go out into the society. But the instructor said something to me, which moved me very much. The Cultural Revolution delayed it for ten years, and they really wanted to restore our major as soon as possible, so they hoped that I could stay and teach in this school with peace of mind. Only by staying in this profession and being a good teacher can this profession continue to have new talents and new developments. I quickly accepted the arrangements in the school and worked hard. I have done a lot of pioneering work over the past few decades. It is very worthwhile when I think about it now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moving from the National People&#39;s Congress to teaching at Fudan is also an adjustment arrangement for the school. At that time, Fudan was in great need of people. Compared with Renmin University, Fudan&#39;s development is more international. Many outstanding students have gone abroad after graduation. The teachers are getting older and their health is getting worse every year. We teachers and students know each other very well, and we see this situation with our eyes and are anxious in our hearts. Therefore, the school raised this expectation and hoped that we can come back to shoulder the heavy burden. I came back without saying anything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the beginning, there was a lot of pressure and a heavy burden. Journalism was delayed for many years by the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; and is in urgent need of development. The desire for talents is everywhere. So whether I stayed at the National People&#39;s Congress or was later called by Fudan University, I just taught with peace of mind, constantly opening new courses and recruiting new students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This has been the case for these years. It can be said that when there is no time to breathe, there is no chance to sleep peacefully. Although we were very tired at the time, we soon overcame these difficulties and continued to make new progress in our work. Looking back now, I still think it was worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Understand your mission”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;/span>;In your opinion, what is the overall shift in current journalism research and what are its deficiencies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing: &lt;/strong>;Differences in theoretical viewpoints are inevitable, natural, and reasonable. (The development of journalism research) I think it ultimately depends on the progress of journalism practice. You are right to insist on your point of view. As a result, newspapers and radio and television have been successfully run. This shows that theory guides practice. On the other hand, if your theory is sound and sound, but no one reads your newspaper or listens to your broadcast, it shows that your theory has no power. Isn&#39;t this a problem? This is where we theorists feel ashamed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, there is still a strong culture of self-appreciation in the academic world, which should not be the case. The academic community should review this and analyze the reasons behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Journalism has always faced the &quot;news What do you think of the questioning and debate about &quot;no learning&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tongbing:&lt;/strong>; The &quot;no-learning theory&quot; has long-term influence on the development of journalism, mainly due to several circumstances. Journalism started relatively late, and there are not many independent scholarships and works. The aspect of journalism that has a deeper impact on China is practice. Running newspapers, radio stations, and television stations are all based on practical work. There are not many people who actually engage in theoretical research. Not big either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;These understandings affect the status and image of journalism in various liberal arts majors. After we got PhDs, China&#39;s journalism research gradually got on the right track and started to have something decent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;How do you understand journalists Mission? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Child Soldier:&lt;/strong>; Journalists must understand their mission. The simplest and simplest requirement is to report the truth to the people. , real news, that’s the most important thing. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #c00000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;Journalism Freshman Can you give some life advice to college students who have just entered school? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Tong Bing:&lt;/strong>; This is a very broad proposition. I think the life development of college students is the same as the operation characteristics of our entire country. , one wave after another, one tide after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As teachers, we hope that the new students can inherit the good traditions of the school and develop them stronger, so that the university will become better and better, and the college students themselves will also become better and better. We can continue to make progress. Only in this way will our country become better and better and our career become more and more brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So after college students enter university, the first thing is to understand their mission. Everyone should have their own arrangements and expectations. This is not just lip service, it is actually something that must be done. We all came slowly from undergraduate to master&#39;s and doctoral degrees. New students especially need to have a sense of mission and have expectations, prospects, and arrangements for the future. I think this is the most important thing. Time flies so fast. Even if you look at the four years of undergraduate studies, half of it has passed in the blink of an eye. However, the task is actually endless. We still need to continue to work hard, strive for, and develop in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;College students should not be afraid of being tired. Only by constantly exploring their own prospects can individuals have new goals, new directions, and continuous progress. Learn more every day, overcome your shortcomings, and show new expectations. This is my common expectation for our college students, whether they are undergraduates, masters, or doctoral students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“机场判官”再曝住宿骗局：虚假定位误导消费者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;July 5, 2020, Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Visual China Map&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/c903be4634.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/c903be4634.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;July 5, 2020, Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yi is a self-media flight blogger. He daily researches where to find tickets and where the airport services are better. He published &quot; Video content such as &quot;How to get a refund for an expensive ticket&quot; is more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the &quot;free transit accommodation scam&quot; at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport was exposed on September 12, 2023, Liu Yi has released 16 videos related to Xi&#39;an Airport, pointing out Its existing management problems have been called the &quot;airport judge&quot; by netizens. With the update of this series of videos, the Xi&#39;an transfer strategy that Liu Yi originally wanted to do has gradually evolved into a &quot;spy war drama&quot;. Netizens not only liked and followed it, but also continued to provide clues to Liu Yi. In Liu Yi&#39;s account (the account name is &quot;This is not too much&quot;), videos related to Xi&#39;an Airport have become &quot;top-rated&quot; content, and many of them have more than three million views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of November 20, Liu Yi once again released a video saying that hotels and B&amp;Bs around Xi&#39;an Airport posted false positioning on the OTA platform (online travel hotel platform) For hotel information, he searched these platforms for a B&amp;B several hundred meters away from the airport, and actually had to take a car there. Previously, the person in charge of Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport promised in a media interview that a more powerful comprehensive management mechanism would be established to address the problems existing at Xi&#39;an Airport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 23, staff of the Airport New District Management Committee of Xixian New City, Xi&#39;an told Southern Weekend reporters that the Market Supervision Branch, Comprehensive Law Enforcement Detachment, and Public Security Bureau that day Staff from the Guangde Road Police Station and the Beidu Street Office have formed a joint law enforcement team to inspect the B&amp;Bs in Bianfang Village and Dashoudou Village and urge them to make rectifications. “Regarding Xi’an’s city image, we are still very Attention.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Falsely positioned B&amp;B&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as Liu Yi released the 10th video related to Xi&#39;an Airport, security personnel can be seen almost everywhere at Xi&#39;an Airport To maintain order, the &quot;liars&quot; who were previously exposed to solicit customers in violation of regulations are hard to find. In the video released on November 20, Liu Yi deliberately took the high-speed train from Beijing to Xi&#39;an in order to avoid leaking his itinerary, and then took a bus to Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport to &quot;patrol&quot;, which confirmed that the positioning of B&amp;Bs around the airport on the OTA platform was fraudulent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this video, Liu Yi searched for the hotel with the closest straight line distance on a platform, and the first-ranked &quot;Jiaxuan Boutique B&amp;B&quot; was marked &quot;from Xianyang The international airport is 340 meters straight.&quot; In fact, the passenger arrived at the online car-hailing parking lot, which is the hotel pick-up location. Then he searched on another platform, and multiple Huangzhixiang Hotel branches appeared on the page, one of which was &quot;119 meters &quot;Straight-line distance from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport&quot;, but when I called, the other party told me that the hotel is behind the terminal and that I need to wait for the car to pick me up; finally, the Shitouji Inn, which was &quot;less than 100 meters away from you in a straight line&quot; on the third platform, was also falsely positioned. . Liu Yi believes that these B&amp;Bs are engaging in fraud on the OTA platform and are operating in bad faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 20, 2023, Liu Yi used the online travel hotel platform to search for nearby accommodation at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6921534e57.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1120&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/29/6921534e57.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 11 On March 20, Liu Yi used the online travel hotel platform to search for nearby accommodation at Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the video posted by Liu Yi, many netizens provided screenshots of the above-mentioned negative reviews of the falsely positioned hotel: &quot;Didn&#39;t pay attention to the words above The straight-line distance is too deceptive. The hotel is actually more than 8 kilometers away from the airport. It is said to be an inn, but it is actually a room owned by farmers near the airport, and the sanitary rooms are extremely poor.&quot; Some netizens said that there are already tourists on the online platform Comments mentioned issues such as long distances and fake room pictures, but this type of B&amp;B still ranks high on the platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yi discovered that the above-mentioned B&amp;Bs were falsely positioned at the online car-hailing parking lot, T3 terminal, and T2 terminal of Xi&#39;an Airport. According to the information he collected, these B&amp;Bs are basically run by villagers from Bianfang Village and Shitou Village near the airport. Because they are close to the airport, these villages have developed a transit accommodation industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 22, Southern Weekend reporters searched on Ctrip, Tongcheng, Fliggy and other platforms, and only &quot;near Xi&#39;an Xianyang International&quot; was displayed in the hotel list. Airport&quot; but does not show the specific distance. Then type in the search for the three falsely positioned B&amp;Bs mentioned in Liu Yi&#39;s video. The Ctrip platform has removed all three stores; however, some platforms can still search for Jiaxuan Boutique Apartment, which shows that it is sold out and cannot be pre-ordered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The address page of Fliggy Search Jiaxuan Business Hotel is still marked &quot;About 300 meters west of Terminal T2 of Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport&quot;. When a Southern Weekend reporter called as a customer to ask if the hotel was within the terminal, the staff told her that it was a 3-minute drive outside the terminal and that there would be someone to pick her up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yi said that these falsely positioned B&amp;Bs not only appear on the above-mentioned platforms, but also exist on other platforms. On another OTA platform, a store that was marked on the 20th as &quot;less than 100 meters away from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport in a straight line, about a 1-minute walk&quot; was modified on the 22nd to &quot;4.5 kilometers from Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport by car, about 9 minutes.&quot; When a reporter from Southern Weekend asked why it was only a one-minute walk away, the store owner did not reply directly, but emphasized that &quot;I am outside the airport, and there is no way it is as cheap as ours inside the airport.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 22, Southern Weekend reporters contacted four OTA platforms, Ctrip, Tongcheng, Fliggy and Meituan, but received no reply. An industry insider on the OTA platform who did not want to be named analyzed that the platform needs to verify the address of the hotel before it goes online, and also conducts daily verification and inspections after going online. The current listings with false addresses should be due to the operators providing fake business operations. For example, the address on the license or lease contract is the same as the online address, so it is difficult for the platform to identify it. At the same time, various online travel and hotel platforms still have some agent listings, and some listings are closed on one platform and re-listed on other platforms. &quot;If the platform does not effectively intercept, it will be difficult to investigate and deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The person in charge of the above-mentioned Airport New City told Southern Weekend reporters that the local market supervision department has interviewed three OTA platforms in the past two days and ordered them to strengthen the management of homestays around the airport. Information review. Offline, the joint law enforcement team they formed also conducted focused investigations on several issues mentioned by the blogger, including whether the names on the special industry license, business license, and door plaque were consistent, and whether the pictures on the platform were consistent with the actual situation. etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Dilemma of Passengers’ Rights Protection&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few days after Liu Yi released the video, netizens left messages one after another, talking about their travels in Xiamen, Kunming, Dali, Airports in Shanghai and other places have also encountered similar problems, but not many people choose to be tough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Netizen Zhang Ning landed at Fuzhou Airport on September 4. At that time, he chose a platform to introduce a hotel only 200 meters away from the airport. The picture looked clean and spacious. The result The man who picked her up drove her for more than ten minutes and took her to a self-built building, saying that this was a hotel. Zhang Ning reasoned with the hotel receptionist about why the hotel location and photos were different from those on the platform. The other party said, &quot;That&#39;s an old hotel and it&#39;s closed.&quot; He didn&#39;t provide a specific address and asked her to get there and take a taxi. It was already late at night, so Zhang Ning could only stay after repeated considerations, and asked the airport pick-up staff to take her back to the airport the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Originally I wanted to give a negative review, but because he has my personal information, I didn&#39;t dare to give it.&quot; Zhang Ning said that she was worried about being retaliated against, and she didn&#39;t want to give it to herself. create unnecessary trouble during the journey. A few months after the incident, Zhang Ning recorded the incident in Liu Yi&#39;s video comment area, &quot;I hope more people will see these issues and support him in safeguarding his rights.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the video recorded by Liu Yi, his process of exposing the accommodation scam was also quite tortuous. On September 12, Liu Yi, as a flight blogger, went to Xi&#39;an Airport to experience transit accommodation for the first time. Unexpectedly, the &quot;scammer&quot; directly solicited customers at the airport gate, posing as a hotel staff with free transit accommodation, and wanted to take him to a paid hotel. Liu Yi simply recorded the video and exposed it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Previously, Liu Yi reported that Xi&#39;an Airport&#39;s transit accommodation was being solicited by &quot;Li Gui&quot;, and the airport promised to continue to improve the passenger experience. Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/a242806d6d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;864&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/29/a242806d6d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260052&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Netizens reported transit accommodation at Xi&#39;an Airport Facing &quot;Li Gui&quot; attracting passengers, the airport promised to continue to improve the passenger experience. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 20, the Shaanxi Airport Public Security Bureau stated that it had stepped up inspection and control efforts and severely cracked down on illegal activities such as pretending to be staff to solicit passengers for transportation and accommodation. For disorderly conduct, 148 people have been punished since September and 3 people were detained administratively. But soon, when Liu Yi arrived at Xi&#39;an Airport again, the scammer only moved from Gate 324 to Gate 322 of the airport, and the security guards did not effectively intercept him. During this period, Liu Yi began to receive various complaints and threats in private messages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Liu Yi landed at Xi&#39;an Airport for the third time, the security guard&#39;s attention became Liu Yi himself. Liu Yi mentioned that the security guard went to him when he passed by. The intercom shouted &quot;He&#39;s passed.&quot; During that trip, some netizens informed Liu Yi that her trip information had been leaked. According to screenshots provided by netizens, Liu Yi checked in at Shenzhen to fly to Xi&#39;an on October 24. At 18:42, a message appeared in the black car group at Xi&#39;an Airport that Liu Yi was about to go to Xi&#39;an, reminding everyone to be careful. For this reason, Liu Yi had to call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the following video, he said that he would buy 15 air tickets, fly from Shenzhen to Xi&#39;an once a week, and inspect the airport for improvements. He believes that compared to ordinary passengers, as a flight blogger, he can enjoy free tickets and discounts from many airlines, which provides a basis for rights protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Liu Yi said that the follow-up handling of his personal information leakage case was not satisfactory. The police found the security guard who spread the information, but were unable to find out who leaked it. He also understands this. The chain involved in the leakage of passengers&#39; personal information is too long and difficult to trace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted the Airport Public Security Bureau of the Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department several times but failed to get through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Yi&#39;s courage to defend his rights has aroused the sympathy of many fans. Liu Yi said that the content he received most in the backend was from netizens from all over the world asking for help, including those whose mobile phones were stolen at the airport, those who were deceived into staying in hotels, etc. &quot;Most of them I can only comfort.&quot; The communication between Liu Yi and the relevant departments of the airport has always been &quot;dialogue over the air.&quot; Liu Yi said that the airport management department contacted him after posting the relevant video for the second time and expressed the hope that he could come to Xi&#39;an to communicate in person. Liu Yi felt that it was inappropriate. Conveniently, I declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The person in charge of the above-mentioned Airport New City Management Committee stated that Xi&#39;an Xianyang International Airport, Xixian New District Airport New City, and the Airport Public Security Bureau of the Shaanxi Provincial Public Security Department have launched a A comprehensive management office was set up in Japan to rectify the behavior of soliciting passengers in the airport terminal. At present, this problem has been basically solved. They got in further contact with Liu Yi on November 23 and will continue to make improvements based on the issues he reported. &quot;Having such enthusiastic bloggers point out some problems in development to us, and if we correct them, I think it will also help progress.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 November On March 24, Liu Yi once again updated the Xi&#39;an Airport series of videos. He asked fans to experience the B&amp;Bs around Xi&#39;an Airport, pointing out that these B&amp;Bs still have problems such as photos that are different from the actual situation and store signs that are inconsistent. &quot;Next, I want to see how this rectification (referring to the joint rectification action by the local regulatory authorities on the 23rd) will be.&quot; It won’t bring good results.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Liu Yi and Zhang Ning are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>; &lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[任伯年和他的公孙大娘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 08:37:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/2dJwOHFCf1QgUgg5MyRO7rgRrqXLoLotXOVfkc18.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/2dJwOHFCf1QgUgg5MyRO7rgRrqXLoLotXOVf kc18. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259265&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Wei Art Museum, Shaoxing, Zhejiang, &quot;The Impermanence of the Pen, the Elegance and the Richness&quot; by Ren Bonian Painting exhibition site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total length is nearly 13 meters and it is opened for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that Xu Wei&#39;s &quot;Flowers of the Four Seasons&quot; collected by the Palace Museum has left the palace. Going out of the palace means going home. At this moment, it is lying quietly in the Xu Wei Art Museum in Shaoxing. This is the first time it has been unfolded so completely. Prior to this, due to the limitations of the exhibition space, this long scroll had never been completely opened. Visitors to the exhibition could only see part of it. Even in the album, it could only be broken down piece by piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flowers in the four seasons have never been in full bloom at the same time. Peonies and peonies in spring, grapes and bananas in midsummer, osmanthus and pines in autumn, bamboo branches and old plums with snow in winter, all splashing together to create a wonderful achievement. The &quot;Rise of Smoke and Clouds&quot; by Xu Wei, the founder of Chinese freehand brushwork and a giant of the generation. The self-revealed poem at the end of the volume is even more sophisticated: &quot;I am dripping with ink while playing games. Flowers and plants will be mixed all the time. No wonder there are two strokes missing in the painting. The way of heaven has been very bad recently.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening time of Xu Wei Art Museum is different. It was only officially put into use in 2021, which was still during the COVID-19 epidemic. Since the opening of the museum, there have been only three large-scale exhibitions, but each of them was &quot;flawless&quot;. The opening exhibition was the exhibition of the &quot;freak Ivy&quot; Xu Wei himself, followed by Chen Laolian. By 2023, It is a special performance by Ren Bonian, and each performance is worth a special trip. The 13-meter &quot;Flowers of the Four Seasons&quot; came from Ren Bonian&#39;s exhibition. Although Xu Wei and his fellow countryman Ren Bonian are more than 300 years apart in time, the intersection in space and the transmission of culture can be called the inheritance of pen and ink in a broad sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/HPXewWe9C11GQigdCrEXNX4QPRGcowIm1pwsasyB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/HPXewWe9C11GQigdCrEXNX4QPRGcowIm1pwsasyB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259263&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhong Kui in the works of Ren Bonian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Bonian, a painter in the late Qing Dynasty, was a leader among the &quot;Shanghai School&quot; and the &quot;Four Rens&quot;, especially the figures. Good at painting. When Ren Bonian was young, his family ran a rice shop, but his father was good at painting and taught him in his spare time. It is said that Ren Bonian was able to draw lifelike figures very early. It is said that one time someone came to see his father, but his father was not there. When he came back and heard about it, he asked Ren Bonian who the visitor was. Bonian was only ten years old at the time and could not answer the guest&#39;s name, so he had to take a piece of paper and draw the person&#39;s name. His appearance was obvious to his father at a glance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ren Bonian was 22 years old, the Taiping Heavenly Kingdom invaded Shaoxing and his father was killed. Ren Bonian was also involved in the war and held the flag for the Taiping Army. He later lived in Ningbo and Shanghai and made a living selling paintings. Ren Xiong and Ren Xun among the &quot;Four Rens on the Sea&quot; are Ren Bonian&#39;s clan uncles, and they both taught him painting, but he soon became better than his master. In this exhibition of Ren Bonian&#39;s paintings titled &quot;Impermanent Brushwork, Elegance and Richness&quot;, his paintings are displayed together with the other &quot;Three Rens&quot;, making a judgment, although he learned from Ren Xun The complicated &quot;nail head and rat tail&quot; brushwork, but the same painting of people, Ren Bonian&#39;s stylist Fa Chen Laolian immediately got rid of Ren Xun&#39;s vulgarity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Wu shepherding sheep, Xizhi loves geese, Zhong Kui...these are common themes in Ren Bonian&#39;s works, and they are characters he repeatedly painted. The Zhong Kui he painted is especially chic, with a high attitude and a swaggering look. The knights, often in these works with new and surprising shapes, you can get a glimpse of the painter&#39;s true temperament and sense of humor. The same goes for his paintings of flowers and birds. The fat bird with its big white eyes comes from Bada Shanren, but the extraordinary rise of Bada turned into joy in Ren Bonian&#39;s place. The chicks that have just emerged from their eggshells under the crape myrtle flowers are fluffy and childish. His gait and expression are like those of a gangster, he is still young and arrogant, which makes people smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Egpnr7tr8haTxsmnwxwnPmwCUl88sESebNpNhPcg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;461&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/Egpnr7tr8haTxsmnwxwnPmwCUl88sESebNpNhPcg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aunt Gongsun is considered to be the best master of sword dancing in the prosperous Tang Dynasty&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most interesting one is &quot;A Picture of Aunt Gongsun Dancing with Swords&quot;. It is said that Aunt Gongsun was the number one dancer in the prosperous age of Kaiyuan, and was promoted to be the best dancer in the prosperous Tang Dynasty for her sword dancing. Zhang Xu, the grass sage, understood the essence of cursive script from her sword skills, and Wu Daozi, the painting sage, also learned about Gongsun Auntie’s dance by watching her dance. Use the sword to learn how to use the pen. What the actual situation is cannot be determined now, but look at Ren Bonian&#39;s painting of sword dancing. Gongsun danced the two white blades as if they were practiced softly. The artist did not hesitate to draw hundreds of circles to record the imaginary and the real. All the traces of the sword flying across the air, the leaves on the big tree branches behind Aunt Gongsun trembled, as if they felt the sword energy, but Aunt Gongsun herself remained unmoved, her expression was quite calm, she was the one who stood firm among the thousands of changes. The core of change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Beihong once said: Ren Bonian is &quot;the first Chinese painter after Qiu Shizhou (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qiu Ying&lt;/span>;) &quot;I don&#39;t care whether this statement is fair or not, but at least it reflects Xu Beihong&#39;s preference for Ren Bonian. This preference may be related to Ren Bonian&#39;s position. He lives in Shanghai all year round and makes a living selling paintings. Therefore, his paintings combine literati paintings and fireworks. Indeed, we can see many traces of connecting the past and the future, connecting China and the world. It is a rich and flexible tradition of calligraphy and painting, which is at the confluence and turning point of the tide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都新力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261516]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-30 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The power of a city to move forward largely comes from the new strength of the new youth. Looking at the country, Chengdu can be one of the leaders in exploring and embracing this urban power engine. From building a nest to attract &quot;Rongcheng drifters&quot;, to building a &quot;City of Volunteers&quot;, to new young people and new careers, we observe the uniqueness of this Chengdu from a top-down perspective.</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[拼多多市值距阿里仅一步之遥，“多多的时代来临”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261574]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 23:19:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73842&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70633&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ff632a6137.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG5565.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pinduoduo’s wall-painting promotion in 2020. Image source: Pinduoduo Weibo&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ff632a6137. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260131&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pinduoduo’s wall-painting promotion in 2020. Image source: Pinduoduo Weibo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 28, 2023, Beijing time, Pinduoduo’s intraday trading repeatedly hit new highs, rising by more than 18%. Within fifteen minutes, the market value increased by $100 million. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the opening to the closing, Pinduoduo’s total market value soared from US$156.4 billion to US$184.7 billion, a surge of nearly 30 billion. As of the close, Pinduoduo was only tens of billions away from Alibaba, which has a market capitalization of US$195.2 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If compared according to the price limit rules of China&#39;s A-share market, Pinduoduo is only one &quot;price limit&quot; away from Alibaba. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinduoduo’s rapid rise has triggered heated discussions among investors. Some people lamented that the throne of e-commerce is about to change hands and that &quot;an era of great things is coming&quot;, while others joked that &quot;the higher the stock price rises, the poorer everyone becomes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fierce reaction of the capital market stems from Pinduoduo’s outstanding performance in the third quarter of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 28, Pinduoduo (PDD.Nasdaq) released its financial report for the third quarter of 2023 (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;financial report&quot;), with revenue of 68.84 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 94%, not in accordance with U.S. GAAP (Non-GAAP), net profit attributable to Pinduoduo’s ordinary shareholders was 17.027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 37%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We can clearly feel the continued recovery of the economy, as well as the potential and resilience of the consumer market. At the same time, we also see from user behavior that consumption upgrades are both about quality and price. The optimization of price-performance ratio is consumers&#39; ultimate pursuit of good products at good prices.&quot; said Chen Lei, Chairman and Co-CEO of Pinduoduo Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reviewing Pinduoduo’s past financial reports, it achieved (Non-GAAP) quarterly profit for the first time in the third quarter of 2020, a year-on-year increase of 89%. Since then, although revenue has doubled on average every quarter, it was not until the second quarter of 2021 that Pinduoduo achieved double growth in revenue and net profit in a single quarter for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to now, Pinduoduo has drawn a significant upward curve of revenue growth and net profit doubling for two consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Buy a lot of groceries, a hidden revenue tool&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Lei attributed the revenue growth to the improvement of the consumer environment and the implementation of the company&#39;s &quot;high-quality development&quot; strategy. Judging from the financial report, Pinduoduo’s 94% revenue growth was due to the double increase in revenue from its two main businesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Online marketing services and other services increased by 39% year-on-year, and transaction service revenue increased by as much as 315% year-on-year. The two account for about half of the total revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What supports the growth of transaction service revenue is generally an increase in the number of active merchants on the platform and an increase in the average transaction service revenue of each active merchant (i.e. commission). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter learned from a Pinduoduo merchant that the transaction commission is charged based on the sales price of the completed order, and the commission will not be refunded if the consumer returns the product. Pinduoduo did not release GMV (gross merchandise transaction) data in this financial report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huang Lichong, President of Huisheng International Capital, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that transaction service fees actually include the income of Duoduo Maicai. This quarter’s unexpected growth is due to the rapid expansion of Duoduo Maicai. Huang Lichong once served as executive director and managing director of the investment banking department of China International Finance Securities (Hong Kong). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duoduomaicai was launched in August 2020. Since then, Pinduoduo’s transaction service fee income has increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Lei commented at the 2020 third quarter earnings conference call that Duoduo’s grocery shopping business is “a platform that consumers use very frequently.” Entering the fourth quarter of 2020, Pinduoduo’s number of active buyers surpassed Alibaba for the first time, reaching 788 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its establishment, Duoduomaicai has gone through many rounds of fierce battles between platforms and has survived the dark moment of community group buying. According to reports from many media including Qilu Evening News, nine provinces have been shut down in order to target the prosperity of the sinking market. Jingxi Pinpin is only left in Langfang, Hebei and Beijing. Other community group buying has also been shut down one after another. Currently, Pinduoduo and Meituan Each controls half of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2023, the US asset management company HAYDEN CAPITAL estimated that by 2025, Duoduo Maicai will contribute at least about 14 billion yuan in EBIT to Pinduoduo, which may start in 2023 Achieve overall profitability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this financial performance meeting, Chen Lei introduced that Pinduoduo started out in agricultural products and retained a number of users through agricultural products services. However, the current online rate of this category is low, and there is huge potential in the future. potential. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Duoduo’s grocery shopping, the market generally speculates that Duoduo’s cross-border services may create a new revenue growth curve for Pinduoduo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2022, Pinduoduo launched the cross-border e-commerce project Temu, which Chen Lei regarded as his &quot;third venture.&quot; At that time, Pinduoduo’s vice president of finance, Liu Jun, said that cross-border business was in its early stages and would have little impact on financial reports. Temu’s revenue data was not announced in this financial report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duoduo’s cross-border project is led by Gu Pingping, the former head of Duoduo’s grocery shopping, and inherits Pinduoduo’s domestic supply, talent, and marketing advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this financial report meeting, Liu Jun said, &quot;Pinduoduo&#39;s global business is still in a very early stage, and the team is still increasing its understanding of consumer needs in different markets around the world.&quot; Currently, Temu has launched a In 2016, it has expanded to 40 countries and regions around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Getting out of the quagmire of losses&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 28, in contrast to the upward trend in Pinduoduo’s stock price, the stock price of Alibaba (BABA.NYSE) dropped all the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumption downgrading is an increasingly clear trend. Consumers are moving from platforms with high unit prices to low-price platforms. Low price is still the key for Pinduoduo to occupy the sinking market in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at Pinduoduo’s growth history, the “10 billion subsidy” strategy has not only opened up the market for it, but is also the main reason for dragging down its financial performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinduoduo has faced significant losses since its listing. From 2018 to the first quarter of 2020, losses continued to expand. In June 2019, after the &quot;Ten Billion Subsidy&quot; was launched, it achieved GMV growth and increased user activity. The price was that its sales and marketing expenses exceeded profits, which was equivalent to all the revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering the second quarter of 2020, Pinduoduo’s losses have narrowed. Ma Jing, Pinduoduo’s vice president of finance at the time, said at the earnings conference call, “Profitability will not be considered this year.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until the third quarter of 2020 that Pinduoduo achieved profitability for the first time, which was also when CEO Chen Lei took office. The first report card after. This year, Pinduoduo launched Duoduo’s grocery shopping business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinduoduo really &quot;taken off&quot; in the second quarter of 2021, with both revenue and profit increasing, and getting out of the mire of losses. Since then, it has almost maintained a double-digit profit growth. In particular, three quarters in 2022 will achieve multiple growth, with profits in the second quarter nearly tripling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jing responded at the second quarter 2021 conference call that revenue growth stems from the increase in the number of users and the increase in user psychological share, and the second quarter is the off-season for marketing, so marketing expenditures are small and there are seasonal factors. Special reasons for sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Pinduoduo executives also made no secret of the fact that the increase in profits comes from cost reduction and efficiency increase during the 2021 financial results conference call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Lichong said that over the years, Pinduoduo has optimized its operating costs, reduced some unnecessary expenses, increased profit margins by increasing product prices and reducing after-sales service costs, while investing in technology, logistics, agriculture and other fields. , improve its own competitiveness and business efficiency. These strategies have effectively helped it get out of losses and achieve profits beyond expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pinduoduo’s executive director and co-CEO Zhao Jiazhen revealed in a recent earnings conference call that during the just past “Double Eleven” promotion, the number of users of Pinduoduo’s “10 billion subsidy” has exceeded 620 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the first trading day after the financial report was released, employees on Alibaba’s intranet discussed Pinduoduo’s performance in the capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba partner Jack Ma rarely replied, &quot;All great companies are born in winter. The era of AI e-commerce has just begun, and it is both an opportunity and a challenge for everyone. I would like to congratulate Pinduoduo for the past few years. Decision-making, execution and efforts. No one is better, but those who can reform for the sake of tomorrow and the organization that are willing to pay any price and sacrifice are respected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戏骨云集的《风声》姐妹篇，砸了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261518]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The new theatrical film &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; is the latest version of &quot;The Wind&quot; &quot;Sister volume of &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also an original work by Mai Jia + director Gao Qunshu, with a spy war theme + a bone drama, but the reputation is far different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5e5887f258139695a465a4e2e7c48738.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1511&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/5e5887f258139695a465a4e2e7c48738.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259921&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Today, 14 years after its release, &quot;The Wind&quot; is still the leading Chinese-language spy suspense film. 600,000 people gave it a high score of 8.4 on Douban, which is better than 95% of dramas and 98% of thrillers. In comparison, &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; has a Douban score of 6.1, and it is unlikely to reach the heights of &quot;The Wind&quot; in terms of both word-of-mouth and box office. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/240c6f058d0b121185dc67f8f21e3e4a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;464&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/240c6f058d0b121185dc67f8f21e3e4a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259919 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/59089ff6d250eacc963658639724d61e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;668&quot; height=&quot;289&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/59089ff6d250eacc963658639724d61e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259922&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Point of the Knife&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Adapted from Mai Jia&#39;s &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; novel of the same name, the background is set in Nanjing in the 1940s. Military agent Jin Shenshui&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Zhang Yi)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has been lurking in the Wang Puppet Government for many years, dealing with all forces, walking on thin ice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/3361926c18fa852e3ae27136aab585d1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/3361926c18fa852e3ae27136aab585d1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259918 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the surface, Director of the Secret Service Jin Shenshui and Director of the Security Bureau Lu Jingyu&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Huang Zhizhong)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Secretary Lin Ying Ying&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Lang Yueting)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; belongs to the same camp, but in fact they do not trust each other. Lu Jingyu is his immediate boss, and the two have deep interests tied together. Lin Yingying was the illegitimate daughter of a wealthy businessman. She was assigned this job under the care of Wang Jingwei, so everyone in Wang&#39;s puppet government avoided her. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/39f5a0dd2029157bf92c32df44bdac58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/39f5a0dd2029157bf92c32df44bdac58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259917 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/92af105b6076864696847138a6260cab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/92af105b6076864696847138a6260cab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259920&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Deputy Director of the Security Bureau Yu Zhiren&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Gao Jie)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has won over another force in the Security Bureau: the anti-special forces Chief Li Shiwu&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Sha Yi)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Deputy Director Xiaoma&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(played by Li Chun)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Confidential Division Deputy Director Qin Guangguang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (played by Jin Shijia)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. Yu Zhiren also holds the title of Commissioner of the Police Station, so he and Lu Jingyu have a rivalry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/3e7f52fc2bb89f9ed27d283ca71e0300.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/3e7f52fc2bb89f9ed27d283ca71e0300.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259923 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The first half of the plot of &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; revolves around the office politics of the Security Bureau. The Japanese military officer issued an order to &quot;find out the insider&quot;, which triggered an office struggle among insiders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, ignoring the bugs in the character&#39;s logic, this part is quite watchable, and it is vaguely a low-end version of Qiuzhuang&#39;s ghost-catching in &quot;The Wind&quot;. Lu and Yu&#39;s small team took action one after another, some to protect themselves, others to bite each other. It didn&#39;t matter who the real mole was, what was important was to take the opportunity to eliminate dissidents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/e48a3c0d3863c0c34d242363a2399c45.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/e48a3c0d3863c0c34d242363a2399c45.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259927 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why is it called a low-end version? Because there is a clear MacGuffin in &quot;The Wind&quot; (the focus of the suspense film) - who is the old ghost. However, &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; revealed the truth to the audience from the very beginning. The identities of Jin Shenshui and Lin Yingying were two bright cards that were played too early, and there was no suspense left. We&#39;re just waiting to see how they can use their strength to survive the internal purge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b3d3ffeeaf284eab333a9359d504203e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/b3d3ffeeaf284eab333a9359d504203e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259924 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The highlight of &quot;The Wind&quot; is by no means torture, but this was highlighted in the pre-release marketing in the past. The trailers and character specials of &quot;The Edge of the Knife&quot; also have similar ideas. It mainly highlights the continuous punishment stunts during the internal fighting, such as pulling out nails, pouring sulfuric acid, sitting on the tiger bench, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/61b498a3a850489f380e99831aef8c6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/61b498a3a850489f380e99831aef8c6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259925 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, the director made reasonable use of the characteristics of the actors&#39; past high-profile roles&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (for example, Huang Zhizhong&#39;s performance is similar to the role of Yang Liren in &quot;The Righteous Way in the World is Vicissitudes of Life&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;, so that they can maintain stable performance while performing experiential performances,&lt;/span>; at least the audience can accurately grasp the characters they convey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cruel scenes that challenge the physical limits, the medium-to-high-intensity &quot;werewolf killing&quot; and the survival game in which everyone is in danger ensure the tension in the first half of the film. But unfortunately, since the victory of the Lu faction and the end of the internal fighting, the film has fallen into piecemeal chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first hour and the last hour of &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; are as separate as if they were not the same movie. The second half of the film focuses on Jin Shenshui&#39;s abandonment of darkness and the light under the influence of Lin Yingying, the destruction of the military command group in Nanjing, and the two men&#39;s revenge like lone rangers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/4d15d7961ec0dec26a49b22d4e8969e5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/4d15d7961ec0dec26a49b22d4e8969e5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259928 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because the plot was too complicated and fragmented, and the time&lt;/span>; span was long, the director had to arrange multiple long monologues for Jin Shenshui, with voiceovers revealing the changes in the situation and the characters. destiny. However, using dubbing to promote narrative in film and television works is undoubtedly a very weak choice. On the contrary, it proves that the film is unable to tell stories with pictures and characters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fc6639ab4d254361f39ebce1ee21cfb8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/fc6639ab4d254361f39ebce1ee21cfb8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259926&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although there are many characters appearing in the first half, they still have distinct personalities. But the characters who appear in the second half, such as the members of the military command team stationed in Nanjing, Lin Yingying&#39;s relatives, etc., these supporting roles are too homogeneous. In fact, there is no need to type subtitles for every person who appears, nor do you need to give everyone equal time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a passing character and a hastily explained ending give the second half a sense of déjà vu and a sense of cohesion in the narrative&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;Compared with the first half, it can be regarded as loose prose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To use a common saying to describe the impression of &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot;, it is &quot;a rush of energy, then fading, and three times exhausted&quot;. The more you watch, the more discouraged you will be, until it collapses thousands of miles. The film wants to portray the change of mentality of the triple agent. It stands to reason that the character will be highlighted and sublimated at the end, but this mechanism obviously fails in this film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/88632c0053d9c80d3cbd10e11477fa59.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/88632c0053d9c80d3cbd10e11477fa59.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259931&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Edge of the Knife&quot; is not as good as &quot;The Wind&quot;, which has a lot to do with the tendency of film and television adaptation. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The original work of &quot;The Sound of the Wind&quot; is divided into Dongfeng, West Wind and Jingfeng. From the perspectives of different narrators, it restores the ghost-catching past events in Qiuzhuang with different versions that are difficult to distinguish between true and false. If it were shot strictly according to the logic of the original work, it would be a polished remake of &quot;Rashomon.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But the director accurately picked out the main line of the story, filled it with flesh and blood, and drastically deleted unnecessary plots. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film version of &quot;The Wind&quot; is a bit like a colorful stage play, and it does use the three principles of drama&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (observe time , location and actions are consistent)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;——The isolated Qiuzhuang is an excellent stage for the story to be staged. The protagonists with different thoughts seek faith and survival. Time and space are further compressed to highlight the characters and stories as much as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/9b97d4839579d0da47de7da325e491c2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;760&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/9b97d4839579d0da47de7da325e491c2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259930 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The original work of &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; is divided into upper and lower volumes. The positive side is about Jin Shenshui, and the negative side is about Lin Yingying. Together they are the complete context of the history of the two fighting side by side. This novel focuses on the growth of the characters and has a large span, which makes the adaptation quite difficult. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The problem with the film version is precisely that it&lt;/span>; wants to completely present the whole character, but ends up copying the gourd and being constrained by the original work. Based on the size of the original work, it would be a good choice to make a 40-episode TV series. The 120 minutes of the film version is really difficult to carry such complex characters and emotions. It is better to only retain the first half of the film and delve deeper into the characters to make them fuller and richer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ff2a834d717cfb87e4f5e915174ce941.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ff2a834d717cfb87e4f5e915174ce941.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259929&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Even without &quot;The Wind&quot;, &quot;The Point of the Knife&quot; would not be considered a success&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. Because it was difficult to choose side branches from the main plot, the movie was turned into a double-speed explanation video of the TV series, which was really a mistake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Director Gao Qunshu also has &quot;The Gunslinger&quot; and &quot;Gunshots from the Secret Service&quot; on his waiting list. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; I don’t know when they will be released. Once again, we can see a spy thriller on the big screen comparable to &quot;The Wind&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[绿色金融榜：哪家银保机构的“绿色”更纯净？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261524]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rapidly developing green finance has been clearly promoted to a national financial strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Central Financial Work Conference listed green finance as one of the &quot;five major articles&quot; that must be done well, the Research Bureau of the People&#39;s Bank of China recently published a report According to the article &quot;Promoting the Effective Connection of Green Finance and Transformation Finance&quot;, as of the end of the third quarter of 2023, my country&#39;s green loan balance and domestic green bond market balance have reached 28.58 trillion yuan and 1.98 trillion yuan respectively, ranking first and second in the world respectively. Bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Central Bank Research Bureau also said that it will draw on its experience in setting green financial standards, gradually launch transformational financial standards that are applicable to all types of financial products, and will strengthen carbon accounting. and environmental information disclosure requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is more worth mentioning is that since the &quot;Green Finance Guidelines for the Banking and Insurance Industry&quot; was implemented in 2022, banking and insurance institutions have increasingly paid attention to green financial services and their own Environmental, social and governance performance. Statistics from the Insurance Association of China show that as of the end of June 2023, green insurance’s half-year premium income was 115.9 billion yuan; the balance of insurance funds invested in green development-related industries was 1.67 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 36%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the efforts of relevant ministries and regulatory agencies, what is the green finance report card of various banks and insurance companies? Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed a green finance indicator system based on the principles of fairness, justice and science to evaluate the purity of green finance of financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The Six&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Big Dimensions of the Green Finance List&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In view of the different business structures of financial institutions in the banking and insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has set up different evaluation index systems to evaluate green finance in the banking and insurance industries respectively. Development status, and explore how various bancassurance institutions can further enhance their green financial business and improve their own ESG performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center conducts qualitative and quantitative inspections and evaluations of commercial banks from the four dimensions of green financial products, environmental contribution, social responsibility and ESG governance. Insurance institutions are evaluated qualitatively and quantitatively based on four dimensions: economic performance, environmental performance, social performance and corporate governance. The quantitative and qualitative scores account for 70% of the total weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on special research on the above-mentioned institutions, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the above-mentioned companies. Conduct a review. The weight of the two scores is 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank ranking indicator system&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;12&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;second-level Indicators&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;25&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;three-level indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research The center inspected and evaluated 20 commercial banks from six dimensions, and set up 12 second-level indicators and 25 third-level indicators, and then gave different weights to different sub-indicators based on their importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /29/4ca1e1b6b1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;3378&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/4ca1e1b6b1.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;259950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the bank ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(1) Green financial products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is the connotation and extension of green financial products? For commercial banks, in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Green Finance Evaluation Plan for Banking Financial Institutions&quot;, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center will include green loan balance, growth rate, proportion, total issuance amount of green bonds, and underwriting scale into the banks in the 2023 Green Finance List List evaluation indicators. The total weight of the five third-level indicators in this dimension is 16%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2) Environmental contribution. Environmental contribution refers to the actual contribution and performance of financial institutions in environmental protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, in order to promote the realization of the &quot;double carbon&quot; goal, various financial institutions have actively established green and low-carbon operating systems, formulated carbon emission targets for the future period, and established The carbon emission statistics platform calculates its own greenhouse gas emissions and per capita greenhouse gas emissions, analyzes its own carbon emission potential, and provides data support for low-carbon operation management. On the other hand, various financial institutions have established the concept of &quot;green operation office&quot; to reduce the impact of operating activities on the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center combines publicly disclosed information and uses greenhouse gas emissions and per capita greenhouse gas emissions to examine the green and low-carbon operating systems of various financial institutions. Per capita energy consumption and per capita water consumption are used to measure the performance of each financial institution in green operations. Overall, the higher the environmental contribution of a financial institution, the better its green and low-carbon operations are, the less damage it causes to the environment, and the higher its carbon neutrality efficiency and energy utilization efficiency. The total weight of the four third-level indicators in this dimension is 8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(3) Social responsibility. Social responsibility refers to the performance of social responsibilities of financial institutions, social evaluation, and employee development and protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This indicator includes four levels: First, it refers to financial institutions adhering to the original intention of serving financial entities, actively serving the country&#39;s major strategic deployments, and guiding the flow of financial resources to national priorities. Support real economic industries such as advanced manufacturing and technology innovation enterprises, and improve the inclusiveness of financial services. The weight of relevant indicators is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The second refers to financial enterprises implementing the rural revitalization strategy, allocating financial resources to all aspects of rural economic and social development, increasing the supply of agricultural-related credit, and consolidating and expanding The results of poverty alleviation and rural revitalization have been effectively linked with financial support. The weight of relevant indicators is 9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The third refers to financial institutions facing the current situation of China&#39;s aging population, participating in the construction of the three pillars of the pension security system, providing high-quality pension financial services, and developing electronic vouchers for medical insurance and social security promotion and application to optimize social security services. The weight of relevant indicators is 8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fourth refers to the development of financial institutions’ own human capital, which is mainly reflected in employee training coverage and per capita training hours, and the establishment and improvement of a standardized, multi-level talent training system. , laying the foundation for employees’ personal career development. The weight of relevant indicators is 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To sum up, the four second-level indicators under this dimension include a total of 13 third-level indicators, with a total weight of 36%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(4) ESG governance. ESG governance here refers to whether financial institutions have established organizational structures and performance assessments that are compatible with green finance, environmental contribution and social responsibility. ESG performance is an important consideration for financial companies&#39; sustainable development capabilities, and ESG concepts have become an important concept for investors&#39; investment decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More and more financial institutions have established ESG governance structures, set up specialized departments or offices to take charge of green finance and other work, and incorporated ESG-related indicators into their performance appraisal systems to Motivate employees to achieve better green financial performance. At the same time, listed companies are subject to ESG ratings by major rating agencies. This list uses MSCI rating results to measure the ESG governance performance of each financial institution, comprehensively reflecting the ESG performance of each financial institution in authoritative rating agencies. The total weight of the three third-level indicators in this dimension is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated the relevant indicators of 20 commercial banks based on the above dimensions and indicator system, and using 2022 to 2023 as the observation period. Score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The green finance list of banking financial institutions shows that Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China and Industrial Bank rank among the top three. They are also the only three commercial banks with a total score of more than 70 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29 /ffe64333fb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2213&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ffe64333fb.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The four major banks: ICBC and Agricultural Bank of China&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;each has its own&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;lead&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;In order to conduct an in-depth analysis of the outstanding performance of different types of commercial banks in the field of green finance, the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center focused on analyzing the green finance initiatives taken by commercial banks with outstanding performance in each sub-category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, the total green loan balance of state-owned banks is much higher than that of other banks. For example, at the end of June 2023, the balance of ICBC&#39;s green loans reached 5 trillion yuan, accounting for more than 30% of the bank&#39;s total loans; state-owned banks are also at the forefront of the total green bond issuance and green bond underwriting amount indicators. For example, by the end of 2022, Bank of China’s green bond issuance amounted to 87.7 billion yuan, and its green bond underwriting amount was 453.9 billion yuan, ranking first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of ESG governance, the six major banks have all set up organizational structures and performance appraisal systems that are compatible with green finance. The latest ESG rating results announced by MSCI also All were A-level and received full marks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the field of social responsibility, the six major banks all performed well in aspects such as aging-friendly services, issuance and promotion of electronic social security cards and electronic medical insurance vouchers, and received full marks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The difference is that the balance and proportion of ICBC green loans, the balance and proportion of agriculture-related loans, and the balance and proportion of manufacturing loans are The indicators ranked first among the four major banks. Although its total greenhouse gas emissions and per capita energy consumption are higher than the other three major banks in terms of environmental contribution, its overall ranking is still first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China’s green loan balance and manufacturing loan balance are second only to ICBC, but the growth rate of green loan balance is the fastest among the four major banks; at the same time, The bank&#39;s county-level green loan balance and proportion rank first among its peers. As of the end of June 2023, the bank&#39;s cumulative scale of carbon emission reduction loans issued and the reduction of carbon emissions it has driven are among the best among its peers. Although the overall score of Agricultural Bank of China is 5.25 points lower than that of ICBC, it is significantly ahead of the other two major state-owned banks, seizing the &quot;second spot&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Joint-stock banks: Xingye stands out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, joint-stock companies The green loan balance of banks is weaker than that of state-owned banks, and the average proportion of green loan balance is about 11%, which is far smaller than the 18% average of large state-owned banks. This shows that joint-stock banks are weak in green loans to support the development of green industries. At the same time, joint-stock banks rarely issue green bonds, and the average size of green bond underwriting is only about 1/10 of large state-owned banks, which also shows that joint-stock banks are weak in green financial products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But there are not no benchmarks among joint-stock banks. Industrial Bank performs well in indicators such as green loan balance, agriculture-related loan balance, manufacturing loan balance, and inclusive small and micro enterprise loan balance, all ranking among joint-stock banks. In Mingsheng ESG Ratings, Industrial Bank also ranks with the four Major banks also received an A grade. At the same time, Industrial Bank&#39;s competitiveness in the field of green finance has also been recognized by most review experts, and its number of votes in the field of green finance tied for first place with Industrial and Commercial Bank of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, Industrial Bank’s comprehensive score beat all banks, beating Bank of China with an advantage of 3.32 points, and was rated as the &quot;Green Finance Ranking of the Banking Industry&quot;. Exploring flowers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;City commercial banks: better incremental indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Received Due to the disadvantages of scale and volume, city commercial banks are generally inferior to state-owned banks and joint-stock banks in the green finance rankings, but they generally perform better in growth indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the overall score, Bank of Nanjing, which performed best, ranked 8th. Despite obvious disadvantages in terms of size and scale, Bank of Nanjing not only ranks first among city commercial banks in comprehensive scores by virtue of its share of indicators in terms of green loan balance, agriculture-related loan balance, and inclusive small and micro loan balance. The score even exceeds that of major state-owned banks and leading joint-stock banks that far exceed its own scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Serving the real economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;State-owned banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;do their best&lt; /strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Overall, state-owned banks are members of the first echelon of social responsibilities, and the second and third echelons are joint-stock banks and city banks. commercial Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When examining the services of commercial banks to the real economy, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to measure the services of commercial banks to manufacturing loans and inclusive small and micro enterprise loans. Economic performance; when examining commercial banks’ support for rural revitalization, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to measure rural revitalization by agricultural-related loans. At these two levels, state-owned banks performed relatively well in terms of loan balance, growth rate and proportion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Joint-stock banks perform well in pension finance and employee human capital development. Relatively speaking, city commercial banks still do not disclose comprehensive information on employee human capital development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;ESG governance shows obvious echelon characteristics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Looking at it as a whole, The ESG governance dimension of commercial banks shows relatively obvious echelon characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;State-owned banks have strong ESG governance performance. Most joint-stock banks have set up relevant institutions and performance appraisal systems, but the overall ESG governance performance level is weaker than that of state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;City commercial banks are weak in ESG organizational construction, which is partly reflected in the fact that they have not set up independent departments or offices to manage matters such as green finance, environmental contribution and social responsibility, and The ESG performance rating is &quot;BBB&quot; or &quot;BB&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life Insurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Indicator System&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Fourteen&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Sub&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For commercially operated financial institutions , economic performance is business results and the basis for sustainable development, but the green finance list also considers the effectiveness of E (environmental performance), S (social performance), and G (corporate governance). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the above concept, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center used public information such as financial reports, announcements and promotional releases disclosed by 9 life insurance companies from 2022 to October 2023. As a benchmark, nine life insurance companies were evaluated quantitatively and qualitatively from the four dimensions of economic performance, environmental performance, social performance and corporate governance, and fourteen sub-indicators were set, and different weights were given to each sub-indicator according to the difference in importance. The total weight of the above indicators accounts for 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center comprehensively rated nine life insurance companies from the two dimensions of expert review and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) , to build a green finance list for the insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List Life Insurance List Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /29/086e8a479b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2086&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/086e8a479b.png &quot; data-key=&quot;259952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Life Insurance List Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance ranking index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the economic performance dimension, based on the scale of green investment , operating profit is measured by two third-level indicators. Green investment refers to investing in green industries or conducting green business activities, such as purchasing green bonds, green index funds, etc.; operating profit is used to measure a company&#39;s operating performance. In theory, it should be measured by green investment business income generation indicators. Taking into account actual information disclosure, operating profit replace. The total weight of the above two indicators is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the environmental performance dimension, total greenhouse gas emissions and per capita values ​​are core indicators, echoing the &quot;3060&quot; dual carbon goals. Taking into account the service industry characteristics of the financial industry, natural resources and energy consumption are measured in terms of electricity, water, gas and oil consumption. The total weight of the above five indicators is 25%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The social performance dimension mainly sets three three-level indicators from the three perspectives of consumers, employees and communities: consumer complaint volume, employee turnover rate and charity investment measure. The total weight of the above indicators is 15%. Stakeholders such as governments and partners are not included because the information disclosure standards of each ESG report are different and comparability is poor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corporate governance dimension, set the number of core issues, MSCI rating, scope&lt;strong>;three&lt;/strong>; data disclosure, ESG reporting third party There are 4 third-level indicators of certification status. The total weight of the above four indicators is 20%. Among them, carbon emission scope three data is an important part of carbon emission accounting at the organizational level, including greenhouse gas emissions from upstream and downstream (value chain) activities related to corporate production. For service industries such as finance, business travel and employee commuting are the main components of Scope 3. However, due to greater accounting difficulties in this part, fewer life insurance companies proactively disclose it. In addition, although the insurance industry has paid more attention to ESG reporting, most ESG reports have not obtained third-party certification, so their objectivity and independence are questionable. Based on the above reasons and from the perspective of encouraging standardized information disclosure, corporate governance dimension indicators are set in a qualitative manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance list: Ping An Life takes the lead&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Life insurance According to the green finance list of industrial financial institutions, Ping An Life, PICC Life and Sunshine Life ranked among the top three in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of quantitative and qualitative indicators, Ping An Life, PICC Life and AIA Life are leading, but PICC Life and AIA Life failed to provide any supplementary information in time during the survey. , so the media factor score is 0, which drags down the total score and ranking. It is worth noting that because Taikang Life is not listed and has not disclosed an ESG report or social responsibility report, its quantitative and qualitative indicators rank at the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Green Finance List - Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29 /81322a3209.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1203&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/81322a3209.png&quot; data -key=&quot;259953&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green Finance List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;China Life ranks first in economic performance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, and &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Sunshine Life has the highest social performance score&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to find advantages and differences and set a benchmark for the insurance industry, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center focused on analyzing the green financial measures taken by the top three life insurance companies in each dimension, with a view to It provides a useful reference for enterprises to achieve green transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of economic performance, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and Ping An Life ranked among the top three. China Life&#39;s total assets rank first in the domestic life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of environmental performance, Xinhua Life has the highest score, followed by Ping An Life and Sunshine Life in second and third place respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of social performance, Sunshine Life has the highest score, followed by PICC Life, and Xinhua Life in third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of corporate governance, AIA Life ranks first, Ping An Life ranks second, and PICC Life ranks third. In terms of ESG organizational structure, compared with other insurance companies, AIA has established multiple functional departments to manage ESG-related matters, and established a relatively complete ESG architecture system from top to bottom to promote the implementation of corporate ESG policies. In terms of ESG performance evaluation, AIA has incorporated environment, society and governance into the salary system of senior managers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life Insurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Company&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;ESG&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;The quality of information disclosure needs to be improved&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As problems such as &quot;greenwashing&quot; and &quot;greenwashing&quot; emerge, various stakeholders not only pay attention to the quality of corporate environmental information disclosure, but also pay increasing attention to The authenticity and reliability of environmental data, and hiring qualified, independent third-party assurance has become a key measure for measurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A survey by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found that among the nine life insurance companies, only Ping An Life, PICC Life and AIA ESG-related reports received the independent first Three-party authentication. According to the &quot;State of Sustainability Information Disclosure and Assurance: Trends and Analysis 2019-2021&quot; report released by the International Federation of Accountants (IFAC), after surveying 1,350 companies in 21 countries and regions, it was found that 64% of companies Attest the ESG information disclosed in 2021. During the same period, among the surveyed companies in mainland my country and Hong Kong, only 37% and 52% conducted some degree of assurance in 2021. One of the reasons is that my country&#39;s regulatory agencies are still in the encouraging stage for companies to disclose social responsibility reports and issue assurance opinions, and financial institutions do not have many actions and positive trends in reporting assurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, financial institutions also need to improve their quantitative disclosure of Scope 3 carbon emission data. Research by researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that among the nine life insurance companies, only Ping An Life, PICC Life, AIA Life and Taiping Life separately disclosed quantitative data in scope three. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 21:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[短视频时代，短剧异军突起：互联网生态“各领风骚三五年”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261532]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;Internet short dramas&quot; have become the focus of public opinion, &quot;Hengdian turns into a vertical store&quot; and &quot;Boss short drama harvests&quot; Topics such as &quot;Europe and America&quot; ​​have been on the hot searches in turn. The former refers to the fact that Hengdian Film and Television Base is now dominated by the &quot;vertical screen short drama&quot; shooting team; the latter refers to the short drama application platform ReelShort, which has begun to conquer overseas markets and even topped the U.S. iOS entertainment list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, the &quot;2023-2024 China Micro-Short Drama Market Research Report&quot; released by iiMedia Consulting showed that China&#39;s online short drama market size will be 37.39 billion yuan in 2023, a year-on-year increase of 267.65%. A total of 481 new short dramas were released in the first half of 2023, exceeding the level for the whole of 2022. It is estimated that the size of China&#39;s short drama market will reach 100.68 billion yuan in 2027. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of short videos has not only reshaped the audio-visual habits of netizens, but also accommodated netizens’ search, shopping, entertainment, and social needs: from search engines to short video platforms, from TV series to Switching to short dramas, switching from playing online games to watching short videos, switching from e-commerce shopping to live streaming... &quot;Short Video+&quot; is profoundly affecting the ecology of the Internet industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, various major Internet platforms have derived new business models of &quot;short video + advertising&quot; and &quot;short video + e-commerce&quot;, which have greatly subverted the traditional profit model: ByteDance recently announced the contraction of its gaming business, Short videos are fully embraced; the time spent watching short videos by netizens has exceeded the time spent on online games; traditional online writers are rushing into new tracks; major film and television bases have turned into &quot;vertical screen versions&quot;... These phenomena show that the short video era has created a new era of short videos. The rise of the drama has also profoundly changed the overall ecology of the upstream and downstream industrial chains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 China Online Audiovisual Development Research Report&quot; shows that among the 1 billion short video users in 2022, about 50.4% of users have watched short dramas within 3 minutes. The size of the short drama market in 2023 will almost reach half of the national movie box office, creating many traffic miracles and myths of sudden wealth. For example, in September 2023, the traffic miracle of &quot;Wushuang&quot; exceeded 100 million in revenue in 8 days, which caused a sensation. , the myth of getting rich &quot;completed in one week, released in one month, and achieving financial freedom&quot; is also widely circulated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The success of short plays is rooted in human nature, which is a deep need that people cannot erase. Human nature naturally loves &quot;refreshment&quot;, &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;relief&quot;, seeks emotional catharsis, and longs for emotional compensation. While the audience scolded the stereotyped short drama, they still couldn&#39;t help but finish watching a short drama with dozens of episodes before going to bed and experiencing the excitement of &quot;it turns out that success and love can come so quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Short plays can often satisfy people&#39;s certain &quot;feelings&quot; and &quot;hit&quot; the inherent pleasure mechanism of human nature. Themes such as &quot;Grand grudges between wealthy families&quot;, &quot;Marriage first, love later&quot; and &quot;The domineering president fell in love with me&quot; are everlasting. Revenge, counterattack, the boss&#39;s sweet pet, a golden son-in-law, marrying into a wealthy family... Such plots are also repeated many times. Can&#39;t get tired of watching it. The protagonist of the short drama has either become an alternative Count of Monte Cristo, or a film and television version of &quot;Long Aotian&quot; or &quot;Mary Sue&quot;, or it seems to be the product of pressing shortcut keys on a long and drawn-out urban emotional drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slightly different from the previous Internet ecology, the current industry supervision has become more and more synchronized, which is a new situation worthy of attention. The recent news that &quot;Tik Tok, Kuaishou, and WeChat platforms are jointly cracking down on illegal short dramas&quot; is also consistent with the fact that the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television has &quot;already removed 25,000 short dramas from the shelves. The next step will be to launch a one-month special rectification work on online short dramas.&quot; ” echoed the announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the Internet industry has indeed been &quot;leading the way for three to five years.&quot; Past success may not be maintained for a long time in the face of new trends. The rise of short dramas with the help of short videos fully illustrates this point. At the same time, the &quot;reckless state&quot; of the Internet industry&#39;s barbaric growth and turf racing has passed, and the advancement of technology and industry and the follow-up of regulatory regulations are increasingly showing a &quot;same frequency&quot; state. In compliance with regulatory requirements, the pursuit of high-quality and high-quality content will still be the main focus of the short drama market in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 29 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>