<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[为什么说把“戛纳”的“戛”读为ɡā是错上加错？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258305]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/09/nKyfrn1jgBybwhiAiyVXv1ywQg2PGF7bUNvyAhWP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/nKyfrn1jgBybwhiAiyVXv1ywQg2PGF7bUNvy AhWP. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;An article published by Fox News discussing the pronunciation of Cannes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May and June every year, you can hear the news about the &quot;Cannes&quot; Film Festival. I always feel very awkward, because when we were studying, the word &quot;jiá&quot; was the original word for &quot;stop suddenly&quot; and &quot;jiá&quot;. Check &quot;Chinese Dictionary&quot; and &quot;Hanyu Dictionary&quot; and you will find that this word is not polyphonic even now. Only when the word &quot;口&quot; is added next to it, can you pronounce &quot;GA [ɡā]&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s different now. The &quot;Modern Chinese Dictionary&quot; probably started from the 6th edition (I don’t have an earlier version at hand), and added the sound ɡā to this word. There is only one meaning below: &quot;Cannes (ɡā&amp;nbsp ;nà), French place name.&quot; This means that as a transliterated word, &quot;ɡā&amp;nbsp;nà&quot; can be pronounced loudly and openly. If you correct this reading, you are wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, this is a double misunderstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cannes International Film Festival (Cannes International Film Festival) is named after the place where it is held. According to the principle of following the owner, it is translated as Cannes. It is the translation closest to the French pronunciation, which is translated as &quot;Cannes&quot; , it’s too far away to be measured. This was originally an error made by the translators at that time in determining the translation name due to lack of audio-visual information. Checking the newspaper database of the Republic of China, there was a news report in the &quot;Central Daily News&quot; on August 18, 1944, &quot;France occupied nine towns eight miles deep, and the Allies took control of Cannes and forced Toulon.&quot; It can be seen that this translation has a long history, but At that time, there were more news articles using &quot;Cancheng&quot;. It can be seen that newspapers in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China put a lot of effort into reviewing and naming. Unfortunately, later generations chose the mistranslated one. &quot;Modern Chinese Dictionary&quot;, as a dictionary that takes normativeness as its own responsibility, should not use &quot;convention&quot; (not &quot;custom&quot;) as &quot;I follow the crowd&quot; (not necessarily &quot;the crowd&quot;) on the basis of mistranslation. As an excuse, he proposed a new pronunciation for the word &quot;Jia&quot; that has no basis in literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General British and American people are probably confused about the pronunciation of the place name Cannes. In 2013, the Fox TV station with the highest ratings in the United States (the audience is mainly American &quot;red necks&quot;) once launched a Twitter Based on a small investigation, the reporter combined the discussions among fans and wrote a very humorous short article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/how-to-pronounce-cannes-cans-can-or- con&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;u>;How to pronounce Cannes: Cans, can or con? | Fox News&lt;/u>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;, the conclusion is that it should be pronounced &quot;Kan&quot;, and the pronunciation is between English between the words can and ken. The online pronunciation of &quot;Cambridge English Dictionary&quot; is the same as when can is stressed:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/pronunciation/english/cannes&quot;>;&lt; span>;&lt;u>;https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/pronunciation/english/cannes&lt;/u>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can predict with the &quot;Modern Chinese Dictionary&quot; &quot;With the blessing of &quot;Cannes (ɡā&amp;nbsp;nà)&quot;, the translation of &quot;Cannes (ɡā&amp;nbsp;nà)&quot;, which is &quot;uniquely made in Cannes&quot;, is bound to become popular, and all efforts to block the car will &quot;come to an abrupt end&quot;. No matter how reluctant you are, I am afraid you can only make mistakes. &quot;Gaga&quot; started to learn the language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川多地曝医疗腐败，宜宾上千人被处理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258307]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More than 1,100 medical staff took the initiative to surrender and explain the problems. More than 1,200 people were dealt with. The medical system of Yibin City, Sichuan collapsed. The issue of sexual corruption was exposed and attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, Nandu reporters found that since this year, many leaders of the city’s medical system have been investigated, and a number of corruption cases have been disclosed, most of which are “top leaders.” It was exposed that staff at all levels in the hospital took kickbacks, patients transferred surgery fees to the head nurse, and department heads threatened to resign to demand a larger share of the stolen money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only Yibin, but corruption cases in the medical field in Neijiang, Deyang and other places in Sichuan are also shocking. The director of a county hospital even &quot;shares shares in the inpatient building under construction&quot; and charges handling fees for &quot;saying hello&quot; for hospital purchases. Regardless of the amount or the amount of property, he will accept the entire order, and the total amount of money collected in violation of disciplines and laws has reached 20.1209 million. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/fa89beda77b1b7eafdc0bae199b5cc08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;373&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/fa89beda77b1b7eafdc0bae199b5cc08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253485&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jiang Huashan, former Party Secretary and President of Yibin Sixth People’s Hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The patient transferred the surgery fee to the head nurse, leading to the &quot;top leader&quot; to take the lead in corruption&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 8, Nandu reporters combed through the Yibin City Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commission&#39;s disclosure The report found that since this year, many leaders in the city’s medical system have been investigated successively, including Zhang Xianjiang, Party branch secretary of Pingshan County Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital, Zhao Zhengbing, Party secretary of Gongxian People’s Hospital, Long Haibing, Party secretary of Yibin Second Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital, Yibin City Shi Jun, the former Party Secretary of the Fifth People&#39;s Hospital, and others, most of whom are &quot;top leaders.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, the &quot;Integrity Sichuan&quot; WeChat public account released &quot;Strictly Investigate Medical &quot;Corpse&quot;&quot;, revealing the centralized rectification process of corruption in the medical field in Yibin City, exposing the corruption of many former hospital directors. Rotten details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the First Inspection Team of the Xuzhou District Committee of Yibin City received a letter of complaint while inspecting the Sixth People’s Hospital of Yibin City. The informant reported that after the urology department of the hospital performed an operation on the patient, the patient directly transferred the operation fee to the head nurse instead of paying through the hospital window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving clues from the inspection team, the task force of the Xuzhou District Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committee conducted an investigation into the Department of Urology and quickly determined that this was the order of Luo Xiance, the director of the department. However, Luo Xiance did not realize the seriousness of the problem. When the investigation team first talked to him, he explained the problems of the department&#39;s private treasury and accepting drug kickbacks, and said, &quot;If the worst happens, I will refund the money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Luo Xiance was investigated, the disciplinary and illegal violations of Jiang Huashan, the party secretary of the hospital, also surfaced. According to the investigators of the task force, &quot;Following the clues of medical representatives returning kickbacks to hospital public officials, we dug into the issue of Jiang Huashan, the party secretary of the hospital, who was suspected of accepting bribes, and took measures to detain him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After investigation, Jiang Huashan took advantage of his position as Secretary of the Party Committee and President of the Sixth Hospital to open accounts in the hospital for relevant companies, and provided services to more than 10 pharmaceutical companies in the introduction and sales of drugs, equipment, and consumables, construction of engineering projects, and payment collection. The representatives provided help, and the amount of bribes they received was as high as more than 6 million yuan, and the medical representatives obtained improper benefits of more than 30 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by Jiang Huashan’s corruption and the interests of high kickbacks, corruption has become common within Yibin Sixth People’s Hospital. A small number of hospital managers did not care about medical skills, and once only wanted to make money. There was even a ridiculous phenomenon in which the deputy director of the department passively sabotaged his work when the rebates for consumables were unevenly distributed, and used the excuse of resignation to force the director to share more of the stolen money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the strong shock of the serious disciplinary and illegal cases of Jiang Huashan and Luo Xiance, the Yibin Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision also launched simultaneous educational warnings throughout the city. As of August this year, through in-depth and meticulous ideological and political work, more than 1,100 medical staff in Yibin City have voluntarily surrendered or clarified their problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Staff at all levels of the hospital collected kickbacks, and unscrupulous drug dealers were used to get through them at all levels&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The corruption case at Yibin Sixth People&#39;s Hospital is not an isolated case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 6 this year, according to the &quot;Integrity Yibin&quot; report, Xie Mingjun, former Party Secretary and President of Yibin First People&#39;s Hospital, was expelled from the Party for serious violations of discipline and law; former Party Committee member of Yibin First People&#39;s Hospital, Vice President Yang Li seriously violated discipline and law and was expelled from the party and public office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, the confession videos of Xie Mingjun and Yang Li sparked heated discussions on social platforms. In the video, Xie Mingjun cried: &quot;I hate myself and have done a lot of ridiculous things. What do I need so much money for?&quot; Yang Li also cried bitterly: &quot;How can I support myself after being released from prison after more than ten years?&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Integrity Sichuan&quot; WeChat public account, Xie Mingjun went from director of general surgery to model dean, national second-level professor, and academic expert. When faced with unscrupulous businessmen coming from all directions, he did not resist the temptation. Start accepting &quot;rebates&quot; and &quot;favorable fees&quot; from drug dealers and equipment manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Yibin First People&#39;s Hospital, hospital leaders, pharmaceutical committees, pharmacy departments, departments and medical staff were infiltrated by unscrupulous drug dealers and purchased drugs with kickbacks. Bribery payments generally reached 30% of the drug price, up to 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Yibin Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision pointed out that this case not only exposed the loopholes in the internal supervision and management of Yibin First People&#39;s Hospital and the construction of medical ethics and medical ethics, but also exposed the problems in the city&#39;s medical system. Common problems existing in the supervision and management of centralized drug procurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xie Mingjun was detained, Shi Jun, the retired former party secretary and president of the Fifth People’s Hospital of Yibin, also failed to escape investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his confession, during his 23 years in office, he took advantage of his position, accepted various bribes, and used ill-gotten gains to purchase 8 cars and 7 properties, including a Porsche Cayenne, a Mercedes-Benz S300, Touareg has real estate mainly in Sichuan, Yunnan, Hainan and other places, and has about 6 million yuan in cash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From serving as the dean in 1999 to retiring to the second line in 2021, Shi Jun has firmly grasped the full say in the hospital&#39;s commercial procurement, personnel appointments and dismissals, infrastructure, etc., and cultivated confidants in key positions to ensure smooth communication. A channel through which power can be realized. The &quot;paternalistic&quot; style has already eroded the rules and regulations to pieces, making the hospital management and employees surrender to them, and internal supervision is completely out of control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Integrity Outlook&quot; report, Yibin City has detained 13 public officials, including 3 county-level cadres, including 11 &quot;top leaders&quot;, and used &quot;four forms&quot; to deal with more than 1,200 people . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The dean of the county hospital’s under-construction inpatient buildings has been “taken as a shareholder and receive dividends”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to Yibin, there are also corruption cases in the medical field in Neijiang, Deyang and other places in Sichuan Equally shocking. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July last year, Neijiang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision has successively reported and exposed Liu Yu, the former Party Secretary of Dongxing District People’s Hospital of Neijiang City, Liu Xiaoping, the former director of Zizhong County Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital, and the former Longchang Municipal People’s Hospital. Zhang Zongming and others were expelled from the party and public offices for serious violations of discipline and law. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, the Neijiang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision received clues about Zhang Zongming, the former director of Longchang Municipal People’s Hospital, regarding disciplinary and illegal violations. In view of the large number of projects in the medical and health system, the large amounts involved, and the complex local relationship network Regarding the situation, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Commissions of Neijiang City and Dongxing District simultaneously intervened in the investigation and found that the amount involved in the case by Zhang Zongming amounted to more than 15 million yuan. In October of the same year, Zhang Zongming was expelled from the party and public office for serious violations of discipline and law. He was sentenced to ten years and nine months in prison by the Dongxing District People&#39;s Court for accepting bribes. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the &quot;Integrity Sichuan&quot; WeChat public account disclosed the corruption path of Liu Xiaoping, the former deputy party secretary and president of Zizhong County Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital in Neijiang. From &quot;saying hello&quot; in hospital procurement to &quot;sharing dividends&quot; in engineering construction, he accepted all orders regardless of the amount or property. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiaoping not only charges &quot;thank you fees&quot; for purchasing drugs and medical equipment, but even the field of engineering construction has become a &quot;nursing place&quot; for him to make money. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, when the Zizhong County People&#39;s Hospital was building a new inpatient building, the project owner Peng Mou promised to share a certain amount of profits with Liu Xiaoping after the project was completed in the name of &quot;buying shares&quot; to jointly undertake the construction. The project progress payment was disbursed as scheduled, and Liu Xiaoping received the first &quot;shareholding dividend&quot; of 600,000 yuan. In the following five years, Liu Xiao would receive an average &quot;dividend&quot; each time the project progress payment was disbursed, totaling 2.8 million yuan. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Liu Xiaoping accepted everything from a pack of cigarettes and a few bottles of wine to 10,000 to 20,000 yuan in cash to hundreds of thousands of yuan in cash, no matter the amount or the amount of property. From 2008 to 2021, Liu Xiaoping took advantage of his position to make a lot of money in drug procurement, engineering construction, etc., providing convenience for others to allocate funds for drugs, medical equipment, medical equipment, and engineering funds, and accepting gifts from others. The total amount of cash received was 17.587 million yuan, and the cumulative amount received in violation of disciplines and laws reached 20.1209 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 14 this year, the &quot;Integrity Sichuan&quot; WeChat public account announced that Zhang Dejun, former deputy secretary of the Party Committee and president of Deyang Second People&#39;s Hospital, had seriously violated discipline and law and was expelled from the party and public office. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report pointed out that Zhang Dejun accepted gifts and gifts that may affect the fair execution of official duties, was passive and slack in his work, was superficial, and had problems with formalism and bureaucracy; violated organizational principles, and acted inappropriately during the recruitment of employees. Seeking benefits for others and not truthfully explaining problems when organizing inquiries; owning shares in unlisted companies and engaging in money and sex transactions; being indifferent to the masses and apportioning expenses to enterprises in violation of regulations; incorrectly performing duties, interfering and intervening in construction project contracting; ethics Corruption and pursuit of vulgar taste; turning public power into a tool for personal gain, willing to be &quot;hunted&quot;, taking advantage of the convenience of one&#39;s position to seek benefits for others and accept property in aspects such as medical equipment procurement, medical consumables procurement, employee recruitment and recruitment, etc. , a huge amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[既要个人自由与空间，又要老人带孩子？权利与义务应对等]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258206]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Internet has brought everything closer and faster. &quot;Chinese Grandma&quot; has become popular internationally. Many &quot;Foreigners&quot; have all heard: Chinese elderly parents take care of their children in the morning, do housework during the day, and take care of the whole family at night. It is harder than working, and it is free, and they even use their own pensions to subsidize their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone posted on the Internet the daily schedule of elderly parents and parents-in-law: starting from 6 a.m., while their sons, daughters, daughters-in-law, and sons-in-law are still asleep, the elderly get up and go to the vegetable market to buy food. The freshest vegetables. Then prepare breakfast, change the grandchildren&#39;s diapers, feed the grandchildren, and greet the children, daughter-in-law, and husband-in-law to wake up and have breakfast. After the adults went to work, the old man did not stop. He was busy all morning, cleaning the house and taking care of his grandchildren several times, including feeding and urinating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon, the elderly are preparing lunch one after another, and some younger generations go home for lunch (in first-tier metropolises such as Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen, there is almost no possibility of going home for lunch), and then they can take a rest, because The grandchildren are taking a lunch break. A few hours later, the grandchild woke up, changed diapers, fed milk, and then took her downstairs to the community garden to play and bask in the sun. After returning, the old man continued to cook dinner, and then the children, daughter-in-law, and husband-in-law went home for dinner, washed pots and dishes, and took care of the children to sleep...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was really busy from morning to night, far exceeding the labor law stipulated, as well as the 8-hour daily shift in the domestic industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of work even leads to conflicts: in the circle of friends, there is a son who has a child. His parents come to Beijing to help take care of him and hire a nanny, but he is extremely busy every day. It’s early for his son to come home at 10:30 p.m., and the couple often can’t sleep until after 12 p.m. The old man cooked three meals for seven people. His daughter-in-law required that the dishes and chopsticks should be scalded with boiling water and sterilized for each meal. Due to different living habits, the old man sometimes forgets, so it often makes trouble. His wife said, &quot;How about we run away secretly?&quot; Let’s go home.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend came back from the UK to visit relatives and took her foreign husband and mother-in-law to travel to China. Her foreign mother-in-law was afraid to come at first for fear of becoming a &quot;Chinese grandma.&quot; After arriving, I saw that almost all of the community was elderly people taking care of their children, and I said seriously, &quot;This is the biggest irresponsibility for children.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theory of foreign mothers-in-law is: 1. It is more conducive for children to grow up if they are brought up by their own parents and enhances the relationship between them and their parents. 2. Intergenerational education will produce contradictions and conflicts. Because the world of the elderly is the past few decades, and there is a big gap between the world of the children and the future decades, the children they cultivate have many weaknesses in their character. 3. Where are the life, space and rights of the elderly? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foreign old lady also said: Foreign elderly people all have plans for their old age. She also wants to travel around the world, participate in community activities, prune roses in the garden, and write memoirs (we may wonder: what kind of memoirs do ordinary people write? ?). She believes that Chinese elderly people are very empty inside. They have been pushed away by work before retirement and have become fallen leaves with no &quot;pushing&quot; motivation behind them and no sense of direction. Therefore, they have no choice but to find a sense of presence in their own children and even intervene in the lives of their grandchildren, just like He works hard like a martyr and places the value of his life on the dependence, respect and gratitude of his children, grandchildren and other young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This old lady also believes that children should be independent after turning 18, live on campus when they go to college, rent their own house when working, have their own boyfriend and girlfriend, and apply for unemployment benefits if they are unfortunate enough to lose their jobs. ...How can you reach your 30s and still use your parents&#39; pension to use your parents as slave labor on the pretext of being grandchildren? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Westerners’ life style, social environment, way of thinking, etc. are all very different from ours. It does not mean that their views and lifestyles are correct and advanced. It is right to listen to the objectionable words as foreign voices. Some views can cause reflection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;rights&quot; that Westerners talk about actually have their counterpart here: for the elderly to help you take care of your children is a matter of affection, not an obligation. This is true whether it is in terms of law, social ethics, or family and emotional aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our Eastern culture uses family settlements and blood relationships as ties to weave its own atmosphere of life. Therefore, we pay attention to the intertwining and entanglement of &quot;father&#39;s kindness and son&#39;s filial piety&quot;, mutual debt, repayment of family affection, and gratitude... In Confucian culture, it is called &quot;kissing&quot;, and in other parts of East Asia, it is also called &quot;righteousness&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The modern/modern changes in Asia-Pacific society driven by the &quot;Western Wind Spreading from the East&quot; for more than a hundred years have made East Asian societies pay more and more attention to individual rights in modern society on the basis of &quot;kinship&quot; culture. It may simplify and weaken the social relationship of mutual entanglement and debt between relatives and friends. More and more young people are beginning to pursue individual rights, individual development, and individual realization that are similar to Westernization. In recent decades, wages in East Asian societies have grown faster than in Western societies, which is evidence of this development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we only need the &quot;individualism&quot; of Western culture, but not its concept of &quot;equivalence of rights and obligations&quot;; we need both the &quot;self-realization&quot; benefits of Western culture and the &quot;kissing&quot; of Eastern culture. Benefits, taking advantage of parents, but unwilling to take any responsibility. For example, the son mentioned above came home from playing until 10:30 in the evening (so-called socializing and socializing). This is too unethical. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to our living habits, it is impossible for us to copy the Western lifestyle. However, it should become a social responsibility to clarify the boundaries of the rights of the elderly, yourself, children and grandchildren, and not to take advantage of your parents all your life. At least, you cannot treat your parents as long-term workers who do not have to pay, or even use them as long-term workers while &quot;gnawing at the elderly&quot; and taking out the wallets of elderly parents. Basic consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This problem is on the children&#39;s side on the one hand and the elderly parents on the other. I often hear elderly people say: their children are too busy and hard at work, so help them if you can. This kind of thinking is: children will never grow up. The children they cultivate are also happy to lie in their parents&#39; arms until they are fifty or sixty years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Do the elderly in Western societies help their children and grandchildren? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answer is yes. According to statistics from the U.S. &quot;Population and Development Review&quot;: nearly 1/3 of the elderly in the United States have helped take care of their families. Americans spend a total of 1.2 billion hours caring for their families each week, equivalent to 30.5 million &quot;nanny&quot; positions. 20% of elderly Americans said they had taken their grandchildren on vacation without their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Statistics show that Americans in their 30s take care of the most children, followed by “grandfathers and grandmothers” in their 60s, while elderly people aged 60-79 rarely help take care of their grandchildren. Especially older American men in this age group are least willing to take care of babies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;79% of older people in the UK say they feel spending time with their grandchildren helps them stay young. But less than a third of British elderly people believe that they have &quot;taught their grandchildren more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How British elders look after their children: prepare tea or dinner for their grandchildren, supervise their children for a few hours after school when their parents are unable to arrive due to work, and play card games with their children. , and teaching children how to be brave. British grandparents proudly say they spend nearly 10 hours a week with their grandchildren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that in general, in European and American societies, there are limits to the elderly&#39;s ability to help their children, and the elderly&#39;s love for their children and grandchildren is also more restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We spend an average of 1.5 hours together every day. According to our standards, this is not taking care of the children, but just taking them to play for a while. But from the point of view of the British elderly: According to the standard of &quot;Chinese grandma&quot;, she is not taking care of her children. She is clearly treating us as slave labor and even taking out my wallet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if the elderly look at the lives of their children: it is true that they are busy at work, but their children spend a lot of time playing outside and at home, and they can spend hours watching short videos. &quot;Chinese grandmas&quot; cannot be the hands-off shopkeepers like British grandmas, but they can let go of their children appropriately and send them away for a few years but not for a lifetime. This is beneficial to the personality growth and responsibility of one&#39;s son, daughter, daughter-in-law, son-in-law and grandchildren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old parents and children should understand that it is a matter of affection, not obligation, for the elderly to help take care of their children. Even if the love is deep, it should be stopped in moderation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[记汉学家叶果夫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258170]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/NKdIy3ol8Ge1jnlPZgoynhIMn5hqbD0hIy7QTvqc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;896&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/NKdIy3ol8Ge1jnlPZgoynhIMn5hqbD 0hIy7QTvqc. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253111&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2012, the authors of this article, Zhang Fusheng and Ye Guofu (pictured left), were published in People&#39;s Literature Publishing House Group photo in the company&#39;s office. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Russian sinologist Yegov (Игорь Aлександрович Егоров) passed away. He was one year younger than me. He was born in 1953 and left before he was seventy. According to our Chinese concept, it was a bit early. Maybe he had a bad life and stayed up late for a long time to translate, which damaged his health. My friend Mr. Liu Xianping from the Writers Association told me that he suffers from diabetes, which is so severe that he is about to have his limbs amputated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the history of Sino-Russian cultural exchanges, Yegov can be regarded as a very contributory figure. First, as the Chinese editor of the Soviet State Literature Publishing House, he devoted great efforts to introducing Chinese literature to the Soviet Union and later to Russia for decades. Secondly, as a Russian sinologist, he translated the works of some writers during the May 4th Movement period such as Mao Dun. Later, he focused mainly on contemporary Chinese literature. The writers he translated included Su Tong, Yu Hua, Mo Yan, Bi Feiyu, etc. He has also translated some English works, but, in his own words, it is to earn royalties and support the Chinese literature he loves to translate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, Yegov is my colleague in work. In terms of business, we can provide each other with practical and useful help and solve problems on the manuscript. At the same time, we are also friends who can open our hearts and exchange ideas, even though our views are sometimes inconsistent or even diametrically opposed on certain issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/FRX7dNtX47uH6giJM1SY6JrX5OfBBtjIW5eTIhRk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;646&quot; height= &quot;944&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/FRX7dNtX47uH6giJM1SY6JrX5OfBBtjIW5eTIhRk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253112&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photo taken during Ye Guofu&#39;s first visit to Beijing in the 1990s. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ten Days in Beijing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ye Guo and I The first time I met my husband was in March 1990. As the Chinese editor of the Leningrad branch of the Soviet State Literature Publishing House, he came to visit the People’s Literature Publishing House where I worked. At that time, Sino-Soviet relations had just begun to normalize. I remember that after the &quot;Selected Novels of Rasputin&quot; that I edited was published in 1982, I gave the author several donated books at the request of the Soviet Embassy. I sent the gift letter to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs as required, and they handed it over to the Soviet Embassy. In 2006, Rasputin came to Beijing Foreign Studies University for a meeting. He told me that he had only heard that a collection of his novels had been published in China, but he had never seen it. When Sholokhov passed away in 1984, researcher Sun Meiling of the Institute of Foreign Languages ​​and Literatures of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences wrote a short message, but there was no place to publish it. The same is true in the publishing industry. It was not until 1986 and 1987 that the leaders of the Soviet State Literature Publishing House and the People&#39;s Literature Publishing House realized mutual visits. In 1989, when our older generation editors Sun Shengwu, Jiang Lu, Xu Leiran, Chen Siyong, and Lu Yongfu visited the Soviet Union, they also visited their publishing house. This time they came to visit for ten days. The formal talks were translated by old comrade Mr. Cheng Wen. I was only responsible for accompanying them on sightseeing and shopping, so everyone was relatively relaxed and casual, talking and laughing. I no longer went to the Soviet Union in the early 1980s. That kind of nervousness at the embassy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four editors came to this visit from the Soviet State Literature Publishing House: Director of the Foreign Literature Editorial Office Klimova, English editor; Chinese editor Yaroslavsky, an old comrade who is over 60 years old , has translated many Chinese classical literary works, and he translated the poems in the Russian version of &quot;Jin Ping Mei&quot;; and Yura Ilyashin, a young Chinese editor who came to China in 1984 as a reporter for the TASS News Agency and reformed After the opening up, he set up a company in China and published the newspaper &quot;Hand to Hand&quot;. These three people are all from the Moscow headquarters, while Yegov is from the Leningrad branch, and his name on his business card is the director of the editorial office. It seemed that he was not very familiar with the three people at the head office, so I took more care of him and spent a longer time chatting with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the conversation, I learned that Yegov, Yura and I both started learning each other&#39;s language in the early 1970s, shortly after the &quot;Zhenbao Island Incident&quot;. The purpose is self-evident and everyone knows it well. I told Ye Guofu that in 1969 I was an educated youth, and the Heilongjiang Production and Construction Corps station where I was located was only 95 kilometers away from Zhenbao Island. His eyes widened in surprise. I continued to tell him: Back then, there was an old high school senior in the company who taught everyone how to speak Russian every morning. I remember the first sentence I learned was: &quot;Raise your hands!&quot; He was startled at first, and was stunned for a moment, but he immediately became alert. Di replied in Chinese: &quot;Hand in the gun and not kill!&quot; We both laughed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another reason why Yegov and I had more contact during those ten days was that our speaking skills were pretty much the same. Yura was stationed in Beijing in 1984 when he was a reporter. I met him at the embassy. His listening and speaking abilities were better than ours. I talked with Yegov. He rushed to speak Chinese and I rushed to speak Russian. He only spoke his own language when he really didn&#39;t understand. It seemed that he was afraid of losing the opportunity to exercise and suffer a disadvantage. Yegov is a shy man. He blushes when seeing our old comrades. He speaks softly and has an elegant manner. He is very Leningrader and not as flamboyant as a Muscovite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they came, they were very interested in shopping, but shopping is my weakness. Every day after get off work, I would memorize Russian words that I might need the next day until late at night. Despite careful preparation, there were still many troubles. One morning, the four of them said seriously that they wanted to buy a must-buy food entrusted by a friend. It was round and colorful in shape and would grow bigger when fried in oil. Yaroslavsky also ridiculously made a sudden explosion with his hands, and made a &quot;pop&quot; sound from his mouth at the same time. The more vividly they described it, the richer my imagination became. I couldn&#39;t figure it out, so I had to lead them into the Dongdan Vegetable Market. We divided the troops into four groups, each of them holding an aisle, and searched carefully. After a while, Klimova&#39;s cry of surprise came. I went over to take a look and it turned out to be shrimp crackers. In order to avoid such trouble and lively atmosphere, I invited Mr. Gao Mang when I visited the Great Wall. He spoke very well. The four guests were extremely excited to see Gao Mang, as if meeting old friends in a foreign land, and they poured out all the words they had been holding in their hearts for several days. Yegov told me that Mr. Gao Mang was very famous in the Soviet Union. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main result of their visit was to confirm the publishing plans of both parties in the next three years: Su Fang published &quot;Nie Haihua&quot;, &quot;Selected Poems of the Song Dynasty&quot;, &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot; and selected works by Guo Moruo, Lao She and Mao Dun; our publisher Published several volumes of &quot;Collected Works of Tolstoy&quot;, &quot;Collected Works of Pushkin&quot;, &quot;Selected Works of Turgenev&quot; and an &quot;Encyclopedic Dictionary of Literature&quot;. The most important thing is that the two publishing houses will each publish a collection of contemporary novels from the other, and the selections will be recommended by the other. The People&#39;s Literature Publishing House completed this project in the second year, but the Soviet State Literature Publishing House failed to publish it until it was disbanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My personal gain is that my hearing has improved. They tell Soviet jokes every day, and sometimes I can’t believe my ears. In my impression, Yegov didn&#39;t say a word, and always maintained a gentlemanly attitude, as if he was listening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XxLnwV880wUjnjlmhS6tWDYQLFbVcyMwEE1N951f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1029&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/XxLnwV880wUjnjlmhS6tWDYQLFbVcyMwEE1N951f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yegov and the author of this article in front of the People&#39;s Literature Publishing House. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Three-month internship&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1991 In May, I was dispatched by the Press and Publication Administration to work as an intern editor at the Soviet State Literary Publishing House. Klimova and Yura Ilyashin, who had just visited our publisher in 1990, were responsible for receiving me and were very warm to me. They also held a welcome meeting for the external editors&#39; office, met with their leaders at all levels, and visited their publishing house. , they treat me like a newly assigned colleague. By the way, this publishing house, especially the configuration of language staff in the foreign literature editing room, is very similar to our publishing house, except that there are more editors in the Indian language group. After I came back and talked about this situation, President Chen Wanchun said: It should be said that we are just like them. President Feng Xuefeng visited this publishing house in 1951, and our publishing house adopted the configuration of their publishing houses when it was first established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 19, according to their arrangements, we arrived in Leningrad. As the head of the branch, Yegov received us and accompanied us on literary sightseeing every day - many writers in the history of literature have left their footprints in Leningrad. Yegov is a native of Leningrad, and he also knows many stories about the corners. . After visiting Tsarskoye Selo on June 24, while resting on the lawn in front of the square, Yegov and I had a debate about the October Revolution and socialism. We spoke Russian for a while and Chinese for a while. The accompanying staff laughed. . Yegov told me some social situations, which surprised me. When I was eating in the cafeteria of the Moscow headquarters, I heard someone say that I thought it was because of my poor hearing and I didn&#39;t understand, but I always felt that something happened. I asked Yura, and his answer was vague and obviously prevaricating, unlike Yegov&#39;s straightforwardness. At that time, the Soviet Union was experiencing painful struggles before its death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 16, 1991, we ended our three-month internship in the Soviet Union and returned to Beijing. Four days later, the &quot;8·19&quot; incident that shocked the world occurred in Moscow&#39;s Red Square. The Soviet Union collapsed on December 25 of the same year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/u4OebnAlHlHNyPKHIOtGbGBubmFSfLht7XayGjrl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;803&quot; height= &quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/u4OebnAlHlHNyPKHIOtGbGBubmFSfLht7XayGjrl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253110&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photographed in Yegov&#39;s office in 1992. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;One year of further study&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;November 1992 In August, I returned to Leningrad again, this time being sent by the State Education Commission to study for a year. At this time, Leningrad was being renamed St. Petersburg. The first sign to be replaced was the Leningrad Railway Station sign. I specially rushed to watch it. Looking at the slowly falling &quot;Leningrad&quot; sign, I felt extremely complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before I settled down at Leningrad University, Yegov came to see me. Seeing that I was living in a crowded four-person room, he was a little embarrassed, as if he had made such a bad arrangement for me. But within a few days, I was transferred to a single room. One day in the lobby on the first floor, the dormitory administrator stopped me and insisted on chatting with me. He first introduced himself: a member of the Soviet Communist Party and one of the first pilots after the outbreak of the Great Patriotic War. However, he was quickly shot down and transferred to the hospital for treatment. When he recovered and was ready to return to the sky, the war ended. Then he said that he respected me very much and knew that I had introduced many Russian writers to China. He even knew that I had translated the works of Semyonov. This writer was well-known in the Soviet Union and had written works about the Soviet-German spy war.经细问我才知道，是叶果夫告诉他的，为的是让他给我换个好房间。这个老兵管理员很狡猾、自私，做过一些可笑的事，但在我留学的一年里给过我许多帮助，我很感谢他，更感谢叶果夫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;叶果夫工作的出版社在涅瓦大街上最漂亮最热闹的地段，圣彼得堡书店的顶层。这座始建于18世纪的建筑，对面就是著名的喀山教堂，所以每天都会迎来大批世界各地的游客。作为欧洲最大书店之一的圣彼得堡书店不仅出售全俄最新的图书和各种外文出版物，还有各种文化用品及纪念品，同时还经常举办各种书展、书友会、新书发布会和作家签名售书活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我每天上课的列宁格勒大学就在涅瓦河河边，步行过桥便到了涅瓦大街上，如果坐地铁，就一站地，所以我经常来这家书店，作为出版人，我喜欢这里，再有，叶果夫就在楼上，累了就去他办公室坐坐，喝口热水抽支烟，走廊上还有长椅，可以在上面平平身子。他们编辑部里的人大都认识我，叶果夫不在的时候，他们就招待我。叶果夫那时正迷翻译，总盼着我去，有时知道我去了书店而没上楼，他还有些不理解。几乎每次去，他都会拿出几页事先准备好的纸，上面写着待解决的问题。每个问题后面都留有空白，是让我写意见的，我只需改写成他能理解的句子即可。叶果夫是个很聪明的人，这样做，既可以避免我俩因口语表达而产生误解，又留下白纸黑字，容他细细琢磨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记得还帮他做过一件事，就是1990年两社签订的那个项目——相互出版对方一本当代小说集，俄文版中国当代小说集的任务就交给了叶果夫。当时中方推荐的中文稿子已堆在他的办公桌上，按编辑体例，每位作家都有个小传，这些小传都是作家自己手写的，字数不一，文体格式不一，有的连“文革”中在宣传队创作的快板词也写进来了。老叶看得一头雾水，苦着脸请我帮忙。我统一改写成了一百字。老叶看懂了，非常感激。这件事花了我一些时间和精力，所以我记得。叶果夫几次来北京，都提到这件事，认为对不起我，因为这本书最后也没有出版。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他当时已译完苏童的《妻妾成群》，让我给他“指正”。我没读过这部小说，为了校订叶果夫的译文，我竟仔细读了一遍。对于他译文的硬伤错误，我只是改正，未作说明，倒是对他选择译文的标准提出了异议。我对他说：作者描写的在中国也属于一种极特殊的畸形生活，不具普遍的典型意义。再者，经过翻译成另一种文字，流失了许多精华，反映不出中国当代文学创作的水平。我建议他翻译梁晓声的《今夜有暴风雪》，推荐名单里有，我读过，很不错。他却说：这部小说描写的内容很像赫鲁晓夫当年搞西伯利亚大垦荒，俄罗斯读者不会喜欢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;叶果夫当时非常努力地搞翻译，除了要实现他自己的崇高目标外，还有一个很现实的原因。 1993年的圣彼得堡，老百姓的日子不好过。我的老师告诉我，工资有时都不能按时发放，拿到卢布也要立刻换成美元，用时再换成卢布。我们刚去的时候好像一美元换三百卢布，一个月后就换四百了，半年后我去莫斯科大学，在越南人的宿舍里竟换到了1300卢布。翻译“三言二拍”的齐一得先生，她是老一辈著名的汉学家，一天晚上打来电话，说没买到面包。我上学稍绕点路就可以经过她家，有时买点面包什么的，挂在她家的门把手上，打个电话告知她。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;难忘的两件事&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;叶果夫搞翻译挣外快，贴补家用。我从与他的接触中深感到他是一位非常顾家的人，对待妻子儿女，很像我们中国的好男人。他帮助人也是真心实意，满腔热忱，在你需要的时候会全力以赴。 1993年8月14日，我接到我们社外国文学编辑室主任李玉侠从国内打来的长途电话，她要我立刻想办法解决《毁灭》《青年近卫军》《静静的顿河》的版权问题，因为国内有出版社先于我们下手了。从她的语调语速中我完全可以意识到情势很危急。这三本书是我社的常备书，尤其是后两种，自八十年代初，年年重版。刚刚加入《伯尔尼公约》，就有出版社来抢了。我是这三本书的责任编辑，自然心急火燎，当天就找到叶果夫，向他讲明了情况。第二天他就帮我联系上了肖洛霍夫的版权继承人，其女儿斯韦特兰娜。她告诉我，她确实收到了中国的出版社递交的申请，但还没有签字。她还告诉我，肖洛霍夫曾有机会到中国访问，但没成行，很遗憾。斯韦特兰娜答应，版权一定给人民文学出版社。从她的话中我感觉到叶果夫事先已跟她谈过，她什么都知道，不用我多费口舌。两天后，我又到了莫斯科文学出版社，尤拉帮我联系上了法捷耶夫的遗孀，她的回答更让我放心：“我家的样书都人民文学出版社出版的，当然这本书还由你们出版。”让我慌了手脚的一件事在两位朋友的帮助下，就这样顺利地解决了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一件事，也让我很感激叶果夫。 1993年9月我妻子要来列宁格勒探亲。当时没有手机，通个长途电话也很困难。不知怎的，叶果夫成了我与妻子联系的枢纽，信息的“传声筒”，大概是因为他的办公室里有个可打国际长途的电话，那时他好像当了一个什么官。我查了一下当年的日记，那个月叶果夫来我宿舍五六次，最后一次已是晚八点了，告知我妻子从北京出发和到达莫斯科的时间。为什么不用电话告诉我？可能是怕我听不明白误了事，当面讲了，还要写在一张纸上。可见，他是一个多么认真靠谱的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;妻子没到几天，叶果夫就邀请我们去他家做客。那天他还到地铁站接我们，其实我去过他家多次，路线很熟。进门时，他妻子盛装迎接，非常热情，摆了一桌子的好吃食。开饭前发生了一件趣事。我正在叶果夫的房间里浏览他的藏书，原本给主客做翻译的叶果夫悄声走了进来，轻轻拍拍我的肩，指了指外边。我看过去，只见坐在沙发上的两位根本不懂对方语言的女士，竟然眉飞色舞，热烈地交谈着。我和叶果夫对视了片刻，差点笑出声来。那天玩得非常开心，临别时两位女士在地铁口相拥相抱，像多年的好姐妹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/oQHaE8Mt6wDy1tGR95ozF8U59FdOQEjP97UhYA8M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;908&quot; height=&quot;522&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/oQHaE8Mt6wDy1tGR95ozF8U59FdOQEjP97UhYA8M.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2012年，叶果夫（左二）、莫言（左三）在人民文学出版社会面。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;二十年后再相会&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;回国后的最初几年，我和叶果夫还有通信通话，托人带好，后来就断了联系。 2000年前后，有人告诉我原来的苏联国家文学出版社解散了，没有了。直到2012年有同事告诉我，叶果夫在网上找我，说要来北京开汉学家国际研讨会。时隔二十年，我们在他下榻的旅馆见面了，他握着我的手说我没有老，我握着他的手说他容貌依旧。我们都知道我们说的是假话。第二天，我们在我的办公室又继续谈话。我给他看了我20年来编辑出版的俄国文学作品，他给我讲了他20年来走过的历程，讲他译过的作品。说他已读了几年莫言的小说，找到了感觉，开始翻译了。在谈体会时，他也像一些人一样，说莫言小说受到西方“魔幻现实主义”的影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我告诉他，中国作家大多数都是本色创作，就我读过的作家，还没觉得有谁受过外国作家的影响。如果说影响，那也是他们出生的地域和与生俱来的个人性格，这两点决定了他们讲故事的方法和特点。比如莫言，如果让我说，其实他就是在用他山东高密那个地方特有的讲故事的方法讲述养育他的那方水土的故事，就像他的山东老乡蒲松龄用他的方法讲述《聊斋志异》一样。他们山东那个地方可是有这种悠久的文学传统，盛产这种文学。叶果夫好像似懂非懂，我倒觉得我们今天的谈话，像是在继续列宁格勒那次关于选择翻译作品标准的谈话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我给他看了近十几年来我社出版的俄罗斯当代文学作品，包括十几部长篇小说和四本短篇小说集，涉及七十余位作家，有五十年代成名的老作家格朗宁的新作，也有六十年代享誉世界的拉斯普京的作品，更有八九十年代获奖的青年作家。他看了甚是惊讶，我们一家出版社出版的俄罗斯当代文学翻译作品抵得上全俄罗斯出版的中国当代文学翻译作品。大概是触到了他的伤心处，他向我大吐苦水，说在俄罗斯出版一本中国文学作品是多么不易，更不像中国拥有数量庞大的俄罗斯文学读者群，而且俄罗斯现在的出版社全成了私家出版社，只注重利润……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年8月21日叶果夫打电话，说明天约定与莫言先生见面，要我参加，地点可否定在我的办公室。我自然同意。第二天莫言先生来得早一些，他送了我两本他的书，我送了一套我责编的《静静的顿河》。莫言先生人很平实质朴，真诚自然，不像是那种藏有心机的人。其实我同他见过面，记得是在北大开斯特林堡研论会，他还发了言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和莫言先生聊了一会，叶果夫就来了。他们俩好像并不很熟，开始还有些拘谨，叶果夫是个不擅言谈的人。还好，很快就放开了，莫言先生还是很会引导话题，活跃气氛的。当时我觉得莫言蛮有口才，认定他会讲故事。我听过冯骥才先生讲故事，那是他在人民文学出版社改稿子的时候，当时他还要求把灯关了，说这样讲更有效果。所以我认为作家大都有讲故事的才能。那天的话题基本上是围绕莫言先生的创作。社长管士光同志中间来过半个多小时，叶果夫话不多，讲的都是中国文学，尤其是当代中国文学在俄罗斯的“遭遇”，讲他翻译的莫言作品出版多么艰难……这个情况我也了解一些，当年在莫斯科、列宁格勒参加过几次书展、图书订货会性质的活动，没见过一本中国文学作品，只是偶尔碰上一两种沾点“功夫”的书。那天到了最后，大家还是聊得很畅快。我查了一下当天的日记：“从下午2点聊天至6点，后在出版社对面九爷府饭馆吃晚饭至8点半。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临回国的前一天，我们一起吃饭，叶果夫告诉我说，刘震云先生也希望翻译几篇他的作品，要我发表一下看法。我说：“你知道，中国有句古语：文如其人。莫言是山东人，行文直白，讲的是故事。刘震云是河南人，行文委曲，有股子河南人特有的幽默，他的作品讲究的就是味道，而味道是很难翻译的。比如鲁迅《头发里的故事》里有句：&#39;各家大半懒洋洋的踱出一个国民来&#39;，其中的&#39;踱&#39;字和&#39;国民&#39;一经翻译，便索然无味。再比如你译的《丰乳肥臀》，如果让一位没有见过原著的俄文工作者根据你的译文翻译成中文，很可能就译成了《大乳房，宽屁股》，味道何在？”我忽然意识到有些不妥，不禁哑然失笑，叶果夫好像也悟出了什么，竟然哈哈大笑起来。我又对他讲了1991年我在莫斯科文学出版社实习时，他们问了我许多老舍作品和《红楼梦》中的翻译问题，大都是类似这种文字背后的“意味”问题。我还对他讲了我负责发稿的《水浒传》（大中华文库俄汉对照版），认真对照罗高寿译本时发现的问题，想进一步证明两种语言互换时失去的都是精华，主要是因为中文里一些字词和表达句式俄文里是没有的。选择要慎重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;最后一次见面&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;最后一次和叶果夫见面是2014年8月28日，在俄罗斯使馆举办的“中俄文学互译出版项目”会上。那天人很多，叶果夫忽然拉着俄罗斯作家叶辛来找我，开玩笑似的说要走后门：叶辛希望他的《巨人之死》在人民文学出版社出版。叶辛是俄罗斯著名作家，还是高尔基文学院院长，这本小说又属俄方推荐的书目，于是我征得一起来开会的社领导刘国辉的同意，当场找来作协的刘宪平先生和著作权协会的总干事，也是“互译项目”的负责人张洪波先生同叶辛、叶果夫开了个小会，决定《巨人之死》在我社出版，由刘宪平翻译。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大概像我们这样现场办公的不只我们一家出版社，会场始终乱哄哄的，我和叶果夫一直没得空单独交谈。快到结束的时候，叶果夫匆匆拉我到一个稍微安静的角落，兴奋地告诉我，中国作协给了他一大笔钱，足够让他几年内一心一意地搞翻译，不必再为生计发愁奔波。望着他略显湿润的眼睛，我也非常高兴，我知道他这些年来日子过得并不轻松。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;安息吧，伊戈尔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是他的小名，他喜欢我这样称呼他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[偷餐者绑天桥示众？店家应该如此喝阻小偷吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258289]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据南方都市报报道，广州蜜雪冰城某门店手写偷餐警告，称偷餐者要被“绑到天桥上示众8小时”，引发热议。 10月8日，南都记者走访该门店后，被工作人员告知该警告已被撤下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/qpBMC7wPFEMRtg1ovzKZU80tubnLI3hkX1RlGlk8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;789&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/qpBMC7wPFEMRtg1ovzKZU80tubnLI3hkX1RlGlk8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蜜雪冰城贴出的偷餐警告。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该蜜雪冰城门店工作人员表示， “好多人偷餐，抓都抓不住，我们是被偷得没办法了，有的人偷餐偷得很恐怖。（警告）写得严重一点吓唬吓唬他们。” 对于是否实行过告示上的惩罚措施，对方表示， “没有实行过，要是实行了就犯法了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然“绑天桥示众”的手段过于激烈，但不少超市、零售店铺都在店内张贴有“偷一罚三”、“偷一罚十”的警告。据媒体报道，也实际发生过有人在超市内偷窃被抓到，最后花几百元私了的案例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你怎样看商家的这种警告？觉得合理吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快来评论区发表你的看法，马上送你上热评！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[泰国喋血枪击案：14岁持枪少年和40声枪响]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258301]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 16:06:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/09/YJKlXzUQZMLpmjzc78uYwcKyFEXAFPN3guaDQlYQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/YJKlXzUQZMLpmjzc78uYwcKyFEXAFPN 3guaDQlYQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three days after the incident, the victim of the Siam Paragon shooting in Thailand finally apologized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, 2023, the parents of the suspect in the shooting issued a letter of apology, apologizing to the victims, injured and their families, and promising to fully cooperate with the investigation. They said in the letter that they would do their best to take responsibility, fully cooperate with the police and other departments to find out the truth, and do their best to mitigate the impact of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the Thai government announced a compensation plan. Suthawan, Thailand’s Minister of Tourism and Sports, said that Thailand will provide 6.2 million baht (approximately RMB 1.23 million) in compensation for each victim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three days ago, on October 3, just a week after Thailand implemented a visa-free policy for Chinese tourists, a series of piercing gunshots rang out in the Siam Paragon shopping mall, and panicked crowds ran in all directions. The tragic shooting resulted in 2 deaths and 5 injuries. The Chinese victim was only 34 years old. At the time of the incident, she was traveling in Thailand with her 5-year-old twin daughters, and they originally planned to take a flight back to China early in the morning on October 4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is surprising is that the perpetrator of the shooting was a boy who had just turned 14 years old. He is accused of suffering from mental illness and has been sent to a mental hospital in Bangkok for evaluation of his mental condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sudden shooting not only made tourists in Thailand uneasy, but also worried Thailand, which is eager to revive the tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jidi, chairman of the Thailand Tourism Marketing Association, told Thailand&#39;s &quot;Public Opinion&quot; that due to the vicious shooting at Siam Paragon, the number of foreign tourists to Thailand may decrease by 1 million in the fourth quarter of 2023. Revenue shrank by 50 billion baht (approximately RMB 10 billion). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;40 gunshots&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If it weren’t for this shooting tragedy, Li Qian’s family could have spent a happy holiday in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on October 3, 2023, Li Qian and his wife arrived in Bangkok by plane with their three-year-old child. After checking in at Chatrium Hotel, they were picked up directly from the hotel at around 4 p.m. The shuttle bus arrives at Siam Paragon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paragon is located in Siam Square in the heart of Bangkok. It is the most famous luxury shopping mall in Bangkok and was once rated as the most photographed place in the world by Instagram. Li Qian decided to make the first stop of her trip to Thailand here, but what she didn&#39;t expect was that she would be greeted by continuous gunshots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As soon as I got to the second floor, I heard a loud bang. I immediately had a bad premonition. Before I could react, there were two more bangs and bangs in succession, and then... I heard screams from downstairs, and people started to run away. My husband rushed to the third floor with the child in his arms, and then there were several gunshots. I was so scared that my legs were weak, and I felt that bullets were behind me. He was about to be hit at any time.&quot; Li Qian recalled to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 3:35 pm on October 3, the assailant took the light rail and entered Siam Paragon. Surveillance video showed that five minutes later, he walked into the bathroom on the M floor carrying a schoolbag containing bullets. At 4:10, gunshots were first heard in the bathroom. Immediately afterwards, a long-haired man wearing a black shirt and a baseball cap with an American flag printed on his head came out and started shooting at the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the gunfire rang out, Huahua was in the aisle separated from the bathroom where the incident occurred, waiting for friends who were shopping at the Chanel store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I didn’t know the murderer was next to us at the time. I just heard the gunshots very clearly.” Huahua told Southern Weekend reporters, “I thought it was a robbery of a luxury store at first. It was nothing special. It wasn’t until we later watched the news and discovered he was right next to us that we started to feel a little scared.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 4:25, the assailant came to the second floor and continued shooting. Minutes later, he took the escalator to the third floor and continued shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the gunman called the Thai police phone number to surrender, and clearly told the police his location and specific clothing. At 5:10, he was arrested in a home furnishing store on the third floor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Bangkok Post&quot; quoted a source familiar with the investigation as saying that before his arrest, the suspect fired about 40 shots in the mall, and a total of 11 shots were found on the dead and injured. bullet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the frightening moment, Li Qian and others were at least lucky enough to return home safely. However, a Chinese tourist and a Burmese migrant worker in Thailand left their lives in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports from the Thai police, the shooting at Siam Paragon resulted in 2 deaths and 5 injuries, and the initiator was a 14-year-old boy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Thailand&#39;s MGR Online news network, the suspect in the shooting incident was born in 2009 and just turned 14 years old on September 21. He is the eldest son in the family. His family is very wealthy, and his father works in a well-known university. The teenager studied in a private school with a tuition fee of hundreds of thousands of baht a year. While at school, he won the Outstanding Student Award for the 2017 academic year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Bangkok’s top luxury shopping mall, Siam Paragon claims to have strict security measures. However, the murderer successfully entered with a gun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tosak, the director of the Thai National Police, explained in an interview that because the gun involved was modified into a plastic structure, it was not discovered in time, and the security of the mall was not as constant as at the airport. They are very strict, with people coming in and out all the time, and it is difficult for the testing equipment to conduct precise inspections on everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many people involved in the shooting recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Siam Paragon had no security measures and only two or three security guards were on duty at the door. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the shooting, just a few hours after arriving in Thailand, Li Qian changed her ticket to return to China the next day. &quot;I didn&#39;t really feel safe until the moment the plane landed. From a person watching the news to a person in the news, everything was so unreal.&quot; Li Qian said that now she hears the gunshots in the video, she is still instantly taken away. Pull back to the scene of the shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hua Hua and her friends continued to spend a day shopping in Thailand with fear, but they did not dare to go shopping in Siam again. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mental problems? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Paragon surveillance video showed that when he was arrested, the 14-year-old suspect looked dull, his eyes flashed, and he kept mumbling to himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tosak said the teenager had received treatment at Rajavithi Hospital for mental health problems in the past, but did not take his medication on the day of the incident. &quot;He felt like someone was telling him to shoot this or that person, as if there was another &#39;him&#39; inside his body.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another netizen who often plays games online with the assailant teenager said, &quot; He often behaves emotionally, and it is obvious that he has a heavy psychological burden.&quot; The netizen also revealed that the young man had mentioned that he had schizophrenia symptoms, but he did not take medication to control it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the boy&#39;s parents said that their son was addicted to shooting games, but he had never had any history of mental illness. In an interview with Thai TV station One News31, his mother said she suspected that her child liked to use shooting to vent his emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the young man who committed the crime has been sent to Bangkok Mental Hospital for detention and treatment. Experts from the hospital will evaluate whether he suffers from mental illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Washin, a lawyer at Thailand&#39;s Mandarin Law Firm, estimates that the results of the mental evaluation will be issued within two or three weeks, and the subsequent inspection report will be handed over to the relevant departments within a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on reports from Thai media, the shooting was not a whim of the teenager, but was well prepared in advance. The Thai news website The Thaiger bluntly called the shooting a &quot;premeditated murder.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Bangkok Post&quot; report, the teenager originally planned to buy a real gun online, but because the price was too high, he then borrowed money through an online lending platform and settled for 16,000 baht (approximately RMB 3164) purchased a modified blank gun. In the teenager&#39;s home, the police also found two guns and a large amount of ammunition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the incident, the teenager had invited friends with whom he was practicing shooting to go to Siam Paragon. Until the moment he arrived at the mall, he had a video call with his friends, saying that he was &quot;going to shoot.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the suspect was arrested, the police found videos from his mobile phone of him practicing with live ammunition at a shooting range, including clips of changing ammunition and shooting targets. Some netizens also posted that they had met the assailant by chance at the &quot;Bangkok Shooting Club&quot; before, and that he was dressed exactly the same as on the day of the attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is still unknown why the former outstanding student turned into a gun-wielding killer. However, Thailand&#39;s Public Opinion reported that after preliminary investigation, the police found that the 14-year-old boy who killed someone with a gun at Siam Paragon faced academic difficulties and his academic performance was poor, but his parents forced him to improve his academic performance. There is chat evidence showing that after the suspected teenager was urged by his parents to improve his academic performance, he instead sent a video of himself shooting at the shooting range and said, &quot;I want to go here.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 4, the head of the Kyoto Police Station in Bangkok, Thailand, stated that the police filed five preliminary charges against the 14-year-old suspect responsible for the shooting, including intentional homicide, murder, illegal possession of a gun, and unauthorized possession of a gun. Carrying firearms into public places with permission and shooting in public places without permission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In Thailand, shootings that cause death can be punished with the death penalty, life imprisonment, or 15 to 20 years in prison. However, because Thailand rarely carries out the death penalty, the maximum penalty is generally only life imprisonment.&quot; Waxin analysis , &quot;Now that the suspect is only 14 years old, he will most likely be sentenced to 15-20 years in prison. But at the same time, the court may take measures such as juvenile detention, mental hospital imprisonment, etc. to replace prison time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mental illness cannot be a reason for acquittal, but if it is ultimately determined that there is a mental illness, the court may reduce the sentence based on his relevant medical history, and may ultimately be sentenced to 10-15 years in prison, or even a sentence of no more than Possibility in 10 years,&quot; Vaxin added. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Belated gun control&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is not the first mass shooting in Thailand. In the past three years, Thailand has suffered three consecutive shooting massacres. The Siam Paragon shooting happened on the first anniversary of the nursery massacre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, 2022, a former police officer broke into a nursery with a gun and a knife in Utai Sawang Town, Nongmo Lamphu Province, northeastern Thailand, killing 38 people, 24 of whom were children. . The murderer returned home afterwards, killed his wife and children and committed suicide. Thailand’s Public Broadcasting and Television reported that this was the first large-scale terrorist attack targeting children’s places in Thailand’s history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously in February 2020, a Thai soldier went on a killing spree with a gun in a shopping mall in the northeastern city of Nakhon Ratchasima, killing 29 people and injuring 57 others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amnesty International human rights researcher and Thai Tatya Karonwang pointed out that given the occurrence of three similar incidents in recent years, Thai society is reminded that this may not be just an isolated unfortunate incident and the country needs to be re-evaluated. Is gun violence a systemic problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the shooting, Huahua did not know that it was legal to hold a gun in Thailand, and he never thought that such a thing would happen to him. But in fact, Thailand has one of the highest rates of gun ownership and gun-related deaths in Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A study conducted in 2017 by the &quot;Small Arms Survey&quot;, a research institute in Geneva, Switzerland, showed that Thailand&#39;s total population is about 70 million, but the number of guns it holds is as many as 10.34 million, of which only 10.34 million are legally registered. About 6.2 million. Investigators estimate that 15 out of every 100 people in Thailand own guns, ranking first in ASEAN and second in Asia after Pakistan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data released by the US think tank &quot;World Population Review&quot; in 2022, Thailand has 3.91 gun deaths per 100,000 people, ranking second among ASEAN countries, second only to the Philippines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for gun control, Thailand’s relevant laws are not strict. &quot;Thai citizens who are over 20 years old need to undergo strict background checks before they can legally hold guns. They are not allowed to hold guns in public and can only be used for specific purposes such as self-defense and hunting. At the same time, citizens must put gun shells, springs Store them separately from bullets and other accessories and cannot be placed in the same place.&quot; Vaxin pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in addition to legal gun ownership, there are still a large number of imported guns and imitation weapons that can be freely traded on the black market and the Internet. Wa Xin said that similar black guns are common in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investigation data from the Thai Police General Administration in 2019 showed that there were more than 31,400 gun-related cases in Thailand that year, of which more than 24,300 cases involved unregistered illegal guns, accounting for 10% of the cases. 77.5% of the total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many illegal firearms are smuggled into Thailand, and Internet sales are exacerbating this trend.” Krisanaporn, a criminologist at Thailand’s Rangsit University, told AFP, “However, only a few police officers have the online Knowledge, ability and experience in tracking the gun market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the shooting tragedy, the Thai police acted vigorously and arrested 6 suspects for selling guns and ammunition to the teenager who committed the crime. At the same time, Thai officials have made it clear that they will strengthen gun control measures and close legal loopholes in online gun sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, Thailand’s Ministry of Interior held a meeting and approved 13 gun control measures, including strengthening the registration and management of firearms, stopping the issuance of firearms business licenses and carry-on firearms permits, and requiring gun owners to Short-term and long-term gun control measures include providing medical certification of mental health conditions, cracking down on illegal weapons trading websites, and redefining imitation guns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, similar measures are just bringing up old matters again. After the tragedy of the nursery massacre in 2022, the lower house of the Thai Parliament stated that it would explore short-term and long-term measures for gun control and response to gun violence. However, until the general election in May 2023, the gun amnesty bill drafted by the previous government failed to pass parliamentary review. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some experts are not optimistic about how effective the new gun control measures will be. A commentary article published on the American Diplomat website stated that short-term policy adjustments cannot fundamentally solve the problem of black market gun trading, and the Thai government must give up its laissez-faire mentality of tolerating the illegal economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Qian and Huahua are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[掏大钱才得见“优质异性”：“相亲顾问”套路深]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258208]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Because of hitting a wall in reality or the dating circle is too narrow and lacks &quot;dating resources&quot;, go to the dating website to try your luck , it is indeed the choice of some people, but what is the outcome? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A netizen’s complaint gives us a glimpse into the words and routines of “dating consultants”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He once received a call from a blind date website, asking him to talk about their blind date services. The dating consultant asked him to find out that he was a manager of a private enterprise, with an annual income of 400,000+, and that he had a house, a car and no loans, so he recommended a dating service with a price of 70,000, and even said to him: For a high-income person like you, 70,000 is not enough. It&#39;s not a high price, but we can provide emotional services. Then he pulled up two resumes with specific information concealed from his mobile phone. Both of them had a photo of a beautiful woman. He told him that both beauties had paid membership fees of N million, and their requirements were very suitable for his situation. As long as Once he joins the association, he can immediately arrange to meet and get to know each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But his psychological price is less than 10,000. He said that 70,000 yuan was an unaffordable price for him. Seeing that he was about to get up and leave, the dating consultant said in a very disdainful tone, &quot;What we are talking about now is your life-long event. If you yourself feel that you are not worth tens of thousands of dollars, then there is nothing we can do.&quot; The dating consultant also emphasized that , &quot;Many of our members have paid membership fees of hundreds of thousands or hundreds of thousands a year, but I didn&#39;t mention it to you considering your income level.&quot; He replied, not thinking that his life event is not worth 70,000, but just I feel that this kind of service is not worth 70,000 yuan. As for hundreds of thousands or hundreds of thousands, only XX would spend such a big sum of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, the dating consultant called him and said in a familiar and friendly manner that if paying 70,000 at once was too much, the website could provide installment payments and discounts. He also recommended other packages, but he hung up the phone directly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar scenes have been exposed by the media for a long time: the target is locked in a room for two to three hours for brainwashing, and is required to pay tens of thousands of yuan in membership fees; after registration, harassment calls are received from various numbers Phone call; after registering, you were invited to go to the offline store, but after paying the money, your attitude was perfunctory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen said that in his opinion, spending tens of thousands of yuan to buy a blind date service is a bit ridiculous. It was not until he saw someone actually posting a blind date service bill of 32,000 yuan that he felt that he was short-sighted. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is not that he is short-sighted, but that in the face of the powerful words and targeted bombing sales of some dating websites, some people will eventually be unable to defeat him. In March 2022, The Paper reported that through phone calls and WeChat, a marriage agency claiming to be from the &quot;MarryU Club high-end membership club&quot; continued to promote &quot;high-end marriage consulting services&quot; to Ms. Guo in Beijing, and promised to be able to provide services during the service period. Help her find the right match. Ms. Guo came to an offline physical franchise store on the platform and signed a 480-day membership service contract and supplementary agreement worth nearly 170,000 yuan. It was agreed that a company in Hangzhou would entrust a consulting and management company in Beijing to perform contract services and promised to provide Ms. Guo with a customized version of &quot;marriage hunting services.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;News reports tell us that the lady’s 170,000 yuan was wasted. During the follow-up service process, Ms. Guo discovered that the identity of the men provided for appointments on the platform was questionable, and some had discrepancies in age and workplace information. Some did not even leave their WeChat or contact information after meeting. “Even if they were added, (the other party) would not No reaction.&quot; While the contract was in effect, Ms. Guo met her current husband in an accidental private social interaction, and the two received their marriage certificate in December 2021. After the marriage, Ms. Guo thought she could return a certain percentage of the service fee, but was rejected by the matchmaking agency on the grounds that she violated the contract by &quot;marrying a candidate who was not recommended by the agency.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you think what happened to Ms. Guo is just an accident, you are totally wrong. Data show that in the first half of 2019, the Jucomplaint platform received a total of 1,686 valid complaints from consumers across the country regarding the dating and dating industry. In the current period, 993 complaints were confirmed to have been resolved, with a resolution rate of 58.9%. Judging from the types of complaints, they mainly include exaggerated service effects and difficulty in refunding. To put it bluntly, some dating platforms are playing tricks on you, and they don’t care about the wine but your wallet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the folk, &quot;matchmaker&#39;s words&quot; have long been the driving force for young people to come together. Theoretically, a dating website is a &quot;virtual matchmaker&quot;, but in reality, this &quot;virtual matchmaker&quot; often shows characteristics that are contrary to the function of a matchmaker. The most important characteristic of a matchmaker is to use his sharp tongue to facilitate the marriage between a man and a woman as quickly as possible. However, some dating websites are just the opposite. Their core appeal is to try their best to sign a long-term contract. To this end, they delay and consume all kinds of things until the contract is due. Period, make a lot of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of paying a large membership fee is to find high-quality men and women, but a disturbing problem is that on some dating websites, there are really high-quality men and women waiting for you, and you only need to pay enough to find the right one. Object? In fact, you can know the answer just by looking at the logic lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, high-quality men and women have long been robbed of their heads. Do they still need to go to a blind date platform? It is said that some platforms have a large number of high-quality men and women, and after paying the money, it is yours. Is this a joke? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you pay a membership fee to a blind date website, you are essentially paying an agency fee. But many times, the agency fee is very strange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of real estate, intermediaries still have &quot;business rules&quot;. They can only charge fees after the house sale is completed, so real estate agents try their best to bring both parties together to reach a deal. However, some dating websites induce eager men and women to spend their money and are irresponsible for the results. They can actually continue to have a prosperous business and have no worries about customer sources. Do they really benefit from the &quot;people are stupid and have more money&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many members of the dating platform spend tens of thousands, hundreds of thousands or even hundreds of thousands, which is really no less than the agency fee for buying a house - the &quot;bulk transactions&quot; displayed in this kind of marriage and love market are full of of fantasy and absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some dating platforms engage in the practice of fabricating portraits, deceiving you, and cutting as many leeks as you can. They are despicable and shameless, but they always gain the upper hand with a series of misleading and risk-mitigating techniques. This makes many consumers miserable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who frequently talk to you about money are not just scammers, but also people who engage in &quot;dating tricks&quot;. It is common sense to realize that it is unlikely that a dating website will have high-quality men and women, it is unlikely that you can get &quot;more&quot; by spending more money, and it is unlikely that you will be invincible with the &quot;guidance&quot; of a dating consultant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finding a partner “online” certainly has a certain effect – in fact, I have friends who found true love online, but do I have to find some “professional platform” to find a partner? not necessarily. The aforementioned Ms. Guo signed a contract but found the right person outside the platform. This &quot;accident&quot; that slapped the platform in the face fully demonstrates that hot life scenes are the &quot;incubation&quot; base for relationships. Sometimes, when you can&#39;t find a partner, it&#39;s not because you haven&#39;t entered the &quot;professional platform&quot;, but because your effective social circle is not large enough, or in other words, you are not deep enough in the ocean of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you really can&#39;t meet the right person on your own, then use your parents, relatives, friends, and colleagues to exert energy and accumulate opportunities, and at the same time try to expand your private social circle and personal media display circle to open up opportunities for yourself. The door to marriage and love is still a trustworthy path. At least, if you take this path, your wallet will not be hurt, your armor will be thrown away, and you will have nowhere to complain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[更能提供情绪价值？网购冲击下，实体店靠什么活下来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258228]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The rise of e-commerce platforms has had a big impact on offline shopping. Coupled with the increase in consumption in recent years, After downgrading, many users, including me, have to shop around online before placing an order, and even start shopping on some platforms that are famous for their low prices, and they still find it really delicious. With such an unstoppable consumer trend, I thought that physical stores would definitely not be able to open. However, after observing my parents’ consumption behavior, I understood how physical stores can maintain a competitive advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown has a newly built self-built house with many rooms and toilets, so there is no one-time renovation. I took advantage of the e-commerce shopping festival to buy a bathroom cabinet for the restroom. This is the product I ordered after reading countless posts on how to choose bathroom ware online. After it was delivered to my hometown, I made an appointment with the installer, and nothing went wrong in the process. The only question came from my dad. In addition to expressing his dissatisfaction with the price, he also asked me a soul-searching question: &quot;Why don&#39;t you go to a store near home to buy it? I know you, it will be easier to repair in the future.&quot; I can&#39;t answer this question, because The reason for online shopping is to pursue cost-effectiveness, but my prices are uncompetitive in front of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I returned to my hometown, my dad couldn’t wait to take me to the bathroom they used and asked me to guess how much the bathroom cabinet in front of me cost. I said I couldn’t guess, “500 yuan!” With a proud look on his face, I could even see his inner monologue: &quot;See if I&#39;m very good. Online shopping is just a cloud!&quot; He explained to me: &quot;This is a sample from the boss&#39;s clearance, and I took it away. &quot;Of course I know that there is a difference between three-no products with nothing and brand-name products. The most direct reflection is the price, but the low price really shocked me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Misfortune never comes singly. After I went home and used the newly installed bathroom cabinet several times, I found that the sink and water pipe connections were not tightened, causing water to seep and drip onto the floor. There was no hexagonal wrench at home, and my dad was sarcastic to me again. If there was something wrong with his bathroom cabinet or water heater, he could just walk a few hundred meters and call someone to repair it, but I could only figure out a solution on my own. So, that bathroom cabinet is still seeping water, and the sound of water dripping on the tiles is my dad’s accusation against me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at it this way, it seems that physical stores rely on price wars to win online shopping. In fact, this is not the case. It’s just that my dad’s consumption concept makes him choose low-priced products. In essence, physical stores still rely on their touchability. The excellent after-sales service earns consumers&#39; dependence and trust on it. What’s even more amazing is that it also allows users to pay by providing emotional value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One summer night, my parents went shopping to enjoy the cool air. When they came back, they brought a water purifier and a staff member. They also carried a complimentary air purifier and juicer upstairs. I was worried that the two elderly people had been deceived, so I quickly dragged my dad aside and asked him what was going on. The thing is that they were &quot;bewitched&quot; and immediately bought a water purifier. The price was less than 5,000 yuan, and it also came with two gifts. The brand is a regular brand, the store is a regular store, and the staff accompanying me also wear polo shirts with the brand logo printed on them. I subconsciously used my mobile phone to open the brand&#39;s online store and looked for the model my dad bought. After searching to no avail, I consulted online customer service. It turned out that the online and offline models were different. I didn’t buy fakes, but looking at the two gifts, I knew they must be expensive. I still don’t understand the reason why wool comes from sheep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My dad is a person who likes petty bargains, but buying a water purifier is not because it is cheap or because of the two gifts, but because the staff really win people&#39;s hearts. They are not robots in online shopping malls that use text to express intimacy. The guy who came to my house to install a water purifier, after being in contact with him for a while, I thought I might not be able to help but pay for him. During the installation process, he patiently explained the knowledge about use and maintenance to my parents. After completion, he was not in a hurry to leave, but opened the packaging of the juicer and demonstrated how to use it. I was standing aside at that time, knowing how to operate the juicer without reading the manual, so he could leave and get off work. But he asked my mother for bananas and milk, put them in the cup, pressed the button, and explained the operation at the same time. The juicer made a sound like an electric drill. My parents stood beside him quietly, watching with smiles. After the juice was finished, he poured two glasses and handed them to my parents. The three of them were talking and laughing. I was at the other end of the living room, watching this scene, and it felt like they were a family of three. Do you think it&#39;s worth the money? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the emotional value that online shopping is difficult to provide. In addition to a large number of middle-aged and elderly people who cannot use smartphones and shop online, there is also a group of people who firmly believe in physical stores and that only tangible products in the store and face-to-face sales staff can bring a sense of security. The e-commerce economy is booming, but many physical stores are not only surviving, but doing well. I think this is also a little bit of the needs of contemporary people who are prone to emotional emptiness. They need companionship, comfort, real touch and face-to-face communication. Only such care can make cold materials have extra value, and can Be willing to pay for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为浙江杭州国企职员）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独家专访诺贝尔文学奖委员会主席安德斯·奥尔森：“他能让沉默和停顿在剧场中说话”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 12:28:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/09/kha3TeOrTYWc4gmxLBcept2eoPt61ZczTcDWmib1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/kha3TeOrTYWc4gmxLBcept2eoPt61ZczTcDWmib1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, the Swedish Academy awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature to Norwegian Drama Author Jon Foss, whose plays are the most performed of any contemporary European playwright. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, 2023, Mats Malm, the permanent secretary of the Swedish Academy, called Jorn ·Fosse, 64, was driving in the village of Bergen, a city on Norway&#39;s west coast, when he called. Fosse had been carefully preparing for this call for ten years—after all, he had been part of the hot debate about the Nobel Prize in Literature for ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was surprised, but at the same time, in a sense, I wasn&#39;t,&quot; he told Swedish public broadcaster. Fosse promised to drive home carefully. He is the most famous living playwright in the contemporary era and his works have been performed the most. He also writes prose, novels, poetry, children&#39;s literature and translation works. His works have been translated into more than fifty languages. After receiving the Nobel Prize, he complained that there would be no more big prizes to win in the future, &quot;Everything will go downhill from now on!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jorn Fosse was born in 1959 in Haugesund, a small town on the west coast of Norway. De, who made his debut in 1983 with the novel &quot;Red, Black&quot;, began drama creation when he was around 35 years old and completed 40 plays including adaptations in 20 years. According to The New Yorker, after a very successful and busy period working almost exclusively as a playwright, in 2012 Fother converted to Catholicism, gave up drinking, remarried, and rarely wrote plays again, &quot;writing another The idea of ​​a script no longer entertains”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, John Fosse published his most important masterpiece of novels in recent years, &quot;September&quot;. This series of seven novels is written in the form of a monologue, nearly a thousand pages of stream-of-consciousness narration, with sentences never interrupted. According to the New Yorker, the narrator of &quot;Seven Parts&quot; is a painter named Asle, a convert to Catholicism who is mourning the death of his wife Ales. On Christmas Eve, Asler discovers his friend, a painter of the same name, unconscious in a Bergen alley, dying of alcohol poisoning. &quot;Their memories overlap, repeat, and gradually merge into A single voice, a vague consciousness capable of existing in many times and places simultaneously.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After winning the Nobel Prize, Fosse said in an interview that after completing &quot;Seven Parts&quot;, &quot;this announcement was expected to a certain extent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse always insisted on writing in Nynorsk, a language spoken only in the western and central regions of southern Norway. Nynorsk, also known as New Norse, is a written language formed by a linguist who collected dialects from rural areas of Norway in the mid-19th century. Compared to Norway&#39;s other official language, written Norwegian, Nynorsk has a small footprint. In Norway, the first language in which students are taught is supposed to be decided by referendum in each school district, but as of 2016, only 12.2% of primary school students accepted Nynorsk as the main written language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ninosk is a language that Fosse, who was born in the West Coast countryside, learned as a child. He attributed the award to the language itself, which he believed brought a sense of freshness. He is good at turning blank space and silence into speech, and even believes that &quot;Oriental audiences can best understand my works.&quot; Anders Olsen, chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature, mentioned in the Swedish Academy’s biography of Fosse that after completely simplifying the language and dramatic actions, Fosse used the simplest everyday language to touch human anxieties and emotions. uncertainty, and provide a profound experience of proximity to the divine. This brought him extraordinary public recognition and established him as a major innovator of contemporary theatre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anders listed several of Fosse&#39;s writing qualities. One of his key themes is to show, through minimalism and fragmentation, the harrowing transformations of critical moments of indecision. For example, a young mother left her apartment to take out the trash but locked herself out while her children were still inside. She needs to go get help but can&#39;t do that because she can&#39;t abandon her child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fosse presents situations that are immediately recognizable from our own daily lives.&quot; While in the 1995 play &quot;The Name,&quot; a pregnant young girl awaits the father of her unborn child, He was delayed. &quot;A tension is immediately built here due to this sense of uncertainty and the resulting fragmented sentences. Furthermore, these interruptions create a gap between the girl&#39;s desire for a new life with her child and her anxiety about being abandoned by her father Gully.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Death Variation,&quot; a one-act play about a suicidal girl, Fother tells the story backwards from the girl&#39;s death. It is written in brief, staccato language by six nameless people from different eras, both living and dead. The play ends with the girl giving a moving speech from the other side of the grave, expressing a fundamental uncertainty about whether her decision to end her life was the right one. Jon Fosse considers his writing difficult to categorize, &quot;You don&#39;t read my books for the plot. But it&#39;s not because I want to be an incomprehensible writer, I never try to write in a complicated way. I always It’s about writing in a simple and—I hope—profound way.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anders Olsen is the chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature. After the 2023 Nobel Prize in Literature was announced, Anders Olson Si received an email from a Southern Weekend reporter as scheduled. He said he was happy to be interviewed and responded within a day. However, he remained tight-lipped on some issues, such as whether the jury&#39;s decision to award the award to Jon Fother went smoothly and whether there were any other strong contenders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is an exclusive interview with Anders Olsen by a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The strongest and deepest emotions are contained in silence and pauses&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past ten years, John Fosse has been regarded as a strong contender for the Nobel Prize in Literature. When did his name enter the Nobel committee&#39;s short list? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For confidentiality reasons, I cannot answer this question. All I can say is that Fosse has been is a globally renowned author whose works have been widely translated since the 1990s and have been with us on the theater stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On what writing qualities does the Swedish Academy pay attention to Jörn· Fother? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Fosse wrote in a wide range of fields. He was a playwright, novelist and poet, especially his scripts and long or short narratives capture our attention. But in all this he was a poet, as he preferred to be called. You can feel it in his language processing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What works of Jon Fother are the main basis for the award? work? Which work does the jury consider to be his most important work? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We think (and Fox said so in the review) that after Fox completed his After releasing three volumes of his masterpiece, The Septology - a well-deserved achievement, this award couldn&#39;t come at a better time. This novel and more of his essays, and of course his highly innovative plays from the 1990s, are decisive for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From a personal perspective, you like him Which works? What strikes you most about his writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He can make silences and pauses speak in the theater, and it is in silences and pauses that the strongest, The deepest emotion, that struck me. &quot;Somebody is going to come&quot;, &quot;Death Variations&quot; and &quot;Dream in Autumn&quot; are all wonderful plays. And in his prose, I was completely immersed in &quot;The Septology,&quot; but I especially loved &quot;Morning and Evening,&quot; a book about life written in sparkling and extremely sensitive prose. Short stories of coming and passing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Give voices a special status”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Nobel Prize in Literature was awarded to Jon Fosse: &quot;His innovative drama and prose give voice to the ineffable.&quot; Where does the jury think his innovation lies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Fosse is good at using silence, interruption and postponement of action to evoke deep anxiety in people. This is a striking feature of his drama. In his prose, his use of repetition and evocation is more typical. In both cases, something must be expressed that cannot be easily said. Fother does this in a very touching way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The word voice in the award speech , also seems intended to emphasize Fother&#39;s contribution to literary language. How do you see the connection between Fosse&#39;s literary achievements and his use of the Nynorsk language? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is the first Nynorsk-language writer to win the Nobel Prize for Literature. I think his work should be read in his native language if possible, it has an unpretentious beauty and is not difficult to translate. Compared to written Norwegian, Norway&#39;s other official language, Nynorsk is more traditional, less urban and more closely related to Old Norse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are reading the Nynorsk version ? Are there any good translations to recommend? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, I read Fosse in Nynorsk, and it is highly recommended. I don&#39;t have much experience with translations, and both Urban Andersson and Lars Andersson&#39;s Swedish translations are excellent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to understand the &quot;ineffable&quot; in Fosse&#39;s works What does it mean? He introduced his own writing ideas and quoted two sentences, one is Wittgenstein&#39;s &quot;Where there is no words, one must be silent&quot; and the other is Derrida&#39;s &quot;What cannot be said, one can only write&quot;. He thinks the latter is closer to his own ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think both statements can be linked to Fosse&#39;s writing. In Wittgenstein&#39;s Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus, &quot;unsayable&quot; refers to the realm where we cannot formulate propositions, and it is also the realm where we can call it &quot;true&quot;. But literature, ethics, and religion do not use propositions; they belong precisely to the realm of the unsayable. Derrida does not have the same strict standard of truth as Wittgenstein. On the contrary, his &quot;saying&quot; gives writing a special position, which coincides with Fosse. Paradoxically, Fother&#39;s writing gave voice a special status, especially in his dramatic works. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Eon Fother believes that he has the greatest influence Among his writers are Tarje Wessos, the Austrian poet Georg Trakl and Samuel Beckett, and the ones he most admires are Kafka and Knut. Knut Hamsun. How do you think these writers influenced him? What were Fosse&#39;s own innovations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s hard to give a short answer. Fother has a negative worldview in the Gnostic sense (Gnostic (ancient Greek philosophy, which believes that the material world is evil and can only be saved through &quot;spiritual knowledge&quot;)), which is very close to Beckett. The most important thing is the use of negation and questions. Fosse&#39;s play bears a striking resemblance to Waiting for Godot, but this does not lead him to nihilism. There was in Fosse a faith that Beckett did not have and a kind of passive mysticism, like that of Meister Eckhart, which appears in the Heptalogy. 》 is very obvious. I won’t talk about other writers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“It’s very difficult to give a great Fosse performance”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You think the uniqueness of Fosse&#39;s writing lies in the fact that after completely simplifying language and dramatic actions, he uses simple daily life scenes to express human beings&#39; strongest anxiety and powerlessness. A lot of writers can do this, what’s so special about Fosse? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A certain strange confidence, almost childlike self-confidence, and a gentle humor in the negativity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the interview after the award, you said you were blessed Ser&#39;s work touches on common human &quot;anxieties, insecurities, and thoughts about life and death.&quot; This is easily reminiscent of the unease that pervades the world. Are there any practical considerations in awarding the award to Fosse at this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You are always influenced by what is happening in the contemporary world, but I don’t think it is the decisive factor. Fosse is always with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you seen his plays on stage? ’s performance? How is it different from reading a script? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It needs to be pointed out that Fosse&#39;s dramatic works are extremely readable. But this is not always the case. In addition, due to Fosse&#39;s special language and less stage scenery, it is very difficult to give a wonderful Fosse performance on the stage. Please read his work first and then perform your own mental show! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is the award given to a playwright? Although Jon Fosse is one of the most well-known playwrights in the contemporary theater world, compared with the popular candidates in the eyes of the outside world, such as Salman Rushdie and Margaret Atwood, this choice will not be the same. Will there be some niche? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For us it is of course important to focus on drama. Harold Pinter received this honor over twenty years ago and I think now is the time. Interestingly, Fosse also translated Pinter&#39;s work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2014, Fother accepted an interview with the British &quot;Guardian&quot; &quot;In an interview, he said that the Nobel Prize in Literature is usually awarded to very old writers. &quot;You will get it when it does not affect your writing.&quot; Coincidentally, Fosse rarely writes for the theater now. Last year, he told the New Yorker that he wanted to take a break after writing &quot;Seven Parts&quot; and that he is now very interested in literary translation. Does winning the award at this time confirm his previous views? Is this a &quot;lifetime achievement award&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it can be regarded as a &quot;lifetime achievement award&quot;, just like Peter Handke (2019 Winner of the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature) won the same award. Of course, this isn&#39;t always the case. In both cases, it is also important to note that they achieved great things before winning the award. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This year Chinese writer Can Xue ranked in the British bookmaker Nicer It ranked first in the odds list on the Odds website, attracting enthusiastic attention from the Chinese people. How did the jury respond to the possibility of Can Xue winning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For our confidentiality reasons, I cannot answer this question. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In my opinion, the Nobel Prize for Literature Giving to the so-called unpopular outstanding writers is a promotion of literature. Do you think that influence is declining? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anders Olsen: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 12:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[706名缅北电诈犯罪嫌疑人分三批移交我方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258285]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 11:26:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In view of the severe situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Yunnan Public Security Bureau continues to strengthen its cooperation with Myanmar-related local law enforcement departments border police cooperation and continued to carry out multiple rounds of crackdowns. Recently, based on the remarkable results achieved in the previous work, the crackdown has achieved another major result. 497 telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to the Lincang Public Security Bureau in two batches, and 209 telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau. Among them, online There are 26 people at large, which has effectively dealt a blow to the arrogance of overseas fraudsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since September this year, the public security agencies in Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er and other places in Yunnan have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar. A large number of overseas fraud dens have been successfully eradicated, and a large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects have been successfully eradicated. The person was handed over to us. In order to continue to build momentum and advance the crackdown in depth, under the command and deployment of the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau further expanded its results. 209 telecommunications network fraud suspects were successfully handed over to us on October 1. At the same time, Lincang Public Security Bureau&#39;s border police law enforcement cooperation has made significant progress. The relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar handed over 497 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us in two batches on September 25 and October 7 respectively. This is another important breakthrough made by the Yunnan public security agencies in border police cooperation, following the Xishuangbanna and Puer public security agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, relevant criminal suspects have been detained by public security organs in Inner Mongolia, Heilongjiang, Zhejiang, Anhui, Fujian, Henan, Chongqing and other places involved in the case. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all the facts of his crimes, and while cracking down on fraud crimes in accordance with the law, they will also dig deep into related crimes such as black and gray products in the country to ensure that the entire chain is cracked down and severely punished in accordance with the law. After continuous and effective crackdowns, 2,317 suspects of telecommunications and cyber fraud in northern Myanmar have been successfully captured and handed over to us, including 23 behind-the-scenes &quot;financiers&quot;, organizational leaders and backbones, and 94 online fugitives, a powerful squeeze This has reduced the living space for overseas fraudsters, and the number of telecom network fraud cases across the country has recently shown a significant downward trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency stated that the telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar mainly involve fraud types such as bill rebates, fake online investment and financial management, fake reseller logistics customer service, fake online loans, etc. The general public is advised to be careful Be vigilant, enhance your ability to detect and prevent fraud, and beware of being deceived. The public security organs will continue to keep a close eye on telecom network fraud criminal groups in northern Myanmar, continue to deepen border police cooperation, continue to organize special crackdown operations, make every effort to clear out fraud dens, arrest fraud personnel in accordance with the law, continue to expand the results of operations, and resolutely protect the people. Property security and legal rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突再起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258274]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-09 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On October 7, Palestinian armed groups in the Gaza Strip launched a large-scale rocket attack into Israel. Israel immediately declared a state of war. The conflict between the two countries has resumed, and geopolitical tensions have escalated. More than a thousand people have died. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>