<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[广州地铁安检要求乘客试喝自带水，被索赔4.8万元，判了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 16:51:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Subway stations are public places, and the subway company, as the person in charge of management, has the obligation to ensure public safety. Is &quot;taking a sip&quot; of bottled water, a common security inspection method, suspected of infringement? Recently, the Guangzhou Railway Transport Intermediate Court disclosed the trial details of a related case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Passengers said they felt unwell after trying to drink their own water&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Taking Guangzhou Metro to court for compensation of 48,100 yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On December 14, 2022, because Zhang entered the station with liquid, the security personnel asked Zhang to undergo a liquid test. Zhang drank the bottled water he brought, and then the security personnel released him into the subway. car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Zhang claimed that the bottled water he drank was self-bottled boiled water, and he himself suffered from gastrointestinal diseases, which caused him extreme discomfort after drinking water, and this incident also caused him severe mental illness. Because of the irritation and distress, the defendant filed a lawsuit with the court, claiming that the defendant Guangzhou Metro Company had infringed the law and requested compensation for medical expenses, lost work expenses, nutrition expenses, mental losses, etc., totaling 48,100 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;[Judge’s statement]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;There is no fault in the security personnel’s request for “drink tasting”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Passengers should cooperate and support subway security inspection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Guangzhou Railway Transport Court held that this case is a dispute over the rights to life, health and body. In this case, Zhang claimed that the violation of his physical and mental health was caused by the security inspection behavior of the defendant Guangzhou Metro Company, and corresponding evidence should be provided to prove it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the Guangzhou Metro Company sets up security checks at the entrance and requires passengers to pass liquid detectors or &quot;take a sip&quot; if they carry liquids. This is because it is an urban rail transit operating unit. Therefore, the security personnel required Zhang to test the liquid he carried, and there was no fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Zhang failed to provide evidence to support his claims of medical expenses, lost work pay, nutrition expenses, mental loss expenses, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The examination report form, outpatient medical records and other evidence provided by Zhang also show that he had been diagnosed with gastrointestinal diseases as early as the end of 2020 and the beginning of 2022 and had multiple examinations and medical visits. He was diagnosed with a sleep disorder due to insomnia symptoms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Zhang cannot prove that the subway security inspection’s request for him to “take a sip” of his own water has a causal relationship with the damage he claims. Zhang claims that Guangzhou Metro Company has infringed upon him and should be liable for compensation. Please, lack of factual and legal basis, the court will not support it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The presiding judge of the Guangzhou Railway Transport Court stated that security inspection is a necessary means for the subway company to fulfill its safety obligations, and passengers should support and cooperate as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Civil Code clearly stipulates that operators and managers of subway stations, railway stations, airports and other places who fail to fulfill their safety obligations and cause damage to others shall bear tort liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Urban Rail Transit Operation Management Regulations&quot; promulgated by the Ministry of Transport also clearly stipulates that passengers are prohibited from carrying toxic, harmful, flammable, explosive, radioactive, corrosive and other hazards that may endanger personal and property safety. Items coming in and taking the bus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a vicious incident occurs on a means of transportation, the space is very limited and it is difficult to evacuate in time to reduce injuries. Therefore, security inspection, as the most effective preventive measure that public transportation managers can take, is reasonable and If necessary, passengers should understand and cooperate as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To claim infringement, it is necessary to prove the existence of a causal relationship between the infringement behavior and the damage results. A general tort must include an infringing act, a damaging result, a causal relationship between the infringing act and the damaging result, and the perpetrator&#39;s subjective fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, Zhang claimed that the security check behavior caused physical discomfort and mental stimulation. However, the existing evidence can only prove that he had suffered from illness and insomnia before, but could not prove that he was physically injured after the security check behavior. Or the disease worsened, so Zhang’s claim for infringement and compensation from the subway company has no factual and legal basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“老实人”成了贬义词：语义嬗变背后是对消费和情绪的无度索求]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259338]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is generally believed that &quot;honest&quot; as an adjective has two levels of semantics in Chinese, one of which refers to morality. Honesty and reliability on one level, and secondly, law-abiding and orderly behavior on the other. Before the 1980s, &quot;honest&quot; was definitely a positive evaluation of a person. Whether in the workplace or in the marriage and mate selection market, the evaluation of &quot;honest people&quot; was similar to some kind of quality assurance and played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that honesty, reliability and law-abiding are out-and-out excellent qualities in any society with normal moral tendencies. However, starting in the 1990s, the semantics of &quot;honest person&quot; changed rapidly, and gradually became associated with negative connotations such as &quot;poor interpersonal skills&quot;, &quot;cowardly&quot;, &quot;stupid&quot; and &quot;low economic ability&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the Internet age, &quot;honest people&quot; have been infinitely deconstructed, especially in the marriage and love market. &quot;Honest people&quot; are directly linked to &quot;low emotional intelligence&quot;, &quot;cannot provide emotional value&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;, and become With the out-and-out &quot;minus points&quot;, &quot;honest people&quot; are completely marginalized in the marriage and love market. A 2017 study showed that &quot;honesty&quot; surpassed &quot;poor economic conditions&quot; and &quot;no formal job&quot; to become the second largest reason why young people over 35 years old in a certain place become &quot;singles&quot; (the first reason is illness or physical disability) ). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a live broadcast not long ago, an online anchor became furious because he was called an &quot;honest person&quot; by his fans. Perhaps he could not accurately grasp the changes in &quot;honest people&quot;. Complex semantics, but he instinctively felt insulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the quality assurance of character to the infinitely deconstructed stigma in the Internet society, what have &quot;honest people&quot; experienced in the development and changes of modern society? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Honest people&quot; wandering in the midst of social changes&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early days of reform, the semantic change of &quot;honest people&quot; from praise to derogation is actually not difficult to understand. In the rapidly changing social environment at that time, the market economy and industrial civilization were rapidly changing all aspects of society. The life experiences that &quot;honest people&quot; who tend to follow the rules and practice in the traditional social life model are quickly overturned. And because they fail to make adaptive changes and responses to social changes in a timely manner, they will naturally be at a relatively disadvantaged level and position economically within a period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, drastic social changes have created considerable &quot;grey areas&quot; in the economic field. In such chaos and prosperity, &quot;the bold will die of hunger and the timid will starve to death&quot; once became a popular survival creed in society. There are indeed a group of people who have made their first pot of gold in these fields. The cautious and lawful side of &quot;honest people&quot; determines that they are destined not to be one of these trend-setters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the above two points, the series of changes in the semantics of &quot;honest person&quot; at the end of the last century are actually a normal manifestation of the changes in individual value evaluation standards during social changes, and it is not difficult to understand. . After the social and economic order stabilized, the reputation and reputation of &quot;honest people&quot; took a positive turn. Especially during the period of rapid growth in the first decade of the 21st century, &quot;honest people&quot; were under construction and development. Showing a series of work characteristics gives honest people an aura of being &quot;down-to-earth, hard-working and willing to work&quot;, which improves the image of &quot;honest people&quot; to a considerable extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the reasons for the infinite deconstruction and image decline of the meaning of &quot;honest person&quot; in the Internet society are much more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Honest people&quot; who are excluded and marginalized by cultural capital&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the end of the last century to the beginning of this century, first television and then the Internet had a major impact on social values. With the popularization of television and the Internet, the cultural center effect of modern society has begun to become prominent. A cultural paradigm based on the cultural center&#39;s lifestyle and values ​​has been created and introduced to the public through countless movies, television, entertainment and variety shows. spread throughout society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When countless young people living in the seventh and eighth tier cities, the urban-rural interface and the vast rural areas are immersed in the cultural products produced in Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen, they are actually unknowingly Accept the life patterns and values ​​advocated by these cultural products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, cultural capital uses a modern approach to reduce the vast majority of people to spectators, consciously or unconsciously watching a few people at the center interpret their lives. Most of the joys, sorrows, joys, sorrows and hatreds on the screen take place in the reinforced concrete forests of Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen. When &quot;small town youth&quot; and &quot;small town youth&quot; watch the screen as viewers, it means that they have subconsciously accepted the &quot;central paradigm culture&quot; expressed and conveyed by these cultural products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This cultural paradigm based on the super city has quite distinctive characteristics - the social environment of a highly developed commodity economy, the values ​​of consumerism and hedonism, and the concept of love and mate selection of the urban middle class. Way. The cultural center effect is so strong that when some film and television works try to change the subject matter or scene, they often fall into embarrassing situations. In a certain film and television work, the protagonist from a poor background wears a down jacket from a North American brand worth more than 10,000 yuan, using seven The fact that the 8,000-yuan iPhone is considered a joke is obviously the result of the screenwriter being trapped in this cultural paradigm and unable to extricate himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, cultural capital spares no effort to promote the central lifestyle and values; on the other hand, it marginalizes and excludes other lifestyles and values. The core of this cultural paradigm promoted by cultural capital is actually the basic feature of postmodern society, that is, the desire for consumption and the emotional demand anytime and anywhere. The former is the most ideal state of material satisfaction that an individual can achieve in a highly developed commodity economy society, while the latter is the basic requirement to combat individual loneliness in a highly atomized society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, under this cultural paradigm, a typical successful social individual either has endless money or the ability to please others anytime, anywhere, preferably both. Of. The problem with &quot;honest people&quot; is that they often have neither such economic standards nor such character conditions. Therefore, it is natural for them to become an excluded and marginalized group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In film and television works and entertainment and love variety shows, &quot;romantic, humorous, rich&quot; are the &quot;perfect characters&quot;, and the advantages of &quot;honest people&quot; are ignored or forgotten intentionally or unintentionally. On the contrary, &quot;honest people&quot; often become the ones who are ridiculed and ridiculed because they are &quot;dull&quot;, &quot;low in emotional intelligence&quot; and &quot;cannot provide emotional value&quot;. This stereotype created intentionally or unintentionally actually changes public perception in a subtle way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned at the beginning of the article, honesty, reliability and law-abiding are out-and-out excellent qualities in any society with normal moral tendencies. A society that regards consumer desires and emotional demands as the highest values ​​must be a society where speculation is everywhere and scammers are rampant. After all, the places where the romantic, humorous and wealthy &quot;perfect individuals&quot; mentioned above are most common, except in Korean dramas, are The pig is being slaughtered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[湖北省原副省长曹广晶受贿、泄露内幕信息案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259393]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 17:05:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, the Xuzhou Intermediate People’s Court of Jiangsu Province held a public hearing of the first instance against the Hubei Provincial People’s Government The case of former party member and deputy governor Cao Guangjing accepting bribes and leaking inside information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/6ffc4b22d9f960091bb13be24853dc6b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/6ffc4b22d9f960091bb13be24853dc6b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255666&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;720&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xuzhou Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate charged: From 2004 to 2022, the defendant Cao Guangjing used his position as deputy general manager of China Three Gorges Engineering Development Corporation and deputy general manager of China Three Gorges Corporation. General manager, chairman of the board, deputy governor of Hubei Provincial People&#39;s Government and other positions, as well as convenient conditions for the formation of authority or status, to provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, project contracting, project development, job promotion, etc. , illegally receiving property from the above-mentioned units or individuals, equivalent to a total of more than 216 million yuan. In addition, while serving as the deputy governor of Hubei Province, Cao Guangjing led the bailout and reorganization of the holding company of a listed company in Hubei Province. In January 2021, Cao Guangjing disclosed the inside information about the bailout and restructuring to others, causing others to buy the shares of the listed company before the inside information was made public, and then sold the shares for a profit of more than 10.42 million yuan. The public prosecution agency requested that Cao Guangjing be held criminally responsible for the crime of accepting bribes and leaking inside information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the public prosecution agency presented relevant evidence, the defendant Cao Guangjing and his defender conducted cross-examination, and the prosecution and defense fully expressed their opinions under the auspices of the court. Cao Guangjing made a final statement and expressed his guilt in court. Repent. At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 40 people including deputies to the National People&#39;s Congress, members of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and people from all walks of life attended the trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改革开放45周年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259361]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The reform and opening up that began 45 years ago brought ancient China to a turning point in changing itself. In the grand narrative commemorating the 45th weekend of reform and opening up, we return to the historical scene with respect, look for the promoters, experiencers, and witnesses of reform and opening up, and return with readers to that moment when passion and vitality regenerated. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[詹安泰、王季思与张仲浦的一段文字因缘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259332]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5EJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5 EJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I recently obtained from Mr. Zhang Zhongpu’s philosophical heir, Mr. Zhang Yan, his collection of sages’ books and artifacts, including Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi. There are one lost letter each to Mr. Zhang, and each of them is accompanied by a note of poems and a note of music. Following the elegant wishes of Teacher Zhang Yan, Hui Yu compiled and published it, writing a short essay and a brief explanation, for the benefit of others, and at the same time, it can be used to preserve the origins of a passage written by a senior scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987), courtesy name Zhanyun and nickname Oubo, was born in Yugan, Jiangxi. He studied engineering at an early age and studied at Jiangxi Polytechnic College, determined to save the country through science. He then changed his studies to law and graduated from the Law Department of Peking University in 1937 with a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. He then specialized in literature, loved classical literature and was good at writing poetry. Dedicated to education throughout his life, he served as a Chinese language teacher at Nanchang Normal University, Linchuan Simple Normal University, and Yuqian Yuting Middle School. In 1934, he taught at the former National Zhejiang University, Zhejiang Normal University, and Hangzhou University, mainly taking charge of modern Chinese literature courses. He is the author of &quot;Guo Moruo&#39;s Historical Drama &quot;Qu Yuan&quot;&quot; (Shanghai Literature and Art Publishing House, 1959), &quot;Analysis of &quot;The New Story&quot;&quot; (co-authored with Wang Rongchu, Zhejiang Literature and Art Publishing House, 1983), &quot;Yan Milou Poetry Manuscript&quot; ( Northern Literature and Art Publishing House, 2004), &quot;Notes on Xia Wanchun&#39;s &quot;Ode to the Great Sorrow&quot;&quot; (Threadbound Book Company, 2016), &quot;Modern Patriotic Poet Huang Zunxian&quot; (Tianhe Press, 2016), etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot; contains nine letters from Zhan to Long Yusheng, Chen Zhongfan, Yang Shuda, Luo Xianglin and Liu Baiduan. &quot;The Complete Works of Wang Jisi&quot; contains nearly 50 letters by Wang. At the end of his letter to Zhang Hanqing in October 1987, he wrote: &quot;I used to occasionally write some prose, but lately I have been immersed in ancient books and have rarely experienced new life experiences, except for relatives and friends. Outside of letters and letters, they rarely write.&quot; It can be imagined that Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi still have a lot of letters and letters lying around, waiting to be compiled. The two lost letters disclosed in this article can be regarded as a source of inspiration, or they can be regarded as A little bit of celery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;804&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhan Antai&#39;s letter and words to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Letter from Zhan Antai to Zhang Zhongpu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhong Pu Written by: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hui Shufeng It is reported that the great work is pure and healthy, and the workmanship is greatly admired. &quot;If you avoid the soldiers, you will face the water of Aotang. When you leave the country, you will still have new willow shoots.&quot; I recite it repeatedly, but there is still pain left. On the first day of the Yuan Dynasty, I occasionally wrote small words, and recorded them on separate sheets of paper to beg for correction. After many years of neglect, thorns grew on my hands. I took a photo of Huanghuagang and sent it to Brother Qu Chan. I hope I have conveyed it to you. At this moment, I would like to pay tribute&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chun Qi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp &amp;nbsp; nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Diantaitonshou&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; on the second day of the first lunar month&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send Brother Qu Chan a piece of paper begging to be conveyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A brief examination of the writing time of this letter shows that it was February 1, 1957, the second day of the first lunar month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The letter involves Xia Chengtao (Qu Chan). According to the &quot;Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, Mr. Xia and Zhang Zhongpu went to Guangzhou to participate in a scientific research seminar at Sun Yat-sen University on January 5, 1957. On January 14, the two of them, accompanied by Zhan Antai and Wang Jinguang, visited Huanghuagang. The diary stated that they were &quot;majestic&quot; and &quot;taken a photo&quot;. This is the so-called &quot;Photography in Huanghuagang&quot; in the lost letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the previously published lost letters and the relevant contents of &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, it can be seen that after Zhang Zhongpu returned to Hangzhou from Guangzhou, he wrote to Zhan Antai and attached his own work. Check his &quot;Yan Mi Lou Poetry Manuscript&quot;, the sentence &quot;avoiding the soldiers and leaving the water in the Aotang, leaving the country is still the new willow shoots&quot; comes from Zhang&#39;s 1944 work &quot;The accumulated rain uses the Du Gongbu Hall to form a rhyme&quot;, the whole poem is: &quot;The accumulated rain and moss cover the grass, and the barbarian suburbs are temporarily stagnated by the smoke. The soldiers are left facing the water of the Aotang, and there are several new willow shoots in the country. The flying kites in the sky are startled by the meteorites, and the Peng in the clouds laughs at the nest. Zilan Ning It has the meaning of curing hunger, and the spirit of Yanjian Mountain is full of laughter.&quot; However, in the &quot;Poem Manuscript&quot; version, &quot;Yue Kun&quot; was changed to &quot;Ji Kun&quot;, which made the emotion even more intense. Zhan Antai said that &quot;it is pure and healthy, and it is extremely admirable for workmanship&quot; and &quot;it is still painful to recite it over and over again.&quot; Of course, he has the ancient etiquette of the older generation of scholars, but he also has a gaze like a torch, which illuminates the advantages of Zhang&#39;s poems. In his letters to Zhang Zhongpu in the 1960s, Miao Yue repeatedly said that &quot;great poems are fresh and elegant, and can integrate new ideas while maintaining the style and charm of old poems.&quot; , &quot;Great poetry can reflect reality, express new thoughts, and be admired after reading it.&quot; The two contrast each other, and the style and characteristics of Zhang&#39;s poetry can be seen better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Yuan Ri Occasionally Small Ci&quot; written in the poem &quot;Begging for Correction on a Separate Paper&quot; also survives in Teacher Zhang Yan&#39;s home. &quot;Yuan Day&quot; is January 31, 1957, the first day of the first month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot; mistakenly refers to New Year&#39;s Day of the &quot;Renshen Year&quot; of Xia Zheng. The full text of the Ci is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qi Tianle&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It would have been twenty years since I had talked with Qu Chan. Guests come from the south in winter, but don&#39;t leave in a hurry. At the beginning of the new year, I have memories, so I wrote this tune and sent it to Hangzhou and Zhongpu, Cambodia. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 20th year, I was sad to see Nan Feiyan (in 36 years, Qu Chan was about to travel to Guangnan, and I had poems to welcome him. ), the reunion suddenly became the present and the ancient. Paying homage to the monument (touring Huanghuagang and Guangzhou Commune with Qu Chan and Zhong Pu), walking on the shallow branches (together in Liwan on the same day), and facing tall sugarcane trees. Drunk and drunk. He also painted a river city with hundreds of dragons dancing. When I saw Fangcun, there were clusters of wild flowers competing with flutes and drums (the plan to go to Fangcun to see flowers did not bear fruit). &amp;nbsp;It’s so wonderful to travel everywhere, old friends are thousands of miles away, can we come again? The ridges and flat pavilions, the lakeside survey, are not wasted time. Thinking about you. It is necessary to make a new start with style and make a grand gesture. Just try your hand at it, and look around with your head raised. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhongpu taught me. My brother An Taichu wrote the manuscript, Ding Youyuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing this word in volume 5 of &quot;Wu&#39;an Ci&quot; collected in the fourth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot;, in the preface, &quot;kuaitan&quot; is replaced by &quot;talk&quot;, and &quot;jianchan&quot; is replaced by &quot; &quot;Bing Cambodia&quot;, the only two sentences in the poem are self-notes of &quot;three and six years&quot;, and the rest are the same. The poem mentioned in the self-note is &quot;I heard that Qu Chan (Cheng Tao) will have a poem to welcome Guangnan&quot;: &quot;Looking at the mountains, I can no longer be proud, and I love you so much that you live next to the raging waves.&quot; (Professor Qu Chan&#39;s River University, the door is opposite the Qiantang River.) It also serves as an adjoining place with Xizi, where I recall Dong Gao from Shuxiao. Touhuang writing can make you healthy, and to read the world, liver and intestine test and show. When will Han Su return to cross the ridge, the spring breeze will scratch the head of the wild clouds.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In the letter, &quot;I have been abandoned for many years, but my hands have grown thorny.&quot; Although this is a modest statement, it is also true. Appendix 3 of Volume 6 of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot; contains Zheng Xiaoyan&#39;s &quot;Chronology of Mr. Zhan Antai&quot;. In 1956, Zhan wrote three words in a row due to Xia Chengtao&#39;s trip to Guangzhou and commented: &quot;At that time, Mr. Zhan didn&#39;t write much anymore.&quot; Read &quot;Wu&#39;an Ci&quot; shows that Zhan Antai wrote very few lyrics after 1949, less than two poems per year on average, so this lost letter and lyrics are extremely precious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Letter from Wang Jisi (pictured on the right) to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Letter from Wang Jisi to Zhang Zhongpu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhongpu:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Seven-day benefit letter received . Master Zhejiang saw off all his works, which were extremely beautiful. Here Huang and Chen Zhulao also have poems to send to comrades going to the countryside. If you can mimeograph them, I should send a volume. I recently wrote a set of Sanqu, please correct me hereby attached. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The draft of &quot;History of Literature&quot; has been put away since its second publication. I don&#39;t know when it will be published. Can finish the manuscript. Notes on the Peach Blossom Fan will be available in February or March. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;CUHK has decentralized 200 cadres, including 13 from the Chinese Department. After that, the work will be heavy, and poetry will be Less writing. This hymn&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Jiao&#39;an. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp &amp;nbsp; nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Qi &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This letter is deemed to be dated January 20, 1958. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1957, Zhejiang Normal University began an anti-rightist struggle. It lasted for more than three months. 120 teachers, cadres and a group of students were wrongly classified as rightists. Professor Ren Mingshan of the Chinese Department was even wrongly classified. For &quot;extreme right&quot; elements. After October, it entered the rectification movement, that is, the stage of rectification with the main forms of speaking out, speaking out, discussing, and big-character posters. Then, in line with the policy that &quot;education must serve proletarian politics and education must be integrated with productive labor,&quot; a large number of teachers and students went to work in the countryside. &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot; records that on December 20, 1957, the Chinese Department held a celebration meeting to celebrate the approval of Lu Moye, Gao Houzai, and Yu Shi to go to the countryside. It mentioned that the first batch of 56 people were approved to go to the countryside that day (&quot;Hangzhou University&quot; &quot;History 1897-1997&quot; stated that the first batch of decentralized faculty and staff was 144), and Mr. Xia also wrote a couplet to congratulate him: &quot;If you can go down, you can grow up, and when you go to the countryside, you can reach home.&quot; Wang Jisi said in his letter that &quot;Zhejiang Normal University saw off all his works&quot;. Zhang Zhongpu&#39;s &quot;Yimilou Poetry Manuscript&quot; contains a poem &quot;Sending Friends to the Rural Areas&quot;: &quot;Mountains are moved by nine ridges. It is common, but a fool of a thousand years will not expect anything extravagant. The truth is The barnyard grass is diligent in checking things, and the mulberry trees are planted by hand to make a home. The red rain in the sky turns over the spring waves, and the devotion to serve the country shines in the morning clouds. Why is it useful to ask Tao Ling to find the source? The east wind bursts with strange flowers.&quot; Mr. Xia&#39;s diary on December 12 also contains &quot;Part 2&quot; There are three poems in &quot;Hometown&quot;, with the preface: &quot;Rural work such as herding cattle, raising geese and ducks, harvesting rice and other tasks, I can still do it competently, so I wrote a poem for each to express my determination to go to the countryside.&quot; The poem goes: &lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The cow returns from its back and takes possession of the saddle, and the string singing urges people to eat more. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The prosperity of the countryside depends on you, and you can see the black peonies of every family. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is not just to show talent, but to go to the countryside to promote prosperity. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The bamboo whip in hand is like a military order, and a flock of geese and ducks will come. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Xincang Gao Yu Le Qiucheng, Nanmu Dongqian takes advantage of the moonlight. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In those days of hard work, in the dragon battlefield, the vast expanse of green clouds listened to the sound of frogs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 11, 1958, Mr. Xia submitted three pieces of &quot;Going to the Countryside&quot; to &quot;Wen Wei Po&quot;, which was published on the 17th. On the 27th, he met Zhang Taiyan&#39;s wife, Ms. Tang Guoli, in the newspaper. &quot;Three Poems of &quot;He Yu&#39;s &quot;Going to the Countryside&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;799&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sanqu sent by Wang Jisi to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation of Sun Yat-sen University at that time was no less favorable than that of Zhejiang Normal University. Zhan Antai, Dong Meikan, etc. were also misclassified. For the right. Wang Jisi&#39;s letter mentioned that &quot;200 cadres of Zhongda University were sent to the lower levels, including 13 from the Chinese Department.&quot; &quot;Huang and Chen Zhu here also wrote poems to send to comrades who went to the countryside.&quot; Huang was referring to Mr. Huang Haizhang (1897-1989), Mr. Chen It should be Mr. Chen Ji (1900-1976). &quot;A Set of Sanqu&quot; written by Wang, the content is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nanlu A Flower Scattered Set&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Jisi&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Farewell to the first batch of comrades from Sun Yat-sen University going to the countryside&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔Nanlu〕〔Yizhihua〕In the past few days, there has been a gust of wind in Kangyuan Garden, and the honor roll has been hung in the aisle; There is a dustpan with clusters of golden flowers and a large double happiness inscription, with more than ten lines of mud and gold inscriptions in block letters underneath. There was an uproar, and the &quot;Roadside Club&quot; spread the news to see who would be the first to go to the battlefield; you can see that this young man had already prepared his bags, and even the old professor was not willing to give in. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔Liangzhou No. 7〕The whole country is united as never before, and we are happy that China&#39;s national destiny has been great, fifteen years Catching up with Britain is not a fantasy. It connects Guangdong and Guangxi in the south, Longjiang in the north, the East China Sea in the east, and Xikang in the west; forest farms have been opened in the snow-capped mountains, and green rice seedlings have grown in the sand; if the Yellow River is not allowed to have turbulent waves, it has to make the Taihang Mountains get out of the way. Take-off beams are installed on the Yangtze River. Going up the mountain, going to the countryside, and seeing thousands of new people rushing forward, crossing the river, crossing the waves, transforming nature and transforming thoughts, and being tempered into steel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[End] Those who go down must cultivate the crops of the entire village, and those who remain must make peach and plum blossoms. With all the walls opened, Kangyuan Garden has already seen a new look. We want to play and sing and beat the gongs and drums to make those right-wing gentlemen who take pleasure in others&#39; misfortunes feel so angry that their bellies swell. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Note: Kangyuan is the seat of Sun Yat-sen University, and the &quot;Roadside Club&quot; is a rectification movement organized by Sun Yat-sen University students. An express newspaper organization organized during the movement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This song is missing from the sixth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Wang Jisi&quot;, &quot;Collection of Rhymes&quot;. Moreover, the handwriting of this song is very different from that of the aforementioned letter, so it must have been written by two hands. Wang Jisi said in &quot;The Vicissitudes of Half a Study Room&quot; written in 1986: &quot;My former lover Xu Bixia was a wonderful partner in my life. In addition to doing housework, she also helped me receive guests and copy manuscripts.&quot; Just like Mr. Chen Yinke wrote a letter in his later years. The signatures were often ghostwritten by Mrs. Tang Yun, and Wang&#39;s piece may have been handwritten by Mrs. Xu. But in the same article, he wrote: &quot;The good times did not last long. After 1957, due to the well-known facts, I praised the &#39;joy of friends&#39; of the previous generations of poets in class and introduced the &#39;joy of the boudoir&#39; in their love works. &#39;, was criticized. Bixia died of illness soon, and the family lost its joy. Political avoidance caused the alienation of friends. This was another small change in half of the study.&quot; Mrs. Xu found out in early 1957 Suffering from a serious illness, he unfortunately died in September 1958. Therefore, there is still some doubt whether the copyist of this essay was Mrs. Xu or other family members or students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The draft of &quot;History of Literature&quot; has been put away since the second big announcement, and I don&#39;t know when it will be completed.&quot; Wang Jisi was involved in the matter several years ago, and Mr. Xia was slightly involved. According to the &quot;Complete Collection of Xia Chengtao&#39;s Diaries&quot; on September 8, 1953: &quot;I received a letter from Ji Si from Sun Yat-sen University, saying that he went to Beijing during the summer vacation and met He Qifang at the Qing family in Pujiang, Peking University. He said that the Institute of Liberal Arts of Peking University wanted to concentrate its efforts on compiling it within two or three years. The first draft of &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; was completed. Ji Si has been sent to work by CUHK for one year, and He Jun also wants to transfer me to participate in this work. Ji Si hopes that Yu can work for one or two years.&quot; September 30, 1955: &quot;Bu Kui Jiao came to the Song and Yuan parts of the literary history written by Ji Si. After reading and discussing the sections of Su, Mei, and European schools, there are many new ideas.&quot; December 24, 1957: &quot;Received from You Guoen, the editorial board member of the &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; of the Institute of Literature , He Qifang, and Yu Guanying wrote a chapter of &quot;The Rise of Ci&quot;, 8,000 words.&quot; May 25, 1958: &quot;Sent &quot;The Rise of Ci&quot; to Yu Guanying of Peking University in the afternoon. This comprehensive university textbook &quot;Literary History&quot; The first draft was supposed to be due in March, but it was two months overdue.&quot; This &quot;History of Chinese Literature&quot; was signed and edited by five people: You Guoen, Wang Qi (Wang Jisi&#39;s original name), Xiao Difei, Ji Zhenhuai, and Fei Zhengang. It was published in 1963. Published by People&#39;s Literature Publishing House, it is the history of Chinese literature textbook with the largest circulation in China for many years and the most widely circulated in Chinese departments of colleges and universities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Annotations on the Peach Blossom Fan will be published in February or March.&quot; &quot;The Peach Blossom Fan&quot; annotated by Wang Jisi and others was published by the People&#39;s Literature Publishing House in May 1958, and was newly published in April 1959. The first edition was included in the &quot;Chinese Classical Literature Reader Series&quot;, which had a profound influence and has been continuously reprinted to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[昌邑盐田：大自然的“调色盘”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259292]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南固始执法人员盗剪茅台高粱：执法者犯法彰显农业投资之难丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259324]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 22, the government of Sanhejian Town, Gushi County, Henan Province issued a notice confirming the participation of public officials The matter of stealing sorghum. Although the public officials involved have been detained by the police and may be subject to disciplinary action thereafter, the reflection on this incident cannot stop there. The top priority is for local governments to strictly protect the interests of foreign agricultural investors in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, a video shot by a drone spread online. In the video, a man wearing a hat and plainclothes is cutting sorghum ears with scissors, while a uniformed man stands not far away and watches. After discovering that they had been photographed, the two walked towards a parked vehicle nearby. The man wearing a hat put the bucket containing sorghum ears into the trunk of a family SUV and walked towards a car in front of him with the word &quot;Patrol&quot; painted on it and equipped with police lights. car. The men in uniform got into the family SUV and started the vehicle. The poster of the video questioned that law enforcement officers from Sanhejian Town drove people to steal sorghum in patrol cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the video attracted attention, Sanhejian Town government propaganda staff said in an interview with the media on October 22 that the uniformed person in the video was indeed a public official of the town, but he did not participate in pinching sorghum. He was filmed while patrolling to &quot;stop&quot; people from picking sorghum, which caused a &quot;misunderstanding.&quot; The publicist also said that in order to eliminate everyone&#39;s doubts, the public security organs have intervened in the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public security agency’s investigation results quickly slapped the propagandist in the face. A notice issued by the Sanhejian Town Government on the evening of the 22nd showed that after police investigation and verification, the uniformed person in the video was Yin Moumou, a staff member of the Sanhejian Town Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Brigade, and the other person was Zhang Moumou, a villager of Sanhuai Village. The two went to Gaoliang. The thieves cut sorghum ears on the ground; the two have been administratively detained by the police. Next, the Sanhejian Town Discipline Inspection Commission will seriously hold the party members and cadres involved accountable and deal with them in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public officials who are supposed to patrol to stop sorghum theft, drive patrol cars and lead people to cut sorghum and participate in the theft. It is really magical. What&#39;s even more magical is that after the incident was revealed, local officials immediately defended &quot;their own people&quot;, claiming that public officials were not involved in the theft, but to stop theft by the masses. If it hadn&#39;t been later verified by the police, many netizens might have truly believed this statement: Look, the person who stole the sorghum cuttings walked to the patrol car and was about to be taken back for questioning. The law enforcement officers drove away the car that stole the cuttings. There is absolutely nothing wrong with bringing back stolen goods, crime tools, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, they are not just facing netizens. Because the sorghum they stole was not ordinary sorghum. That is the local raw material production base of Moutai Group. As one of the most well-known brewing companies in China, Moutai Group has a high influence. In order to ensure the supply of brewing raw materials, Moutai Group has established raw material production bases in many places, and Gushi County in Henan is one of them. No matter where Moutai Group builds its raw material base, it will undoubtedly receive great attention from the local government. The Gushi County Government has set up a special Moutai organic raw material base construction office, which shows that the local government attaches great importance to this matter. Therefore, when the theft of sorghum cuttings attracted attention on the Internet, the local government would not dare to fool them. The public official literally hit the steel plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, even for agricultural projects that the local government attaches great importance to, public officials dare to participate in theft, which shows that theft of crops is common in the local area. Some netizens said that many local farmers have a large amount of sorghum drying in front of their homes, but they do not grow sorghum themselves. So where does the sorghum come from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant information released by Moutai Group, Moutai uses a specialized sorghum variety &quot;Hongyingzi&quot; for brewing. In Renhuai, Guizhou and other places, Moutai Group has purchased Hongyingzi sorghum at a protective price and will acquire it in 2022. The price is as high as 11.2 yuan/kg, much higher than the price of ordinary sorghum on the market. The sorghum grown at the Moutai raw material base in Gushi County is claimed to be organic sorghum, and its purchase price may be higher. Perhaps each thief may not steal too much, but if many people steal, it will cause huge losses to the growers. Perhaps this is why sorghum farming companies have to use drone patrols to detect and stop thieves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is a common problem faced by foreign agricultural investors. Just a few days ago, news broke out in Dancheng, Henan, that hundreds of farmers were robbing corn. News about people stealing peanuts, pumpkins, watermelons, and fish and shrimps emerged one after another across the country. These incidents all have one thing in common. Most of the people who steal things are local farmers, while those who are stolen are mostly people who transfer land for agricultural investment. Of course, there are also people who return to their hometowns to start agricultural businesses, and they are also stolen. After the incident, the local government often excused the local farmers by saying they were &quot;picking up&quot; crops that their owners had missed and discarded. But in fact, these so-called &quot;pickings&quot; often occur when growers are in the process of harvesting. The owner&#39;s harvesting machinery was still working, and the &quot;picker&quot; ran in front of the machine. Is there such a &quot;picker&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Allowing farmers to steal crops will not only harm the interests of investors, but may also cause serious injuries. Recently, there have been many incidents in which farmers were seriously injured or even killed by large harvesting machinery while &quot;picking up&quot; crops. Propaganda staff from Sanhejian Town in Gushi County also said in response to the media that patrols were organized considering that it might be unsafe for people to pick up sorghum during the sorghum harvest. As for the losses caused to growers by farmers stealing sorghum, the propagandist did not seem to care too much, &quot;Rural people just love to take advantage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is not a trivial matter that some farmers &quot;love to take advantage&quot;. The local government&#39;s &quot;harmony&quot; excuse for local farmers instead of safeguarding the interests of agricultural investors in accordance with the law undoubtedly embolden the thieves and makes agricultural investors feel disappointed. If things continue like this, who will dare to invest? Farmers who steal crops shall be subject to public security penalties and criminal penalties. Only in this way can this trend be stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, an urban management law enforcement team member from Sanhejian Town, Gushi County was arrested for stealing sorghum. He hit a large steel plate. The interests of small agricultural entrepreneurs should also be protected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[神舟十七号载人飞船发射取得圆满成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259342]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 11:46:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/451b72081ad4d31f5e60b2323543aa71.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height=&quot;1104&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/26/451b72081ad4d31f5e60b2323543aa71.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255595&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office, the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft successfully separated from the rocket and entered the predetermined orbit. The astronaut crew is in good condition and the launch was a complete success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the spacecraft enters orbit, it will conduct autonomous rapid rendezvous and docking with the space station assembly according to predetermined procedures. The astronaut crew of Shenzhou 17 will rotate in orbit with the astronaut crew of Shenzhou 16. While working and living on the space station, the Shenzhou 17 astronauts will conduct multiple extravehicular activities and carry out a large number of space science experiments involving basic microgravity physics, space material science, space life science, aerospace medicine, aerospace technology and other fields ( Test) and complete various tasks such as installation, commissioning, maintenance and repair of equipment inside and outside the cabin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mission is the second manned mission in my country&#39;s manned space program entering the space station application and development stage, and the 30th launch mission since the project was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the space station assembly has entered the docking orbit and is in good working condition, meeting the conditions for rendezvous and docking with the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft and the entry of astronauts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[昆明住烂尾楼的业主住房梦终圆，“别样的烂尾生活”画上句号]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259294]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun and her daughter Feifei walked on the new community trail.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b8d8232dd8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b8d8232dd8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun and her daughter Feifei walked on the brand new community trail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After paying the down payment and paying off the loan for more than nine years, Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping finally moved into their new home - starting from the suspension of work in 2014, they were located in Yunnan The house in Kunming has been unfinished for nearly nine years. The owners are still waiting for the good news. Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; can be handed over and moved into in January 2023, almost 8 years after the original delivery time of April 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun sat in the spacious and bright living room of her new home. In 2020, she was the first to move into a property that was unfinished at the time.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/16500e1cba.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/16500e1cba.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255496&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023, Chen Yanchun was sitting in the spacious and bright living room of her new home. In 2020, she was the first to move into a property that was unfinished at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ping and her daughter were in a beautifully decorated new house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f386496a1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/f386496a1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023, Liu Ping In a beautifully appointed new house with my daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong finally moved into his new home ten years after buying a house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/43516986f9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /43516986f9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong finally moved in ten years after buying a house My new home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, movers unloading trucks in &quot;A Different Kind of Happy City&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/72f37ac63a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/72f37ac63a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023,&quot; Movers unloading a truck in &quot;A Different Kind of Happy City&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The clock is turned back to May 2020. More than 40 owners have moved into their unfinished &quot;homes&quot; one after another after the houses have been unfinished for many years and the delivery is far away. They purchased some second-hand furniture, and some residents installed solar panels to power lights and chopped firewood for cooking in the house. The community has 12 buildings with 18 floors and a total of 1,243 residences. The neighborhood was once the location of Kunming Wujiaba Airport. According to the plan, the new Wujiaba area will be the future urban CBD center area of ​​Kunming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On August 24, 2020, as night fell, an owner of an unfinished building in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; lit up a lamp and stood in front of the window.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b77fb99a8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b77fb99a8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On August 24, 2020, as night fell, an owner of an unfinished building in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; lit up his lights and stood in front of the window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, less than half of the residents of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; are currently occupied.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/bc3f93d88d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25 /bc3f93d88d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; currently has less than Half of the residents are occupied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, when night falls, the lighting in the community turns on, which is completely different from the previous appearance without water and electricity.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7d5e2b95ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/7d5e2b95ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, night falls, the community’s The lights come on, which is completely different from before when there was no water or electricity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun&#39;s daughter Feifei looked in the mirror in a simple room with advertising plastic sheeting on the floor.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/9e036e4eed.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/9e036e4eed.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun’s daughter Feifei Looking in the mirror in a simple room, the floor of the room is covered with advertising plastic sheeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun&#39;s daughter Feifei finally moved into a beautifully renovated house.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/e4edb1596d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ e4edb1596d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun’s daughter Feifei finally moved into the beautifully decorated house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Yanchun was the first owner to live in an unfinished building at that time. She moved her several-year-old daughter into an empty building, spread plastic sheets on the ground, and planted vegetables in the open space outdoors. From time to time, she had to drive away wild dogs and other uninvited guests. Faced with her daughter&#39;s question &quot;When can I live in a beautiful house?&quot;, she could only cry helplessly. One after another, other owners saw that such a single mother could take her daughter to live in an unfinished building with nothing, and many desperate owners also moved in. Liu Ping is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun, the first owner to live in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, reclaimed a vacant land Vegetable patch.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f5e073b552.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f5e073b552.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Chen Yanchun, the first owner to live in Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, reclaimed a vegetable plot in the vacant land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun took her daughter for a walk in the community and picked vegetables. She placed several foam boxes in the open space below her home to grow vegetables.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6b494d0906.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6b494d0906.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 In October of this year, Chen Yanchun took her daughter for a walk in the community and picked vegetables. She placed several foam boxes in the open space below her home to grow vegetables. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong planted some plants in her new home.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e2a5060a19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/e2a5060a19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Liu Ruiqiong planted seeds in her new home picked up some plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, the owners are satisfied with the environment of the community that is no longer what it used to be.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/0eee253301.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ 0eee253301.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the environment of the community that is now different from the past makes the owners feel satisfy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Different Happiness City&quot; Plot 4 began construction in May 2013, and obtained a commercial housing pre-sale license in May 2014. Liu Ping paid a down payment to buy a 151-square-meter house. The monthly mortgage loan is close to 10,000 yuan. With the hard work of her and her husband, the pressure of repaying the loan is not too great. Later, the developer Kunming Xiaoan Demolition Management Co., Ltd.&#39;s capital chain broke, causing the project to be unfinished and unable to be delivered on time. It wasn&#39;t until 2017 that Liu Ping and his wife realized that the house was really in ruins. In June 2020, she moved into an unfinished house with her 11-year-old daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In August 2020, Liu Ping, the owner of Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, was cleaning up her room. Her room There is only a bed and a table.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/47b6ad4c44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/47b6ad4c44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2020, Liu Ping, the owner of Lot 4 of &quot;Different Happiness City&quot;, was cleaning up her room. Her room only has a bed and a table. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Liu Ping&#39;s daughter was doing homework in her room. There was a big white bear on the bed. This was her birthday gift.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/27c8434fde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/27c8434fde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 , Liu Ping&#39;s daughter was doing homework in her room, and there was a big white bear on the bed, which was her birthday gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, residents of &quot;Different Happy City&quot; walked their children in the recreational facilities provided by the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/be0e0ee3d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/be0e0ee3d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; Residents walk their children in the recreational facilities provided by the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, a child took a selfie in front of the stainless steel dolphin statue in the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/b3411b52b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ b3411b52b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, a child stood in front of the stainless steel dolphin statue in the community Selfie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 27, 2020, Guandu District Guan Guan Sub-district Office announced that after research, the &quot;Different Kind of Happy City&quot; No. 4 is scheduled to be launched at 9 o&#39;clock that day. The construction of the land is resumed and continued, and the house will be completed and handed over by the end of October 2021. In order to ensure construction safety and normal and smooth operation, the owners who have moved into Lot 4 are requested to actively cooperate in moving out of the construction site. Owners who do not have a place to move to the construction site due to living difficulties can promptly contact the sub-district office to apply for temporary transitional housing and handle transitional living matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun was chatting with other owners in the community and sunbathing.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/caf211e348.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/caf211e348. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yanchun was chatting with other owners in the community and sunbathing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, children played on the basketball court provided by the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; community.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7544031d16.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/7544031d16.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 10 In August, children played basketball on the basketball court provided by the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping and other owners who lived in unfinished buildings moved into the government&#39;s temporary resettlement housing without any fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, children played in the green square of the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/f69c707f85.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/f69c707f85.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, children in the community Play in the green square. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is understood that in order to properly resolve the historical issues left over from the &quot;Different Happy City&quot; project and to deal with claims and debts fairly and equitably, Kunming City, March 10, 2021 The Guandu District People&#39;s Court issued the (2021) Yun0111 Poshen No. 1 Civil Ruling, ruling to accept the bankruptcy reorganization of Xiaoan Company. Since Xiao&#39;an Company entered bankruptcy proceedings, the government has set up a special working group for the disposal of the &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; project to guide and coordinate Xiao&#39;an Company in carrying out bankruptcy proceedings and resumption of work and construction. With the support of state-owned enterprise mutual benefit bond funds and special loan funds for Guaranteed Delivery Buildings, the project fully launched the resumption of construction and construction in May 2021; at the end of November 2022, the main projects of the project were completed and the current housing delivery started; in January 2023, the project was completed After acceptance by five parties, water and electricity were officially connected, and the centralized delivery of houses started on January 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; will be handed over in early 2023, and some owners will move in one after another.&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/32bcbddeb4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/32bcbddeb4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255516&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 In October 2020, the &quot;Different Happiness City&quot; was handed over in early 2023, and some owners have moved in one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After taking over the house, Chen Yanchun and Liu Ping decorated the house and moved in smoothly. Liu Ping&#39;s ten-year mortgage was about to be paid off. &quot;My father finally came to live in his new home for two days before he died.&quot; Liu Ping told Southern Weekend reporters that her father passed away not long after he moved into her house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, two children holding balloons walked through the green square of the community.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/25/2a8d9c100f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ 2a8d9c100f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255517&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, two children holding balloons walked through the greenery of the community square. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[白领因午睡1小时被辞退：为什么只有中国人爱午睡？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259316]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[史地生化移出北京中考：如何理解“选拔”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259183]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many Beijing parents who have children who will take the high school entrance examination in 2025 and beyond have become uneasy recently. In the parent group Various analyzes and discussions. Because Beijing recently issued a new high school entrance examination plan, which will be applicable to students in eighth grade (second grade) this year. The main change is to move the primary four subjects of history, geography, chemistry, and biology out of the examination subjects. They will no longer be counted in the total score of the high school entrance examination. They will be changed into examination subjects, divided into four grades: A, B, C, and D. &quot;The results will be used for graduation.&quot; , for reference in further studies.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, the entrance exams (selective exams) and graduation exams (passing exams) for middle and high schools were separated. The former is the well-known high school entrance examination and college entrance examination. The scores of each subject are counted into the total score. High schools or universities are admitted from high to low according to the total score. The latter is called the Huikao, with passing scores (100 points for the paper-based test and 60 points for the paper-based test). Pass), if you pass the national examination in all subjects, you will obtain a junior high school or high school diploma. The HKCEE in the past was equivalent to the &quot;Academic Proficiency Examination&quot; today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now Beijing&#39;s Primary 4 Course of History, Geography, Biochemistry has been changed to grade-based grades. In essence, this Primary 4 subject has been changed from a selective subject in the high school entrance examination to a subject of a general examination nature. That&#39;s why &quot;the results are used for graduation&quot; &quot; said. As for &quot;use for reference in further studies&quot;, is it left to the high school to decide whether to use it or not, or is it to be used when two candidates have the same total score in the high school entrance examination, and there is no clear statement yet about who has a higher level than the primary four subjects. . The subjects that are still included in the total score of the high school entrance examination include: Morality and Rule of Law, Chinese, Mathematics, Foreign Languages, Physics, Physical Education and Health, a total of 6 subjects, of which Morality and Rule of Law will be changed to open-book examinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some parents think this change is good: there are fewer subjects that require high school entrance examinations, and the academic burden on their children is also reduced. This view needs to be looked at in two ways: If parents are not obsessed with their children entering a good high school, that is naturally correct; if parents still want their children to go to a prestigious school, then in the context of a 50-50 split, merit selection It is still inevitable that students will compete for the total score of the remaining six subjects. In order to increase the degree of differentiation, the difficulty of the questions in these six high school entrance examination subjects may be increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other parents disagree and believe that when there are many subjects, if the child cannot learn well in one or two subjects, it can be remedied and he can learn other subjects well. However, now the number of subjects in the high school entrance examination has been reduced. With four doors, there is no room for such remediation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latter believes that kicking the primary school students out of the high school entrance examination will be detrimental to Puwa, who has average qualifications. A netizen said that his distant cousin just took the high school entrance examination in Beijing this year and scored more than 80 points in the math test. She relied on the primary four subjects to get close to the perfect score to bring her total score up, and she was admitted to a city key point. But now this document has Come on, after 2025, children like her will basically have no chance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This view actually makes sense. For subjects like mathematics and physics, even if students memorize every definition, theorem and even every page in the book, it will not help if they do not understand the meaning and connotation. Ultimately, these subjects examine students’ logical thinking (abstract thinking) and pattern (structure, regularity) recognition abilities, which are the core of general intelligence. If you are not talented in this area, relying on experienced teachers to make up lessons may not necessarily have significant results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, in the primary four subjects of history, geography, biochemistry, history is classified as a liberal arts subject, and geography, biology, and chemistry are regarded as science subjects, but the latter are generally regarded as &quot;liberal subjects among science subjects&quot;, especially in junior high schools. At this stage, this Primary 4 exam mainly tests students&#39; memorization. Students with good memory or sufficient diligence will be able to pass the test perfectly and get high scores. Considering that merit-based examinations such as the high school entrance examination and the college entrance examination rank and select students&#39; intelligence and abilities, let subjects such as physics and mathematics remain within the scope of the high school entrance examination, and put Primary 4 subjects within the scope of the passing/standard examination. , is understandable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing wrote in the basic principles of the new high school entrance examination plan: &quot;Cultivate students&#39; scientific spirit, promote the training and selection of talents in basic subjects, and better utilize the role of examination enrollment in improving the quality of the people and serving the strategy of rejuvenating the country through science and education. &quot;It is a basic requirement for a &quot;qualified&quot; merit-based selection examination to allow students with outstanding talents and curiosity to explore the truth to stand out instead of being buried in a pile of high scores without distinction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are also issues worthy of discussion. For example, starting from 2025, Beijing will continue to include sports in the merit-based high school entrance examination, and the score will be increased from 40 points to 70 points. The Beijing Physical Education High School Entrance Examination in 2022 will be changed to a qualifying examination, and reaching the standard will mean full marks, which is a good attempt. Because athletic talent, like intellectual talent, is mainly innate. Sports schools want to select talents with athletic talent, and it is appropriate to conduct relevant merit-based examinations; if they want to go to high school, it is appropriate to conduct passing/standard examinations like Primary 4, otherwise it will affect the &quot;promotion of The goal of &quot;training and selecting talents in basic disciplines&quot; constitutes significant interference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most athletically gifted people and the most intellectually gifted people do not overlap very much. The two kinds of merit-based selection combined will lead to the following: the most athletically gifted and most intelligent people are likely not to go to the best high schools. On the contrary, one type of people will have an advantage: they are not the most outstanding in both talents but The combination is better, the family background is good, the parents are willing to invest, and the individual is willing to work hard. Changing sports to standard examinations can solve this problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media have reported on &quot;junior high school students in the gym.&quot; Parents apply for gym memberships for them and hire private teachers to give them one-on-one tutoring at a cost of several hundred yuan per hour, so that they can strive for the highest possible scores in the physical education high school entrance examination. This is already contrary to the original intention of sports to strengthen the body, and over-training of developing children in adolescence is counterproductive to physical health. There are many cases of knee wear and sports injuries among junior high school students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s high school entrance examination is often regarded as a benchmark. How it is modified may have an impact on the reform of high school entrance examinations in other places. Therefore, it is normal for everyone to be concerned, analyze and discuss a lot. How to take the test will determine how to teach and how to learn. How can the test and teaching truly match the original goals? This is worthy of continuous exploration and reflection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>