<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[再获雨果奖，中国科幻文学更进一步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259145]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of October 21, the 2023 Hugo Awards were announced at the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, with a total of 17 Hugo categories selected Awards and Category 2 non-Hugo Awards, Chinese writer Hai Miao won the Best Short Novella Award for &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot;. This is also the first time that the Hugo Awards are announced and awarded in China. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对李春生涉嫌受贿一案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259201]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on October 24 that the former deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress Li Chunsheng&#39;s suspected bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate of Hunan Province. Recently, the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chenzhou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Chunsheng of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant, and listened to the opinions of the defender. Prosecution charges: Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County in Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security and director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province and director of the Provincial Public Security Department, and deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress. , deputy director and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status, to seek benefits for relevant units and individuals in business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc., illegally accepting property from others, the amount is particularly huge, and should be legally accepted He will be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访经济学家吴晓求：“要把A股市场从融资市场转变为投资市场”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259197]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the Chinese capital market for more than thirty years, with more than 200 million investors and more than 5,300 listed companies, there is no A market that touches the nerves of all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Political Bureau meeting of the CPC Central Committee proposed “activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence.” The China Securities Regulatory Commission and other departments subsequently launched a package of policies for “active capital markets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges are the product of reform. They later underwent two historic reforms: shareholding split and registration system. But for a long time, every investor has suffered from short-term bullishness and bearishness. What loopholes have been left behind by the share-trading reform that once inspired the Long Bull market? How to fix blockage? What loopholes have arisen from the registration system? How to fix it quickly? How can the positioning of China&#39;s capital market mature through changes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of the 45th anniversary of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial industry, Wu Xiaoqiu, former vice president of Renmin University of China and director of the China Capital Market Research Institute, emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the establishment of the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges and the split of shares Reform and comprehensive registration-based reform are three monuments in the more than 30 years since the establishment of China&#39;s capital market. While they have achieved great success, they have also left some loopholes. These loopholes are the important institutional constraints that have caused the capital market to stagnate over the past decade. At present, regulatory authorities have realized and stepped up efforts to improve system design and plug loopholes. In the longer term, the main function of China&#39;s capital market is to transform from financing enterprises to a wealth management platform for investors, and from a financing market to an investment market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu is the youngest professor of economics in the history of Renmin University of China and the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in China. He has been engaged in securities teaching and research for more than 30 years. He led the compilation of the first edition of China Securities Practitioner examination materials. He is also the promoter and witness of many major reforms in the capital market, such as the share-trading reform and the registration system reform. He has made many suggestions for active capital markets. Among them, his consistent assertion that &quot;the time is not ripe for the implementation of the T+0 trading system&quot; is in line with the China Securities Regulatory Commission. The current stance is consistent. The &quot;Phaseically Tightened Securities Lending and Strategic Investors Placement and Lending of Shares&quot; notice issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission on October 14, 2023 is also related to the loopholes in the shareholding reduction rules and systems that Wu Xiaoqiu has been paying attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;569&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Xiaoqiu: former vice president of Renmin University of China; currently dean of the National Institute of Financial Research and China Capital Market Research Institute of Renmin University of China, national first-class professor, and executive director of the China Society for Finance and Banking . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Engaged in the economy&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Financial and Capital Market Research&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Forty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are a college student in the &quot;New Third Class&quot; (1977-1979). If the college entrance examination and reform and opening up had not been resumed, how would your life trajectory have evolved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I never went to high school. Before college, he worked as a carpenter and later as a secretary in the county commerce bureau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination and reform and opening up changed the destiny of my life, just as it changed the destiny of thousands of my contemporaries in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee was held in December 1978, but the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977. Putting the resumption of the college entrance examination before the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee, I think this is to prepare for reform and opening up in terms of ideology, talent, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination is a reform in itself. It is equivalent to a fundamental adjustment of the talent training system during the ten-year &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; period, bringing order to things. Looking back on the past, without reform and opening up, a key move that determines the fate of contemporary China, China would not be what it is today, and neither would I be what I am today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you apply for the national economics major of Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I initially applied for the philosophy major at Jiangxi University because I like philosophy. When my father found out, he asked me to change my major. He believes that he should study at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics. The major in national economic planning is very good and the economy may still be very important in the future. This change is also a &quot;decisive move&quot; for me personally. I later thought about my father&#39;s decision. He foresaw the future development direction of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my first year of college, I got to know Sun Yefang, Yu Guangyuan, Xu Dixin, Song Tao, Dong Fuzhen and other seniors. They are monuments in my mind. The dream of a scholar and the dream of an economist have been with me since I was in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the postgraduate entrance examination in 1983, I ranked second overall and was admitted to the National Economic Planning major of Renmin University of China. For the National Economic Planning major, Renmin University is a palace. Later, I studied for a Ph.D. and stayed at the school to teach after graduation, and I never left. I first did economic research for about 10 years. From 1993 to 1994, I officially switched to financial research and capital market research, which now has a history of almost 30 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;If you don&#39;t emancipate your mind, you can&#39;t find the right path to development&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of his studies (1983-1986), reform and opening up developed from rural areas to cities, urban economic system reform began, township enterprises began to sprout, and opening up to the outside world continued to expand. During this period, which reform events impressed you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four things that impressed me deeply: The first time was attending an economic system reform seminar in Chaohu, Anhui. In 1985, the central government issued the &quot;Decision on Economic System Reform&quot; and launched the economic system reform that combined planning and market. It was a historic decision. I was a second-year graduate student at the time, and my supervisor, Mr. Hu Naowu, and I attended this seminar. That was my first time to participate in a national, high-level forum. It touched me greatly and expanded my horizons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time was in 1985, when I participated in the Second Youth and Middle-aged Economic Forum held in Tianjin. The young people participating in the forum were active in thinking, participating in various debates, thinking about China&#39;s future, and exploring the focus of reform. I was writing an article about corporate bankruptcy. Bankruptcy is a thing of the market economy. There was no such thing as bankruptcy in China under the planned economy at that time, only &quot;shut down and transfer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time in 1985, I participated in a forum held in the Great Hall of the People. That forum was hosted by Mr. Dong Fucheng, and my speech attracted the attention of Li Chengrui, then director of the National Bureau of Statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth time was in 1986, when I participated in another discussion meeting on economic leverage in Leshan, Sichuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was only in my twenties at the time. It can be seen that that era gave young people many platforms and opportunities to speak freely at high-level forums held in the Great Hall of the People. This activates your mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were sparkling days, full of youthful dreams and pursuits of young people everywhere. Only when the mind is liberated can academics prosper and the country develop. Without emancipating our minds, we cannot find the right path to development. Everything must be explored, discussed and even debated before you know which is the right path. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Cracking the mystery of China&#39;s special economic phenomenon&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During your doctoral studies (1987-1990), the basic line of &quot;one center, two basic points&quot; and &quot;science and technology are the primary productive forces&quot; were proposed. In the meantime, what are your views on China’s economic reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most important thing when studying for a PhD is to learn advanced theories, study the Chinese economy, and how to solve the mystery of the special phenomena of the Chinese economy at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book that had the greatest impact on me at that time was &quot;The Economics of Shortage&quot; by the Hungarian economist János Korny. In the mid-to-late 1980s, many people read this work. &quot;Shortage Economics&quot; is a book that describes the basic characteristics of socialist economic operations under the traditional planned economic system. It is rich in strong theoretical logic, including soft budget constraints, paternalism, etc. Inspired by his thoughts, I started writing &quot;Theory of Compact Movement&quot; in 1987. &quot;The Theory of Tight Operation&quot; and my doctoral thesis &quot;Analysis of Socialist Economic Operation&quot; were published in 1991 and 1992 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did this book receive such special attention at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The real value of these two books is their attempt to explain the characteristics and laws of socialist economic operation under the traditional system. Because of these two books, as well as articles and papers published in People&#39;s Daily, Guangming Daily, Economic Research and Journal of Renmin University of China, I was promoted to professor by Renmin University in 1993. That year, Renmin University made an exception and promoted five professors, and I was the youngest among them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Transforming securities research and taking a road less traveled&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1994, you were transferred to the Department of Finance and Finance as a professor in the field of securities research in finance. The following year, you became the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in my country. Since then, you have been closely associated with China&#39;s securities industry. The relationship has been developing for thirty years. Why focus on securities research from now on? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was already studying finance at that time, so I offered to be transferred. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two opportunities: one is to alleviate poverty. In the early 1990s, I was about to become a professor and still lived in a Tongzi building with only 800 yuan in savings. At that time, someone gave me an idea, saying that you write a best-selling book, we will be responsible for selling it, and then give you a share. I thought of stocks and bonds. So I edited the &quot;Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, which contained about 5 million words in two volumes. It was a great seller as soon as it was launched. Later, I was given some money, and I got out of poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because I am the editor-in-chief, people ask me to speak. This forced me to really learn securities knowledge and securities investment. This has begun to deviate from the direction of my economics research, which is entirely the study of capital markets and finance. At that time, people did not think it was a science, and even thought it was a bit &quot;crooked&quot;. An important scholar among my predecessors once talked to me. The core idea was that I should return to the mainstream track of economic research such as economic operation analysis, macroeconomics, macroeconomic management and inflation theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The path of securities research was a sparsely traveled path at that time. There were few professional researchers, a lot of noise, and very little rational research. But in my opinion, the more in-depth securities research is, the more valuable it is. I am one of the few people left who has done research in the early stages and is still doing front-line research now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then president of Renmin University, Mr. Huang Da, was a professor in the Department of Finance, so I applied to go to the Department of Finance. I taught a course on securities investment. At that time, there were not many securities investment courses offered in colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I first entered the stock market both for making money and for research&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There was a movie called &quot;Stock Crazy&quot; in 1994, which tells the story of the various crazes caused by mass speculation in the stock market in the early days of the stock market. Was the stock market back then really like in the movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; (The craze for stock trading) has indeed begun. The stock market has begun to enter people&#39;s lives, more and more people are investing in the stock market, and various theories, methods and stock reviews have begun to appear. Because I wrote &quot;The Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, I also started doing research on it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a research expert on securities investment, what will happen to you? Is stock trading practical? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was only after 2000 that I really entered the stock market as an investor. After entering, I found that practice was more profoundly helpful to my theoretical research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the difference between securities research and stock trading? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My goal in entering this market is not only to make money, but also to do research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set two goals for myself at that time: first, not to lose money, and to see through practical operations whether what I learned theoretically would work in practice; second, to establish a direct perceptual understanding of the research object. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, I understand the rules of securities investment and the market better. When I write textbooks, I will be more enriched and my writing will be more vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period, I presided over the compilation of the first set of teaching materials for the securities practitioner qualification examination in China. The first edition consisted of six volumes. The general structure of the later textbooks compiled by the China Securities Regulatory Commission did not deviate from this edition. It plays a very important role in the qualification examination for securities practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the expectations of making money been met? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I also wanted to catch the bull market and make a fortune. The first one I remember was buying Sichuan Changhong, and one day I suddenly discovered that it was going up quite well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;The loopholes left over from the split-share structure reform must be closed &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once said that China’s capital market has three monuments: Shanghai The establishment of the Shenzhen Stock Exchange, the share-trading reform, and the pilot registration system. What have you been involved in promoting? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I participated in the share-trading reform and promoted the pilot registration system. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. However, since the theoretical preparation failed in 2001 when the reduction of state-owned shares failed, we began to think about how to carry out share-trading reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did the reduction of state-owned shares fail in 2001? What inspiration did it provide for the subsequent share-trading reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, the regulatory agency believed that the reduction of state-owned shares could be reduced at market price, but it was hastily stopped due to the huge market reaction. Later analysis concluded that reducing state-owned stocks based on market prices lacked both logic and theoretical support, so it was bound to fail. As a result of this failure, we were reflecting on how to promote split-share reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period of reflection, the academic community organized many discussions, and I was probably one of the people who participated the most, whether in small-scale discussions hosted by the China Securities Regulatory Commission or in large-scale discussions. I participated in almost every discussion. Among them, the most impressive one was when Shang Fulin, then chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, called me one day in 2004 and discussed with me alone how to change the split share structure. Later, I went to his office many times to participate in discussions, with about ten people in a small group and twenty or thirty people in a large group. After discussion, we reached a consensus on two points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first point is that the split share structure reform must be promoted. If we do not promote the reform, China&#39;s capital market will have no future. This is what I also emphasize; the second point is what method should be used to reform the split-share structure reform. The design of this path is very difficult. We slowly considered that consideration reform is appropriate. Consideration reform is only a direction. It becomes more difficult to determine the appropriate consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I clearly remember that during a meeting of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, Tu Guangshao, then vice chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, asked me, what do you think is the appropriate proportion of the consideration? I said 30% or 30% off, because the price of additional issuance of stock is 30% off the circulating price. This provides a reference for the consideration of the share-trading reform. Later, practice proved that the consideration plans for the share-trading reform of various listed companies fluctuated around 30% off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the early days of the share-trading reform in 2005, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets did not Too big a reaction. The big bull market seems to have started only after 2005. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. At that time, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets had been in the doldrums for more than four years since 2001, and the market response was lukewarm. Later, the market gradually learned that this thing was serious, and more and more people had a premonition that this was an opportunity for a big bull market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We judged at that time that the long bear market in the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets would be reversed during the share-trading reform process. After the reform is completed, it will lay a good foundation for the long-term healthy development of the capital market. From today&#39;s perspective, the general direction of the share-trading reform is correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The share-trading reform took about two years. What shortcomings does it have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From May 2005 to March 2007, 95% of listed companies completed the share-trading reform. It is a monument, but it does have flaws. This flaw is the lack of effective constraints on the reduction of major shareholders and actual controllers. This policy loophole had an important impact on the subsequent stagnation of the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets for more than ten years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have also said recently that the most important thing that seriously restricts the development of China’s capital market is the institutional design of the asset supply side. Among them, the asset supply side is mainly the reduction rules of existing assets, which is the actual Controllers and controlling shareholders do not have financial constraints to reduce their holdings, which makes it difficult for the market to grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you think this loophole is being fixed now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On August 27, 2023, there have been some amendments in the China Securities Regulatory Commission policy. This is a loophole left by the share-trading reform, and we must make up for it. Because it seriously damages the ecological chain of capital supply and demand in the capital market and causes a serious imbalance in the capital supply relationship. At present, major loopholes are being patched, so at least we know where they are. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Registration reform has had mixed effects”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The third monument you mentioned in China’s capital market is the registration-based reform. Why start the registration system reform? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After 2007, the theoretical research, or policy formulation, that I participated in was mainly the registration system reform. Why should we carry out registration reform? Because the approval system has major flaws. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the biggest problem with the approval system is that the choice of listing a company is not left to the market, but to the Issuance Review Committee and to visible hands. The second problem is that the pricing is not market-oriented, so there is a strange phenomenon of 20 daily limit after listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third problem is that the regulatory body and the auditing body are not separated. The China Securities Regulatory Commission both audits and supervises. This is of course problematic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the fact that the approval system has at least these three problems, if we want to correct these three defects, we must carry out the registration system reform. In accordance with the principle of marketization, the exchange adopts a flexible system, and at the same time does not adhere to the requirement that companies to be listed must be profitable. Compared with the approval system, which requires companies to be listed to be profitable for three consecutive years, one of the biggest innovations of the registration system is that major high-tech companies that are planning to be listed are allowed to have losses in the past three years, but they must have sustainable operating capabilities. This is a major change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 is the first year of the comprehensive registration system reform. As a promoter and policy participant of the registration system reform, are you satisfied with the current results of the reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Bittersweet. Fortunately, some unicorn companies and high-tech companies have become listed companies through this mechanism. Although they are losing money in the short term, they have the ability to operate sustainably. The registration system reform naturally serves specialized and high-tech innovative enterprises, and is naturally coupled with high-tech enterprises. Only under the registration system can technology and capital markets be coupled, and we will still work in this direction in the future. I think this is of great value and significance to us in promoting the development of high-tech enterprises, transforming my country&#39;s industrial structure and upgrading and iterating industries, improving the structure of listed companies, and enhancing the investment value of China&#39;s capital market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is worrying is the generalization of the definition of loss in the registration system. This is a serious misunderstanding, which damages market confidence and is not in line with the original meaning of the registration system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why does this vulnerability occur? What are the dangers of this vulnerability? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Like the share-trading reform, the registration-based reform also has a loophole. Frankly, no one realized it at the time. Just like designing a spacecraft, there are a lot of details and a lot of sparse details. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The loophole of the registration system is that it generalizes the market-oriented functions, or it generalizes the indicators that listed companies do not strictly require profitability. So later, some listed companies seized on such a loophole and established a so-called high-tech enterprise. Under the banner of the so-called &quot;breaking the bottleneck project&quot;, they hired dozens of researchers and started to apply for IPO after two or three years. . This has done huge damage to market confidence. They do not comply with the basic spirit of the registration system, and also exceed the requirements of the risk boundaries that a public market, exchange market, and public investors can bear. The financing of this type of enterprise should mainly be completed by PE and VC, and direct IPO is not allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I define this loophole as: a generalized understanding of the non-profit requirement under the registration system. This is a very serious misunderstanding, which is closely related to the subsequent stagnation of the stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this vulnerability currently being patched? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I once made it clear to the China Securities Regulatory Commission that the requirement that companies to be listed be unprofitable cannot be generalized. Judging from the recent IPO situation, the China Securities Regulatory Commission and exchanges have also paid special attention to the listing requirements of companies with negative financial indicators, especially those with negative net assets, negative cash flow, and negative profits. These major financial reporting indicators are all negative, and such companies cannot be listed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fixing the loopholes, the registration system reform is completed What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Far from it. The registration-based reform is an all-round, whole-chain reform. The market-oriented reform of the issuance system is only its historical and logical starting point. It will also be followed by transactions, mergers and acquisitions, information disclosure, supervision, delisting, penalties for violations and illegal acts, legal models, etc. Adjustments in many other aspects must be incorporated into the model compatible with the registration system reform and continuously improved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;Twin Peaks model is the ideal compromise&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2022, you proposed the &quot;twin peaks model&quot; of China&#39;s financial system. What are the deep observations and thoughts behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Frankly speaking, the first thing I proposed was the &quot;single bee mode&quot;. Around 2002, I believed that China’s future financial model would be dominated by the capital market. Twenty years have passed, and I have found that the &quot;single bee model&quot; is very difficult to achieve in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, in the past 20 years, the scale of China&#39;s capital market has expanded relatively rapidly. From a market capitalization of two to three trillion in the past to a market capitalization of more than eighty trillion today, its proportion in the financial system has increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, I finally realized that China’s commercial banks play a huge role in China’s economic life, and China can only implement the bimodal model-the banking system and the capital market jointly dominate. This is an ideal compromise and a realistic situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is it difficult for the capital market to become dominant? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The development of the capital market has not changed the dependence of the Chinese economy on money and credit. From the perspective of the capital market itself, the stock prices of listed companies have not increased in the past 20 years, and the market index has not increased. Only the market value has expanded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the number of listed companies has increased from 1,000 to more than 5,300 in the past 20 years. Almost China’s largest and best companies have achieved IPOs, including many state-owned enterprises and central enterprises. and “unicorn” companies. In a sense, the function of China&#39;s stock market in facilitating enterprise financing has been realized, but it itself is a pie-spreading expansion, constantly expanding outwards without intensive cultivation, and the unit output rate of enterprises after obtaining financing is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is our index not growing? A very important reason is to go back to the two loopholes I just mentioned, especially the first loophole, which is the reduction rule, which has a huge inhibitory effect on growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China’s stock market&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Why&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is still immature&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our capital market has developed for more than 30 years. At the age of thirty, can it be considered a mature market? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China’s capital market has slowly found a basic direction in practice and reform, but it is still an immature market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first immaturity is that there are many loopholes in the system design. The second immaturity lies in the lack of a deep understanding of what the capital market means to China and what it means to financial reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, we often said that the main purpose of establishing the stock market was to facilitate corporate financing. This is an incorrect positioning and perception. The securities market appears to be financing, but is actually investment. If you don’t continuously strengthen your investment function, financing will be unsustainable, and people will vote with their feet. If you leave, how can you raise funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we need to transform China’s capital market from a financing market that facilitates corporate financing to a wealth management platform and investment market for investors. Transforming from a financing market to an investment market is our future direction. It will take a long time to achieve this goal. For institutional effects to take effect, it will take time for corresponding institutional arrangements to be put in place. Our current institutional arrangements are closing loopholes and moving closer to this aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A-shares are bullish and bearish. The main problem is the loopholes in the system design and Don’t really understand the significance of the capital market to financial reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The reason for this phenomenon in China’s capital market is not only the profound cultural and legal background, but also the misalignment of rules at the meso level. For example, there are two loopholes in the share-trading reform and the registration-based reform mentioned earlier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, part of the reason is that our entrepreneurs do not have a deep understanding of what listing means to them. Originally, going public was a means, but these company founders suddenly discovered that it was so easy to make a fortune by going public, which was much easier than working hard in the real economy. This corroded their original intention to start a business in the past. He will take listing as his goal and stop doing the real economy. He will find a way to cash out and leave as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To correct this misdirection, we can only guide it through institutional reform - only by doing a good job can you cash out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What specific suggestions do you have for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To achieve a fundamental transformation of the functions and orientation of the capital market, the first step is to transform the overall macro-system design. On the asset supply side, the system design must be conducive to the transformation of market functions, the introduction of transparent and growth-producing assets into the market, and the attraction of more and more new investors and the entry of new funds into the market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, we should have certain restrictions on all pre-listing shareholders reducing their shareholdings, especially controlling shareholders and actual controllers, including second shareholders, third shareholders, etc. How to use Financial indicators constrain shareholding reductions and require innovative system designs to allow all shareholders to focus their attention and efforts on how to do a good job in the company, create profits, and improve distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, we must continue to improve the ecological environment of the capital market. Whether institutional investors or individual investors, in this market, they can obtain returns commensurate with their risks, and only then will the market grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The stock market continues to not improve, and we need to come up with the right response&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of July, the central government clearly proposed to &quot;activate the capital market.&quot; What signal does this send? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It should be said that the supervisory authorities have seen the problem. No field in China covers such a large scope as the capital market. There are at least 200 million investors in the capital market, and behind them may be 200 million families. Almost half of the people in China have something to do with the capital market. Second, although the global capital markets have gone through the epidemic, China&#39;s capital markets among major economies have not performed well. We need to pay more attention to the problems behind it. Third, activating the capital market is also an important measure to boost market confidence. We need to come up with the right response. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are also many expert suggestions for activating the capital market A shares switch from T+1 to T+0. But regulators have long said the opportunity is premature. What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The transaction reform has no substantive significance, T+0 is not conducive to the growth of the market, and the logical basis of the T+0 reform is unclear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the biggest benefit of T+0 is to securities companies. T+0 will directly lead to an increase in brokerage commissions, thereby driving the rise of brokerage stocks. The goal of our reform is not to make securities companies prosperous, and the original intention of activating the capital market is not to increase commissions. An increase in commissions will instead mean the leakage of capital market funds. As for what some people say that T+0 has a correction mechanism for market prices, I think more empirical research is needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the trading rules based on T+1 were chosen in the early days of the birth of China’s capital market and against the background of many trials and errors of trading rules. After more than 30 years of practice, they have become very mature and more Suitable for China&#39;s national conditions. I like the T+1 system very much.上午买的股票，为什么一定下午就要卖呢？既然下午要卖，那你上午就别买。逻辑是很清楚的。如果说买错了，那明天卖也是一样的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，T+1制度也不是中国独有，国际上也是很成熟的。不见得有些国家用T+0，我们也用。从我个人来说，不太喜欢T+0，因为这个制度会把人们搞得癫狂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末：你对中国股市有信心吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴晓求:中国股市好起来的前提是中国经济要好起来。我一直说中国经济只要想搞好，是一定能搞好的。从本质上说，中国经济基础是好的。只要发挥市场的主导作用，适应历史的趋势，遵守市场规律，尊重企业和企业家精神，推动改革开放，走市场经济之路，中国经济就一定能搞好，怎么可能搞不好？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下中国经济的问题，主要不是周期性因素带来的。我一直坚信，只要把过去45年改革开放中被证明是成功的经验坚持下去，进一步完善，中国经济就能继续保持良好趋势，中国资本市场也就有了成长基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：已缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259195]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在今天（24日）上午国务院新闻办公室的举行“权威部门话开局”系列主题新闻发布会上，公安部有关负责人介绍，今年8月以来，全国电信网络诈骗案件发案数、造成财产损失数同比分别下降24%、20.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照公安部统一部署，各地公安机关持续强化打击力度，深入开展“云剑”“断卡”“断流”“拔钉”等专项行动，截至今年9月底，缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名；联合最高人民检察院挂牌督办一批重大案件，公开曝光一批典型案例；围绕境内打击，持续组织开展区域会战、专案攻坚、集群战役，密切与各部门协作配合，严厉打击引流推广、转账洗钱、技术开发等犯罪团伙，坚决切断犯罪关键链条，坚决遏制电信网络诈骗犯罪高发态势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部坚持关口前移、防范为先，采取多种防范措施，最大限度预防案件发生。指导各地公安机关建立分级分类预警劝阻机制，推动“厦门经验”在全国落地生效。今年以来，累计向各地推送预警指令3.1亿条，各地自主产出预警信息1.3亿条；会同工业和信息化部建成12381涉诈预警劝阻短信系统，累计发送预警提示短信、闪信6.4亿条；会同中央网信办建设推广国家反诈中心App，累计预警提示1578.5万次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公安部联合中央宣传部开展主题为“预警劝阻别忽视，财产安全要重视”的“全民反诈在行动”集中宣传月活动。其间，国家反诈中心发布《2023版防范电信网络诈骗宣传手册》；会同相关行业主管部门督促金融机构、电信业务经营者、互联网服务提供者对本行业从业人员及服务对象深入开展反诈宣传；联合中国老龄协会举办全国老年人防诈反诈知识竞赛；联合教育部启动“反诈宣传进校园”活动；联合中国电影集团在全国农村地区和中小学校园组织反诈优秀影片公益展映活动，持续掀起全民反诈、全社会反诈的新热潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[情侣住酒店被偷拍勒索：应大力查办暗黑产业链丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259191]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;情侣住酒店一年后收到亲密视频，到店拆开吊灯发现摄像头竟然还在，令人细思极恐。住酒店被偷拍，酒店应该承担什么责任？偷拍屡禁不绝，背后的产业链又该如何铲除？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据广西电视台日前报道，南宁胡先生近日收到一年前和未婚妻住酒店时的亲密视频，到店后发现吊灯里隐藏的两个摄像头竟然还在。而酒店经理称，他们也是受害者，排查其它房间没有异样，只愿退还房费。这一报道在网上引起了极大关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;住酒店被偷拍的新闻屡屡出现。在某搜索引擎搜索“酒店偷拍”可以搜出几千万条相关信息。近期的新闻，除了上文中提到外，还有江苏连云港、湖南娄底等地都有出现。几年前河南郑州某酒店负责人甚至声称80%的酒店都有偷拍摄像头。其实，偷拍不止出现在酒店，服装店试衣间、写字楼厕所，甚至连动车洗手间里都发现了隐藏的摄像头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些隐藏的摄像头，严重侵犯了他人的隐私，毫无疑问是违法犯罪行为。如果是酒店私自安装了摄像头，酒店当然要承担责任。但如果是其他人在酒店不知情的情况下偷偷安装的，酒店需要承担责任吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的情况确实不少。据业内人士称，坏人可以伪装成客人住酒店，每次只要十几分钟就可以把摄像头装好，然后以各种理由换房间，一次就能偷装几个房间。在连云港酒店发现摄像头案件中，警方抓获的犯罪嫌疑人是无业人员，并非酒店员工。最高检2022年发布的一个指导性案例中，犯罪分子也是在多家酒店的客房内偷偷安装摄像头偷拍的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种情况下，难道真的像南宁那家酒店的经理所称，他们也是受害者，不需要对客人被侵害承担责任？当然不是，旅客入住酒店，当然是把酒店房间视为私密场所，对自己在房间里的隐私具有合理期待，酒店应该对客人的隐私尽到合理的保障义务。客人被偷拍，被侵犯隐私，与酒店没有尽到安全保障义务有脱不了的关系。而南宁这家酒店，一年多后摄像头还在，可见其多么疏于管理。出现偷拍事件，酒店除了要停业整顿，也要对客人进行赔偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店有义务保障客人的隐私。其实，现在市面上已经有专门针对针孔摄像头的便携式检测仪器，酒店只要给保洁或者保安人员配备一套，就可以在短时间内查出大多数隐藏的摄像头。这样做需要的成本并不高，关键是反偷拍要像打扫卫生一样，成为酒店行业标准，成为每家酒店都要做的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店偷拍之所以屡禁不绝，还因为其背后有一条黑色的产业链。犯罪分子偷拍视频，并不是为了刺激，而是会把这些偷拍的视频放到暗网等非法网站去售卖。一些网站、社交账号打着“酒店偷拍”等旗号，吸引用户付费观看隐私视频。整个偷拍的黑色产业，每年可能有上千亿元规模。在前述最高检发布的指导案例中，犯罪分子就通过非法网站、即时通讯软件等发布信息贩卖偷拍的隐私视频。 2021年，辽宁警方也打掉了一条利用隐蔽摄像头在酒店偷拍、直播获利的黑色产业链。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了到暗网售卖，还有人利用拍到的隐私视频敲诈勒索。 2022年底，湖南娄底一名女子在酒店被偷拍后，就有人把视频发给她然后勒索钱财。这次广西南宁的胡先生收到偷拍视频，对方也很可能并不是好心提醒他被偷拍了，也有很大的可能是要对其敲诈勒索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于偷拍行为必须加大打击力度。在各种通讯账号都实行实名制的当下，警方要找到犯罪分子应该并不太难。对于发信息敲诈勒索的，警方可以通过发信息的账号找到勒索者，然后顺藤摸瓜，查清勒索者是如何获得视频，以及客人的联系方式等隐私信息的，将整个链条都打掉，同时也可以查清酒店是否存在泄露客人隐私的问题。毕竟，就算犯罪分子偷偷安装摄像头，没有酒店的内鬼，也很难知道客人的联系方式，是没有办法敲诈勒索的。只找到偷拍摄像头的，警方也有手段找到安装者。连云港酒店的摄像头、天津某写字楼女厕的摄像头，警方都很快就抓到了犯罪嫌疑人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对猖獗的偷拍，一方面警方要加大对黑色产业链的打击力度。对偷拍偷录设备也要加强管理。现在网络上随处可以买到各种微型隐蔽摄像头，还有各种摄像头破解、漏洞利用等教学视频，这些都助长了偷拍的泛滥。酒店行业也应该制定标准，把反偷拍摄像头等纳入行业的日常管理中，尽最大可能保护客人的隐私安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“毛孩子”上幼儿园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVA PLvRo1Tt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Two &quot;students&quot; participated in the agility game course in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an autumn afternoon, three pet dogs of different types participated in games under the guidance of their dog trainers. Balance boards, skateboards, number recognition, toy sorting...these adaptive and educational games are part of the Beijing Cute Pet Hotel (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as It is part of the pet kindergarten teaching system offered by &quot;Cute Beast School&quot;. In addition, there are courses such as swimming, sniffing and desensitization. Kindergarten care hours are from 8 am to 8 pm every day. In addition to classes, dogs can also enjoy services such as nutritious meals, lunch breaks, bathing, hair care and massage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; is two and a half years old this year. Its &quot;parents&quot; are a couple born in 1995. They love traveling and send &quot;Fat Tiger&quot; to a pet hotel for a few days every month &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three dogs participating in the game class entered the classroom one after another. They were the Shiba Inu, the Poodle and the Samoyed. At the beginning of the course, when they saw the stranger taking pictures with the camera, the three students immediately gave different feedback: the little Shiba Inu focused on the handler&#39;s commands; the poodle kept barking while tentatively approaching the stranger, and the course was unable to do so for a while. The Samoyed also noticed the presence of the camera and tried to get closer in a friendly manner. When the dog trainer gave the instruction, it immediately returned to the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; participates in the educational game class in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; experiences the cute beast theater in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dogs also have their own personalities. You can see that the three of them are completely different. This has nothing to do with their body shape. It is determined by genes first and is related to their growth experience. Poodles are very vigilant. In fact, they are very vigilant. It&#39;s not to attack you, it&#39;s just to scare you - &#39;Don&#39;t come here, don&#39;t hurt me, I&#39;m very fierce, listen to how loud I scream&#39;, but in fact this just reflects its timidity and sensitivity. The other two They can only focus on their own things, which shows that they are well socialized, can regulate their own behavior, do not affect others, and are very confident and brave when facing new things.&quot; Li, the founder of Cute Beasts Chen analyzed the students&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been almost five years since Mengzhupai opened its kindergarten, during which time it experienced the COVID-19 epidemic and its business almost stagnated. Starting from the beginning of 2023, Li Chen found that the demand for pet foster care and kindergarten attendance had “exploded.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sister Wang and 9-year-old &quot;Coffee Bean&quot; are in the cute animal party. This is the fifth year that Coffee Bean has come to kindergarten &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Young pet-raising groups are interested in The acceptance of kindergartens has suddenly increased. They will not sacrifice their lifestyle (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;socializing, business trips, travel, etc.&lt;/span>;) The price is to raise a dog - I have my life, you have your life. I do my best to make your life colorful, send you to school, and make you live a full and happy life every day. It does not need to be just Wait for me at home. I will be very calm when I go out and don’t have to feel guilty. I always feel that the dog has only one thing in his life, which is to wait for me at home.” Li Chen believes that with the progress of society and the changes in the thinking of pet owners, Nowadays, pet owners are no longer concerned about whether their pets are eating imported dog food, but also about the mental health of their pets - whether you are happy today. Dogs also need their own spiritual world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The slogan of the kindergarten is &quot;Let dogs be dogs again&quot;. Through many courses, training is provided to help them regain their instincts as animals, such as sniffing, hunting and swimming, and enhance the dogs&#39; confidence and physical fitness. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;San San’s mother took her 4 adopted elderly dogs to the cute animal party for a birthday party&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Chen, the current kindergarten parents are mainly those born in the 1980s and 1990s. They are not all middle-class or white-collar workers from well-off families, but they are very willing to give to &quot;hairy children&quot; Spend money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only young people, but some elderly people also spend a lot of money to create a healthy and comfortable life for their &quot;hairy children&quot;. Li Chen calls it &quot;a step-by-step relationship.&quot; She hosted a retired couple who regularly visited their daughter out of town every year. During the two or three months away from Beijing, they adopted two Chuan Chuan children (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hybrid breed dog&lt;/span>;) and put it here with Li Chen. &quot;In their eyes, pets are the same as family members.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;254457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Three huskies are waiting in the restaurant&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coffee Bean is a teddy dog ​​who is 9 years old this year. Sister Wang remembers the first time after she went to kindergarten, the clerk dropped it off, turned around and left, with the coffee beans still chasing her. &quot;The dog&#39;s reaction was very real. From then on, I knew that they must be good to Doudou.&quot; This is the fifth year that Coffee Bean has come to the kindergarten. From the beginning, no one could touch him and he would bark when he saw people. Now he often pretends to be Doudou. Cuteness attracts the attention of those around you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister Wang and her husband are from the DINK tribe. She “raises coffee beans as sons” and never hesitates to spend money on them. Whenever there is an event in the store, Sister Wang always thinks about renewing the fee. Li Chen saw the sufficient balance on her card and always advised her to spend rationally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Cheng used to love traveling and buying bags, but now she spends all the money she has saved on 90,000 yuan, which is about 4,000 to 5,000 yuan a month. Taking Jiuwan out for fun every week has turned Xiaocheng from a homebody into an outdoor expert who is familiar with pet-friendly places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3-year-old &quot;Fifteen&quot; enjoys a pet birthday cake&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Three years ago, Xiao Cheng’s son was born. She felt that raising dogs and raising children each had their own advantages, but raising children was definitely more difficult, and 90,000 yuan brought her only happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding some news about uncivilized dog-raising circulating on the Internet, Xiao Cheng believes that it should not be a confrontation between dog-raising and non-dog-raising, but a confrontation between civilized dog-raising and uncivilized dog-raising. &quot;Dog owners must first do their best: leash, pick up poop, walk the dog at different times, and avoid pedestrians - especially the elderly and children. I also understand that some people are naturally afraid of dogs, so stay away from each other. We all understand each other about waiting for an extra elevator.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 254455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Bottle&quot; (top) finishes swimming and enjoys a snack at the pet restaurant. More than three years ago, &quot;Milk Bottle&quot; was picked up from the road by its current owner &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;At the beginning of the creation of Cute Beasts, Li Chen designed a space of nearly 300 square meters on the second floor into an audio-visual room to meet the needs of owners and dogs to watch movies together, and it was open to members free of charge. This plan was questioned by some shareholders at the time, who believed that it was a waste in terms of profitability. But Li Chen had his own ideas. Although some pet-themed movies would be reserved, the speakers in the theater were designed for humans and were not suitable for dogs&#39; hearing systems. &quot;I hope to provide owners and pets with a diversified choice, even if it meets some very niche needs, but there is no way to experience it elsewhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This The huskies are being frightened - screening out and weeding out dogs who tend to be overly fearful, aggressive or overly excited about running, screaming, overly enthusiastic people. This test simulates situations that therapy dogs may encounter in service facilities, minimizing safety hazards. Dogs that pass the assessment are trained and have the opportunity to come to serve special groups (the elderly, autistic children, etc.)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the past six years, Li Chen has been surrounded by some controversy, mainly questioning that she treats relatively high-end and niche services as a gimmick, and that the form is greater than the content. &quot;Actually, most of our services are very urgent, and some may be relatively advanced, but they are scientific and I believe they are also in line with future development trends. Pet services face the needs of different customers, so they must provide different services. There is no unified standard answer to the choice, and there is no need to have one,&quot; Li Chen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the 2022 COVID-19 epidemic, Cute Beasts assisted the Chaoyang District Government of Beijing in the centralized transportation of pets, and immediately converted the store into a pet shelter, which alleviated the problem of pet placement during the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ninety Wan&quot; takes swimming lessons in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Li Chen still vividly remembers the large-scale transfer in Nanxinyuan Community. More than 120 pets, mostly dogs, but also cats, rabbits, turtles and chickens, were pulled back one by one for transfer. For two whole days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the normal operation, pets must be evaluated for foster care: age, underlying diseases, and whether they are aggressive... But that time there was no choice, time was tight, and the owner gave his contact information on the spot. The pet and the basic information are written on a piece of paper. The staff puts the paper and the pet together to take a photo, and the registration is completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The foster care rooms on the first floor of the Animal Pet Hotel all have independent yards. In order to avoid separation anxiety, some owners will bring their pets’ toys or cushions at home to help them adapt to the new environment as soon as possible &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Back in the store, Li Chen and the store staff managed different categories of pets, and tried their best to send the latest photos and videos of the pets to the owners to appease their emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Trust was not established at the beginning. Some owners saw the video and said that although they looked similar, they could tell from the expression that this was not my dog. It doesn&#39;t matter, we will take 10 more pictures of him. Video, let him look for feelings or expressions to judge whether it is his own dog. In the first three days, we received calls from owners every day, some questioning, some crying, and some cursing. On the fourth day, everyone I started to believe that you really placed my dog ​​with you, so I started to buy food and supplies for us online to express my gratitude.&quot; This experience gave Li Chen a deeper understanding and understanding of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kindergarten photo wall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isolation At the end of the period, these more than 120 pets returned to their owners intact after undergoing nucleic acid tests one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since starting a pet hotel, Li Chen has seen countless dogs and witnessed many touching stories: During the swimming class, the dog did not dare to go into the water, but when its owner &quot;fell&quot; into the pool, it jumped into the water to save him regardless of his own safety. ; If there are pregnant women or children at home, the dog would rather not go to the toilet by itself when walking the dog, but also make sure that the owner is within his sight and not let strangers approach...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烈犬伤童事件后，“失焦”的多地捕狗风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259173]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A Guangzhou resident is walking his dog. There is a sign on the side of the road &quot;Walking your dog on a leash&quot; , civilization will not lose its link.&quot; Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A Guangzhou resident was walking his dog. There was a sign on the roadside, &quot;Walking your dog on a leash, being civilized and keeping the leash on&quot;. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t say that we beat dogs, we really have never beaten them.” On October 20, 2023, Zhang Yong was a little nervous when talking about the recent public opinion about dog hunting, and emphasized that they were civilized law enforcement. , the entire process was recorded with a law enforcement recorder and recorded in the ledger. &quot;It must be ensured that they are all alive and cannot be damaged.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director of the Publicity Unit of the Urban Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau of Saihan District, Hohhot City is worried about the public opinion that a Rottweiler dog bit a 4-year-old girl in Chongzhou The chain reaction of events. A video of a ferocious dog biting a person swept the entire Internet, and dog hunting operations took place in many places. It was reported on the Internet that a residential property management team had set up a &quot;dog fighting team&quot;, and security guards patrolled with sticks and nets; Bozhou in Anhui, Zhengzhou in Henan, Taixing in Jiangsu, Urban management departments in Qingdao, Shandong and other places have successively released videos of catching stray dogs, and netizens have begun heated discussions about whether stray dogs should be culled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Controversial cases also emerged. A stray dog ​​living in Chongqing University of International Business and Economics was driven to death by security guards. On October 20, the school reported that a student was chased by a stray dog ​​on his way back to bed. The school security guard had engaged in inappropriate behavior during the chase and the security guard involved had been suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that after this incident, many places carried out special rectifications on the behavior of ownerless dogs, aggressive dogs, and not wearing leashes. But at the same time, various rumors are also circulating on online platforms. In fact, in many places, catching stray dogs is a regular task. The captured stray dogs will be sent to stray animal rescue centers for shelter and will not be killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What responsibilities should the property owner bear?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the Rottweiler dog biting incident, slogans were hung in many places in the Xichen Oasis Community of Hengda where the girl lived: &quot;Walking dogs in a civilized manner and keeping the leash on them&quot; &quot;, keep your mouth shut and don&#39;t hurt others&quot; &quot;Tighten the &#39;civilized rope&#39; and be a civilized dog owner&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, a mother who lived above the victim girl told a Southern Weekend reporter , the day the girl was bitten, the angry owners were already discussing in the owner group: &quot;If such a big thing happened, where is the security guard?&quot; &quot;Why don&#39;t they know when an outside dog comes in?&quot; Under pressure, the property began patrolling daily to catch off-leash dogs. These tasks will be posted to the group one by one and reported to the owner, with arrest videos and photos attached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tense atmosphere quickly spread to other communities. On October 17, the media reported that a &quot;dog fighting team&quot; was set up in Fuhe Yujing Community in Chengdu City. In the video, security guards were patrolling with sticks and nets. The property staff said: &quot;All stray dogs are left unattended and without leashes.&quot; Yes, the whole community needs to be rectified.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, the Sanduhui Chaowai Community in Chengdu hung a banner in the name of the property saying &quot;The community will hunt and kill unleashed cats and dogs.&quot; The word &quot;hunt and kill&quot; immediately caused worries and accusations from pet owners in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Ming, a resident of the community, the idea of ​​&quot;hunting and killing&quot; actually came from the community&#39;s mother group. Out of concern, the mothers suggested in the group &quot;methods to deal with stray dogs: first, kill or capture them as much as possible, second, drive them out of the community and then call the police to notify the community.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, those who opposed the culling called the government service hotline 12345 to complain one after another on the evening of the 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next morning, the property management company stated that the banner was inappropriate and had been removed. &quot;The property management company no longer dares to answer the phone. The street refused to allow them to kill the people by force and warned them in the morning.&quot; Li Ming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters called the property and street office of the community many times, but none of them got through. On the 20th, the Property Affairs Service Center of the Chengdu Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau responded to the media saying that the center had not received a notice that a dog hunting team was set up in a community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Sha, a lawyer at Beijing Jingdu Law Firm, has been involved in cases of dog injuries. She believes that the community property has a safety obligation to the owners. Therefore, if there is an ownerless dog in the community, the property owner must be responsible for evicting it. Or management responsibility, otherwise you will have to bear fault liability for stray dogs hurting people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the other hand, the property management company does not have the power to enforce the law, so for dogs with owners, the property management cannot take mandatory management measures, such as directly arresting them. In non-emergency situations, property management can only be handled by persuasion or handed over to urban management and public security agencies with law enforcement powers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Remediation in many places, rumors go hand in hand&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 18th, when the owners of a Chengdu community were arguing about whether to cull stray dogs, the urban management department of Jinshui District, Zhengzhou City, Henan Province targeted dogs without leashes. The act was enforced overnight and broadcast live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dog-catching controversy began to spread to many places across the country, resulting in law enforcement actions. In this live broadcast in Zhengzhou, a young man holding a French bulldog was chased for a long distance. According to the live video, although the urban management personnel repeatedly emphasized that they would not harm the dog and would only take it back for registration and investigation, the young man tried to escape with the black dog after some unsuccessful negotiations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This video has become another spreading point of this Internet storm. Xiao Zhen, a citizen who also raises French bulldogs in Zhengzhou, told Southern Weekend reporters that it is indeed prohibited to raise French bulldogs in Zhengzhou. Dog licenses are usually not allowed, but the law enforcement is not strict and &quot;we would check occasionally in the past.&quot; At the same time, many cities across the country allow the breeding of French bulldogs, including Beijing, Shanghai, Xi&#39;an, Dalian, Harbin, Nanjing, Hangzhou, Changsha, etc. After learning that the young man needed to pay a fine of 5,000 yuan, the group of French bullfighting enthusiasts sent him red envelopes one after another, saying that they would help him get his dog back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Fan, president of the Wuhan Small Animal Protection Association, said that the current management of dogs in cities is mainly based on regulations formulated by each locality. Such administrative regulations are not very effective, so many people do not apply for dog licenses. Nor do they keep dogs according to regulations. (For details, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258846&quot;>;&quot;Many experts talk about the Rottweiler dog biting a girl: &quot;The key is to manage people, followed by managing dogs&quot;&quot;&lt;/ a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the division of powers for dog management in cities is not clear. Most cities are currently in charge of public security, and some are under the charge of urban management. Dog management also involves industry and commerce, food safety, and public security. Management and other departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident of Rottweiler dogs injuring children, many places issued special management actions. Bozhou in Anhui, Taixing in Jiangsu, Shenqiu in Henan, Shehong in Sichuan and other places targeted ownerless dogs, aggressive dogs, and unprotected dogs. The behavior of traction ropes will be specially rectified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In it, rumors and facts are mixed. Southern Weekend reporters found that in videos calling for not killing stray dogs, photos of dozens of dog corpses and scenes of being thrown to death often appear, but there is no time stamp. Just looking at the background of the picture, buses and buildings should be numbers. years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the hot topic on Weibo &quot;Puppies don&#39;t feel like they are wandering&quot;, many netizens identified a photo of a puppy that was still grinning after being arrested as the one involved in the Chongqing University of International Business and Economics. It was a yellow dog, with the caption &quot;It was still laughing when it was caught, it thought it was going to have a home&quot;, and expressed condolences. However, the author of the original picture refuted the rumors and said that the smiling puppy was taken in April and is not the same dog as the one in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s a bit out of focus.” Zhou Wei, director of the Jiangsu Provincial Zoological Society, found that as the situation developed, netizens’ discussions gradually turned into opposing issues such as loving dogs or not, and culling or not culling. , without going into details. For example, many video titles say &quot;catching&quot; stray dogs, but most of the current videos only show &quot;catching&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Normalization of Urban Management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found through searches that many dog-catching videos were released by the official accounts of urban management and public security agencies in various places, such as Qingdao West Coast New District Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau. It released three videos in a row, introducing that catching stray dogs is a regular task. The captured stray dogs will be sent to the stray animal rescue center for shelter and will not be killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The distribution of dog leashes and dog muzzles has attracted attention. The Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau of Shehong City, Sichuan Province, which is considered by netizens to be a model of civilized law enforcement, told Southern Weekend reporters that they will set up dog leashes starting in 2021. The management office is equipped with professional dog-catching equipment and vehicles, and has 5 staff members daily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Saihan District, Hohhot City, according to the City Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau, the bureau took over the work of catching stray dogs in 2020. In 2023 alone, it received more than 1,100 related reports and has captured stray dogs. There are more than 300 dogs, and most of the reports are about barking dogs disturbing people, especially in the early morning and early morning. Zhang Yong, head of the bureau&#39;s publicity department, said that when team members receive a reporting call, they must contact the person involved in a timely manner and respond to the person after handling the case. If they cannot catch the person, the team members will have to go there at least three times within a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This does not sound like an easy job. Zhang Yong said that they have specially formulated a long-term mechanism for this purpose, which is divided into day shift and night shift. &quot;There are 38 people in the mobile squadron participating in dog hunting.&quot; They have to patrol the 1,025 square kilometers under the jurisdiction of Saihan District. When the dog climbs over the fence and enters the bush, it is difficult for law enforcement officers to catch up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, stray dogs have a keen sense of smell. As soon as the law enforcement vehicles that carry stray dogs all the year round stop in a place, &quot;no dogs will come out of this area.&quot; Zhang Yong said that one of their team members saw a stray dog ​​while driving around in his car and called for a law enforcement vehicle. Before the vehicle arrived, the stray dog ​​started to get restless. &quot;It could smell the smell of the car.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every dog-catching team member in Saihan District has been bitten by a dog, and some have broken their legs while catching dogs. The tool they use is a fishing net. Dogs of different sizes use different types of fishing nets. The largest ones use fiber rope nets as thick as their thumbs. &quot;They have very good teeth and can bite through thin ropes in one bite.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sichuan Province Shehong City Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau and Qingdao West Coast New District Comprehensive Law Enforcement Administration both responded to Southern Weekend reporters that the tools used to catch dogs are mainly fishing nets. In most of the dog-catching videos circulated on the Internet, law enforcement officers used fishing nets. Only one video showed a dog-catching video with a license plate number from Taizhou, Zhejiang, using curved clamps. Zhou Wei believes that the fishing net is currently a more suitable tool for catching dogs. It has a soft texture and can trap dogs without causing too much harm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yong said that after the stray dogs are caught, they will be sent to the detention center managed by the public security department for adoption. After the dog is inspected, the detention center will give the urban management team member a receipt, which will clearly indicate the receipt. Quantity and condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend called the Hohhot Public Security Bureau Dog Inspection Station, and the other party replied that the institute has 50 acres of kennels and is currently able to raise stray cats and dogs until they die of natural causes. In addition, the center is open to the public for adoption, and you can visit, adopt or donate materials during the open day. As for the number of stray cats and dogs currently detained in the inspection center, the staff member said that detailed data could not be provided for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Bodhi Nursing Home for Stray Fur Children in Shehong, Sichuan is a privately run base for stray cats and dogs. It occupies a hilltop in the mountains and feeds stray cats and dogs in different areas. In 2021, the base began to receive stray cats and dogs caught by the urban management department, 20-30 every year. &quot;They are sent here sporadically, and they are all caught after being complained about disturbing the residents.&quot; Ms. Ren, the person in charge of the base, said that the urban management department Part of the cost of dog food is provided. Cats and dogs will be checked for infectious diseases in advance before delivery. If there are injuries or illnesses, they will go to the pet hospital for treatment first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Ren said that Shehong has launched a special operation to capture stray cats and dogs since October 20, and 11 stray dogs were delivered in just one day. She was a little worried that too many cats and dogs would be sent in a short period of time and that the base would not be able to handle the load. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;More sophisticated, professional and scientific&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 20, the French Dou who was captured in Zhengzhou has been brought back to his hometown for adoption , and the Zhengzhou Urban Management Bureau told the media that the case is still going through the process and the fine has not yet been determined. The topic of why French bulldogs are banned has been hotly discussed in the dog breeding circle. Mao Jing, who has raised French bulldogs for many years, saw from this the management problems of dog breeding in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Jing said that French bulldogs are not clearly marked on Shanghai’s prohibited list, but French bulldogs have long been regarded as a type of bulldog and face different management methods in various districts of Shanghai. In 2014, she raised her first French bulldog, and she successfully applied for a dog license in Siping Street, Yangpu District. In 2016, Mao Jing was planning to raise a second French bulldog, but when she applied for a dog license in Jiangpu Street, the same district, her dog license was rejected. It was approved after a phone appeal. &quot;The handler didn&#39;t know much about this dog breed.&quot; In 2019, Shanghai stated that legal fighting is allowed in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the French Bulldog incident in Zhengzhou, she specially compared the lists of banned dogs in Zhengzhou and Shanghai, and found that Shanghai clearly prohibited the breeding of British bulldogs, but French Bulldogs were not allowed; while Zhengzhou clearly prohibited the breeding of French Bulldogs, But I can&#39;t help but raise heroes to fight. Mao Jing said that the two types of dogs have different body shapes and agility. In comparison, Yingdou can grow to 60-80 pounds. &quot;Even if it doesn&#39;t bite, hitting someone may be more serious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There is actually no common standard for dog breeds in our country.” Zhou Wei said that when foreign dog breeds were introduced in the early stages, there may be a lack of understanding of the dog breed’s habits or translation problems. &quot;This reflects management lag.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s pet industry has developed by leaps and bounds in more than ten years, and the problem of how people and animals coexist in cities has continued to become highlighted. The &quot;2021 China Pet Industry White Paper&quot; shows that the total number of pet dogs and pet cats in cities and towns nationwide in 2021 will exceed 112 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Wei believes that in terms of dog management, a more refined, professional and scientific management mechanism is needed starting from the source. For example, when breeding, attention should be paid to the breed genes and how to train them. The problem is that there is currently a lack of supervision in the upstream breeding stage, and it is only at the pet raising stage that it starts to get tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Fan also holds a similar view. He believes that many incidents of dog injuries can be traced back to the source: &quot;Why are banned violent dogs still sold on the market?&quot; From this, he suggested that dogs are born from Establish a series of supervision mechanisms for sales and breeding, and clarify departmental responsibilities and management rights and responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Wei suggested that solving the current problem can start with popular science education, such as providing professional training services to campuses and real estate properties: how to deal with fierce dogs in the community, how to correctly place and capture them; People provide training: how to scientifically understand and control their pet dogs, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wuhan Small Animal Association, where Du Fan works, has reached a cooperation with the local public security department. Around the 25th of each month, some captured stray dogs from the inspection center are open to the public for adoption, calling for &quot;adopting instead of purchasing&quot; &quot;. Du Fan said that the previous two adoption events were successfully held, and all the dogs kept for inspection were successfully adopted. &quot;We are currently preparing for the third one.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末记者高伊琛对本文亦有贡献，文中李明、毛静为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美经济工作组举行第一次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259175]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to He Lifeng, Vice Premier of the State Council and Chinese leader of China-US Economic and Trade, and Janet. Following the consensus reached by Yellen during her talks in Beijing in July, the China-US Economic Working Group held its first meeting via video on October 24. The meeting was chaired by officials at the deputy ministerial level of finance from the two countries. The two sides had in-depth, candid and constructive communication on issues such as the macroeconomic situation and policies of the two countries and the world, bilateral economic relations, and cooperation in responding to global challenges. China expressed its concerns. Both parties will continue to maintain communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“第一学历歧视”？别用这样的观念轻易否定企业丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259163]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, many media launched reports related to &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;. It is worth noting that on September 29, the Ministry of Education responded to a netizen’s question about “Whether the first degree after graduation is a junior college or a bachelor’s degree?” The concept of “first degree” is not used in the relevant policies and documents of the national education administration department regarding the learning experience of scientific and cultural education and skills training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an objective point of view, graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees from prestigious schools generally have some advantages in the job market. Needless to say, this may be &quot;first degree discrimination&quot; The realistic background in which relevant issues have received attention. But is similar recruitment behavior “merit-based” or “discriminatory”? It may not be possible to generalize, but the issues of corporate operational autonomy and employment autonomy that run through it are also important aspects worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, for graduate students from 985 universities, does the recruiting unit or human resources specialist make a clear employment choice based on the prerequisite of &quot;undergraduate degree from a prestigious school&quot;? This is actually hard to say. Especially as a for-profit organization, the company will ultimately look at whether the applicant&#39;s abilities and talents match the company&#39;s employment needs. It may also be that the company&#39;s interviewer confirms the match between the applicant&#39;s abilities and the company&#39;s needs through a comprehensive, complete and systematic assessment. . And graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees who have been blessed by famous schools may have shown certain advantages in this link and finally got the opportunity, but it may not necessarily be simple and crude academic qualifications that win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the recruitment process of the employer is that the human resources specialist will screen the resume before the interview. Only after passing the preliminary screening will he be qualified to participate in the initial interview hosted by the human resources department and even the professional interview hosted by the leader of the hiring department. interview. If some companies clearly stipulate in black and white that they will not recruit students with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; or are suspected of academic discrimination, if graduates with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; and master&#39;s degrees can pass the resume screening, in this sense, 985 As a stepping stone, colleges and universities have already been used in the preliminary screening stage. The stepping stone is just a stepping stone. Next, it depends on whether the job seeker has real ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时应该说明的是，社会也没有必要过分放大所谓“第一学历”的光环加持。如今，本科毕业于985的学子何其多也。在严峻的就业形势下，北大物理博士去争城管编制的有之，上海交大医学院博士去中学当校医的有之。本科985真的没有一些人想象的那样有多耀眼的光环与多有力的加持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，客观地讲，本科985院校学子相对于非985，在就业市场上总体上多多少少是有些优势的。这本身也有合理的一面。如果这个优势不存在，那学子们秋雨寒灯努力考上好大学的动力或许就不存在了，也就无所谓好大学与一般大学的差异了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，表面上是学子得到了985院校文凭的加持，获得了一些优势，但实际逻辑是反过来的：高考考分排序及名校与非名校的分际，是对学子智力、能力的排序。在这个意义上，总体上是优秀的学子成就了985院校，而不是反过来。所以985文凭就具有了重要的信号功能，对用人单位筛选简历构成了一个重要的参考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，高分低能是有的，低分高能也是有的；高考失误是有的，高考超常发挥也是有的，不过，一要看是大概率还是小概率；二是大家最终都要接受市场与用人单位的检验，要看真才实干的，是骡子是马拉出来遛遛就知道了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业是营利机构，最终会看应聘者的能力才干与企业用人需求是否匹配，能否为企业创造更高的价值。人事与用人部门对985本科的求职者可能会高看一眼，但也就仅此而已，接下来要看求职者在面试中的表现能否符合他们对人才的期待。尤其是自由竞争行业，企业没有任何动机放着更能干的非985本科就职者不用，反而用不能干的985本科求职者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果两个人，一个非985本+985研，另一个985本+985研，企业没有录取前者而录取了后者，是不是就成了“第一学历歧视”？恐怕并非如此。求职者与用人单位是双向选择，达成合意才是对双方权利的尊重与市场效率的提升。推而广之，求职者本身很能干，想去高薪单位不想去低薪单位，是否构成对后者的歧视呢？就算是，也是效率歧视，应属正当。正如大家婚嫁时愿意找个人、家庭条件好的而不愿找条件差的，也不能说是对后者的歧视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，在严峻就业形势之下，让学子有更多更好的工作机会可选择，关键在于激发企业家的信心与对未来的预期，让他们敢于用真金白银下注，扩大投资，创造更多更好的就业岗位。这就要尊重企业家的经营自主权与用人自主权，而不能动辄否定企业“择优”的权利，削弱企业家投资下注的动力与信心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不让企业显示自己的招聘偏好，结果无非有二：一是短期内企业把自己的偏好隐藏起来但写在心里，无非是让求职者做更多的无用功，对求职者真的好吗？二是长期看企业会觉得营商环境与观念环境不好，会更加谨慎投资下注，创造就业岗位的过程就会受到影响，对求职者又有什么好处呢？总之，社会应给企业家创造一个宽松、理性的观念环境，让他们用自己的聪明才智与真金白银推动我们的经济，最终也会有利于每一个求职者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:01:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[触碰寻亲直播间里的伤痛 | 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259121]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年7月14日，贵州贵阳，四个寻亲家长开车从云南昆明出发，奔波上千公里寻子。 （南方周末记者刘怡仙/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;采访杨妞花被拐案（详见《&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/253854&quot;>;人贩余华英被判死刑：拐卖11名儿童，还卖过亲儿子&lt;/a>;》），是我第一次接近寻亲家长们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月14日早晨，拐卖杨妞花的人贩子余华英在贵州省贵阳市中级人民法院受审，法院外站满了寻亲家长。他们大多穿着白色衬衫，上面印着宝贝的照片，手里还举着红底黄字的寻人牌子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“寻找儿子李先芳”“寻儿子安旭和安彪”“棉花糖爸爸寻找女儿陈杨梅”……每张寻人牌子上都标注着孩子的出生年月日、走失时间、走失时的身体特征等等。牌子后面，大多是愁苦的面容，仿佛五官都耷拉了下来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;等待的过程中，也有寻亲家长在做直播，给网友介绍庭审进展，法院外现场是什么情况，中间穿插&lt;span>;着&lt;/span>;说自己的孩子是如何丢的，为了找孩子去过哪些地方，又是怎么来到这儿的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我和其中的几位家长打招呼，告知记者身份，在旁边录采访视频。此后，只要我举起手机录像，旁边的家长马上凑上来，抱着寻人牌子转悠一圈，偶尔搭腔说话。他们知道如何“蹭流量”，在任何可能的机会里，露一次脸，增加一点曝光度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这种急切在杨妞花出现后更为明显。寻亲家长们几乎一窝蜂地涌了上去，前后包围着，一个挨着一个举着牌子。好几次，杨妞花被淹没在寻亲牌子中，记者根本找不到她。混乱中，有家长把自己的寻人牌塞到杨妞花手中，还有家长将写有寻亲信息的背包挂在了她身上。杨妞花理解这些寻亲家长的心情，也不拒绝。这些家长常年奔波于各地，出现在各种热点场景里，争取让孩子看到自己，看到“爸爸妈妈一直在找你”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;结束庭审的那天下午，我敲开杨妞花的房门，却惊讶地发现房间里挤满了寻亲家长，床上、椅子上、地板上，每个角落都坐满了人。他们都在排队等着上杨妞花的直播间，介绍自己寻亲情况。杨妞花在2021年网络寻亲成功后，引发了诸多关注，在短视频平台也积累了30余万粉丝。在庭审这样的重要日子，她也乐意利用自己的流量，让家长们上直播间扩散寻亲信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我在一个50多岁的阿姨身边坐下来，看着房间里人来人往上直播。那时还是7月盛夏，这位阿姨穿着印有孩子信息的套头长袖衫，里头还叠加了几件衣服。一番攀谈后，她说自己是贵州布依族人，左脚天生&lt;span>;残&lt;/span>;疾，难以走远路。可丈夫生病卧床，无奈她只能独自出来找孩子。说着她脱下左脚的短靴，露出的足面是畸形的，看起来难以受力。难以想象这些天她是如何跟着寻亲队伍辗转福建、贵州多地的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我印象比较深的还有一位“棉花糖爸爸”，他的女儿2003年出生，3岁时在云南昆明失踪。杨妞花庭审后接受采访时，他就站在杨妞花身后，突然无法控制地哭出了声，声音一点点变大，最后蹲在地上痛哭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;多年来，“棉花糖爸爸”一直用小面包车四处做生意，一边卖棉花糖一边找孩子，妻子则在家里卖气球支撑生活。在“棉花糖爸爸”的视频号主页里，他去过多个寻亲成功的认亲现场。那些天贵州榕江村超正是热点，他接连赶路，到村超现场找孩子。为了节约用费，4个寻亲家长一路上都是自己做饭吃，露天支起灶台架子炒菜，4个人一天花费二十多元就够了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;寻亲艰难，寻亲家长们都痛恨人贩子。但对于收养家庭，他们有着不同的看法。有人支持买卖同罪，认为应该追究养家的责任。但更多的家长，则会强调自己只是想见见孩子，不求孩子回到亲生家庭，也不追究养家责任。一个很重要的原因是，许多被拐孩子担心伤害养父母感情，不愿主动站出来寻亲，这将增加寻亲的难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;余华英拐卖儿童案件里，仍有几位被拐孩子不愿正式认亲，他们陷于复杂的家庭关系里，不知如何是好。也有已经认亲的被拐孩子与父母并不亲近，亲子关系空荡荡的，不知从何建起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在寻亲直播间里，家长们呼吁对自己身世有怀疑的孩子前往公安局采血，录入寻亲数据库，将来有一天认亲成功，“你想回来就回来，你要是不想回来，也可以留在养家生活”&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;这句话大概饱含苦楚与伤痛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;祝愿他们与亲人早日团聚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[睡眠保单规模有多大？如何常态化唤醒？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259165]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;睡眠保单正被要求限期清理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家金融监督管理总局近期发布限期清理人身保险“睡眠保单”的专项通知。根据通知，针对2013年1月1日至2023年6月30日期间产生的“睡眠保单”，专项清理工作从2023年10月起持续为期一年。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员调研获悉，各寿险公司开始为“睡眠保单”寻找“主人”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内为何会有睡眠保单？投保人的权益又将如何获得保证？海外在处理睡眠保单时有何经验？南方周末新金融研究中心研究员研究海外经验后认为，睡眠保单清理不能仅仅依靠监管机构不定期的督促，而应建立易得易查全国性系统，且保险公司应主动披露睡眠保单情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;何为&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“睡眠保单”？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;何为“睡眠保单”？中国社会科学院金融研究所保险与社会保障研究室副主任王向楠对南方周末新金融研究中心研究员称，“睡眠保单”并没有明确定义，一般是指保险事故发生或保险合同到期但尚未领取赔偿或满期给付保险金，以及保险合同效力中止或效力终止但尚未领取现金价值的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员查询发现，国外与之相类似的概念为“未领取保单（unclaimed life insurance）”。美国好事达保险公司（Allstate）将其特指为保险人过世，受益人未申领保险赔偿的情况。根据美国政府网站，美国把未申领的保险收益与未支付的工资、养老金、退税、基金收益、债券收益等统一纳入未申领资金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通俗而言，国家金融监督管理总局这次要求限期清理的“睡眠保单”即是保单主人“失联”导致保单“应领而未领”，最终被保险公司“束之高阁”的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“睡眠保单”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;何以产生&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;睡眠保单为何产生呢？北京大童保险销售公司一位合伙人告诉南方周末新金融研究中心研究员，保单主人“失联”的原因有很多。比如，有的家里长辈买了年金，没有知会家人，还没等到领取的时候，长辈去世了。这将导致无人申请理赔；也有消费者购买保险后，因更换联系方式、缴费中断等，导致保单失效，而自己也忘记了这件事，没去退现金；很多家庭没有好好保存和管理保单，家庭成员互相之间不了解保单持有情况。保险公司一般很难对这类保单进行处理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员还了解到，孤儿保单也是导致睡眠保单产生的原因之一。 &lt;span>;孤儿&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保&lt;/span>;单指因为原营销人员离职而无人主动跟进服务的&lt;span>;保单&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与国内睡眠保单产生的原因类似，国外睡眠保单也多由投保人各种原因的“失联”导致。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于投保人而言，“睡眠保单”意味着一笔“睡眠资金”或一段“保险空窗期”。前者对应的是投保人名下有到期生存金和满期金未领取的情况；而后者发生在保单因“失联”欠费而中止时。这意味着保险公司有权解除保险合同。基于此，国家金融监督管理总局组织的这次专项清理行动，既能盘活社会沉睡的“闲置资金”，也维护了消费者权益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;睡眠保单规模有多大&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;监管机构专门发通知限期清理“睡眠保单”。这意味着“睡眠保单”不可忽视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“睡眠保单”规模究竟有多大？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员梳理发现，截至目前，监管部门并没有公布全国范围内的统计数据。可参考的一项数据是，2014年8月，原中国保监会曾对“1999年6月10日以后签发生效、截至2014年6月30日24时，所有缴费期为一年以上的人身保险失效保单”开展专项清理，共排查出人身保险失效保单1857.93万件，现金价值350.83亿元。该专项清理行动针对的“人身保险失效保单”特指因保险缴费中断导致合同效力中止的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“睡眠保单”不仅仅包括“人身保险失效保单”。据此可见，睡眠保单涉及金额也应该更大。各地数据可做例证。安徽省保险业协会披露的数据显示，截至2023年6月30日，安徽省人身险公司应领未领取生存金保单件数为7.79万件，涉及金额9.2亿元；据中国银行保险报报道，2022年，浙江40家人身险公司开展“寻找保险生存金领取人”活动，截至2020年12月31日，浙江（不含宁波）到期未领取人身险保单共计12.13万件，金额7.79亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同保险公司的数据亦显示，睡眠保单不是小事。平安养老保险浙江分公司2022年4月至8月为客户找回了“满期生存金”1.4亿元。新华人寿官方称，&amp;nbsp;2021年到目前，新华保险浙江分公司开展寻找生存金领取人活动，通过走访村委、社区，寻求出单银行、派出所、户籍中心等寻找“失联”客户，共找回“失联”客户2193人，协助客户办理领取手续，支付生存金9046万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;财报未单独披露&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;险企清理睡眠保单的动力有多大？躺在账上的“睡眠资金”对保险公司而言是一笔意外之财？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员查询各上市险企财报发现，各公司对此没有单独披露。这意味着各公司在财报上将此作为正常保单处理了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家上市险企的一位资深士在接受南方周末新金融研究中心研究员调研时确认，从保险业务端来看，保险公司在财务报表中并不区分“睡眠保单”和正常保单。 “睡眠保单”同其余保单一样，执行相同的会计准则，如保费收入计入资产类账目，保险责任准备金依据精算确定金额计入“提取保险责任准备金”科目等。准备金提取比例，按照保险种类和准备金种类，规则较多，各家保险公司情况存在差异。加上受保险期限长和保单状态多样等因素，“睡眠保单”清理是一项复杂的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家保险销售公司一位合伙人更称，保险公司不一定有动力清理睡眠保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何唤醒“睡眠保单”？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;海外如何唤醒睡眠保单？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证券时报2020年5月报道，美国每年数百万美元的人寿保险权益无人申请索赔。英国保险公司协会网站2023年援引消息人士保守估计，英国各地被遗忘和无人认领的保单预计共涉及2亿英镑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员梳理发现，在美国，消费者既可以登录美国保险监督协会（NAIC）的系统查询，也可以找第三方机构帮助查询。根据美国家庭人寿保险公司（Aflac）网站介绍，美国不同州对于未领取保单有不同的法律规定。在许多案例中，受益人可追溯的保单没有时间限制，一旦受益人提交保单，保险公司会用几周到一个月的时间来处理并赔付。受益人除了可以领取保险赔付外，还可以领取部分利息收入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，为配合“睡眠保单”清理工作，国家金融监督管理总局这次也指导相关机构研究建立统一的“睡眠保单”信息查询平台，供消费者自主查询。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，睡眠保单的清理不能仅仅依靠监管机构不定期的催促监督，除了尽快建立全国统一的保单查询系统，监管部门和行业协会应要求保险公司把提醒投保人工作前置。与此同时，各保险公司应利用金融科技赋能睡眠保单的追踪，甚至可以利用大数据系统对所有保单每年进行一次检查，实现常态化唤醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>