<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[一起“非典型”涉黑案：曾因律师手机法庭被扣陷舆论风暴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261925]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 6, 2023, the defense lawyer Chi Susheng in this case caused a conflict because his mobile phone was detained. After discovering that he was unwell, the court called an ambulance. (Photo provided by the interviewee) &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/fa73441145.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;814&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/fa73441145.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 6, 2023, Chi Susheng, the defense lawyer in this case, caused a conflict because his mobile phone was detained. After discovering that he was unwell, the court called an ambulance. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is an &quot;atypical&quot; incident In the gang-related case, the prosecutor accused a gang of 10 people, which had just reached the minimum number of participants in a gang, and there was only one injury appraisal report in the whole case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first defendant Liu Shunping is from Xuanwei City (Qujing City), Yunnan Province. The case has gone through three stages: first instance, second instance, and retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first instance of the original trial determined that the case did not constitute a crime of a gangland nature, and the second instance court remanded the case for a retrial on the grounds that some facts were unclear. However, the public prosecution still insisted on charging the suspect with gang-related crimes, and added new charges and criminal facts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, the Xuanwei City Court opened a new trial, which has lasted for a month and a half and has not yet ended. During this period, the court hearings attracted public attention several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The incident with the widest impact is the seizure of lawyers’ cell phones. On November 6, 2023, Chi Susheng, the defender of the third defendant Li Zhengyan in the case, was ordered to withhold his mobile phone by the presiding judge, which caused a conflict in the court. This unexpected incident ended with Chi Susheng being sent to the hospital for emergency treatment and Xuanwei City Court. The dean apologized to Chi Susheng and returned the mobile phone. After that, Chi Susheng went out to recuperate and did not participate in the subsequent defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Three cases merged&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shunping&#39;s involvement in gangs originated from the arrest of Zhang Jian, the gang leader in Xuanwei City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On January 13, 2019, the Xuanwei City Public Security Bureau controlled a large number of members of the gang headed by Zhang Jian while promoting the special campaign against gangs and evil. Later, Zhang Jian was sentenced to suspended death. There were more than 90 defendants in the &quot;Zhang Jian case&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three months after Zhang Jian was controlled, on April 12, 2019, Liu Shunping was controlled by the Xuanwei City Public Security Bureau on suspicion of committing extortion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shunping was born in Longtan Town, Xuanwei City in 1977. Xu Jinde, a veteran employee of his company, introduced that Liu Shunping joined the army after graduating from junior high school and returned to Longtan Town to work as a joint security guard after his discharge. While working in the joint defense team, Liu Shunping discovered business opportunities in coal transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information shows that the coal fields in Xuanwei are vast and rich in coal reserves, with proven and predicted reserves reaching 2.178 billion tons, making it the largest coal resource in Yunnan Province. One of the rich areas. Among them, the coal mine reserves in Longtan Town are about 100 million tons, and there are 12 developed large and small coal mines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the late 1990s, Liu Shunping borrowed money from relatives and friends to start a coal transportation business and earned his first pot of gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shunping&#39;s brother-in-law Jin Huaiying told Southern Weekend reporters that Liu Shunping bid for the Cide Coal Mine from the Longtan Town Government in 2004 and applied for a mining license. The mining license is valid for 10 years. Two or three years later, Liu Shunping bought Fangmaping Coal Mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jin Huaiying was the director of Cide Coal Mine. He introduced that as the operations of the two coal mines gradually got on track, Liu Shunping also accumulated a certain amount of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While operating a coal mine in Longtan Town, Liu Shunping met Zhang Jian, the local evil leader in Xuanwei. The first-instance judgment of the &quot;Zhang Jian case&quot; shows that Zhang Jian was born on March 6, 1978 in Tianba Town, Xuanwei City. He was involved in society in his early years and became somewhat famous in the local area. Later, he gradually developed into one of the major evil forces in Xuanwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Many people in society don&#39;t understand how a private enterprise owner could associate with a gangster boss.&quot; Jin Huaiying explained that the social environment at that time was quite special, &quot;He The two didn&#39;t know each other before. Zhang Jian celebrated his birthday twice a year, and every time he invited the boss of Xuanwei&#39;s business. Everyone went, how dare Liu Shunping not go?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Relevant evidence and materials show that the &quot;1.5&quot; task force established by the Qujing Municipal Public Security Bureau in response to the &quot;Zhang Jian case&quot; took control of Liu Shunping during the handling of the case, and took control of his brother Liu Shunfu on the same day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Indictment No. 310 of the Second Propaganda and Inspection Department (2020) shows that during the investigation process, the Qujing Municipal Public Security Bureau established another investigation against Liu Shunfu, Zhang Qiang, and Tao Yunrui. , Shan Qingze, Shan Qingman, Xu Wanquan, Guan Yuan, Li Jixiong and other eight evil forces criminal group &quot;4·11&quot; task force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The public security organs also captured Li Zhengyan while handling the &quot;Zhang Jian case&quot;. Li Zhengyan is a key figure in connecting the &quot;Zhang Jian case&quot; and the &quot;Liu Shunping brothers case&quot;. Among the criminal facts listed in the verdict of Zhang Jian&#39;s case, in 2011, Li Zhengyan conspired with Zhang Jian, Liu Shunping, and Liu Shunfu to extort a local coal mine owner, making illegal profits of more than 6.7 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since October 2019, the Qujing Municipal Public Security Bureau has successively investigated the cases of Liu Shunfu and other eight people and Li Zhengyan on suspicion of extortion. Liu Shunping is suspected of organizing and leading a gangland organization. The criminal cases were transferred to the Qujing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate for review and prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above cases were assigned to the jurisdiction of the Shizong County People&#39;s Procuratorate under the jurisdiction of Qujing. In August 2020, due to the Qujing Intermediate People&#39;s Court&#39;s decision to change jurisdiction, the entire case was transferred to the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Procuratorate, and in September 2020, the case was prosecuted to the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court for crimes such as gang involvement, provoking trouble, and extortion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the three cases of Liu Shunfu, Li Zhengyan and Liu Shunping were merged into one case, there were a total of 10 defendants in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the &quot;Minutes of the Symposium on Trial of Criminal Cases of Triad Organizations in Some Courts across the Country&quot; issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court in 2015, underworld organizations should have a certain scale and number of people. There are usually more than 10 members in the organization. According to the &quot;Opinions on Several Issues Concerning the Handling of Criminal Cases of Evil Forces&quot; issued by the &quot;Two High Schools and Two Ministries&quot; in 2019, evil forces generally consist of more than three people, and the number of people who gather is relatively fixed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;The first instance was &quot;anti-criminal&quot;, and the second instance was remanded for retrial&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xuanwei City Procuratorate alleged that since 2005, Liu Shunping had committed a crime against Zhang Jian Provide economic support and help, and gain shelter and connivance by roping in Yin Dabao, the former director of the Xuanwei City Public Security Bureau, Tian Fei, the former secretary of the Party Committee of Longtan Town in Xuanwei City, and gradually formed a situation with Liu Shunping as the organizer and leader, and Liu Shunfu as the organizer and leader. , Li Zhengyan as the key members, and a 10-person underworld organization with Tao Yunrui, Shan Qingze, Shan Qingman and others as active participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yin Dabao and Tian Fei both handled separate cases. Many of the 10 defendants charged by the prosecutor have criminal records. Tao Yunrui has a criminal record for drug abuse, Shan Qingze has a criminal record for robbery twice, and Shan Qingman has a criminal record for picking quarrels and provoking trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to prosecutors&#39; accusations, 2005 was a key time point for the formation of Liu Shunping&#39;s gang organization, but Xu Jinde and Jin Huaiying both said that Liu Shunping was not adapted to the special conditions of the local coal industry. Ecology, 2005 was a critical year for Liu Shunping’s “career change”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2005, Liu Shunping registered and established Huaping Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. in Xuanwei City. The company has developed real estate projects such as Jingang Yujing Mingdu and Jingang Yujing Wenhui in Xuanwei City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Jinde introduced that with the successful development of real estate projects in Xuanwei urban area, Liu Shunping&#39;s main business actually shifted from coal mining to real estate. In 2013, Liu Shunping went to Qujing to engage in real estate investment business. During this period, he purchased real estate in Qujing City and brought his family to Qujing City to work and live. Later, he invested in real estate projects in Kunming, Pu&#39;er and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On April 19, 2021, the gang-related case involving Liu Shunping and 10 people was heard in the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The charges charged by the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Procuratorate are divided into two parts: organized crimes and individual crimes. Among them, there are 3 crimes involving organized crime, 7 crimes of picking quarrels and provoking trouble, 2 crimes of extortion, and 1 crime of illegal detention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the personal violations and criminal facts of the organization members, the personal crimes involve two crimes, 1 criminal fact of loan fraud, 1 criminal fact of bribery, and 3 personal illegal facts rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the indictment, Liu Shunping did not participate in all the criminal facts. Among the organized crimes he was accused of, Liu Shunping participated in 5 crimes of picking quarrels and provoking trouble and 1 crime of extortion, and did not participate in the crime of illegal detention. Liu Shunping participated in all personal crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On December 10, 2021, the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court issued a first-instance judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The court held that to identify a gang organization, it must have four statutory characteristics: organizational characteristics, economic characteristics, behavioral characteristics and harmful characteristics. However, in this case , although the behavioral characteristics charged by the public prosecution can be confirmed, the organizational characteristics and economic characteristics cannot be identified, and the harmful characteristics cannot be all identified. Therefore, the public prosecution’s accusation that Liu Shunping and 10 people constituted a crime of a gangland nature cannot be established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court held that ten people including Liu Shunping should be identified as an evil criminal group, and Liu Shunping was the leader of the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The court sentenced Liu Shunping to 20 years in prison and fined him 2.34 million yuan. Liu Shunfu, Li Zhengyan and others were also sentenced respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All 10 defendants in the case refused to accept the verdict and appealed to the Qujing Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On December 9, 2022, the Qujing Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a second-instance ruling, holding that some of the facts identified in the original judgment were unclear and sent it back to the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court Rehearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 9, 2023, the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court retried the case, and the trial has lasted for more than a month. (Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/684c3abbb7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/05/684c3abbb7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260780&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 10 On March 9, the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court reheard the case, and the trial has lasted for more than a month. (Southern Weekend reporter Zhai Xingli/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;Injury appraisal report issued after 6 years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the original trial, the public prosecution agency accused The facts of the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble are that on the evening of February 14, 2013, Xuanwei locals Lu Hongquan and He Liping quarreled in front of Liu Shunping&#39;s house over trivial matters, and then had an argument with Liu Shunping&#39;s driver. Liu Shunping then notified Zhang Jian, Li Zhengyan, and Liu Shunfu . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shunfu went alone, while Zhang Jian and Li Zhengyan led more than 20 people to go there and beat Lu Hongquan and He Liping with weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On February 25, 2013, He Liping had a miscarriage. After the Liu Shunping case occurred in 2019, He Liping was diagnosed with minor injuries of the second degree. This is also the only crime in this case where the victim’s injuries were assessed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters saw at the scene of the crime that Liu Shunping&#39;s home is a five-story building. There is a road outside the gate and a row of shops across the road. and residences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, in addition to Liu Shunping and his wife on the second floor, there were also the driver on the first floor and Li Jishe, an employee of Liu Shunping&#39;s company. Li Jishe recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that the day of the incident was Valentine&#39;s Day in the West. During the time of the incident, he heard someone arguing outside on the first floor of Liu Shunping&#39;s house. When he looked outside, he saw an entertainment venue opposite Liu Shunping&#39;s house. , Lu Hongquan and He Liping were fighting with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the quarrel between the two, Li Jishe heard that He Liping found Lu Hongquan celebrating the festival with other women in the entertainment venue. Li Jishe also said that Lu Hongquan knocked He Liping down and dragged him across the street to a car parked in front of Liu Shunping&#39;s house to leave. He Liping chased Lu Hongquan, and the two exchanged curses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;His car was parked in front of Liu Shunping&#39;s house. Liu Shunping&#39;s driver wanted to drive out. The road was blocked by Lu Hongquan&#39;s car, so I went over and asked Lu Hongquan to move. car.&quot; Li Jishe said that Lu Hongquan immediately pulled out a knife and chased him. He Liping took out a long knife from the car and several men accompanying Lu Hongquan also chased Liu Shunping&#39;s driver and Li Jishe with weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Jishe said that after Liu Shunping&#39;s gang-related case, the public security agency questioned him and produced a transcript. He gave a complete account of the above-mentioned incident. However, in the first-instance judgment, Li Jishe&#39;s witness testimony was only used to prove that Liu Shunping asked Zhang Jian to bring people to injure Lu Hongquan, and did not provide the complete story of the incident as claimed by him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Also puzzled is Liu Shunping&#39;s brother-in-law Xu Wanjing. Starting from February 2022, Xu Wanjing invited He Liping several times and recorded conversations with He Liping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters asked two local outside lawyers to listen and translate part of the recording. In the recording, He Liping narrated the situation on the day of the incident, saying that she was not beaten by Liu Shunping&#39;s side, and recalled the process of questioning Liu Shunping by the public security organs after the gang-related case. However, according to her story, there seemed to be some inducement and accusations during the interrogation process. Southern Weekend reporters asked the Xuanwei City Public Security Bureau for confirmation, but they refused to be interviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order for He Liping to issue a written explanation of the situation, Xu Wanjing paid her 30,000 yuan. In March 2022, during the second trial of Liu Shunping&#39;s gang-related case, Xu Wanjing and He Liping went to the post office together to mail a statement of the situation to the Qujing Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unexpectedly, after receiving the document, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Qujing City believed that there was suspicion of perjury and handed it over to the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Qujing City as a criminal clue, and then the public security agency Launch an investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The People&#39;s Court of Zhanyi District, Qujing City made a first-instance judgment on July 29, 2023. Xu Wanjing was sentenced to two years in prison for obstructing testimony. After Xu Wanjing appealed, Qujing Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a second-instance ruling on September 26, 2023, rejecting the appeal and upholding the original judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Wanjing&#39;s second-instance ruling shows that He Liping immediately changed her story after arriving at the case, saying that the mailed statement was a false statement. After the Liu Shunping gang-related case, the public security organs Her statements are true when questioned. The court accepted this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to this ruling, on April 21, 2022, the Zhanyi Branch of the Qujing Municipal Public Security Bureau opened a case against He Liping on suspicion of perjury, but Zhanyi District The People&#39;s Procuratorate decided not to prosecute He Liping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When interviewed by Southern Weekend reporters, He Liping only admitted that she had a history of abducting women and children, but she said she &quot;didn&#39;t know&quot; about Liu Shunping&#39;s provocations and troubles and Xu Wanjing&#39;s obstruction of testimony. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New charges&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 11, 2023, the Xuanwei City Procuratorate submitted a Prosecution and Sentence Change Appeal (2023) 6 to the court The number change and the supplementary prosecution decision still accuse Liu Shunping and others of being involved in crimes of a gangland nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Xuanwei City Procuratorate also changed Liu Shunping&#39;s personal illegal facts in the original indictment to an organized crime of gathering a crowd to attack state agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Comparing the changes, the supplementary prosecution decision and the original indictment show that the incident occurred before the Spring Festival in 2012, and Liu Shunping claimed that the Longtan Town Government of Xuanwei City had defaulted on his debts. On the grounds of receiving project funds, he instigated others to hire several villagers at a salary of 100 yuan per day to make noise and move around the Longtan Town government office area, eat free food in the government cafeteria, and lock official cars for more than ten days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, in the original indictment, the two criminal facts of picking quarrels and provoking troubles, one criminal fact of extortion, and one illegal detention crime that Liu Shunping did not participate in were all disclosed. The change was made to Liu Shunping&#39;s &quot;behind-the-scenes command and tacit approval.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The decision also added the criminal facts of Liu Shunping&#39;s collusion in bidding and the criminal facts of illegal detention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the fact of a new illegal detention crime is that in January 2015, Liu Shunping and Liu Shunfu arranged for others to detain Tao Zongzuo in order to collect illegal debts. , Yin Deping restricted his personal freedom for about 9 hours, and beat, insulted, and coerced Tao Zongzuo to force him to pay his debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Jinde said that Tao Zongzuo and Yin Deping made large loans to Liu Shunping and failed to repay them as agreed. Around 2016, Yin Deping borrowed 9 million yuan from Liu Shunping on the grounds of business turnover, but has not repaid the principal and interest so far. Around 2017, Yin Deping introduced Tao Zongzuo to borrow 22 million yuan from Liu Shunping. Tao Zongzuo has not yet repaid the principal and interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter asked Tao Zongzuo for confirmation that his mobile phone has been turned off. Judgment documents website shows that Tao Zongzuo and his company were sued many times for not fulfilling their repayment obligations and lost the lawsuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted another creditor of Tao Zongzuo. The creditor said that Tao Zongzuo was a native of Xuanwei and had borrowed money from many local business owners on the pretext of operating a coal mine. For unknown reasons, Tao Zongzuo was unable to repay the loan and left the country to avoid other creditors after the Liu Shunping case was revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A material obtained by Southern Weekend reporters showed that after Zhang Ji was arrested by the public security agency on January 13, 2019, Tao Zongzuo reported to the relevant departments on February 16 of that year Send a report letter and report Liu Shunping as an evil force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, the retrial of Liu Shunping and others&#39; gang involvement was heard in the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public information shows that in addition to the incident of lawyers&#39; mobile phones being seized during the retrial, there were also many incidents that aroused widespread public attention, including the presiding judge&#39;s persuasion before the trial. The defendant pleaded guilty, and after the four defendants left the court, the court continued a 20-minute trial in absentia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters asked the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court for relevant information, but the other party refused because the case was under trial. As of press time, the trial has not ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[受贿1647万余元，国家粮食和物资储备局原党组书记、局长张务锋被判10年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261923]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 17:10:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On December 5, 2023, the Intermediate People’s Court of Deyang City, Sichuan Province publicly announced the verdict of the former party group of the National Development and Reform Commission Zhang Wufeng, member and former Party Secretary and Director of the State Grain and Material Reserves Administration, was sentenced to ten years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 1 million; Zhang Wufeng’s property and property obtained from the crime of accepting bribes and their properties were investigated The interest shall be recovered and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/c83891fb7c8655f817d04fa7c5060faf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;3837&quot; height= &quot;2614&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/c83891fb7c8655f817d04fa7c5060faf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260777&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After trial, it was found that from 2003 to 2022, the defendant Zhang Wuli served as a member of the party group and deputy director of the former Shandong Provincial Administration for Industry and Commerce, and as deputy secretary of the Linyi Municipal Party Committee in Shandong Province , mayor, member of the Party Leadership Group of the People&#39;s Government of Shandong Province, deputy governor, member of the Party Leadership Group of the National Development and Reform Commission, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, Director of the State Administration of Grain and Material Reserves, etc. The conveniences in their positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of their powers or status, are for Relevant units and individuals provided assistance in matters such as project contracting and cadre selection and appointment, and illegally received property equivalent to more than 16.47 million yuan, of which 1.6 million yuan had not been actually obtained at the time of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/162e3745bdaeb35823b28b867e4fd622.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4215&quot; height= &quot;2783&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/162e3745bdaeb35823b28b867e4fd622.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260778&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/be7dcec647182f3fe27c350a925941b5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/be7dcec647182f3fe27c350a925941b5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260776&quot; data-mce -width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Deyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court held that the defendant Zhang Wufeng, as a state worker, took advantage of his position to seek benefits for others. Taking advantage of the convenient conditions created by one&#39;s power or status to seek illegitimate benefits for others through the behavior of staff members of other countries, illegally accepting property from others, and the amount is particularly huge, such behavior constitutes the crime of accepting bribes. In view of the fact that Zhang Wufeng truthfully confessed all his crimes after arriving at the case, took the initiative to explain some of the bribery facts that the supervisory authority had not grasped, confessed his guilt and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the property obtained from the bribery and its interest have been seized and brought to the case, some of the bribery attempts were unsuccessful, and he had made major meritorious services. It shows that there are statutory and discretionary lenient punishment circumstances, and he may be given a lighter punishment in accordance with the law. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[五月天演唱会疑似假唱：应尊重观众要求“真唱”的权利丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261919]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the suspected lip-syncing incident at the Mayday concert has attracted widespread public attention. The incident originated from the analysis video uploaded by the blogger &quot;Wheatfield Farmer&quot;. He used software to analyze the 12 song videos taken by fans at the Mayday Shanghai concert on November 16. After extracting the vocal analysis, he accused Mayday of &quot;in 12 songs. &quot;Five of the songs are lip-syncing,&quot; and another one is &quot;the first few lines are fake, but the rest are true.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident fermented, it triggered reactions from all parties. Some music bloggers said they had reported it to the China Consumers Association; the Shanghai Municipal Bureau of Culture and Tourism said it would require the organizers to cooperate with the investigation; staff of the China Performance Industry Association said they had paid attention to the matter and were &quot;waiting for the results of the cultural law enforcement department.&quot; Mayday officials first posted on Weibo that they would broadcast the entire Paris concert live online, which was interpreted by the outside world as &quot;to dispel doubts.&quot; On December 4, their agency also issued a &quot;solemn statement&quot; stating that &quot;the tour will There is no lip-synching behavior in it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, the audio and video materials of the Mayday Shanghai concert have been submitted to the local cultural market inspection department. The relevant departments will conduct scientific evaluation and analysis and publish the investigation results. Regardless of whether Mayday &quot;lip-synced&quot; this time, the old topic of &quot;lip-syncing&quot; has been thrown back into the public opinion field, which deserves further analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, this incident has brought new problems to &quot;how to define lip-synching&quot;, which requires industry research and follow-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Article 31 of the &quot;Implementing Rules of the Commercial Performance Management Regulations&quot;, lip-synching &quot;refers to the act of actors using pre-recorded songs and music instead of live singing during the performance.&quot; In this incident, judging from the blogger&#39;s accusation, Mayday&#39;s suspected lip-synching was not the simple and crude &quot;pre-recording&quot; in the past, but the method of &quot;back-up singing&quot;: importing instrumental music and music into the concert project file in advance. For the vocal track, &quot;the lower part of the verse is really sung, and the chorus is sung in the background.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If &quot;undersinging&quot; is true, then the definition of &quot;lip-syncing&quot; will have a new question: Does &quot;singing the main song really, singing under the chorus&quot; count as lip-synching? In other words, what percentage of a song must be performed live for it to be considered lip-synching? Furthermore, today, when artificial intelligence has developed to the point where it is difficult to distinguish authenticity from fake, if the AI ​​training voice in the future is &quot;promoted and applied&quot;, how should the industry define and prevent it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Commercial Performances&quot; stipulates that &quot;actors may not deceive the audience by lip-synching, and performance organizers shall not organize actors to lip-sync. No unit or individual may provide conditions for lip-synching.&quot; In fact, fake The turmoil caused by lip-synching did not start today. Similar incidents are common, and many singers have become the butt of jokes because of their genuine lip-synching. The reason is simple. Even without the constraints of the Commercial Performance Management Regulations, lip-syncing by entertainers will harm their social reputation. Lip-synching at a concert is unjustifiable in terms of professional ethics and legal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Mayday’s agency has issued a statement categorically denying lip-syncing and accusing the relevant remarks of “malicious attacks and rumors and slander”, one of the two statements must be false, and one party is destined to be suspected of violating relevant laws and regulations. This matter also deserves an authoritative investigation result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Commercial Performances&quot; stipulates that &quot;the performance organizer should send a dedicated person to supervise the performance to prevent the occurrence of lip-synching behavior.&quot; According to a staff member of the Beijing Cultural Market Law Enforcement Corps, Mayday this year Law enforcement officers were on site to supervise the six concerts in Beijing. It is worth asking whether Mayday’s suspected lip-synching was only in Shanghai this time? At the previous six concerts in Beijing, did the on-site law enforcement officers fulfill their responsibilities of &quot;supervising the performances&quot; to prevent lip-synching? This should all be clarified in subsequent investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this incident also raises a question: how to define and protect the consumer rights of commercial performance audiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Mayday’s lip-synching is true, some viewers’ demands for “refund,” “compensation,” and “apology” should be supported. Of course, there are many viewers who &quot;don&#39;t care whether they actually sing or not&quot;, and there are also many fans who regard the concert as a ticket to a meet-and-greet. After the Mayday suspected lip-synching incident, some fans also said that &quot;just feel the atmosphere of the scene&quot;, &quot;just seeing them is enough&quot; and &quot;it doesn&#39;t matter whether they lip-sync or do the real thing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a famous saying in the legal world: &quot;struggle for rights.&quot; Any right needs to be asserted before it can be implemented. It is not difficult to imagine that there are people in the audience who are serious about lip-synching, and there are also people who don&#39;t care about lip-synching. There are people in the audience who have &quot;high standards and strict requirements&quot; for the viewing experience, and there are also people who bought tickets and came in just to have fun. In reality, &quot;concert audiences&quot; are not a homogeneous group, and their expectations for &quot;quality of goods and services&quot; are also different. However, since there are audiences claiming their rights in accordance with the law and regulations, the performers should respect their demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there are a lot of lip-syncing in the European and American music circles. For example, in concerts later in his acting career, Michael Jackson would choose to lip-sync when singing and dancing some dance numbers due to physical reasons, but he The city will state in advance on its official website that the audiences who come for the &quot;moonwalk&quot; are not interested in whether they really sing or not; Pavarotti also lip-synched at the opening ceremony of the Turin Winter Olympics, but a generation of tenors can perform powerfully. He has won the admiration and respect of the world for showing up despite his illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chinese music scene, &quot;lowering expectations&quot; and &quot;advance notification&quot; are also widely used methods in the industry. For example, some singers lower the key or change the song in order to ensure the true singing effect. This is a frank admission of the voice. I can no longer really sing. In this case, it may be possible to respect the independent management rights of entertainers and require them to fulfill their obligation to inform, not to sell dogs on sheep&#39;s head, and let the market judge and consumers make their choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, in the face of the controversy over Mayday’s suspected lip-syncing, the industry must define “lip-syncing” more accurately, regulate commercial performances with more detailed legislation and law enforcement, and at the same time In accordance with the Consumer Rights and Interests Protection Act, we protect consumers’ rights to know the truth, make independent choices and fair transactions, and respect the legitimate rights and interests of consumers who come forward to question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[湖南一县委书记在下乡调研返程途中坠江身亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261911]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 15:57:45&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of December 5, the Hunan Rucheng County Party Committee Office issued a notice stating that the deputy director of the Chenzhou Municipal People’s Congress Standing Committee, Comrade Huang Siping, secretary of the Rucheng County Party Committee, died of an accident at 15:31 on December 4 on his way back from a field trip to the countryside. He was 55 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/afcac9eef4bc13d1644d339a5699a463.jpeg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;463&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/afcac9eef4bc13d1644d339a5699a463.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260766&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Previous reports&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently Recently, the news that Huang Siping, deputy director of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Chenzhou City, Hunan Province and secretary of the Rucheng County Party Committee, was rumored to have &quot;fallen into a river and died&quot; has attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, on December 4, Huang Siping fell into the river and died on his way back to the city from the countryside. The accident occurred in Fengkeng Village, Haotou Township, Rucheng County. That day, Huang Siping came to Haotou Township from the county seat for investigation. At about 1 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, Huang Siping returned to the county seat along County Road 007. When passing near the Huamuqiao Reservoir in the lower reaches of the Cangjiang River, Huang Siping got off the car and came dozens of meters away. by the river, and then fell into the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/4a6c39afd3203435ae3d0593e4df5f00.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;688&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/4a6c39afd3203435ae3d0593e4df5f00.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260765&quot; data-mce- width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Huang Siping, Deputy Director of the Standing Committee of the People’s Congress of Chenzhou City, Hunan Province and Secretary of the Rucheng County Party Committee&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Paper reported that after the incident, the accompanying personnel went into the water to rescue him, and village cadres also came to the rescue and pulled Huang Siping ashore from water about three meters deep. Medical staff from the Haotou Township Health Center rushed to the scene to provide first aid. Afterwards, Huang Siping was sent to Rucheng County People&#39;s Hospital, where he died after resuscitation failed. After the incident, local public security and other departments went to the scene to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Dafeng News report of the Chinese Business Daily, the staff of the Rucheng County Funeral Home stated that Huang Mouping was indeed sent to the county funeral home, and his body was temporarily stored here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, staff from the Rucheng County Party Committee Office said in an interview with Nandu that the matter was under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉嫌打“擦边球”被约谈，喜茶下架联名款“佛喜茶”系列]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261889]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Due to suspected violation of religious affairs management regulations, HEYTEA &quot;Buddha HEYTEA&quot; was removed from the shelves less than a week after it was launched. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 28, HeyTea and Jingdezhen China Ceramics Museum jointly launched tea latte and surrounding packaging. At noon on the day of launch, a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News noticed that the &quot;Buddha Hey Tea Latte&quot; in some stores in Guangzhou The &quot;Iron Peripheral Package&quot; has been sold out, and many consumers complained on social media that they could not buy the best-selling product &quot;Speechless Buddha&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of December 4, a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News confirmed from Heytea that Heytea has removed the joint &quot;Buddha Hey Tea&quot; series from the shelves. As for the reason for the removal, the relevant person in charge of Heytea did not disclose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/415715c6c3ff9593de6897821d6d2a7e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1423&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/415715c6c3ff9593de6897821d6d2a7e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260719&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to The Paper, the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Religious Affairs&quot;, &quot;Several Opinions on Further Governing the Commercialization of Buddhism and Taoism&quot; (Guozongfa [2017] No. 88), &quot;Measures for the Management of Internet Religious Information Services&quot; and other clear provisions , commercial promotion in the name of religion is prohibited. On December 4, staff of the Shenzhen Municipal Ethnic and Religious Affairs Bureau reported that the bureau interviewed Heytea Company on December 1st, and Heytea was removed from the shelves on December 3rd, and at the same time, it conducted an inspection on the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned staff said that after consultation and research with the ethnic and religious departments, market supervision and other departments, they (HiTea) were actually playing a &quot;side ball&quot;. &quot;Now we can only interview them, and interviewing is also legal.&quot; One of the methods, and their company is also very cooperative and has a good attitude of admitting mistakes. They sent us a rectification report on Friday night, and they have all been removed from the shelves on December 3.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中央生态环保督察：甘肃张掖网红景点涉未批先建、违规取水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/12/05/ea9137e62a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/ 05/ea9137e62a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Zhangye Lushuiwan Scenic Area. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The blue lake is suspected of &quot;illegal water intake&quot;, and the beautiful scenery is suspected of being &quot;built without approval.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 4, 2023, the leading group meeting for the rectification and reform of the central ecological and environmental protection inspectorate’s public notification of typical cases in Zhangye City, Gansu Province was held, and it was proposed to carry out law learning, law popularization and law enforcement activities in the ecological and agricultural fields throughout the city , focus on rectifying problems such as illegal water abstraction and use, and carry out actions for the Year of Breakthrough in Water Resources Standardization Management, the Year of Reform of Water Rights, Prices, and Water Management Systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously on December 1, Zhangye City’s Lushui Bay Scenic Area was notified by the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Supervision Group that the core landscape of the scenic area-three artificial water surfaces were built before approval in 2011, with an excavation volume of 465 10,000 cubic meters, with a water area of ​​2,250 acres, approximately equal to the water system area of ​​two Beijing Olympic Forest Parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lushui Bay in the early winter morning, a thin layer of ice formed on the lake, reflecting the blue sky. Citizens were jogging on the greenway around the lake. Hotels, restaurants, art centers, and Olympic sports centers were built around the lake. , entertainment clubs, etc. are waiting for guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lushui Bay is a ten-minute drive from the center of Zhangye. It used to be a mine left behind by sand mining. It is now a national AAAA-level tourist attraction and &quot;the most beautiful scenery in the development of ecological tourism in the Hexi Corridor.&quot; In July 2023, a &quot;Water Carnival&quot; was held here. Someone on the social media platform commented that &quot;it does not have the dust of the northwest, but has the feeling of beautiful mountains and clear waters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/f549fa2025.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/f549fa2025.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;An exhibition board near the Lushui Bay Scenic Area shows comparison pictures before and after construction. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the reputation, the artificial water surface in the scenic spot has never been issued a water abstraction permit-26 million cubic meters of water will be abstracted from the Heihe River in 2022 alone, which is equivalent to nearly half a year of life in Zhangye City Use water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The weak water in &quot;Three thousand weak waters, only take one scoop to drink&quot; is the Black River. The Heihe River originates from Qinghai, and Zhangye City is located in the middle reaches. It contains more than 90% of the cultivated land and population in the basin, and more than 80% of the water consumption and GDP. Lushui Bay is known as Zhangye&#39;s &quot;humidifier&quot;, but if too much water is intercepted, it may affect downstream water use. The Ejina Banner of Alxa League in Inner Mongolia in the lower reaches of the Heihe River is one of the origins of sandstorms in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhangye, located in the Hexi Corridor, is located at the intersection of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau and the Inner Mongolia Plateau. It is a natural oasis on the Silk Road. The &quot;gold&quot; in the ancient name &quot;Jin Zhangye&quot; not only reflects the wealth of this place, but also shows that in this arid zone oasis, water resources are as precious as gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Including Lushuiwan Scenic Area, the inspection report showed that there are more than 30 artificial water surfaces in Zhangye City with illegal and illegal problems, with a total water area of ​​more than 6,000 acres. These artificial water surfaces, which have only appeared in the past ten years, also carry expectations for the transformation and upgrading of Zhangye&#39;s cultural tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Zhangye City was designated as my country&#39;s first water-saving society pilot area by the Ministry of Water Resources as early as 2002, and has made many water-saving explorations. However, this time the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspectorate not only reported that Zhangye illegally extracted surface water, but also failed to control over-exploitation of groundwater. &quot;Zhangye City has not implemented the strictest water resources management system in place. Economic development and urban construction have not fully considered the water environment carrying capacity of the Heihe River Basin. The problem of inaction and random actions by some departments is outstanding.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1,248 acres of artificial The water is involved in &quot;building before approval&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhangye Ganzhou is known as &quot;half city of reeds, half city of pagoda shadows&quot;. The name &quot;Lushui Bay&quot; may place its hope on recreating its historical features. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with famous scenic spots such as Zhangye Danxia National Geopark, Lushui Bay is a new attraction. Before 2009, there was no open water landscape here, but rocky beaches, sand pits, stone quarries, and construction waste dumps, all of which were inaccessible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking from the map, the Lushuiwan Scenic Area is connected by three artificial lakes. To the northeast is the Zhangye National Wetland Park, which was built at the same time. The two together form the Lushuiwan Tourist Resort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9fe1fabd75.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9fe1fabd75.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Zhangye National Wetland Park. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the Luchuiwan scenic spot is beautiful and crowded with tourists; in the wetland park, great egrets &quot;stand guard&quot; next to the water plants, and densely packed white mergansers, pintail ducks, Red-billed pochards are waiting on the water to hold a &quot;meeting&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development and construction of Lushuiwan tourist resort, the bungalows and shanties here were demolished, and lake-view community houses were built one after another. Song Xiaoyu, associate researcher at the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and others have made calculations. In 2011, the average selling price of commercial housing within a 500-meter radius of Zhangye National Wetland Park was 3,232 yuan/square meter, rising to 4,147 yuan/square meter in 2021. square meter, excluding factors such as inflation and infrastructure construction, the landscape value premium of the wetland park is 715 yuan/square meter, and the total added value of the landscape reaches 32 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9fed4194bd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9fed4194bd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Zhangye National Wetland Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past, there was a rock and sand quarry, and today we are an ecologically happy river.” The transformation of Lushui Bay has been promoted as a positive and typical case of ecological and environmental governance. However, as the core landscape in the Lushui Bay Scenic Area, the artificial water surface was notified by the inspection team as being built before approval. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the staff of Zhangye Water Affairs Bureau, the preliminary procedures involved in the artificial lake include: project approval, construction project land pre-examination opinion, environmental impact report approval, water resources demonstration report approval, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inspection team members said that almost none of these procedures were completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person familiar with the Zhangye Municipal Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the Lushui Bay Scenic Area project did not have a project approval from the development and reform department, and there was no environmental impact assessment of the construction project. &quot;The project approval is a birth certificate, otherwise it is &#39; Black households&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Lushuiwan Scenic Area, which was built 12 years ago, has not gone through the relevant procedures, which is incredible. “Lushui Bay is so good that everyone is used to it,” said the above-mentioned person familiar with the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The artificial water surfaces built before approval in Zhangye are not an isolated case. They also include 11 artificial water surfaces in the Olympic Forest Park (referred to as Orson Park) across the river from Lushui Bay, totaling 1,248 acres. Since the country strengthened the investigation and rectification of &quot;lake digging and landscaping&quot; in June 2020, two artificial lakes have been newly built in Zhangye Ruoshui Park, with a water area of ​​165 acres; the newly built artificial lakes in Baita Rainbow Park and the park on the west side of Zhangye Grand Theater have It also occupied 24.4 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Mine pit turned into park, lack of ecological restoration plan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the artificial water surfaces reported by the inspector, the water intake area of ​​Zhangye Aosen Park is second only to the artificial lake in Lushui Bay Scenic Area, equivalent to half of the latter. Its story is also similar to Lushui Bay: restoration-planting trees-water diversion-development-development of tourism + real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before 2017, the original site of Aosen Park was a deserted Gobi desert with no grass growing on it. There were many large pits left by sand and gravel mining in the sand and gravel factory. The relevant person in charge of the Zhangye Water Conservancy Bureau responded to Southern Weekend Reporters, diverting water from the Heihe River to build artificial water surfaces is an ecological restoration method that “kills two birds with one stone”: the mine pits are treated to prevent seepage and then filled with water, which is low-cost; the water storage can also provide water sources for the surrounding forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/a36244a7a3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/a36244a7a3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Zhangye Olympic Forest Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Aosen Park is the largest artificial afforestation base in Zhangye - as of 2023, Aosen Park has completed 60,000 acres of afforestation and greening, and built 37 new water storage ponds and dams. 22.41 kilometers of river channels were dredged. According to its plan, it attempts to create an ecological leisure and health gathering area integrating tourism, health care, sports and entertainment. Aosen Park not only plans to build distribution plazas, sports fields and parking lots, but also supports Shenkeng Hotel, Heihe Water Ecology Museum, Forest Health Care Community, Forest Sports Town, etc. The investment is estimated to reach 2.86 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inspection team members believe that these mines should develop tailor-made ecological restoration plans in accordance with relevant national management regulations and scientifically demonstrate their ecological impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the person in charge of the Ganzhou District Heihe Forestry Farm, the unit responsible for the Osun Park project, said frankly that how to repair the more than 40 mine pits, whether to cover them with soil and then plant grass and trees, or to prevent seepage and then fill them with water , and no ecological restoration plan has been carried out independently. Finally, depending on factors such as the topography of the mine pit, some cover the area with soil and then plant trees, while others do anti-seepage and then inject water. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why not apply for a water abstraction permit? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Open the satellite map on your mobile phone. The green Zhangye is surrounded by the yellow Gobi Desert. Pieces of agate-like blue water are embedded in the territory of Zhangye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhangye is not rich in water resources. Zhangye has a temperate arid climate, with annual precipitation of only 100-250 mm, but annual evaporation as high as 1400-2700 mm. These artificial water surfaces are created mainly from the Heihe River flowing through Zhangye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/2dd96aa896.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;553&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/2dd96aa896.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The artificial water surface in the Lushui Bay Scenic Area contrasts sharply with the dry Heihe River bed next to it. Screenshot of the video of the inspection team&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are there no water abstraction permits for these artificial water surfaces? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ganzhou District Water Affairs Bureau of Zhangye City explained that the water in the Lushui Bay Scenic Area is diverted from the surrounding agricultural main canals. The water in the main canals has obtained a water abstraction permit. The water consumption of the artificial water surface in Lushui Bay is increased by the main canals. The water consumption for agricultural irrigation does not exceed the total water permit. However, members of the inspection team said that the permitted use of water in the main canal is limited to agricultural irrigation, and the artificial water surface in the Lushui Bay Scenic Area is ecological water and does not comply with the water intake permit regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only does Lushui Bay Scenic Area not have a water permit. The inspector reported that Zhangye Ruoshui Huahai Scenic Area has not applied for a water abstraction license from 2016 to 2021. After applying for a new license in 2022, it still drew an excess of 67,000 cubic meters of water from the Heihe River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/3580c4d48a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/3580c4d48a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Zhangye Ruoshuihuahai Scenic Area. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The runoff of the Heihe River has been relatively low in recent years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A bigger concern is whether diverting water from the Heihe River to create such a large-scale artificial water surface in the city will affect downstream water use And ecology? According to the Heihe River water diversion plan determined by the State Council in 1997, about 60% of the water volume was released downstream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Zhangye Water Affairs Bureau said that since August 2000, Zhangye City has continuously completed the water diversion tasks from the Heihe River. Especially in 2023, the precipitation will be 20% less than in previous years, and the annual runoff will be dry. However, The discharge task has still been exceeded, and the downstream Dongjuyan Sea has not dried up since 2004. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, relevant people believe that Zhangye’s arid climate, high evaporation, and illegal construction of artificial water surfaces in the city have exacerbated water shortages. The performance may not be obvious during the wet season, but in recent years the Heihe River runoff has been relatively dry, which has already revealed ecological risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/e391ba7df0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;551&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/e391ba7df0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The artificial water surface in the Lushui Bay Scenic Area contrasts sharply with the dry Heihe River bed next to it. Screenshot of the video of the inspection team&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gansu Provincial Hydrological Station introduced that since 2003, the Heihe River has entered a rare 18-year continuous wet season. Song Xiaoyu said that according to data from the Yingluoxia Hydrological Station in the upper reaches of the Heihe River, the multi-year average runoff entering the middle reaches is about 1.58 billion cubic meters. The average annual runoff from 2005 to 2020 exceeded 2 billion cubic meters, reaching a peak of 23.5 in 2017. One hundred million cubic meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ejina Banner in the lower reaches of the Heihe River feels the greatest changes in water volume. According to &quot;Ban Yue Tan&quot;, from 2016 to 2020, the number of days when rivers in Ejina Banner were closed was reduced from the previous average of 250 days to 55 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the runoff of the Heihe River has decreased in recent years. According to the Gansu Provincial Hydrological Station, the runoff during the 2023 dispatch period is only 1.38 billion cubic meters, less than 60% of the peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, the Ejina oasis ecology, which has already improved, has begun to &quot;cry thirsty&quot; again. Data provided by the Alxa League Water Conservancy Bureau to &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot; shows: Since 2020, the Ejina in the Heihe River Basin has The number of flow-free days in this section has been around 100 for three consecutive years. On May 20, 2022, the entire Ejina section of the Heihe River Basin was cut off. The East Juyan Sea has not received water supply for more than 10 months. Many lakes and wetlands have dried up one after another. Degenerative trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/1cf473b8e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/1cf473b8e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260742&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On October 14, 2023, Alxa League, Inner Mongolia, aerial photography of the ancient residence of Yanze. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ineffective management of groundwater overexploitation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The annual runoff of the Heihe River is relatively low, which is also reflected in Zhangye&#39;s groundwater level data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspector reported that the groundwater level in Zhangye City continues to decline due to overexploitation of groundwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the notification mechanism for water level changes in groundwater overexploitation areas established by the Ministry of Water Resources and the Ministry of Natural Resources, the groundwater level in Zhangye City has dropped year-on-year in almost every quarter from 2020 to 2023. For example, in the first three quarters of 2023, respectively Year-on-year decreases of 0.39, 0.26, and 0.81 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, due to long-term large-scale extraction of groundwater, Zhangye City has formed 7 over-exploitation areas, all of which are restricted mining areas. The &quot;Groundwater Management Regulations&quot; stipulate that the provincial water conservancy department, in conjunction with the natural resources and other departments, organizes the delineation of groundwater prohibited and restricted areas within the administrative region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspector also reported that since 2020, thousands of excessive water withdrawal problems have occurred in Zhangye&#39;s over-mining area, and the local water affairs department has basically failed to investigate and deal with them in accordance with the law. In the restricted mining area, 160 million cubic meters of groundwater was used beyond the permitted limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter, the relevant person in charge of the Zhangye City Water Affairs Bureau said that although some water wells drew more groundwater than allowed, other wells drew less water than allowed, and the total amount of groundwater drawn in the region was not. Exceeds total permitted range. The reason why there are no administrative penalties for thousands of excessive water withdrawals is because the local government implements a tiered water price mechanism. After exceeding the permitted water use, higher water fees can be charged and adjusted through market mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, relevant analysts believe that this move is suspected of &quot;selling water&quot; and is not conducive to the management of groundwater overexploitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, the State Council&#39;s &quot;Opinions on Implementing the Strict Water Resources Management System&quot; required that &quot;in areas where groundwater is over-exploited, new withdrawals of groundwater from agriculture, industrial construction projects and service industries are prohibited.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspector reported that since 2016, the local water department has illegally approved 20 wells including Zhiyuan Forestry Technology Co., Ltd. In January 2016, the Gansu Provincial Department of Water Resources required that all self-provided water wells within the coverage of the public water supply network be closed in 2016. Not only did Zhangye City fail to implement the relevant requirements, it even issued water abstraction licenses for 49 wells of enterprises in the Economic Development Zone. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that the groundwater data provided by the relevant authorities in Zhangye City are confusing and contradictory. The 2015 groundwater water consumption data provided by the Municipal Water Affairs Bureau to the inspection team differed by more than 46 million cubic meters from the data provided to reporters. Southern Weekend reporters asked the Municipal Water Affairs Bureau for the reason, but as of press time, no reply has been received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inspector stated that this was not an isolated case. During the inspection process, due to the prominent cases of misreporting, concealment and false reporting by relevant competent authorities, the workload of on-site verification was greatly increased. For example, the inspection team reviewed the list of self-provided water wells covered by Zhangye City’s public water supply pipe network. The Municipal Water Affairs Bureau only provided a list of Ganzhou District, including the water wells of three companies. However, the inspection team went to the Economic Development Zone in Ganzhou District for on-site inspection and found that there were 49 water wells in dozens of companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Water conservation requires institutional reform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In winter, the Heihe River enters the dry season. When driving on the Zhangye Heihe River Bridge, the river bed under the bridge has dried up, exposing yellow soil and gray sand and gravel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/3196d705e1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/3196d705e1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;At the end of November 2023, in the Zhangye Heihe River section in winter, some rivers had dried up. Photo by Southern Weekend Lin Fangzhou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The per capita water resource in Zhangye City is only 1,250 cubic meters, which is 60% of the national average. As a large agricultural city, the average water quantity per mu is only 511 cubic meters, which is only 60% of the national average. Thirty percent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhangye’s water resource shortage is inseparable from its economic structure. In 2022, Zhangye&#39;s three industrial structure ratios will be 29.3:20.4:50.3, with agriculture accounting for a larger proportion of the economy than industry. Agricultural water accounts for about 90% of the city’s water use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thanks to climatic advantages such as long sunshine hours and large temperature differences between day and night, Zhangye is rich in high-quality agricultural products. The &quot;Wujiang tribute rice&quot;, which has been famous since the Tang Dynasty because the rice grains do not stick together after being cooked, has been significantly reduced due to the water-saving rice planting area. On the large tracts of farmland near Lushuiwan Scenic Area and Aosen Park, billboards proclaiming &quot;100,000 acres of vegetable base for Guangdong, Hong Kong and Macao&quot; were erected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seasonal distribution of water resources in the Heihe River is uneven, and the timing of incoming water and agricultural water use is not completely coordinated. Song Xiaoyu told Southern Weekend reporters that the Heihe River water resources come from glaciers, frozen soil, snowmelt water and rainfall. The precipitation is mainly concentrated from July to September, and from March to June when agricultural water is most urgent, 60 to 70% The water needs to be supplied by glaciers, frozen soil, and melted snow. Winter snowfall and snow contribute 20%-25% of the water source to the Heihe River runoff in the second year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xiaoyu said that Zhangye, located in high latitudes and high altitudes, is a sensitive area greatly affected by climate change. The temperature is increasing at a faster rate. The glacier area has decreased by about 20% in the past 50 years, and the snow line is also rising. From October to December 2022, the snowfall in Shandan, Minle and Sunan counties in Zhangye was 70% less than the average of the past ten years. The decrease in surface runoff has also led to an increase in groundwater withdrawals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under such economic, social and climatic conditions, Zhangye urgently needs to further improve water resource utilization. Song Xiaoyu believes that Zhangye City has gone through long-term exploration of water conservation work, and the current irrigation efficiency is already at a high level. The next step is to make breakthroughs in institutional mechanisms, such as further deepening the reform of agricultural water rights and water prices, improving the water rights trading system, and continuing to promote High-standard farmland construction, accelerating industrial structure adjustment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xiaoyu and others have conducted research on Ganzhou District of Zhangye City and found that optimizing the water rights allocation model, high-standard farmland construction and industrial structure adjustment can respectively increase the comprehensive carrying capacity of water resources by up to 1.87%. , 8.72% and 3.06%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For local authorities, institutional reform faces many challenges such as funding, technology, and talent. However, in order to continue to optimize water resource management and improve water resource utilization efficiency, this work is imperative. .&quot; Song Xiaoyu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[裁判文书里出现“安徽省南京市”？深圳福田法院通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 15:05:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Situation Report&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, some media pointed out Our court has corrected the misstatement of &quot;Nanjing City, Anhui Province&quot; in the enforcement ruling. At the same time, we have ordered the relevant responsible persons to make a profound review and hold them seriously accountable. Our hospital will take this as a lesson, strengthen management, and effectively improve the quality of judgment documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen Futian District People&#39;s Court&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;December 5, 2023&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部：学生患病期间的作业不做硬性要求]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261905]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 15:10:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Preventing and Controlling Epidemic Diseases in Winter Schools&quot; to deploy various arrangements Educational administrative departments and schools must effectively prevent and control epidemic diseases in winter to ensure the health of teachers and students and the normal order of education and teaching. The &quot;Notice&quot; focuses on six aspects of work requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;First, attach great importance to the common prevention of multiple diseases. &lt;/strong>;Fully understand the current work situation and significance of epidemic prevention and control in winter, adhere to bottom-line thinking and common prevention of multiple diseases, and respond to the possible overlapping epidemic periods and alternating epidemic peaks of multiple epidemic diseases, Make scientific and effective responses according to the time and situation, and solidly implement various prevention and control measures to protect the lives, health and safety of teachers and students to the greatest extent possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The second is to strengthen monitoring and early warning intervention. &lt;/strong>;Strengthen the construction of the epidemic monitoring system, focusing on the implementation of morning and afternoon inspection systems for primary and secondary schools and kindergartens, infectious disease epidemic reporting systems, and tracking and registration systems for absences due to illness. Regarding the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases in local schools, proactively consult with the health and disease control departments to strengthen information exchange, collaboratively carry out risk analysis and prediction and early warning, and guide schools to achieve scientific and accurate responses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The third is to strengthen daily health education. &lt;/strong>;Carry out full-coverage, multi-form publicity on prevention and control knowledge of COVID-19 infection and other winter epidemic diseases. Teachers and students should be guided to deepen the concept of &quot;everyone is the first person responsible for their own health&quot;, wear masks scientifically, wash hands frequently, ventilate frequently, pay attention to cough etiquette, participate in appropriate exercises, and improve health literacy and self-protection capabilities. Strengthen family epidemic prevention guidance, and cooperate with relevant departments to promote and guide children and adolescents on influenza, pneumococcal and other vaccinations. Instruct teachers and students with symptoms such as fever and cough to take protective measures, seek medical treatment promptly, standardize treatment, use medicine scientifically, and attend school without illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The fourth is to strengthen services for sick students. &lt;/strong>;We will improve the response plan, ensure an orderly connection between online and offline teaching, and guide students who are absent from school due to illness to use rich online teaching resources to study at home. There are no strict requirements for students’ homework during their illness. Based on the characteristics of the course of respiratory diseases, parents are guided to allow sick students to receive adequate treatment and rest, and to make practical and scientific arrangements for returning to school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The fifth is to provide material support. &lt;/strong>;Work with the health and disease control departments to scientifically predict possible epidemics, dynamically adjust epidemic prevention material reserves, ensure the supply of medical and daily supplies, and improve the level of medical service security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sixth, we must pay close attention to the implementation of responsibilities. &lt;/strong>;Work with the health and disease control departments to strengthen the organization, leadership, supervision and inspection of the prevention and control of winter epidemic diseases, coordinate the advancement, and work together to ensure that all prevention and control measures are implemented in detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2022年全国教育经费总投入首次超过6万亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 14:28:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Ministry of Education, the National Bureau of Statistics, and the Ministry of Finance recently released a statistical announcement on the implementation of national education funding in 2022. The announcement shows that the total investment in education funding nationwide in 2022 will be 6.132914 billion yuan, exceeding 6 trillion yuan for the first time, an increase of 5.97% over the previous year. The national financial education funding is 4.847291 billion yuan, an increase of 5.75% over the previous year, accounting for 4.01% of the GDP, and achieving &quot;generally no less than 4%.&quot; The national general public budget education funding was 3.925696 billion yuan, an increase of 4.79% over the previous year, accounting for 15.07% of the general public budget expenditure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the statistical announcement, the national average general public budget education funding based on the number of students in school in 2022 will be 15,731.97 yuan, an increase of 2.44% over the previous year. The growth rates of general public budget education funding per student in kindergartens, ordinary primary schools, ordinary junior high schools, ordinary high schools, secondary vocational schools, and ordinary colleges and universities across the country are: 7.29%, 3.32%, 2.14%, 1.64%, 2.14%, and -1.69% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 14:55:22 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[那些痴迷过山车的人：“事故是小概率事件”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261892]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73989&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70780&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/9194657f29.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG239.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;2016, Busch Gardens Tampa, USA , the roller coaster &quot;Cheetah&quot;. Photo by Xun Hang&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/ 9194657f29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260729&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2016, Busch Gardens, Tampa, USA, roller coaster&quot; Cheetah&quot;. Photo by Xun Hang&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On National Day this year, Xun Hang completed the 480th roller coaster check-in in Europe. As a high-risk amusement equipment, roller coasters have a history of more than 100 years since their birth in the 19th century, and have been introduced to China for nearly 40 years. To some extent, they have become a reference for measuring the configuration level of an amusement park. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t have the most, some friends have more than 800.&quot; Xun Hang, 32, has been riding roller coasters for ten years. &quot;. He could not remember the details of his first roller coaster ride as a child. He only remembered that &quot;it felt like I was going to fly. It was very exciting and very happy.&quot; Since then, I have wanted to go to an amusement park every holiday, and every time I go to an amusement park, I must ride the roller coaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Among the many projects in amusement parks, most equipment is highly homogeneous, but roller coasters can be infinitely varied.&quot; In order to have a better and more experience It’s a rollercoaster. When he was a student, Xun Hang visited many cities in China. After working as an adult, he expanded his footprints to North America, Japan, South Korea, Australia, Europe, the Middle East and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is difficult to explain to outsiders why my hobby is riding roller coasters. Around 2010, Xun Hang found several roller coaster fans like himself through some forums and forums. In order to keep warm and share information, they formed a fan group called &quot;Roller Coaster Dream&quot;. Thirteen years later, this small team, which started with just a few people, now has nearly 150 members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 27, 2023, an accident occurred at the roller coaster &quot;Snow Eagle&quot; project in Shenzhen Happy Valley. A roller coaster broke down after going uphill along the track. It slipped and collided with another roller coaster that had arrived at the station and was discharging passengers, resulting in 4 serious injuries and 13 minor injuries. In November, the State Administration for Market Regulation deployed a nationwide special investigation and management of hidden dangers of roller coaster accidents to resolutely prevent the recurrence of roller coaster accidents like the &quot;10·27&quot; roller coaster accident at Shenzhen Happy Valley. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite major negative events, the enthusiasm of roller coaster fans has not diminished. Xun Hang noticed that most members of &quot;Roller Coaster Dream&quot; regarded the above-mentioned accidents as sporadic cases and regarded them as &quot;small probability events.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73962&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70753&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/05/86d66a1897.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111461504461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;On October 20, 2021, tourists at the Shenzhen Happy Valley roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; kept screaming while playing. Visual China&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/86d66a1897.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260730 &quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 20, 2021, tourists were playing the Shenzhen Happy Valley roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project The screaming continued. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;One in 17 million chance of injury&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; roller coaster in Shenzhen Happy Valley , officially opened in July 2012, with a total of two trains. The track length of the car is 887 meters, with the highest point reaching 60 meters. It is one of the tallest and longest catapult roller coasters built in China. It can run at a speed of 135 kilometers per hour. It is also one of the fastest roller coasters built in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We didn&#39;t believe it at first, but later we realized it was true.&quot; Yang Kaichun, a member of &quot;Roller Coaster Dream&quot; said that the reason why he was surprised was because &quot; &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; has the &quot;very safe&quot; elements recognized by experienced players - brand parks, large-scale equipment and first-tier manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;23-year-old Yang Kaichun has experience riding nearly 200 roller coasters. The first time he rode a roller coaster, he was in sixth grade at Lotte World in South Korea. He was timid and reluctantly got on the roller coaster with the encouragement of his mother and the companionship of his younger brother. &quot;I sat down and took a lap and found that it was different from what I thought. Not only was it not scary, it was also very exciting. After sitting there, I was still unsatisfied and wanted to wait in line again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;This experience made Yang Kaichun have a strong interest in roller coasters. What is the control system of this unpowered car? How are the track paths designed? How to grasp human physiological limits during tumbling and spinning? How relevant is the human riding experience to the overall design? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to satisfy his curiosity, Yang Kaichun not only searched for roller coaster-related materials on the Internet, but also visited various parks at home and abroad. He even chose to go to college. majored in mechanical engineering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Roller coaster is a niche hobby, but Yang Kaichun has found many like-minded friends. In addition to sharing his experience on roller coasters, he also enjoys discussing the mechanical principles and control systems of roller coasters with like-minded people. &quot;It was a very pure and selfless exchange. Everyone didn&#39;t care whether they offended others. They just quarreled over an issue, but it didn&#39;t affect their feelings at all. Everyone purely loved roller coasters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the &quot;October 27&quot; roller coaster accident at Shenzhen Happy Valley, a heated discussion started in the &quot;Roller Coaster Dream&quot; WeChat group. &quot;The discussion started mainly at the technical level, and everyone speculated that there might be a problem with the anti-retraction device.&quot; Xun Hang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xun Hang said that among the members of &quot;Roller Coaster Dream&quot;, some may reduce the frequency of riding similar roller coasters from the same manufacturer in the near future, but overall, &quot;the It’s time to go to the amusement park to visit the amusement park.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the past ten years of riding experience on hundreds of roller coasters, these roller coaster fans claim that they have never encountered personal safety incidents, which makes them believe that roller coasters The safety is very high. &quot;If the probability of an accident on an airplane is much lower than driving to the airport (the probability of an accident), then the probability of an accident on a roller coaster is also much lower than driving to the amusement park.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xunhang brushed 480 cars. He only experienced a bumpy ride caused by the uneven track of the roller coaster, which &quot;knocked his knees red&quot;; fans both (pseudonyms) brushed the cars More than 320 vehicles have never experienced a &quot;risk situation&quot;, but they encountered service personnel buckling their shoulders but not wearing seat belts when riding in a car, and did not carry out &quot;double insurance&quot;; Yang Kaichun brushed 200 vehicles and experienced this in the United States. During a &quot;hanging parking&quot;, the car climbed to the highest point and got stuck. Finally, under the command of the park management staff, everyone collectively &quot;jumped&quot; forward before continuing to &quot;start&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The safety of roller coasters reflected in individual experience also has some objective basis. According to statistics from the International Association of Amusement Parks and Attractions in October 2023, the probability of people being injured on amusement equipment is about 3.7 times per million people, which is lower than playing football, swimming, cycling, etc. Based on a three-year average, the probability of someone being injured on a fixed theme park ride is one in 17 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;If the vehicle hovers in the preset area, or encounters collisions, etc., these are common problems that will not cause safety issues for passengers. Not only are we not afraid , such as hovering, sometimes I hope to experience it and enrich the riding experience.&quot; Xun Hang said. Other roller coaster enthusiasts interviewed were similar to Xun Hang in their identification of roller coaster safety risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, in the eyes of professionals, hovering is not always a &quot;common problem&quot; even if it does not cause casualties. &quot;Under normal circumstances, if passengers hover in a normal position, there will be no safety problems. However, if the hovering time is too long, or if the hovering is upside down with the head down, many parks will pay special attention to it, and even if the situation is serious, Report it to the national competent authority,&quot; said Han Zhiyi, a well-known theme park executive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Huanjie, president of the China Theme Park Research Institute, reminded that whether it is a small problem or a major accident, tourists should maintain their safety when riding a roller coaster and encounter unexpected situations such as hovering. Stay calm and wait patiently for guidance and rescue from the staff. Do not shake the car violently out of excitement and panic. &quot;Because people&#39;s excessive reactions may affect the equipment&#39;s ability to handle emergency situations according to the design plan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73963&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70754&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/dcbccc433c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111454610890.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 17, 2023 local time, A roller coaster at the Oktoberfest in Munich, Germany. Two roller coasters collided at the Oktoberfest on September 16, causing 8 injuries. Visual China&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/dcbccc433c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260731&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 17, 2023 local time, Munich, Germany, the roller coaster at the Oktoberfest. On September 16, two roller coasters collided at the Munich Oktoberfest, injuring eight people. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Every car has a new experience” &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Different from the short-lived stimulating experience that ordinary tourists occasionally ride on a roller coaster, The experience gained by these experienced players from high-frequency car brushing seems to better capture the designer&#39;s intention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I think roller coasters are the epitome of contemporary human wisdom. Whether roller coasters are excellent or not often tests the artistic aesthetics, manufacturing technology, scientific and technological level of designers and manufacturers, and even medicine. Common sense.&quot; Xun Hang said. He believes that the wonderful thing about roller coasters is that almost every car has a new experience, and even the same car has a different feeling every time it is ridden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the National Day holiday this year, Xun Hang rode a catapult-type spinning roller coaster in Belgium. In his opinion, this car not only combines two seemingly unrelated elements of spin and electromagnetic ejection, but also relies on the up and down track to allow riders to experience ejection one after another. &quot;The car body is always spinning irregularly, and you never seem to know what the next spin will feel like.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This roller coaster also has an electromagnetic section In the ejection area, the vehicle travels to the second section. Relying on a vertical undulating slope section, the roller coaster accelerates while losing weight. There are also tumbling elements interspersed in the middle, making people feel like they are in a washing machine. The overall feeling was hearty and comfortable, so much so that Xun Hang &quot;swiped it 8 times a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Compared with the feeling of pushing back and explosive power, I especially prefer the feeling of weightlessness brought by roller coasters. The heart feels like being pulled up, and people will experience a kind of weightlessness. The ultimate pleasure.&quot; Xun Hang said. This ride experience in Belgium greatly satisfied his preference for weightlessness, so it became his &quot;favorite&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for Yang Kaichun, in addition to the ultimate riding experience, he also hopes to know what is happening and why. All aspects related to the roller coaster riding experience will become his exploration issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In terms of the appearance of the track, the material used is often hard steel, but when it forms the winding and circling track of the roller coaster, it appears smooth and smooth, and the overall appearance A kind of beauty that combines strength and softness. The track construction of some large-scale parks can often become landmark buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a vehicle without power, the riding experience of a roller coaster is often closely related to the direction of the track. Under different logics, designers need to consider not only whether the passengers will The physical safety of being dropped also needs to consider what physiological reactions a person will have as their physical position changes under a given sprint, rotation or gravity acceleration, and explore the safety margin of this reaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Under a given acceleration of gravity, a person&#39;s body may be suspended in the air, or as if he is flying, or as if he is climbing on top of a boulder... I am very curious about this kind of How do you create a safe, moderate but exciting feeling?&quot; Yang Kaichun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Both like the ups and downs of riding a roller coaster, and can also immerse themselves in the fun of different themes. Parks in different countries will have different themes when building roller coasters. For example, most Chinese parks will incorporate some traditional cultural elements, while European and American parks will be linked to Disney, Marvel and other styles. Along with lighting, VR, water spray and other effects, riding a roller coaster is often like experiencing a &quot;fantasy journey&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More often, they simply like the happiness brought by roller coasters. This kind of happiness is not only brought by physical stimulation, but also by the excitement surrounding them. A happy atmosphere. &quot;Whether you are watching the roller coaster or riding the roller coaster, everyone is very happy. Seeing so many happy smiling faces makes you happy too.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73988&quot; group- id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70779&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/05/e246b49bf9.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG230.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;In 2016, the roller coaster &quot;El Toro&quot; at Six Flags Great Adventure in the United States. Photo by Xun Hang&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/05/e246b49bf9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;260732&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;In 2016, the roller coaster &quot;El Toro&quot; at Six Flags Great Adventure in the United States. Photo by Xun Hang&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“China’s safety standards are stricter”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Car fans believe that their trust in the safety of roller coasters does not arise blindly . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As an iconic amusement facility that has gone through a century of history, roller coasters have corresponding safety standards for their production, installation, operation, maintenance, and retirement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Huanjie introduced that at present, domestic large-scale roller coasters are mainly imported. Such equipment must be submitted to China&#39;s special equipment testing agency for review during the design stage. Place an order for production, and a dedicated person needs to be assigned to supervise on-site during the production process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the roller coaster is installed, it needs to complete a certain hour of testing in accordance with the manufacturer&#39;s requirements, and then conduct an idling test and load test again in accordance with China&#39;s national standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the equipment declaration and operation stage, the regulatory authorities will not only review the filing materials, but also conduct on-site testing of the equipment. After completion, the trial operation qualification will be issued first. During this period, no safety problems will occur, and then the formal operation qualification will be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the official operation, in addition to regular inspections such as daily inspection, monthly inspection, and annual inspection, the roller coaster will also conduct safety management and maintenance of the equipment in accordance with the requirements of the manufacturer. Welcome the random inspection by the superior unit of the park and the corresponding regulatory department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corresponding to the aforementioned security defense lines, there is a series of institutional documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many interviewees mentioned that when it comes to the management of roller coasters, China’s safety standards are stricter than those in countries such as Europe, the United States, Japan and South Korea. &quot;For example, when we play in China, we are generally not allowed to bring backpacks, mobile phones, keys and other items, but in European and American countries, they are more casual and don&#39;t care much.&quot; Yang Kaichun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lin Huanjie believes that safety problems in roller coasters are generally related to front-end design flaws, mid-end detection loopholes, and inadequate follow-up operation and maintenance. In reality, &quot;it is difficult for a large-scale accident to occur if there is a simple flaw in a certain link. Safety problems are often caused by the accumulation of layer-by-layer failures in multiple security inspection links.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the interviewees related to the operation and management of the park said that the safety issues of roller coasters in the real environment are often related to whether the operator strictly follows the Provisions are made to implement inspection, maintenance and upkeep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;For example, in order to save money, some operators do not replace some parts that should be replaced, do not repair those that should be repaired, and do not repair some equipment that should be overhauled; Some problems are also related to unprofessional operators, who cannot detect problems, or it is difficult to strictly enforce regulations during peak seasons.&quot; A professional close to a special equipment testing agency revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In November 2023, the State Administration for Market Regulation launched a nationwide safety inspection of roller coasters, which emphasized the need to consolidate the manufacturing, operation and use of large-scale amusement facilities. The main responsibility for unit safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, whether the management and operation of the equipment are professional and standardized is also related to the scale and conditions of the park where the equipment is located. Many interviewees said that in some cities, small parks, street parks, carnival venues, etc., because most of the equipment are non-first-line brands, and there are fewer passengers, the management and operation are also relatively loose. In comparison, the stability of the equipment and poor security. Respondents do not recommend riding roller coasters in some overseas countries that rely on human traction, roller coasters that are old and rusty in appearance, or roller coasters that have a high rate of bumps and complaints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When safety incidents occur on roller coasters, passengers sometimes bear some responsibility. &quot;It happened once before. Because there was a lot of cash in the bag, a tourist took the bag from the locker on the platform to the foot of the car at the moment of departure after depositing the bag. As a result, when the car flipped over, the bag was hit upside down. Passengers in the back.&quot; Han Zhiyi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, the aforementioned professionals also introduced that the roller coaster track is equipped with multiple highly sensitive sensors, and sometimes small objects dropped by passengers can be broken into as foreign objects. Identification, affecting the regular operation of the roller coaster. However, Lin Huanjie said that among the many roller coaster problems, the probability of them being triggered by tourists is extremely small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xun Hang believes that some people currently have some misunderstandings about roller coasters, such as equating roller coasters with extreme sports, or equating excitement with danger, but &quot;this project It’s about experiencing excitement, not looking for conventional comfort.” In his opinion, in most cases, riding a roller coaster is safe and can bring people some ultimate pleasure. &quot;We hope that everyone can understand it more comprehensively and enjoy it more relaxedly.&quot; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多近的关系，才应该给份子钱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261890]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-05 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, there has been a lot of talk about molecular money. First, a Jilin Yanbian girls&#39; circle of friends posted an unceremonious post: &quot;We were just ordinary classmates when we were in school. We have no contact after graduation, and we don&#39;t have any intersection now.&quot; Later, a woman from Chengdu found out that her college roommate had deleted her WeChat account, and deliberately added her as a friend to get back the 500 yuan she had received four years ago. Some netizens said: This generation of young people have begun to organize their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Young people have been suffering from the heavy pressure on rituals for a long time. Classmates who were not familiar with each other in school, colleagues who have only met once in the company, friends who have not been in touch for several years or even more than ten years, there will always be wedding invitations that make people reluctant and helpless, and in the end it is inevitable that they will be a pain in the wallet. In this regard, Zhou Xiaoyan, a psychology professor at Chongqing Normal University, said bluntly, why are such blessings that cannot be reached with eight poles coming? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;you What kind of relationship do you think should give money to members? Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>