<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“最后一代务农人”：他们正在消失的技艺、生活方式与价值观]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259340]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of the fourth day after returning home during the National Day holiday, my mother and I went for a walk. We met Grandma Yang in a vegetable field near the river. She was planting radish seedlings with her hunched back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother told me that Grandma Yang is 81 years old and is the oldest person in the village. Grandma Yang’s wife has passed away many years ago. Her two sons are developing in Wuhan, the provincial capital, and she lives alone. I saw that there were daikon, carrots, beetroot, and cabbage planted in the field, so I asked Grandma Yang why she planted so many. She said, &quot;Four months later, the children all went home, and together they had 9 mouths.&quot; Zi realized that the Spring Festival would be in four months. She also added, &quot;Not only do they come back to eat during the Chinese New Year, I also have to prepare some for them to take with them when they leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that the radishes I planted earlier were not growing very well, I asked Why, she told two reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Firstly, many farmers have gone to cities to work, many fields are deserted, bushes are everywhere, and there are many more wild boars, badgers and other animals than before. Just like the numbers of people, they have Instead of sneakily eating crops including vegetables at night, they can also freely invade vegetable fields, valleys, and sweet potato fields during the day. During the day, the old man can come to the vegetable fields with a stick from time to time to guard them and drive away wild animals. , at night, she had absolutely no choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, due to the long-term use of pesticides and chemical fertilizers, the soil structure of farmland has changed. The soil has become seriously compacted, fertility has dropped sharply, and the output of various crops, including vegetables, has dropped sharply. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;In fact, we can’t go back&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After telling Grandma Yang to be careful, my mother and I continued walking. There was a large field of rice fields in front of me. My mother asked me which one belonged to my family. I guessed twice, but my mother shook her head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I suddenly felt ashamed. I didn’t even know where my own farm was. Probably since I started working in 2008, every time I go home, my parents rarely go to the fields to do farm work, but stay with me. Of course, I rarely have the opportunity to go to the fields. As time went by, I forgot the exact location of the fields at home. Seeing that the rice was golden yellow, I suggested harvesting it the next day and helped cut it. Unexpectedly, my mother was very worried about my rice cutting skills. &quot;It&#39;s better to wait until you return to Guangzhou. Your dad and I will take our time. If you haven&#39;t gone to the fields for many years, it will be bad if you cut your hands.&quot; I was speechless, because the fact is that although I go home often, I rarely work in the fields. I am no longer an important labor force in the family like when I was in elementary school and junior high school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I work at a university in Guangzhou. I have a long summer and winter vacation. I go home for many more days every year than other young people in the village. For example, my brother started his working career after dropping out of school in his second year of high school at the age of 17. He basically works outside all year round, except for about half a month when he goes home during the Spring Festival. My brother is 44 years old and has been working for 27 years. Now, he has bought a house in Wuhan, and his sister-in-law and two nephews also live in Wuhan permanently. The eldest nephew is studying in college, and the sister-in-law takes care of the younger nephew who is in elementary school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, my family of four is in Guangzhou, and my brother’s family of four is in Wuhan. We have all been actively or passively involved in the wave of urbanization, and it is difficult for us to return. The hometown is developed or settled. In fact, we can&#39;t go back because we are no longer an &quot;agricultural population&quot; and have been engaged in &quot;non-agricultural industries&quot;, which has nothing to do with my brother&#39;s household registration in his hometown. No matter whether we enjoy the various benefits or treatment of authentic Guangzhou or Wuhan citizens, we are already veritable (new) Guangzhou people or (new) Wuhan people. Guangzhou or Wuhan is our permanent residence, and it is the place where we and our children A place to eat, drink, have sex, and have basic necessities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My brother and I are born in the 1970s. What are the people born in the 80s and 90s who are younger than us in the village doing? Where now? A small number of people have left their hometowns by studying, but most of them, like my brother, work outside all year round. What they have in common is that they are away from home all year round, and they only come home for ten and a half days during the Chinese New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are those born in the 1960s who are older than us doing? There are eight people born in the 1960s in my village. Four of them went to the city to work with their children, either taking care of their grandchildren who were in school or working for their sons who were construction workers. Two of them opened decoration companies, starting in Wuhan and Xining respectively. The last two are in the education industry. One is a teacher at a university in Wuhan, and the other is the principal of a village primary school in his hometown. It is not difficult to see that the eight people born in the 1960s have basically left the countryside and agriculture, and they all only go home during the Chinese New Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people born in the 60s, 70s, 80s and 90s have all moved into the city and are currently working hard in the city. Do they have any plans or signs of returning to the village in the future? I feel minimal. They have been in the city for many years, and their food, culture, and habits have already been highly urbanized. The post-80s and post-90s generations have experienced the rinsing of urbanization. They can no longer live without these things in shopping malls, KTVs, cinemas, fast food, and game arcades. Even Uncle Xia, who was born in 1962, said, &quot;Although I have been farming in my hometown for more than 20 years, I am no longer used to going home because life in my hometown is too inconvenient and the city is too convenient.&quot; In Northeast China Brother Wen, who works part-time, also mentioned, &quot;The winter at home is too cold and I am not used to it. I have stayed in Harbin for 32 years. Although the outdoor temperature is low, the indoors are heated and very comfortable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Farmers Vs Peasants&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It goes without saying that the only people who are still farming in their hometowns are those born in the 1940s like Grandma Yang, and those born in the 1950s like my parents. As children have gone to the city to go to school, many women have also joined the migrant workers, and the post-60s generation who went out to make a living in the early 1980s have adapted greatly to urban life. In the past, the &quot;386199&quot; army, which mainly constituted the rural population , now only the lonely &quot;99&quot; is left, and the corresponding specific groups are those born in the 40s and 50s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I would like to express that this group of people is truly the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot;. In particular, the author does not use the concept of &quot;farmers&quot;. In my opinion, concepts such as &quot;farmers&quot; and &quot;workers&quot; have distinct political and identity attributes. In the context of the use of the word &quot;farmers&quot;, there are often several contrasting groups, such as &quot;which group does farmers correspond to?&quot; &quot;Farmers are in rural areas, and workers are In the city&quot;, this is not the case. In essence, they are just differences in industry or professional division of labor. There are no political or identity differences or oppositions. A similar situation exists with the word &quot;worker&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As times have changed, we are more willing to use concepts that are familiar and easier for ordinary people to accept, such as &quot;migrant workers&quot;, &quot;migrant workers&quot;, &quot;migrant girls&quot;, &quot;farmers&quot; and &quot;migrant workers&quot;. Whether they are &quot;farmers&quot; or &quot;laborers,&quot; they are all industrial workers/laborers in the true sense of the word. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The skills of farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As &quot;farmers&quot;, this group of elderly people are naturally well versed in various techniques and techniques of farming or rural areas and agriculture. They have been familiar with agricultural seasons since they were young. , know when to spring plow, when to raise seedlings, when to sow seeds, when to fertilize, when to weed, when to harvest, and what to use to store crops. They know how to use ashes from stoves or firewood piles as fertilizer, and they also know how to use human, chicken, pig and other manure as an important supplement for crop nutrients, instead of just relying on pesticides or chemical fertilizers to improve soil fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will use the corner land in front of and behind the house to grow some vegetables, or reclaim idle or abandoned land in the mountains that is full of rocks or has been deserted for a long time to grow things. Before building a house or choosing a cemetery, they would ask Feng Shui masters to take a look; they invented bamboo beds for cooling in the summer, drying cages for heating in the winter, and chamber pots for using the toilet at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of them have been standard rural craftsmen since they were young, such as blacksmiths, painters, oilers, carpenters, quilters, tailors, midwives, barefoot doctors, fortune tellers, and witch doctors. When the village was renovated, they reminded young people not to easily remove the ancient trees at the entrance of the village, and strongly recommended that the old ancestral hall in the center of the village be retained. When family members have stomachaches, diarrhea, or other three diseases and two pains, they will go to the fields to find Houttuynia cordata and mugwort leaves, and use them to soak their feet, bathe, smoke them, or boil them in water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is no exaggeration to say that there are countless skills that they are familiar with or master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the vast majority of them have a very low level of education, with a high proportion of illiterates or semi-illiterates, but this does not hinder their deep understanding and familiarity with agricultural technology, rural memories and agricultural civilization. They may have never spoken about circular economy, ecological agriculture, intensive and economical land use, intangible cultural heritage, etc. in textbooks or propaganda slogans, nor do they know how to express them, but they have been practicing them all their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This illustrates the truth that culture and civilization often or usually have little or not much to do with educational level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; has made significant contributions to the inheritance of agricultural technology, the continuation of agricultural civilization, the harmony of families, and the country&#39;s urbanization and modernization. It is they who have succeeded their forefathers and ancestors, passing on from generation to generation, that agricultural civilization can be carried forward and passed on; it is they who guard their hometowns and rear areas so that their children and their younger generations can enter the city calmly and confidently Work hard to create a new life for the new generation; it is the kindness and hard work of them and their children that created the miracle of China&#39;s low-cost industrialization, urbanization and modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The lifestyle and values ​​of farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In terms of lifestyle, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; generally have a thrifty character, such as eating as little as possible and eating as much as possible. How many people eat leftovers for pigs, dogs, chickens and other livestock and poultry? Although they are very pleased with the various express delivery out of filial piety and respect for their children, they occasionally complain. They feel that their children spend money like water and spend money lavishly. . The acquisition and cultivation of thrifty character is certainly related to the most difficult and difficult years they experienced, but in that era of extreme material poverty, without frugality and frugality, there was no way to achieve the accumulation of material and wealth, as well as capital accumulation. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;capital accumulation&quot; here can be understood as &quot;without money, unable to pay tuition, even if the children are admitted to college, they will not be able to go to college. As a rural person, the biggest ambition is to &#39;jump out of the farm gate&#39; , as well as the future glory of the family and the glory of the ancestors, naturally they cannot be fulfilled.&quot; The assumption of the above statement is that children are the most important investment area of ​​the family, the expenditure on raising children is the investment cost, and the future development and returns of the children are investment income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of values, the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot; are very &quot;selfless&quot; and &quot;selfless&quot; to the extreme. The whole meaning of their lives lies in contribution and dedication. Many of them spend most of their lives or their entire lives living for others and their families. They have gone through untold hardships and have been stuck to the land all their lives. They have never or rarely left their hometowns and have been doing farm work all their lives. The so-called &quot;face to the loess and back to the sky&quot; accurately refers to their generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of them have been the main labor force in their families since they were young. They work hard and save all their lives, build houses, marry and have children, and then live frugally to raise their children and provide them with education. When the children grow up, they still think about Give your children a subsidy to share the pressure of buying a house in the city or getting married and starting a family. A few people even endured the torture of acculturation and still chose to go to the city to cook for their children and take their grandchildren to and from school when they were in their twenties. Only when their grandchildren were older could they return home to the home they had been used to all their lives. . After returning home, they finally no longer have to be busy, but they find that they have already fallen ill. Some people choose not to tell their children because they are afraid of using their children&#39;s money. Some people simply do not go to the hospital for a physical examination, fearing that if the problem is found, it will cause trouble for their children. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since they are the &quot;last generation of farmers&quot;, they are the &quot;last generation&quot;. Just like many villages that have experienced and are experiencing decline and decline, the torrent of the times will not pity them because of their hard work or hardship. them, or keep them. The exit of the old and the emergence of the new has always been an inevitable law of historical development and evolution, and no one can stop it. We can feel desolate, but we still need to let go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡适之父胡铁花之死真相]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259328]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/cmE0watQ4X4hR3EdC4BMdX1zy6V3ZcKH0xoxzto7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;641&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/cmE0watQ4X4hR3EdC4BMdX1zy6V3ZcKH0 xoxzto7. png&quot; data-key=&quot;255537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Chuan (Hao Tiehua), the father of Hu Shi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1895, the Qing government ceded Taiwan. Hu Shi&#39;s father, Hu Chuan, was the magistrate of Taitung Prefecture at the time. Hu Shi recalled that his father was &quot;unable to &quot;Willing to release&quot; delayed medical treatment and died, and most academic circles gave a conclusion of &quot;death from illness&quot;. The author discovered from the diary of Yuan Chang, a disciple of Zhang Zhidong, that Hu Chuan was imprisoned and blackmailed by Liu Yongfu, which worsened his condition and died on the ship back to Xiamen. Liu Yongfu&#39;s final release was the result of Yuan Chang&#39;s request for Zhang Zhidong&#39;s intervention. Yuan Chang was killed in 1900 for speaking out. He was a loyal and upright person, and his record deserves attention. The content of Yuan Chang&#39;s record is consistent with Hu Shi&#39;s recollection, but the wording is slightly different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Shi&#39;s father&#39;s official name was Hu Chuan, also known as Shousan and Shoushan, also known as Tiehua and Blunt Man. He experienced twists and turns in his life. He went north to Ninggu Pagoda, south to Hainan Li District, and finally arrived in Taiwan. The governor of Dongzhili Prefecture. For a long time, people have been under the impression that Hu Chuan died of illness. Luo Ergang, a disciple of Hu Shi and the famous scholar who compiled &quot;Hu Tiehua&#39;s Manuscripts&quot;, also agrees with this theory. There are many people who hold this view. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author also believes that Hu Chuan died of illness, but he died of an aggravation of his illness due to delays in treatment in captivity, and did not die of a normal illness. Hu Shi recalled: &quot;My father was in Taitung in charge of the defense of Houshan. Telegraphs were blocked and his salary source was cut off. At that time, he had suffered from beriberi and could no longer move his left foot. He stayed there until the third day of the fifth lunar month before leaving. Back Mountain, when they arrived in Anping, Liu Yongfu insisted on keeping him for help and refused to let him go. By June 25, he could no longer move his feet, so Liu Yongfu let him go. On June 28, he arrived in Xiamen. He could no longer move, and he died in Xiamen on July 3rd.&quot; (Hu Shi&#39;s &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot;) Hu Shi later added: &quot;But in my &quot;Autobiography at Forty&quot;, I stated that my father&#39;s death was due to beriberi. It can be cured. My father originally wanted to rush to Shanghai to seek medical treatment, but because Liu Yongfu refused to let him go, it was delayed for nearly two months. It was not until he was critically ill that he was let go. He arrived in Xiamen on June 28th and arrived in Xiamen in early July. He died at the age of three. My original intention (and the opinion of my late brother and late mother) is that my late father’s death was due to Liu Yongfu’s refusal to let him go.” (Hu Songping’s “First Draft of the Long Chronicle of Mr. Hu Shizhi”, Volume 1 Page 27) The person accompanying Hu Chuan that day was Hu Shi&#39;s second brother Shaozhi, who was also responsible for carrying the coffin back home. The situation described by Hu Shi should come from his second brother. Hu Shi&#39;s addition is extremely important and is consistent with Yuan Chang&#39;s diary records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/8eG93hRZLCT8OzKR3OWQNDJHsCTfvSs2GHoZ85hf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;584&quot; height= &quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/8eG93hRZLCT8OzKR3OWQNDJHsCTfvSs2GHoZ85hf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Yongfu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reading Hu Chuan&#39;s &quot;Taiwan Diary&quot;, he wrote to Tang Jingsong on the 6th of May, requesting &quot;to open a vacancy and return to his hometown for medical treatment&quot; and &quot;recover as soon as he obtains Yuan Shuangqiu&#39;s observation book from South Anhui Province.&quot; This diary entry proves that Hu Chuo&#39;s intention was to return to the mainland for medical treatment, and that he had frequent correspondence with Yuan Chang. Yuan Chang&#39;s official position at this time was Guangtai Road, Ningchi, Anhui Province, referred to as &quot;Wannan Road&quot;. Because he was stationed in Wuhu, he was sometimes referred to as &quot;Wuhu Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Yuan Chang&#39;s Diary&quot;, Hu Chuan was &quot;imprisoned and deprived of food&quot; by Liu Yongfu, which caused his condition to worsen. He died on the ship, and only a corpse arrived in Xiamen. Yuan Chang was a student admitted by Zhang Zhidong when he was the deputy chief examiner of Zhejiang Province in his early years. Yuan Chang&#39;s &quot;Diary of a Sanren in Bixietai Mountain&quot; collected in &quot;Diaries of the Past Dynasties&quot; has the same content as Sun Zhimei&#39;s punctuated version of &quot;Yuan Chang&#39;s Diary&quot;. It is an abridged copy of reading notes and a small number of notes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the diary, in the 22nd year of Guangxu (1896), he met Chen Wenluo (Chen Zhongying) and recalled what happened the previous year. Yuan Chang wrote in 1896: &quot;Chen Zhongying once guarded Tainan. He talked about how his late friend Hu Shousan (biography) was an official in Taitung Prefecture. He asked Liu Yongfu for a bribe of 20,000 yuan for the commander-in-chief Liu Yongfu, but he was not allowed. He was imprisoned and had no food. Yongfu originally surrendered to the thieves. It is a true act of thieves. I went to Xia to beg the governor Zhang Gong to interrogate Liu, and released Huzhou as a pastor. Before crossing the Taiwan Strait to Xiamen, he drank wine on a ship. He was so angry that he could not pursue his ambition and became ill.&quot; (Compiled by Sun Zhimei, &quot;Yuan Chang&quot; (Diary, Volume 2, page 1224) Chen Wenluo was appointed as the prefect of Taipei in 1892. He had never been stationed in Tainan, but he obeyed the order to cross over in May. Chen Wenluo is a colleague of Hu Chuan. His official experience makes his testimony irreplaceable and authoritative, and he is closest to the historical scene. Jiawu and Yiweizhangzhidong were in charge of the governor of Liangjiang, and Wuhu Road was under the governor of Liangjiang. According to the diary, it was Yuan Chang who asked Zhang Zhidong to call Liu Yongfu to release Hu Chuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the governors of the late Qing Dynasty, Zhang Zhidong paid the most attention to Yi Wei&#39;s surrender. Tang Jingsong, the governor of Taiwan, and Liu Yongfu, the assistant commander of Taiwan Defense Nan&#39;ao Town, were all supported and commanded by Zhang Zhidong during the Sino-French War. , Hu Chuanze inspected the Li District of Hainan in 1887 on the order of Zhang Zhidong. These three people all have deep connections with Zhang Zhidong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation in Taiwan during the Yiwei period was very complicated. Zhang Zhidong, the Governor-General of Liangjiang, ostensibly complied with the imperial court&#39;s decision to cede Taiwan. He also secretly supported Tang Jingsong and Liu Yongfu in resisting Japan and protecting Taiwan, and provided money and weapons. However, after receiving a telegram from the imperial court to challenge him, he stopped and left Tang and Liu to their own devices. Decide on orientation. Tang and Liu were originally famous generals who fought against the French, but were misled by their fame. They initially decided to stay in Taiwan to fight against the Japanese. However, their military strength could not last long. Tang Jingsong soon sneaked back to the mainland, while Liu Yongfu was &quot;overshadowed&quot; by others. Liu Yongfu felt that he had been tricked by Zhang Zhidong. When most of the local officials had been transferred inland, it was impossible to detain Hu Chuan, the magistrate of Taitung Prefecture, to demand payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Liu Yongfu cut off support from the mainland, it was a relatively simple way to obtain military pay from local officials. After careful reading of what Chen Wenluo said about &quot;asking for bribes,&quot; I feel that it is more reasonable to interpret it as &quot;asking for salary.&quot; Liu Yongfu detained Hu Chuan and &quot;deprived him of food and drink in captivity.&quot; However, Hu Chuan had no cash in his hands, and it was very difficult to raise wages as the Japanese troops advanced deeper and deeper. Yuan Chang from Wuhu Road asked Zhang Zhidong for help and called Liu Yongfu to release him. Hu Chuan died on the ship returning to Xiamen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Chuan died because he was imprisoned by Liu Yongfu and fasted, which delayed his treatment and his condition worsened. This was not a normal death. During the Sino-French War, Tang Jingsong took the initiative to sneak into Vietnam and fight side by side with Liu Yongfu. He had a deeper understanding of Liu Yongfu. In 1884, he reported to the court through Cen Yuying, the governor of Yunnan and Guizhou, saying that Liu Yongfu &quot;valued wealth too much, treated his subordinates with little kindness, and showed no mercy.&quot; No discipline.&quot; (Page 91 of Volume 1 of &quot;The Telegram of Duke Zhang Wenxiang (Unpublished)&quot;) Linking this phrase with the way he treated Hu Chuan in 1895, another side of Liu Yongfu&#39;s character becomes apparent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在何种情况下，以色列会使用核武器？丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259428]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/lPGP575q0cEcOl9oyhbIVi2CCvaUQuFNCyKKvSjE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lPGP575q0cEcOl9oyhbIVi2CCvaUQuFNCyKK vSjE. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The northern Gaza Strip was attacked in Sderot, Israel, on October 23, 2023. Thick smoke rising after Israeli air strikes &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Israeli Knesset member &quot;Tali&quot; Gotliff (Revital &quot;Tally&quot; Gotliv) actually told the media that Israel should use nuclear weapons to retaliate against Hamas&#39;s attacks on Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gotliff also wrote on her social media: &quot;Jericho missile! Jericho missile! Strategic alert. Before considering troops entering. Doomsday weapon (used)! This is mine Viewpoint. May God bless us with all our strength.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She later publicly declared that &quot;only an explosion that shook the Middle East can restore this country (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;means Israel&lt;/span>;) dignity, strength and security! It’s time to kiss the end of the world. Launch powerful missiles without limit. Don’t level a neighborhood, smash and level the entire Gaza…nothing Show no mercy! Show no mercy!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, this is an outright nuclear threat. Gottliff is a lawyer and an opponent of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. Her remarks have always been known for being extreme and crazy, so her extreme remarks this time were not regarded by anyone as a serious nuclear threat. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we have to admit the fact that Israel is indeed the only country in the Middle East that possesses nuclear weapons, and it almost decided to use nuclear weapons to save the defeat in the 1973 Yom Kippur War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is now a lot of public opinion that if anti-Israel allies such as Iran and Lebanese Hezbollah join the war, Hamas&#39;s goal of completely destroying Israel is expected to be achieved. But even if we do not take into account the fact that the combined conventional military strength of these opponents is still far behind that of Israel, as well as the fact that two US aircraft carriers are within easy reach, and only consider the existence of Israel&#39;s nuclear power, if Israel is completely defeated, this war will be The possibility of escalation to a nuclear war cannot be ruled out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So is Israel ready to use nuclear weapons in reality? To answer this question, we first need to understand what kind of nuclear power Israel has and what is the positioning of its nuclear strategy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Israel does not accept the supervision of its nuclear facilities by the International Atomic Energy Agency, and the Israeli government has always implemented a vague nuclear strategy, neither admitting nor denying the possession of nuclear weapons, and has not announced the deployment of its nuclear weapons to the outside world, the outside world is very concerned. It is difficult to know exactly how many nuclear weapons Israel possesses and whether the nuclear weapons are in a state of war readiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The international arms control research community now generally believes that Israel possesses at least 90 nuclear weapons and also retains key nuclear materials that can produce 200-300 nuclear weapons. Although Israel&#39;s nuclear weapons are very small, it is one of the very few countries with a triad of nuclear strike capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel has the Jericho medium-range ballistic missile with a range that can cover the entire Middle East and parts of Africa and Asia. This system is considered the core of Israel’s land-based nuclear strike force, among which the latest Jericho The Type 3 missile has a range of up to 4,800 kilometers, enough to cover Islamabad, the capital of Pakistan, and even Moscow, the capital of Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both the Israeli Air Force’s F-16 and F-15 fighter jets are capable of carrying nuclear bombs. The outside world even generally believes that Israel’s customized F-35 fighter jets will have the ability to drop nuclear bombs. It is expected that the Israeli Air Force’s There are at least 30 aerial nuclear bombs similar to the American B-61 type in the arsenal. This is the core of Israel&#39;s first-hand nuclear strike force. It maintains a very high level of combat readiness and can launch nuclear attacks from the air at any time, posing a threat to surrounding hostile countries. Very big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Israel is also one of the very few countries with underwater nuclear forces. Although it is not equipped with nuclear-powered submarines, the Dolphin-class conventionally-powered submarines in service in its navy are equipped with nuclear cruise missiles. The Israeli Army and Air Force Even if they no longer exist, the submarine force can still carry out doomsday strike missions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This triad of nuclear strike capabilities enables Israel, despite its small land area, to possess nuclear combat capabilities that surpass those of Britain and France. It is one of the few countries that can carry out preemptive nuclear strikes against major deterrence targets. If Israel really faces the risk of national annihilation, it is very likely to use nuclear weapons at the last moment in a desperate move. In fact, Israel&#39;s nuclear deterrent took shape after the Fourth Middle East War. This was also one of the strategic considerations for secular Arab countries such as Egypt to normalize relations with Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Congressman Gotliff’s statement that nuclear weapons should be used in Gaza is obviously just a personal statement. No matter how crazy Israel is, the radiation fallout after the nuclear explosion is an unacceptable and catastrophic consequence for Israel, which is very close. However, if the war expands and Iran directly participates in the war, then Israel&#39;s use of nuclear weapons is not an impossible option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Israel and the United States jointly conducted exercises to attack Iran&#39;s nuclear facilities, and Israel&#39;s combat plan is likely to include the option of launching a nuclear strike against Iran in extreme circumstances. This Hamas attack is generally considered to be the worst situation Israel has encountered after the Yom Kippur War. If Israel had prepared for a nuclear strike in 1973, it is not ruled out that there will be relevant plans this time. What&#39;s worse is that the number and means of use of the Israeli military&#39;s nuclear weapons have now far exceeded those of the past. Therefore, the international community should be alert to the possibility and harm of Israel preparing to use nuclear weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一碗海鲜面和便民热线]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259434]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;During the holidays, my husband and I joined in the fun and went to an island with the outdoor club. When we arrived at the island, it was already lunch time, so let’s look for seafood noodles. Who let seafood noodles be my obsession? I turned into a restaurant and found that it was a fast food restaurant. I asked casually, &quot;Are there any seafood noodles?&quot;, and the answer was, &quot;Yes, you can prepare seafood by yourself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, I happily served myself chilled shrimp, clams and dragonhead fish. The store owner asked me if I wanted razor clams. I told me that I didn’t want to eat razor clams because they would cause abdominal pain. The store owner took my selected seafood to the kitchen. I also remembered the club leader’s reminder to ask how much it would cost to eat seafood noodles. Last time she went there to eat, she was overcharged a lot without asking, so she specifically asked the price. The boss paused and said it was 48 yuan. I was a little surprised and thought to myself, this seafood noodle has never cost more than 30 yuan this year, but now it has increased by more than 50%? After thinking about it again, 48 yuan is not a big amount, so I acquiesced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After waiting for a while, the seafood noodles arrived. Because I was hungry, I picked up my chopsticks and ate it. I barely tasted it, but I found a lot of things wrong with it: Why was there razor clams in it? I chose three dragonhead fish that are more than ten centimeters long. Why are there only three small sections? Why is the shell of the shrimp so crispy and the meat of the shrimp so dry? It doesn’t look like it’s fresh, but it looks like it’s been dried in the sun? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My husband ate fast food. He ate before me and paid for it after he finished eating. After eating, I felt dissatisfied and argued with the boss, questioning whether the ingredients were out of the bag. This is great, three or four people in the store surrounded us, talking all over the place, and arrogantly denying my doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked: &quot;Who is in charge of your store?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Me,&quot; the boss said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Okay, everyone else shut up. We will negotiate with you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boss asked: &quot;What do you want to do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I said: &quot; Refund my money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He asked: &quot;Full refund?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I thought about it and said, &quot;That&#39;s not true. I also ate the noodles, so I will refund 20 yuan. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boss&#39;s eyes widened and he raised his voice: &quot;What? Impossible! Just go and complain!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I really didn&#39;t think of complaining before, but when he said this, I It also became popular and I directly dialed the 12345 hotline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About an hour later, I received a call, saying that it was from the Market Supervision Bureau. They had arrived at the scene and asked me if I had complained about the store adding extra razor clams to the seafood noodles. When I heard this, I was very surprised that the packaging of ingredients was so fresh and refined. I quickly said, I will review the matter for you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After repeating it briefly and concisely, the other party said that he would wait for him to verify it before making any decision. After a while, a call came, saying that no dried shrimps were found in the kitchen, and the razor clams were put in by mistake. I had no corresponding evidence, so I would not handle it. I said, I don’t accept this result. The boss had no fear from the beginning and asked me to “just complain.” Did he know that your arms would be bent inwards? I will continue to complain to the next higher level department. The previous complaints were: 1. The price deviated from the market and was suspected of robbing customers; 2. Ingredients were swapped; 3. The attitude was bad. If you insist on this attitude, then add another one: local protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;50 minutes later, I got a call. First, the boss was willing to apologize to me for his attitude and the wrong ingredients, and second, he was willing to refund 20 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Should we be happy that things have come to this? No, no, no, I&#39;m not happy at all. Not only does it taste bad to eat a bowl of seafood noodles, but you actually have to call 12345, and the market supervisor will make you a mess. Although the matter was finally dealt with, I always felt that without my &quot;threat&quot;, the matter would have been settled. It would be frustrating if the resolution of the matter depends on such &quot;threats&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always trusted 12345 because of her awareness of serving the people, because of her efficient work efficiency, and because of her responsive and well-organized style of doing everything. In my complaint, the corresponding functional department personnel rushed to the scene in more than an hour, and the work efficiency was not high. But if we talk about the matter, I think there are still flaws in the handling of this matter. If I had a fair heart and was not partial to local businesses and not perfunctory to foreign tourists, then I wouldn’t feel so sorry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That evening, we came to an internet celebrity village on this island. We saw someone eating seafood noodles, so we asked the price and were told 30 yuan. The seafood noodles were made by an old couple who were over seventy years old. I asked them what kind of seafood was put in the seafood noodles. The old woman replied that there were live shrimps, razor clams, clams, and a poached egg. We happily ordered two bowls of seafood noodles, and my husband ate all the razor clams in them. It felt good to enjoy the sea breeze, listen to the waves, and watch the moon rise little by little. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While we were eating noodles, I saw this old couple selling more than a dozen bowls of noodles. I did a rough calculation and found that a bowl of noodles costs about 10 yuan, so their income for a day is quite considerable. A bowl of seafood noodles costs 30 yuan. The store makes a profit and tourists can accept it. What a harmonious ecology! I can’t understand why some businesses still want to rip off customers. Are they afraid of losing their own business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a retired teacher)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt; /span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163 .com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吴尊友因病去世，中疾控发布讣告]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259458]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 18:24:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Chief epidemiologist at the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, former director of the Center for STD and AIDS Prevention and Control at the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention , researcher, Comrade Wu Zunyou, member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and member of the Standing Committee of the 15th Central Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, died in Beijing at 12:56 on October 27, 2023 due to ineffective treatment due to illness. He was 60 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respect my last wishes, keep the funeral simple, and do not hold a farewell ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 27, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高铁二等座盛不下的“大码女孩”，特意被大家看见]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259438]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Doudo challenged to ride the merry-go-round. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/8ee95a226a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;971&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/8ee95a226a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pay Dolphin challenges riding the merry-go-round. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;26-year-old Fu Doudan (pseudonym) had two nights of insomnia after a video went viral. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In that video, Fu Doudou, who is 1.7 meters tall and weighs 286 pounds, is riding a high-speed train wearing a pink tutu skirt and squeezes into a second-class seat. , stuck himself in the seat, with an expression of despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Whose problem is it that &quot;plus-size girls&quot; can&#39;t be seated in second-class seats on the high-speed rail? Netizens are talking a lot. Some people support that &quot;plus-size girls should be seen,&quot; while others accuse Fu Doudou of saying, &quot;If you don&#39;t lose weight, you blame it on the high-speed rail.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We made this video not to blame the high-speed rail department, but to express that we did encounter this problem.&quot; Fu Doudu said that the video went viral After the fire, she saw the plight of a group. &quot;At first, I thought I was the only one encountering this situation. Surprisingly, many plus-size girls sent me private messages, saying that they would have the same difficulty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 26, 2023, the Guangzhou High-speed Railway Customer Service Center responded to a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;If there is a need in this regard, we can collect information and feed it back to the relevant departments here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;On the afternoon of the previous day, Southern Weekend reporters met Fu Doudou in Guangzhou. She has always been used to being a &quot;conspicuous bag&quot;, and she is still a little nervous. She did not expect that she would be pushed to the public in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fu Doudu said that she suffers from hypothyroidism and other diseases and has been fat for a long time. Being extremely obese also caused her to repeatedly hit the wall when looking for a job. She worked in sales, customer service, and as a plus-size women&#39;s clothing model, and eventually started her own business making plus-size women&#39;s clothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“坐高铁卡座”话题突然爆红，但在她遇到的困境中，这其实只是极其普通的一例。生活的方方面面都在提醒她，自己是个胖子，“胖”几乎占据了她生活的全部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;付豚豚挑战坐高铁二等座被卡住。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/c44527be08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1417&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/c44527be08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255765&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;付豚豚挑战坐高铁二等座被卡住。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以下是“大码女孩”付豚豚的自述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我们是不能说话的群体”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我叫付豚豚，但我不姓付。我在幼儿园第一个朋友姓付，很多年我都联系不上她，叫这个姓是想纪念她。 “豚豚”，是因为有一天我爸开玩笑说，我好像一只海豚在床上翻来覆去的，那就是这个名字了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但我没想到，网友可以根据“豚”，联想到“猪”。我是因为身体有甲减和甲状腺（疾病），一直瘦不下来。从小到大，我一直被骂“肥猪”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;前期就策划想拍这样一则坐高铁的视频，太远的地方我不敢去，朋友说去清远，从广州过去不到半个小时。我说试试，就直接过去了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我挤进高铁座位之后，突然发现比隔壁高那么多，屁股是有点紧张的状态，后腰因为有赘肉，卡得很紧。我当时穿的裙子有点膨，也不敢把扶手收起来，怕身体像水一样溢出来，非常尴尬。走过道也是这样的，我穿那件蓬蓬裙把过道都占满了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一开始他们跟我说上微博火了，我第一反应是先回家躲起来，问粉丝和同事可不可以帮我看评论，我不敢看，好像会被网暴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在发视频前，我猜到可能会有一些人骂，但没想到网友们骂得五花八门，看都看不过来。有一个粉丝在网上帮我说话，被七千多个网友网暴，有人说我不是大码，是特大码。我还收到一个女生私信，“建议你自杀，恶心的东西”，之后就把我拉黑了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;视频走红后，付豚豚收到的网络私信。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/ffae1bde1e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/ffae1bde1e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;视频走红后，付豚豚收到的网络私信。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有趣的是，也有蛮多人喜欢我，他们可能会评论“喜欢你”“你很漂亮”。也有很多大码姐妹说，她们也遇到过这个事情，从小时候就被叫“肥猪”。就感觉我们是一个普通的群体，但也是一个不能说话的群体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我们一出门，就会被讨论。想保持平和的心态都做不到，恰巧大家都默不作声，可能每个人都觉得自己是个例，说出来也没有人帮我们。有些人对我们已经到了看到就厌恶的程度，之前我在城中村还被一个大爷吐口水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有一次，我在路边等公交，旁边一对情侣讨论我。女的说，“如果胖成这样，你还会爱我吗”。男的说，“你怎么可能胖成这种猪一样，我会爱你的”。他们跟我一起上车，又在公交车上说了我一路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;前段时间，我在地铁口突然被人揪住，是一个跟我年龄差不多的女生，她问我多少斤，我说286斤。她说“你这样你还吃饭，怪不得长那么胖，你这样很容易死的”。虽然我看起来很大只，但跟她们吵架，我一直是哭的那个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;也有人说，如果我是男生，可能就不会被这么说了。因为在大众的概念里面，比较高壮的男生，被挑衅以后暴打的几率比较大，但女生可能就忍过去了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“很多场合我不能参与”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有些时候，别人很轻易就能做到的事情，对我来说很难。我会提前想好要不要干，避免碰到很尴尬的点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比如我进地铁，基本不坐，一般就靠角落站着，因为我坐下去就会占1.5个位置。有时刚坐下，旁边的人就自动弹开了。还有一个原因是，胖人确实容易出汗，夏天穿得少，如果碰到别人之后会很尴尬。我从小到大都没有踩过别人的脚，也没有专门去挤过别人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我没有去过外面的城市，到现在也没坐过飞机。我坐高铁都这样挤，飞机的宽度更窄，可能容不下我。我在单位就坐坏了两个转椅，之前也因为挤电梯超重，默默退出来，很尴尬的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;还有更尴尬的事。我有次租房，不想弄坏房东的床垫，就换成自己的薄垫，结果我坐了一下，下面的合成木板就出现了屁股大的洞，陷下去了。床板要找人回收，工作人员把床板抬下去的时候，我捂住脸，想找个地缝钻进去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;像聚餐我也不太去，会提前看一下这家店的凳子我能不能坐。有一些大排档的塑料凳，我们坐上去很容易摔，还把人家凳子坐坏了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;出门住酒店时，我也总担心床会塌，会提前看一下床。没有任何东西是能让我很随意的定下来的，虽然这么说有点夸张，但真是这样，每次出行，我都会提前看很多东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这也是导致我性格比较内向的原因之一，因为很多场合我不能参与。有时候大家出去玩，我这个玩不了，那个玩不了。作为朋友，他们也不想让我落单，可能会留下来陪我，我不想这样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;还有健身房追着我卖卡，我走在路上也会被围着。他们都觉得我像大客户，那种长期持卡者。实际上我真这么干，一直都有健身卡，不同的地方我都买过。从2016年开始，我就在学校附近办年卡，有空就去。上班以后也办，有回报了个很贵的课程，一百多块钱一节课，最后健身房跑路了，我还有二十多节课没上，亏死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们的销售话术我熟到能背出来，前不久还有家保健品店的销售带我去店里玩游戏，玩得很开心。然后拿出来一个产品，说喝了就会变瘦，他们觉得我很好骗，但他确实赚到我的钱了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“生活的全部是减肥”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我记性不好，有些伤心的事偶尔想起来会难过一下。有一天，他们问我减肥经历了什么，我一边想一边哭，想起了很多遭遇，哭到停不下来，胖确实给我加了很多心理阴影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我是广东人，在南方长大，周边的人都跟杆子一样瘦。但我小学二年级就有80斤，看起来圆圆的，初中到了120斤，身高1米68也会被说胖，高中体重到160多斤，同学都喊我猛男。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;哥哥从小就比我瘦，我们俩出去，他们都说我把我哥的饭全都抢了，其实没有，我们俩一直吃一样的东西。上学时，班里同学会直接把我当成壮丁，扛书扛水搬东西，运动会被安排扔铅球，但其实不一定胖的人都力气大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我生活的全部就是减肥，一直减肥，一直没成功，减得我很崩溃。只要稍稍吃一点点碳水，体重就会很快涨起来，锻炼也没用。在外面看那些吃的东西，这个不能买，那个热量高。比如糖炒栗子我不吃，广东很常见的炒米粉、河粉、肠粉这些我也不能碰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;上大学时，为了能够更好融入集体，我节食减肥，确实瘦了二十多斤，但是我身体出了问题，脱发，生理期也紊乱了。而且我一饿会发慌，整个人很虚脱。减肥因为各种原因撑不下去，那种放弃已经长期存在我的人生里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;去年，我报了一个瘦身训练营，脱产三个月训练，学费15000元。 60个学员里面，跟我差不多体型的可能有六七个人，我们互相鼓励。早上7点多起床，做健身操，下午练力量型的杠铃哑铃，晚上骑动感单车，一群人像蹦迪一样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;每天要练四五个小时。一顿饭只有三勺米饭，搭配一小格素菜和很小一格子肉。但因为我吃的东西太少，锻炼有点撑不上劲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;练到第三个月，大家都在咳嗽，但还是一边咳一边跳操，整个包房全是咳嗽的声音，很响。所以大码的女生她不想减吗？她不想努力吗？我们坚持了3个月，可最后我只减掉了22斤。我问教练，我没有偷吃东西，为什么瘦不下去？他说，“你就不要吃。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来我去医院检查，抽了11管血，查出了胰岛素抵抗和甲减，我代谢功能差，比大部分人瘦得慢，可能正常人减肥一天掉一两斤，我一星期才掉一两斤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2022年，付豚豚参加瘦身训练营。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/567c16cc49.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;749&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/567c16cc49.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年，付豚豚参加瘦身训练营。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我确实在很多的环境里面被排斥，在家里也无法被容纳，其中有六成原因是我的身材，我爸妈可能会向别人宣扬他儿子有多厉害，但从不宣扬我，觉得丢人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以我很少回家，不敢回去，每次都被人说。很多亲戚会劝我减肥，他们要说什么我都能背得出来。我妈会指着一个碟子问我，“你知道这是什么吗？你的脸就像这么圆。”你也知道她是开玩笑，但刀子永远是扎心的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我退到无路可退，只会跳入一个更大的坑，我真的会跳下去。有段时间，我因为在公司受排挤，家里关系紧张，减肥又减不好，很失落。我们公司在18楼，我跨在栏杆上想跳下去。正巧有个附近工作认识的朋友发消息问我，要不要出来吃个雪糕。那条消息让我突然醒了一下，好像也有人关心我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我想，我可能真的没有办法生存下去了。我一个人吃饭，一个人走路，躲在房子里不愿意见人，崩溃过几次，也抑郁过，在很静音的状态中度过了一年。那一年。我哥哥每个月会打一次电话，他只问两句，你还好吗？还活着吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;直到后来跟家人关系缓和了一些，慢慢走出来了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“做一些自己害怕的事”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;改变是从一次野外活动开始的。之前我跟公司的人团建，几十个人去玩山地摩托越野车。一开局，大家跑开了100米，就我的摩托车一直熄火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我也很着急，不想掉队，旁边的教练很不耐烦地说，“你这样很危险的，不要开了，我退钱给你。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我同事看不下去，他怼了一句教练，“人家不会，你就教人家，为什么要叫人家下来？”我很感动，好久没人这样支持我了。教练教我以后，我刚开出去一会儿又死机了。教练又说，“不要开了，你下来，我退票给你，保险都退给你好吗。”我说你再让我试一次，就再试一次。那次我真的开上去了，虽然中途我熄火了十几次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;你知道吗？到了很高的地方，我的车几乎要翻过来。坡很陡，车子要急速往上冲，我的体重可能会把速度拖慢。但我后来看那段路不止我过不去，很多人也过不去，还有体重太轻的，车真的翻了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;到山顶以后，几个教练问我合影。我以为他们又开我玩笑，但听一个教练说，“这个女孩很棒，一开始她一直在熄火，现在开到这里，真的很棒。”他夸我哎，那天心里一直都很暖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;付豚豚骑越野摩托车。受访者供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/062697426b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/062697426b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;付豚豚骑越野摩托车。受访者供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我一直没有说做成哪件事情让我有成就感，可能别人的人生是起起伏伏，但我一直在伏。总之这件事，让我第一次觉得自己很勇，也让我反思，有些事情是不能停的，如果我一开始放弃，就没有那样的成就感了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;还有一次，健身房的朋友抓我登山，约好去一个比较高的风景区，爬几百级的阶梯。一开始我不敢上，有个妹妹每一层都拉着我，每上十几层台阶我就往回看，想着我等一下怎么下去，最后我是在台阶上躺着往下试探，一小步一小步挪下去的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们扶我，我说不要，我怕连你们一起滚下去，那天心跳飙到180。但每次铁着头去干我不敢干的事情以后，都能长点勇气值。后来，我还挑战坐过山车和旋转木马，比如铁索桥这种景点，我以前没办法接受，总担心我上去它就断了，后来也尝试了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我确实很害怕各种东西。可能以前生活的全部都是减肥，但现在我想去做一些自己害怕的事情，用其他事情充实自己。我也希望“大码女孩”这个群体站出来，勇敢一些，被大家看见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 18:25:11 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深秋青海：如诗如画]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259290]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家烟草专卖局原局长凌成兴落马，反腐震荡至烟草系统最高级别]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259432]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/JQJFMogZw7WnI1B7dpthiLXvmzRWXL7acvFQXdak.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/JQJFMogZw7WnI1B7dpthiLXvmzRWXL 7acvFQXdak. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ling Chengxing once proposed to &quot;prevent (tobacco control) from becoming expanded, one-sided, and absolute.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, 2023, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that the former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration Ling Chengxing is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that three days ago, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced that the Eighth Central Inspection Team will inspect the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration’s party group work mobilization meeting, which will “highlight the supervision of the ‘top leaders’ and leadership teams and conduct in-depth investigations. Corruption issues in key positions and key areas.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, many former officials of the State Tobacco Administration have been dismissed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zehua, former member of the Party Leadership Group and deputy director, was investigated in July, and Zhang Hong, former director of the Department of Science and Technology, was investigated in July. Ling Chengxing is the highest-ranking official dismissed from the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration since its establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Zhao Hongshun, a former party member and deputy director, was investigated in February 2019, and Pan Jiahua, a former party member and leader of the disciplinary inspection team, was investigated in January 2022. Zhao Hongshun was sentenced to life imprisonment in June 2020, and Pan Jiahua was sentenced to 11 years in prison in April 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The starting point of official career&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Ling Chengxing was investigated, the tobacco system had been continuously shaken, and many department and bureau-level cadres were dismissed intensively across Yunnan, Anhui, Jiangsu and other places, among which Jiangxi, the starting point of Ling Chengxing&#39;s official career, was the hardest hit area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1, 2023, Li Benjian, a former division-level cadre of the Jiangxi Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), underwent disciplinary review and supervisory investigation. According to Caixin reports, this person once served as Ling Chengxing’s driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 6, Zheng Wei, Party Secretary, Director and General Manager of the Guangdong Provincial Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), was dismissed. He was previously the General Manager of China Tobacco Jiangxi. On the same day, Fu Wujun, the first-level business manager of the Human Resources Department of China Tobacco Jiangxi, was subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanggao County in Jiangxi Province was the starting point of Ling Chengxing’s career. He started working in 1980 and was promoted to the Standing Committee and Deputy County Magistrate of Shanggao County at the age of 27. Thereafter, he served as director of the Jiangxi Provincial Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, and eventually became a member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Party Committee and executive deputy governor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Ling Chengxing was elected as a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress in Jiangxi. A media person who interviewed Ling Chengxing at the Two Sessions told Southern Weekend reporters that during the discussion, everyone still called Ling Chengxing &quot; Governor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring in 2018, Ling Chengxing was still very concerned about his hometown Shanggao. His only public appearance after retirement was to visit the water supply company in his hometown accompanied by the local county party secretary, county People’s Congress director and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Area hardest hit by corruption&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From 2013 to 2018, Ling Chengxing served as a member of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure, China&#39;s cigarette sales fell by 2.4% in 2015, the first decline since 1995, equivalent to smokers reducing their consumption of 60 billion cigarettes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason is that the tobacco tax will be raised by 6 percentage points starting from May 10, 2015. The price and tax rate of the cigarette wholesale link will be increased from 5% to 11%, and the price will be increased by 0.005 yuan/cigarette. A specific tax is levied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the trend of declining sales, Ling Chengxing, who has always been low-key, took the initiative to accept an interview with the &quot;Study Times&quot; sponsored by the Party School of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, proposing to &quot;prevent (tobacco control) from becoming expanded, one-sided, and absolute.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Two Sessions in 2015, this also became the focus of reporters’ questions. What is the expansion of tobacco control? Ling Chengxing replied: &quot;Let me give you an example. Some people say that bone hyperplasia is caused by smoking. I think this has no scientific basis. What do you think?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, China&#39;s cigarette sales stopped falling and rebounded. rose, with 47.378 million boxes sold throughout the year, an increase of 0.8% compared with 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the discussion of tobacco control, the tobacco industry’s government-enterprise integration system has always been the focus of discussion. In the eyes of the tobacco control party, the government-enterprise integration system has become the biggest obstacle to tobacco control in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ling Chengxing’s predecessor, former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, Jiang Chengkang, made the biggest institutional reform of China’s tobacco industry by promoting the “separation of industry and commerce” at the provincial level, but the reform failed to continue. further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Ling Chengxing took office, he followed the previous ideas and rapidly expanded the scale of the company through mergers and alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop for his research after taking office was in Yunnan. After the merger of Hongyun Group and Honghe Group, the newly established &quot;Hongyun Honghe Group&quot; became the largest group after Altria Group, British American Tobacco, and Japan Tobacco. , the world&#39;s fifth largest tobacco group after Imperial Tobacco. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 30, 2013, a symposium on cultivating major brands of Yunzhen cigarettes was held in Mile County, Honghe Prefecture. Ling Chengxing, who had just taken over as the director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, issued the tobacco &quot;Policy Agenda&quot; for the first time: Adhere to &quot; &quot;Three Stabilities&quot; (the guiding ideology determined at the beginning of the year remains unchanged, the goals and tasks remain unchanged, and the work measures remain unchanged); maintain the &quot;Three Stabilities&quot; (stabilize the leadership team, stabilize the cadre team, and stabilize the morale of the employees); think, plan, and practice &quot;Three major issues&quot; (where are the dividends of tobacco industry reform, where is the potential for development, and where is the goal of catching up). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ling Chengxing also implemented a number of reforms during his tenure. Starting in 2014, the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration issued the &quot;Key Points of the Market-oriented Reform of Cigarette Marketing&quot; for four consecutive years, but it was limited to the marketing level, focusing on &quot; How can commercial enterprises truly reflect market demand, how can industrial enterprises meet demand in a timely manner, and how can industrial and commercial enterprises respond to market demand in a timely manner?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike the previous &quot;foreign troubles&quot; in which China Tobacco faced direct competition with foreign brands, Ling Chengxing faced more internal management pressure. During his tenure, many major cases occurred in the tobacco system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, a scandal broke out in the Henan Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, and many people including the former director were arrested. There is also the case of Yang Weizu, chairman of Yunnan Ruisheng Group, who is associated with the Yunnan Tobacco Science Research Institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, at least a dozen central officials in the tobacco system have been eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Ping, Party Secretary and General Manager of Hunan China Tobacco Industry Co., Ltd., was investigated in October 2020 and was suspected of accepting bribes of 413 million yuan and misappropriating public funds of 135 million yuan. This case is known as the most serious job-related crime in the tobacco system since the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A disciplinary inspection cadre analyzed the causes of corruption in the tobacco system to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The tobacco system is different from other vertically managed departments. It is a system that integrates government and enterprises, and the path to realize power is very difficult. Short, all links are accompanied by indicators, which results in power being permanently concentrated in the hands of a few people and the lack of effective supervision, making it more difficult to fight corruption in the tobacco system.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tobacco Bureau even controls the money bags of local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An interesting detail is that during the National People’s Congress in 2015, a mayor publicly appealed to Ling Chengxing that he wanted to improve the quality of cigarette production. “It used to be that Septwolves were basically OEM, and the taxes and profits of Septwolves were relatively low. It would be great if the next step is to produce Chinese cigarettes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was refuted by Ling Chengxing on the spot, &quot;That&#39;s impossible. China Tobacco is a banner of the tobacco industry.&quot; The mayor said with a smile that “it may not all be the pen of the (old) governor” and suggested that better equipment could be invested in production. Ling Chengxing still insisted, &quot;When you come to engage in Zhonghua Cigarettes, you will immediately destroy the Zhonghua Cigarettes (brand).&quot; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the mayor continued, &quot;While the (old) provincial governor is in the position of the General Administration, a certain city&#39;s tobacco industry chain tax revenue can reach 10 billion yuan.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that this media record at the time was preserved under Ling Chengxing&#39;s instruction. According to an insider, &quot;He may have just wanted to show that he rejected the other party.&quot; The mayor who made this request was dismissed soon after because of his involvement in the Su Rong case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“啥都不用干”是最大的福气吗？ ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259230]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many people have said &quot;I don&#39;t want to work&quot; when they are sleepy or frustrated, but these words are probably inappropriate. Really, if we don’t have any mines or pie from the sky, what else can we do if we don’t move bricks honestly? But there are indeed some people who regard &quot;no work and someone to support you&quot; as the highest ideal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger said that since childhood, her aunt has indoctrinated a bunch of little girls, including her, with the idea that girls are &quot;blessed&quot; and can enjoy a good life without doing anything. . Not only do you not have to do anything, but you marry a good family and you don&#39;t even need to take care of the children yourself. That is what you are blessed to do. This concept is close to &quot;labor equals shame&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all have inertia and a desire for comfort. In our subconscious, we may have had the image of just lying down and enjoying ourselves. When I was a kid, I experienced the intense itching pain all over my body after harvesting and threshing rice and wheat by hand. I also had &quot;plans&quot; to stop working. But honestly, just think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The extravagant and luxurious life in books and movies is described in the wonderful lyrics of &quot;Huang Liang Meng&quot; by the Pingdiao Luozi Theater Company in Handan City, Hebei Province: &quot;Endless generosity, endless power; Endless delicacies to eat, endless money to spend; endless carols to listen to, endless gifts to receive; endless wealth to enjoy, endless New Years to live.&quot; Ordinary people can just think about it, and really educate themselves like this Children, that&#39;s really gone astray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary people, when they are minors, they are supported by their parents, and when they become adults, they have to support themselves and their families on their own. If you want to live a good life, you can only accumulate it step by step. This is the first meaning of work for most people: to support their families. In order to achieve this goal, many people work very hard and may not be in a career they like, but they persist because this job can bring acceptable returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is very painful to do a job that you don&#39;t like for a long time. A friend told me that the joyless days at work day after day were really a torture. But even so, we can&#39;t &quot;just leave&quot;, we can only wait for the opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend’s words moved me deeply. The reason why people should work hard is because work should have a second meaning: combining it with one&#39;s own talents and interests, making the work itself a source of fulfillment and happiness. Many writers have been doing writing work for a lifetime based on their talent and interest. I have also been a media commentator for many years based on my talent and interest. This is a blessing. There is also a kind of work that may seem heavy and tiring, but it may be something that workers like to do. For example, blacksmithing is not acceptable to most people, but in reality there are people who work very hard at it. I also heard a car mechanic say that although it may be tiring and dirty all day long, it is a job that interests him and cannot let him go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are the values ​​that ordinary people should uphold, try to do meaningful work and live a meaningful life. In other words, a livelihood should be one that can not only meet the purpose of earning money to support the family, but also satisfy interests and hobbies. Accordingly, we not only get practical benefits, such as income and evaluation, but also spiritual satisfaction. This sense of gain is the spiritual source that enriches us in this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people envy the financial freedom of wealthy families, but they only know one aspect but not the other. Even among the envied few &quot;giant pandas&quot; in society, most of them do not relax their requirements for their children. Instead, they pay more attention to providing high-quality education and scientific employment guidance to their children, and to promote their children to pursue a decent and respectable career. jobs and better realize the value of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, these families need their children to inherit the family business. In order not to be left behind for this goal, they are motivated to help their children avoid becoming &quot;waste&quot; and &quot;dandy children&quot; who only consume high amounts of money and live in vain. Look at the young people who have inherited the family business of wealthy parents today. Which one has not experienced the nourishment of a good education and the tempering of basic work. Many people have the ability to protect their children from dust, but they still let them start from the &quot;workshop&quot; and perceive the meaning of life. This is true wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the many second-generation rich people do not sit around doing nothing all day long, eating, drinking, and waiting to die as some people imagine. In other words, people who are more &quot;qualified&quot; than ordinary people to do nothing work harder than you. What other reason do you have for fantasizing about “doing nothing”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t forget, if you really have nothing to do, you will definitely fall into emptiness. If a person does not &quot;fill&quot; his life with meaningful things, he will easily fall into emptiness and become as light as a feather. In this case, even if you get a fortune one day, you will not be able to control such wealth. In Yu Hua&#39;s novel &quot;To Live&quot;, he explained the story of a swinger brother who lost his family fortune by gambling. How many such folk narratives are there? After the demolition in my hometown many years ago, the &quot;second generation&quot; became rich instantly. However, it is not uncommon for them to lose their property overnight due to gambling, dissoluteness, and being cheated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am obviously middle class or even poor, but I still always want to live a &quot;fairy life&quot; like a powerful or wealthy family, just enjoying myself and not working. To put it mildly, this is unrealistic, but to put it seriously, it is unrealistic. This is a lack of self-awareness. This idea is difficult to realize. In short, humans are animals of meaning, and meaning is the food of the spiritual world. On the basis of establishing a good life, people should do meaningful work or career to nourish our spirit. Under the sun and on the earth, we should still let ourselves &quot;sink&quot;, settle down, and become human plants that are truly not afraid of wind and rain. This principle applies to both the second generation of rich people and the children of ordinary people. Meaningful work or a meaningful career is the &quot;key&quot; that helps a person lead to a happy and transparent state. Only when you find a sense of presence and cultivate your character in your work or career, can you follow the trend. For, gradually improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[取消个人医保账户？国家医保局辟谣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 15:04:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, an article titled &quot;Employees Attention! &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From 2024, employee medical insurance premiums will be completely changed&quot; article and related screenshots were circulated online in some WeChat groups, WeChat Moments and other places. After verification, the relevant contents in the article such as &quot;employee medical premiums will no longer be transferred to personal accounts&quot; and &quot;individuals will no longer have their own medical insurance accounts&quot; are pure rumors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In accordance with the decisions and arrangements of the central government and the requirements of the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Establishing and Improving the Outpatient Mutual Aid Security Mechanism for Employee Basic Medical Insurance&quot; (Guobanfa [2021] No. 14), local medical insurance departments have adopted Carry out the reform of employee medical insurance outpatient mutual assistance security, establish and improve the general outpatient coordination of employee medical insurance, and effectively improve the outpatient protection level of employee medical insurance participants. After the reform, the employee medical insurance personal account system will still be retained, with three &quot;unchanged&quot; features. First, the ownership of personal account balances remains unchanged. The historical balances before the reform and the newly transferred balances after the reform are still owned by the individuals and can be used for medical expenses and other expenses for individuals and their families, and can be carried forward and inherited. Second, the proportion and flow of personal contributions of active employees remain unchanged, and the full amount is still transferred to their personal accounts. Third, the policy of retirees not paying contributions remains unchanged, and personal account funds are still transferred from the overall fund. At present, the reform has achieved positive results, and the level of outpatient benefits of employee medical insurance has been steadily improved. In the first half of 2023, general outpatient services will benefit 1.124 billion people insured by employee medical insurance. The contents and screenshots of articles and screenshots related to &quot;cancellation of personal medical insurance accounts for employees&quot; circulating on the Internet are completely false. We reserve the right to hold the relevant rumor makers accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;国家医疗保障局办公室&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;2023年10月27日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259430]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuw SokpK2C. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, members of the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition summit team were rushing to the summit&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May and October 2023, the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and the Tibetan Plateau Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hereinafter referred to as &quot;Northwestern Institute&quot; and &quot;Qinghai-Tibet Institute&quot;&lt;/span>;) inspected the Everest area, Gradandong Peak, Cho Oyu Peak and other places, and obtained ice core samples . This is one of the tasks of my country&#39;s second comprehensive scientific investigation and research on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores are like natural archives, recording natural changes and human activities. However, climate change caused by human activities is also erasing the memory in the glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why ice core? Why study glaciers? Who is studying Mount Everest? With various questions, we followed the Everest scientific expedition team in 2023, traced the history of the Everest scientific expedition for more than 60 years since China&#39;s first comprehensive expedition centered on Mount Everest in 1959, and recorded the progress of the glacier scientific expedition. The goals and actions can gradually describe the outline of those engaged in glacier research: most of them come from rural areas, are brave, can endure hardship, love nature, and love field work. They find peace and joy in nature, they are not stingy with time, they are aware of and concerned about the pulse of the earth, and they believe that the world is a community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Shi Yafeng, the father of Chinese glaciers, said, glacier research is a career for brave people and a heroic career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mount Everest is the main peak of the Himalayas, the tallest and youngest mountain range in the world. The Everest region mainly includes the &quot;Everest Nature Reserve&quot; in China on the north slope and the &quot;Sagarmatha National Park&quot; in Nepal on the south slope. With widespread glaciers, it is an important treasure house of freshwater resources on the earth and is also a source of climate and environmental change. Sensitive areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UWRilmxdoeZ2bErRTuZhdK8y4UyVlv1RajRdhTFV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UWRilmxdoeZ2bErRTuZhdK8y4UyVlv1RajRdhTFV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, 2023, members of the scientific expedition team took snow and ice samples at the top of Mount Everest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ice cores, nuclear explosion tests and pesticides&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;All four drill motors were broken. If it breaks down, just go down the mountain, Chen Pengfei thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of May 20, 2023, at a pass at an altitude of 6,500 meters on Mount Everest, in a military green tent that was blown by the wind, Chen Pengfei and his colleagues shot two Ice core and a shallow ice core. Shallow ice core is an overloaded task: we have worked hard to get there, and we have to drill more until the drill breaks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores are cylindrical ice and snow samples that are continuously taken out from the glacier section by section using a drill from top to bottom. A bottom-through ice core means that the ice core is drilled into the rock layer and reaches the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Snowfall falls on glaciers and ice sheets. Year after year, it is deposited into ice, and the information of nature is sealed in it. The scientific expedition team members always want to obtain longer ice cores, hoping that the ice cores will contain more physical and chemical parameters. Relying on these parameters, scientists were able to reconstruct the history of changes over millennia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Antarctica, the North Pole and the Tibetan Plateau are collectively known as the &quot;three poles&quot; of the earth. Human activities in these three poles are weak and are used as the basis for environmental research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We need to know what the earth was originally like.” Chen Pengfei’s colleague Guo Junming said. They are all associate researchers at Northwest China Institute of Technology, which belongs to the State Key Laboratory of Cryosphere Science. This laboratory originated from the Lanzhou Institute of Glaciation and Permafrost, Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;established in 1965&lt;/span>;) and was founded by the &quot;Father of Chinese Glaciers&quot; It was established under the leadership of Shi Yafeng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores know the original appearance of the earth. For example, the ratio of stable isotopes of hydrogen and oxygen reflects the fluctuations in climate, and high values ​​of sulfate ions represent volcanic eruptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores also retain evidence of violent human activities, such as nuclear explosion tests and nuclear leaks one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Everest ice core drilled in 2005 was measured to have two beta activation peaks, corresponding to the global thermonuclear test in 1963 and the Chernobyl nuclear leak in 1986. In other words, the memory of the Cold War is sealed in the glacier. In 2017, ice cores drilled in the Aru glacier area at an altitude of 6,150 meters on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau were measured with five beta activation peaks of varying levels, which not only correspond to 1963, but also correspond to the 2004 Mihama Nuclear Power Plant in Japan. Steam leaks, the 2005 nuclear leakage accident at the Sellafield Nuclear Power Plant in the UK, the 1968 impact of a US bomber carrying four nuclear bombs and the 1970 explosion of the 10,000-ton underground nuclear device at Jakapin in the US, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WsbAJ4gjyJziZ2EIlI8fJ57HFd0b5SD0JK4b5QoT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WsbAJ4gjyJziZ2EIlI8fJ57HFd0b5SD0JK4b5QoT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, at the Mount Everest Mountaineering Base Camp, Kang Shichang (right), deputy director of the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, viewed a drill drill from an altitude of about 6,500 meters on Mount Everest. Ice core samples taken &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have found rich records of human activities in the ice cores. The peak lead content in the Greenland ice core drilled in 1994 corresponds to the peak period of the Roman Empire; the black carbon concentration in the East Rongbuk ice core on Mount Everest reflects the continued impact of pollutants emitted by human activities since the Industrial Revolution on the atmospheric environment; more The concentration of DDT in the Everest ice core corresponds to the malaria outbreak in India. DDT is a highly effective but environmentally damaging pesticide that is difficult to decompose. It has been banned by many countries since the late 1990s, but is still used in India. Therefore, the content of DDT in the forest soil of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau is currently the highest in the world, higher than Nordic Forest 10 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice core research is difficult to do because the sample size is very small and the appropriate detection indicators are limited. Even if there are good ideas, ice core research is extremely time-consuming and laborious. But ice core research is exactly the direction of Chen Pengfei’s transformation. “At this stage, I need the quality of papers more than the quantity,” he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To ensure that the ice core does not melt, ice core drilling always starts at seven or eight o&#39;clock in the evening and ends before the sun rises. Engineers use exhalation to judge when to start work: if you can exhale &quot;white air&quot;, the temperature is low enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before finishing work at 8 o&#39;clock in the morning, Chen Pengfei always walks out of the tent to watch the sunshine on Jinshan Mountain. The golden light falls from the sky and shines on the snow-capped mountain top. He had seen this scene more than 30 times at the pass, and he was delighted and moved every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How to describe it, starting from the top of the mountain, the golden color slowly falls, and then the entire Mount Everest is golden. It is very spectacular and I like it very much.&quot; Chen Pengfei said. His WeChat avatar is Rizhao Jinshan, a photo he took when he first came to Mount Everest in 2013. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nHTIwV6CtvarPGACGZCX91n3jXsBx6ldim9Lmia8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nHTIwV6CtvarPGACGZCX91n3jXsBx6ldim9Lmia8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, 2023, the scientific expedition team members maintained and upgraded the automatic weather station at an altitude of about 8,830 meters on Mount Everest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The glacier snow surface is printed with a complete human shape”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Those who engage in scientific research are always the poorest, and many scientific research team members They all say this with some embarrassment or a joke. There are too many places to spend money, and the equipment and consumables in the laboratory are the real gold-swallowing beasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for the specially designed drilling rig, the ice cores are surrounded by ordinary objects: ice cores in ordinary plastic bags, marked with black markers; the insulated box is the most common one, dark blue in appearance, one meter in diameter. It is half a meter long and wide, with soft pads inside to protect the ice core from impact; the soft pads are basically cut military green quilts, with red or black mottled cotton batting exposed here and there; as for the freezer, it is a common cold drink cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, it seems that the difficulties Chen Pengfei encounters can be attributed to saving money. On the second day of work, the generator failed to start. It was a non-Yamaha generator. The next day I pulled up the Yamaha generator and worked all night. Closed on the third day, Yamaha was damaged by a rare strong wind. On the fourth day, I borrowed a generator from Everest Base Camp to work, and asked my colleagues to quickly transport another generator. On the fifth day, the tent was completely blown to pieces and the business was closed again. Although the strong wind made people unable to stand steadily, the working tent was just a slightly thicker outdoor tent that had been blown by the wind on the Qilian Bayi Glacier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/sEz01Dwdsa2zl4XMJ4peip4mBeM6yO7jy5wzn99V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/sEz01Dwdsa2zl4XMJ4peip4mBeM6yO7jy5wzn99V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Pengfei&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t shave, Stop shaving.&quot; Chen Pengfei recited silently every night. It wasn&#39;t until the seventh day when new tents and new generators were used that the team members began to work continuously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As everyone in the cryosphere knows, ice coring is hard work. Chen Pengfei’s teacher, Vice President and Researcher of Northwest Institute Kang Shichang wrote in his Antarctic scientific expedition diary: “Compared with the glacier scientific expedition on the Tibetan Plateau, the conditions for the Antarctic ice sheet expedition are much better... The glacier expedition on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, There are only tents, especially in high-altitude areas. They usually use stones to build a stove, use a box to support a chopping board, and cook and cook in a corner of the tent. Sometimes chefs and scientific expedition team members can only sleep in the kitchen tent. Large We don’t have beds for part of the time, so we lie on the ground.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For Everest expeditions, we usually camp on moraine ridges surrounded by rocks. We try to find a few slightly flat stones and lay them with moisture-proof mats. Leather mattress. Every night we are constantly moving and changing sleeping positions, trying to avoid the direct &#39;collision&#39; of sharp rocks and looking for a relatively flat and comfortable position. Sometimes, we also need to camp on the glacier. Once on Mt. During the inspection, I lived for a month on the 6,300-meter-high Rongbuk Glacier in the Far East. When I left, there was a complete human shape printed on the snow surface of the glacier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Shichang participated in the China-U.S. Joint Pearl River Delta Initiative in 1997 The scientific expedition team on Mount Everest drilled the first ice core on Mount Everest; in 2005, he served as the captain of China’s fourth comprehensive scientific expedition team on Mount Everest; in 2013, he led the team to drill 3 ice cores on the East Rongbuk Glacier, including 142 The meter-long one is the longest Everest ice core drilled in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The suffering on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau cannot be compared to the Antarctic.&quot; He said. Almost all work in Antarctica is mechanized, but on the glaciers of the Tibetan Plateau, all work relies on human power, such as shouting slogans to drag dozens of kilograms of ice cores across the ice ridge. Not only must we overcome altitude sickness, we must also do heavy physical work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Creating ice is also a laborious activity. Therefore, in addition to scientists, there are more workers in the team. Most of them have cooperated with Northwest Institute for many years, going to the plateau to climb snow-capped mountains, and walking far away carrying a 100-pound generator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/j9gcOLRvL7U9oBvhhtHO2xip2WHxU3DuARq9qLuk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/j9gcOLRvL7U9oBvhhtHO2xip2WHxU3DuARq9qLuk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Zhaofu (left)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 6500 After working continuously for more than ten days at Mi Chu, everyone felt weak. The strong wind not only damaged the tents and generators, but also made the team members unable to walk every night. &quot;It was obvious that the team members were a little out of control, their tone was a little tough, and they were a little broken.&quot; Chen Pengfei said. Sometimes everyone would sing in the tent, singing loudly without knowing the words or music, which was more like a way to vent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I couldn’t eat or sleep well, and there was strong wind and heavy rain. Everyone has had the experience of getting lost, either using Mani Stones to identify the direction, or relying on teammates&#39; calls to find someone. Everyone has worked on the plateau until they were exhausted. Kang Shichang once chased a frightened yak carrying samples at an altitude of 5,000 meters for samples, until both the yak and he were unable to move due to lack of oxygen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In your subject, will there be more children from rural areas?” We asked Kang Shichang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s absolutely true.&quot; Kang Shichang replied loudly, &quot;Almost all are rural children, and rural children can endure hardship.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The youngest member of Kang Shichang&#39;s team is Hu Zhaofu, 2023 He left his postdoctoral position in 2011 and joined Northwest Institute. He is from Suzhou, Anhui and grew up in a village next to the Lianhuo Expressway. Before going to middle school in the county town, he not only often climbed mountains, but also caught scorpions: he would lift up rocks, and when he found a scorpion, he would hold its tail and blow on it, and then skewer it with chopsticks. Small scorpions are sold for 1 or 2 cents, and larger ones are sold for 40 or 50 cents. Hu Zhaofu, a primary school student, can get more than one yuan of pocket money every time he catches a scorpion. I was stung four or five times, but I didn&#39;t deal with it, saying that the pain would be gone in a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Hu Zhaofu participated in the scientific expedition to the Geladandong Snow Mountain. He worked for 20 days at an altitude of about 5,800 meters, and was able to eat, sleep, and be physically strong. That time he was particularly happy and a little proud. &quot;I see that other people are a little high-reflex, so I feel that my body is capable of doing this job, and God is giving me food.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/8WI03FcUtgWZ3wQwrIKW9NwgjxT1P60rH0SGtYmo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/8WI03FcUtgWZ3wQwrIKW9NwgjxT1P60rH0SGtYmo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Junming&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Reporter Dashi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The ice tower forest is gradually melting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The ice tower forest is getting less and less.” Hu Zhaofu said. The first time he climbed Mount Everest was in 2019. In the past four years, the shrinkage of the seracs was visible to the naked eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 5800 and 6300 meters on Mount Everest, the seracs gradually shrink to become sparse and low, making them hard to find at a glance. You have to walk to the mountain col to see them. The seracs look like the teeth of a giant shark and are a form of ice unique to high-altitude areas. Seracs that appear in groups are called seracs. Unlike most seracs that are not as tall as a person, the Everest seracs are scattered in heights, with the tallest ones exceeding 30 meters. Because the seracs on Mount Everest are so tall and resemble a Gothic spire church, Western explorers call them the &quot;Penitentes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seracs are remnants of the melting glaciers. Due to the different movement speeds and ice densities of various parts of the glacier, some cracks and gaps will appear on the surface of the glacier. Mount Everest is located at 27°59&#39; north latitude, which is a low latitude and uneven sunlight exposure. When glaciers melt, the ice in the cracks melts faster, and seracs gradually form. As the temperature rises, the seracs gradually melt and may accumulate into glacial lakes or merge into rivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Permafrost areas are most sensitive to climate change. The Tibetan Plateau is warming at a rate more than twice the global average, and scientists warn that by 2100, the Tibetan Plateau will lose two-thirds of its glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where is the boundary between man and nature changing each other? Every time he goes out to work in the field, some broad, abstract, and unanswered thoughts will envelope Guo Junming and last until he goes down the mountain. &quot;Human beings are part of the earth. When people adapt to the earth, they will inevitably change the earth. What degree of change is appropriate? The future temperature control value we call is actually the boundary where humans feel comfortable. What about the earth itself? The earth has never experienced such violent activities. Where is the boundary of the earth?&quot; He asked a series of questions and finally concluded, &quot;I sometimes wonder if the earth can be in any state without humans?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no answers to these questions, but these questions give meaning to Guo Junming’s research. His recent research focus is on the mercury cycle in the cryosphere of the Tibetan Plateau. Human activities cause large amounts of mercury to enter water bodies, atmosphere and soil, and then enter the ecological cycle. Mercury can be detected at all three of Earth&#39;s remote poles. In the 1950s, mercury-containing wastewater was discharged from Minamata Bay in Japan. Fish and shrimp were contaminated, and then entered the bodies of birds, cats, and humans through the food chain. The victims ranged from slurred speech and staggering, to neurological disorders and death. This is the &quot;Minamata Disease Incident in Japan&quot; that shocked the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2017, the Minamata Convention on Mercury came into effect, and so far 128 countries have signed it. In Guo Junming&#39;s view, it was batch after batch of scientific researchers who used research results to clarify the environmental behavior and hazards of mercury, which promoted the birth and signing of the Minamata Convention. He hopes that his research can help all parties understand mercury more fully, and then promote the implementation of the contract by signatory countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Currently, mercury emissions in many countries in Europe and the United States have dropped, but emissions in South Asia are still very large. What I want to study is what impact and how mercury emissions in South Asia have on our Qinghai-Tibet Plateau.&quot; He explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WU7AmICxijsST7iuLs8uDqokazvx1aj00Q5JnVBx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WU7AmICxijsST7iuLs8uDqokazvx1aj00Q5JnVBx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gao Tanguang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter’s food/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Enjoyed this Such freedom, no longer wanting to do regular work&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The ice cores that were dug were buried in the snow. After the ice core penetrated to the bottom, the team members walked back from the pass to the camp at 6,350 meters, packed the boxes until late at night, and waited for the yaks to carry the insulated boxes down the mountain the next day. They then stored them in the base camp freezer and transported them back to Lanzhou by truck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not two days after returning to Lanzhou from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, Guo Junming returned to the office to be busy. He is 36 years old, in his prime academic years, and the breadwinner of his family. Every day he receives a steady stream of phone calls, routine work one after another, and noises he wants to avoid again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice coring is different. There is no signal at 6,300 meters, and Guo Junming’s mobile phone hardly turns on. &quot;It&#39;s so cool not to have a mobile phone, hahaha,&quot; Guo Junming laughed, &quot;I said it a bit harsh, and that&#39;s true. As soon as I got back to the city, I kept calling, emailing, WeChat and all kinds of things. Even if I couldn&#39;t receive them on Mount Everest, I would reply. No, I didn’t do it on purpose, I just couldn’t help it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called his home satellite phone every two or three days. In addition, Guo Junming only has three things to do on Mount Everest: eat, sleep and make ice cores. &quot;Creating ice cores with peace of mind.&quot; Guo Junming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having been to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau many times, Guo Junming is now quite proficient in climbing Mount Everest. He knows how far it is to walk from an altitude of 5,300 meters to 6,300 meters. He can always reach it by walking slowly at his own pace and taking his time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tjNJmoO8ystPHYNqgPbyjL9xgC3zDj1wrykNdOPl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tjNJmoO8ystPHYNqgPbyjL9xgC3zDj1wrykNdOPl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255399&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zou Qiao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going out into the wild is work, and it is also an adjustment to one&#39;s life. &quot;It&#39;s really depressing to stay in the office for a long time. Go out and see the mountains, lakes, and climb mountains. There will be a few days where you can experience another kind of life, and your mental state will be better after you come back.&quot; Guo Junming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although going out into the field is no longer a necessary condition for geological research, and samples taken by colleagues or partners can also be used for research, in our interviews, everyone participating in the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition Scientific researchers all love nature and love going out into the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Tanguang, associate professor at the School of Resources and Environment of Lanzhou University, offered to take us mountain climbing during the interview. &quot;Let&#39;s change places. It&#39;s a bit silly to sit here (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;café&lt;/span>;),&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who would have thought that the interview would be in Wuquan Mountain, the northern foot of Gaolan Mountain, a natural barrier in Lanzhou city. Not only does Gao Tanguang take his children to climb Wuquan Mountain every Saturday, he even holds group meetings for students by climbing the mountain first and then talking about academics after climbing to the top. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is the senior brother of Chen Pengfei and Guo Junming. He also graduated from the Tibet Institute and studied for a doctorate in Beijing for five years. As a native of Shandong, he worked as a teacher at a key high school in Beijing after graduation and also worked in his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GKxiX67cZQvbT3hDKbojRgth2FIx0tQ9ss06yVG7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GKxiX67cZQvbT3hDKbojRgth2FIx0tQ9ss06yVG7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, near the Mount Everest Mountaineering Base Camp, scientific expedition team members from the School of Ecology and Environment of Tibet University collected aquatic life samples&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both of these work experiences were very short because they were boring. &quot;When you have experienced the scenery of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau for several consecutive years, when field work accounts for a large part of your life, when you have enjoyed the atmosphere of the research group chatting and laughing in the wild, and enjoyed the abundant time to search for something for several days in a row, I have been running around in the mountains, not caring about anything, completely isolated from the outside world. I have enjoyed this kind of freedom, but once I enter a regular job, it is really unbearable.&quot; Gao Tanguang said, &quot;I have always felt that cities are just reinforced concrete. It&#39;s hard to never get out of the forest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He wanted to live freely and live freely. It is difficult to tell whether this is his nature or whether it was shaped by his five years of studying at the Institute of Tibetan Studies. In the past five years, he not only went out in the wild, but also loved to ride mountain bikes in Beijing. He rode from his dormitory to Yanqing, a round trip of more than 100 kilometers. He spent a year as a visiting scholar at the University of Jena, Germany, and traveled through Northern Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;focused on playing in the Arctic Circle&lt;/span>;). He spread out a blanket at the train station and slept, not afraid or alone. &quot;I was in a small town in Norway. I was going to sleep at the train station at night. A group of German college students came in and sat together and took turns reading to everyone. My German is not good, so I couldn&#39;t understand anything I read, but it was so interesting. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tJ3R0BpP98C1XsEeQVFiJopSqi3mArE4kkE7kZYH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tJ3R0BpP98C1XsEeQVFiJopSqi3mArE4kkE7kZYH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, near the Mount Everest climbing base camp, scientific expedition members collected soil samples&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Danger&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Pengfei refuses to miss every sunshine on the Golden Summit, Guo Junming finds peace in making ice cores, and Gao Tanguang is free due to field scientific research. But the romance and charm of glacier scientific research often belong to the lucky and brave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, the name Lin Shubiao was mentioned. In 2011, 29-year-old Lin Shubiao, a doctor from the Institute of Tibetan Studies, disappeared while inspecting the Muztag Glacier in Xinjiang. After completing the installation of the automatic weather station on the Muztag Glacier in Xinjiang, he lost contact while descending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most speculations are that he fell into a deep and winding ice crevice and could not be found by search and rescue. He is a native of Tangkou Natural Village, Zhendong Village, Jiushi City, Zhaoqing City, Guangdong Province. He won the &quot;township top scorer&quot; in the high school entrance examination. He walked out of the mountains in the college entrance examination and was called &quot;the pride of the mountain people&quot; by the villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice crevasses are the biggest danger in glacier scientific research. Most of the time, the crevasses are covered in snow and difficult to see. Kang Shichang once fell into a half-meter-wide ice crevasse. He held his feet on both sides of the crevice, and his body was suspended in the air, waiting for rescue. &quot;I wasn&#39;t afraid at all at that time. The other team members would definitely look for me when they saw that I was missing!&quot; Today, 22 years later, when he talked about this past incident, he suddenly slapped his thigh and said, &quot;Hey! I&#39;m really scared when I think about it now, but I didn’t panic at all at that time! I was so courageous at that time.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if they have never fallen into an ice crevasse, everyone can tell a story about a serious case of high fever that they witnessed with their own eyes. Urgent transports down the mountain often encounter dangerous moments: they may get lost halfway and fail to arrive late at night; or they may have become incontinent, and the consequences would be unpredictable if they were slower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, modern glacier scientific research was born along with mountaineering expeditions that represented human courage. Early scientific expeditions to Mount Everest were always closely tied to Everest expeditions. They also began with human curiosity and desire for unknown territories. Mountaineers not only want to climb Mount Everest, but also get back precious basic information, such as images or samples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The first expedition made very valuable geological surveys, and both expeditions also observed and collected many geological and botanical specimens. The geologists wanted a stone from the summit of Mount Everest , so that you can determine whether the peak is at the top or bottom of the fold.&quot; In 1922, Mallory, the British explorer who first attempted to climb Mount Everest, introduced the scientific gains of climbing Mount Everest twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time China organized scientific researchers to conduct a comprehensive investigation of the 7,000 square kilometers centered on Mount Everest was in 1959, in order to cooperate with the national mountaineering team in preparing for the first climb of Mount Everest. The first modern glacier scientific expedition in China was just two years ago, in 1957. At that time, regarding the activities organized by the All-China Federation of Trade Unions to climb Mount Gongga, He Long, then director of the National Sports Commission, instructed: Mountain climbing should serve scientific research and expand social effects. Three scientific workers were selected to climb Mount Gongga: Cui Zhijiu, Ma Wenfu and Ding Xingyou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That&#39;s a hero! Our hero in the glacier world!&quot; In a chat, someone mentioned Cui Zhijiu. Kang Shichang gave a thumbs up and said in a loud voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Zhijiu’s glacier career began in 1957 when he climbed Mount Gongga. The following year, he published &quot;Preliminary Observation of Modern Glaciers in the Gongga Mountains&quot;, filling the gap in the study of modern glaciers in China. The subtitle of this paper is: &quot;In memory of the comrades who died heroically in the conquest of Gongga Mountain.&quot; In Gongga Mountain, four team members encountered mountain disasters, including scientific worker Ding Xingyou, who was an assistant professor in the Meteorology Department of Beijing Agricultural University at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next 10 years, Cui Zhijiu visited the Everest region twice and climbed Nyenchen Tanglha, Muztagh and Shishapangma. He lost five fingers from the cold, suffered from severe snow blindness, and experienced the sacrifices of 12 teammates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that such tragic stories have rarely been seen in glacier scientific expeditions in the past 30 years, but what the older generation of scientists experienced and persevered still has lasting power for those who come after them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Tan Guangzheng, who was born in the 1980s, read &quot;Qinghai Tibet: 50 Years of Scientific Investigation on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Published by Sanlian Bookstore in 1999), I have been fascinated by the Qinghai-Tibet scientific research since college. He also loves to read &quot;National Geographic&quot; and goes to the old market every month to buy back issues with their covers torn off. &quot;It&#39;s said to be a back issue, but it&#39;s actually only one month away. It only costs 3 yuan a copy. Hahahaha, for only 3 yuan, you can own a copy of last month&#39;s National Geographic.&quot; He learned from National Geographic&#39;s I learned about the Qinghai-Tibet Institute and Kang Shichang in the special episode of Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, and later became a disciple of Kang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/HfsJGXoMZdcG0Vr9R6cVG4oSNNbTt0HNaEXptuvu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/HfsJGXoMZdcG0Vr9R6cVG4oSNNbTt0HNaEXptuvu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 10, 2023, at the Everest Atmospheric and Environmental Comprehensive Observation and Research Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, scientific expedition members used scientific instruments to collect greenhouse gases in the air&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Vast Tibet&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, it seems that due to the update of scientific research results, &quot;The Vast Tibet&quot; is no longer a good book. popular science readings, but the hundreds of people mentioned in detail or in detail still exude the charisma of passing on scientific research from generation to generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1968, glaciologist Xie Zichu signed up to participate in the scientific expedition to Mount Everest. He returned home with a full load. As soon as he got off the train, he was dragged into a fight and locked up in a cowshed that night. He was criticized for three years, but he quietly compiled the investigation data in the bullpen and completed a thesis on the ice-forming effect of infiltration on Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 1972, the Qinghai-Tibet Scientific Expedition Team was established. Many experts who had lost their jobs and had been working in the &quot;May 7th Cadre School&quot; all year round told each other that they called it a &quot;safe haven&quot;. Through this scientific expedition team, our country began to establish an understanding of the Tibetan Plateau from different subject dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the 1950s, the main achievements of the 30-year first phase of modern glaciology in China were the completion of regional and national filling of snow, ice, and frozen soil. This basic work means long and arduous field expeditions and a lifelong dedication of a group in particularly harsh conditions: the starting point of the work of glaciologists is where the snow line lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the snowy swamp area, the car was stuck and dug repeatedly, and on the extremely cold night when the wind and snow overturned the tent, you would feel the burden on the lungs and heart every step you took, and for those with severe mountain sickness, emergency rescue, the joy of surviving a desperate situation, the fragility and magnificence of life that can be experienced in the snowy mountains and ice fields, as well as the relief and countless emotions at the end of each expedition... After every danger is saved, they will always I was overjoyed: &#39;It was so dangerous!&#39; After every field trip, I couldn&#39;t help but sigh with regret. But when I went out to the field again the next year, I was brave enough to move forward courageously. Choosing this career also meant accepting it. Everything related to it.&quot; There is such a passage in &quot;Qinghai-Tibet Vast&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;The Vast Tibet&quot;, in 1980, when the International Scientific Symposium on the Tibetan Plateau was held, Deng Xiaoping smiled loudly and replied in Sichuan dialect: &quot;We in China have With so many mountains, it doesn’t matter if you take away a few stones. They can take them if they want.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, international exchanges and cooperation in Tibetan Plateau research have become routine work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My mentor is very far-sighted.” Kang Shichang talked about academician Qin Dahe, the first Chinese to cross the Antarctic continent on foot and the author of the assessment report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When my supervisor trains students, he must first be international. When I was studying for a Ph.D., he asked me to study abroad several times, and my postdoctoral work was also done in the United States.&quot; Kang Shichang was a little emotional, &quot;When I was in After traveling around the world, I realized that there are differences in culture and good and bad politicians, but people are very amiable. Many times, group interests and political interests lead to many conflicts on our planet. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because the subject research he is engaged in is always related to the changes of the entire earth. In Kang Shichang’s eyes, the earth is the dust of the universe, and human beings are the dust of the earth. Disputes and conflicts are inevitable in the face of the vast universe. Lost meaning. &quot;Global warming is not caused by any country, but by all mankind. Human beings on the earth must be peaceful and united without too many conflicts.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/eqTDESi1mURABf2rWjkoots7uARONNc9rvAa7QGe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/eqTDESi1mURABf2rWjkoots7uARONNc9rvAa7QGe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xi Zhenhua at Everest Base Camp &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Reporter Dashi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Don’t waste time at the Mount Everest Station&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years , every scientific researcher who goes on the scientific expedition to Mount Everest has to deal with Xi Zhenhua. He is the observation supervisor of the Mount Everest Atmosphere and Environment Comprehensive Observation and Research Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Everest Station&quot;&lt;/span>;), and is also The person in charge of various specific affairs at the Everest Station in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua has been at the foot of Mount Everest for 10 years, and this time is constantly lengthening. He is an indispensable part of various scientific expeditions on Mount Everest. The Everest Station, 30 kilometers away from the base camp, is the last preparation area before the Everest scientific expedition. Here, the scientific expedition team members can use the power supply from the national grid, sleep in bed with air conditioning, and use the toilet normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its completion in 2005, in the past 18 years, the Everest Station has evolved from a tent to a prefabricated house to a building, and its observation and monitoring instruments have gradually been completed. After Xi Zhenhua came to the Mount Everest Station, he added several people as helpers to perform data collection on different scientific research tasks, such as regularly monitoring the hydrology of the Rongbuk River, observing the growth of alpine shrubs, and guarding against local plum blossoms being eaten by plateau sheep, instrument The battery was stolen. During the peak season of the scientific expedition, he helped the scientific expedition team communicate with the locals, arrange food and accommodation, and deal with various practical problems, such as driving injured workers to the hospital in Shigatse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, in order to prove that he could stay at the Mount Everest station, Xi Zhenhua stayed on the mountain for more than half a year for the first time. He had diarrhea as soon as he drank water and lost more than 20 pounds. It was not until he spent the New Year at the village cadre&#39;s house that he learned that boiling water in a pressure cooker could cure his acclimatization. &quot;Now it doesn&#39;t matter whether I use a pressure cooker or not. I just get used to it as I drink,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua is already half a local. On the way up the mountain with him, he chatted enthusiastically with his &quot;three brothers and three sisters-in-law&quot; and regretted that he missed the horse racing festival. There are two boys from the nearby Basong Village who often come to play basketball in front of the Everest Station. Xi Zhenhua watches with gusto. He went to a Tibetan home to celebrate the Tibetan New Year, where he ate steamed vegetables, drank wine, sang, danced and played dice. After the round, he came back to eat, drink and sing. He also collects donations of clothes from his circle of friends and distributes them to villagers with financial difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is not good at sociability, but he has become familiar with the locals because of his time. &quot;Over the past few years, they have become familiar with this place. Maybe they think that I am very honest and I will not treat them badly, so they are very willing to help me with many things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This place was only opened in 2016 When the power was turned on, the violent storm cracked the window glass. Peppers, potatoes, leeks and rapeseed are grown in the vegetable greenhouse. During the meal, eight people share a plate of scrambled eggs with leeks. The weather is getting colder, and I shiver with cold every time I go down the river to measure data; when going up or down the mountain in the middle of the night, there are frequent rockfalls, and swarms of moths and lime hit the windshield. Every time I go forward, it is like breaking through the fog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once upon a time, Xi Zhenhua’s closest friend was a native dog named Dahuang, who had been there since he entered the station. Every time he returned to the station in the middle of the night, Dahuang would lie at the door waiting for him, and would rush at anyone he saw. Wags the tail forward. &quot;Last year, before I got on the plane, I found out that Dahuang was dead. I couldn&#39;t stop crying all the way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a secular sense, Xi Zhenhua has many disappointments. But after seeing mountains and rocks for months and years, he forgot about that. &quot;Sometimes you can live very easily if you don&#39;t think about the messy things. Day by day passes like this, very fast.&quot; Xi Zhenhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is not stingy with time, has few desires, and is somewhat insensitive. Staying at the Mount Everest station for 10 years is not painful for Xi Zhenhua. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He loves to pick up stones and relies on his imagination to select stones: like a lady dancing, like a white tiger lying prone, like a Tibetan antelope leaping. When I was most lonely, stones were piled up on the wall behind the Everest station. He doesn&#39;t smoke and doesn&#39;t drink much, so he passes the time by recreating stone textures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua’s real pain is his relationship with his daughter. He spends little time with his family and knows that his children have a weak relationship with him. Sometimes the video only hangs up after saying two or three sentences. &quot;We will face this kind of problem in the wild for a long time. It is always a problem and there is nothing we can do about it,&quot; he sighed. Every time he thought about this, he felt a little regretful about coming to the Everest Station. &quot;I want to stay with my wife at home.&quot; Children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After coming down from the mountain in 2023, Xi Zhenhua went to his daughter&#39;s school to participate in the &quot;Parents in the Classroom&quot; activity. He told the primary school students about the origin of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, his work on the station and interesting stories. The daughter was very happy that day and thought her father had done a good job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At least I can gain some status in the children&#39;s hearts.&quot; Xi Zhenhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking from the open space in front of the Everest Station, if the sky is clear, you can see a small section of the Golden Summit at sunset. Sometimes there are colorful auspicious clouds, so colorful that they have the gentle power to soothe people&#39;s hearts. In the middle of the night, I looked up and saw the starry sky, with the Milky Way brushing across the night like a brush. Many steep unknown mountains have names in Xi Zhenhua&#39;s mouth: This one has a lion&#39;s face, that one has a horse&#39;s body. His favorite saying is: Compared with Mount Everest, these are nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZQxbMx6X9tJPsw9g9DNDvqUFfmpHNtIZ1Mqdr3fi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZQxbMx6X9tJPsw9g9DNDvqUFfmpHNtIZ1Mqdr3fi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;British explorer Mallory&#39;s photo spot&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zou Qiao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cross Two photos from the year 102&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before reaching 6,500 meters in 2023, the scientific expedition team will stay at the base camp for many days to complete glacier end sampling, glacier lake measurement, and an idea of ​​​​slanting out: find Here’s another photo of the location of the Rongbuk Glacier in Mallory’s 1921 photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest existing image of the Everest glacier was taken by British explorer Mallory. Mallory once said a famous sentence in the history of mountaineering - when someone asked him why he wanted to climb Mount Everest, he replied succinctly:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because the mountain is there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;The dream of climbing Mount Everest has attracted the British elite for many years. Veteran and mountaineer Mallory was selected by the British Mountaineering Club to become the hope of seizing the afterglow of the once &quot;empire on which the sun never sets&quot; after entering the 20th century. Since the second half of the 19th century, British exploration has ceased to lead. They repeatedly failed in the race to open the Northwest Passage and reach the North and South Poles of the Earth. After the end of World War I, Mount Everest, known as the &quot;Third Pole&quot;, became Britain&#39;s last hope to prove itself. Many newspapers in the UK published a speech by Younghusband, chairman of the Royal Geographical Society - better known as a colonist who led troops to invade Tibet in 1903-1904 and killed many people - saying that he was the first to stand on Everest. Those at the top will inspire countless comers and cheer up the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mallory climbed Mount Everest with the team in 1921 and 1922. The first time he reached an altitude of 7,000 meters, he photographed the Zhongrongbuk Glacier; the second time he reached an altitude of 8,320 meters, with 7 people on the way. Sherpa killed by avalanche. His teammates found a trail leading up through the East Rongbuk Glacier: a rise of dirt and rock right in the middle of the glacier that made it possible to hike directly across the glacier. Since then, climbers and scientific expedition team members of all generations have walked through this road to reach the 6,500-meter mark of Mount Everest. Western explorers call it the &quot;Miracle Highway&quot;, and Chen Pengfei said they call it the &quot;Yak Trail&quot;: this is the last section of Mount Everest that yaks can pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1924, Mallory climbed Mount Everest for the third time. This time he had a young partner, Andrew Owen, a student from Oxford University. On the morning of June 8, the two set off from 8,300 meters with new oxygen equipment, and then disappeared on Mount Everest. It was not until 1999 that an American mountaineering team sponsored by the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) discovered Mallory&#39;s body at about 8,170 meters on the north slope of Mount Everest, but there is still no trace of Owen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the two men had ever reached the summit during their lifetimes has become one of the most famous mysteries in the history of modern mountaineering. The climbing team did not find a photo of Mallory&#39;s wife in Mallory&#39;s well-preserved belongings. He once promised that if he reached the summit, he would leave a photo of his wife on Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Rongbuk Glacier photographed by Mallory is a photo familiar to permafrost researchers. Kang Shichang even used this photo as the cover of a course teaching the changes in Mount Everest glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finding Mallory’s shooting spot was Gao Danguang’s task, and he was quite excited about it. Mallory was his favorite explorer: full of grit, heroic tragedy, and unsolved mysteries. He initially did not know that the 1921 photo of Zhongrongbu Glacier was taken by Mallory and that it had appeared in his study materials. When he learned that the photographer was Mallory, a sense of intimacy came over him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many years ago you read bits and pieces about someone, and then suddenly discovered that you had already met him in your work, and it was like the intimacy of meeting an old acquaintance in a foreign country. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glaciers are changing all the time: accumulation and melting constitute the material balance of ice and snow. Climate change can tip this balance off at any time, causing glaciers to advance or retreat. Therefore, scientists always want to obtain as much data as possible on changes in glaciers over time to study the changing processes of glaciers and climate. Although glacier monitoring in the Himalayas has made rapid progress in the past 20 years with the help of satellite remote sensing technology, long-term continuous observations are still lacking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we can take another picture of the Zhongrongbuk Glacier at the Mallory shooting point, it will move the time scale of observing glacier changes forward by 102 years. This is the scientific significance of finding Mallory&#39;s shooting spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaotanguang failed three times, for different reasons: unable to cross the moraine on the west side of the Rongbuk Glacier; there was a problem with the instrument; the shooting point was found but was blocked by clouds and fog. Finally, his junior brother Wang Shaoyong and an accompanying reporter took a picture of the Zhongrongbu Glacier in 2023 at the Mallory shooting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the first glacier distribution map of the Mount Everest region drawn by the British mountaineering team in 1921, Gao Tanguang compared the two photos spanning 102 years and was surprised to find that the distribution of the Rongbuk Glacier in mid-1921 The seracs are about 4 kilometers below the current terminal seracs, and the huge glacial lake at the end of the glacier today did not exist back then. This means that as the global climate continues to warm, the end of the Zhongrongbuk Glacier is retreating by an average of 40 meters per year, and the retreat rate is increasing year by year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the end of the Halong Glacier in the Animaqing Mountains in the Yellow River source area has retreated by 450 meters in the 11 years from 2006 to 2017, while the Gangjiaquba located in the east of Geladandang, the source of the Yangtze River The glacier has retreated more than 4 kilometers since 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SGCzy0HK8bSTD86oxanq9IR03P3EWHWGGyFL5Yvq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SGCzy0HK8bSTD86oxanq9IR03P3EWHWGGyFL5Yvq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At about 12:30 on May 23, 2023, the 13 summit members of the 2023 Everest Scientific Expedition successfully climbed to the top of Mount Everest, the top of the earth. After that, they will complete important scientific research tasks such as collecting snow and ice samples from the peak&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The memory of the disappearing glaciers&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;At this time, one day in October 2023, Chen Pengfei went to the Geladandong Peak of Tanggula Mountain to take ice cores again. On the way to the foot of the mountain, the falling snow enveloped the surroundings in a white mist. The spray-like snow blown off from the snow-capped mountains looks like endless white scarves against the blue sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 40 centimeters of snow in Gradandong delayed Chen Pengfei’s work progress: every step seemed to be opening a path. “I thought it would take two days to move everything, but now it looks like it will take five or six days.” When he thought he would lose the signal, he shared a photo of a snowy field with us. It was a vast expanse. “Under the snow were stones and straw bags. , It’s easy to sprain your feet and you have to return to the tent before dark. If you are too tired from walking, the team members will collapse easily.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Kang Shichang’s team took ice cores from Gradandong was in 2005. Chen Pengfei This time we walked higher than 18 years ago: the higher the altitude, the less likely it is for the glacier to melt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 Gradandong ice core was cut into more than 3,000 small pieces. Zhang Qianggong, a researcher at the Tibet Institute, tried to date it by testing indicators related to nuclear explosions - this is the most mature method for dating ice cores. one. But it took him two years to locate the peak of tritium activity in the 1960s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We expected that the peak should appear at about 20 meters, but in fact it appeared at 5 meters. In another ice core from Nyenchen Tanglha Mountain, we did not find a corresponding nuclear explosion Value, this has caused us a lot of trouble, what is the problem?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, Zhang Qianggong brought the ice core to the Paul Hill Institute in Switzerland. &quot;This is the world&#39;s largest nuclear energy and chemical laboratory. The research finally determined that the top of the Gladandong ice core corresponds to 1982, but this ice core was drilled in 2005, and the top should correspond to 2005. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In other words, the records of the Gradandong ice core from 1982 to 2005 are missing. The information loss of the Nyenchen Tanglha ice core is even greater. The records only stop at 1950. Ten years of memories have disappeared.&quot; Zhang Qianggong shared this research experience in a speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Global warming is melting the ice. Research by two generations of scientists has confirmed that human activities are causing rising temperatures. Based on the six climate change policies issued by the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (hereinafter referred to as IPCC&lt;/span>;) from 1990 to 2003) Take the first assessment report as an example. The 1990 report stated that “there is very little observational evidence to detect the impact of human activities on climate.” By 2007, the report stated that “global warming since the mid-20th century is likely to be caused by human activities.” By 2023, the IPCC is very convinced that &quot;there is no doubt that human activities have caused warming of the atmosphere, oceans and land.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glaciers remember human activities, but human activities are also erasing glaciers memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fairness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As temperatures rise and glaciers melt, the consequences are of course not only the disappearance of serac forests, but more importantly, the occurrence of avalanches, floods, and the reduction of fresh water resources. There are an increasing number of large glacial lakes in the Himalayas that could burst their banks at any time and destroy high mountain communities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Global warming is not only about the environment, but also about fairness. The most vulnerable people and ecosystems are disproportionately affected by loss and damage and are suffering a disproportionate share of the adverse impacts of climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2006, the village of Harji in western Nepal has been hit by glacial lake floods every summer. Floods and reverse currents flew down from the glacial lake on Namunani Peak at 5,300 meters in the western Himalayas, sweeping away houses, horses and crops; in 2012, an avalanche in the Himalayas caused river flooding and killed more than 70 Nepalis; In 2016, the Nepalese military spent several months dredging Lake Imza, the glacial lake on Mount Everest. In 2018, scientists warned that climate warming will cause the glaciers in the Himalayas to melt at an alarming rate, and Lake Imza may continue to expand. Eventually it collapses, possibly causing horrific floods in Nepal. Rishi Ram Sharma, director of the Nepal Hydrological Meteorological Service, said: &quot;As a small country, it is difficult for us to prevent what happens to the glacier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the IPCC&#39;s Sixth Assessment &quot;Synthesis Report&quot; stated , almost half of the world’s population lives in areas that are highly vulnerable to climate change. Over the past decade, deaths from floods, droughts and storms were 15 times higher in highly vulnerable areas than in low vulnerability areas. “Taking the right actions now will bring about fundamental changes that are crucial to building a sustainable and equitable world.” IPCC emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1961 to 2016, the Tibetan Plateau lost more than 43 billion tons of ice, but this is less than one percent of the global ice retreat. The global ice volume has lost more than 9 trillion tons in 55 years. In the 1990s, about 0.8 trillion tons of ice melted every year. From 2000 to 2017, the annual ice melt volume was about 1.3 trillion tons. In simple calculation, 1 trillion tons of ice is a large ice block with a length, width and height of 10 kilometers, which is higher than Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now is the warmest time in the past two thousand years. Recovery is a very slow process. I can&#39;t imagine how to cool the earth and restore the seracs. You won&#39;t be able to see this by the end of this century. &quot;Arrived.&quot; Kang Shichang said, &quot;The amount of water released by the glacier ice sheet causes the sea level to rise by 3 millimeters per year. If the global sea level rises by 15 meters, it is equivalent to the demise of the Greenland ice sheet. Then the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, Yangtze River Delta, The Pearl River Delta will be in catastrophe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have made many early warnings, but the power of change often does not belong to them. IPCC Chairman Li Huisheng told government representatives around the world during discussions at the 2023 conference: “Mainstreaming effective and equitable climate action will not only reduce loss and damage to nature and people, but also bring wider benefits. If we take action now, we can still provide a livable and sustainable future for everyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time we take ice cores, the team always asks some Tibetans to help, 24-year-old Dundang Also among them. He is from Quzong Village, one of the villages closest to Everest Base Camp. Everest tourism, Everest scientific expeditions and commercial mountaineering have brought new livelihoods to the people of Quzong Village. Dundang said, &quot;Here, Everest is our greatest resource.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What do you think of Mount Everest?&quot; Has the peak changed?&quot; a reporter asked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mount Everest has not changed, it is still the majestic Mount Everest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do you want to leave?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No, we are here There is a relationship between people and Mount Everest.&quot; He gestured a thumbs up to the camera and said with a smile, &quot;Welcome to come back next year!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to the Northwest Institute of Eco-Environmental Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences and He Peiyun for their help with this interview.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>