<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[人类请回答：科幻能否跟上现实的魔幻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260297]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VHmTK17O6xJf358f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Ys72GFTbx0IzSk18UAKRY3j6VH mTK17O6xJf358f. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 18, 2023, the main venue of the 81st World Science Fiction Convention-Chengdu Science Fiction Museum, people walk in the &quot;time and space tunnel&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A problem that has never occurred in 5 million years&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy for Mr. Bryant, an 80-year-old science fiction fan, to travel to Chengdu from Hampshire. He first took a flight from the UK to the Netherlands, transferred in Beijing, and finally arrived in Chengdu. Pidu District, Chengdu City is the venue for the 81st World Science Fiction Convention. The local area is famous for Pixian Doubanjiang. Two years ago, Mr. Bryant voted for Chengdu, China, at the World Science Fiction Convention. In mid-October 2023, he arrived at the appointment and came to mainland China for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Mr. Bryant has not read the most popular science fiction work in China - Liu Cixin&#39;s &quot;Three-Body&quot; series, nor has he read any Chinese science fiction works, after a few days with Chinese science fiction Face-to-face communication with fans, his interest in this place has gone beyond science fiction. As a lover of cooking, he plans to bring several jars of bean paste and a local cookbook in English when he returns home to study Sichuan cuisine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chengdu Science Museum, which looks like a giant spacecraft and covers an area of ​​nearly 60,000 square meters, people often excitedly share their encounters with him in the WeChat group of science fiction fans on site. At the age of 80, he still has a strong curiosity about the world, which gives young science fiction fans a lot of encouragement. However, the language barrier has become Mr. Bryant&#39;s biggest challenge in participating in this conference. He has participated in 14 World Science Fiction Conventions before, and only 4 of the previous 80 conferences were held in non-English speaking countries. The venue in Chengdu had elements from science fiction movies and TV shows like &quot;Star Trek&quot; and &quot;Doctor Who&quot; that he was familiar with, but the most popular ones were Panda and &quot;The Three-Body Problem.&quot; People often take photos with the &quot;Three-body&quot; stone pillars outside the venue. One of them is engraved with the warning issued by the Three-body monitor about the risk of the destruction of human civilization, &quot;Don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer, don&#39;t answer!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/bn2zGldvjY1sCwDdmlRMKEovx91lUiUKWM1vhFOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In November 2014, Liu Cixin and Liu Yukun (middle left) were in the same frame at the 5th Chinese Science Fiction Nebula Award Ceremony held in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Yibo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Chengdu, Ethan, a software engineer from New York, USA, was about to finish reading &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; The first one, for which he temporarily put aside a collection of short African science fiction novels he was reading. At nearly 40 years old, the only Chinese science fiction work he had read before was &quot;The Story of Your Life&quot; by Ted Chiang (the original work of the movie &quot;Arrival&quot;). This time, the Chengdu Organizing Committee provided benefits such as travel assistants, transportation, Hugo Awards, and opening ceremony viewing quotas for science fiction fans who came from 3,000 kilometers away. However, Ethan believes that many European and American science fiction fans have given up on attending the conference remotely. Obviously, &quot;there are language barriers, there are few direct flights, air tickets are expensive, and you need to transfer in other countries.&quot; He said that science fiction fans in Europe and the United States are mainly middle-aged and elderly, and traveling for more than ten hours will be very hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, the 79th World Science Fiction Convention was held in Washington, USA. The Ethan family witnessed the success of Chengdu Science Fiction. This process was full of twists and turns. “At that time, there were many discussions about whether the conference should be held in China, such as whether it could comply with conference traditions, voting formats, cultural differences, etc. Of course, the current political situation is also very complicated,” he said. In the travel warning to China issued by the U.S. State Department at the end of June 2023, mainland China was listed as a &quot;third-level&quot; travel destination, calling on U.S. citizens to &quot;reconsider whether to go.&quot; After hesitating for a month or two, Ethan finally decided to come to mainland China to take a look. When he said this, we were sitting around a table eating butter hotpot. Several other sci-fi fans attending the meeting were from Russia, Canada and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2880&quot; height= &quot;1958&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/jEkakaNGNzaoKw0NJjQQ9UMV6ivOVdf7ZMZ7Kao0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257751&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 26, 1999, Liu Cixin attended the &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; PEN Conference in Chengdu. At this time, he was participating in a PEN discussion with his new work &quot;The Wandering Earth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The organizing committee has previously announced a set of data as of August 31: In addition to members of the World Science Fiction Association who enjoy offline participation rights, non-Chinese participants who purchased offline participation packages There were 51 people, accounting for 1% of the total number of people who purchased offline package tickets. There were 3,908 Chinese citizens who purchased offline package tickets, most of whom were attending the conference for the first time - including Xiami. Xiami, who is in his early 30s, is a physics teacher at a university in Xiamen, Fujian. In 2003, Xiami, who was in the second grade of junior high school, read novels by Wang Jinkang, Liu Cixin and others in a borrowed magazine &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;, and &quot;officially entered the pit of science fiction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, let Xiami prepare What makes him feel disappointed is that although the venue is large, the area and number of science fiction fan exhibition areas are far less than he expected. Afterwards, Xiami was very sorry to hear that Ethan brought the board game with him but could not find a suitable venue or playmate. After college, he mainly devoted his energy to theoretical research. &quot;This conference is like going back to the pit to take a look.&quot; There is a long &quot;tail&quot; on Xiami&#39;s participation card - if you participate in the booth activities, you will have the opportunity to obtain a booth. Homemade creative ribbons, this is a traditional peripheral for science fiction conventions. During the second half of the conference, Xiami turned to the salon of new generation writers. His notebook was filled with notes about the creation of science fiction novels, and his suitcase also contained more than a dozen novels by new generation writers. He is ready to restart the dream he had in high school - to write science fiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with the rapid changes in reality, can science fiction still provide people with enough strangeness and surprise, and can science fiction creation keep up with the magic of reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;624&quot; height= &quot;558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/sd1AP8gnUYwcVFgmbA2gVB8c6qU0QtiFMtE3tCkL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Hague, Netherlands, August 1990, Yang Xiao (second from left) with famous American science fiction writer Harry Harrison (first from left) and British science fiction master Brian Aldis The couple attended the WFS annual meeting together. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now, reality and science fiction do have a competitive relationship.&quot; Science fiction writer Han Song said. Sometimes he serves as a judge for science fiction awards and finds that some science fiction works are not as surprising and strange as reality. &quot;Reality is more like an alien world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 58-year-old Han Song is the leader of the external editorial department of Xinhua News Agency , is also a science fiction writer. Before arriving at the venue, he had already published a rather optimistic report on Xinhua News Agency, &quot;Embracing Science Fiction, Creating Tomorrow.&quot; For more than thirty years, he spent the day writing, editing and distributing news reports for the world at the Xinhua News Agency building on Xuanwumen West Street in Beijing. He got up at three or four in the morning to write science fiction before going to work. In 2018, he finished writing the science fiction novel &quot;Hospital&quot; trilogy. A few years later, when the COVID-19 pandemic hit the world, many people turned to his novels to contrast the visions of reality. Han Song continued to compile and publish reports on the COVID-19 epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1939, the first World Science Fiction Convention was held in New York, USA, reflecting that in the 20th century when the theory of relativity and quantum mechanics appeared, the evolution of human civilization entered a new stage, &quot;another turning point has been reached.&quot; Han Song He said, &quot;Quantum mechanics and the theory of relativity have appeared in the past 100 years. All the material foundations we have today are laid by these two theories. In these 100 years, humans have created weapons that can destroy themselves and other life on the earth. This is 500 years of human evolution.&quot; A phenomenon that has never happened in ten thousand years. Now we have nuclear weapons, artificial intelligence, nanotechnology, and life technology.&quot; One of the meanings of the existence of science fiction is to face these problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many salons at this science fiction conference talked about artificial intelligence, controllable nuclear fusion, quantum computing and communications. More than 80 years after the birth of nuclear weapons, some countries have used controllable nuclear fusion technology to solve the earth&#39;s energy problems. During the conference, science fiction writers were invited to the Southwest Institute of Physics of the CNNC Nuclear Industry to visit the nuclear fusion device known as the &quot;artificial sun&quot; - China Gyre 3, a new generation of artificial sun - which was selected for the &quot;Annual Science Fiction Plan&quot;. 74-year-old science fiction writer Wang Jinkang stood in front of the &quot;artificial sun&quot; and observed. As a senior engineer specializing in internal combustion engines, he once used nuclear energy to build a new path from the earth to outer space in science fiction novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Song, who also came to visit, immediately conducted an interview and wrote a report &quot;Science Fiction Writer Approaches &quot;Artificial Sun&quot;&quot;. The two-story ring-shaped device is covered with colorful pipelines and surrounded by instruments and computers. The nuclear fusion device looks like a giant monster. Most of the scientists explaining it on site are women. Han Song immediately thought of &quot;Frankenstein&quot; written by the British writer Mary Shelley in 1818, which was the first modern science fiction novel in human history. &quot;Science fiction was created by women.&quot; He was also thinking about his own science fiction. If controllable nuclear fusion solves the energy crisis of the entire earth, and if everyone on the earth has equal access to so much energy, will families and marriages disappear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Han Song’s view, science fiction is a species literature. &quot;Sometimes literature is the spiritual history of a nation, but science fiction is literature that describes the human species as an object.&quot; He feels that this is the meaning of every science fiction conference, &quot;So you will always be curious and want to know the same things as us What do these people think when faced with the same technology and the same proposition?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8ENsufAnh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sST6wtu8xTS4xm5jtKpTe6CO7qz7SZH8EN sufAnh .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 18, 2023, at the theme exhibition of the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, Audiences are choosing sci-fi IP peripheral products &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Science Fiction Literature of the World&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1990, In order to save money, Ms. Yang Xiao took an 8-day and 8-night train across Eurasia to attend the annual meeting of the International Science Fiction Association (WSF) in The Hague, Netherlands. She was accompanied by the then Director of the Press and Publication Division of the Sichuan Provincial Foreign Affairs Office. Zaiwang, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; art editor Xiang Jichun. They dragged a large box of the achievements of Sichuan science fiction literature and gifts with panda elements, and once again fought for the right to host the 1991 WSF Annual Conference in Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May of the previous year, as the editor-in-chief of &quot;Science and Literature&quot;, Yang Xiao went to the WSF Annual Conference held in San Marino alone. Twenty or thirty people sat in a small conference room to discuss the most popular science fiction topics in the world. &quot;We are talking about atmospheric pollution, human beings&#39; position in space, low-temperature life support, flying into space...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chinese science fiction is taking off, and Chinese teenagers like science fiction very much.&quot; She said at the meeting Said repeatedly. Her English was not very good. During the defense, she held two small volumes of &quot;A Concise Chinese-English Dictionary&quot; and &quot;A Concise English-Chinese Dictionary&quot; and wrote down the translations from English to Chinese and then from Chinese to English. However, she finally won the 1991 award for Chengdu. The right to host the WSF annual meeting. Others present said she &quot;With a little English and lots of determination to do a lot of things (with a little English and lots of determination to do a lot of things)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this decision was later overturned, and the host country for the 1991 meeting would be re-voted at the 1990 WSF Annual Meeting. This time, Yang Xiao and his team were well prepared, answered various questions and doubts, and showed off the achievements of Chinese science fiction and the cute appearance of pandas. At the end of the discussion at the meeting, Brian Aldiss, the leader of the British New Wave Science Fiction Movement and one of the founders of WSF, stood up. His words always meant what he said, and he, who was always gentle, said seriously and solemnly: &quot;Political disputes are just temporary. Yes, the dialogue and understanding between East and West are long-term, and the friendship between people is eternal. We should not follow political trends.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, Aldis and Chinese science fiction writers Zheng Wenguang has correspondence. Zheng Wenguang was born in 1929 and was a researcher at the Beijing Observatory of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. In 1957, Zheng Wenguang&#39;s novel &quot;The Builders of Mars&quot; won the award at the World Youth Festival in Moscow. This was the first Chinese science fiction work to win an award abroad. Once, after receiving a letter from Zheng Wenguang and his new book &quot;Selected Works of Zheng Wenguang&quot;, Aldis expressed surprise at the title of the book in his reply. Is it really called that? This kind of name won&#39;t sell to us. For this collection, we have to pick the most interesting novel in it as the title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 1991, in Chengdu, China, at the annual meeting of the International Science Fiction Professional Association, 66-year-old Aldis and 62-year-old Zheng Wenguang reunited. At that time, Zheng Wenguang was already in a wheelchair, and Ordis Dees helped push his wheelchair on every occasion. Also present that year were American science fiction writer Frederic Bohr and others. This annual meeting also invited Wu Yan, a scholar who teaches science fiction creation courses in colleges and universities, and others, and was full of encouragement for young creators. In order to invite Han Song, a student of Wuhan University, to join, Tan Kai, the editor-in-chief of &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; wrote a letter To the stranger Qi Minyou, the president of Wuhan University and mathematician, Qi quickly approved and funded 400 yuan for room and board expenses. At the meeting, Han Song showed the &quot;Cosmic Tombstone&quot; that had been rejected earlier to the Taiwanese scholar Lu Yingzhong who was present. Lu Yingzhong took it to Taiwan and gave it to the writers Zhang Xiguo and Zhang Dachun. In the end, this novel won the World Chinese Science Fiction and Literature Award in 1991. prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/hmnGcAFANFyUPNgruABWm91w6vPdBiLhUwF4ADWP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 18, 2023, at the theme exhibition of the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, visitors watched the robot &quot;Silence&quot; playing drums&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this annual science fiction conference that connected many people, Chinese science fiction is back on track. &quot;Science and Literature&quot;, founded in 1979, was renamed &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; in the same year, and later successively published science fiction novels by new authors Wang Jinkang, Han Song, He Xi, and Liu Cixin - now they have become the &quot;Four Kings&quot; of Chinese science fiction. . During a collective visit to Dujiangyan at the annual meeting, 23-year-old Han Song asked an old foreigner how to write about political themes in world science fiction? He later learned that this man was Aldis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He has been here twice and always talks very enthusiastically about the people he knows and what is happening in the science fiction world. He also very much hopes that Chinese science fiction works can get more recognition, which is also the case for him. The reason why he is keen to hold that science fiction annual conference. There is always a photo of him and Yang Xiao in his study, which is very important to him.&quot; At the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, Aldis&#39;s daughter Wen Di Aldis told me that this afternoon she completed two salon conversations with Yang Xiao. Mr. Aldis has been dead for six years now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he arrived in Chengdu in 1991, Aldis was upset that a piece of luggage was lost when he transferred before arriving in Chengdu. It was a small box of science fiction books given to the editorial department of &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;. Wendy brought a large pile of her father&#39;s books with her this time and placed them on the salon table during the event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the things in Aldis&#39;s book have become reality. Aldis&#39;s most famous work is &quot;Jungle Greenhouse&quot;, which has been serialized in the British &quot;Fantasy and Science Fiction&quot; since 1961. He constructed a &quot;post-Earth era&quot; in which intelligent plants dominate the earth. At that time, the earth was already a The huge greenhouse that stopped rotating formed a stable system with the moon. The plants reaching the sky extended their branches and leaves to the moon where flying people lived. The movie &quot;Artificial Intelligence&quot; directed by Steven Spielberg is adapted from Aldous&#39;s &quot;Super Toys That Lasted All Summer.&quot; The novel is poetic and melancholy, about a robot with human emotions who doesn&#39;t want the humans who raised him to discover that he already knows he is a robot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aldis’s works are full of reflections on modern civilization. In fact, British science fiction literature, which was born in 1818, is a product of the technological revolution and the industrial revolution. This literary genre, which appeared very late compared to other literary genres, originally had two visions for creating modern society: one is Utopia, a true and false travelogue that originated in the Age of Discovery; the other is the idea that human beings will continue to progress. , a narrative that gradually took shape with the Enlightenment and the French Revolution, and has had a profound impact on human thought around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese science fiction literature was born along with enlightenment modernity. At the beginning of the 20th century, Lu Xun translated science fiction novels (called &quot;science novels&quot; at the time) such as &quot;Travel to the Moon&quot;, &quot;Travel to the Underground&quot; and &quot;The Art of Creation&quot;. At the same time, more and more famous writers have joined in the translation or creation of science fiction literature. At that time, most participants in science fiction literature longed for the changes in the times brought about by technological progress, and explored various possibilities for the future of mankind and the world. After the founding of New China, the first batch of science fiction writers in New China such as Zheng Wenguang appeared. Their science fiction novels assumed part of the responsibility of popularizing science. The positive attitude towards modernity in Chinese science fiction at the beginning of the last century was continued to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2qy1dSFciYTRFgg47ZjOeSRntGsa4z5AfmsRDNBb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 17, 2023, a drone performance next to the main venue of the Chengdu Science Fiction Conference&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the West, where the modernization process was earlier, there has always been no shortage of science fiction works that are wary of modern civilization. Even in the first modern science fiction novel &quot;Frankenstein&quot;, there is already a Scientific doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When humans can develop weapons to destroy the earth and launch wars to exterminate species, mature works that reflect on modernity also appear outside Western countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, the year Japan hosted the Olympic Games, Japanese science fiction writer Sakyo Komatsu began writing &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. This novel, which took nine years to be written, caused a sensation in Japanese society after it was published. The novel describes the Japanese archipelago being destroyed by the earth&#39;s crust. Big changes and sinking to the bottom of the sea. Japan&#39;s postwar economic miracle made Komatsu Sakyo deeply worried. He was worried about people&#39;s consumption of large amounts of resources and energy, and their tense and conflicting relationship with nature and society. He also showed great compassion and sympathy for the fate of mankind. &quot;Japanese science fiction has a great influence on me. As for &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; specifically, it was actually greatly influenced by &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. I was shocked after watching &quot;The Sinking of Japan&quot;. A science fiction work can actually reveal the deepest depths of a nation. The sensitive and fragile fear of the future is reflected.&quot; Liu Cixin once said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hoshi Shinichi, a Japanese science fiction writer who was active in the second half of the 20th century like Sakyo Komatsu, wrote his short story &quot;Hey! &quot;Come Out&quot; was included in Chinese language textbooks in the early 21st century. Many domestic middle school students read this type of story in their textbooks for the first time. In the novel, a bottomless pit suddenly appeared on the earth. Human beings discovered that the hole was endless, so they dumped all the garbage and pollutants they produced into it without any scruples. Later, when all the endless destruction and desires of mankind were sprayed back to the ground and returned to mankind, what served as a harbinger was the innocent and ignorant cry of mankind when they discovered this hole, &quot;Hey - come out!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In 2007, the World Science Fiction Convention came to Asia for the first time. In Yokohama, Japan, at the opening ceremony of the 65th World Science Fiction Conference, 76-year-old Sakyo Komatsu appeared in a wheelchair. He was the first person to introduce Japanese and even Asian science fiction to the world. &quot;More than half a century ago, he was like a prophet, predicting that scientific progress does not necessarily make people happy. He expressed human pain, revealed the barbarism of human nature, and at the same time placed hope and light.&quot; Han Song likes Sakyo Komatsu very much, That year, he went to Yokohama to attend a science fiction conference with writer and scholar Wu Yan, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; president Qin Li, and editor-in-chief Yao Haijun. Komatsu Sakyo was very happy to see them. He held Han Song&#39;s hand and said repeatedly in Chinese, &quot;Thank you, thank you so much.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The times have caught up”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the World Science Fiction Convention will come to Asia for the second time. At the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention, whenever Liu Cixin is present, he always attracts the cheers and attention of the audience like a magnet. Even if he is not a guest on the spot, his name and &quot;Three-Body Problem&quot; are unavoidable topics in the salon for guests from all over the world. As China&#39;s most famous science fiction writer, Liu Cixin&#39;s autograph session was specially arranged by the organizing committee for three hours, starting at 2:30 p.m. However, just after 11 a.m. that day, there was already a long queue in the autograph hall. In the past, Liu Cixin insisted on signing the last reader in line every time he signed. This time he signed for three hours. His hands were shaking when he signed, and he wanted to persist, but was stopped by the organizer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nabBdy5qmcBucAUx3G7IUI6wHYmPB9UT7Ll5xaKO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 21, 2023, in Chengdu, Sichuan, &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot; created by Chinese writer Hai Ming (middle) won the Hugo Award for Best Short Novella&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; won the 73rd Hugo Award for Best Novel, and Liu Cixin became the first Asian writers who have won this award. Today, 60-year-old Liu Cixin has become one of China&#39;s most famous writers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this science fiction conference venue, there is a white sculpture about 9 meters high in the most conspicuous position in the atrium. The prototype is the lunar robot mechanical dog &quot;Benben&quot; in &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;. There are many people taking pictures around Benben. It is the most representative product image in the &quot;Wandering Earth&quot; IP licensing business. &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, adapted from Liu Cixin&#39;s novel of the same name, has a cumulative box office of 4.029 billion yuan in mainland China and a global box office of US$598 million. It will also represent mainland China in the competition for Best International Film at the 96th Academy Awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before becoming a famous writer, Liu Cixin worked as an engineer at a power plant in a small town called &quot;Niangziguan&quot; in Yangquan City, Shanxi Province. After he became famous, the town was visited by many news reporters. In a series of activities at this science fiction conference, Liu Cixin showed rare relaxation and enjoyment in a salon with the theme of &quot;Engineer Science Fiction&quot;. &quot;No matter how difficult things are in reality, they can be solved in novels without any effort.&quot; The difficulty lies in the tortuous technical construction, how to write the craziest imagination and the most ethereal super technology in the most realistic details, so that readers can feel as real as reading news reports and historical records.&quot; He loves engineer science fiction. I long to be able to do it myself, and also long to read it in other people’s works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;With the depletion of resources on each continent and the deterioration of the environment, the world has turned its attention to Antarctica... But human reason has won on the other hand, and the final process of the complete elimination of nuclear weapons around the world has begun. With the realization of global denuclearization, mankind&#39;s fight for the Antarctic continent has become safer.&quot; Liu Cixin&#39;s short story &quot;Earth Cannon&quot; published in &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; in 2003 is Xiami&#39;s entry into the trap. There is a sense of calmness and perseverance throughout the novel: the government built a tunnel from Mohe through the center of the earth to the Antarctic. The mega-project was closed due to a catastrophic accident. Since then, the global environment has further deteriorated. In order to find a way out, mankind has decided to transfer the industries on the earth to space. The tunnel was reactivated, and humans added magnet coils to it, using gravity and Ampere force to turn the earth into an &quot;earth cannon&quot;, which allowed them to launch surface objects into low-Earth orbit at low cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I read this ambitious story for the first time, Xiami, who was still in the second grade of junior high school, felt the excitement and surprise that was very different from other literary works. &quot;I was immediately attracted by the novel setting and... The grand epic hit me.&quot; Since then, &quot;Science Fiction World&quot; has become Xiami&#39;s monthly must-read publication. In 2006, Xiami read the newly serialized &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; in &quot;Science Fiction World&quot;. When science fiction fans were eager to analyze the physical settings in &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, no one could foresee that this novel would What kind of future will Chinese science fiction lead to? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/8LvrxC3JN96XASg4oy696aVY9Mjn9dJeNjAcQzbQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the break of a salon at the Chengdu World Science Fiction Convention, Mr. Bryant showed our reporter his self-made laminated card, which contained his certificates from the past 14 World Science Fiction Conventions he had participated in. Highlights. The 80-year-old said that after he returns home, he will share his thoughts and suggestions from the conference with the organizer via email. &quot;If China holds the World Science Fiction Convention again in ten years, I hope I can still attend&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Chen Yang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Liu Cixin was writing the third part of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, he participated in a pen meeting for science fiction writers in Hangzhou. Everyone was talking about &quot;What method should be used if Hangzhou is to be completely destroyed?&quot; He got excited and said that he could first make the city two-dimensional, into an ink landscape, and then one-dimensionally into a thin thread. Everyone was very excited after hearing this. After sobering up, Liu Cixin was very nervous. Fortunately, no one appropriated this science fiction idea. The two-way foil is one of the most amazing cosmic law weapons in &quot;Three-Body III: Death Eternal Life&quot; published in 2010. Its ability is a dimensionality reduction attack, which collapses three dimensions into two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, when &quot;Three Body III&quot; was published, with the popularization of smartphones and 4G networks, China entered the mobile Internet era from the PC Internet era. Xiaomi and Meituan were established that year, and WeChat was launched the following year. Xiaomi founder Lei Jun recommended it to other entrepreneurs after watching &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; in 2010, and has publicly talked about the &quot;dimensionality reduction attack&quot; and &quot;dark forest&quot; of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; on many occasions as an inspiration for Internet strategy. The &quot;Three-Body&quot; series has been highly praised by the science fiction circle, and the discussions among these Internet upstarts have allowed this work to break through the circle and truly enter the public eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of science fiction in a region requires realistic soil, which has long been verified in other countries. In the 19th century, British and French science fiction literature benefited from the industrial revolution and developed, represented by Verne and Wells. After World War II, Western science fiction literature represented by the United States entered its heyday. The period of rapid development of Japanese science fiction was from the 1970s to the 1980s. In the 1970s, Japan created the &quot;Japanese Miracle&quot; with rapid economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being translated by Chinese-American writer Liu Yukun, the English version of &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; began to spread in 2014. Facebook founder Zuckerberg said that &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; &quot;liberated me from the economic, social, and scientific books I have read recently, and made me feel relaxed and happy.&quot; After watching &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;, then-U.S. President Obama &quot;felt that being a U.S. president was too small compared to the vast universe. After all, all he dealt with every day were trivial matters arguing with Congress, and there was no need to worry about alien invasion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the English copyright renewal fee for &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; reached as high as US$1.25 million, setting a record for the overseas copyright export of Chinese literary works. The &quot;Three-Body&quot; series produced by American streaming subscription platform Netflix will hit the screen in 2024. &quot;Chinese science fiction is a very successful example of international communication. It does not matter how much money is spent, nor does it have to be promoted to the world. I think Chinese science fiction learns from the world and combines the good things of world science fiction with China&#39;s traditional culture and modern culture. Integration, with a strong Chinese imprint, allows the world to experience Chinese science fiction. Chinese science fiction faces universal problems in the world, such as the environment, space, war, etc., and puts forward Chinese-style answers, allowing the world to experience This solution is valuable and unique, and can bring unexpected gains and surprises to the world,&quot; Han Song said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kttYdh7TW0YaLkcyp1U8UappuIV3d4czYpezAiXW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Song in the office&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various things Chance and necessity make the &quot;Three-Body&quot; series a miracle that is difficult to recreate. At every public event, people ask Liu Cixin when he will release a new work that will surpass &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This science fiction writer is racing against technology. Liu Cixin has always maintained the habit of reading cutting-edge scientific and technological articles. He is accustomed to &quot;writing it out in one go&quot; after accurately modeling it in his brain. In 2015, in an interview with Sanlian Life Weekly, he mentioned a &quot;good idea&quot; that he had conceived for two years. This subject had high hopes for him. Not only did the setting leave a lot of room for development, but he also His experience working in power systems can also help him portray full-bodied characters. Until one day, he saw an article published by researchers at Waseda University in Japan. The other party not only proposed the same idea, but also &quot;calculated the total power generation&quot; and proposed &quot;building a relay station at the Lagrange point to send the microwave back&quot; and so on. After reading this article, Liu Cixin completely gave up the idea, and the 300,000-word manuscript was shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Cixin set the threshold for releasing new works as &quot;something that can excite myself&quot; and emphasized that she &quot;has been working hard&quot;, but the resistance has also been unprecedented. &quot;I often feel shocked when I first start writing, but halfway through writing I find that the times have caught up and I feel bored, so I start writing again, and time is wasted.&quot; Liu Cixin told me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The rapid development of science and technology has weakened the sense of magic of science and people&#39;s expectations for the future that science can create. This has a great impact on the traditional type of science fiction.&quot; He believes that this is like him A common problem for hard science fiction writers who &quot;rely on creativity and world construction&quot; is that &quot;colleagues in the East and the West are working hard, hoping to use more expression techniques to restore the vitality of science fiction creation. But frankly speaking, the current effect is not good.&quot; He even regretted it, feeling that the more than 30 short stories and short stories he published in his early years were an excessive waste of subject matter and exhausted his passion. In the future, as the expression vehicle of science fiction stories shifts from novels to the screen, he is also worried about whether he can adapt to the changes in roles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The time I can write is about 10 years at most.” Liu Cixin feels that artificial intelligence is accelerating this countdown. “The science fiction novels written by ChatGPT are getting better and better. I don’t think so. Knowing that artificial intelligence will leave us at least as much time as possible.&quot; He believes that this is a natural law and cannot be considered pessimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Wrcopdeg1Rje5L3q25kA1Nx59Wac2G1ngtXZXmAt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Guo Fan on the set of &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New crisis and science fiction The vitality of , a fleeting excitement arose in the dying heart.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Song read in a low voice &quot;Cold War and the Courier&quot; he wrote 30 years ago, which is the only one at this science fiction conference reading activities. He thinks this is a love story, &quot;two generations, politics, war, men&#39;s rights, women&#39;s rights. The humbleness of people in time and space.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This novel was insistently chosen by the science fiction writer Sugar Bandit. She I think it is very suitable for the current situation where local conflicts occur in many places. An American science fiction fan who came to China to attend a conference was banned from bringing a computer by his company before departure. Uri Aviv, the founder of the Tel Aviv International Science Fiction Film Festival, comes from the war-torn areas of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.等大会结束，他又要回到屡遭空袭的以色列特拉维夫。特拉维夫国际科幻电影节将于12月开幕。一些工作人员被征召入伍，许多工作面临调整。 “我们肩头的责任比以往任何时候都更重，科幻作品能为人们提供平静和治愈的力量，帮助他们在对当下和时代的忧虑重压下喘一口气，得以思考、构想和期待更美好的未来。”一个小时的读书中，活动现场挤满了人，竟有人听得落下泪来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类不得不直面这充满不确定的现实。韩松原本想在读书会上展开读糖匪的新书《后来的人类》，甚至准备了三段内容，分别对应着设定架构、机器、关系。小说构建了一种未来的新型公寓，人工智能“家庭主脑”控制着公寓的一切，以无所不用其极的方式来照顾人类，实际却是一个监视者，甚至成了统治者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管新生代的科幻作家对外部世界的描写更加多元和令人兴奋，也更广阔，但韩松觉得科幻文学目前还需要更大的想象力。此外，他觉得女性作家写得更细致，有时候写得更深刻，“不仅体现在对情感的了解，还有对历史和社会的认知。”他觉得反映社会问题最好的作品之一就是郝景芳的《北京折叠》（获雨果奖），慕明和双翅目的作品也有很强的社会风格，技术后面有很强的历史和社会认知。 “但有些男作家写现实就显得有点着急，我觉得比较粗线条。不一定写到这样的主题，就算写到了，小说到他技术惊奇的画面那里就截止了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场科幻大会的几天之前，韩松赶去浙江绍兴参加了一场中日作家的交流会，与会者有多位芥川奖得主和鲁迅文学奖得主。会议特意选在了鲁迅的出生地举办，鲁迅是最早把科幻小说译介到中国的人之一。这一场交流会谈论的问题，成为世界科幻大会探讨的许多内容的预演。这些东亚作家首次一起深入讨论人工智能时代的文学到底是什么、人类在新技术条件下生活的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一场科技革命都会引起欢呼和惊恐，人工智能的发展也不例外。但全球对人工智能产生全面的紧张感是从2022年底ChatGPT的发布开始的。有观点认为，随着以AI为代表的智能化生产方式的出现和普及，第五次工业革命正在发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NU9S1x16GXPBcpUGJvCJ4bSdryw9zxnrhlcEFa70.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《三体》剧照(2023) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人类以前只是感觉到危机。更早以前大机器出现，感觉到要失业，然后核武器出现，感觉到人类会被灭绝。但是这次不一样。前面几次工业革命创造的都是物质，这次人工智能的科技革命，创造的是精神。”韩松说，“而且这个精神，看上去比人类思考得还要厉害，而且人类也不知道这个人工智能是怎么想的。”这是人类物种（被更替）的危机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“反倒是科幻小说，对未来人工智能做了方方面面的预测性描述。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年写人工智能和元宇宙的科幻小说变得非常多，而且将未来建模得相当详细。最近，韩松读到墨熊的新小说就是写后人类时代，全球人工智能挽救人类，让人类能在整个宇宙演化的灾难中继续生存，最后的办法是人与机器融合的怪物更替了人类这一物种。科幻作家江波近几年也写了很多人工智能。 “他还是很悲观地认为人和机器的战争是很难避免的。写共生的也有，人机耦合也写过，但我还是觉得不可预测。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;653&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/oXUEpR76zdXPv5JK7cG4TQDGMtRrrV4cc803y453.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松的“医院三部曲”在2018年全部出版，这个系列由《医院》《驱魔》《亡灵》组成，也想象了人工智能：“药时代”里，医药成了新的神；“药战争”接替了全球“核战争”；在医药战争中，整个宇宙也像病人一样走向死亡，而不得已遭遇所有故事的，不过是一个因为喝了坏水而被送进医院的可怜上班族。书中的忧思最初只在学界传播，哈佛大学教授王德威在参加北京大学纪念“五四”运动百年活动演讲时，指出韩松的“医院三部曲”重启了早期鲁迅对科学与文学的批判性思考。到2020年全球暴发新冠疫情时，一些人找到韩松的这套《医院》，来对照眼前惊人的生活。 “在社会发展、生活逐渐繁荣的同时，每个人内心深处都有一层伤口。生活凭靠运气，下一步怎么活下去没有把握。许多担忧与无力交织在人心里，内化成心底的巨大惧怕。”2017年，刚写完《驱魔》的韩松对我说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;662&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/F5d7uwczBmSNRHXvTyULxyhKotFuebTa4AREg0GY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;694&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KNBH3M7JfSPvvdWlzMvAPlD1IE5UY1q7oBXyZllx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Qjntpd16GuHr0hW1p6gSIJNkGYRN2o2DGxCF1GBe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;677&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/eGYUAOlqOIcyWFkhoIErtkByObjZ0Tluc28DOE36.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文学发展到现在，韩松认为其处理的核心问题没有根本性的变化，科幻对现代性的继承、发展和反思与主流文学是一致的，“最早的&#39;鲁郭茅巴老曹&#39;本质上就是在写现代性的问题。 ”在他的观察里，这些年主流文学在应对现代性方面有些弱化，“我不知道是什么原因，它跟现实好像有点脱节。有些纯文学好像要把现实描写得很精确，也在写现实，但好像不是我们真正的现实。但是科幻某种程度上弥补了这种现代性，尤其是揭示了科技和经济又一次巨大变革后，民族也好、人类也好，危机的存在。虽然不能完全做比较，但我觉得科幻文学像鲁迅《呐喊》一样地喊大家。文学还是要直面现实问题，而不仅仅是语言的技巧。我觉得中国科幻崛起的一个根本原因，是它反映了现代性。 ”11月2日，韩松在电话里平静地说。他正在福建厦门的金鸡百花电影节担任创投大会“科幻片单元”的特邀嘉宾，在这通采访电话结束后便要去参加讨论会。科幻片单元入围作品《星际信使》就改编自他的《冷战与信使》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，我在新华社对外部实习时，想做一篇北京地铁的报道，我的实习老师建议我采访部门领导韩松，并读一读他的短篇小说《地铁惊变》。韩松每天上班来得很早，总是拍下1号线首班地铁中乘客的样子。我还记得自己在韩松楼下办公室读完《地铁惊变》后因惊栗而久久无法动弹的状态，那是我第一次看见熟悉的现实在科幻中的扭曲和变形。他又写了《高铁》《轨道》，和《地铁》组成“轨道三部曲”。他写那些在新闻中总以进步和繁荣之姿出现的技术，“新闻成为世界的镜子就很不容易了，讽刺小说是一面哈哈镜，科幻像个万花筒。 ”韩松拿这个万花筒看高铁，看科技、经济、政治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/tB0lwOu8v6XckTtxN2P0coIdYQ3oRWS93K3dlo5E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;20世纪80年代初，中国科幻期刊界最受欢迎的“四刊一报”：《科学文艺》《科幻海洋》《智慧树》《科幻世界》（科学普及出版社）和《科幻小说报》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩松编发过很多灾难报道。2008年汶川地震发生时，新华社第一个向世界报道了震级，“整个晚上，我们特别难过的，是不断地编发了一所一所学校倒塌的新闻，大批的学生被埋在下面。学校，还是学校……”在那个书山一样的办公室，韩松依然写新闻或科幻，又过了两年，他交了科幻小说《再生砖》：大地震后，建筑师用废墟瓦砾、麦秸和死尸制造了新型建筑材料。在艺术展斩获国际大奖后，再生砖被大规模生产并在灾区和全国推广，再生砖风靡世界，带动灾区振兴，人类聆听和赞美砖头里亡灵的哭声。人类如此迷恋再生砖，以致记不住任何教训，甚至去外星球播撒人造微生物来制造新灾难，最后发现，宇宙本身就是一块由废墟和生命建成的再生砖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对韩松来说，是科幻作家叶永烈带来了科幻的火种。叶永烈的《小灵通漫游未来》在1978年出版后很轰动，“中国人之前沉浸在人与人的斗争中，很久没有想象未来时空了。 ”他觉得叶永烈最了不起的科幻小说，自己至今也无法超越的，还是那篇《巴金的梦》，发表在1980年代的《科幻世界》。“他写中国未来一定会建这么一个牢记历史的博物馆，而且是与国际合建，他详细描写了这个馆怎么建，有什么馆藏。这个小说光是能发表就很了不起了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，叶永烈对未来是乐观的。他是《十万个为什么》的主要作者，又写了《小灵通漫游未来》。他在20世纪60年代写了21世纪的中国，有生产粮食的工厂，有给学生上课的机器人，有电脑的普及，有人造肉、人工控制天气，还有会飞行的汽车等等，向那个年代的小读者描绘出一个充满希望与光明的未来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/f2PQXd1rD7H5R46OwmYvzhxi19L7hOPSZmUtXG9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014年11月，刘慈欣（中右）与刘宇昆（中左）在北京举办的第5届华语科幻星云奖颁奖礼上&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（李一博提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GAZ7WDq48np5ky6gkEMPY0HeR34LZA5HYP9omoUx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年世界科幻协会年会在成都举办期间，主办方组织作家采风，韩松（左）与科幻作家张劲松（中）、舒明武在四川彭州银厂沟合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;金字塔的地基&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月21日，1990年出生的作家海漄凭借《时空画师》获得雨果奖“最佳短中篇小说”奖，成为继刘慈欣、郝景芳后第三位获雨果奖作品奖的中国科幻作家。雨果奖评选委员会负责人戴夫·麦卡蒂在颁奖晚会后对《南方周末》说，《时空画师》“创造了一个无英文译本、完全由中文作品获奖的历史”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这届世界科幻大会上，多项科幻产业发展相关的计划公布，甚至有科幻产业项目的集中签约仪式。与科幻素有渊源的成都提出“科幻全产业链生态圈”“IP打造”“强化科幻之都形象”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;熙熙攘攘的会场、沙龙和展厅，都在彰显科幻的“热”。但作为文化产业的一部分，国内科幻产业的发展仍在起步期。据“IT桔子”的数据，2022年国内文娱行业有投融资事件88起，涉及投资金额46.36亿元，数量和金额创近5年新低。据《证券日报》不完全统计，截至2023年9月14日，该年国内文娱行业（含传媒、游戏、元宇宙、社交、体育）共发生13起投融资事件。而2022年国内文娱领域投融资事件为96起，2019年该数据为2158起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻文化品牌“未来事务管理局”（以下简称“未来局”）创始人姬少亭是第三次参与世界科幻大会，此前两次分别在英国伦敦和芬兰赫尔辛基。许多西方参会者向她提起他们的惊讶发现——中国科幻迷群体的年轻化和较高的女性占比。海外科幻的发展历程较长，科幻迷大多是中老年。收获同行惊羡的同时，姬少亭心里思考的却是另一个问题，从青年到白头，这些西方读者为何能数十年保持对科幻的热爱？答案很明确。 “他们一定是被持续投喂了大量优秀的作品，这意味着有创作热情的人才在源源不断地涌入科幻行业。归根结底是因为这个行业体量足够大，足够提供就业和发展的强大支撑。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0toZNT9B4RYcpAlIAu2uL1KP2uc7F1Yh47U1D0PI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2015年8月23日，美国宇航员凯尔．林格伦在地球之外350 公里的国空间站通过视频连线向全球宣布:中国作家刘慈欣凭借科幻小说《三体》（第一部）获得第73 届雨果奖最佳长篇故事奖，从而成为该奖自1953 年创立以来首位获此殊荣的亚洲人&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/y844VALuAbRhTMF8YG9grwuzcp7rKSgVXASoXyFg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，成都世界科幻大会会场的巨型雕塑，原型是《流浪地球2》中的月面机器人机械狗“笨笨” &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，姬少亭离开工作10年的新华社，创立未来局，开始深度参与到科幻产业发展。七年来，未来局已成为国内主要的科幻IP开发方之一，参与了众多图书、影视、游戏、玩具等行业科幻IP项目的开发和策划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年1月，未来局举办了《流浪地球》的第一个观影会，导演郭帆和刘慈欣第一次在电影院完整地看成片。映后，姬少亭十分坚定地对我说，这部电影肯定会火的。这部电影被认为“开启了中国科幻电影元年”，票房和效应超出预期，并给电影行业带来巨大的启示。 《流浪地球》在中国大陆票房累计达46.88亿元，全球票房7.39亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，影视行业对科幻题材的理解整体还处于初级阶段。同时，受累于羸弱的投资环境，科幻影视的市场化步履蹒跚。据阿里影业总裁李捷2023年4月在一场创投大会上介绍，阿里影业的科幻电影创投，10到15个项目中，进入成片阶段的只有1到2部。在同一场活动中，《流浪地球》《宇宙探索编辑部》的监制王红卫则勉励科幻创作者“咬住牙”，“我希望以后一年起码有一部高质量的科幻作品，能够再撑住我们这个类型。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《流浪地球》系列的成功反映出国内对优秀科幻作品需求惊人，需求和供给之间的巨大沟壑就是行业的机遇所在。对于具体的公司、事和人，机遇是肯定存在的，就看谁能把握住。好的作品是一切。”姬少亭说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年，由于发表渠道和推广资源收紧，姬少亭明显感觉推进一件事的阻力要比过去大得多。 “经济面临下行压力，各个环节都缺钱，变得保守，不愿试错，资金和资源会向顶级作者和作品集中。当然，这更有利于实现单点突破，弊端则在于新人出头和成长的机会在缩减。”未来局在成立那年就启动了科幻写作培训，致力于持续培养并帮助新兴科幻作者成长。姬少亭常被问道，什么时候才会出现下一个刘慈欣，“我真正希望看到的局面是大量中等以上作品的出现。如果我们连金字塔的地基都不扎实，没有足够庞大的基数，要如何期待下一个刘慈欣呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;淡蓝的小点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;吴文琛重返科幻的世界，是因为《流浪地球》。 2019年上映时，他和妻子、儿子一起去影院看了这部电影。现在，他11岁的儿子在写一个科幻小说。吴文琛小时候也看《科幻世界》，写科幻小说的念头倒是从来没有过。当年《科幻世界》每页的最下边是读者栏目，刊登读者的一句话想象和地址，来稿的多是中学生。吴文琛在中学时也投过稿，还在《科幻世界》发表了一句对世界的好奇和想象，那像是人在少年时对宇宙的呐喊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次从成都市中心来郫都参加科幻大会，就是儿子拉他过来的。上高中后，他再也没读过科幻，后来工作、开公司，生活工作连轴转。看到台上坐着创办《科幻世界》的编辑们，他一下被刺激到，在互动环节举手，几乎不停歇地说了几分钟：“我从一个理想主义者变成了何夕老师口中的现实主义者，但我也没有办法……现在小孩的教育压力真的太大了，我非常忧愁这样的教育会影响孩子的想象力发挥，但我也不知道怎么办。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨潇有一个写着很多中外科幻作家名字的本子，上面有郑文光，有奥尔迪斯，像一本中外科幻交流的合集。这次大会结束后，杨潇的本子上又多了一个名字，是吴文琛的儿子吴嘉麒。杨潇和谭楷把这个11岁的孩子请到台上，鼓励他的写作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年代，《中国少年报》编辑找到郑文光，请他为孩子们写一篇科幻小说。这是天文学家郑文光成为新中国成立后第一位科幻作家的契机。他在故事里虚构了三个偷偷开走火箭船的小孩，他们一路飞到火星的上空，看见了这颗星球上的红色沙漠和蓝绿色植物，这么绕着火星转了一大圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/FUIkvdfftlBYE3rtenqs3PN2Qw91RazBpIOrbToo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1991年5月，出席成都世界科幻协会年会的日本作家柴野拓美在卧龙点燃了象征友谊的籍火，随后大家围着籍火跳起了锅庄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/UAAu4sYsxH6vqbJwOq8xPgsmBleVznUQ1l82754Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，在2023成都世界科幻大会主题展览上，一名小科幻迷在VR设备上观赏太空景象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个天真烂漫的故事发表在在1954年的《中国少年报》上，引发了意想不到的热烈反响，《从地球到火星》成为新中国第一篇有影响力的科幻小说：北京掀起了“火星热”，那时候，北京天文馆还没有成立。为了满足孩子们的好奇心，《中国少年报》编辑部在建国门上的古观象台架起一座天文望远镜。孩子们吃了晚饭，就到古观象台排队看火星，为此可以一直排到深夜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成都的这场大会同样热闹，有非常多的新闻报道，“但科幻还是一个小众的东西，甚至读它的人还没有读奇幻和魔幻的多。科幻不是一切，不要以为它代表一切、能拯救万物，好像科幻才能让科技发展，不是那么回事，我觉得就一个平常心来看待它。科幻大会是一个粉丝的文化，大家喜欢在一起。”韩松说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种平常心更接近韩松刚写科幻时的心境。在他的少年时代，1980年代，人们总想把什么送上太空去看一看。韩松的第一篇小说是中学时写的，他首先写陨石在地球砸了一个洞，人们往洞里看，什么也没有。老师说不行，他就写了一篇小说送一只熊猫上太空。 “没有写科幻的话，很可能我就是一个整天泡在酒局饭局里、吃完大家胡扯一通、然后打牌睡觉又开始第二天的人，一辈子就过去了，甚至更糟糕的是，加入到争名夺利的战争里去。”这么多年写科幻，与其说带来什么变化，不如说是不变，“科幻让一个人保持了少年时候那种好奇、纯粹、探究的心，甚至包括那时候那种莫名的惆怅、恐惧，那种本能的跟宇宙、自然的天然的联系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在科幻大会落幕的傍晚，成都科学馆像日落中停泊的一艘飞船。我和吴嘉麒在馆里聊他的小说。他之后要回家赶作业，有点担心接下来的功课过多，不知什么时候才能完成那写了一半的科幻小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也是一个有关太空漫游的故事。 11岁的作者在小说里，给两年前过世的曾祖母造了一座宇宙飞船，她离开了地球，在浩瀚广阔的星际，见到了那些人类无法想象的风景。故事里，她已经找到了一颗移居的星球。当她回头望地球，那颗所有人类出生和死亡的星球，那颗众多文明诞生又毁灭的星球，凝成了宇宙中一颗淡蓝色的小点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（感谢吴岩、杨枫、科幻光年、糖匪、西夏、刘悠翔、北落师门等对采访提供的帮助，感谢八光分文化提供历史图片支持。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被控受贿2.1亿，招商银行原党委书记、行长田惠宇案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月9日，湖南省常德市中级人民法院一审公开开庭审理了招商银行股份有限公司原党委书记、行长田惠宇受贿、国有公司人员滥用职权、利用未公开信息交易、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息一案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ec6edb4ca3972cfdfb565dcfa6fb74f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;常德市人民检察院起诉指控：1997年至2022年，田惠宇利用担任中国信达信托投资公司副总裁，上海银行股份有限公司党委委员、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司上海市分行党委副书记、副行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司深圳市分行党委书记、行长，中国建设银行股份有限公司北京市分行党委书记、行长，招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长等职务便利以及职权、地位形成的便利条件，为有关单位和个人在贷款审批、业务承揽、工作调动等事项上提供帮助，非法收受他人给予的财物，折合人民币共计2.1亿余元；田惠宇在担任招商银行股份有限公司党委书记、行长期间，为徇个人私利，违反规定，滥用职权，干预招商银行股份有限公司附属机构正常经营决策活动，致使国家利益遭受特别重大损失；利用因职务便利获取的内幕信息以外的其他未公开信息，违反规定，从事与上述信息相关的证券交易活动，情节特别严重；身为证券内幕信息知情人员，在对证券交易价格有重大影响的信息尚未公开前，买入该证券，或者泄露相关信息，或者明示、暗示他人从事上述交易活动，情节特别严重。检察机关提请以受贿罪、国有公司人员滥用职权罪、利用未公开信息交易罪、内幕交易、泄露内幕信息罪追究田惠宇的刑事责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庭审中，检察机关出示了相关证据，被告人田惠宇及其辩护人进行了质证，控辩双方在法庭的主持下充分发表了意见，田惠宇进行了最后陈述并当庭表示认罪悔罪。庭审最后，法庭宣布休庭，择期宣判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人大代表、政协委员及各界群众三十余人旁听了庭审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电诈和战乱，热搜不断的缅北]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年10月27日，缅北多地的政府军据点遭武装袭击并爆发交火，战事激烈，胶着至今。战乱之外，近几年的缅北深陷电信诈骗漩涡。战乱加上电诈让缅北成为舆论焦点。</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[历时9月，金融机构“标杆”呼之欲出]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260291]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;标杆是商业竞争的至佳境界和核心考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央金融工作会议强调，金融是国民经济的血脉，是国家核心竞争力的重要组成部分。牵一发而动全身的金融业，它的标杆又应有何特异之处？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为彰显金融标杆的共性，南方周末新金融研究中心研究团队历时9个月，已相继完成“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”的指标体系优化、测评对象调整、数据更新、深调研和外部专家评审团打分等各项工作。榜单名次呼之欲出。“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”和“2023年中国新金融发展趋势报告”将于2023年12月8日在北京举办的“新金融大会”上正式发布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何确定测评对象？测评制作榜单为何耗时如此之久？外部专家评审团成员是谁？较之市场上的各类金融业榜单，“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”有何特异之处？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心为此进行部分揭秘。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;聚焦“主力军”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“金标杆——中国新金融竞争力榜”将分为八个子榜单和总榜。本次榜单测评对象锁定中国金融业的主力军。哪些金融机构是主力军？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心认为，商业银行、商业保险公司和公募基金领域的头部机构即为中国金融业主力军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;较之7—9月发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，此次榜单有何调整？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时移事易。针对商业银行领域，南方周末新金融研究中心根据2023年9月中国人民银行发布的国内系统性重要银行名单，将6大国有银行、9家股份制银行和5家城市商业银行共计20家商业银行纳入测评范围。因此，较之7月发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，测评名单增加了一家商业银行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对商业保险领域，南方周末新金融研究中心将业务规模排名前八的寿险公司纳入测评之中。较之此前发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”，测评名单增加了一家未上市大型寿险公司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在公募基金和基金销售领域，南方周末新金融研究中心重点测评了资产管理规模排名前32名的公募基金机构和18家第三方基金销售机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综上所述，榜单测评覆盖金融机构总数量达79家，极具代表性。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;覆盖&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;八&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;大领域&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;金融机构哪些业务领域是榜单测评核心考量范畴？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据商业银行、寿险公司、基金公司及基金销售公司的战略业务板块和与公众密切相关的业务领域，南方周末新金融研究中心将财富管理、绿色金融、数字金融、数据安全、寿险效能提升、信用卡质效、风控合规和投教品质等八个领域作为榜单的核心考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，为更客观反映金融行业动态发展，南方周末新金融研究中心进一步全面优化财富管理榜、绿色金融榜、数字金融榜、数据安全榜、寿险效能提升榜和信用卡质效榜六个子榜单的指标体系及各指标的相应权重，以期指标体系及相关权重更合理更科学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时移数也易。南方周末新金融研究中心以2023年各金融机构中报所披露内容为基准，并辅以其它相关数据，对榜单数据进行大面积更新。而此前发布的初版“中国新金融竞争力榜”以各金融机构2022年年报数据及相关数据信息为评测基准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，南方周末新金融研究中心对于大多数金融机构披露而个别金融机构没有披露的数据，对其实施降权处理，以体现对充分披露相关信息金融机构的鼓励。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心还将基于南方周末自研的“牧羊犬—金融合规云平台”发布2023年“金融合规榜”。其中，“牧羊犬—金融合规云平台”已完整收录中国人民银行、国家金融监督管理总局、国家外汇管理局公开发布的行政处罚大数据，并成功实现数据库的标准化运作。因智能和人工双校验，该平台已是金融领域数据最完整最精准且功能最强大的合规数据库。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为激励新秀和倡导创新，南方周末新金融研究中心还特设新金融人物和新金融创新案例等三个年度奖项，并公开接受报名&lt;strong>;。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;三维&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”内外兼&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;评&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如何为各金融机构定座次呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;定量定性的指标测评体系，依然是此次榜单的核心权重，但非全部权重。其中定量定性合计权重占比70%。因此，在各项科学权威的指标里，真实透明的各项数据在为各金融机构的分值“说话”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心对上述各金融机构的深调研将构成另外一个权重。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员持续一个多月以问卷调研、电话调研、线上会议调研和实地调研等形式调研了解各金融机构最新最深的发展情况。此调研结果将占测评权重的15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心还特邀了7名在金融领域的重磅专家。他们以自身长期研究结果对测评对象实名打分，权重为榜单的15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数研结合、内外兼评，“三维”测评法将提升榜单的权威和含金量。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;谁是专家&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;评&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;审团成员&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为进一步凸显本次榜单的客观、权威和公正，并充分考虑上述榜单涉及细分领域的专业性，南方周末新金融研究中心特邀对应行业的7位权威专家和学者组成外部评审团。他们将独立实名行使测评权，测评权重占榜单权重15%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外部专家评审团成员究竟是谁？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们分别是郭田勇、郝演苏、尹振涛、张伟、郑尊信、李秀兰和姚泽宇。（排名不分先后）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;尹振涛&lt;/strong>;现任社科院金融研究所金融科技研究室主任、国家金融与发展实验室金融法律与金融监管研究基地秘书长。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/Ljkoo5AF6AdWcCYYKu5ugPYyLMXX2TxM2tPo6ikN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;389&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/Ljkoo5AF6AdWcCYYKu5ugPYyLMXX2TxM2tPo6ikN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;张伟&lt;/strong>;现任清华大学国家金融研究院副院长、国家顶尖金融智库专家，多次受邀为决策层授课、建言。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/U5Eo4SfqJPGfdDOURjR96fRHX21QwuoHppfYPnl1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;407&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/U5Eo4SfqJPGfdDOURjR96fRHX21QwuoHppfYPnl1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郭田勇&lt;/strong>;现为中央财经大学金融学院教授、博士生导师并兼任中国银行业研究中心主任，还担任亚洲开发银行高级顾问、中国人民银行货币政策委员会咨询专家。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/AFZJT4YjmzTfqqBhbGS7u4jCCvMFTmLIWm8Vef1M.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;431&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/AFZJT4YjmzTfqqBhbGS7u4jCCvMFTmLIWm8Vef1M.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郝演苏&lt;/strong>;现为中央财经大学风险管理与保险系教授、博士研究生导师，曾任中央财政金融学院（现中央财经大学）保险系主任、保险学院院长，兼任全国保险专业研究生教育指导委员会副主任委员、《保险研究》杂志编委。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ZroMrjYguLPOsX0gaIDstE7qw5D5lcB31fHW2Yt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;553&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/0ZroMrjYguLPOsX0gaIDstE7qw5D5lcB31fHW2Yt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257733&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;郑尊信&lt;/strong>;现任深圳大学经济学院院长，是我国数量经济学领域的顶尖学者，在金融工程、资产定价、货币金融等领域拥有深厚造诣。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/QE9YvQjZ0VgylQ3URknpHyAtNl8RX704MTWzNuAr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/QE9YvQjZ0VgylQ3URknpHyAtNl8RX704MTWzNuAr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李秀兰&lt;/strong>;现任英国标准协会（BSI）可持续发展总监，绿色金融、ESG管理方面的资深研究者，连续多年参加联合国气候峰会并就气候变化、绿色金融、可持续发展等话题发表主旨演讲。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/zBgaabVyS6eFVJjV9KAcnHGWpN8OlWnzIpdQ7agz.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;499&quot; height=&quot;696&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/zBgaabVyS6eFVJjV9KAcnHGWpN8OlWnzIpdQ7agz.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;姚泽宇&lt;/strong>;现任中金公司研究部执行总经理、非银金融及金融科技行业首席分析师，在科技金融、数据安全等方面在海内外资本市场具备广泛影响力。（见下图，评委供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/666BeD7AR3IME1pUQTI48FA5Whs5Lueoken2Aegb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;637&quot; height=&quot;568&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/666BeD7AR3IME1pUQTI48FA5Whs5Lueoken2Aegb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（榜单研制：南方周末新金融研究中心研究员李鹤鸣、廖浩伦、张文景&amp;nbsp;蒋昭昆；助理研究员杨超群、邹欢、梁承昊、张金湖、许颖、白雨彤、杜城仪、李晓宛、张琦、陈淑怡、余瑶、李璐、彭君婷、丘子颖、陈祖旭、李金宇、杨相龙、陈乐瑶、刘伟钊、洪新、陈森荣、李书曼、曾子桓和廖剑豪对此榜单亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;数据库技术支持工程师：陈晓龙&amp;nbsp;叶伟豪&amp;nbsp;肖杰&amp;nbsp;唐伟斌&amp;nbsp;甄楚霏&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的《立冬》，竟是冒牌诗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260295]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;November 8, 2023, the beginning of winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Weibo and other online platforms that day, a variety of Beginning of Winter posters occupied the homepages of major official accounts. There is no shortage of ancient poetry and text on these posters. Among them, the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; appears quite frequently: &quot;I am lazy to write new poems with frozen pens, and the wine is warm in the cold furnace. When I am drunk, I look at the white ink flowers and the moon, and I wonder if the village in front is full of snow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems, The situation described in this poem is indeed suitable for the beginning of winter. While retweeting the poetry copy, major official accounts also did not forget to add the poet&#39;s famous name: Li Bai. Perhaps because of these reasons, in recent years, every Beginning of Winter, this poem always &quot;stands out&quot; among other poems and has become a frequent visitor to the Beginning of Winter solar term promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as early as 2016, some Weibo netizens published a post revealing that the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; was not written by Li Bai, but a forgery. On November 7, 2018, the netizen posted on Weibo and wrote: &quot;I have been refuting rumors for three consecutive years, but I still can&#39;t withstand the official big V being so tough... becoming the most powerful official disseminator of &#39;Li Bai&#39;s &quot;Li Dong&quot; fake poem.&quot; Until the Beginning of Winter in 2023, when this netizen posted, he would still include the rumor-refuting entry &quot;Li Bai&#39;s fake poem on the Beginning of Winter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Yu Xianhao, a professor at the School of Liberal Arts at Nanjing Normal University and an expert on Li Bai, also called the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; a forgery in an interview with the &quot;Yangtze Evening News&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this fake poem by Li Bai is not an isolated case. In 2020, Chen Shangjun, a professor of the Chinese Department of Fudan University, gave an example in an interview with Southern People Weekly. The most famous pseudo-poem in Tang poetry is &quot;Qingming&quot;, which is said to be written by Du Mu. He believes that this poem was not written by Du Mu, but by Du Mu. It was written in the Song Dynasty. In the interview, he also cited the statistical results of Japanese scholar Takeo Hiraoka, saying that although the Qing Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; contains 49,403 poems, there are many fake poems in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2023, in Beijing, Li Bai’s humanoid robot appeared at the 2023 World Robot Conference. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, where does the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; come from? How are these pseudo-poems produced? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It suddenly appeared, which is very suspicious”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As an ancient poetry lover who graduated from the Chinese Department, Xu Rongyu has been reading poetry as early as four or five years ago. While paying attention to the phenomenon of pseudo-poetry, she noticed that the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; was actually even earlier. However, at that time, because she had long been accustomed to Li Bai&#39;s many fake poems, she did not think of researching them specifically. It was not until 2022 that many readers and fans asked her some questions about pseudo-poetry, and she wrote a special research article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, the most direct way to check whether a poem is a forgery is to examine the circulation process of the poem - in which book did it first appear? Has it been tampered with by later generations during its circulation? Is the text you see today the original appearance? These are important questions. &quot;For ancient works to spread, they must have a carrier.&quot; Xu Rongyu told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The existing ancient books database provides great convenience. Xu Rongyu first searched for the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; in &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and various existing collections of Li Bai&#39;s poems, but found no results. She turned her attention to the database of modern publications and found that some more rigorous books would include the sources of the poems. Some of them mentioned that the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; came from the &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot; is a printmaking collection of poetry, calligraphy and painting compiled and published by Huang Fengchi during the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty. In &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot;, the so-called poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; is actually called &quot;Winter Scenery&quot;, and the content of the third line of the poem is also slightly different. The &quot;Winter Scene&quot; version is &quot;Drunk and watching the white plum blossoms and the moonlight&quot;, while the &quot;Beijing of Winter&quot; version is &quot;Drunk and watching the whitening of the ink flowers and the moonlight&quot; - Xu Rongyu feels that although the latter looks very elegant on the surface, if you look closely at the &quot;moonlight whitening&quot;, You will find it difficult to explain the image of &quot;white flowers and moon&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot;, in addition to &quot;Winter Scene&quot;, there are also &quot;Spring Scene&quot;, &quot;Summer Scene&quot; and &quot;Autumn Scene&quot;. These four six-character poems are all falsely attributed to Li Bai. After more detailed research, Xu Rongyu discovered that there were rhyming errors in &quot;Xia Scene&quot;, while &quot;Autumn Scene&quot; had allusions that &quot;travelled&quot;, that is, the allusions used in the poem were decades later than when Li Bai was alive. year, this proves from the side that these poems were not written by Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Moreover) This poem has no carrier or record from the Tang Dynasty when Li Bai lived to the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty, and this poem has never appeared. Then in &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot; , it suddenly appeared, which is very suspicious.&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the media in 2018, Yu Xianhao also mentioned that there were many editions of Li Bai&#39;s poetry collection before the Ming Dynasty. There are 998 poems by Li Bai, and none of the many anthologies and engravings handed down since then include six-character poems. In 1908, the Frenchman Pelliot discovered a Tang manuscript in Dunhuang, in which the Tang Dynasty&#39;s Selected Tang Poems included many poems by Li Bai, none of which were six-character poems. After more than 800 years, so many six-character poems suddenly appeared. It is very likely that booksellers fabricated them in order to sell books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In fact, many of the works in &quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot; are forgeries, including those of many well-known Tang Dynasty poets such as Du Mu. They may have been made by (booksellers) by asking some people to make money, because those The poet is well-known and has high traffic. (This bookseller) is a bit like today&#39;s gunmen.&quot; Xu Rongyu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She introduced that the commercial economy of the Ming Dynasty was relatively developed, and the book engraving industry was also very developed. Engraved book printing was one of the hardest hit areas for forgery at that time. &quot;Many of the (forgeries) we see now were created by booksellers at that time in order to make profits and attract traffic. (Those celebrities) were big IPs.&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The ancients have always liked to ask others to write things&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Shangjun once said in a media interview that the main source of about a thousand Li Bai&#39;s poems currently available to the public is It is a collection of Li Bai&#39;s own essays, various poetry selections from the Tang and Song Dynasties, as well as various history books, notes, poems, books, local chronicles, etc. &quot;Some poems are 100% Li Bai&#39;s, and some poems have only a 1% chance of being Li Bai&#39;s. There are at least dozens of pseudo-poems in Li Bai&#39;s name, and each situation is different.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gave an example of &quot;Puppet Poetry&quot; written by Li Bai: &quot;Carving wood and pulling silk to make an old man, chicken skin and white hair are the same as the real one. After a while, nothing happened, and it still seemed like a dream in life. in.&quot; In &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, this poem appears simultaneously under the names of Li Bai, Tang Xuanzong and Liang Kun. Among them, the title of the poem under Liang Kun&#39;s name is &quot;Old Man Ying Wood&quot;. It is now generally believed that he is the author of this poem. This poem is indeed a Tang poem, but it was not written by Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Li Bai, there are also many fake works under the names of famous poets such as Su Shi and Xin Qiji. Lin Shan, who was born in the 1980s, is also a lover of ancient poetry and has been creating in this field for about ten years. Since 2022, he has successively conducted research on thirty pseudo-poems that have been widely circulated on the Internet, including the works of famous poets such as Xin Qiji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lin Shan’s view, forgery has a foundation in the history of literature: “The ancients have always liked to ask others to write things for various reasons. Some do not want to leave their own names, and some do. My own thoughts, but I didn’t dare to say them at the time, so I asked the ancients to write them. As for the fake poems, such as forging Li Bai, it may be just to seek fame. Although I am not famous, others mistakenly think that it is really Li Bai’s work, and I feel sad in my heart. It will be very cool. There are also cases like the Ming Dynasty where people deliberately forged (to make money).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the means of forgery, Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters that a relatively common The situation is to piece it all together, such as taking apart the sentences of the couplet and putting them together with other sentences to form a poem. Another option is direct forgery. For example, someone may want to engrave a forged book of Li Bai&#39;s works. Then he may directly ask a scholar to create the book and put it under Li Bai&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two are also relatively typical means that lead to the emergence of many forgeries. As for some cases of false recognition, for example, the poet&#39;s name was mistakenly read when copying, and it has been passed down since the mistake was written; or in some movies, poems that were actually written by screenwriters were mistakenly thought to be really written by a certain poet during the dissemination process. , may also lead to forgery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary readers who do not know much about ancient poetry, it is actually very difficult to identify and verify forgeries. &quot;Ordinary readers basically can&#39;t tell it apart, unless you have some knowledge of meter. But if the ancients compiled it, it&#39;s useless if you have knowledge of meter, because the ancients were all good at writing poetry, so it would be easy for them to forge it. &quot;Lin Shan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, he feels that if some metrical knowledge can be disseminated to students in the compulsory education stage, such as the fact that flat and oblique characters cannot overlap, it will also be helpful, at least for some &quot;particularly outrageous&quot; students. Most people can spot the forgery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Rongyu also believes that it is difficult to identify fakes. “In fact, the biggest reason for the popularity of fakes is (there are problems in the communication link). People with very high influence may not necessarily have professional identification capabilities. Then you can pass the test; but people like us who can identify some things and write some popular science articles do not have such great influence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But she feels that it is still important to have a questioning spirit, at least It&#39;s possible to be closer to the truth. &quot;I think the main thing is to have a sense of questioning: If you think something is wrong, go check it out. If you search on the Internet, you may find some people&#39;s doubts, and you can get closer to the truth. The main thing is to have this kind of&quot; &quot;Ask more, think more,&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，林杉为笔名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[CEO被传失联，斗鱼“内忧外患”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260293]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 21:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 6, Douyu’s entry confirming that CEO Chen Shaojie was missing became a hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, there were rumors that Chen Shaojie was under investigation and lost contact for three weeks. The 39-year-old CEO has always kept a low profile and rarely appears in the spotlight. The last time he appeared in the public eye was the Douyu 2023 second quarter results conference call held on August 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu (DOYU.&amp;nbsp;Nasdaq), which was born in 2014, has survived the brutal fighting in the early days of China’s game live broadcast industry. It once ranked among the top two players in the industry with its ferocious playing style and Huya, which entered the game earlier than it. male. In 2019, Douyu ushered in a bright moment, following Huya to become a listed company on the US stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the past two years, large comprehensive short and medium video platforms such as Bilibili, Kuaishou, and Douyin have accelerated their attacks, and the game live broadcast track has become increasingly popular. Douyu has also experienced the loss of anchors, weak performance, frequent scandals, etc., and its prospects are not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, Douyu received a compliance warning from the Nasdaq Listing Qualification Department, stating that its closing price had been lower than US$1/share for 30 consecutive trading days and did not meet the compliance requirements. Nasdaq&#39;s minimum share price requirements. Douyu must maintain the closing price of its stock at no less than $1 per share for at least ten consecutive trading days within 180 days, or before April 22, 2024, in order to return to compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Echoing Douyu’s unpredictable prospects, there is also the whereabouts of CEO Chen Shaojie. Douyu told Southern Weekend reporters that Douyu has no official response to this news and the company is currently operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, Douyu closed at US$0.82 per share, a decrease of 1.19%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;A person who likes adventure and licks blood&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1984, Chen Shaojie was born in Jinan, Shandong. Looking at his life experience: addicted to games, majoring in computer science, dropping out of college, and starting a business continuously, Chen Shaojie has gathered many characteristics of the trendsetters in the Internet era and successfully turned his hobby into a career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Shaojie himself once said bluntly in a Douyu live broadcast that he had a high school degree and dropped out of college after one year. He believes that spending four years studying does not necessarily mean you have a deep understanding of the Internet. He compared the Three Kingdoms and said that one&#39;s background is not the most important. &quot;Liu Bei originally sold straw mats, Guan Yu sold dates, and Zhang Fei slaughtered pigs. As their respective With their growth, they have become the most awesome generals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2009, Chen Shaojie and his partner Zhang Wenming sold their first entrepreneurial project, the &quot;Master&quot; battle game platform, to Shanda Games, and Chen became the general manager of Shanda Winger Wuhan Company. The function of the leader is to realize online battles in stand-alone games. Geek Park once reported that Leader is a successful product. One year after it was launched, it has registered a total of 450,000 people and has more than 200,000 daily active users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Chen Shaojie, who made his first pot of gold, acquired the two-dimensional video website AcFun (referred to as Station A) for about 4 million yuan, and launched the &quot;Shengfang Broadcasting&quot; live broadcast channel. In January 2014, Chen Shaojie independent &quot;Shengbangshu&quot; into a game live broadcast platform with barrage function - &quot;Douyu TV&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following years, China’s game live broadcast industry entered an explosive period. In May 2014, Zhanqi Live, backed by the state-owned enterprise Zheshu Culture (600633.SH), was launched. In November of that year, YY spun off its game live streaming business and established Huya Live. In 2015, Longzhu Live and Wang Sicong’s Panda TV were established. In 2016, NetEase and Tencent successively launched CC Live and Penguin Esports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu has been the darling of capital since its appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qichacha shows that Aofei Entertainment (002292.SZ) made an angel round investment of RMB 20 million in Douyu just after its establishment in 2014. In the same year, Sequoia Capital invested another US$20 million in Series A financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2016, Douyu’s Series B financing was led by Tencent, which invested RMB 400 million, followed by Nanshan Capital and Tianyu Digital (002354.SZ), with the total investment scale reaching US$100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Series C financing five months later, Phoenix Capital and Tencent led the investment, with participation from many institutions. Douyu finally raised 1.5 billion yuan. Before going public in 2019, Douyu received financing every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu, who is backed by financing, plays fiercely, which is also related to Chen Shaojie’s personal character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been media reports that Douyu insiders evaluated Chen Shaojie as &quot;a person who likes taking risks and licks blood at the edge of a knife.&quot; Douyu once poached six anchors from the industry within a month, with a total fee of more than 60 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Feng, founder of YY Game Live, once wrote an article analyzing why Douyu was able to overtake Huya in its early stages. “A big reason for the rise of Douyu is that we spent huge sums of money to sign the top anchors in YY and the industry from the beginning.” Before Douyu, YY game live broadcasts could be relatively controlled by controlling traffic and income distribution. Live anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, game anchors are different from entertainment anchors. The former has external effects, does not rely on live broadcast platforms, and has other opportunities to become Internet celebrities (such as e-sports events, Youku game channels, Weibo etc.), has the ability to bring its own fans, and can also bring fans to migrate, so YY Game Live has not signed a contract with the head anchor. This gave Douyu an opportunity to directly use the signing fee instead of the share to obtain top anchors, which became the core reason why Douyu could overtake Huya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the game live streaming industry went through a period of consolidation after a big wave, forming a &quot;fish and tooth confrontation&quot; pattern in the first echelon. Douyu and Huya shared most of the game live streaming market share. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The problem of profitability is difficult to solve&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On July 17, 2019, Douyu was listed on Nasdaq at an issue price of US$11.5 per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But its stock price only experienced a short period of sustained growth during the epidemic. On February 16, 2021, Douyu once reached an intraday high of US$20.54 per share, and then plummeted to less than US$1 per share now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering 2021, Douyu’s quarterly revenue, except for the fourth quarter of that year, has been negative growth. According to its 2022 financial report, Douyu’s revenue growth relies heavily on paying users and revenue per paying user. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Douyu is losing users. Wind data shows that in the second quarter of 2023, the number of quarterly paying users of Douyu was 4 million, a year-on-year decrease of 39.39%. The number of monthly active users was 50.3 million, a year-on-year decrease of 9.69%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu’s current revenue still mainly comes from live broadcasts and advertising, and its attractiveness to advertisers continues to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2022, Douyu’s live broadcast revenue was 8.8522 billion yuan, 8.5966 billion yuan and 6.7973 billion yuan, accounting for 92.2%, 93.8% and 95.6% of the total revenue in the same period respectively. Douyu&#39;s advertising sales revenue was 645.2 million yuan, 464.9 million yuan and 190.3 million yuan, accounting for 6.7%, 5.1% and 2.7% of the total revenue in the same period respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although revenue continues to decline, it will be profitable for two consecutive quarters in 2023. In the second quarter of 2023, Douyu’s net profit was 6.8 million yuan, and the net loss in the same period of 2022 was 38.8 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Douyu’s turnaround from losses to profits is the result of cost reduction and efficiency increase.” Ding Daoshi, a senior Internet observer, told Southern Weekend reporters that he does not think this is a healthy way to make money, but Expressing understanding, &quot;This is also a helpless strategy in extraordinary times.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second quarter of 2023, Douyu’s expenses were 196 million yuan, a decrease of 42% from 340 million yuan in the same period last year. Among them, sales and marketing expenses decreased by 48% compared with the same period last year, research and development expenses decreased by 30.2%, and general and administrative expenses decreased by 48.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sluggish performance of Douyu is due, on the one hand, to the impact of short video platforms on traditional live broadcast platforms; on the other hand, it is also due to the impact of leading video platforms such as Bilibili, Douyin, and Kuaishou on the gaming field. Strong preemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2019, Station B spent 800 million yuan to defeat domestic live broadcast platforms such as Kuaishou, Douyu, and Huya, and won the exclusive live broadcast of the League of Legends (LOL) Global Finals (S Competition) in China for three years. copyright. In July of the same year, Kuaishou launched the “Million Game Creator Support Plan” and frequently held various competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the unfavorable situation, in July 2020, Tencent tried to lead the merger of Douyu and Huya, but was later stopped by the regulatory agency on antitrust grounds in accordance with the law. As of March 31, 2023, Tencent held 46.7% of Huya’s shares and 37.7% of Douyu’s shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Game industry analyst Zhang Shule told Southern Weekend reporters that although Douyu and Huya are survivors of the game live broadcast melee, the failure of the merger means that both have lost an opportunity to integrate resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Douyu and Huya continue to experience brain drain. In August 2023, Xuxu Baobao, the head anchor who had been live broadcasting on Douyu for 5 years, announced that he would switch to Douyin. In March before this, Huya outdoor anchor Mu Yingying also joined Douyin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Anchors are like migratory birds, they go wherever it’s warm.” Zhang Shule said that anchors have no loyalty to the platform and are now jealous of selling products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ding Daoshi’s view, Douyu and Huya have few moats. In their early years, they relied on the Tencent system and related popular e-sports live broadcasts to rise. In recent years, Bilibili, Douyin, Kuaishou, and even video accounts can also conduct game live broadcasts. “There are so many people sharing the cake, but the growth rate of the cake is obviously not synchronized.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that in this context, traditional e-sports live broadcast platforms represented by Douyu and Huya are in these A year-on-year decline is inevitable and the downward trend will continue. They are all looking for new growth paths outside of games, such as sports live broadcasts, but the results will take time to be verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shule said bluntly that the overall revenue scenario of Douyu game live broadcasts and short videos is single. Facing the attack of other pan-entertainment platforms, Douyu lacks more effective checks and balances besides relying on Tencent. &quot;The biggest pain point is Profitability is still a problem.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that Douyu’s only moat is Tencent, one of the three giant domestic game companies (the other two are NetEase and MiHoYo). Tencent has a huge control over the field of e-sports, and can use IP licensing and e-sports event licensing to reserve some private space for Douyu. However, opponents can still look for game and e-sports cooperation outside the Tencent system, so the moat is not wide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shule said that the plight of Douyu and Huya is almost the same, but now under the arrangement of Tencent, the two companies cannot merge and try and make mistakes at different times in order to find a way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his opinion, Douyu’s gaming attributes are too strong, and the user portraits in the outdoor, appearance, and two-dimensional areas highly overlap with the gaming area. The real possible direction for Douyu to get out of trouble may be to combine new profit models in e-sports events that are also difficult to make profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Ten Thousands of People Gather to Gamble”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a leading game live broadcast platform, Douyu has frequently received negative news about pornography, vulgarity, and suspected gambling in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, the official blog of the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League published an article saying that the live broadcast room of Douyu anchor &quot;彡彡九屋&quot; (hereinafter referred to as 339) is suspected of hosting tens of thousands of people for gambling, and the daily turnover can reach several million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, the official blog of China Youth Network’s short video stated that the Douyu anchor “Changsha Village Death Squadron” is the “biggest casino in Douyu” and a lottery suspected of gathering gambling will be opened at 10 o’clock every night. , thus forming the public codename &quot;Ten Points Economic Lessons&quot;. In 2020, its turnover was as high as 177 million yuan, and its daily turnover was as high as 13 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, &quot;彡彡九Outdoor&quot; will be characterized as gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sichuan Legal News, 339 member Fu Moulong and three other people &quot;tried to turn their bicycles into motorcycles&quot; through &quot;one card application for 50,000 yuan to take home&quot; between March 2017 and September 2020. &quot;A large number of inflammatory words such as &quot;Encourage live broadcast room viewers to participate in the lottery, and push lottery time and amount information to other people who did not participate in the live broadcast through platforms, WeChat groups, etc., resulting in a large number of people entering the live broadcast room during the live lottery period and paying.&quot; Apply for a card&quot;, swipe virtual gifts, etc. to participate in the lottery. After the draw, winning cash will be distributed to the winners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to the time of their arrest, Fu Moulong and others had organized a total of 4,267 draws (times), with more than 4.42 million people participating, and gambling funds of nearly 120 million yuan. After trial, the Dujiangyan Court held that the actions of the three people constituted the crime of opening a casino, and they were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment ranging from six to three years, and were also fined. This case is also the first gambling case involving a live broadcast platform in the country supervised and handled by the Ministry of Public Security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, Qian Xiaojia, the first brother of the former Douyu outdoor anchor, revealed in an interview that although gambling-related activities in 339 and other live broadcast rooms are not officially held by Douyu, the platform is not unaware of it. There will even be internal guidance. In the second half of 2019, Qian Xiaojia was banned by Douyu for violating regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 30, 2023, the Cyberspace Administration of China&#39;s WeChat public account &quot;CyberChina&quot; released the national cyberspace administrative law enforcement and supervision situation in the first quarter of 2023, stating that it will continue to promote the &quot;Qingming&quot; series of special actions , resolutely investigate and deal with all kinds of online illegal activities in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It mentioned that Internet platforms such as Baidu, Sina Weibo, Douyu, and Douban failed to fulfill their main responsibilities and failed to manage the information released by their users, resulting in obscenity, feudal superstition, and solicitation of prostitution. Regarding the spread of harmful information on the Internet such as prostitution, gambling, and loan sharking, the Cyberspace Administration of China instructs the local Cyberspace Administration to conduct interviews, order rectifications, and carry out punitive measures in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 8, &quot;CyberChina&quot; issued another article stating that in response to serious ecological problems such as pornography and vulgarity on the Douyu platform, the Cyberspace Administration of China directed the Cyberspace Administration of Hubei Province to send a working group to station Douyu platform launched a one-month centralized rectification supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Shule’s view, China’s live broadcast craze originated from game live broadcasts. However, game live broadcasts failed to break the barriers of consumption scenarios and failed to become the leader in the trend. It was not until the emergence of live broadcasts to bring goods. A new situation has opened up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The current game live broadcast platform is also looking for its own &#39;live broadcast delivery&#39;, but through crazy trial and error, many problems have arisen.&quot; Zhang Shule said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[100万？300万？想不上班到底要存多少钱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260278]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen in Jiangxi shared his story. She and her husband spent 7 years saving 1 million yuan. After part of it was used to buy a house, the remaining 500,000 yuan was deposited in the bank. Now the monthly living costs can be covered by interest alone. She also shared a series of ways to save money, such as cooking at home for many years, not drinking coffee outside, only buying discounted clothes, taking her children to sunbathe instead of taking interest classes, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the authenticity of this experience has not been verified, in February this year, a Shanghai couple did decide to &quot;retire&quot; with a deposit of 3 million yuan. This news sparked widespread discussion at the time. Just recently, Professor Chen Bingzheng from the Department of Finance at the School of Economics and Management of Tsinghua University was interviewed by CCTV Finance. He mentioned that “a survey found that over 70% of those born after 90 start to think about pension issues.” He said that it is too late to start thinking about pension issues at the age of 35. From work After receiving your first month’s salary, you should start saving for retirement in a planned way. It can be seen that young people’s anxiety about saving money for retirement is not an idle complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much savings do you think you need to retire from the workplace with peace of mind? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[董明珠称孟羽童兼职接广告不合规：非工作时间能否干副业？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260289]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In May this year, Dong Mingzhu’s secretary Meng Yutong resigned, triggering various speculations and discussions. Recently, in an interview with Guangdong Satellite TV&#39;s &quot;Financial Eyes&quot;, Dong Mingzhu responded publicly to the matter for the first time: Internet celebrities do not judge people&#39;s quality, and it is illegal for people to advertise outside Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Dong Mingzhu said Meng Yutong’s part-time job accepting advertisements was illegal” was once a hot search topic. According to a report by the Shanghai Securities News on May 16, the reason for Meng Yutong&#39;s resignation was that he &quot;often missed work to participate in business activities and take on private work&quot; during his time at the company. After the company talked to him, he still carried out related activities without improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure, Meng Yutong did receive advertisements on social media platforms. In the short videos on his Xiaohongshu account, he appeared many times selling clothing, beauty products, electronic products and household goods. In the &quot;Good Things Pocket&quot; column, there are 65 notes included, none of which have anything to do with Gree Electric products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I originally thought that the rights and wrongs of this incident were very clear. However, many netizens believe that the contract Meng Yutong signed with Gree is a labor contract, not an endorsement contract. The time outside the eight hours is her own. Of course, she has the right to control how much she earns through endorsements and part-time advertising. Money is a reflection of her ability. This has also led to some discussions: Is it appropriate for the company to restrict employees from doing side jobs? If the income from your main job is not as good as your side job, will you leave your job? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this point of view and these discussions? First of all, it must be said unequivocally that it is not appropriate to use Meng Yutong&#39;s case to demonstrate the rationality of employees taking part-time jobs or doing side jobs outside of their own jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Yutong did graduate from a prestigious university, has a sweet appearance, and has good looks, but these qualities are not sufficient or necessary to become an Internet celebrity. There are a lot of people with these qualities, but only a few lucky ones are successful. The track for Internet celebrities is very crowded and very winding. If someone says that Meng Yutong’s ability to become an Internet celebrity depends entirely or mainly on his personal abilities, that is undoubtedly not objective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that Meng Yutong became an Internet celebrity mainly due to Dong Mingzhu’s efforts on top of his buildable personal qualities. Dong Mingzhu made her his secretary, and announced that he would train her to be his successor and take her to various occasions. Through the event, many hot searches and topics were created, bringing her countless traffic. Dong Mingzhu is working hard to make her the first person to bring goods to Gree live broadcast. In this sense, Meng Yutong, who has become an Internet celebrity, is an asset of Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Dong Mingzhu and Gree are obviously old-school, hoping that gentlemen&#39;s agreement and personal consciousness will have enough behavioral constraints on Meng Yutong, rather than &quot;first Before the company invests resources in an individual, it ensures and locks in potential future earnings, and limits and eliminates the risk of breach of trust of a sparrow that turns into a phoenix and then soars into the sky and escapes control. That is, the contract stipulates the rights and obligations of both parties and improves the The cost of breach of trust should be taken into account before you can safely invest in betting and package marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, when it was discovered that Meng Yutong was using the Internet celebrity status created by the company to do private work, Dong Mingzhu and Gree did not immediately send a clear and strong signal saying &quot;this is not acceptable&quot;, but The reason is that there was no timely intervention or the intensity of the intervention was not enough. The mentality may be that the matter can be solved quietly internally, through reasoning and persuasion, so as to prevent the matter from turning into a negative incident or scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if Meng Yutong had been given a clear choice the first time he did private work, either to stop and hand over the proceeds from his private work, or to leave, the problem might have been solved long ago. When Meng Yutong took on more and more private jobs and his income outside of work became higher and higher, it became difficult for him to stop. At a certain stage, Dong Mingzhu could no longer tolerate it and had to resolve it through a final showdown, which brought us to the scene in May this year. Therefore, if there is something wrong with Dong Mingzhu and Gree, it is that they made the above two mistakes one after another. But this does not disprove that it is in line with professional ethics for Meng Yutong to use the Internet celebrity status created by the company to do private work and make big money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is no simple answer to whether employees can work part-time or do side jobs outside of their regular jobs, and it needs to be analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it depends on whether there are express provisions on this in the labor contract or other types of contracts signed with the company or organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, units within the system generally have some clear restrictions on employees&#39; part-time work, and will regularly conduct inspections on employees in this regard, allowing employees to declare on their own. Of course you can lie or conceal the situation, but if your employer finds out, you will inevitably be punished or even lose your job. In addition, well-regulated companies generally prohibit employees from receiving remuneration from competitors, suppliers or customers. This not only potentially harms the company&#39;s interests, but may also lead to criminal investigation in serious cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it depends on the nature of your part-time job or side job, and whether there is any conflict of interest with your work in the unit and the business of the unit. You are a salesperson and have accumulated a lot of customer resources. At a certain stage, if you set up a business and go it alone, the company may not be able to do anything to you. But if you are receiving a salary from the company while secretly setting up a business with a similar nature to the company, A company that imports customer resources into its own company is undoubtedly against professional ethics, and the company may not let it go if it finds out. Or if you are a technical R&amp;D personnel and you resell the code you wrote in the company to a competing company or other companies, or take work from a competing company, this will also damage the company&#39;s rights and interests and seriously violate professional ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, &quot;Besides the eight-hour working time, it is all your own time, you can do whatever you want.&quot; This statement must be at least restricted by the above two rules. In the final analysis, it means respecting the contract and Observe professional ethics. As long as it does not violate the contract and company regulations, does not harm the company&#39;s rights and interests, has no conflict of interest with the company, and does not affect the main job, generally speaking, the company has no objection to individuals doing side jobs and part-time jobs to increase their income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[桐子故事丨峡河西流去]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/NutlzMHR2UbsNNB6zpzzOTaygMtBDmbXoFeHEPjT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NutlzMHR2UbsNNB6zpzzOTaygMtBDmbXoFeHEPjT . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tongzi flowers bloom. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;一&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Xiahe to Luanzhuang, we have to cross three ridges. It&#39;s not the three ridge heads, it&#39;s the third ridge head counting from Taoping. Taoping has now been transformed from a township into an administrative village. It is where Santiao Ridge originates and Yitiao Ridge begins. Going further south is the Funiu Mountains and then enters Nanyang. It is not clear why it is called Santiaoling instead of Sandaoling or something else. Indeed, the word &quot;Tiao&quot; is a bit strange, as if it is a ridge rather than a mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The side of Santiao Ridge near Luanzhuang is a ten-mile downhill slope. At the bottom of the slope is the Bada River. After crossing the river and going five miles eastward, you will reach Luanzhuang Town. Luanzhuang Town has been the capital of Luanzhuang since the Republic of China, the so-called economic, cultural, transportation and power center. The ancient town that was more than a hundred years old now has no trace of the past. Instead, there are concrete buildings rising from the ground on both sides of the Luanzhuang River, which is sometimes dirty and sometimes clear. Everything sold on the street is modern. For example, household appliances used for heating in winter are electric braziers instead of charcoal. Even the dogs running on the street have many fashionable hair styles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the side of the ten-mile downhill road, there are all tung trees. Of course, that was a scene more than thirty years ago. Nowadays, it is all pine trees and arrowgrass. The pine trees are domineering, and the arrowgrass is not a fuel-efficient lamp. With them, there is no one else. There are only a few tung trees, and the old-fashioned people have nowhere to stand. In today&#39;s spring and summer, the mountains are green and interspersed with wild flowers of strange colors. Walking through this place gives people the excitement and satisfaction of returning home in rich clothes. In winter, half of the mountains are green and half are withered and yellow, like a failed oil painting.小地方经济不好，管理交通的人员躲在那些弯道里，借地势和草木掩护，抓来往的违章摩托车，罚款创收，一抓一个准，人们如果不是大事急事，一般很少骑车过往，要过往，也会选择早晨或晚上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十多年前，我在峦庄镇读初中。那时候大部分同学都不怎么爱学习，上学似乎只是为了完成打发少年光阴的任务。比较起来，我算是较爱学习的一个，但和那些烧脑的文字数字比较起来，我还是更爱那些与成绩无关的东西一些，比如桐子，从桐子花到桐籽都爱，爱得也没啥道理，就是觉得好，觉得它们是我的，我也是它们的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花三月开，这时候很多花已经收尾，桃花、杏花、梨花海棠花们全都香消玉殒了，而更多的夏花们还没有到来。天已经很暖和了，这时候，天突然冷一场，甚至还会下一场雪来，待气温再暖和时，桐子花就开了。大人说，桐花还要寒风冻。桐子花算不上好看，也不难看，朵算不上大，也不小，但它的香气不一样，是一种清香，气味像极了它的颜色和形状：白色花瓣镶嵌着淡红色的蕊，每一朵每一枝都相似，像双胞胎姐妹。桐子花一开一坡，浩浩荡荡，密实得不见其它。远远看，一坡的花，像话痨，谁也插不上嘴，不像别的花，有红有绿有空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候孩子多，如果上学都赶一块儿了，从前到后要排好长的队伍。前面进了桐花阵，后面还在岭那边，前面过了八岔河，后面还在花阵里。上学的人每人提一只网兜，兜里白馍黑馍杂面馍一目了然。女孩子爱虚荣，在馍外面遮一层报纸，只能看见祖国欣欣向荣的景象，看不见馍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花有一个用处，治烫伤。八岔河口，有一个还俗的老道士，很老很老了，弯了腰，须发尽白。他经常上岭来收集凋落的桐子花。凋落的桐子花铺满了一地，像树头一样密实，奇怪的是树上并不见减少，仿佛它们一边凋落一边在生长。他背一只编织口袋，一收集一袋子落花。也不知道他拿回去怎么处理的，掺了别的什么材料，调成膏，装在大大小小的瓶子里，涂在伤者烫伤上，百医百效，几乎不留疤。也不知道哪一年，老道士死了，治烫伤的方子就一同带走了。他没儿没女，传也没人传，再说，治烫伤也糊不了口，一年到头，没有几个烫伤的。他也不靠这个吃饭。再有烫伤的，只能去医院，花好多钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花开过两个月，桐子出来了，个个青嫩得要滴水，但其实都坚硬得砸不开。男孩子用它互掷打仗，脑袋上一砸一个包。用石头砸开来，桐籽白白胖胖挤在一块，嚼在嘴里很香，比核桃仁都好吃，但过一会儿头疼、恶心。去了桐籽的壳晒干了是烧火的好材料，冬天正好烧炕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学校食堂只有一种饭，玉米糁糊汤，玉米糁急火慢火熬成的粥，且只有早中两餐，晚上只能吃自带的馍或者干熬到天亮。就饭的菜就显得很重要，要有油水，可大部分没有油水，没有油水也行，有花样也行，但花样也少，就是一桶蒜汁调酸菜，且量也有限，要合理分配。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金锁家门前有一棵漆树，三丈多高，合抱粗，这么大的漆树，不多见。夏天遮天蔽日，到了秋天，漆籽打下来能熬一大盆漆籽油。漆籽油也是食用油的一种，也能点灯，送亡人的路上，点长明灯。但是树太老了，半荣半枯，树杆有一半已经朽了。有一年夏天，下过一场雨，天晴后枯的那边长出一大朵树菇来，颜色又红又黄，像西天一朵火烧云落了下来。漆树菇是上好的树菇一种，鲜嫩鲜美，能上席面。我和金锁把它掰下来，满满一盆，但他家里没有油，翻遍了柜子和墙角也找不到。我说，有办法，去弄桐子炼油。我们上了三条岭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐籽炼油不难。我们摘了一筐桐果，把它砸开，把桐籽抠出来，用蒜臼捣碎了，放进锅里熬，去了渣，竟炼了一碗油。听大人说过，不论什么油，只要放了毒就没事了。桐籽在锅里熬，熬掉了水汽，放了烟，就算放毒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我俩上吐下泻了一晚上，金锁他爹给我们灌了洗衣粉水，第二天才停下来。也幸亏那天吃得不多，油也放得少。我俩三天没上学，那一年，我俩都初三。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若干年后，金锁上了大学，我上了矿山，从此命运分道扬镳。我没有他的电话，他没有我的联系渠道，从他爹妈死了后，我们彼此更加一无所知，唯一隐约知道的是，他没工作几年就去了欧洲，娶妻安家，他乡变作故乡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三条岭上仅剩的桐子有些年景还会开几枝，零星的桐花躲在万绿丛中，比大片绵延的桐花更好看，一点也不显得孤独。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;桐果通常在十月中下旬成熟，果子由青绿变为淡红，最后变成黑褐色，就可以采收了。桐果的蒂很结实，和枝头连接得很紧密，不像核桃和板栗这些果子容易敲打下来，釆收桐子是非常缓慢辛苦的活，枝头不高的话，女人和孩子用手摘反倒是最快的。男人们爬上树，用竹竿敲打，把树头枝杈棒打成了披发鬼，总有几个桐果纹丝不动，最后只有任它留到来年。桐子身沉，运输也是件费力的事，一个好劳力，背一筐，吃力得弯腰驼背气喘吁吁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;碓的用途十分广泛，几乎任何有关破碎的活都可以用捣的方法解决。把桐果彻底晾晒干了，倒进碓窝里捣，是最有效的出桐米的方法，这项工作一般由妇女和孩子完成。处理干净的桐米又白又嫩，像羊脂似的。我们这些孩子，夹在其中忙前忙后，趁人不备，丢一粒在嘴里，又被大人给抠出来，哇哇吐了一地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐油就是桐籽榨的油，榨桐油的流程和榨花生油差不多。我小时候好事，一身猴气，曾多次参与大人们的榨油劳动，繁琐的细节都不记得了，只记得桐油的透明纯净，那淡黄的颜色找不到对应参照的东西，所以无法描述，用一物去形容和说明另一物，这古老的、无所不能的语言方式在桐油面前彻底失效了。榨出来的桐油装在盆盆钵钵里，有外地人来收购，虽说卖不了多少钱，油盐酱醋钱有了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐油是最好的漆染家具的漆物，林师傅是最好的漆匠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一般说来，木匠也是漆匠，漆匠也是木匠，很少见谁家请了木匠，打好了家具又请漆匠的。木匠不一定多才，但一定多艺，否则，没法踩百家门头，只有林师傅，偏偏只会漆工，木匠的活一窍不通，但因为手艺太好，哪怕是身怀独技，仍然不愁饭吃。也因为手艺太好，弄得同行常常没了活路，让人慕又招人恨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅也不是当地人，有说是河南的，有说是湖北的，也有说是四川的，他自己不说，别人当然只是乱猜。人们的根据是他的口音，但出门久了的人，吃四方饭，应八方景，乡音早已无存，留下的是两掺三掺的杂糅音腔。林师傅来到峡河时，四十岁了，手艺不是在峡河学的，是从远处带来的，他一到来就是大师傅。他自己说是家传，这一说法大家自然是信的，好手艺大多来自家传。四十岁的林师傅到了峡河，四十一上就娶到了女人，自然也是得益于他的好手艺。女人小他十七八岁，还是个闺女，叫刘兰花。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花她爹是个席匠，一辈子织苇席。出门织，也在自己家里织，需要的人上门来买，或用东西交换。刘席匠的席匠生涯就这两个方式，一半出外上门，一半家庭作坊。刘席匠老了的时候，就不出门了，房后山上养了一片芦苇园子，五六亩，方圆几十里的人家用席也够了。刘席匠织了一辈子席，手里也攒了点钱，在方圆算殷实人家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早些年，人都穷，置不起棺材，大多数人死了，用苇席一卷就入了土，那苇席自然也是出自刘席匠的手。刘席匠东山织到西山，白天织到晚上，织出的席，一半用来晒粮，一半用来卷人。后来，人们日子过得宽松些了，有人开始使用棺板，当然，芦席这时也没有缺席入土为安的事业，再后来，全都改用棺板了，就没苇席什么事了。有了星星想月亮，这时候，又有人开始给棺材上油漆，要让死者在地下长眠得更安然、长久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘席匠织了一辈子席，看到亲手织的席卷了数不清的人，但从内心里，他对席卷人入土的方式是不认可的，他觉得那才真叫草菅人命。同样的，他对后来的人们给棺材刷满从街上买来的化学油漆也深恶痛绝，那玩意不但不防腐，那气味怎么让人安宁？总之，人这一辈子太忙，没睡过好觉，走了，到了另一个世界，一定得睡安稳些踏实些。刘席匠的最大理想，是有一口桐油棺材。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个理想，林师傅帮他实现了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那一天，我们全村老少见证了桐油由生油变熟油的伟大又壮观的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅在刘席匠家的院子里砌了一只齐腰高的土灶台，灶上架起一只大铁锅，用柞木柴火在下面猛烧；先将从河里挑选来的光净石子放在锅中炒，石子炒烫后，倒入生桐油，倒多少，肯定有讲究，林师傅只是倒，嘴里不说。接着锅里翻江倒海，随着温度越升越高，桐油里的水汽逐渐蒸发掉了。空气里有了香味，香味铺天盖地，像一个大毯子蒙住了整个院子，但那个香，是谁也没有闻过的香，浓烈放荡，说不出来是好是坏。此时，大家看到锅中的桐油泛起油花。林师傅快速加入了一铲粉状东西，一会儿，桐油面上泛起一层白色的泡沫，并冒出浓浓的黄烟。林师傅指挥一个青年用木棒奋力搅拌，泡沫迅速地与桐油密合，这时候烟色由黄转黑，浓烟直冲天上，渐渐消散。林师傅用木棍挑出一缕儿桐油，滴在石头上，用手指蘸着桐油往上拉长，拉出很长的细丝来。林师傅命人迅速浇灭锅下的火，大喊一声:成了！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观看的人好奇又紧张，又不得要领，像做了一场梦。觉得林师傅真神，才知道原来桐油可以这么熬成好东西，以前总是把桐油生生卖掉，好可惜。若干年过去，当熬桐油不再是独门绝技，大家才知道，那粉状的东西是土子粉和樟丹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经熟桐油由外到里刷过三遍的柏木棺板，简直像一只多棱的镜子，映照出一群人怪异好奇的嘴脸，映照出天上的太阳和游荡的云彩。为证明桐油的功效，林师傅往棺里倒了一桶水，倒进去时满满一桶，舀出来一桶满满，不多不少。刘席匠说，这狗日的桐油，怕能护人身子一千年！ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;三&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;林师傅和刘兰花生了一个女儿，叫林萍儿。刘兰花一副好身段，两扇好屁股，像一团棉花，要多饱满有多饱满，生多少都不是问题，但不敢生，政策紧，根本承受不起罚款。林师傅走的那年，林萍儿十三岁，还在读初中。满打满算下来，刘兰花和林师傅做了十四年夫妻。对林师傅的走，刘兰花是真的舍不得。下葬的那天，天下着雨，刘兰花从头到脚都湿透了，有人说是雨浇的，有人说是泪浇的，其实两个都是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;满打满算，林师傅在峡河生活了十四年，桐油匠职业生涯十四年，不算长，也不算短，但经他使用过的桐油，刷过的家具，不知道用什么才能计量清楚。他传下的手艺，他有意无意带动的行业，在他离开五年后也戛然而止，按新的经济发展要求，乡村产业转型，上面要求弃桐子改播松树。一种产业、一个行业随着世事的转腾而终于凋落、寂灭了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一年的有一天，林师傅送林萍儿上学去，学校在镇上，星期六接回来，星期天送到校。他骑一辆大杠，车头上挂着书包和干粮袋子，车后座上载着女儿。车下三条岭，桐子花正开，路里的花，路外的花，头连着尾，尾连着头，人车在花中穿行，头上的天，鼻孔里的花香，真叫人快乐啊。林师傅想，今年又是好收成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车到二道盘，那里有一处泉眼，四季清水汩汨，又甘又甜。来往的人、雀鸟、小动物都在这里饮水、歇脚。因为潭在低处，人需要双腿跪下，伸长脖子才能饮到水。有一个传说，说泉眼里有一条鱼精，受人的跪拜时间久了，已经得道，有时晚上会出来清理水潭的脏物，让泉永远清清净净，但谁也没有见过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅有些饿了，他把一只饼分两半，自己一半女儿一半，就着泉水吃起来。在吞第二口时，他感到饼在喉咙里卡住了，上不上，下不下。他掬起一捧水，灌下去，也不管用。他知道这是怎么回事，他想起母亲也是这样的情形，这样卡了几年，走了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅请匠人给自己打的棺是一口泡桐木棺，泡桐木材质松软，不经腐，但好处是得来全不费工夫，一排大树就长在院子边，就地取材。刘兰花说，还早呢，让树再长几年。林师傅说，不早了，早晚都得准备。刘兰花说，也给我备一口。林师傅说，你的还早，让树再长几年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅给自己熬桐油的壮观场面和十四年前在刘席匠院子第一次熬桐油的场面如出一辙，围观者众多，帮忙的也多。虽然这时候这门技术早已不是秘密。在最后退去锅底的柴火时，刘兰花有些慌张，把锅底打了个洞，熬成的桐油倾泻而下，虽然众人奋力抢救，熬成的晶亮的好东西只抢救出三分之一，漏掉的部分化作了一阵冲天大火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅的棺板刷到一半，没有桐油了，另一半，只好去街上买来一桶洋漆完成。林师傅叹口气，说，这都是命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅走了两年后，有一天，刘兰花收到一封信，寄件地址不详，寄件人不详。收信人姓名是林懿德，刘兰花不认得名字里的中间那个字，问女儿林萍儿，林萍儿这时已上了高中，没有不认识的字，说那个字读yì。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花开始以为寄信人把地址和名字写错了，想退回去，丈夫的名字叫林建业，从来没有听说过这个怪怪的名字。乡邮寄员说，没有错，邮政编码都是对的，再说，谁知道往哪里退，退给谁？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花就拆开信读了，说完，才知道寄信的人没有寄错地址和收信人。她读完了信，悄悄抹了一阵泪，就随手把信丟进锅洞里烧了，烧尽的信没有成灰，保持着纸的形状，从灶洞飘出来，飞出了院子，在空中飘飘荡荡。刘兰花心里说，你就落下来吧，我读过了，就是你读过了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林萍儿从房里拿着一件衣服出来，问写的啥？刘兰花说，没写啥，是有人把信寄错地方了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[东西方贵族是如何消亡的？从贵族到精英是身份政治的式微]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一位自称是“英国礼仪专家”的博主Lucy Challenger，在TikTok上发布了一条视频，教网友如何在正式场合用刀叉吃米饭。她认为在西方环境中，不应该用手、勺子或筷子吃米饭，而应该用餐刀把米饭推到叉子背面顶端处，然后优雅地放进嘴里，这样可以显得更有教养和风度。这一“贵族风”的视频引发各种调侃与群嘲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多国人也喜欢强调贵族概念，什么房中贵族、车中贵族、服饰品牌贵族……甚至前几天，在建材商店里还看到了乳胶漆中的“贵族”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;言必称贵族，其实多是消费妄想症。贵族这个社会群体，在东、西方社会中，都已经死亡，或接近于死亡。大致了解下东、西方社会的贵族诞生、发展、衰落、消亡过程，也是蛮有意思的历史回顾之旅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在远古的东、西方社会，贵族几乎同时代诞生于文明初期。发展大致可以划分成：古典贵族、古代贵族、近代贵族三大历史阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古典贵族，在东方始于西周-春秋时代，在西方产生于古罗马共和时代。因其产生于农业社会早期，所以东、西方的古典贵族，都源于大土地占有者。东方的春秋，诸侯就是贵族，分封制是上古大土地所有制。钟鸣鼎食、酒池肉林是贵族区分于平民的生活方式。公、侯、伯、子、男等爵位划分了贵族等级，包括依附于贵族的“士”阶层，构成了上古东方农业社会的统治秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，比古罗马稍早些的古希腊社会，贵族力量不太强。由于巴尔干半岛缺乏大片连绵土地，所以古希腊发展出早期民主体制，体现出城邦商业富裕阶层均分权力的诉求。罗马在其征服地，譬如北非和西班牙拥有大量土地，所以产生了大量土地贵族，他们是支撑罗马帝国的强大基础，在元老院中分享权力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在古典主义时代，东方和西方的贵族，不但垄断了大量土地、财富，而且也垄断了文化、知识、艺术，产生并消费了那个时代惊人的文化艺术成就：古希腊和罗马的雕塑与建筑艺术，东方的《楚辞》、《诗》中的雅、颂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公元4-5世纪，是人类文明变更的大分水岭时代：东、西方的古典文明（东汉与西罗马）均败亡于北方蛮族，人类文明进入长达数百年的黑暗时代（或曰“中世纪”）。古典贵族在这个时代消亡，取而代之的是，东、西方都产生了第二轮次的“古代贵族”（中古贵族），而且，此时代东、西方产生的都是军事领主贵族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，日耳曼族群征服了西罗马之后，分疆裂土、大肆封侯，产生了大批蛮族军事贵族，这些中世纪的爵爷们，粗野、颟顸、质朴……几乎全是文盲，他们只强调尚武精神，比谁的胳膊粗、力气大、宝剑长，没事就骑马比武。欧洲军事贵族把读书写字视为羞耻、男子气概不足。在管理层面的文字需求，几乎全部由教士和侍从承担，基督教因此垄断了中世纪欧洲的意识形态与文化艺术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时代的东方，南北朝和隋唐的士族（类似于贵族）产生了分化：南方士族，因“衣冠南渡”，文化和艺术修养较高，素有清雅文弱之名。而北方贵族，有相当部分胡人血统，文化艺术水准较低，但武力值较高，此即支撑了隋、唐两代的“关陇军事贵族”。公元6-7世纪，北方贵族军队征服了南方士族，华夏进入了第二个大统一时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;统一促进了经济与社会发展，文化艺术亦蓬勃发展。北方贵族的文化水准虽低，但仍在不断进步，其巨大财富，足以供养并消费李白、杜甫、吴道子、阎立本、李龟年等巨匠，盛唐气象创造了国族文化艺术的巅峰时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文化与艺术发展，似乎不可避免会带来文弱、享乐、颓废乃至腐朽的生活模式，东、西方皆如此。在东方，唐代末年“黄巢大起义”彻底终结了中国的贵族时代，简单说，就是贵族被杀光了，“天街踏尽公卿骨”。自唐代以后，中国就再无贵族，进入庶族地主时代，皇帝和贵戚亦是庶族地主阶层的代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国也类似，从“百年战争”之后到“大革命”之前，法国贵族荣华富贵、骄奢淫逸，过了几百年人间天堂般的生活，创造了惊人的世界顶级文化艺术，同时燃尽了国家财富，导致法国社会和经济崩溃。最终，整个法国的近代贵族集团几乎被终结在断头台上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德意志和英吉利作为日耳曼族群的盎格鲁-撒克逊分支，中世纪武德延续较为长久。这俩族群的军事贵族传统，甚至一直延续到20世纪中叶，直到两次世界大战，机枪、大炮、坦克、轰炸机……在战场上终结了大量英、德军事贵族，欧洲的近代贵族终于式微。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影《Kingsman：The Secret Service（王牌特工）》生动地讲述了这一历史过程：由于大量军事贵族亡于战场，天量贵族财富成为无主财产，CEO们（而非Boss）才促进了欧洲社会的现代化转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代社会，兴起的是精英阶层，而不再是贵族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵族是身份政治、世袭罔替。而精英则强调非身份政治、能力至上、自我奋斗、优胜劣汰。按我们古代的说法是“学而优则仕”，但仅仅学习好还不够，还要善于做事、遵纪守法、有社会担当。现代社会精英：多出自平民阶层，譬如马斯克（Elon Musk），在获得成功之前，还在车库里打过地铺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代精英政治，不像贵族政治那样垄断权力，而是打破阶层固化，开放个体跃升与降维的通道，这对于防止社会僵化、腐化具有重大意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哪怕是坐拥几千亿美金的世界首富马斯克，其儿子里也有不肖的。若不能有效传承、开拓、进取，那就重新归于平庸，而不可能享有贵族的世袭特权，这就是现代精英体制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希望大家尽可能多振奋精神、昂扬上进，尽可能多产生推动社会进步的精英、实现自我价值，少做贵族梦，那概念已经被历史所淘汰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南方周末6件作品获广东新闻奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260282]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 17:29:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月8日，由广东省新闻工作者协会、广东省新闻学会主办的2022年度广东新闻奖、广东省第十五届新闻&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;金梭奖&lt;/span>;金钟奖评选结果揭晓。381件作品获2022年度广东新闻奖，其中一等奖49件、二等奖122件、三等奖210件。10位同志获广东省第十五届新闻&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;金梭奖&lt;/span>;，1位同志获广东省第十五届新闻金钟奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末报社的6件作品获得广东新闻奖。其中，《“文明互鉴·海外对话”汉学家系列访谈》（作者余雅琴、王华震、宋宇、黎衡、朱圆，编辑朱强、刘悠翔、李慕琰）获得系列报道类一等奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末常年关注中华文化的交流互鉴、学术研究、大众传播，该系列报道通过对国际汉学界举足轻重的10位汉学家做长篇访谈，展示其研究成果、学术人生、中国故事等，为其群像立传，向海内外传播其学术成就，促进中外文化交流。这些汉学家来自美、法、德、日等国知名高校和研究机构，治学领域包括文学、艺术、历史、语言学、教育学、哲学社科、科幻等。这是同类选题中少有的成品牌、成系列的深度报道。包含视频在内的该系列报道在南方周末各平台发布，获得良好口碑，并实现了有效国际传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此外，《“并不容易”的监护权变更》（作者冯皓辰，编辑苏有鹏、钱昊平）获得通讯类二等奖，《总有奋不顾身的相信，总要坚韧恒久的勇气》（作者黎衡、李焱鑫，编辑王巍）获得评论类三等奖，《准确理解科学新闻的科学性和社会性》（作者王江涛，编辑卢文炤）获得新闻业务研究类三等奖，《“红树林之城”的超级造林计划》（作者黄思卓，编辑曹海东、冯飞）获得典型报道类三等奖，《共富征途——迎接党的二十大》（作者谢艳霞、张玥、冯叶、周小铃、梅岭，编辑谢艳霞、张玥、冯叶）获得重大主题报道类三等奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在此之前，由中华全国新闻工作者协会主办的第33届中国新闻奖评选结果11月6日揭晓。来自全国各级各类媒体的377件作品获中国新闻奖，其中，特别奖3件，一等奖73件，二等奖114件，三等奖187件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;南方报业获广东新闻奖作品名单如下：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;一等奖（13件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/G8Y1NCHbMmY72XY7TLY3SQo76yUQuUkKJIa9FqZh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2530&quot; height=&quot;4608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/G8Y1NCHbMmY72XY7TLY3SQo76yUQuUkKJIa9FqZh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257713&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;二等奖（23件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/4Tjx0rxWDt6JLeTmIdcKAPRTCxqC4Pr6t441Ql26.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1678&quot; height=&quot;4608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/4Tjx0rxWDt6JLeTmIdcKAPRTCxqC4Pr6t441Ql26.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257714&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;三等奖（34件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/w5cREKCLaVnRcJuXd6Jwue6acaPc7rlWYQq2EOnA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;5334&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/w5cREKCLaVnRcJuXd6Jwue6acaPc7rlWYQq2EOnA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257715&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第33届中国新闻奖获奖全名单：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/eC0eSQ5UHvE6KPytWwufSizNsqJc8BOwgerh5kQY.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1988&quot; height=&quot;1108&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/eC0eSQ5UHvE6KPytWwufSizNsqJc8BOwgerh5kQY.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257717&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/CqbExEjZl6ympnLVG4jwD89ekRNY48BFpg9eu2DV.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;4896&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/CqbExEjZl6ympnLVG4jwD89ekRNY48BFpg9eu2DV.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257721&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6s7kadbWLoOM0ccvBiNpYn9k339ybOXvU4km8Aug.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;5884&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6s7kadbWLoOM0ccvBiNpYn9k339ybOXvU4km8Aug.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257722&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/IxFY5OpQwk4TQ3pbcgVdz0iC4ZuKw5m6Lw9q4NYm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height=&quot;7552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/IxFY5OpQwk4TQ3pbcgVdz0iC4ZuKw5m6Lw9q4NYm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257723&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/PAPDjEYZ2IOzHfIwWT7E2VGFzcjhZEeL1IgwmnXZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;9820&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/PAPDjEYZ2IOzHfIwWT7E2VGFzcjhZEeL1IgwmnXZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257724&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>