<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[浙江国祥 IPO申购前夕暂停，谁欲分享资本盛宴？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258403]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/EzqH3Y4F6QmiFFWlwVxyIw3QnpuhD4Fv75Ob7Szf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/EzqH3Y4F6QmiFFWlwVxyIw3Q npuhD4Fv75Ob7Szf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253745&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Retailers play cards on the exchange. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang, which plans to start subscribing in the secondary market on October 9, 2023, due to Public opinion surged, and the Shanghai Stock Exchange actually stopped the IPO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, the first day of resumption of work after the holiday, the Shanghai Stock Exchange issued a response to reporters&#39; questions, saying that in the spirit of being responsible for the market and investors, it would respond to the situation reported by the self-media and treat Zhejiang Guoxiang Conduct a special inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the prospectus, Zhejiang Guoxiang was established in 2009 and is headquartered in Shaoxing City. It is mainly engaged in the research and development, production and sales of industrial and commercial central air-conditioning special equipment. It has served Luxshare Precision, BYD, and Ningde Well-known customers and projects in various industries such as Times, Hangzhou Metro Group, Shanghai Ruijin Hospital, and Beijing Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2015, Zhejiang Guoxiang was listed on the New Third Board, and submitted prospectus materials to the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Science and Technology Innovation Board twice at the end of 2016 and in 2020, but the IPO failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Zhejiang Guoxiang once again impacted the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange. It took 159 days to obtain approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission for its IPO registration, which was just one step away from success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, Zhejiang Guoxiang announced an issue price of 68.07 yuan per share, with an issue price-to-earnings ratio of 51.29 times. The plan was to open subscriptions on October 9. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, after a short holiday, the clamor that its issue price was too high has become louder and louder. In addition, there have been doubts about Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s secondary listing of the same asset in the past, and the controversy has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, the Shanghai Stock Exchange once again issued a response to Zhejiang Guoxiang’s suspension of IPO issuance, introduced the Shanghai Stock Exchange’s preliminary review and supervision of the company, and stated that in response to the market and the majority of investors, Concerned, the Shanghai Stock Exchange will seriously organize a special inspection of Zhejiang Guoxiang and will decide on follow-up work based on the results of the special inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did Zhejiang Guoxiang cause public outrage? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Second listing of the same asset? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the prospectus, Zhejiang Guoxiang’s assets come indirectly from Zhejiang Guoxiang Refrigeration Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Guoxiang Refrigeration), which is the first Taiwan-funded enterprise listed on the A-share market. , which is quite symbolic in the mainland capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taihai.com reported in 2008 that the parent company of Guoxiang Refrigeration was Guoxiang Refrigeration Machinery Company, which was established in Taoyuan, Taiwan in 1966. It was the largest manufacturer of industrial refrigeration and air-conditioning equipment in Taiwan at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above report stated that in 1995, Chen Hegui, chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration Machinery Company, went to Zhejiang to invest and established Guoxiang Refrigeration as a joint venture with Zhejiang Shaoxing Refrigeration Equipment Factory. After that, Chen Tianlin succeeded his father Chen Hegui and became the chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration. Guoxiang Refrigeration was listed on the A-share market in 2003 with the stock code 600340. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to subjective and objective factors such as poor operating conditions, Guoxiang Refrigeration suffered continuous losses in 2007 and 2008. In May 2009, it was issued a delisting risk warning and became *ST Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2009, Guoxiang Refrigeration announced that it planned to sell out all its existing assets and liabilities through major asset swaps and the issuance of shares to Xingfu Foundation, and at the same time inject the shares held by Xingfu Foundation into Real estate development and regional development business assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month ago, Chen Tianlin resigned as chairman of Guoxiang Refrigeration, and Chen Genwei served as chairman and general manager of Guoxiang Refrigeration. Chen Genwei has been working for Guoxiang Refrigeration since 1997, and has successively served as section chief of the Quality Assurance Department, Secretary of the Board of Directors, and Director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2011, Guoxiang Refrigeration Asset Restructuring received approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission, and the real estate company China Fortune Land Development successfully used its shell to go public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since China Fortune Land Development’s main business is real estate investment and development and has no intention of operating central air-conditioning business, in 2012, Zhejiang Guoxiang Holdings Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Guoxiang Holdings) controlled by Chen Genwei and his wife used 80 million to acquire the transfer Zhejiang Guoxiang has 100% equity, and Chen Genwei has also been promoted to chairman of Zhejiang Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Retailers therefore questioned Zhejiang Guoxiang’s IPO, which was considered a secondary listing of the same asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, during the IPO application process of Zhejiang Guoxiang in 2020 and this time, the Shanghai Stock Exchange made inquiries about the source of Zhejiang Guoxiang’s assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the Shanghai Stock Exchange asked Zhejiang Guoxiang to explain the proportion of its assets from the original listed company in its current assets and the role of its production and operations in its inquiry. It also asked the company to combine Past cases in the capital market indicate whether there are similar precedents in which the assets of a listed company were reorganized and then relisted with the same assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang listed a number of similar cases in its reply, such as Sichuan Instruments (603100.SH), Leon Micro (605358.SH), etc., saying that their main assets came from listed companies’ acquisitions. out assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the secondary listing, the Shanghai Stock Exchange stated in its response to reporters on October 9 that after review, the transactions of this part of the assets occurred in 2011 and 2012, and the total book assets related to the acquisition at the end of 2022 The relevant net fixed assets accounted for 15% and 0.06% of Zhejiang Guoxiang’s total existing assets respectively. Zhejiang Guoxiang has shifted from focusing on commercial central air conditioners to mainly industrial central air conditioners. Its business, products, and technology Substantial changes have taken place in research and development, personnel and sales models, actual controllers and management. At the same time, there is basically no overlap between Zhejiang Guoxiang’s sales customers and suppliers and *ST Guoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding listing standards, the Shanghai Stock Exchange quoted Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus, saying that its cumulative net profit in the past three years was 387 million yuan, its net profit in the most recent year was 186 million yuan, and its cash generated from operating activities in the past three years The cumulative net flow was 600 million yuan, and the cumulative operating income was 4.226 billion yuan. &quot;Zhejiang Guoxiang complies with the first set of motherboard listing standards.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/IMsplTUYVODSvJG1Hixdfl4GpDumv6wy93BY5qAF.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/IMsplTUYVODSvJG1Hixdfl4GpDumv6wy93BY5qAF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 253746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The closing stock index of the day is displayed on an LED screen outside a building in Lujiazui, Shanghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Super Raising&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;1.4&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Billion Yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to the secondary listing, the trigger for IPO controversy is also the excessive issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s issue price is 68.07 yuan per share, and the issue price-to-earnings ratio is 51.29 times. Such a high issue price was also beyond Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that the company is expected to use 737 million yuan in raised funds for this fundraising project. Based on the issue price of 68.07 yuan per share and the number of new shares issued of 35.0234 million shares, if this issuance is successful, Zhejiang Guoxiang is expected to raise a total of 2.384 billion yuan, after deducting the issuance expenses (excluding value-added tax) of 227.8 million yuan, The net amount of funds raised is expected to be 2.156 billion yuan, with an excess of 1.419 billion yuan raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s issue price-to-earnings ratio of 51.29 times is not only higher than the industry average, but also higher than the comparable companies in the industry it lists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;special equipment manufacturing industry (C35)&quot; in which it is located, as of September 26, 2023, the static average price-to-earnings ratio of C35 in the CSI Index industry in the past month was 27.81 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang disclosed five comparable companies in the same industry. After excluding the extreme value Jialitu (180.3 times) and the loss-making Yimikang, the average price-to-earnings ratio of the remaining three companies in 2022 is 45.82 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market criticized Zhejiang Guoxiang’s operating performance as being unable to match the issue price. Within the industry, Zhejiang Guoxiang has not yet occupied a dominant position, and its sustained profitability has been repeatedly questioned by the Shanghai Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang stated in the prospectus that since its establishment, it has been focusing on the research and development, production and sales of industrial and commercial central air-conditioning. After years of efforts, it has grown into a relatively large player in the industrial and commercial central air-conditioning industry. An enterprise with high brand competitiveness. However, the company&#39;s market shares in 2020, 2021 and 2022 are only 1.20%, 1.28% and 1.77% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that Zhejiang Guoxiang’s revenue increased from 470 million yuan to 834 million yuan from 2015 to 2019. However, its net profit fluctuated greatly, which were 53.3466 million yuan, 47.1391 million yuan, and 28.3440 yuan respectively. Ten thousand yuan, 43.937 million yuan, 67.3813 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years of the epidemic from 2020 to 2022, Zhejiang Guoxiang not only increased its revenue steadily, but its net profit also increased significantly, reaching 99.7907 million yuan, 101.3427 million yuan and 185.9114 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this IPO issuance process, the first question in the implementation letter of the Shanghai Stock Exchange Review Center required Zhejiang Guoxiang to disclose the matching of its net profit growth in 2022 with the company&#39;s revenue growth, and analyze the rapid revenue growth in 2022 The main logic of growth and the sustainability of future growth, and reveal the risks of unsustainable rapid growth and provide reminders of major matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Shanghai Stock Exchange Listing Committee meeting held on June 19, the Shanghai Stock Exchange once again required Zhejiang Guoxiang to explain whether its ability to continue operating has been significantly improved and improved based on the fact that its assets came from the original listed company *ST Guoxiang. , whether the relevant risk disclosure is sufficient. At the same time, the sponsor representative is requested to express clear opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The motivation for institutions to create new products at high prices&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The high issuance price is reported by institutional investors during the inquiry period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement shows that a total of 8,732 placement targets managed by 800 offline investors participated in Zhejiang Guoxiang’s preliminary inquiry. The quotation range is 7.80 yuan/share-103.50 yuan/share, corresponding to the total number of proposed subscriptions. The total number of shares sold was 51.074 billion, and the overall offline subscription multiple was 2,700 times the initial offline issuance scale before the callback. Quotation subscriptions were relatively active. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After excluding invalid quotes and the highest quotes, there are still 733 investors, corresponding to 8,547 allotment objects. The highest excluded quotes refer to allotment objects whose subscription price is higher than 81.49 yuan/share, and allotment objects whose subscription price is 81.49 yuan/share and whose planned subscription quantity is less than 3.8 million shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lower of the average and the median quotes from offline investors is 73.6 yuan/share. Among them, the median quotations from public funds, fund management companies, insurance companies, securities companies, futures companies, trust companies and private equity funds are all around 74 yuan, which is higher than the final issuance price of 69.07 yuan per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among public funds, this is especially true for those who quote high prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seventeen products of Golden Eagle Fund quoted a high price of 92.52 yuan per share, a 33.9% premium to the issue price, and were all eliminated. 29 products under Harvest Fund quoted 81.94 yuan per share. They were eliminated because the number of planned subscriptions was less than 3.8 million shares. Another 122 products with the same quotation met the subscription quantity requirements and were shortlisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the valid quotes, Wells Fargo Fund (quoted at 80.75 yuan/share), Chuangjin Hexin (quoted at 80 yuan/share), Shenwan Lingxin Fund (quoted at 79 yuan/share), ICBC Credit Suisse Fund and CCB Credit Fund (quoted at 79 yuan/share) The quotations of public funds such as 78 yuan/share) far exceeded the issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is a company whose performance is really not impressive so sought after by institutions? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A private equity fund person explained to Southern Weekend reporters that the issue price pricing rules are relatively complex, involving the average and median of institutional quotations, and the average and median of quotations from social security funds, pension insurance, etc. Compare. The inquiry for new stocks only eliminates 1% of the high prices. As long as the quotation is slightly higher than the average price, institutions can be shortlisted and finally get the new stocks at the issue price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If new stocks in the market have a good profit-making effect recently, or the subject of new stocks is popular, institutions will increase their quotations to ensure shortlisting. The person said frankly, &quot;Regardless of the finalists, we all point to other institutions to look at the fundamentals. In fact, no one looks at it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main board’s new stock inquiry and pricing mechanism originally had an invisible ceiling of 23 times the price-earnings ratio. After the comprehensive registration system reform was launched, the company&#39;s issuance price was liberalized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, market voices generally believed that companies to be listed with good development prospects would obtain higher valuation levels in the issuance of new shares, and companies with relatively limited development space would see their valuations return quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Former senior sponsor Wang Jiyue told Southern Weekend reporters that after the new IPO policy, the supply of new shares was low and the risk of new shares was expected to be low, so prices went up. Not only the institutional quotations of Zhejiang Guoxiang are high, but the overall quotations of new shares are also high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are some irresponsible quotations.” Wang Jiyue analyzed that the reason why institutions quoted high prices was because they expected that the stock price would not break within a few days after listing. Loss is a small probability event and does not affect the interests of fund managers. , the quotation is not binding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Institutional quotations have become based on transaction expectations, rather than based on the company’s true value.” In his view, the meaning of the existence of institutional investors is to guide correct quotations. &quot;The power to set the issue price is in the hands of institutions, and there are not many practical constraints on institutional quotations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Institutional investors who participated in the inquiry also attributed the motivation for high-priced new products to &quot;making money from new products in the near future.&quot; Private equity fund Shiva Mavericks has 6 products quoted at 73.65 yuan, which were shortlisted for Zhejiang Guoxiang’s effective quotes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Hong, the manager of Shiva Mavericks Fund who is known as the &quot;Ten Billion Private Equity Boss&quot;, responded to the quotation in Xueqiu and said, &quot;Monguli will have an obvious effect of making new money in the future, and it will sell on the first day of trading.&quot; The average profit is 80%, so the main purpose is to seek finalists for quotations, and don’t care about the price. If you lose money after a few losses, then you have to be selective and quote a lower price.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liang Hong’s view, the problem lies in the high-priced IPOs, rather than in recruiting new ones. &quot;Some people say that this or that company is not worth the money, so why should they pay a high price? I want to know even more, why do they take over the market at a high price after there is so much money after listing? If not, why should I call you?&quot; At present, Liang Hong is Messages have been deleted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after the new shares are listed, who will take over? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xueqiu user &quot;Xiaye Guapeng&quot; cleverly discovered that for stocks listed at the end of each quarter, through the top ten circulating shareholders disclosed by them, we can know what the new shares will be after 5 trading days. Which funds are taking over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no limit on the price of new shares in the first five trading days, and they are subject to special regulatory attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this logic, he analyzed 9 stocks that were listed at the end of each quarter in 2022 and 2023, and found that securities companies, which are strongly related to the issuance of new shares, will use their own funds to make large-scale purchases a few days after listing. Buy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Zhiou Technology (301376.SZ) and Guoke Military Industry (688543.SH), which were listed on June 21, 2023, the ten largest circulating shareholders disclosed in the interim report include the securities firm CICC , CITIC Securities, Huatai Securities, Guotai Junan Securities and China Merchants Securities, and they are all new shareholders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Jiyue’s view, high-priced innovation by institutions is not a single issue. &quot;New stock pricing rules, new stock supply and demand, stock circulation ratio, and behavioral finance under the tradition of new stock speculation all need to be taken into consideration.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hundreds of millions of underwriting fees are suspended&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Stock investors also have doubts about Orient Securities (600958.SH), the sponsor of Zhejiang Guoxiang, and believe that Orient Securities has not been diligent and responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Orient Securities’ sponsorship fee for undertaking Zhejiang Guoxiang’s IPO this time is 2 million yuan. In addition, Orient Securities is also the underwriter, and underwriting fees are charged based on a certain proportion of the total funds raised. This is the more important income of Orient Securities in this IPO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus shows that the underwriting fees charged by Orient Securities vary according to the total amount of funds raised, and the rate ratio fluctuates in three levels: 7.50%, 7.70%, and 8.70%, and different fixed fees are also attached. cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Zhejiang Guoxiang’s total fund-raising of 2.384 billion yuan, Orient Securities can receive over 184 million yuan in underwriting fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, the total revenue of Orient Securities’ investment banking business was 741.5 million yuan. Zhejiang Guoxiang’s underwriting fee of nearly 200 million yuan is of great significance to its performance in the second half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, Orient Securities issued an announcement on the investment banking project, stating that the underwriting rate for the Zhejiang Guoxiang issuance was 7.74% as determined through negotiation between the sponsor and the issuer. However, the specific calculation method was not disclosed. Zhejiang Guoxiang&#39;s issuance has been suspended, and Orient Securities has not yet collected underwriting fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhejiang Guoxiang’s prospectus, the company also has indirect equity relationships with Orient Securities and its affiliates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Orient Securities Hande holds 2.74% of the total pre-issuance share capital of Zhejiang Guoxiang, while Shanghai Orient Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Orient Securities, invested 11.11% in Orient Securities Hande. In other words, Orient Securities indirectly holds 0.03% of the shares of Zhejiang Guoxiang before its listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhejiang Guoxiang’s controlling shareholder Guoxiang Holdings holds 16.34%, 14.71%, 4.44% and 12.51% of the capital contributions of Orient Securities Zhoude, Orient Securities Tangde, Orient Securities Xia De, and Orient Securities Hechuang respectively. share. Shanghai Orient Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd., a wholly-owned subsidiary of Orient Securities, holds 15.03%, 19.12%, 18.89% and 19.99% of the investment shares of these four companies respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned five companies named &quot;Orient Securities&quot; are all investment institutions mainly funded by Shanghai Oriental Securities Capital Investment Co., Ltd. and serving as executive partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oriental Securities has been investigated by the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 15, 2016, two penalty decisions issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission disclosed the entire process of creating the &quot;demon stock&quot; of Anshuo Information (300380.SZ), which Oriental Securities was mainly involved in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 30, 2014, a then computer industry researcher from Orient Securities sent an email to the chairman and general manager of Anshuo Information, saying that the stock price of Anshuo Information had fallen to near the issue price and that the value was absolutely underestimated. , expressed the hope to communicate with the company and then recommend it to the organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From June 22, 2014 to April 30, 2015, the then chief analyst of the computer industry at Orient Securities and the above-mentioned researcher used &quot;extremely business scalable, strongly optimistic, and the best quality banking IT&quot; We wrote emails with inductive and exaggerated words such as &quot;Target, Unparalleled, Absolutely Leading&quot;, and sent a total of more than 11,000 emails to 1,279 people in 128 funds, securities firms, private equity and other institutions, disseminating iShares information to carry out Internet financial services and the Internet. financial business situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some fund management companies bought a large amount of iShares Information from November 1, 2014 to May 27, 2015. At the peak, a total of 221 public funds held more than 70% of iShares Information. outstanding shares. Anshuo Information&#39;s stock price rose from 28.30 yuan/share on April 30, 2014 to 450 yuan/share on May 13, 2015, an increase of 15.9 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the China Securities Regulatory Commission opened the case for investigation, the above two Orient Securities employees were ordered to make corrections and were given administrative penalties of 200,000 yuan and 150,000 yuan respectively, and a warning was given to Anshuo Information and the company’s chairman and secretary. , and were fined 600,000 yuan, 300,000 yuan and 200,000 yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[147万名“塔尖”客户金融资产21万亿，“最耀眼明珠”撑起银行逆周期重任]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258401]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the existing mortgage interest rates were reduced in batches&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;Almost all deposit and loan business interest rate spreads fell&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;historical lows&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;very cyclical businesses Do banks still have countercyclical sectors?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The latest &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mid-year reports disclosed by various commercial banks revealed an unusual information&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Researcher from Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Taked relevant data of 12 major banks as samples, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; combined with research reports from professional consulting institutions&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;from &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;People&#39;s Bank of China&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Hereinafter referred to as &quot;private bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Number of clients and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;structure&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Assets per capita&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The development status and influencing factors of private banks were &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; sorted out, compared and analyzed from dimensions such as /span>;&lt;span>;, private bank asset management scale and other dimensions, and it was found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>; overwhelmingly The retail assets under management (AUM) of most commercial banks have performed well. The private banking business, which is considered &quot;the most dazzling jewel in the &lt;span>;crown of the financial industry&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, has bucked the trend and has grown well. Become a strong anti-cyclical sector.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Statistical analysis also found&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, 147&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ten thousand&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;names&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;Private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Customers have 21 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; assets, average assets per household&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The amount reached 1477.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; million&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The overall private travel customer base&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Tend to be younger&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But domestic private banking services are still in their infancy&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Financial asset allocation and non-financial services are far away from the international mature system&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The strong will always be strong&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Five banks&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;private bank AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;all Over&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The number of customers and the scale of&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are undoubtedly the two most direct indicators for observing the business conditions of private banks. Data from 12 listed banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mid-year reports&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; show that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; commercial banks The number of private clients and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; growth rates are both positive&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, and the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;growth rates are the lowest&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; 3.76%,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And there are four banks with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;AUM&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; double-digit growth&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;There are three banks with double-digit growth in customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The head effect is becoming more obvious&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As of the end of June, China Merchants Bank &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China and China Construction Bank &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; four &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The assets under management (AUM) of major state-owned private banks all exceeded 2 trillion yuan, an increase of 5.89 from the end of the previous year&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;-&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12.90%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank, which has the reputation of &quot;King of Retail&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This indicator&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;high&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; achieved 4.02 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, becoming the only one&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;among the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; banks mentioned above&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Private Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bank with AUM exceeding 4 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank Private Bank’s average financial assets per account Up to &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2804.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;10,000&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;almost twice as much as &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The average household value is 14.7799 million yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of the number of private banking customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the above five&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has more than 100,000 customers, accounting for 69.18% of the total private banking customers of the 12 listed banks. Among them, the number of private customers of ICBC, China Construction Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Agricultural Bank of China &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; exceeds 200,000, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Its&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;number of customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; increased by 15.9%, 10.12% and 13.50% respectively&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Much higher than the growth rate of other businesses&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Except&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the above five&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;head banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;In addition, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Ping An Bank, which has been aiming to create a new benchmark for &quot;light banking&quot; in recent years, has also demonstrated its ambition to focus on the private banking field. Data show that as of the end of June, Ping An Bank&#39;s private banking AUM reached 189 million yuan, an increase of 16.3% from the end of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;.&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;The growth rate ranks first among the 12 banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The ratio of private bank AUM to the bank&#39;s retail AUM is as high as 49%. Ranked first among the 12 listed banks;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;its private&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; average AUM per account was 21.7922 million yuan, second only to China Merchants Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Based on the two indicators&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;number of private clients and asset size&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, 12 listed banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;&#39;s&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1.47 million&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private banking&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; customers, with 21 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; assets , the average household assets reached 1477.9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6ecKSHFsvknF6pHq1kj6Gr2jodvJ5CWaPGNbbuyv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1713&quot; height=&quot;2008&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6ecKSHFsvknF6pHq1kj6Gr2jodvJ5CWaPGNbbuyv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253793&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/V13FS5vCfSfCefOeMt6iyydR3UHrpnmyjhFweujC.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1713&quot; height=&quot;1594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/V13FS5vCfSfCefOeMt6iyydR3UHrpnmyjhFweujC.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253792&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private banking clients are getting younger&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The wealth creation effect of the new economy is obvious&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why the number of private clients and asset size buck the trend Growth&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The huge customer base&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is an important condition for the rapid development of the private banking business of the above banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of the year, the &quot;China Banking Industry Private Client Management White Paper 2023&quot; released by the Boston Consulting Group and other institutions mentioned &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt; span>;, in order to bring about the same increase in asset management scale, the bank&#39;s cost of acquiring new customers is five times higher than maintaining old customers, while the profit contribution of existing customers is 16 times that of new customers. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In other words&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, under the same target number, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; compared with &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; other small and medium-sized banks, state-owned banks have more retail customers. The customer acquisition costs required to develop private banking business are relatively small. This can also confirm the principle of the pyramid model commonly used in the field of customer management: that is, a large base of ordinary customers can lay a solid foundation for the cultivation of high-end customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center&#39;s review&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The mid-year report also confirmed this again&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As of the end of June, the corresponding value of the total retail AUM of the four major state-owned banks in industry, agriculture, China and construction &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; was 14 trillion&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;-&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;20 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;; although China Merchants Bank is a joint-stock bank, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;because&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;With many years of deep business strategy in retail business, the bank’s total retail AUM reached 12.84 trillion&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; during the same period, far exceeding other joint-stock banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/iM3Il9BtplHUzjyUOxEHr5lEdbP85EkCnXq8tC5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/iM3Il9BtplHUzjyUOxEHr5lEdbP85EkCnXq8tC5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253750&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Researchers at the Financial Research Center also &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; learned &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; among the above-mentioned 12 listed banks, only China Merchants Bank The threshold &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is determined as &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; “the monthly and daily average fully discounted RMB total assets are 10 million yuan and above” standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The threshold for other banks is mostly &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;600&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;ten thousand yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;However, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the setting of high threshold &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; does not allow China Merchants Bank to operate privately &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Business development brings resistance. Data from the same period show that compared with&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;end&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, China Merchants Bank’s AUM and customers The quantity achieved an increase of 5.89% and 6.21%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9JuMgJLu06PflealulQuK9pb6OLMFVecN1H4EeRT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9JuMgJLu06PflealulQuK9pb6OLMFVecN1H4EeRT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;More interesting Yes&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the midst of economic transformation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the composition of private banking customers has also changed&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Change. China Merchants Bank&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and Bain &amp; Company&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; recently&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; released the &quot;2023 China Private Wealth Report&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;It shows that compared with 2021, in 2023, the proportion of the first generation of wealth creators, directors, supervisors and second generation of the family&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the total number of private banking customers surveyed was respectively 25%, 16% and 12% dropped to 20%, 14% and 9%. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;And &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the proportion of professional people increased from 12% to 17%. Among them, among the two categories of wealth creation generation &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;directors, supervisors and senior management, private banking groups engaged in the new economy accounted for 7% of the total number of private banking customers surveyed&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This reflects the wealth creation effect associated with the rise of the new domestic economy. At the same time, the proportion of people under the age of 40 who engage in private practice has increased from 42% in 2021 to 49%, and the high-net-worth population has become further younger. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center surveyed several large regional private banking branches and found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private customers value Preservation and inheritance of financial assets&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; rather than appreciation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Because they believe that corporate operations have higher risks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;financial assets in private names must be safe&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The above-mentioned report research &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has supported this &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Only&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; accounts for 12%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Among them&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;36% of the people said that “the income is higher than the savings income”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private banking&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Light capital&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Help&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Banks through the cycle&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Private&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;Business&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Why do business firms flock to it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Private banking business is basically an off-balance sheet business for banks, and it takes up little capital&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is a capital-light business&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;. In recent years, when facing problems such as shrinking net interest margins and non-performing assets, the capital-heavy development model driven by the scale of the banking industry has come under pressure. Private banking business is expected to become a new engine for banks&#39; own profit growth and business model transformation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Finance&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Research&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Researcher at the Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Combining&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The 2023 &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mid-year reports of the above-mentioned 12 banks found that ICBC spent a small amount of space describing the profit data of private banks. Data show that as of June 30, the bank&#39;s &quot;Personal Financial Management and Private Banking&quot; category achieved fee and commission income of 14.019 billion yuan, accounting for 17.02% of the bank&#39;s total fee and commission income, ranking second only to &quot; Settlement, clearing and cash management&quot; ranked second. Since this income also involves personal finance items including ordinary customers, it is impossible to make precise statistics on the income of private banking business. The proportion of private banking AUM in retail business AUM in the table below may be evidence of its contribution to the retail business field. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NFNcXkXomvnztAF5ykpJUJPyF5S0fxsfxP20UDBd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/NFNcXkXomvnztAF5ykpJUJPyF5S0fxsfxP20UDBd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Weekend New Researchers at the Financial Research Center believe that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in terms of &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; business categories, private banking business is related to asset management, retail &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;Investment banking and many other businesses. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The establishment of a private banking system has strong extendibility for the operation and management of high-net-worth customers. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As a top retail brand, private banking has a prominent brand spillover effect, which is very important for bank retail business. The advancement will also be of great help. In addition, most of the private banking clients are entrepreneurs, who have diversified needs for investment banking and corporate business. By leading the private sector to the corporate sector, it can also have a strong linkage effect on the investment banking and corporate business lines. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yMbrIwXun5ui95CTO0MULgNQdfEVd7kptfYGJg9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1256&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/yMbrIwXun5ui95CTO0MULgNQdfEVd7kptfYGJg9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From&lt;/ span>;&lt;span>;On the liability side, private bank customers can accumulate a larger proportion of demand deposits and reduce deposit cost rates. On the one hand, high-net-worth customers have greater daily liquidity needs and tend to reserve a certain proportion of demand deposits to meet daily capital needs. On the other hand, high-net-worth customers are important buyers of bank wealth management products and asset management products. Before the establishment of wealth management products, customers&#39; prepaid funds are included in current deposits. Banks can flexibly arrange the issuance period and duration of wealth management products to achieve the purpose of depositing a large number of current deposits and reducing bank liability costs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared financial report data and found that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; years&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ago In 6 months, the deposit interest rate cost of China Merchants Bank&#39;s retail customers was only 1.36%, which is not only far lower than the 2%-2.4% range standard of joint-stock banks of the same size, but even lower than The level of state-owned banks is around 1.7%. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;This proves&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; that when private banking business develops to a certain scale, it will have a positive effect on reducing bank deposit costs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/C8wIZtTf1G95F9pNss8iDxG1mQ6cxWOozLJemKrw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 953&quot; height=&quot;1256&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/C8wIZtTf1G95F9pNss8iDxG1mQ6cxWOozLJemKrw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>; Instruments such as family trusts&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;are mainstream&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Based on the special contributions and demands of private banking clients&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;What financial instruments have commercial banks reserved and innovated for private banking customers&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that as one of the tools in private bank asset allocation pools, family trusts with inheritance and bankruptcy isolation functions are being widely used. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Five major state-owned banks such as Industry, Agriculture, China, Construction, and Communications&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;China Merchants Bank, Ping An Bank, etc.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;Joint-stock banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are all in&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Interim Report&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; for&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The business growth data of the family trust is described. As of the end of June, the cumulative paid-in scale of ICBC Family Trust was 29.18 billion yuan, an increase of 40% from the end of the previous year; the scale of paid-in funds of China Construction Bank was 95.074 billion yuan, an increase of 6.82% from the end of the previous year; the number of Bank of China Family Trust customers increased by 52.5% from the end of the previous year. The scale of Agricultural Bank of China’s family trust business is nearly 80 billion yuan, a net increase of 32 billion yuan from the end of the previous year; the scale of Ping An Bank’s family trust and insurance trust business is 44.086 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 39.3%; the number of family trust business orders of China Merchants Bank exceeds 10,000, and the business scale An increase of 22.79% compared with the end of the previous year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Insurance trusts have leverage and inheritance functions&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; have also become popular configurations in the past two years&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;private firms&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;employees&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; members of the South A researcher at the New Financial Research Center on the Weekend said that due to limited business scope, banks currently establish trusts for private banking customers through cooperation with external trust companies. But for investors, entrusting their personal property through a bank is equivalent to psychologically receiving the bank&#39;s brand endorsement&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the past two years, the number of bank private banking customers and asset size have continued to grow, including the growth of wealth such as family trusts, which shows that in the face of an uncertain environment, high-net-worth individuals are still willing to invest in Wealth is held in the banking system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;2023 China Private Wealth Report&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; also&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mentioned that as the &quot;first rich&quot; group,&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;Private banking clients&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s comprehensive needs have expanded from focusing on individuals, families, and businesses to the fields of social responsibility, public welfare, and charity. They look forward to better charity projects, charitable foundations, charitable trusts, etc. Architectural design services. The survey shows that 73% of high-net-worth individuals have started or are preparing for wealth inheritance. In terms of intergenerational inheritance, the current first-choice method for high-net-worth individuals is to pass on wealth to their children. The purchase of insurance and real estate is expected to be expanded in the future, including the creation of family trusts and corporate equity arrangements. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Private practice&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Still &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;at the junior level Stage&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Benchmarking international private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;What is the level of private banks that are increasingly valued in China&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the financial &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; regulatory authorities first proposed the concept of private banking in 2005, China’s private banking industry has gone through more than ten years&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Process&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the past ten years or so&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; many domestic commercial banks have opened related businesses, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; The scale of assets has grown rapidly. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the meantime&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Although many banks have set up their private banking business separately as a business unit system&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;National vertical management&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;but after the separation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; returned to the large retail system&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;and&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;have the potential to accelerate&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;If we take the mature private banking systems of developed European countries as a reference, domestic private banks are still in their infancy in terms of wealth management coverage and customer service levels. This may be one of the reasons why many domestic banks still put private banking business into the large retail framework and do not conduct separate accounting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As for the development of domestic private banking business, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that we can start from the following three aspects&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; ：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First, strengthen investment research and professional product design capabilities, and enrich the product system. Continue to track customer needs and market changes, and promptly adjust asset allocation strategies and product structures. Improve the level of asset allocation in major categories, achieve regional diversification and asset class diversification through overseas diversified asset allocation, and help investors ensure investment returns and asset value preservation and appreciation;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;The second is to use technology to help build a digital private bank. With the rapid development of technology, the integration of financial technology and wealth management continues to deepen, and its application chain will gradually penetrate from the client side to product development, investment portfolio, valuation management and other product-side links. With the help of financial technology, we provide investment advisors with investment advice, conduct operational warnings, track customer investment progress, and greatly improve the efficiency of private banking services and customer experience;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The third is to attach importance to non-financial businesses . &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Different from traditional wealth management business, the business scope of private banks&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; includes financial services and non-financial businesses, among which non-financial businesses involve very Extensive, including investment consulting, tax planning, daily consumption, medical health, tourism, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the international &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;mature private banking system, consulting management fees generated in the non-financial field are expected to account for 45% of the overall income&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Domestic private banks can use this as a starting point, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;link to various professional institutions&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;create more&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;Profit&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海女童海滩搜寻现“罗生门”，全国究竟有多少“蓝天救援队”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258417]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 20:06:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Blue Sky Rescue Team of Taihe County, Jiangxi Province is conducting a drowning prevention inspection. &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot; Under the banner, brand controversies often arise. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/498a10b00f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/498a10b00f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253788&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Blue Sky Rescue Team of Taihe County, Jiangxi Province conducts a drowning prevention inspection. The banner of &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot; often causes brand controversies. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same uniforms are also called the &quot;Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; by the outside world. These days, two &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Teams&quot; that do not recognize each other have appeared on Shanghai Nanhui New Town Beach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the staff of the Shanghai Blue Sky Emergency Rescue Service Center (hereinafter referred to as the Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center), after a 4 and a half year old girl in Shanghai was lost on the beach on the evening of October 4, 2023, they were rescued the next day. Received search and rescue requests from family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, on October 7, the center announced that the rescue team &quot;originally planned to carry out a search and rescue mission tonight, but it was suspended due to some reasons.&quot; The statement also stated that any subsequent activities carried out at the rescue site in the name of &quot;Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; will have nothing to do with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, another team &quot;BSR Blue Sky Rescue&quot; with the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot; logo also released news to the media, saying that the above statement was issued by another group of people without authorization and did not represent the Blue Sky Rescue Team. Officially, the Blue Sky Rescue Team has been searching and rescuing the 4-year-old girl at the scene and has not stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters discovered that behind the conflict between the two parties was the &quot;separation&quot; dispute between Blue Sky Rescue Team that lasted for several years. Zhang Yong, the founder of Blue Sky Rescue Team, and Cao Weiwei, the current legal representative of Beijing Blue Sky Rescue, both advocated The legitimacy of himself and the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; - the &quot;Blue Sky&quot; brand, has become the focus of competition between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Simultaneous search and rescue&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center told Southern Weekend reporters that on October 5, they were entrusted by their families to go to Nanhui New City Beach to carry out search and rescue, and they The search and rescue operation was reported to the Pudong New Area Emergency Management Bureau. &quot;After dark, we also use drones (lighting search and rescue).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff member did not reveal the specific reason for the evacuation on the 7th: &quot;It&#39;s not convenient to say, I just evacuated that area.&quot; At present, &quot;the government has been conducting search and rescue operations.&quot; But the staff member also said that he had also seen other &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; at the search and rescue site in the past two days. &quot;The other party started to think that we were together, but I said no. He also wondered, why is there another Blue Sky (rescue team)?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff member said angrily that at some disaster sites before, Some rescue teams will carry out operations under the name of &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot;, some will raise funds in WeChat groups, but the payee will be a personal account, and some will charge a fee to kill, so that they have to report to the police. Report the crime. &quot;When doing charity, do charity well. If you are really capable, don&#39;t use other people&#39;s names.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was indeed another &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; involved in the rescue at the scene. On the afternoon of October 9, He Dongping told Southern Weekend reporters that as the captain of the Shanghai Mobile Blue Sky Rescue Team, he had been involved in the search and rescue of the girl from the 5th to the 9th, entrusted by the family, and the search and rescue is still ongoing. He Dongping introduced that he is also a member of the &quot;BSR Blue Sky Rescue&quot; mentioned above. &quot;BSR&quot; is the English abbreviation of Blue Sky Rescue Team. However, he had a &quot;bad opinion&quot; about the evacuation of another team, the Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center, from the search and rescue site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qichacha information shows that the Shanghai Blue Sky Emergency Rescue Service Center was established in July 2014, and its legal representative is Yang Chunming. For a long time, this was the only social organization registered as Blue Sky Rescue in Shanghai until 2023. On September 21, 2019, a private, non-enterprise organization named &quot;Shanghai Baoshan Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; was registered and established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Dongping introduced that Shanghai Baoshan Blue Sky Rescue Team is the name they registered with the civil affairs department. Shanghai Mobile Blue Sky Rescue Team, Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Team, Shanghai Qingpu Blue Sky Rescue Team and Shanghai College Student Blue Sky Rescue Team are all The team under its jurisdiction. On weekdays, these four teams are coordinated by an internal organization called the &quot;Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Coordination Center&quot;, and each team carries out rescue work according to different functions and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Dongping said that the brands of the four &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot; teams in Shanghai were authorized from the Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team. He and his teammates have been doing search and rescue for many years under the name &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; before. However, before 2023, the local civil affairs department cannot register non-governmental organizations ending with the word &quot;team&quot;. &quot;In order to justify their name,&quot; they officially registered in 2023. The civil affairs department registered as the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Dongping believes that although the Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center has exactly the same costumes as them, in fact, &quot;the authorization given to them was canceled many years ago.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to He Dongping, the search and rescue scene was stormy and the waves were strong. Staff from government departments once came to them to verify which team was the real Blue Sky Rescue Team, as well as the team’s skills and equipment. “We told them truthfully. After that, I asked them to leave.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Competing for &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters discovered that the Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center is also a private non-enterprise organization registered with the civil affairs department. The difference between them is actually that they belong to different blue sky rescue systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The list of Shanghai Blue Sky Rescue Center and its team members is listed on the website &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Information Disclosure Platform&quot;; the list of personnel of the four blue sky rescue teams including the Shanghai Mobile Blue Sky Rescue Team is posted on the website &quot;Blue Sky Rescue .China” on. Through the domain name retrieval system and Tianyancha, the owners of the above two domain names are Chi Xiang, the legal representative of Guangdong Blue Sky Rescue Team, and He Dongping, the legal representative of Shanghai Little Savior Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The information published on the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Information Disclosure Platform&quot; shows that Zhang Yong is the commander-in-chief of the Blue Sky Rescue Team; &quot;Blue Sky Rescue. China&quot; shows that Cao Weiwei is the person in charge and captain of the brand management of the Blue Sky Rescue Team . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, the country&#39;s earliest Blue Sky Rescue Team was registered with the Beijing Civil Affairs Bureau, becoming China&#39;s first private, non-enterprise rescue team with independent legal person qualifications. Zhang Yong, who proposed the establishment of the Blue Sky Rescue Team, has long served as the legal representative of the Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Beijing Blue Sky&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/b3e2a93676.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;488&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/b3e2a93676.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two different national blue sky rescue platforms. Network screenshot&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/74d72032e4.png&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/74d72032e4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253790&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Two different national blue sky rescue platforms. Internet screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in 2020, Beijing Blue Sky’s board members underwent drastic changes. According to the minutes of the Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team board of directors released by the WeChat public account &quot;BJBSR&quot; (the name of the public account at the time was &quot;Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot;), on July 27 of that year, Zhang Yong resigned as captain and legal representative at the board meeting. position, the board of directors also elected Cao Weiwei as vice chairman and legal representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Zhang Yong later did not admit the authenticity of the meeting minutes. According to the China Judgment Documents Network, Zhang Yong once filed a lawsuit against Beijing Lantian regarding the minutes of the board of directors that &quot;expelled&quot; him, requesting that the four meeting minutes be found to be invalid. Zhang Yong claimed that Cao forged the signature on the minutes of the board of directors. However, the court believed that the evidence submitted by Zhang Yong was insufficient to prove his claim and ruled that Zhang Yong lost the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the WeChat public account &quot;Yuanshan Shuo&quot; has become the account actually operated by Zhang Yong. On December 23, 2020, &quot;Yuanshan Theory&quot; explained the whole incident, saying that Beijing Lantian discovered huge financial loopholes during its audit at the beginning of that year. After investigation, the target was Cao Weiwei, who was the captain of the Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team at the time, and it was decided to expel Cao Weiwei from the Blue Sky Rescue System. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Zhang Yong ended up being the one who was &quot;fired&quot;. In February 2022, the legal representative of Beijing Blue Sky was changed to Cao Weiwei. In April of the same year, Zhang Yong posted a video on &quot;Yuanshan Shuo&quot;. In the video, he was wearing a dark blue uniform of the Blue Sky Rescue Team. He raised many questions about Cao Weiwei, who had served as his assistant, saying that he was seeking personal gain. By stealing official seals, forging materials, etc., the legal representative of Beijing Lantian was registered as an individual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 31, 2023, the official WeChat public account of the &quot;Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; issued a statement announcing the removal of Chairman Zhang Yong, the removal of director positions and expulsion from the team, and the election of Cao Weiwei as Chairman. On October 1, the public account issued another statement explaining that the reason why Zhang Yong was fired from Beijing Blue Sky was &quot;violation of discipline.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cao Weiwei explained to Southern Weekend reporters that there were many reasons for expelling Zhang Yong, including &quot;personal issues&quot; and his self-proclaimed &quot;captain&quot; who violated relevant regulations that social groups cannot be managed vertically. &quot;To put it bluntly, he is doing it outside with other people now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Relationship between the headquarters and local teams&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the above disputes are Beijing&#39;s &quot;Blue Sky Headquarters&quot; and Blue Sky Rescue in various places. &quot;Brand licensing&quot; relationship between teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s private rescue teams were originally composed of outdoor sports enthusiasts. After experiencing the 2008 Wenchuan earthquake and the 2010 Yushu earthquake, the private rescue force gradually developed into a large scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Regulations on the Registration and Management of Social Groups&quot; stipulates that social groups are not allowed to establish regional branches. Therefore, both Zhang Yongfang and Cao Weifang have stated that there is no hierarchical affiliation between the more than 2,000 registered Blue Sky Rescue Teams and Beijing Blue Sky. However, the Beijing Blue Sky dispute will still affect other Blue Sky rescue teams across the country through some intangible assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, &quot;BJBSR&quot; stated that the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Information Disclosure Platform&quot; that the National Blue Sky Rescue Team has used for several years has belonged to Chi Xiang&#39;s personal company, and Beijing Blue Sky terminated its cooperation with Chi Xiang in 2020 . Currently, Beijing Blue Sky holds the copyright and patent rights of the Blue Sky Rescue Team, which are well-known to the public, such as the &quot;BSR Blue Sky Rescue Round Logo&quot;, BSR Square Logo, and Blue Sky Team Uniforms. Information about Zhang Yong&#39;s Blue Sky Rescue Team is disclosed through the &quot;Blue Sky Rescue Information Disclosure&quot; Published through channels such as &quot;Platform&quot; and &quot;Yuanshan Shuo&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 30, &quot;Yuanshan Shuo&quot; announced that the Blue Sky Rescue Team would change the VI logo system and rescue phone number. Many Blue Sky teams from various places, including the Shanghai Blue Sky Emergency Rescue Service Center, responded one after another. The next day, the &quot;Beijing Blue Sky Rescue Team&quot; issued a response stating that &quot;the relevant signs and logos of the Blue Sky Rescue Team have not been updated or changed&quot; and once again emphasized that Zhang Yongshi was &quot;fired&quot; and &quot;removed&quot; from Beijing Blue Sky for &quot;violating discipline&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the &quot;separation&quot;, in 2014, Blue Sky Rescue Team formulated the &quot;Fuyang Convention&quot; and established the brand licensing model of &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot;. Beijing Blue Sky is the brand holder and maintains the national system through the structure of &quot;Beijing Team-Provincial Brand Supervisors-Local Blue Sky Teams&quot;. Any locality that is willing to form a team will submit an application, and Beijing Blue Sky will send a liaison officer to review and inspect the application. Those who meet the Blue Sky team building standards will be approved to form a team. Beijing Blue Sky authorizes it to use the name and logo of the Blue Sky Rescue Team, and sets up &quot;brand supervisors&quot; in each province, who are responsible for supervising whether the Blue Sky Rescue Team in each province carries out activities in accordance with the system stipulated by Beijing Blue Sky. If it fails, it will be removed. Local teams have the obligation to implement the various management systems of the Blue Sky Rescue Team and adhere to the development philosophy. However, people, finances, and materials are independently managed by the local rescue teams. The headquarters does not interfere with the regular operations of each team in normal times. It only requires that when conducting unified rescue. The unit obeys the dispatch and command of the headquarters and frontline headquarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years since then, the Blue Sky Rescue System has developed rapidly across the country. Some teams and personnel have chosen to withdraw, and more volunteers want to join. But from the actual legal status, the Blue Sky headquarters is equal to the Blue Sky teams across the country. Zhang Yong once explained that private rescue teams can register with the local civil affairs department to become a &quot;certain blue sky rescue&quot; organization. If this team does not want to join the blue sky rescue system after registration, or has withdrawn from the blue sky rescue system, it can still continue to use it. The registered name of &quot;Blue Sky Rescue&quot;. When they carry out activities, they do not need to assign tasks through the headquarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cao Weiwei explained to Southern Weekend reporters that &quot;brand management&quot; is a kind of intentional cooperation. Unified trademarks and team uniforms are for resource sharing and common ideas among different team members. In addition, Beijing Blue Sky cannot restrict the behavior of teams from various places through other means, &quot;it all depends on the spirit of volunteerism.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But some civilian rescue team staff have different perspectives. Li Yanzhao, an early member of the Blue Sky Rescue Team and captain of the Qingdao Red Cross Rescue Team, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that many private rescue teams need &quot;Blue Sky&quot; because it has a high social reputation. Relying on this &quot;brand&quot;, many times they can &quot;protect yourself&quot;. Li Yanzhao left the Blue Sky Rescue Team in his early years because he disagreed with the Fuyang Convention. In his opinion, compared with the unified &quot;Blue Sky&quot; brand, what the private rescue team actually needs most is &quot;professional and standardized operation and rescue.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[入职三天因“氛围不好”走人：要分清是公司不行还是自己不适应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258393]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a post viewed by more than 5 million people on the Internet has aroused heated discussion: A young man has been working for three days because of the atmosphere of the unit. It’s not easy to leave your job. As soon as this topic came up, countless netizens started a heated debate on the working atmosphere and salary and benefits: some said that the working atmosphere is very important and is the bottom line of being a human being; some believed that working is just to make money, and as long as the treatment is good, you should endure it. Just have to endure it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the working atmosphere or salary is more important is a matter of opinion. There is no unified standard answer. But everyone should pay attention: the working atmosphere cannot be defined simply as &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad&quot;. The key is whether it suits you personally. When considering whether you are suitable or not, you cannot rely on your own vague feelings, but must have measurable standards, such as: industry prospects, company development, leadership ability and charm, teamwork, nature of work, job division, your own suitability, and Salary level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it is a sunset industry, a company that lacks a future, a strong bureaucracy, widespread flattery, team intrigues, a depressing working atmosphere, fierce competition and other truly bad operating conditions, there is nothing wrong with choosing to leave. And habitat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if the industry is booming, the company has a good future, the company is full of vigor, the leadership and business backbones are strong, the teamwork is close, the relationship between colleagues is harmonious, the competition is fierce but the system is fair, and rewards and punishments are clear... it&#39;s just that It is not good to easily give up a hard-won offer based on some vague feelings because you are temporarily unsuitable, unable to keep up with the rhythm, and your self-esteem is temporarily frustrated. After all, it is difficult to fully and objectively understand a company and related industries after only a few days of employment. Frequent employment and resignation within a short period of time will also have a negative impact on an individual&#39;s credibility in the workplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 20 years ago, when I was young, I had several experiences of leaving my job quickly after a short time in the job. This was because I felt that the company was small, the equipment was backward, and the business it undertook was also small. The lower end is not good for your future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I had the opportunity to join a 4A advertising company. I was very frustrated at first. The working atmosphere was not good. The &quot;senior creative&quot; was unwilling to teach a new &quot;design assistant&quot; like me. The creative director (Creative Director) was basically Don&#39;t look at me seriously. However, seeing so many award-winning works in the company, the advertising agencies of large companies, the profound insights of CDs and SCs in analyzing problems during meetings, and the many Apple &quot;Macintosh&quot; graphics workstations in the creative department... I feel that I am lucky to be in the company. As long as people don’t forcefully kick me out of this prestigious creative enterprise, I must stay and learn all their skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, when I became the creative director, I also faced the problem of new employees leaving within a few days of joining. The reason was: I felt that the big brothers and sisters in the company did not respect them enough. This new employee was in school. He had served as a cadre of the student union at that time, and other classmates were probably polite to him and were used to it. Suddenly he entered a company and became the bottom of the team. The psychological gap was too big. This is not a &quot;bad atmosphere&quot; in the company, but a &quot;bad mentality&quot; on his part. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A HR friend from a headhunting company once said to me: Do you plan to be a part-time worker for a long time, or will you be able to do it yourself in the future? The way you deal with it in the workplace is different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you plan to be a part-time worker for a long time and eventually become a professional manager, then in the early stages of your career experience, you should change jobs frequently to enrich your experience and look for opportunities as much as possible. As you gradually mature, you will need to slow down the frequency of job changes in order to accumulate your own workplace personality. Because the headhunting market is now all connected to the Internet, the boss and the board of directors have increasingly strict requirements on the workplace ethics of senior managers. The previous &quot;meritocracy&quot; has gradually developed into &quot;both ability and political integrity&quot;. In the early days of starting a business, I was still rampant in an immature market, so of course I advocated &quot;meritocracy&quot;. Now, as those with successful careers are getting older, they have to consider whether their foundation will be passed on to the &quot;second or third generation&quot; in the future. Therefore, their employment methods have also begun to select harvest-type talents to avoid &quot;restless&quot; talents. People rise to the top. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you plan to do it yourself in the future, you must find a company that is large enough and complex enough, fully understand how an industry operates, how a company operates, and understand the market and people in the workplace. How do you survive? The focus is on observing the market, understanding people&#39;s hearts, and understanding human nature, not &quot;working atmosphere&quot; or &quot;salary benefits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This HR friend also believes that &quot;college students&quot; should be cautious when starting a business. If they have just graduated from college and do not understand the market and have no insight into human nature, they will go into debt to start a business and even use up their parents&#39; pension. That&#39;s not good. Tens of millions of college students graduate every year around the world. How many Jobs and Musks are there? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;College students should find employment first. Even if they change jobs a few times, experience some things in the world, get a preliminary understanding of the market, get in touch with complex human nature, and then start their own business, the probability of success will be higher. Even so, we do not advocate &quot;resigning after three days of employment&quot;, because in three days, you can&#39;t learn anything, you can&#39;t understand anything, and you can&#39;t even find out what problems the company has. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[往事琐忆丨人来人往]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/EsoGMZ7gxCvPcnc1mEkEuGnUkMgCc7JAfXCjhMRQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;539&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/EsoGMZ7gxCvPcnc1mEkEuGnUk MgCc7JAfXCjhMRQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253655&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Campbell Soup cans. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Green Leaves&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Car driving on Prince Edward Road, Kowloon , during the afternoon rush hour, it was suddenly blocked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is nothing to do at this time, so I have to calm down. There is no way to advance or retreat anyway, so why be upset? Looking outside the car, there are trees on both sides, and all kinds of trees are fluttering in the wind under the sun. There are large clumps of green leaves with varying shapes, some pointed, some round, &amp;nbsp;some long, some short. Probably no one would pay attention to green leaves in normal times. Only in this season when there are no flowers to enjoy, only when the heat is overwhelming and you happen to be in an air-conditioned car, can you enjoy them so easily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leaves, lush and small, swayed in the wind. Under the sunlight, they flickered in the sun, as if thousands of small mirrors were vying for beauty. How many times have I passed by this scene? Why do I always turn a blind eye to this scene? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As people grow up, there are many times when they turn a blind eye and turn a blind eye. The rigid daily rhythm has dulled the once sharp mind, and it is no longer possible to feel the subtle and wonderful gifts in life. I don’t know how to cherish everything I have, nor do I think it will be lost in an instant. I always think that everything is inevitable. What is there today will still be there tomorrow. When it is lost in an instant, I am shocked to realize why I didn&#39;t take advantage of it in the first place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greenery outside the window reminds me of the years when I was studying in Taiwan when I was young. Materials were really scarce at that time, and broken appliances were repaired again and again; watches had to be worn for a lifetime; there were only three or two pieces of clothing, and they were passed down from brother to brother and from sister to sister. Still, it was a good time. For example, when we were in art class, the teacher often taught us to be ingenious, develop our creativity, and create magnificent and colorful pictures with limited materials. Once, let us draw leaves. The method is to first go to the wild to collect all kinds of green leaves, and then lay out the various leaves on white drawing paper according to your own preference, then cut out a piece of the old screen window to use as a sieve, and lightly paint it with dark and light watercolors. The colors pass through the fine grid and fall on the painting paper like rain and dew. Then the green leaves were uncovered one after another, and each time they were painted with different colors. Finally, a masterpiece with vivid patterns and brilliant colors was finally formed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, I have fallen in love with leaves. I like to look at flowers and don’t forget to admire leaves. At that time, I lived in a large courtyard on Heping East Road in Taipei. There were several simple bungalows built in the courtyard, and several families lived there. The martial arts novelist Gu Long also lived there when he was a child. He didn&#39;t like to study and only wanted to write novels. , everyone called him &quot;the son of the Xiong family&quot;. In the middle of the yard is a public open space where chickens are raised and dogs are let out. The remaining narrow corners are filled with some inconspicuous flowers and plants. I don&#39;t know who planted them. There is an oleander tree next to the public toilet. It has bright pink flowers, pointed and long leaves, dark green leaves and light green backs. Several canna plants were planted beside the ditch, some red and some yellow, with egg-elliptical leaves. Although the variety is ordinary, it has swayed in the morning and sunset, adding a lot of interest to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Taipei at that time, there was a lot of farmland and greenery everywhere. Before moving to Dazayuan, I lived in a place called &quot;Liuzhangli&quot; (what a pastoral name). There was only a fence between the residence and the large farmland. The fence is covered with morning glories. Every sunrise, the purple flowers are in full bloom, resembling trumpets, and the leaves are tender and green, smiling and waving in the morning breeze. No wonder this flower is called Morning Glory in English. In that rice field, you can see buffaloes working hard and farmers working hard all year round. Speaking of green, there is no more beautiful scene than the beautiful spring seedlings and the green color that fills the eyes! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the way home from school, I often see piles of large green leaves on the streets and in puddles, similar in shape to lotus leaves, but I have never seen a lotus flower in bloom. When I asked an adult, I found out that they were taro leaves. Although taro leaves are ordinary, it turns out that this leaf has a special feature. Whenever it rains, the falling raindrops are sprinkled on the leaf surface, and they will condense into water droplets, rolling back and forth, just like diamonds. When the sun shines after the rain, It looks even more dazzling. I remember once I wrote this scenery into a composition &quot;After the Rain&quot;, which was greatly praised by my class teacher (called a grade teacher in Taiwan) Chen Wenbin. This inspired my love for words, and thus I embarked on a career in literature and translation in the future. the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, when I returned to Paris, I was introduced by a friend to the works of French painter Chen Jianzhong. He was good at painting all kinds of leaves. The green leaves in each picture were crystal clear and glowed with the brilliance of life. , exciting. It&#39;s a pity that I didn&#39;t have enough money to buy a treasure back then, and now I can&#39;t even afford the astronomical current price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter! Just look out and enjoy the greenery outside the window! The layers of green are soothing to the eyes and the mind. I am already very rich and contented. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Canned food&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the epidemic is not over and the lockdown is over, I don’t want my Filipino maid to go to the vegetable market often, so just ask her to buy it in the supermarket. As a result, there were more canned soups, luncheon meats, etc. on the table. I usually have no interest in canned food, the only exception being tomato sauce beans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time I go out with my daughter, we always order All Day Breakfast for lunch, and the must-have soybeans in tomato sauce in this dish is my favorite. Whenever my daughter watches me eating beans with gusto, she is always a little puzzled. What is so special about such ordinary food? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sour and sweet, glutinous and crispy, what you taste when you taste the tomato sauce beans in your mouth is not only the feeling of melting in your mouth, but also the memory of hard work in your youth. When I was a sophomore in high school, I moved to Hong Kong from Taipei and was lucky enough to be admitted to Pei Ching Middle School. I was unfamiliar with the place and I didn&#39;t know the Cantonese language. I had to take the national college entrance examination a year later. I was caught off guard and I was in a hurry. Fortunately, the whole class did not exclude me, a transfer student from Taiwan. I hung out with everyone every day in school. Within half a year, I could speak Cantonese casually and became as fluent as I am today. At that time, I was only thinking about Taiwan&#39;s university entrance examination. I really didn&#39;t know much about Hong Kong&#39;s high school entrance examination. I only know that my classmates are nervous preparing for the exam, and I am also nervous. There were five or six girls in the class. Some time before the college entrance examination, we would meet from time to time to go back to school on Sundays to review their studies. Mathematics, physics and chemistry were the highlight. For a new student like me, having someone to work hard with and solve puzzles with after school was certainly a blessing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Life was simple and materially scarce at that time. Five or six young people got together to buy a long loaf of white bread and a can of beans with tomato sauce&amp;nbsp; (This was my first experience with such a thing. canned food), not even soda and juice, so it was our lunch.温习之余，给物理定律的难缠、数学题目的棘手、生化名词的繁复弄得头昏脑胀时，打开罐头，把橙色的黄豆铺满白软的面包，大口大口地咀嚼起来，但觉甘美无比。还记得酸酸甜甜酥酥软软的豆香，随伴着窗友同伴之间一个打气的手势，一个鼓励的眼神，马上激起共赴考场“同仇敌忾”的感觉，考试前小小的烦困，也就因此一扫而空。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外一种罐头更使我至今念念不忘。来港前在台湾北一女就读，从初一到高二。当时住在和平东路的一座大杂院里，房东姓严，是四川人。他们家有三个女儿三个儿子。女儿都比我大，所以搬去后，在家中孤单无伴的我，一下子多了三个姐姐。严家三姐Lucy是个开心果，整日笑脸迎人，手舞足蹈，稀奇古怪的念头也特别多。那时候正值发育时期，吃完晚饭不久肚子会咕噜作响，找不到吃的，就跟着三姐转。 Lucy说有个好法子，把晚餐吃剩的冷饭拿来用热水一冲，就变成泡饭，没小菜吧？开罐“独山盐酸菜”！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“独山盐酸菜”可是当年台湾的名牌，打开罐头，蒜香扑鼻。也不知道为什么，可能是那年头没有任何其他的选择吧！只记得每每时近午夜，跟三姐躲在小厨房里，在热乎乎的泡饭上加满又酸又辣的“独山”，狼吞虎咽，不亦乐乎，空空如也的肠胃，也因此得到了无比的满足。自此，我爱上了辣椒，也爱上了蒜头，这对身为上海人的自己来说，似乎有点“离经叛道”，然而在日后前往巴黎进修时，碰上以“大蒜、黄油、葡萄酒”为三宝的法式烹饪，又大有“如鱼得水”的感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在北一女上初中时，全体学生都接受童军训练。有一回，学校让大家去露营，不过营地不是在郊外，而是设在学校操场上。这样也罢，同学还是乐呵呵、兴冲冲。每班同学都分成六七人一组的小队，各队扎好营地后，还得自己负责炊事，各显本领，亮出拿手好菜，让教官品尝评分，一比高下。记得我们那队，好不容易扎好了帐篷，已经手忙脚乱了，哪里还来得及做菜呢？情急之下，不知道谁出了个主意，说不如祭出“独山盐酸菜”这样法宝吧！时近黄昏，教官施施然巡场而至，兴许像腊月岁暮的灶君菩萨，她这一路行来，已经在各队遍试大鱼大肉有点嘴里发腻了，一尝到我们的“独山盐酸菜”，竟然赞不绝口，认为是无上美馔，几乎要赏我们挂头牌了。这下，倒把大家吓得非同小可，这行径可不是跟考试作弊不相上下吗？结果如何，已经不复记忆，只是这独特的经历却牢牢留在脑海中，多少年后重游宝岛，心痒痒想在超市找罐“独山盐酸菜”，可惜这牌子早已随着逝水流年而芳踪邈然了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一种罐头装的是去骨鸡肉，名堂不记得了，是个外国牌子。大学毕业后赴美攻读硕士学位。刚去不久，就在圣路易华盛顿大学的宿舍里邂逅了来自台湾的女孩石，两人一见如故。宿舍里供应早晚两餐，中午就由自己张罗。我们两人为了省钱，决定每天中午买一条白面包，开一罐去骨鸡肉，在我的房间里分而食之。石是念化工的，手力比我大，开罐头之类的活，她手到擒来，易如反掌。有一天中午，我回去晚了，一进没有上锁的房门，发现室内静悄悄的，不见人影，仔细一瞧，那小桌上有个开了一半的罐头，旁边血迹斑斑，再一看，&amp;nbsp;一滴滴血竟然先往地下流，再向门口淌，这光景，就像是谋杀案现场似的，好不吓人！我追寻着斑斑血迹，急忙往外跑，血印点点滴滴带领着我跑过走廊，奔向另一端的房间，冲进一看，赫然见到平时硬朗的石，正在按着血淋淋的手指，神情张皇，不知所措！我们匆匆赶去医疗室，不记得她给缝了多少针。多年后，每念及负笈美国时的俭朴岁月，以及我们这一群女孩之间毕生不渝的纯真友谊，就会不期然想起这个去骨鸡肉罐头！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三种罐头，承载了生命中三段过程，从青葱到成熟。那些年岁月静好，度过的是平凡安逸的日子；如今呢？风急雨骤，变幻莫测，遥望前程，再也无语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳大利亚籍人员成蕾被国家安全机关依法执行驱逐出境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258395]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;2023年10月11日，澳大利亚籍人员成蕾在服刑期满后，被北京市国家安全局依法执行驱逐出境。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;成蕾，女，1975年6月生，澳大利亚籍，原系境内媒体聘用人员。 2020年5月，成蕾受某境外机构人员攀拉，违反与聘用单位签署的保密条款，非法将工作中掌握的国家秘密内容通过手机提供给该境外机构。北京市国家安全局经立案侦查，于2020年8月对成蕾依法采取刑事强制措施。成蕾到案后，如实供述犯罪事实，自愿认罪认罚。北京市第二中级人民法院经开庭审理，以为境外非法提供国家秘密罪判处成蕾有期徒刑二年十一个月，附加驱逐出境。成蕾未提起上诉。中国司法机关严格依法审理案件，充分保障了成蕾依法享有的各项权利。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又疑似吃出鼠头？高校食堂为何难让学生满意？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258385]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月10日，话题#华北理工食堂被曝吃出鼠头#登上微博热搜榜。当日有华北理工大学学生反映，在食堂饭菜里吃出疑似老鼠头的不明物体。爆料图片里筷子夹住的深色的肉上有几根毛，当事学生称这份食物是其室友在学校食堂买到的，看上去像是老鼠头，但食堂的店家说是牛肉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/bHGuwl0bM6nfGSKilvSIK06xyBtSAutZYsTt8k4X.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/bHGuwl0bM6nfGSKilvSIK06xyBtSAutZYsTt8k4X.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253726&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;学生爆料截图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月10日晚，华北理工大学官网发布公告称，承包了涉事食堂的宁波市江徽美食餐饮有限公司于2023年10月10日违反食品卫生相关规定，在经营过程中发生食品卫生问题。校方解除与其之间的委托经营合同，并将依法依规追究其相关责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/HxIHBEWmuQhfQFhcFvXgEEl0MS7kXKFBJfGHvTWh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/HxIHBEWmuQhfQFhcFvXgEEl0MS7kXKFBJfGHvTWh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253727&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;学校公告截图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（华北理工大学官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这已经不是高校食堂第一次因鼠头登上热搜。就在今年6月，江西工业职业技术学院就因为“鼠头鸭脖”事件引发舆论风暴。不止食品卫生问题，高校食堂难吃也常被学生吐槽。2019年3月，南京邮电大学就因为#南邮食堂难吃#上了热搜榜。2020年9月，教育部也曾印发文件，要求学校食堂改良菜品口味和改进烹饪工艺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月11日，山东省教育厅下发文件，要求2026年8月底前，全省高校学生食堂原则上全部实现自主经营。这也被认为是为了解决高校食堂问题的一次试点，或在不久的将来推广至全国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学校食堂该如何管理才能让学生和家长放心满意？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快来评论区发表你的看法，马上送你上热评！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[哈马斯“瞒天过海”，破灭以色列“情报神话”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258388]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 14:57:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2rusj5FGboq151HgW6R36rtGXJtzmHphrKAmlB5m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2rusj5FGboq151HgW6R36rtGXJtzmHphrKAmlB5m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是10月7日在加沙地带拍摄的向以色列发射的火箭弹。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社法新/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月7日早晨，一场国际音乐节上，凄厉的防空警报声突然响起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一刻开始，巴勒斯坦伊斯兰抵抗运动（哈马斯）持续向以色列境内发射数千枚火箭弹。自1973年“赎罪日战争”之后，50年来最严重的冲突爆发了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至10月10日，据以色列媒体和巴勒斯坦医疗机构公布的最新消息，冲突已造成超过1900人死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对如此大规模的袭击，一向以中东头号军事强国自称的以色列，为何事先没有丝毫察觉？随着冲突的持续升级，这个疑问也成为国际舆论焦点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前来看，不管是以色列还是西方媒体，都认为以色列引以为豪的情报系统出了“大问题”。哈马斯称，为这次袭击秘密准备了超过一年时间，而以方安全和情报机构却没有提前发出任何预警。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“情报神话”破灭？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;高度戒备的边界隔离墙，布满了以色列的监控摄像头和守卫士兵。空中还时不时出现监视无人机，不断“嗡嗡”作响。这一场景对于加沙的巴勒斯坦人来说，已持续了近30年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在哈马斯发动新一轮袭击之前，以色列的情报系统似乎“闭上了眼睛”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯冲破巴以边境屏障，派出数百名武装人员渗透到以色列人控制区。以色列情报部门摩萨德前负责人埃夫拉伊姆·哈勒维公开表示，他们没有收到任何形式的警告，“战争的爆发完全令人惊讶”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国有线电视新闻网报道，加沙地带被以色列军队封锁和严密监视，巴勒斯坦武装人员很少能够进入以色列。但哈勒维表示，巴勒斯坦武装人员发射的火箭弹数量“前所未见”，这也是他们“第一次”能够“深入以色列并控制村庄”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管以色列对于巴方的袭击并不陌生，但此次以色列军方发现自己“措手不及”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“整个情报系统失败了，它仅仅是一个组件，未能为以色列平民提供必要的防御。”以色列国防军前国际发言人乔纳森·康里克斯说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;路透社表示，自2005年以色列从加沙撤军以来，花费数亿美元建造了一个带有传感器和地下墙的智能边界，以保护边境免遭袭击。以军还&lt;span>;在美国帮助下，开发了一套&lt;/span>;专门拦截火箭弹和迫击炮弹的“铁穹”防御系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列情报机构更因几十年来的一系列“成绩”，被本国和西方媒体写成了“神话”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这一次，“神话”看起来被哈马斯打破了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列退役将军阿米尔·阿维维表示，加沙的武装分子已经找到了逃避技术情报收集的方法，让以色列无法完全了解他们的意图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他们已经回到了石器时代。”阿维维解释说，武装人员不使用电话或电脑，而是在专门的技术间或地下房间里交接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海国际问题研究院外交政策研究所研究员李伟建向南方周末记者分析，虽然以色列有一套完整的情报系统，但反过来看，对于以色列的每一套做法，加沙地带的巴勒斯坦武装也在不断地总结、防范，甚至在以色列都有其眼线。“这完全也有可能”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列《国土报》披露，成百上千的哈马斯人员已经为突袭准备了几个月，甚至超过一年，“但没有泄露出去”，结果可见是灾难性的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李伟建表示，巴勒斯坦武装通过总结长期的斗争经验，也可能抓住了以色列的某些“防范弱点”，找到一些“防范规律”，不能单方面地认为以色列的军事情报团队强大到无懈可击的地步了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一点值得关注，以色列从年初以来的司法改革和政治纷争，带来了国内的撕裂、对立。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;复旦大学中东研究中心研究员邹志强向南方周末记者表示，目前以色列国内的政局不稳和内耗比以往上升，分散了以色列自身的注意力和精力，削弱了士气。所以对于哈马斯这种“创新型、多渠道”的闪击打法，以色列措手不及。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“海陆空”全方位进攻&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“哈马斯成员从陆地、海上和空中三路进行渗透。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以色列国防军发言人丹尼尔·哈加里表示，自当地时间10月7日早上6点30分以来，从加沙地带向以色列发射了2200多枚火箭弹。与此同时，几十名武装人员对隔离墙发动猛攻，并用炸药炸开路障，驾驶推土机、悬挂式滑翔机和摩托车在多个地点发起袭击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邹志强认为，从一个非正规武装组织的角度来讲，哈马斯此次行动具有压倒性优势，对防守严密的以色列造成如此大杀伤和打击，从军事上说还是相当值得关注的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从袭击方式看，哈马斯武装人员通过海陆空多个途径渗透到以境内。以色列警察局、定居点和多个军事基地遭到袭击，以方包括主战坦克、装甲车在内的重型武器被缴获。大量以军官兵和普通犹太定居者被俘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在军事专家张学峰看来，哈马斯快速取得“战果”的关键，首先在于哈马斯武装达成了打击的“战役突然性”。按照西方的说法，哈马斯开发了一套不依赖手机等电子系统的协调和通信系统，让以色列情报部门无从刺探，同时隐藏了自己的进攻企图。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，哈马斯利用无人机和导弹，对以色列防空系统和军事基地进行打击，还派出潜艇和快艇对以色列海岸线进行渗透和登陆，突破了以方的海防。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在突袭前，哈马斯就做好了付出代价的准备。”邹志强表示，那些冲进以色列境内的武装人员，就没想着回去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着更多细节浮出水面，外界越发认为此次行动“早有准备”。哈马斯下属武装派别“卡桑旅”发布的训练视频显示，哈马斯早就在加沙建造了一个模拟的以色列据点，其成员在那里练习登陆和突袭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，路透社报道，自2021年以来，以色列一直寻求通过提供包括数千个许可证在内的激励措施，维持加沙经济的基本稳定。也是在这两年里，哈马斯没有对以色列采取军事行动，这让以方放松了警惕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邹志强认为，从以色列长期的实力优势及对技术手段的依赖来看，由于过往多次应对加沙冲突的经验，他们可能松懈了，并且有一种疲惫心理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但从长远来看，邹志强表示，这一次哈马斯可能没有办法让以色列让步。相反，以色列可能变本加厉地“报复”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;复制&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“赎罪日战争”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这次哈马斯是在“赎罪日战争”（第四次中东战争）50周年纪念日之际，对以色列发动了闪击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每年的10月6日，正好是犹太教的“赎罪日”。当天以色列会全国放假，暂停一切正常活动。而在1973年10月6日下午，埃及对以色列发动了进攻。埃军强渡苏伊士运河，冲垮巴列夫防线。以色列在猝不及防之下，一度面临亡国的危险。当然，最终以色列还是逆转了战局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少西方媒体因此评价，以色列和美国这次在情报战线上的重大失误，堪比当年“赎罪日战争”爆发前以方的表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;战前，埃军对预备役人员进行反复征召和复员，使以色列丧失警觉。现役部队频繁前调后撤，以掩盖军事部署。在“赎罪日”当天开战，正逢犹太人实行斋戒，不利于迅速动员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“二者之间，有一定的可比性，也有一定的关联。”邹志强认为，哈马斯选择赎罪日的第二天搞突然袭击，突袭的方式相似，以色列方面措手不及的反应也比较类似。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少受访的专家学者告诉南方周末记者，哈马斯这次袭击既是为了纪念50年前那场同样“秘而不宣”的行动，也是趁着当天是以色列的“安息日”，攻其不备。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《纽约时报》认为，尽管大规模战争已经过去了半个多世纪，但村庄再次被占领、平民被杀或被扣为人质，唤醒了人们“原始的恐惧”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邹志强表示，由于第四次中东战争是埃及和叙利亚联合起来进攻以色列，是国与国之间大规模的正面作战。而现在哈马斯实施的是一种非对称游击战，战场的烈度、双方对抗的情况，无法与前者相提并论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“和50年前不同的是，如今巴以问题已经边缘化。这让巴勒斯坦产生一种非常失望甚至绝望的情绪。”李伟建认为，在各种情绪夹杂之下，巴勒斯坦人希望通过自己造成一个有影响力的行动，企图重新让国际社会关注巴以问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;冲突背后多方博弈&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;巴以双方冲突由来已久。2020年，以色列、阿联酋和巴林领导人在白宫签署了亚伯拉罕协议，同意双边关系正常化，并在经济、科技、安全等领域开展合作。该协议被认为是中东地区历史性的突破。但是巴勒斯坦、伊朗、土耳其等国对此持反对和批评的态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哈马斯一向反对阿拉伯国家越过巴以问题，与以色列改善关系或建交。”邹志强分析，传统的阿拉伯国家之间的共识，是要先解决巴以问题，再解决阿以问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外界普遍猜测，哈马斯只是巴勒斯坦加沙地区的地方武装，和以色列的军事实力对比悬殊，这次“豁出去”的突袭，会不会有其他国家支持？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至目前，伊朗、黎巴嫩真主党、卡塔尔、科威特、伊拉克、叙利亚等国家和组织公开发声支持哈马斯，这些国家大都和以色列、美国有着不小的“梁子”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国《时代》杂志认为，伊朗一直是哈马斯最大的单一“赞助商”。除了军事训练和人道主义援助外，每年还提供超过1亿美元的军事援助。在哈马斯对以色列发起突袭后，伊朗在10月7日晚放烟花“公开庆祝”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哈马斯发言人加齐·哈马德10月8日接受英国广播公司采访时也表示，该组织得到了盟友伊朗的支持和“其他国家”的帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，10月8日，伊朗驻联合国代表团在一份声明中表示，“我们坚定地支持巴勒斯坦。但是我们不参与巴勒斯坦的行动，因为这完全是巴勒斯坦自己的决定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;站在以色列一边的也不乏其人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在冲突爆发的第一时间，美国就表态称，“将和以色列人民以及政府站在一起”。白宫还特别表示，美国将“继续向以色列提供支持，包括深入的情报交流”&amp;nbsp;。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据美国《时代》杂志报道，美国每年向以色列提供超过30亿美元的国防援助，是最大的受援国，并且“可以想象这一数字可能还会增加”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，中东是大国博弈的“核心区”之一。如今巴以局势再次升级，背后各方少不了暗中博弈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邹志强认为，冲突还是会限于巴以之间。未来在短期内，巴以问题可能重回中东外交的核心舞台，但从长远来看，依然难以改变被边缘化的地位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李伟建则认为，如果以色列大开杀戒，疯狂报复，造成大量人员死亡，可能会引发中东内部矛盾激化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月9日，中国外交部发言人呼吁尽快停火，保护平民，同时国际社会应当增强紧迫感，加大对巴勒斯坦问题的投入，为推进“两国方案”作出切实努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生林曦、包婧玥对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[墙塌压坏菜园成最高法案例，民间调解呼唤“新乡贤”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258381]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，最高法发布了一批解决灾后矛盾纠纷的典型案例。在其中的一个案例中，河北涿州一户人家的院墙在大雨中坍塌，压坏了邻居的菜园，双方发生纠纷，要闹上法庭。法官在诉前进行了调解，矛盾最终得以化解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自家院墙倒塌压坏邻居的菜园，除了压坏一些菜，没有其他大的损失。这是一件小事，在很多地方，很可能两家私下就解决了，或者在村里调解人的主持下止息纷争，不至转向法院。比如，在鲁东南一个村子里，一位六十多岁的老人，是同族中辈分最高的，因为能言善道，加之平素持事公正，很有威望。村民之间出现矛盾纠纷，都愿意找他来主持公道。很多纠纷都在他的调解下得到解决。再如《南方周末》前段时间报道过的，福建莆田很多地方设立的“妈祖评理室”，也在民间纠纷解决中发挥了重要的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种由乡土“调解员”主持，依托乡土社会内生的伦理规范而成的调解机制，是解决民间纠纷的重要渠道之一。不久前，农业农村部、发改委、民政部等联合印发的《“我的家乡我建设”活动实施方案》提出，要聘任一批有威望、讲公道的回乡能人作为邻里矛盾调解员，积极探索“包案化解”等工作方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传统上，中国社会是个乡土社会。广大乡村的大多数民间纠纷都是通过乡土调解力量来解决的。因为村民之间的纠纷，多数是张家的牛吃了李家几口苗，王家的鸡啄了刘家几棵菜这类琐事，涉及的利益并不太大。而乡村由熟人乃至同族人组成，彼此关系密切，在长期相处中形成了一套共同的行为规范，成为乡村的习惯法。主持调解的，多是当地德高望重之人，或者是一族族长、耆老，或是告老还乡的乡贤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国乡村多数是聚族而居，不少村子的村民多是同一祖先繁衍而来，当然也有一些村庄是两姓或者几姓合居，或者有少数的小姓家族。但总体来说，这些村民世代共居，形成了一套相处之道，也有共同信服的人。尤其是在一族之内，族长耆老具有很高的权威。村民之间发生矛盾，多愿意主动寻求他们的帮助。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对村庄内部的各种矛盾与纷争，这种调解，不仅仅是裁判，更是说理、教育的过程。费孝通在《乡土中国》中曾说，“调解是个新名词，旧名词是评理。乡村里所谓调解，其实是一种教育过程。”也因此，这些调解往往比官方的裁判更容易得到矛盾各方的信服，多数会得到自愿执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，随着这些年社会迅速变化，人口流动加大，农村原有的熟人社会也开始陌生化、原子化。要找到被居民们共同信服的“调解人”变得困难。一些农村尤其是城郊的农村，有不少外地人来租房居住。这些租户与村庄没有历史联系，是村里的“外来人”，他们对村里原有的权威往往并不是非常认同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，外出流动的村民也大大增加。很多村民常年在外，很少回村，与其他村民之间的联系逐渐减少，宗亲、乡邻感情越来越淡薄。加之在外地陌生人社会的长期经历，也让他们更加认同陌生人社会的法治规则，而非乡村的传统规则，以及乡村规则之下的传统权威。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这两方面的陌生化、原子化，都让乡土社会原有权威的威信下降，定分止争功能不断弱化。外来租户和本土村民之间没有共同信服的传统权威，久在外地的村民，也越来越少完全信服本村的老人。如此一来，外来租户与原住民之间发生矛盾，甚至村民之间发生纠纷，就不太愿意适用以前的乡土规则，而更愿意转向体制性权威比如政府、法院等寻求解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要重建传统的民间调解机制，需要寻找新的在社区有足够威信的“调解人”。“新乡贤”就是一个可能的选项。让这些“新乡贤”出来主持公道，常能定分止争，比之正规司法过程，社会成本较低，他们的调解也更容易得到矛盾各方认同，调解方案易于执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乡村鸡毛蒜皮的小纠纷也转向法院，确实可说是一种法治“现代化”，但同时消解了传统，也会让司法系统不堪负担。发挥民间调解定分止争的作用，让小矛盾就地解决，需要重建社区的凝聚力，寻找居民都熟悉、都信服又有相当现代法律知识的“新乡贤”来充当“调解人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲击波里的人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258379]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 12:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/RNMXhTWmmzgEdNZZYxb1YtlDDqmJIaXkAcSUimk0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/RNMXhTWmmzgEdNZZYxb1YtlDDqmJIaXkAcSUimk0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253628&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是10月7日在加沙地带拍摄的向以色列发射的火箭弹。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社法新/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果不是突然响起的枪声，2023年10月7日本该是一个愉快的周六。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在特拉维夫，北京游客刘子慧将迎来国庆旅行的最后一日。依照计划，她要去参观特拉维夫大学犹太民族博物馆，然后去雅法古城。在雷霍沃特，中国厨师张锋做好上班准备，这是一周中餐厅生意最红火的时刻，不少以色列人会选择这天外出吃饭休闲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在靠近加沙地带的一片地区，27岁的女乐迷米丽特·本·柴姆（Millet Ben Haim）和朋友在音乐节上彻夜狂欢，这一刻，她和朋友期待了好几个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同一时间，年轻的以色列学者哈依姆·凯茨曼像往常一样待在位于Holit的家中，这里距离加沙地带只有1.5公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场突然发生的袭击，突然改变了他们生活的航向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们之中，有的目睹了火箭弹划过天空的白色轨迹，有的听到了旷野上四面八方的枪声，有的则与哈马斯武装正面相遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“危机，从南到北”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月7日清晨，“平行宇宙”音乐节上，年轻的乐迷们唱跳正酣。该音乐节源自巴西，已有23年的历史。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从主办方公布的时间表里看到，音乐节从10月6日晚23时开始，不间断持续至7日下午。这意味着乐迷们可以赶赴一场“通宵舞会”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场预热已久的音乐节，乐迷们非常期待，米丽特就是其中之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;音乐节举办地位于雷姆基布兹附近，这里距离以色列最大城市特拉维夫约有1.25小时的车程，不少乐迷开车前来。与此同时，这里距离加沙地带仅有数公里，这为后续的悲剧埋下了伏笔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎明时刻，危险开始降临。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月7日凌晨，哈马斯向以色列发射了数千枚火箭弹，多名武装人员运用自制简易滑翔机从加沙地带隔离区渗透进入争议地区。而社交媒体上出现的视频和图片显示，哈马斯武装分子还乘坐皮卡车和摩托车进入以色列控制区。巴以隔离地带沿线首当其冲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“早上6点31分左右，音乐停了，警报声响起来。”米丽特在社交媒体上用视频记录了这一时刻。“越来越多的火箭弹飞向天空，我们意识到必须马上离开。”她写道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社交媒体上流传的一段视频显示，数十名年轻人在空旷的田野中惊慌奔跑，周围是舍弃的汽车，身后是密集的枪声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沿着火箭弹飞行的航线，以色列多地持续拉响防空警报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中部城市雷霍沃特，中国厨师张锋同样在早上6点多被“声音”吵醒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里处在加沙地带到特拉维夫之间，张锋看到“一波又一波”火箭弹经过城市上空飞往北方，“其中有很多火箭弹被拦截”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袭击开始后，张锋和同事们一次次挤进小小的避弹间，听着外面防空警报声、炮弹飞行声、遭拦截后爆炸声密集响起。第一波袭击持续了两三个小时，来以色列两年多，张锋感觉“这是最厉害的一次”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张锋在雷霍沃特市一家风味餐厅工作。7日上午，他和同事们都收到了放假通知，这让他们颇感意外。据他介绍，每逢周六，不少以色列人会带全家出门吃饭，这时往往是餐厅生意最忙碌的时刻。此前虽然也多次经历防空警报，但危险解除后，他们依然会正常上班。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“以前很少放假，这次能放假就说明事态很严重。”张锋说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在北部城市耶路撒冷，刘子慧和同伴们9点多乘车从酒店出发。趁着十一长假，她开启了一场“人文深度游”。按照原计划，他们将在7日上午到达特拉维夫，住一晚后就回国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，从耶路撒冷出发不久，刘子慧一行人就听到了防空警报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“司机立即停车，导游带我们躲到路边的音乐厅。”刘子慧听音乐厅的工作人员说，他们也是临时接到通知取消了演出。解除警报后，工作人员还专程表示歉意，称“很抱歉让你们的旅途有这样糟糕的体验”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出于安全考虑，原计划行程取消，导游带大家直接去了酒店。因为预订房间尚未准备妥当，一行人在酒店大堂等候，午饭也是就近中餐厅预定送来。刘子慧的房间处于10层，窗外可以直接看到“直升机飞过”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚上7点起，特拉维夫又响起了几次防空警报。刘子慧说，大家不得不在酒店的安全屋里吃掉了晚餐。直到晚上9点多，才变得平静。“我和同伴和衣而卧，凌晨三点才敢洗澡收拾东西”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;撤离，人群涌向机场&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;危机发生时，中国游客艾米正在乘车前往以色列漩涡中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾米热爱旅行，对宗教色彩浓厚的中东国家一直充满好奇。前几年，她已经去过埃及和土耳其，而这次旅行的目的地则是约旦和以色列。艾米和丈夫计划从约旦入境以色列，这样两个国家能连着一起玩，“落地签办理也很方便”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了艾米和丈夫外，一起拼车的还有一个美籍阿拉伯裔年轻人。按照计划，一行人要走约旦中部过境处，但突袭发生后，这一过境处临时关闭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“司机说去不了的时候，我们还不敢相信，非要过去一探究竟，但是路上也有警察拦着。看到司机展示的血腥场面时，我们仨都震惊了。”艾米说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴以冲突由来已久，艾米一行人起初不以为然。随着越来越多的冲突消息传来，他们决定放弃原计划，改从北部过境处前行。“时间很紧张，我们也没法多想。再加上语言不通，司机说怎么着，我们就跟着去了。”艾米说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;约旦北部过境处相对偏僻，人员稀少。艾米和丈夫想找人拼车，问了多个过境客人，却都被拒绝。艾米正准备向保险公司打电话求助时，他们“奇迹般地”在更远的一条街上招到了一辆出租车。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时过境处的人都传言&#39;今天不可能飞&#39;，我们很担心航班取消。再加上当天是安息日，上班的人少，我们也担心不能准时到机场。”前往机场的路上，艾米和丈夫反复给航空公司打电话，确认飞机是否正常起飞，同时又要给保险公司打电话咨询理赔事宜，“一路提心吊胆”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们下午3点半到达机场，看到已有不少乘机旅客在排队等候。“幸亏提前值机，如果误了飞机，以后再回国感觉更难了。”艾米说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾米的担心并非杞人忧天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;突袭发生后，美国达美航空公司和美国航空公司取消了原定7日和8日从纽约飞往以色列的航班。德国汉莎航空也在7日宣布，将大幅取消飞往特拉维夫的航班。此外，飞常准App显示，近日中国上海、深圳直飞以色列特拉维夫的往返航班也已取消。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和艾米的“一日多国”不同，刘子慧在袭击次日搭上回国航班。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8日一大早，刘子慧就收拾好行李。依照计划，他们将从本古里安国际机场飞往首都北京。抵达机场后，刘子慧发现人虽很多，但秩序井然。在交流中，刘子慧发现，有的人因为害怕机场关闭，头一天就到了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;航班大屏上一片红，只剩下零零星星的绿色，“大量航班取消了，只有少量是正常飞”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到飞机起飞，刘子慧悬着的一颗心才落了地，在接下来的旅程中沉沉地睡了过去。10月9日凌晨5:28分，飞机落地北京首都国际机场，机舱里响起热烈的掌声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“透过舷窗看到北京地面一片灯光璀璨，内心有些激动。无数次降落，从来没有像今天这样激动。”刘子慧说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不幸的消息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;并不是所有人都能像艾米和刘子慧一样顺利撤离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月9日上午，从事海外劳务派遣业务的江苏中澜境外就业公司工作人员告诉南方周末记者，截至当日上午11时，公司已知有3人在以色列失联，其他情况还在更新中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月10日，外交部发言人称，外交部和相关驻外使领馆针对以色列和巴勒斯坦当前形势已经发布了安全提醒，建议中国公民暂勿前往以色列和巴勒斯坦，已在当地的中国公民和机构保持高度警惕，加强安全防范，做好应急准备和就地避险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参加音乐节的米丽特经历了一场“死里逃生”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据米丽特在社交平台上的讲述，她和朋友一开始驾车逃离，当她们穿过一条主干道时，却遇到了袭击者的双面夹击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有人尖叫着，袭击者正在朝去那里的人开枪，于是我尽快掉头。两分钟之后，我发现另一个方向上的袭击者更多。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，米丽特和朋友们在旷野中逃跑。大约三个小时后，虚弱又害怕的她们躲在了灌木丛里，用树叶盖住自己。期间，她们试图报警，但警方没有回应。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;米丽特的经历受到多家媒体关注，《华盛顿邮报》在10月8日报道中援引其经历。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;袭击发生后，“平行宇宙”音乐节主办方发布了希伯来语和英语双语公告，寻找失踪人员。在社交平台评论区，挤满了焦虑的人们。他们不断留言，询问失联的亲友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们感到震惊和痛苦。”主办方“新星部落”在公告中称，正在尽一切努力协助安全部队在该地区搜索失踪人员。该组织还提供了一个失踪者的在线统计表单，失联者的家人们可以上传人员详细信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们祈祷好消息很快降临到你我身上。”公告称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样是靠近加沙地带的边界，以色列年轻学者哈依姆·凯茨曼死在位于Holit的家中。10月8日，凯茨曼的母亲在社交平台公布了这个消息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯茨曼是一位从事以色列研究的年轻学者。他的简历至今仍挂在华盛顿大学的官方网站上。从中可以看到，他先后在以色列开放大学、本古里安大学、华盛顿大学攻读本硕博学位，研究方向包括以色列的宗教、政治等。凯茨曼的母亲汉娜任职于以色列一家NGO组织。凯茨曼遇害后，该组织也在社交平台进行公开悼念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从凯茨曼母亲公布信息可见，起初她误以为凯茨曼被“绑架”，为此她还在社交平台发布寻人信息。当噩耗传来，那条寻人信息已更正，“他在家中就已身亡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯茨曼的邻居兼朋友阿维塔尔·阿拉吉姆(Avital Alajem) 10月9日接受了美国有线电视新闻网(CNN) 采访。她说，当哈马斯武装分子破门而入并向她开枪时，凯茨曼和她一起躲在壁橱里。她自己没有在袭击中受伤，“凯茨曼救了我的命”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯茨曼曾获得以色列研究协会颁发的2019年度“金默林最佳研究生论文奖”。该奖项旨在纪念以色列公共知识分子和社会学家巴鲁克·金默林。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在获奖论文中，凯茨曼有这样一句致辞：献给约旦河和地中海之间所有形式的生命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凯茨曼的好友玛尔瓦·马齐德（Marwa Maziad）在悼词中写道，“他确实认为所有生命形式都是平等而美丽的，包括他照顾的植物。以色列/巴勒斯坦，阿拉伯-穆斯林/犹太人，愿他的灵魂安息。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（刘子慧、张锋、艾米为化名，南方周末实习生徐子仪、包婧玥、翟桓对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用利息生活小组火了，但攒钱，能不能攒到]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258341]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/60fb01dc9ced91e2ce8a37e4e3964ea2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/60fb01dc9ced91e2ce8a37e4e3964ea2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;曾经被认为最自我个性，崇尚及时行乐，拥抱“消费主义”的年轻人，不知道何时起，已经开始默默攒钱打卡了。社交媒体上，一股储蓄风潮正在盛行。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为了攒钱，这届年轻人可以有多拼？可以说只有你想不到，没有年轻人做不到的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;当代人新爱好：不消费，狂攒钱&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;在上班和上进之间，这届年轻人选择上香；在买包和买醉之间，他们更倾向于选择买彩票；在理想和理由之间，理财才是年轻人的最爱——主打的就是一个攒钱，搞钱！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;豆瓣的“用利息生活：储蓄小组”，现在组里的成员已经超过了10万，“用利息生活：投资理财”的小组，组员人数超过了60万。更别提还有“抠门女性联合会”，“抠门男性联合会”，累计已经百万人员入组。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为了攒钱，有人选择记账、精打细算，有人选择用利息生活，理财买基金，也有人选择主业副业两手抓，做个斜杠青年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;记账APP用起来，定期整理个人账单只是入门级举措，从各类攒钱小组中吸取群体智慧，挖掘各种薅羊毛神器，购物红包、会员折扣、积分抵扣、直播团购、多平台比价，坚决不放过任何潜藏的福利，是年轻人get的新生活智慧，例如就有年轻人每日零点后蹲抢临期食品与剩菜盲盒，降低饮食开销成本。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这些算是年轻人的进化版行动，而更高段位的同学，已经玩起了特种兵攒钱，对比全国各地银行，就看谁家的利息更高一些，选择不远万里去奔赴。有媒体报道，今年银行利率下调后，有年轻人一天跨越两千公里，花330块车费，只为了多赚1800块利息。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有人觉得这也太委屈自己了吧，与“苦日子”和平共处，年轻人却甘之如饴的原因，大概率在攒钱如同滚雪球，看到自己的小金库日渐丰满，那种成就感，在一定程度上，让人能够忘却前期的艰苦卓绝。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;就像日本作家松浦弥太郎曾在《慢慢变富：让人生更富有的金钱与工作法则》中写道：“攒钱比花钱更容易。毕竟花钱的方法有很多，但攒钱的方法就只有一个，那就是&#39;少花钱&#39;。”因为路径单一且清晰，所以只要目标足够坚定，沿着既定的方向走下去，总能成功实现，也因此，吸引着越来越多的年轻人躬身入局。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;拒绝消费主义的陷阱，年轻人成了真的人间清醒。不再执着于跟随潮流，买最新的电子产品；不再频繁点外卖，而是选择和大妈们一起赶大集买菜，自己带饭；不再每逢百步必打车，而是能步行就步行，能地铁绝不出租车。每一步省下的钱，如同涓涓细流，最终汇聚成溪、成江河。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/db7bc1d8642781493c9860d7666c2e84.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/db7bc1d8642781493c9860d7666c2e84.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/ 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;攒钱，能不能攒到钱&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那么在攒钱上，年轻人希望攒到什么程度呢？有报告显示超过53.7%的30岁年轻人认为存够10万元可以算作是有一定存款的基础。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;然而，冰冷的现实是第一财经的一项调查显示：存款超过10万元，你就已经超过53.7%的同龄人。超半数年轻人存款不足10万，“有心无力”是现实。拼命攒钱的年轻人，却发现钱就如同细沙，握得越紧，流失的就越多。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;通往财富自由之路，荆棘丛生。但年轻人的意志逐渐坚定，不再被消费主义乱花渐欲迷人眼，而是不买立省全部，一切为小金库的充实让步。年轻人奋发攒钱，反映了什么社会趋势？有人攒钱的雄心壮志是提前退休，实施FIRE计划(Financial Independence, Retire Early 经济独立,提前退休)；也有人是为了更多安全感，有更多应对未来的底气。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;毕竟余额越多安全感越足，金钱意味着有足够的保障，抵御未知的风险。可以让年轻人生活不慌张，遇事少求人。归根结底，本质上还是因为骨子里的风险厌恶。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;就像乌尔里希·贝克在《风险社会》中所言，生活性风险如影随形，个人迫不得已必须面对的个体化进程，早期现代化阶段构建的保障体系无法再为个体提供保障，个体化因此而进入新的阶段。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;社会流动性增强，失业和就业的边界日益模糊，宗族式家庭关系瓦解，工作与亲密关系，这代年轻人无可回避的课题，所有这些让年轻人感知到对风险，也激发了他们渴望在风险的浪潮袭来之时，能够攀住一个具有稳定性的东西，谋求到自身的岁月静好。而在曙光乍现之前，金钱成为现实的坐标轴，攒钱才是年轻人的抗风险制胜法宝。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如果你以为年轻人攒钱就是不花钱，那就大错特错了。与老一辈的单纯省钱不同的是，年轻人主打的是该省省，该花花。在这届后浪的价值观认知里，攒钱是为了更好地花钱，是为了把钱花在刀刃上，追求更高的价值感和性价比。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比尔·盖茨说过：“巧妙地花一笔钱和挣到这笔钱一样困难。”所以，凡是觉得值得的，旅行看世界、学习新技能、获得新体验，那就值得攒钱去实现，而凡是觉得不值得的，涨了钱的外卖套餐，商场里昂贵的丑衣服，那就是一毛不拔，坚决不愿意额外付费。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;并且常在互联网上冲浪的年轻人，已经给各种“无痛攒钱”方式冠上了新的title，命名为“公主存钱法”“365天存钱法”“木鱼存钱法”……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;甚至为了增加存钱的仪式感，在达成目标之时，会适当地给自己增加奖励，比如每天攒钱50块，三个月一张演唱会门票钱攒出来了，既不影响自己的正常生活水平，同时又能够满足自己的爱好兴趣，如同投币式许愿，在人生的旷野里，勇敢的人走在前列，先享受世界，缔造属于他们的独特style与生活方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;让荷包鼓起来，让生命充实起来，这届年轻人的攒钱观，你爱上了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>