<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[农业农村部：“村播”是乡村振兴的新型人才]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5CKBUu5vtw3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5 CKBUu5vtw3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 8, 2023, fruit farmers in Zhuxi Town, Cengong County, Guizhou Province broadcast live Selling golden autumn pears. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rural areas, like cities, have huge consumption potential. On September 12, 2023, Zhang Guoqing, deputy director of the Information Center of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that farmers’ income has grown faster than urban residents for 11 consecutive years, and the township and village consumer markets account for 38% of my country’s total consumer market, but to To build a connection between resources and markets and promote the further development of rural economy, &quot;village broadcasters&quot; who use short videos and live broadcast tools are also needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Zhang Guoqing said in his speech at the Kuaishou Light Chasing Conference that as a new type of talent for rural revitalization, &quot;village broadcasters&quot; have brought the &quot;source of living water&quot; of talents to rural revitalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emphasis on &quot;village broadcasting&quot; is to a large extent inseparable from the development trend of Internet e-commerce. At a special press conference on August 15, 2023, Li Gang, Director of the Circulation Development Department of the Ministry of Commerce, introduced that in 2022, the national rural online retail sales will reach 2.17 trillion yuan, and the online retail sales of agricultural products will reach 531.38 billion yuan, which is similar to that in 2014. Compared with the same period last year, it increased by 11 times and 4 times year-on-year. By the end of 2022, the number of rural online merchants (stores) nationwide has reached 17.303 million, and the number of rural Internet users nationwide has exceeded 300 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Suning County, Hebei Province alone, a small county located at the western end of the central city of Cangzhou, more than 6,500 online fishing rod and fishing gear shops have already solved the employment problem for nearly a quarter of the local population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chaohui, director of the Digital Economy Development Service Center in Suning County, Hebei Province, said that among the local 340,000 permanent residents, 30,000 are directly engaged in e-commerce, and 85,000 are indirectly engaged in packaging, video production and other related work. The products are online The sales rate is over 90%. According to a previous report by China News Network, in a three-hour live broadcast in early July 2023, a &quot;village broadcaster&quot; in Suning County attracted 150,000 viewers, and the transaction volume in a single session exceeded 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the 26-year-old &quot;village broadcaster&quot; Gerong Zhuom, as a representative of new farmers, once again recalled the first attempt that took place in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a mountain more than 5,000 meters high, she posted her first video under the account &quot;Hide Dolma&quot;. It was a snowy May. In the camera, she was walking among exposed rocks, bending down to look for wild cordyceps. Behind her was a gray valley, and a snow-white stream was vaguely visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, this 14-second daily record received more than 500,000 views the next day. In private messages, hundreds of strangers from far away offered to buy Cordyceps. &quot;I sold it for more than 2,000 yuan at that time, and I was very happy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past six years, more and more new farmers like Gerong Zhuom have appeared on camera as &quot;village broadcasters&quot;. They sell agricultural products through short videos and live broadcasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Guoqing introduced that as early as 2022, the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs and the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League jointly launched the Kuaishou platform with the goal of increasing farmers’ income and strengthening the county economy in 160 national key counties for rural revitalization. Focus on supporting the cultivation of &quot;rural youth anchors&quot; in counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emphasis on rural talents has been written into the No. 1 Central Document of 2023. In the &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; work in 2023 and in the future period, it is necessary to &quot;strengthen the construction of rural talent teams&quot;, implement the rural revitalization talent support plan and the high-quality farmer cultivation plan, and carry out the cultivation of rural entrepreneurial leaders has been included in the plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“By the end of 2022, the number of people across the country who have returned to their hometowns to start businesses has reached 12.2 million, driving more than 34 million rural employment, and the coverage rate of innovation and entrepreneurship among rural returnees has reached 83.6%.” And. In Zhang Guoqing’s view, the power of digital technology and digital economy has not yet been fully exerted. By 2025, the number of people returning to their hometowns across the country is expected to reach more than 15 million. “I believe that in this digital age, every ordinary person, Every village, every cheer can shine with enthusiasm.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[这几种新型网络传销骗局，你要小心了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In recent years&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development and popularity of the Internet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Online MLMs continue to change their criminal methods&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various MLM scams emerge in endlessly&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leading victims into heavy debts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even families are ruined...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to prevent New type of online MLM? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come and learn the routines and precautions&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 14/1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc31 1. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc311.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb. png&quot; data-key=&quot;250772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; data- key=&quot;250767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; data-key= &quot;250773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250770 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250769&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中华儿慈会志愿者疑卷走近千万救助款，大病家庭再陷配捐骗局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1kePsVXTtsk1Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1keP sVXTtsk1Z. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250787&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Children’s Charity Aid Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the China Children’s Charity Foundation) was exposed that its “Hebei project leader” made off with tens of millions of aid funds, and the patients’ families were suspected of being defrauded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, 2023, parents who realized that they had been deceived came to the door of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association again. Some family members told Southern Weekend reporters that they participated in the matching donation activities of Ke Mouxiao, the &quot;Hebei project leader&quot; of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association. According to the early publicity, taking &quot;48,500 to match 1,500&quot; as an example, parents raise 48,500 yuan to &quot;donate&quot; to the designated account. After 20 days to a month, they can receive the principal plus 1,500 yuan in matching donations, a total of 50,000 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many patients had participated in this project, and their families had no doubts. It was not until the end of August 2023 that the promised funds were not paid back, and they discovered that they had been cheated. Wang Jun, a family member of the patient, told Southern Weekend reporters that preliminary statistics from parents revealed that a total of 88 families had been defrauded, involving more than 9 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 13, the China Children’s Charity Association issued a statement denying that Ke Mouxiao was a staff member of the association and had never entrusted Ke Mouxiao to personally raise funds for the 9958 Children’s Emergency Relief Project (hereinafter referred to as 9958). funds. As for the 10 million yuan of funds circulated online, the statement stated that the association&#39;s account had never received these funds. &quot;The person involved transferred the funds to Ke Mouxiao&#39;s personal account and received rebates from Ke Mouxiao&#39;s personal account.&quot; Staff of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association told the media that Ke Mouxiao was a volunteer and the police had opened a case for fraud by impersonating him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1242&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, the Chinese Children’s Charity Association issued a statement. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(China Children&#39;s Charity Association official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The customary &quot;matching donation&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The afternoon of September 13 When Southern Weekend reporters came to the entrance of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society in Beijing, some family representatives entered the Children&#39;s Charity Society office to communicate, while more family members of the children were waiting outside the hospital. Most of them take their children to seek medical treatment in other places, from Hubei, Hunan, Sichuan and other places to Hebei Yanda Ludaopei Hospital and Shandong Provincial Cancer Hospital for treatment, and rent houses near the hospitals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yan’s child was diagnosed with neuroblastoma, a very rare childhood cancer, when she was two years old. For this reason, her family traveled from Sichuan to Shandong Cancer Hospital for treatment. In the past two years, the family has spent millions of yuan on treatment. &quot;Immunotherapy costs hundreds of thousands a month, all at my own expense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her child was diagnosed, Li Yan joined a patient group. In the patient group, she found that people often posted information on fundraising and matching donations for serious illness relief, and patients always participated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the pages displayed by some parents, the descriptions of these matching donation notices are simple, such as &quot;101,500, matched with 2,500, repayment in one month&quot; and &quot;There is only one quota this month, sign up if you want.&quot; Li Yan said that the amount of matching donations is different each time, and the number of participants is also different. Taking a 49,000 yuan matching donation of 1,000 yuan as an example, parents will raise 49,000 yuan themselves to invest in the project, and they must also provide a 50,000 yuan medical invoice in order to receive a 50,000 yuan return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many parents said that the matching donation rebates were sometimes transferred back to the parents’ personal accounts, and sometimes were transferred directly to the hospital’s designated account. Parents used the reimbursement documents to write them off one by one. “They can’t take them out, they can only use them. Treated in hospital.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For parents, having a seriously ill child at home is a heavy burden. &quot;A cold for ordinary people is just a trivial matter. For them (leukemia patients), it may cost tens of thousands of dollars to treat.&quot; Chen Chen, another parent at the scene, said that his 12-year-old daughter suffers from myeloid leukemia and is only a child. A box of targeted drugs costs more than 30,000 yuan. &quot;We are very willing to match the donation of 1,000 or 2,000 yuan to pay the rent and improve the food.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of taking care of the children, the families of the children shared their treatment experience, comforted and understood each other, and formed a A different sense of trust. Li Yan calls the patients who were diagnosed earlier as &quot;seniors&quot;. She knows that some patients have been making matching donations for several years, and they all get their money back normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other patients value the &quot;signature&quot; of Project 9958. It is organized by the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association and is known to almost all families of children with the disease. When soliciting parents to make matching donations, organizers will ask whether they have been registered. &quot;Filing&quot; refers to entering the files of the Children&#39;s Charity Society 9958 project. Parents scan the QR code to fill out the &quot;Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Society 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue Center Application Form (Langfang)&quot; and provide the child&#39;s name, age, condition and other information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You know that many people have done this before, and everyone has a default attitude towards this matter.” Li Yan said that it was this normalized operation method and the mutual trust between patients that made her enthusiastic about the project. There is no doubt about the authenticity. In addition, seriously ill children require careful care, and parents are devoted both physically and mentally to their children, making it difficult to have the energy to verify the authenticity of the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, Li Yan and several patients at Shandong Cancer Hospital transferred 48,500 yuan to Zhang’s account. Zhang transferred the money layer by layer and remitted it to Ke Xiao, and it was agreed on September 15 Refund of 50,000 yuan. But in early September, they learned that the previous batch of patients&#39; money had not been paid back in time, and Ke Mouxiao had also lost contact. Only then did they realize that the money could not be recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun, whose family members were being treated at Ludaopei Hospital in Yanda, Hebei Province, told Southern Weekend reporters that after Ke Mouxiao failed to pay his patients back in time on August 30, more than a dozen family members came to Ke Mouxiao to ask for an explanation. After Ke Mouxiao refused many times, the parents jointly reported the case to the police in Yanjiao, Hebei Province. After the police filed the case, they took criminal detention measures against Ke Mouxiao. After the accident, the families of the children asked each other. Most parents participated in the projects of &quot;48,500 for 1,500,&quot; &quot;101,500 for 2,500,&quot; and &quot;126,000 for 4,000.&quot; &quot;The minimum investment was 48,000, and the most was more than 300,000.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height= &quot;1079&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Information records of the patient’s family members participating in the “matching donation” project. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Volunteers of &quot;Best Leadership&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact , similar charity matching scams have appeared many times. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/pOTRdqBYVw-c9-xTie39dQ&quot; >;&lt;u>;&quot;The whereabouts of millions of dollars are unknown, and leukemia families are suspected of &quot;charitable donation&quot; scams&quot;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;) This incident has attracted widespread attention, perhaps because of the large amount and involvement Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Children’s Charity Aid Foundation was established in 2010. It is a national public foundation under the supervision of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. It mainly provides assistance to children in need and those who have no one to support them in the aspects of medical care, growth, education, culture and sports, etc. Carry out assistance activities for children, left-behind children, street children, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 9958 Children’s Emergency Relief Project was established in 2012. It is a self-owned brand project of the China Children’s Charity Association. This project serves the group of children in need aged 0-18 years old, integrating information services, financing channel services, Three major functions of rescue execution services. According to the official website of the China Children&#39;s Charity Association, 9958 has currently established more than 50 cooperation projects, established an emergency rescue channel network and 25 rescue sub-centers across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the statement of the Chinese Children’s Charity Association, Ke Mouxiao only served as a short-term volunteer in the association’s 9958 Children’s Emergency Relief Project Hebei Langfang Regional Cooperation Agency, and the parents’ transfer was made to Ke Mouxiao personal account. Southern Weekend reporters learned at the scene that the fundraising matching donations of the parents interviewed were indeed not transferred to the public account of the 9958 project, but were transferred to multiple different personal accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, parents all believe that Ke’s filial behavior is related to the Children’s Charity Association. Many parents told Southern Weekend reporters that to participate in the matching donation project for the first time, they must scan the QR code and fill out the &quot;Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue Center Application Form (Langfang)&quot;. Pan Changrong, 60, said that his grandson was being treated at Lu Daopei Hospital for leukemia. Their information It has been entered into the system of the Children&#39;s Charity Association, &quot;indicating that the code is real.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the family members said that the statement of matching donation receipts showed that the appropriator was the China Children&#39;s Charity Society, and based on this, they believed that these matching donation projects were regular projects operated and implemented by the China Children&#39;s Charity Society. However, no parents showed relevant payment receipts to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun said that before September 7, parents could still see Ke Mouxiao’s personal introduction on the official website of the Chinese Children’s Charity Association, indicating that he was the director of the Langfang team of the 9958 project, but on 9 When formally communicating with the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association on March 8, parents discovered that the relevant information had been deleted from the official website. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the person in charge of the China Children&#39;s Charity Association also issued a contract termination document to the family members who came to communicate. The contract termination document stated that &quot;the contracting agency of Langfang Rescue Station of Children&#39;s Charity Society&#39;s 9958 Rescue Project is Tianjin Beichen District Tianjuan Public Welfare Service Center. Because the rescue volume did not meet the standards and did not meet the development needs of the 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue Project, after evaluation, The contract with the Langfang Rescue Station was terminated on March 31, 2023. After the termination of the contract, any nominal fundraising, publicity and other activities conducted by the 9958 Rescue Project Langfang Rescue Station have nothing to do with the 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Relief Project of the China Children&#39;s Charity Society.&quot; Southern Weekend reporters saw from the photo that the document was stamped with the official seal of the Children&#39;s Charity Association and was signed on March 31, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun said that after the case was filed and accepted by the police, the police asked the person in charge of the project of the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association about this situation, and the other party admitted that the termination letter was issued in the past two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun pointed out that there is still an article on the national online platform training event released in February on the public account of 9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Rescue, with a picture showing that Ke Mouxiao was awarded the &quot;China Children&#39;s Charity Association&quot; Best Leadership Award 2022”. During the signing ceremony, it was Ke Mouxiao who signed the contract and took a group photo as the representative of the Langfang team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 13, staff of the China Children’s Charity Association stated that they were temporarily unable to accept interviews from Southern Weekend reporters, and the above information could not be confirmed. In a subsequent statement, the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association did not explain the above information. It only mentioned that Ke Mouxiao was currently detained by the Yanjiao Public Security Bureau of the Sanhe City Public Security Bureau in Hebei Province and was under investigation. They also reported to the public security organs. Report and actively cooperate with the public security organs in their investigations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family representatives who communicated with the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association told Southern Weekend reporters that the Chinese Children&#39;s Charity Association told parents that the case has been criminally filed and they need to wait until the police investigation is completed to determine how much money can be recovered. How much compensation to pay. &quot;But many families can&#39;t wait that long, and their children are in the hospital.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Tencent Charity and Sina WeChat Public Welfare issued respective responses, saying that the suspected fraud of 9958 did not occur on the platform, but based on In accordance with the platform operating rules, industry self-discipline conventions and user-oriented principles, fundraising for all 9958 projects has been suspended pending the investigation results of government departments, and further processing will be carried out based on the results. After checking, Southern Weekend reporters found that a total of 2,939 9958 projects were launched on Tencent’s public welfare platform, and all of them are currently marked “fundraising ended.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The patient’s family members in the article are pseudonyms, and Southern Weekend reporter Wang Xuqiulin also contributed)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI火爆之下，英属小岛安圭拉为啥躺赚了一笔横财？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256613]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The global popularity of artificial intelligence (AI) has brought Some interesting surprises. While OpenAI was still losing money, a British island in the Caribbean actually made money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This place is Anguilla. With an area of ​​only 96 square kilometers and a population of only 16,000, it earned Al dividends because the top-level domain name suffix in Anguilla is .ai. AI is booming and a large number of startups have registered product URLs with the .ai suffix. A .ai domain name costs about $70 per year. As a result, Anguilla got a pie that fell from the sky. This year&#39;s government revenue is expected to surge by US$30 million, equivalent to 10% of annual GDP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The highest management organization for domain names in the world is called ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers), the Chinese abbreviation for Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers. It is an established A non-profit international organization in October 1998. Originally a non-profit organization under the U.S. Department of Commerce, the U.S. government announced in 2016 that ICANN would no longer be affiliated with the Department of Commerce and become a self-managed independent organization. Of course, the United States certainly has a lot of influence on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;ICANN is responsible for managing the operation of the world&#39;s domain name system. One of its main tasks is to formulate the top level domain name (top level domain) and stipulate which strings can be used as top level domain names. The so-called top-level domain name (TLD) is the highest-level domain name, which is the last part of the website address. For example, .com, .cn. Today&#39;s domain name types can be divided into three major categories. One is .com, .net, .org, .info, .biz, etc., which can be said to be global domain names. The second is country or regional domain names, such as .cn Chinese domain name, .us American domain name, .uk British domain name, .de German domain name, etc., which are only two letters in length. The third is new top-level domain names, such as .top domain name, .vip domain name, .xyz domain name, .app domain name, .site domain name, etc., with suffix length starting from 3 characters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;ICANN cannot manage more than a thousand domain name suffixes by itself, and it is not appropriate to charge this money for being both a referee and a player, so ICANN provides services for every top-level player. Find a reliable registry (host) for the domain name, which will be responsible for managing the server, registration, use, fees and other matters of this domain name. A registry can also manage multiple domain name suffixes at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Verisign currently manages the .com domain name suffix. Verisign also manages the .cc domain name, .net domain name, and .tv domain name. . Generally speaking, for security reasons, country or regional domain names will be managed by ICANN to the government organizations of the country or region. The China Internet Network Information Center (CNNIC) manages the .cn domain name suffix. CNNIC also manages the China Internet Network Information Center (CNNIC). domain name. The domain name registry only has management rights and cannot participate in market transactions. Therefore, there are many domain name registrars under the Domain Name Registry, including Alibaba Cloud, Yuming.com, Tencent Cloud, Baidu Cloud, etc. in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Country or regional domain name registration usually requires payment of a certain fee, which depends on the type of domain name, top-level domain name and registrar. Registration fees are usually annual and require periodic renewal to maintain ownership of the domain name. The price of a domain name is determined by the domain name registry. For example, the price of cn domain name is determined by China Internet Network Information Center (CNNIC). This is the cost price of the domain name. After the domain name registry sets the bulk registration price (wholesale price) for domain name suffixes, the domain name registrar service platform will charge corresponding registration fees and a certain percentage of service fees based on this standard. Domain name registrars have to complete the real-name authentication of domain names and domain name resolution services on behalf of the government, and earn hard-earned money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, a large part of the money Anguilla earns should be due to the country or local hosting companies raising prices. In Deyue, local people registered some domain names and then sold them to the companies that wanted them first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, for hosting providers, the higher the domain name price, the better. First of all, the supply of domain names is actually unlimited. There can be countless domain names in front of a top-level domain name suffix. Therefore, if the hosting agreement is set too high, the sales volume will be reduced, and the total revenue may be reduced. Secondly, domain names still have certain alternatives. For example, you can use .com, .cn, and .net. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A good domain name plays an important role in gathering corporate visibility and popularity. More importantly, the domain name is the identity mark in the Internet era and has &quot;uniqueness&quot;. This becomes an asset. Generally speaking, domain name registration is based on a first-come, first-served principle. Whoever registers it early belongs to it. If a latecomer needs it, he or she will have to pay for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For enterprises, especially large enterprises, domain names are a signal of strength. The reason is very simple. If a company does not have the most suitable domain name for itself, then the domain name must have been registered and the company does not have the strength to buy it back. Therefore, Internet companies are highly dependent on domain names. JD.com, Xiaomi, and Apple all spend a lot of money to buy domain names that are more suitable for them. It has been reported that Apple paid approximately US$1.5 million to acquire the domain http://icloud.net; earlier it spent a huge sum of nearly US$5.2 million for http://icloud.com. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, this kind of domain name registration is not a first-come, first-served basis without a bottom line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Article 8 of the &quot;China Internet Network Information Center Domain Name Dispute Resolution Measures&quot;, you can complain about some domain name registrations. For example, the domain name complained of is the same as the name or logo in which the complainant has civil rights and interests, or is similar enough to cause confusion; the domain name holder complained of does not have legitimate rights and interests in the domain name or its main part; the domain name holder complained of has no legitimate rights and interests. Someone registers or uses the domain name with malicious intent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Article 9 also stipulates the malicious registration or use of domain names. For example, the purpose of registering or transferring a domain name is to sell, lease or otherwise transfer the domain name to the complainant or its competitor who is the owner of the civil rights and interests in order to obtain improper benefits; repeatedly use the name of another person who has legitimate rights and interests; or The logo is registered as its own domain name to prevent others from using the name or logo in which it has legitimate rights and interests in the form of a domain name on the Internet; the domain name is registered or transferred to damage the complainant&#39;s reputation, disrupt the complainant&#39;s normal business activities, or confuse the complainant. and the complainant, misleading the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, it should be pointed out that &quot;registering a domain name with the purpose of selling or leasing&quot; is no longer a criterion for judging malicious intent. For example, it is legal to register an Apple domain name first, and it is legal to sell it to Apple, but it cannot be sold to Apple&#39;s competitors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti ; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《过往人生》：所有分手，皆是前世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3xhFWCTzZEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/QGTof9q2QyCrgQnIXw8Jz9Wl3BVjA3 xhFWCTzZEO. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250685&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The English title of the movie &quot;Past Lives&quot; (&lt;em>;Past Lives&lt;/em>;) is a pun, which is both past life and plural. previous life. This shortlisted film for the main competition of the 2023 Berlin Film Festival has recently been praised by many audiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Nora reunited with Haisheng, a boy who had first fallen in love at the age of 12, after 24 years of separation, she had already changed her English name. On Nora&#39;s left hand side, her husband, American Jewish writer Arthur, sat, speaking English to him; on Nora&#39;s right hand side, Hae Sung, who had miraculously transformed from a child into a mature man, spoke Korean to him. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora and Haisheng discussed that the reason why they can sit here is because they were full of bonds in their previous lives. In those previous lives, they were either a princess secretly in love with her servant, or two people who did not love each other and betrayed each other due to family marriage, or they just happened to be seated next to each other on the train, or they were a bird and the person who carried it. Early morning tree branches. When they parted, they said that this moment might also be the past life. Because the past life is not only the talk of karma in Buddhism, but also a parallel time and space of imaginary, regretful, and missed possibilities. Since their relationship in this life is still full of shortcomings, then think of it as a vague past life, think of it as something that has happened and been written, rather than something that is being created, think of it as a dream and a bubble. Not vividly. What will be their afterlife? No one knows the answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Three past lives or parallel time and space&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the tetralogy of the Japanese writer Mishima Yukio&#39;s posthumous novel series &quot;The Sea of ​​Plenty&quot; , the reincarnation of past life, present life, and afterlife slowly unfolds in a bizarre and reasonable way. It is a completely different view of time from the West. All tragedies can always be soothed by the endless world of possibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the film, at the age of 12, Nora is still called Moon Na-young in Seoul. Her father is a director and her mother is an artist. She is a cultural elite and middle class in South Korea, and she decided to immigrate to Canada with her family. Hae Sung was Na Young&#39;s classmate in elementary school, because Na Young always came first in the exam. Once Hae Sung got the first place in the exam, Na Young became a crybaby. When her classmates asked her why she wanted to immigrate, she said it was because Koreans could not win the Nobel Prize for Literature. Naying drew a bird on Hae Sung&#39;s arm with a colored pen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 24, Nora accidentally found a post looking for her on her father&#39;s Facebook page. Haisheng had been looking for Naying online, but she had already changed her name to Nora Moon. The two communicated through text messages, made video calls, and crush each other again, their hearts pounding. For a while, their relationship was like an exotic online relationship. In order to adapt to Haesheng&#39;s time zone, Nora changed her schedule and got up early to talk to him. When Haesheng was riding the cable car in Namsan, he would also make video calls to Nora and show her Seoul from the air. landscape. But the signal in the air was unstable. After the connection was disconnected, Nora&#39;s expression seemed to be worried that something might happen to Hai Sheng. The network&#39;s Aladdin&#39;s lamp withdrew its promise to her, and Hai Sheng was imprisoned in the darkness of the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Haisheng said to Nora, your Korean is really bad. She said, I only speak Korean to my mother and you. Online dating will always come true one day. Nora hopes that Haisheng will come to New York, where she has dreams of drama and writing. But what she wants now is not the Nobel Prize for Literature, but the Pulitzer Prize. Haisheng is going to China for exchange. He has always wanted to learn Chinese because it will be useful in the future. Is the distance between the two just the vast Pacific Ocean? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 36, Haisheng came to New York under the pretext of traveling, but actually he made a special trip to visit Nora. Nora has been married to Arthur for seven years. Compared with Hai Sheng, Arthur looks ordinary and is used to wearing worn jeans and brown jackets. He is a writer. Of course, he will not take a yacht to see the postcard scenery like the Statue of Liberty like a tourist. But after learning that Nora is accompanying him on the sea Sheng had been to this travel project, but felt a little bit disappointed. He met Nora at a creative writing residency and got married for Nora&#39;s green card. Arthur asked Nora if our story was a little too plain. You only spoke Korean in the dream, which was a world I couldn&#39;t understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora finally sent Hai Sheng to the street where he was waiting for the bus. The two of them were silent for two minutes, one meter apart, as if this meter was the Pacific Ocean. For two minutes, they had no kiss, no lingering affection, no confession. They had never become true lovers. It was not until the car came that they had a hesitant courtesy hug. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why these two minutes of silence are touching? Perhaps no one said it better than the American writer Salinger: &quot;Some people think that love is sex, marriage, a kiss at six o&#39;clock in the morning. Pile of children, that may be true, Miss Leicester. But you know what I think? I think love wants to touch and then withdraws its hand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There is no paradise, no paradise on earth&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Celine Song, the director of &quot;A Life in the Past,&quot; must be no stranger to Salinger. She is a writer of Korean descent in Canada. She came to New York to do theater in her twenties and wrote this story based on similar experiences. A few years ago, she was sitting with her American husband and her childhood friend at a bar in New York&#39;s East Village, and she kept translating for them. Song felt the eyes around him sizing up this strange trio, so he started talking about it in the voice-over at the beginning of the film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song loves romantic dramas. She feels that what drives romantic dramas are often adults who act like children. She hopes that the characters will show what love is like when everyone reveals their feelings for each other. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Korean-American actress Greta Lee, who plays Nora, read the script, she couldn&#39;t help sobbing and had to continue reading with difficulty while crying. Although Greta Lee is a second-generation immigrant born in the United States, she can obviously understand the double dilemma of Asians in North America. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nora told Arthur that in New York, she knew many Korean Americans, but Haisheng was not like them. He was an authentic Korean. However, when chatting with Hai Sheng, she also became more Korean. Nora asked Hai Sheng why he was not married yet. She seemed to have completely lost the New York artist&#39;s tolerance for multiculturalism and marital status, and asked her compatriots in a conservative way of thinking. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the difference in life choices between Hai Sheng and Nora is a metaphor for Korean society: Hai Sheng studied practical engineering and came to China, which has deep historical roots with South Korea and broad economic prospects. Exchange; Nora studies literature and drama and wants to pursue her ambitions in New York, a global cultural center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Nora said that the reason for immigration was that &quot;Koreans cannot win the Nobel Prize for Literature,&quot; this line with quite a comedic effect revealed a common anxiety among third world residents. ：一方面对诺贝尔文学奖代表的文学成就充满认同和钦羡，另一方面无意识地掉进了诺贝尔文学奖评选机制无可避免的西方中心主义陷阱。 “韩国人拿不到……”这一否定句式包含的自恨，背后是对落后地区的社会结构、文化制度、整体创造力的不信任。但当她脱离韩国、使用英语写作时，当她被识别为一个北美的亚裔，她便永远卡在了既非韩国作家也非美国作家的中间状态。因为合租省钱才跟亚瑟搬到一起住，因为移民政策才早早结婚，诺拉问，这真的是父母移民时，期待女儿过上的生活吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;豆瓣网友toska在短评中说：《过往人生》“让我感到最不适的是暗流的优越感”，纽约优于多伦多，多伦多优于首尔，她自己优于或等于美国韩裔，美国韩裔优于韩国人（电影里用的一个词是Korean Koreans，前一个词是文化意义上的韩国人，后一个词是族群意义上的韩国人），“可怕的是我觉得创作者本身是不自知的，却觉得自己委屈。在缺乏自我反思的前提下高歌自身贫瘠的体验和感受”。这或许提供了思考这部影片的另一个角度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年釜山国际电影节的开幕影片《我讨厌韩国》根据小说《走出韩国》改编，主人公桂娜是一个学历、工作、容貌都平平的人，未来的一切都已注定，没有奇迹发生，她说：“韩国爱的人是它自己，而不是我。它只爱让它发光的那些人……而对于那些让它蒙羞的人，它都是避之不及的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样的离散主题，《走出韩国》的主人公是为了逃离内卷和阶层固化，《过往人生》的诺拉是期待登上世界的舞台，留在韩国的海盛则想成为“更优秀”的人，即便身体辛苦，精神也不肯认输。真正的问题是，不论在哪片土地，都不能期待一个人间天堂，没有一劳永逸的乐土，只有永恒的困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海盛问诺拉，假如你12岁时没有出国，假如我24岁时来到了纽约，会有什么不同？也许，正因为他们24年来只有两度惊鸿一瞥，没有陷入生活的琐屑、放大彼此的缺点，这缺憾才完美而迷人，值得诺拉失声痛哭，一边是不完美的祖国的完美的初恋，一边是完美的乌托邦的不完美的日常，她徘徊在曼哈顿的街区，也徘徊于无地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海一初中现投毒事件？警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256619]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:23:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年9月12日15时37分，浦东公安分局接报警称，下南路某中学有多名学生身体不适。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经初步调查，该校学生杨某某（&lt;span>;女，13岁&lt;/span>;）与同班同学郑某某（女，13岁），于当日上午趁体育课期间返回教室，将具有清洁漂白作用的混合液倒入同班学生的水杯内，导致多名学生出现不适症状。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关学生经送医治疗，均于当晚出院，现已恢复正常上课。目前，警方正会同教育部门开展进一步调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;295&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/04bed165965be3c00268163257c169f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当买不起LV包的年轻人入手了百元高奢包装袋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3075a924c16abd1190831eba2b7d2279.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo/ 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;身着最新款香奈儿外套，戴上珍藏版卡地亚手表，拿起爱马仕的“梦中情包”，感受一番娇兰香水的沁人芳香后，正式踏出家门——这是不知多少男孩女孩心中的“奢华&lt;/span>;都市梦”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，一则“浙江人1年花18亿买香奈儿”的帖子引发热议，杭州大厦的香奈儿门店去年销售额达到了18亿元。包括香奈儿在内的一众奢侈品标榜着“有钱”，网友调侃：“贫穷限制了我的想象，有&lt;span>;钱人这么多，为什么不能多我一个。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“普通商场没啥&lt;/span>;人，奢侈品店却排起长龙。”对于奢侈品门店，不少网友有着此类感受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观全国，无论是北京、上海，还是其他城市，爱马仕、香奈儿、古驰等奢侈品品牌的门店常常人满为患，新品发布时更是堪比大型“检票”现场，和普通品牌门店里三三两两的顾客相比，可谓是冰火两重天。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中国的奢侈品热：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;吸睛、吸金千层套路&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;奢侈品在国际上被定义为“一种超出人们生存与发展需要范围的、具有独特、稀缺、珍奇等特点的消费品”,又称为非生活必需品。然而，消费低迷的环境似乎并没有影响“死忠粉”们对这一“非生活必需品”的抢购热情。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;以路易威登的一&lt;/span>;款手袋来说，法国地区售价为一万七千元，在中国内地要卖到两万四千元。除了在门店外大排长龙，还有一群人默默地点开了海外代购平台的页面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为世界奢侈品消费的重要力量，品牌扩张的路上少不了中国市场这块“香饽饽”。《2022中国奢侈品报告》显示，2022年中国人奢侈品市场销售额达9560亿元，同比略微下滑4%，在全球奢侈品市场占比高达38%，其重要性可想而知。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是贵，奢侈品的价格还“一路狂飙”。去年11月，香奈儿将所有产品的价格上调3%到11%，据时尚网站Purse&lt;span>;Bop统计，低端奢侈品的年均涨幅约4%，高端奢侈品则在15%到18%。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;虽然价格“涨涨涨”，奈何抵不住买主的热情，抢购奢侈品俨然成为了一种备受追捧的时尚。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2831&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e55eb820dad92ee5310bf926fa491c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“追奢”背后，是奢侈品品牌倾力打造的&lt;/span>;“吸睛”“吸金”双管齐下的千层套路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着“元宇宙”概念的火热，众多品牌将目光投向了这一新鲜玩法。古驰曾与游戏平台Roblox合作，开设古驰快闪店，推出一款数字版古驰酒神包被炒至4100美元，比实体包高出700美元。而巴黎世家也为游戏《堡垒之夜》多个角色制作虚拟服装，玩家花8美元就能穿上“正版皮肤”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“这钱不花白不花，现实中买不起，就游戏里享受享受呗。”资深的游戏玩家小罗谈及购买“皮肤”的看法时提及。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不仅如此，普拉达、路易威登、博柏利等品牌都纷纷试水“元宇宙”。这波操作免不了网友调侃：“现实里的韭菜&lt;/span>;割不完，又来割&#39;元宇宙&#39;的韭菜了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打破消费次元壁还不够，“它经济”的火热风口同样少不了奢侈品的身影。所谓“宠随主贵”，不少猫狗在宠主的“万般宠爱”下享受着奢华猫/狗生。五千元的牵引绳、两万元的宠物便携包、一万七千元的宠物床……爱马仕推出的宠物用品，主打一个“金贵”，“这年头，狗都比我有钱。”宠主小方在社交媒体上评论，“怎么连宠物也内卷，哭了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/11101fec82b3cfae0de0403e6b42fd04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当然，奢侈品品牌不会放过任何的潜在消费者。除了箱包、服饰、珠宝这些传统项目，手机壳、耳机套、钥匙扣等小物件也悄然而出。某种草博主在小红书上写道：“买不起五位数的路易&lt;/span>;威登包包，还买不起周边？冲冲冲！”不知有多少买主上了头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;翻开奢侈品品牌的商品目录，还可以看到不少的新奇产品：棺材、装尸袋……款式丰富、价格昂贵。网友脑洞大开：“这难道就是&lt;span>;传说中的&#39;优雅地死去&#39;？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/d79f42d88a980d5c9755b3b6e5f06bec.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC pho&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;to / 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;年轻人玩高奢：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;二手买卖、大牌小样&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;奢侈品消费水平与城市经济实力有着密不可分的关系。《2019奢侈品行业洞察报告》显示，中国内地奢&lt;/span>;侈品消费水平城市排行榜中，北京和上海被分别位列第一和第二。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在爱马仕的全国53家门店中，除去港澳台共20家门店，北京和上海分别达到了5家，占据中国内地门店数量的近1/3。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在这些买主中，高净值群体（中国内地拥有千万元人民币资产）是消费“顶流”，他们和“奢侈品”像是双向奔赴的最佳拍档。不过，如今奢侈品消费者不只是传统的“高端局买家”，包括数量巨大的年轻人，都能成为买主。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报告显示，中国奢侈品市场的90后成为了奢侈品消费的主力军，占总体市场消费人群的50%。与此同时，贝恩奢侈品研究报告曾预测，到2025年，千禧一代及25岁以下的消费者将成为奢侈品消费市场的主力军，占比将达65%至70%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为潜力派的年轻人，奢侈品品牌为打通他们在数字营销方面下了不少功夫——68%的年轻人会被明星或博主所发布的内容“种草”，进而产生购买行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4537&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e5c0fce6c515d725e8f04f8432c32e6a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不过，并非所有年轻人都有着惊人的财力，年轻买家靠着“精致穷”买二手也能玩转奢侈品。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《2021年中国二手奢侈品行业概览》显示，半数以上的二手奢侈品消费者在30岁以下，过半消&lt;/span>;费者的购买原因是价格比新品低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;买了卖，卖了买，市面上的“绝版”货能通过二手方式淘到，双方在买卖中享受着奢侈品流转的快乐。据统计，市场上有超半数的用户选择“既买又卖”，“买卖一体化”趋势显著。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《2023年循环时尚行业趋势报告》显示，2020年国内二手奢侈品市场规模达173亿元，预计2025年或将达到384&lt;span>;亿元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;买家淘货的类别多样，主要集中在箱包皮具、服饰鞋帽、高级腕表和珠宝配饰等领域，由于受众广、保值高等原因，箱包皮具成为了二手奢侈品消费者的首选。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;面对易耗损的高奢化妆品，还有更为实惠的“大牌小样”法。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“两三位数的价格就能享受到大牌，何乐而不为？”大三学生小甜是个化妆小白，和许多美妆达人一样，她集齐了各种大牌粉底、口红、香水、护肤品，唯一的区别是她的都是“&lt;/span>;小样”：“一个月化妆的次数不超过十次，买正装浪费，买便宜的担心，大牌会心安一点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;庞大的消费市场驱动下，商家嗅到了商机，不仅“小样”被单独出售，大牌化妆品的分装版也深受追捧。电商平台上，100ml的香奈儿嘉柏丽尔天性香水官方售价约1690元，其10ml的“小样”仅需约130元。但这些产品多是被店名为“XX代购”或其他难以判断正规性的店铺出售，产品鱼龙混杂、真假难辨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1074&quot; height=&quot;3659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/395ada715de24f8838c649ee3df1a1a7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;同时，还有一度火出圈的“物尽其&lt;/span>;用”法。抖音、小红书等平台曾掀起外包装改造风。一些博主几经折腾，印着品牌logo的包装袋或包装盒就被变身成为纸巾盒、首饰盒，以及可外带的包包，一时间催&lt;span>;热了奢侈品外包装的购买潮流。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;目前闲鱼上仍有不少人在出售奢侈品外包装，从几十元到上百元不等，前来询价者络绎不绝。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/81d34f1a3f06b0fefb0cfdf0094fee02.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;IC photo / 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;奢侈品争议：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;正品质量堪忧，假货率达80%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不&lt;/span>;过，奢侈品留给大众的印象不仅是昂贵，还是深陷争议的产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，网络上几乎每年都会轮番嘲笑某些奢侈品推出的“传奇”单品。比如登上时装周的“搬家专用编织袋”、长满绿草的运动鞋、“葬爱家族”同款杀马特假刘海，还有“躲雨躲个寂寞”的破洞雨伞等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不管是不是设计师有意为之，营销效果拉满，即便全网吐槽，也挡不住一批人偷偷下单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，奢侈品购物被各路博主描述为“魔咒”般的体验。“穿便宜衣服进店后被鄙视”“柜姐看不起普通人”……此类购物测评充斥着短视频平台，网络的放大使得不少人产生了对奢侈品店的恐惧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再者，奢侈品的质量问题饱受诟病。今年2月，福建的张女士在成都旅游时花两万元购入一个香奈儿手袋，结果刚背15分&lt;span>;钟链条就断了。此类问题屡见不鲜，黑猫投诉平台上关于奢侈品的各类投诉层出不穷。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;网络上有一个流传甚广的段子：如&lt;/span>;果买回来的奢侈品包包出现掉色等问题，不用怀疑一定是真货，如果特别结实、耐磨，那就要小心可能是假货了。“要客数据”显示，在品牌官方渠道外的其他渠道中，假货率高达80%以上。目前的中国市场，奢侈品假货数量是真货的6倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;4178&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/98b41035a658c2ee30e3fce4924cce4f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;更让人绷紧神经&lt;/span>;的，莫过于近几年频出的奢侈品抄袭问题。去年，迪奥推出的一款中长半身裙撞车中国传统服饰“马面裙”，品牌却称其为“迪奥标志性廓形”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无独有偶，“马面裙”事件余波未了，迪奥推出2022年的秋冬系列服装，标注原创的迪奥冬季花园图案再一次撞车中国国画“花鸟图”。面对接一连二的抄袭行为，抵制“文化挪用”的声音愈发响亮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，目前备受追捧的世界级奢侈品依然主要来自海外。反观我国本土品牌，在成为世界名片的路上还有着巨大的成长空间，我们也期待着本土品牌在国际上&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育部启动首届全国大学生职业规划大赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the Ministry of Education issued a notice to launch the first National College Student Career Planning Competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first National College Student Career Planning Competition, with the theme of &quot;Building Dreams and Aiming for Youth in All Places, Planning to Start Careers and Lead the Future&quot;, was co-sponsored by the Ministry of Education and the Shanghai Municipal People&#39;s Government. By holding competitions, we strive to create a large classroom that strengthens career education, a large platform that promotes the connection between talent supply and demand, and a large market that serves graduates&#39; employment. We strengthen career education and employment guidance in colleges and universities, enhance college students&#39; awareness of career planning, and guide college students to prepare for employment as early as possible. Better promote high-quality and full employment of college graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition will be held from September 2023 to May 2024. It will adopt a three-level competition system of school competition, provincial competition, and national finals. It will set up a growth track, an employment track, and career development and employment guidance courses for college students. The teaching track is for teachers of career development and employment guidance courses for junior and middle school students, senior students and college students in colleges and universities. The school competition is organized by each university, and the provincial competition is organized by each locality. The national finals are hosted by the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission, Fudan University, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai Normal University, and Shanghai Vocational College of Arts and Crafts. There are gold, silver, and bronze awards, as well as individual awards, local and university outstanding organizations. Award, Outstanding Instructor Award and other awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Registration for the competition will begin on September 20, 2023. At that time, participating students can register through the National College Student Career Planning Competition platform (website: zgs.chsi.com.cn) or designated channels. Registration deadline The time is determined by each locality according to the provincial competition arrangement. During the competition, universities across the country will also hold a series of activities such as employment guidance, campus recruitment, school-enterprise supply and demand matching, and career experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《校外培训行政处罚暂行办法》颁布：严管校外培训，能否压缩外力鸡娃的空间？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Education promulgated the &quot;Interim Measures for Administrative Penalties for Off-Campus Training&quot;, with 6 chapters and 44 articles, which will be implemented in 2023 It will come into effect on October 15, 2020. As soon as the regulations of this department were promulgated, they attracted concern from all parties, especially training institutions and their employees and even parents, who wanted to know where the legal and illegal boundaries of off-campus training were drawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common consensus among everyone is that in-service teachers should not engage in off-campus training. Article 16 of the above-mentioned measures stipulates that if the parties involved &quot;are in-service teachers in primary and secondary schools and the training content is subject-based off-campus training&quot;, they shall be severely punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been cases like this: a teacher did not teach well in class, and then mobilized students to participate in paid private training organized by him, and even put small shoes on students who did not participate. This is undoubtedly against professional ethics. Public school teachers, teaching is their main job, and they have to be worthy of the salary they receive. How can they charge students a second time for the content that should be taught in the classroom? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what are the core contents and provisions of this regulation? The following three points deserve attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, Article 2 of the Measures stipulates: If a natural person, legal person or other organization recruits preschool children, primary and secondary school students over 3 years old from the society, and illegally conducts off-campus training, and shall be given administrative penalties, these Measures shall apply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, if a natural person or institution enrolls infants and young children under 3 years old, it is almost equivalent to day care. It is okay for the children in day care to play educational games and recite Tang poetry. It will be considered as off-campus training or illegal off-campus training. Indeed, logically, only when a child goes to kindergarten or school can there be &quot;school&quot;, and only then can there be &quot;outside school&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for this article, the General Provisions do not define &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Among the various types of penalties, specific circumstances of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; should be punished. The basis for the document&#39;s definition of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; is: the 2021 &quot;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Training Burden of Students in Compulsory Education&quot; issued by the two offices in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;double reduction&quot; programmatic document defines the boundaries of off-campus training as follows: for training institutions, &quot;all localities will no longer approve new subject-based off-campus training institutions for students in compulsory education. All discipline-based training institutions are uniformly registered as non-profit institutions, and the original registered online discipline-based training institutions are changed to an approval system.&quot; For training content, &quot;Establish a training content filing and supervision system, and formulate and release training materials for off-campus training institutions. &quot;Management Measures&quot; &quot;It is strictly prohibited to exceed the standard and advance training, it is strictly prohibited to engage in subject-based training by non-disciplinary training institutions, and it is strictly prohibited to provide overseas education courses&quot;; for students and teachers, &quot;Online training must pay attention to protecting students&#39; vision, and each class period shall not exceed 30 minutes. The interval should be no less than 10 minutes, and the training end time should be no later than 21:00. &quot;The hiring of foreign personnel within the country must comply with relevant national regulations. It is strictly prohibited to hire foreign personnel abroad to carry out training activities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this measure stipulates that the &quot;off-campus training competent department&quot; shall enforce the law and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Article 6 stipulates that administrative penalties for off-campus training shall be implemented by the off-campus training authorities of governments at or above the county level, and the off-campus training authorities shall be determined by provincial governments in accordance with relevant national regulations. So, is the “off-campus training authority” the local education bureau or education committee? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This regulation is formulated and promulgated by the Ministry of Education, which also authorizes provincial governments to determine what is the competent authority for off-campus training. There is a trend in administrative law enforcement: instead of allowing each department to enforce the law on its own, a comprehensive law enforcement agency will be established to ensure that law enforcement is carried out within legitimate substantive matters and due procedures, and to reduce the number of departments that rely on the weak and the weak. Create space for rent-seeking to reduce nuisance to natural persons and enterprises and improve the business environment. Therefore, it remains to be seen who will enforce the law on &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this measure is very strict. It must control and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. The subjects include not only institutions, and the identification standards for institutions are strict, but also natural persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict standards for the identification of institutions. Article 17 of the Measures stipulates that if a natural person, legal person or other organization conducts off-campus training without approval and meets these three conditions, (1) there is a special training venue for offline training, and a specific website or application for online training, (2) Having more than 2 training practitioners, (3) having corresponding organizational structure and division of labor constitutes &quot;organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization&quot;, and will be ordered to stop organizing, refund the fees charged, and impose a fine of more than double the illegal income A fine of up to five times. This means that a mom-and-pop shop or a partnership shop between friends that handles training and operations, with as few as two people, may be recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution.&quot; Once recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution&quot; and without approval before opening, it may It constitutes organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict control over individuals engaged in subject training. Article 18 of the Measures stipulates that natural persons, legal persons or other organizations carry out off-campus training in subject areas in disguise, but do not meet the conditions stipulated in Article 17 of these Measures and commit any of the following acts: (1) Through instant messaging, online conferencing, live broadcast platforms, etc. (2) Using residential buildings, hotels, cafes and other places to organize paid off-campus training such as &quot;one-to-one&quot; and &quot;one-to-many&quot;; (3) Using consultation, cultural dissemination, quality development, For paid off-campus training in the name of competitions, thinking training, housekeeping services, family education guidance, live-in teachers, crowdfunding private tutors, study tours, study tours, winter and summer camps, trusteeship, etc., the punishment can range from an order to make corrections and a refund of fees to a fine. A fine of not less than 50,000 yuan but not more than 100,000 yuan is imposed. In theory, college students who serve as tutors will also be subject to supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Landlords or business premises that provide premises will also be subject to joint penalties. Article 19 of the Measures: If a natural person, legal person or other organization knows or should know that illegal off-campus training activities exist, but still provides a place for them to carry out off-campus training, the punishment can range from being ordered to make corrections within a time limit to being given a warning or a notice of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This measure began to solicit opinions in November last year. Now that it has finally been implemented, it will definitely have a profound impact on the form and pattern of off-campus subject training. If implemented to the letter, it will greatly reduce the space for parents to rely on external forces to help their children. Of course, it remains to be seen how much this will shake the parents’ determination and motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[仅仅多一项选择，外卖平台就显著减少了污染]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256558]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 8, 2023, the magazine &quot;Science&quot; published a report by the University of Hong Kong, Peking University, etc. The results of the research team, “Green Boosting Reduced Disposable Tableware Use: Evidence from China’s Takeaway Industry.” This paper studies the impact of the green promotion practice of changing the cutlery selection user interface of the Ele.me food delivery platform on the consumption of disposable tableware (SUC) and the reduction of plastic waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This new study of 10 major cities in China shows that making &quot;no cutlery&quot; the default option when placing orders on food delivery apps and rewarding customers who choose not to use plastic cutlery can significantly reduce the number of orders The waste of sexual tableware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, the fact that the results of a study involving environmental protection, business, psychology and economics can be published in a world-class journal is enough to show the importance of this research. More importantly, this study answers an important question and provides an idea and method to solve the problem, that is, environmental protection not only requires green promotion, but also requires joint efforts online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as September 2017, the Chongqing Green Volunteer Federation took Meituan, Baidu Waimai and Ele.me to court on the grounds of causing waste of resources and environmental pollution. Volunteers believe that the defendant did not provide users with the option of &quot;whether to use disposable tableware&quot;, causing the system to default to distributing disposable tableware, causing huge waste of resources and ecological damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is first of all focusing on offline environmental protection to online ordering. In response to the green volunteers’ complaints and facing severe environmental protection issues and huge responsibilities, food delivery industry giants have responded positively. In 2018, Meituan and Ele.me launched environmental protection programs such as the &quot;Qingshan Plan&quot; and &quot;Blue Planet Plan&quot; respectively. When ordering meals, users can choose &quot;no tableware required&quot; to help environmental protection. In addition, some takeout platforms encourage merchants to use environmentally friendly paper bags instead of plastic bags for takeout packaging to reduce environmental pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if these food delivery companies responded at that time, some people still suspected that it was not easy to solve the pollution problem derived from food delivery. The food delivery platform alone had limited effect and had to go through food delivery merchants and food delivery platforms. Only through the joint efforts of multiple relevant parties, including lunch box manufacturers and consumers, can the problem be alleviated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the results of scientific research have provided a preliminary answer to these questions and doubts. As long as we do and take action, even if it is just one link of effort, it is possible to reduce plastic pollution and improve the environment, and the results will be Significant, significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the research results of Chinese and foreign research teams, Alibaba’s online food ordering platform Eleme (similar to Uber Eats and DoorDash) has made adjustments in the application using the concept of green promotion: 1. Add a pop-up window that requires customers to explicitly select the quantity of disposable cutlery in their order; 2. Set the default value of the pop-up window to &quot;no cutlery&quot;; 3. Provide a small non-monetary reward to those who choose not to use cutlery --Some &quot;Ant Forest Green Dots.&quot; These green points can be redeemed for planting real trees in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An analysis of detailed customer-level data on the ordering history of 197,062 randomly selected users in 10 major cities in China from 2019 to 2021 found that these green boosts significantly reduced the use of disposable tableware. The proportion of orders without cutlery increased by 648%. If implemented across China, such an intervention could save more than 21.75 billion sets of disposable tableware, reduce 3.26 million tons of plastic waste, and save 5.44 million trees each year, without affecting the business performance or revenue of Alibaba or individual restaurants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This result is a win-win for all, but it is not just a win-win for all. It provides a feasible measure to reduce plastic pollution that can be used as a reference, especially for countries with large populations and countries that use a lot of plastic products. effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a February 2022 report from the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), global plastic production increased from 2.34 million tons to 460 million tons from 2000 to 2019. The generation of plastic waste has more than doubled, reaching 353 million tons in 2019. According to the United Nations Environment Program, plastics account for at least 85% of total marine debris. In 2019 alone, 22 million tons of plastic were released into the environment, with 6 million tons ending up in rivers, lakes and oceans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, 32% of the world&#39;s plastics were produced in China; more than half of the plastics came from Asia. China&#39;s production alone accounts for 1/3 (32%) of global production. China is also the world&#39;s largest producer and consumer of disposable tableware. In 2022, more than 753 million users will be active users of takeout services, and more than 50 million sets of disposable tableware that have not been fully recycled or processed are consumed every day, including Plastic bags, plastic forks, plastic spoons, wooden chopsticks and napkins. Therefore, reducing disposable tableware is an urgent and important mission. Moreover, China has also set a goal of reducing the use of disposable tableware in takeout food delivery by 30% by 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now it seems that as long as the online ordering platform scientifically sets up the program, it can greatly reduce the use of disposable tableware, and it will not reduce the order volume and the income of the platform and restaurants. This is of course an online platform. It can only be accomplished by the joint efforts of both online and offline. However, there is also a scientific basis for implementing such measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The changes to the user interface of the Ele.me food ordering app reflect the concept of &quot;nudging&quot; in behavioral economics and social psychology, that is, changing the choice environment (or choice architecture) or providing indirect information to influence individuals Methods of behavior and decision-making. The key characteristic of nudges is that they do not limit the choices available to an individual, nor do they alter monetary incentives, but they can provide some kind of boost or promotion, such as environmental protection. Moreover, nudges have been used in many social fields. From this concept, online and offline actions can greatly reduce the use of disposable tableware, thereby protecting the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the green promotion of the food ordering platform is not perfect, and there are also shortcomings that need to be improved. First, although customers choose &quot;no cutlery required&quot; when ordering, some businesses still provide disposable cutlery. The reason is that this happens when merchants are too busy to check orders one by one or worry that consumers may have chosen the &quot;no cutlery required&quot; option by mistake; second, customers often waste their green energy or fail to accumulate enough green energy. energy to plant trees; third, the impact of the green boost was most evident in the first few months after implementation but declined slightly over time, suggesting that some customers later decided to change the default “no cutlery required” option . This is consistent with previous research on the attenuation effect of default options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, to solve these problems, more efforts must be made offline. Of course, if green boosting can be tried and promoted on all domestic food ordering platforms, as well as food ordering platforms in other countries, such as DoorDash and Uber Eats, global plastic waste will be greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼儿园教师，过剩还是不足？村小撤并与否，有更好的选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGKVGV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1116&quot; height=&quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGK VGV. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 8, 2022, a kindergarten in Zhongmu County, Zhengzhou City. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, Xiong Bingqi, director of the 21st Century Education Research Institute, participated in a training for teachers in small rural schools. A principal told him that the local government was once willing to open small rural schools, but now almost all of them are not in favor of it and believe that they should be withdrawn and merged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Education Statistical Yearbook&quot;, the number of rural primary schools in China dropped from 416,198 in 2001 to 90,603 in 2018, a decrease of 325,595. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A major background for the decrease in the number of rural primary schools is the declining birth rate. The results of the seventh national census show that the proportion of China&#39;s population aged 0 to 14 is 17.95%, which is lower than the standard of 20% of the total population defined by the narrow concept of low birthrate. Correspondingly, the number of kindergarten-age children has also decreased, posing challenges to the development of preschool education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the birthrate continues to decline, how should preschool education respond? With declining birth rate and urbanization, where will small rural schools go? On September 7, 2023, the &quot;Transformation of Education in the New Era&quot; seminar and the &quot;China Education Observation (2022)&quot; new book preview event hosted by the 21st Century Education Research Institute were held in Beijing. Many participating scholars focused on these educational issues. discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;When there are less than&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;56 students, the kindergarten cannot maintain operation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;If To maintain operations, kindergartens must have a certain scale.&quot; Liu Shanhuai, a professor at Northeast Normal University&#39;s China Rural Education Development Research Institute, came to this conclusion after conducting calculations on an inclusive kindergarten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The calculation results of that kindergarten show that the monthly education fee for each student is 390 yuan, which is charged for 9 months a year. The government subsidizes kindergartens for 12 months per year at a rate of 365 yuan per student per month. When there are fewer than 56 students, the kindergarten cannot maintain operations. The number of students must be no less than 115 to maintain a good operating level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;855&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, Beijing, Professor Liu Shanhuai (middle) of the China Rural Education Development Research Institute of Northeast Normal University shared at the seminar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewee/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impact chain of declining birthrate, preschool education bears the brunt. Xiong Bingqi believes that the government should increase investment in preschool education and “should not plan future development according to the existing resource guarantee model.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He further suggested that preschool education should be guaranteed in accordance with compulsory education standards, that is, compulsory education should be extended to 12 years, which is conducive to building a child-friendly society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the number of students entering kindergarten is decreasing, Feng Wanzhen, associate professor at the Department of Education of Beijing Normal University, noticed that the number of kindergarten teachers in China has nearly tripled in 2020 compared with 2010, with an increase of 3.349 million teaching staff. , the number of full-time teachers increased by 1.769 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the growth data, she found that some areas already have a surplus of kindergarten teachers, but in some areas there is still a serious shortage. As of 2020, there are still 11 provinces including Guangxi, Yunnan, and Sichuan where the ratio of the total number of children in kindergarten to the total number of full-time teachers has not reached the minimum standard for large class configurations stipulated in the &quot;Kindergarten Staff Staffing Standards (Interim)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Feng Wanzhen’s view, faced with the imbalance of teacher resources, reasonable coordination should be carried out to supplement the structural shortage of kindergarten teachers. In some areas with abundant teacher resources, we can explore the integration of daycare and kindergarten teachers and divert kindergarten teachers into the team of daycare teachers who are in short supply. At the same time, combined with its own actual conditions, the kindergarten&#39;s service forms will be expanded and the benefits of existing teacher resources will be brought into play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the number of teachers has increased significantly, kindergarten teachers have a high turnover problem due to low salary, insufficient staffing and other reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the above issues, the &quot;Draft Preschool Education Law&quot;, which has been submitted to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress for first review in August 2023, stipulates kindergarten teachers&#39; salaries, benefits, staffing, etc.: Private kindergartens should refer to local public kindergartens The salary income level of similar teachers should reasonably determine the teacher&#39;s salary standard, and social insurance should be paid in accordance with the law; kindergarten teachers enjoy the same treatment as primary and secondary school teachers in terms of professional title evaluation, job appointment (employment), etc.; local establishment departments at all levels follow the basic establishment standards for kindergarten teachers and staffing standards, the number of teaching staff in public kindergartens is approved and dynamically adjusted, and the local education department, in conjunction with the human resources and social security department, promptly replenishes teachers in public kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is difficult to achieve &quot;small but excellent&quot; in rural schools&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike preschool education, which has begun to face the impact of declining birthrate in recent years, small-scale rural schools also have to face the impact of urbanization. The challenges of globalization and the existential crisis come earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If rural education has higher quality, the school-age population will not have to flow into urban areas to choose high-quality education.” Liu Shanhuai believes that the positive interaction between education and population should be achieved by improving the allocation of educational resources. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During research in a county-level city in Northeast China, he learned that the city will have more than 1,200 people born in 2022, and will lose another 300 to 400 people when they enter primary school six years later. The first-grade school-age population will only be There are 800 to 900 people left. This means that “if the distribution of students is not considered, (the city only needs) one primary school is enough.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in reality, students are scattered. When students move from rural to urban areas, the supply of educational resources will not necessarily be more adequate. But it is foreseeable that the number of students in rural schools will become smaller and smaller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Shanhuai believes: &quot;In the future, small-scale rural schools will be the norm, and more and more central schools will become small-scale schools, and more and more teaching points will disappear.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;In his view, some scholars’ expectations for “small but excellent” rural schools are difficult to realize based on the existing resource allocation, and whether they can offer a complete range of subjects is also a question mark. He gave an example. According to the teacher-student ratio of 1:19, a certain school has 12 students distributed in three grades. &quot;One teacher is simply not enough.&quot; This will lead to low-quality and inefficient operation of small schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the quality of teaching will be affected, Liu Shanhuai is worried that if the number of students in the school is too small, it will also affect students&#39; social development, mental health and communication skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of rural schools is indeed continuing to decrease. During the question and answer session, a reporter shared her findings from interviews in a county in Henan. The county will close a total of 70 rural schools in 2023. According to the plan, schools with less than 50 students will be merged this year, schools with less than 100 students next year, and schools with less than 200 students the year after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liu Shanhuai’s view, simply using the number of students in a school as the criteria for merging schools is too single and unreasonable. The reduction in the number of schools is more convenient for administrators, but it increases the distance for students to go to school and also brings inconvenience to parents. &quot;The distribution of rural schools should be determined according to the natural population distribution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decline in students is difficult to reverse. How to improve the quality of rural schools? Liu Shanhuai believes that public funding standards based on the number of students cannot meet the actual needs of rural schools, and the funding structure should be improved to ensure the economic foundation for the development of rural education. At the same time, we will consolidate diverse supplementary channels for rural teachers through targeted training of rural teachers, special post plans, and retired teaching support. In the information age, the application of information technology can also help improve the level of rural education. The configuration of hardware facilities and the construction of digital resources in rural schools should be further strengthened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2012, the number of compulsory education schools in rural areas was significantly reduced, which led to longer distances for some students to go to school, increased traffic safety hazards, increased financial burdens on students’ families, and caused a shortage of boarding schools in rural areas and some urban To address issues such as excessive school class sizes, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Adjustment of the Layout of Rural Compulsory Education Schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opinions call for resolutely stopping the blind dismantling of rural compulsory education schools. At the same time, the layout of rural compulsory education schools should ensure that students need to go to school nearby. In principle, villages with relatively concentrated populations should set up village primary schools or teaching points. Sparsely populated, Teaching points should be reserved or set up in remote and inaccessible places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the aforementioned training for teachers of small rural schools, several principals from Henan once again strongly called for an end to the one-size-fits-all approach to withdrawing and merging schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After conducting grassroots research, Liu Shanhuai found that in practice, whether to withdraw and merge small schools faces conflicts among many parties, and &quot;there is no best choice.&quot; Education department staff reported to him that the original withdrawal of schools was due to the consideration of integrating educational resources. Criticisms emerged after the merger, arguing that students have to travel further to school and that the cost of education for families has increased. But now many small schools have been retained, and there are different opinions that students do not develop as well as in county schools and township central schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Shanhuai said that in the face of this conflict, there is currently a lack of scientific standards. He suggested comprehensively considering various factors such as the comprehensive development of students, education costs and educational equity, and issuing operational guidelines at the national level to provide reference for various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>