<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[男子有偿代骂被拘：Al正推动新业态进化，购买服务者是否担责？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260134]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a security case has attracted attention. According to the Zhuzhou police report, the man Yi Mou uses paid &quot;scolding&quot; on the Internet as a way to make money. According to the customer&#39;s requirements, he personally attacks and insults specific objects through WeChat and phone calls, and charges fees ranging from 20 to 30 yuan. , causing serious impact on the victim’s work and life. From February 2023 to now, Yi has made more than 3,000 yuan in profits by relying on such illegal services. Currently, Yi has been placed under administrative detention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time that practitioners of scolding have been punished. In August 2023, the police in Changsha, Hunan Province captured Li Moudong, who posted a &quot;swearing&quot; advertisement online, and detained him in accordance with the law. According to police investigation, Li Moudong helped customers verbally abuse others online on designated social platforms for 100 yuan a day, and has made illegal profits of nearly 10,000 yuan since October 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The risk of &quot;scolding on behalf of others&quot; is that the person being scolded may call the police. Article 42 of the &quot;Public Security Administration Punishment Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;repeatedly sending obscene, insulting, threatening or other information that interferes with the normal life of others&quot; constitutes a violation and shall be detained for not more than five days or fined not more than 500 yuan; if the circumstances are serious, In serious cases, the offender shall be detained for not less than five days but not more than ten days, and may also be fined not more than five hundred yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the police punish the illegal behavior of &quot;screamers&quot;, there are also several issues worthy of in-depth consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, scolding has already broken the law. Do people who purchase &quot;scolding services&quot; need to bear legal responsibility? In other words, by spending this money, the buyer can &quot;use someone&#39;s mouth to curse others&quot;, thereby achieving the effect of &quot;using a borrowed knife to kill people&quot;, and can still exempt themselves from responsibility? Judging from this case, Yi has replaced at least a hundred people to insult others. If there are cases of &quot;serious consequences&quot;, then the person who paid for the &quot;mouth substitute&quot; has become a hidden &quot;behind-the-scenes manipulator&quot; , you can brazenly &quot;buy evil and curse others&quot;. Is this because the target of each business is too small and not handled? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that if two or more people jointly commit infringement and cause damage to others, they shall bear joint and several liability. Anyone who instigates or helps others commit infringements shall bear joint and several liability with the perpetrator. Theoretically, the person who purchases the scolding service is the source of the infringement, which meets the identification standard of &quot;instigating and helping others to commit infringement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;swearing&quot; itself is a very broad and general concept, and there is a problem of how to define it. Which verbal attacks are considered curses, and which curses are personal attacks and insults that are suspected of illegal crimes? There is still a very large range of distribution, and it is not suitable to generalize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also &quot;swearing&quot; in a broad sense. Verbal counterattacks after encountering injustice are obviously not comparable to organized and premeditated verbal bullying and insults. The former can be regarded as legitimate in language no matter how you say it. defensive. In addition to the &quot;cussing service&quot;, there is also the &quot;quarrel service&quot;. This kind of &quot;storm in the teapot&quot; is less likely to be suspected of illegal crimes. Following this line of thinking, the old-school literati&#39;s &quot;knowing yourself and your enemy&quot;, &quot;stopping in moderation&quot;, &quot;speaking elegantly&quot; and &quot;retreating in order to advance&quot; - these &quot;elegant scolding&quot; tactics used today are still outdated, and I am afraid it will be more difficult to classify them as words and deeds that violate the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine that the reason why these scolders were detained was because their words and deeds met the definition of personal attack and insult, constituted an infringement on the victim, and were even suspected of illegal crimes, rather than general &quot;swearing someone&quot;. The development of mobile Internet technology has only made personal attacks, insults, slander and defamation more convenient, and has even turned it into a &quot;service&quot; that can be traded on the platform. Technology itself is neutral, and there will naturally be &quot;services to praise&quot; and &quot;services to scold&quot;. These &quot;emotional needs&quot; are rooted in the depths of human nature. &quot;Screaming service&quot; seems to be a new thing, but its core is quite old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, since &quot;cussing service&quot; is a new business format supported by Internet technology, technological progress may also give rise to newer &quot;swearing&quot; business formats. This is probably worthy of careful consideration and strict enforcement. Alert. Generative AI, represented by the large language model ChatGPT, may bring about an even crazier and unimaginable future. It is conceivable that today&#39;s &quot;scolding services&quot; are just real people &quot;taking orders and scolding&quot; on the Internet. What if it is &quot;AI scolding&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, AI-trained face-changing, onomatopoeia, and composition are almost real. It is completely possible to clone a real person’s digital life in cyberspace, and then use a virtual number/account to intervene in reality. If you are scolded by a real-life AI dummy with a voice that is exactly the same as in real life, or by a completely virtual AI dummy, and the content of the insult is highly consistent with your personal information, and the person involved is difficult to trace , the various troubles and legal risks caused by it will definitely be several orders of magnitude higher than today&#39;s scolding by real people, which will bring greater difficulties to the protection of personality rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, if you think that someone in real life has scolded you, in fact, it is just a third party that has purchased an AI scolding service that only extracts and uses the timbre and voice characteristics of a real person. You may mistakenly have an actual interaction with the real person. Conflict, and all this is the result of manipulation by a third party. The problem this creates is to some extent isomorphic to video head-swapping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the recent popularity of &quot;AI dubbing&quot; as an example. From Trump to singer Taylor Swift, everyone can speak Mandarin with their own distinctive voice. &quot;AI is replacing voice workers.&quot; The prospect is not far away. If this technology is also used to &quot;scream on someone&#39;s behalf&quot;, the consequences will be even more sensational than if a real person scolds someone on their behalf. Imagine that one day your communication tool receives &quot;insulting audio and video messages&quot; from relatives, friends and even celebrities. The mental damage alone may be enough for you, and it will also take time and effort to resolve misunderstandings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in the face of the nascent &quot;cussing service&quot; and the raging generative artificial intelligence, it is indeed necessary to proactively clarify its boundaries and define which swearing behaviors are infringing and which are suspected of illegal crimes. Purchase Do service providers who curse others need to be held accountable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雨季炮火，“三兄弟联盟”联军激战缅北]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 2, 2023, new refugees continue to arrive at Kokang 125 refugees Camp. Photo provided by interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2e83a721df.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2e83a721df.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 2, 2023, new refugees continued to enter the Kokang 125 refugee camp. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 7, 2023, local time, Min Aung Hlaing’s armed stronghold No. 11 at Dashuitang in the Western District of Kokang, Myanmar, was attacked. After 30 minutes of fierce fighting, the stronghold was captured by the Myanmar Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army (also known as the Kokang Alliance Army). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the Kokang Allied Forces shared a battlefield video on social platforms. In the video, the red flag of the Confederate Army was flying high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, the Kokang Alliance Army, the Arakan Army and the Ta&#39;ang National Liberation Army formed the &quot;Three Brothers Alliance&quot; and launched armed attacks on the Myanmar Army&#39;s military strongholds in many places in northern Myanmar. attack. For more than ten days since then, the Kokang Allied Forces have maintained a daily update frequency on social media and announced their results in a high-profile manner. According to the Kokang Alliance Army, the Northern Myanmar Alliance Army has occupied more than 120 National Defense Forces camps and is still continuing to advance towards Lao Cai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Myanmar military government rarely expressed its position, only responding that three government-controlled areas were out of control. On November 2, the Myanmar National Defense Force declared a state of emergency and will launch a counterattack soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, civilian armed forces often launched operations against the Myanmar government forces alone. Even with the assistance of coalition forces, they fought alone on separate lines. However, this time the military operation of the Kokang Alliance Army not only involved civilian armed forces, but also It has also received response and support from other anti-military forces, which will make the war situation more complicated.&quot; Heng Kai, a Burmese Chinese scholar and assistant professor at the Institute of Overseas Chinese and Regional Countries at Huaqiao University, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the fighting continues to escalate. The northern Myanmar coalition forces and the National Defense Forces are constantly exchanging fire, and a confrontation situation is gradually forming around Kokang. Under the continuous gunfire, tens of thousands of people in northern Myanmar were forced to flee their homes, and the number of refugees continued to increase. Wanding, a small border town in Yunnan across the river from northern Myanmar, was also affected by the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, the spokesperson of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs called on all parties to immediately cease fire and end the war, insist on resolving differences peacefully through dialogue and consultation, avoid escalation of the situation, and take practical and effective measures to ensure the security of the China-Myanmar border. safe and stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 31, 2023, volunteers were unloading supplies in the Kokang 125 refugee camp. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/08/6dbbdc23aa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/08/6dbbdc23aa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 31, 2023, Kokang 125 Refugee Camp , volunteers are unloading supplies. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have never been so nervous”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 4 o’clock in the morning on November 4, 2023, the Aren family was once again awakened by the intensive sound of gunfire coming from Lashio City, Myanmar. . &quot;The government troops fired about 17 artillery shells outside the city in a row, and everyone was awakened,&quot; A Ren told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aren is from Myanmar and has lived in Kunming, Yunnan for a long time. On October 25, he returned to Lashio from Yunnan to visit relatives. Unexpectedly, on the third day after arriving home, he unexpectedly witnessed the conflict in northern Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhixiang, who has worked in Kokang Old Street in Myanmar for 13 years, seems to be luckier. On October 16, Zhixiang left the old street for something and happened to avoid it. He originally planned to return on the 28th, but as a result of the war, ground transportation was paralyzed, and Zhixiang failed to return to Kokang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting at 4 a.m. on October 27, Qingshuihe, Menggu, Guidi, Gunung, Lashio and other areas in northern Shan State were simultaneously attacked by the northern Myanmar coalition forces. Toll booths, police posts, The city&#39;s military as well as its police station were attacked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The sound of gunfire that day was so dense that it felt like it was exploding in my ears. It was very scary.” Aren recalled, “I never expected to encounter such a thing. There has never been such a tense situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lashio is the capital of Shan State in northern Myanmar and the seat of the Myanmar military&#39;s Northeastern Military Region Headquarters. &quot;On the top of the mountain in the center of the city, government troops have been launching missiles for more than ten days. &quot;Many artillery shells were fired.&quot; Aren said that in order to appease the people, the local media in Lashio once issued a special reminder that these artillery shells were mainly used to support other war zones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Operation 1027&quot; is named after its launch date, October 27. Kyaw Hsan Hlaing, a political analyst at The Diplomat magazine, estimated that approximately 20,000 northern Myanmar coalition troops participated in the operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Compared with previous conflicts in the Kokang area, this military operation is not only larger in scale, but also has wider and more comprehensive strategic coverage.&quot; Heng Kai pointed out that the &quot;Three Brothers Alliance&quot; not only targeted the areas including Qingshuihe They launched an offensive at the strategic location of Kokang in the country and simultaneously attacked Lashio in an attempt to contain the Myanmar National Defense Forces and prevent them from supporting northern Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, Zaw Min Tun, spokesperson of the Myanmar National Management Council, responded that after continuous fighting in multiple places, the three government-controlled areas of Qingshuihe, Pengxian and Bangsai were lost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingshuihe is located in Kokang, while Pengxian and Bangsai belong to Muse, both of which are important trade ports between China and Myanmar. The three places are close to the China-Myanmar border, and are separated by only a river of water. According to statistics from the Ministry of Commerce of the Myanmar Government, from April to September 2023, the total border trade between Myanmar and China was US$1.8 billion (approximately S$2.5 billion), more than a quarter of which was traded through Qingshui River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myanmar ethnic local armed forces stated that blocking the road from Lashio to Qingshui River and Muse can cut off the land access of Myanmar government troops into northern Shan State. But for the people in northern Myanmar, these land passages are even more important life supply lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Most of the supplies in Kokang Old Street rely on the Qingshui River. Now goods from China and Myanmar cannot come in, and the price of rice has soared more than three times.&quot; Alan, a Chinese from Myanmar, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot; A bag of rice used to cost about 200 to 300 yuan, but now it has increased to 1,400 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Worried about not being able to buy supplies in the future, Alan&#39;s friend wanted to stock up on several boxes of instant noodles for emergencies, but he failed Nowhere to buy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiaomai and Lashio, because it is difficult to transport goods out of the country, prices are being sold at reduced prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Akin’s family is engaged in breeding in Jiaomai, northern Myanmar. &quot;There are a large number of farmers in Jiaomai, and they usually transport eggs to Mandalay and other cities for sale. Since roads are now restricted, eggs can only be sold cheaply in the city.&quot; Ajin told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 6, 2023, workers in yellow vests were cleaning the Kokang 125 refugee camp. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/370d14e572.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/08/370d14e572.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 6, 2023 , Kokang 125 refugee camp, workers wearing yellow vests are cleaning. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Retreating or staying, unable to escape&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the conflict first started, the Aren family was ready to flee Lashio at any time, and they prepared it in the car in advance food and drinking water. &quot;But now there is no such panic. It is safer at home. After all, Lashio is still in the hands of the government forces. They have a lot of heavy equipment.&quot; Aren explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in other war zones where conflicts are more intense, it is difficult for people to choose calmly between retreating and staying. Some people had to flee in a hurry, while others were forced to stay in fear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the conflict entered the second week, the northern Myanmar coalition forces fought continuously in Gunong and the Dongshan and Xishan Districts of Kokang, gradually forming a siege on Lao Cai. The Kokang Allied Forces unilaterally stated that it had eliminated many Burmese military strongholds around Lao Cai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The situation in Lao Cai is getting more and more tense.” Zhixiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the people in northern Myanmar are facing difficulties that are difficult to escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;From Lao Cai back to Lashio, you need to pass through Qingshui River, Gunong, Nanzala and Mubang. These places are either occupied by the northern Myanmar coalition forces or are engaged in fighting. It&#39;s not that they don&#39;t want to leave, but I can’t leave because I’m afraid the road will become unsafe.” Alan told Southern Weekend reporters that many of her friends are now trapped in the old streets. “They are panicking, but they have no choice.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, 2023, Stéphane Dujarric, spokesman for the United Nations Secretary-General, said that since October 26, nearly 33,000 men, women, and children have been displaced in northern Myanmar. According to local media reports in Myanmar, the resettlement sites set up near the 125 Kokang border currently accommodate more than 12,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhixiang has been engaged in volunteer service in Kokang for the past 13 years. Since the conflict in northern Myanmar, his service organization and the Kokang United Youth Association have jointly taken on the operation of one of the refugee camps. In just ten days, the refugee camp has received more than 1,300 refugees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a video of the refugee camp sent by Zhixiang to Southern Weekend reporters, simple tents in various colors of red, yellow, blue and green are densely arranged in a wilderness, with intrusive rocks under the tents. and loess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The current power supply in the camp is good, but what we lack most is water and rice, and the price of rice is getting higher and higher, making it increasingly difficult to buy.&quot; Zhixiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to successive fierce battles between the Northern Myanmar Coalition Army and the Myanmar National Defense Force, a large number of Gounong people fled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Southern Weekend reporter contacted a person who had asked for help on the social platform. She told the Southern Weekend reporter that &quot;it has been safely evacuated&quot;, but she was unwilling to discuss the specific details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even safe evacuation does not mean that you are immune to the suffering of war. A family fled for safety and found the house burned to an empty shell when they returned. Zhixiang has seen too many similar scenes in the past few years. &quot;As long as you run to remote mountainous areas to escape, you will basically have nothing when you come back, and I think this time is no exception.&quot; Zhixiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;November 6, 2023, breakfast in Kokang 125 Refugee Camp. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/08/123db821dd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08 /123db821dd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 6, 2023, breakfast in the Kokang 125 Refugee Camp. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Peace is the most important”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Having worked in the Kokang area for 13 years, Zhixiang has experienced many conflicts in the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kokang Autonomous Region and its capital Laojie Town, which borders Yunnan, have long been the stronghold of the Kokang Allied Forces. On August 8, 2009, the Myanmar government forces sent 30 police officers to search the Kokang Gun Repair Factory on the pretext that it was manufacturing drugs. After being refused, they formed a confrontation with the Kokang Allied Forces. Subsequently, internal strife broke out within the Kokang Allied Forces, and deputy commander Bai Suocheng led his troops to defect to the Burmese government. On August 30, Myanmar government forces took full control of Kokang, and the remaining Allied forces retreated into the mountains and forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the Kokang Allied Forces launched two consecutive military operations in 2015 and 2017 in an attempt to regain control of the Kokang, but both were collapsed by the Myanmar government forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, the northern Myanmar coalition issued a joint statement stating that Operation &quot;1027&quot; aims to unite all revolutionary organizations to overthrow the dictatorship of the Myanmar military group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 29 is the 1,000th day that the Myanmar military government came to power. In Heng Kai&#39;s view, it was not accidental that the civilian armed forces in northern Myanmar chose such a time to launch the attack, but was based on comprehensive considerations of strategic goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After the 2021 coup, Myanmar launched a massive anti-military operation, with constant conflicts between government forces and opposition forces. The northern Myanmar coalition launched military operations in the name of &#39;anti-dictatorship&#39;, making it easier to obtain counter-attacks.&quot; The military forces responded.&quot; Heng Kai analyzed that the most fundamental purpose was to recapture Kokang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than ten days, the northern Myanmar coalition forces have continued to advance towards Kokang. It said that from October 27 to November 5, three civilian armed forces had captured more than 120 National Defense Force camps. However, the Myanmar military government did not respond directly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Northern Burma Allied Forces are so powerful that it is not difficult to capture these strongholds, but it is not easy to hold them.&quot; Heng Kai pointed out that, from the current point of view, the Kokang Allied Forces have won Most of them are only strongholds around the city, and it is difficult to say how much impact they will have on urban jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, Min Aung Hlaing, the top leader of Myanmar’s military government, warned that the military would launch a counterattack against local ethnic armed groups in Shan State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Myanmar National Defense Forces still have overwhelming strength, but since 2021, the Myanmar military government has been attacked on all sides, and even the capital Naypyitaw has been attacked.&quot; Heng Kai analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 1, 2021, Myanmar’s political situation suddenly changed, and state power was transferred to the Commander-in-Chief of the Myanmar Defense Forces, Min Aung Hlaing. Some anti-military figures immediately established a national unity government and the People&#39;s Defense Force, took military actions against the National Defense Forces, and took joint actions with local armed forces from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from the Myanmar Institute for Strategic and Policy Research, in the 21 months from the coup in Myanmar to November 15, 2022, at least 7,855 conflicts broke out across Myanmar. Among them, the military exchanged fire with ethnic minority armed organizations 4,548 times, with the People&#39;s Defense Forces 2,267 times, and the military exchanged fire with ethnic minority armed organizations and the People&#39;s Defense Forces 925 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the northern Myanmar coalition launched the military operation, 14 &quot;revolutionary organizations&quot; across Myanmar have announced their support for &quot;Operation 1027&quot;, and some of them have announced that they will join the fight. According to local media reports in Myanmar, after four consecutive days of offensive, the Kachin Independence Army and the local People&#39;s Defense Force occupied Gaoling Town in Sagaing Province on November 6. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;With the Myanmar military government facing enemies from both sides, it is still difficult to say exactly where the war will go,&quot; Heng Kai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for the people in northern Myanmar who have suffered from war, discussing politics may be too far away, and the rice waiting to be harvested in the rice fields is more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Myanmar has three seasons a year - hot season, rainy season and cool season. Now it is the rainy season rice harvesting season.&quot; Aren said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A farmer in Lashio told local media, &quot;In the past two weeks, it was impossible to harvest rice because of the rain. After the rain stopped, the fighting started. Because the sound of aircraft and weapons was often heard, everyone did not If you dare to go to the fields to harvest, you can only act according to the situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview, Southern Weekend reporters asked many interviewees about their views on this conflict, and the answers they received were almost unanimous. ——No matter who wins, for us people, &quot;peace is the most important thing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Ajin, Alan, Aren, Zhixiang, and Zou Li are pseudonyms in the article. Southern Weekend intern Lin Xi also contributed to this article Contribution)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传湖北襄阳一医院“贩卖出生证明” ，涉事院长正在接受调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260114]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to the online rumor that &quot;the director of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital in Hubei colluded with online intermediaries to use online platforms to openly sell birth certificates and sell babies. &quot;The reporter learned from relevant departments in Xiangyang City, Hubei Province on the 7th that the director of the hospital involved is currently under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, an online post reported that Hubei Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital was suspected of selling birth certificates, saying that after more than a year of undercover visits, it was discovered that Ye Moumou, the director of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital, colluded with intermediary gangs in many places. Use social platforms to publicly publish birth certificate information, identify customers, and sell birth certificates and vaccine books. According to the online post, the buyer only needs to provide identity information and pay 96,000 yuan, and the hospital will follow the &quot;normal&quot; production process and handle a full set of true information such as filing, prenatal check-up, hospitalization, delivery, and discharge at the hospital. &quot;Two days after being discharged from the hospital, the customer can take the &quot;bought child&quot; to the hospital to collect foot blood (foot blood is collected when a newborn is born), and then apply for a birth certificate. The entire process can be completed in up to 7 days. At the same time, the hospital provides a national version of the vaccination book, and &quot;vaccines&quot; according to the &quot;real&quot; newborn birth process, printing hepatitis B and BCG vaccine injection records, injection dates, vaccine manufacturers, and vaccine batch numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the online post was published, it sparked heated discussions among netizens. In response to this, the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission responded on the evening of the 6th that it had contacted the public security department and the Health Supervision Bureau to intervene in the investigation, and also arranged for dedicated personnel to contact relevant insiders to plead for support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 7th, reporters learned from the relevant departments of Xiangyang City that the person responsible for the hospital involved has been controlled and the hospital director is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“募集”资金经由个人账户，流入房地产：河南老基会“吸储”始末]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260106]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The medical care center in the Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/37625adedd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/37625adedd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The medical care center in the Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From bank president to &quot;scammer&quot;, Zhang Shihe&#39;s life has been like a roller coaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe is a native of Shangshui County, Zhoukou City, Henan Province, and the former vice president of a commercial bank in the county. After retirement, he joined the Henan Elderly Cultural Development Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Old Foundation&quot;) and was responsible for collecting private funds from the county. In the eight years he witnessed, people were able to get their principal and interest back as scheduled. Until August 2021, no more money could be withdrawn, and savers began to &quot;visit&quot; every now and then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn on October 24, 2023, the first guest welcomed into Zhang Shihe’s home was 69-year-old Zhang Fenglan. Six years ago, she deposited the 100,000 yuan she had saved for most of her life into the Lao Foundation and became a &quot;five-star member.&quot; Zhang Shihe is the person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Fenglan’s reminder voucher is not a passbook or an IOU, but two membership certificates. The issuing organization is the Old Foundation. If you deposit money to it, you will receive consolation money, which is interest. In Shangshui County, for every 10,000 yuan saved, you can get 570 yuan/year in consolation payment, with an annualized rate of return of 5.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I thought I had saved my money in the safest place, but I never imagined that something like this would happen.” Zhang Fenglan sighed repeatedly to the Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe persuaded the other party in a low voice, saying that he was also a victim and felt very guilty for &quot;losing&quot; everyone&#39;s money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He revealed that the entire Shangshui County involves more than 300 depositors, with a total of more than 41 million yuan in deposits. Looking at the entire Henan Province, the tentacles of the Old Foundation are everywhere. Several insiders of the old foundation revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the old foundation may absorb as much as 500 million yuan in depositors&#39; funds in Henan Province, involving 18 offices in Zhoukou, Nanyang, Luohe, Luoyang and other cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs mentioned in its reply to Li Yazhong and others’ letter of complaint that in June 2020, the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs transferred Henan Herong Industrial Group Co., Ltd. ( (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Herong Group&quot;) suspected illegal financing-related materials were handed over to the Henan Provincial Public Security Department in the name of the Lao Foundation. The official website of the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs also records that on July 28, 2020, the Lao Foundation was included in the list of social organizations with serious violations of laws and breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many heads of old foundations confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that under the guidance of the Henan Provincial Public Security Department, public security bureaus in many places have launched investigations into county-level old foundations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late October, Southern Weekend reporters visited several counties and districts in Zhoukou and Luohe cities and found that the Lao Foundation used local political and private network resources to weave a huge deposit-absorbing network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did a provincial public foundation “self-raise” such huge sums of money in the past ten years? Where do these huge sums of money ultimately go? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Network&quot; retired cadres and farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to become a veteran foundation member? A &quot;Membership Instructions&quot; found by Southern Weekend reporters states that applicants fill out the membership application form, and after review and approval by the Old Foundation, register information and pay membership fees. After receiving the membership card, they become a formal member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe said that these membership fees will be returned to members when they expire (one year), and you can also receive consolation money by presenting your membership card to the issuing agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Membership fees are essentially deposits, and the amount is replaced by points on the membership card. Members are divided into one-star, three-star and five-star, and the corresponding points represent RMB 10,000, RMB 30,000 and RMB 50,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 82-year-old Lu Zhiqiang is a big customer of the old foundation and has 22 membership cards in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is a retired cadre in Shangshui County. He has a monthly pension of more than 3,000 yuan, plus a front-end house, and an annual rent of more than 30,000 yuan. He and his wife cannot spend this money. How many. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled that in the early days of the establishment of the Lao Foundation, Chen Zhihong, the person in charge in Shangshui County, often invited people to have dinner together to promote the Lao Foundation in order to build momentum. As a fellow villager, he even participated once. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because it is a public foundation, I think there is no problem. Even if you deposit money in a bank for a fixed term, you don&#39;t have much money.&quot; He remembers Chen Zhihong motivating him like this, &quot;This foundation is managed by the Civil Affairs Department, so it can&#39;t be wasted.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Zhiqiang hid the deposits of the old foundation from his children, not even his wife. &quot;If you tell them, they will stop it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Fenghua, 77, is the former head of the financial section of the Shangshui County Industrial and Commercial Bureau. She has deposited 250,000 yuan in the old foundation. She only learned about the old foundation through the introduction of a retired cadre from the Shangshui County Civil Affairs Bureau. &quot;I only knew that the interest rates were high and the certificates issued had the seal of the Civil Affairs Department, so I thought it was more reliable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t dare to tell my child at that time, for fear of exposing that my child was asking for the money. I wanted to save it so that I could hire a nanny when I get old.&quot; Guo Fenghua sighed, &quot;It&#39;s too late to regret it now. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to retired cadres in the county, the Lao Foundation has also extended its tentacles to the vast rural areas of Henan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shang Fugui, 70, is from Chengding Village, Guxiang Township, Linying County, Luohe City. He is responsible for helping the Lao Foundation collect deposits in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that at first the villagers saved little money, &quot;but because of the high interest rates, you saw me saving, I saw him saving, and word spread slowly.&quot; Some villagers even offered to give him cigarettes in order to do something for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He absorbed 2.75 million yuan in funds, involving about 40 depositors, accounting for half of the village&#39;s population. There are also a few savers from other villages who are his relatives. Shang Fugui said that for every 10,000 yuan deposited, depositors can receive a condolence payment of 600 yuan per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, we are a small bank down there.” A head of the county-level office of the old foundation told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Luohe, the old foundation showed the first signs of trouble. In October 2015, the Provincial Lao Foundation said that its funds were broken and gradually stopped local principal and interest payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shang Fugui recalled that after the payment was stopped, the depositors became enemies with him. Seven years later, in October 2022, he was beaten once by villagers. &quot;Sometimes the tricycles are not dared to be released outside. They will poke holes in you and vent your anger.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every Spring Festival, Shang Fugui and his wife would run to the city. &quot;What if I don&#39;t run away? They all gather at the door of my house to ask for money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A depositor has as many as 22 membership cards. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/07/0ef86b4c0e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/0ef86b4c0e .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257258&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A depositor has as many as 22 membership cards. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Using &quot;volunteers&quot; as the starting point&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Intermediaries such as Zhang Shihe and Shang Fugui are called &quot;volunteers&quot; in the old foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are often retired cadres or former loan officers. Their personal status provides credit endorsement to local people. Choosing such a group of &quot;hands-on&quot; is also a reason why similar foundations can always grow rapidly among the people. One of the &quot;mysteries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second floor of No. 8 Zhengxin Street, Shangshui County, Zhoukou City is the local office of the Old Foundation. When Southern Weekend reporters visited on October 23, the place was deserted and the door was locked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe said that there are five &quot;volunteers&quot; in the office, basically all retired cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Chen Zhihong is the person in charge of the Shangshui County Lao Foundation. He once served as secretary of the Party Committee of Tangzhuang Township in Shangshui County and deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Shangshui County Party Committee. Zhang Shihe is the former vice president of a commercial bank in Shangshui County. The other two &quot;volunteers&quot; have served in the Shangshui County Finance Bureau and the Procuratorate respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former staff member of Weiji Township Government in Shangshui County told Southern Weekend reporters that he and Chen Zhihong are fellow villagers. I often sit at the same table with Chen Zhihong during meetings in the county. I am familiar with her, so I also saved some money. &quot;He is not like a liar, he is a very down-to-earth person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a criminal verdict obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, Yang Yiting, a &quot;volunteer&quot; at the Linying County Office in Luohe City, mentioned in his testimony that the old man When the foundation&#39;s Linying office was established, the director of the office, Xue Xiaoge, came to him and said that the provincial old foundation hoped to find a local cadre with prestige, good popularity, and retired cadre to serve as the honorary director. &quot;The foundation is engaged in charity. Shang Qi had been retired at home for two years and wanted to do something.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xue Xiaoge confessed that Yang Yiting was the former political commissar of the Linying County Public Security Bureau and the honorary director. &quot;When there is an event, he takes part in it. He doesn&#39;t usually go to work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to retired cadres from government agencies, former rural loan officers are also an important force for the old foundation to sink into the rural market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;70-year-old Feng Junfu is a villager in Guzhuang Village, Daguo Town, Linying County, Luohe City. In 1975, he was elected as a loan officer of Daguo Township Credit Union by the Guzhuang Village Committee and worked there for 34 years until 2009. Get fired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Junfu said that township residents are accustomed to depositing funds in local rural credit cooperatives or township banks, and loan officers play the role of handling business for villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Loan officers must first be ideologically progressive, trustworthy by the people, and have no stains.” Feng Junfu told Southern Weekend reporters that there are 20 old foundation “volunteers” in Linying County, most of whom have worked as loan officers in township banks. , and people from all over the country regard them as their &quot;own people&quot; who are worthy of entrustment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2013, Xue Xiaoge found Feng Junfu and showed him the approval document of the old foundation from the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, the foundation’s legal person certificate, tax registration certificate, organization code certificate, etc., saying that it was formal. organization and invite him to join. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The most important thing is that we have depositor resources in our hands.” Feng Junfu told Southern Weekend reporters that he thought about staying in his old business and the process was roughly the same, so he readily agreed. In Guzhuang Village, Feng Junfu developed more than 50 villagers into members of the Lao Foundation and collected a total of 1.85 million yuan in savings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Provincial Veterans Foundation stipulates that for every 10,000 yuan taken in, 300 yuan will be set aside for &quot;volunteers&quot; and another 200 yuan will be used for office expenses of the county and district offices. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Origined from the Henan Song Qing Ling Foundation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to the source, the old foundation is inextricably linked to the Henan Soong Ching Ling Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Henan Song Qing Ling Foundation&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2005, the Henan Song Foundation collected deposits from villagers in the name of public welfare medical insurance. (See Southern Weekend’s September 2011 series of reports on “Where is the Money of China’s Most Fundraising Charitable Organization—Who Controls the Henan Soong Ching Ling Foundation”)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2013, the old foundation officially It was established and Lu Dawei was appointed as the president. According to the Henan Provincial People&#39;s Government website, Lu Dawei served as assistant to the governor. In addition, Southern Weekend reporters learned from the Henan Song Foundation website that he is also the vice chairman of the Henan Song Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A county-level person in charge of the old foundation revealed that the management method of the old foundation is under the leadership of the president, with the secretary-general taking responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge told Southern Weekend reporters that Guo Jianxin is the secretary-general of the Old Foundation and is responsible for the overall work, while the deputy secretary-general Huang Yuejun is responsible for specific work. &quot;Huang Yuejun turned out to be from the Song Foundation. Basically, we follow the management style of Song Foundation, otherwise we wouldn’t be able to get this thing done.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In interviews with reporters from Southern Weekend, we found that most of the county-level directors of the old foundations had working experience in the Henan Song Foundation. After the Henan Song Foundation&#39;s savings-absorbing business ceased, Guo Jianxin and Huang Yuejun recruited these people. &quot;In the past, we were all familiar with the business at the Song Foundation. Huang Yuejun gave us advice and introduced us to the old foundation,&quot; the person in charge said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted Huang Yuejun by phone. The other party said that he had left the Lao Foundation at the end of 2015 and was currently residing in a nursing home in Sichuan Province. He did not know much about the past and then hung up. Disconnect the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Cuiyun was originally a depositor of the Henan Song Foundation. After the Song Foundation ceased its deposit-taking business, she withdrew the original 100,000 yuan from the Song Foundation and transferred it to the old foundation. Then save another 50,000 yuan every year until 450,000 yuan. &quot;Generally (every year) I don&#39;t ask for the principal, I get the interest, but I add some money to make up 50,000 and deposit it again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Left-hand foundation, right-hand open Company&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that the Elderly Foundation is located in Zhengzhou City, Henan Province, and its purpose is to &quot;promote the development of social welfare, culture, sports, education and other undertakings for the elderly in Henan Province.&quot; Access to the foundation’s official website is currently closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters obtained a reply from the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on the establishment and registration of the Henan Provincial Elderly Cultural Development Foundation (Yu Min Han [2013] No. 47). According to the &quot;Foundation&quot; According to the provisions of the Management Regulations, after review, the old foundation, which was donated a total of 4 million yuan as the original fund by Guo Jianxin, meets the conditions for establishing a public foundation. It is hereby approved to register and obtain the legal person status of the foundation in accordance with the law. Its business supervisory unit is Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2023, Southern Weekend reporters repeatedly contacted the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs to verify many issues regarding the old foundation, but no one answered the relevant calls. Inquired through &quot;12345&quot;, but still no reply after waiting for many days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many savers, they are willing to deposit money in the foundation. On the one hand, they trust the &quot;volunteers&quot;, and on the other hand, they see the business scope on the foundation&#39;s legal person registration certificate. On this certificate issued by the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, the business scope reads &quot;raising social funds in accordance with the law and carrying out elderly cultural activities such as loving and helping the elderly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of many savers and &quot;volunteers&quot;, being able to &quot;raise social funds in accordance with the law&quot; means that they can legitimately accept deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A search shows that many foundations do mention &quot;raising social funds in accordance with the law&quot; in their business scope. For example, the business scope of the Henan Province Yellow River Cultural Foundation is “raising funds in accordance with the law, rescuing cultural heritage, and establishing cultural undertakings”; the business scope of the Henan Province Youth Entrepreneurship and Employment Foundation is “raising funds in accordance with the law, subsidizing youth entrepreneurship and employment, and conducting research on youth entrepreneurship, etc. &quot;Related social charity activities&quot;; the business scope of the Henan Province Old District Construction Foundation is &quot;raising funds in accordance with the law and supporting poverty alleviation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Zeng Jie of Guangdong Guangqiang Law Firm told Southern Weekend reporters that there is an essential difference between raising funds and deposits. Deposits mean a commitment to guarantee principal and interest. “The foundation can absorb funds from the society within its business scope. However, returns cannot be promised, and projects that repay principal and interest are not allowed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that deposit business requires a formal banking license. The old foundation used consolation money instead of interest without approval, which is a disguised form of absorbing savings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The business scope on the registration certificate makes depositors and volunteers think it is &quot;natural&quot; to save money here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/11365ba5da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/07/11365ba5da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The business scope on the registration certificate makes depositors and volunteers think that saving money here is &quot;natural&quot;. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2021, the Linying County Court of Luohe City convicted the Henan Elderly Cultural Development Foundation of illegally absorbing public deposits, sentenced it to a fine of RMB 200,000, and ordered the elderly to Participants in the foundation&#39;s compensation fund-raising raised 29.71 million yuan, and Henan Herong Industrial Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Herong Group&quot;) bears joint liability for compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the relationship between Herong Group and the Lao Foundation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the secretary-general of the Lao Foundation, Guo Jianxin is also the chairman of Henan Herong Elderly Care Industry Group and was once the major shareholder of Herong Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that Herong Group was established in 2010 and is an enterprise mainly engaged in business services. On March 15, 2010, Guo Jianxin, as the major shareholder, participated in 90% of the shares for the first time. Another shareholder, Wang Shuling, is also a member of the board of directors of the Lao Foundation and holds 10% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To put it bluntly, Herong Group and the Lao Foundation are one and the same to the outside world, but in reality they are the same.&quot; A person close to Guo Jianxin told Southern Weekend reporters that there are people under the Lao Foundation and Herong Group. Division of labor, top management is a group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registered office address of Herong Group is also the same as that of the Old Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 5, 2013, the Lao Foundation and Herong Group officially signed a letter of authorization. The Lao Foundation will authorize Herong Group to invest in projects with the raised funds to ensure the maintenance and appreciation of the funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investigation by Southern Weekend reporters found that in order to avoid supervision, most of the private funds absorbed by the old foundation went through personal accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As can be seen in a criminal verdict, the financial personnel of the Provincial Veterans Foundation are Zhang Xiaodan and Wang Jie. Wang Jie is responsible for receiving funds (resigned in September 2015), and Zhang Xiaodan is responsible for disbursing funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xiaodan mentioned in his testimony that the Provincial Veterans Foundation has bank cards in its offices in various counties and districts. The bank card account names are all the names of provincial and ministerial personnel, and most of the funds are transferred through China Construction Bank. Yes, a small part is transferred through ICBC and Postal Savings Bank of China. After the various offices in the county and district paid dues, Wang Jie transferred the money to the Herong Group&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wang Jie swiped directly from the POS machine at the foundation headquarters and transferred it to the account given by Herong Group.&quot; Zhang Xiaodan saw Wang Jie transfer like this with his own eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xiaodan said that the foundation transfers the dues transferred from each office to Herong Group. &quot;This is the case every day.&quot; Any money received is transferred to the company and transferred to his personal bank card. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the available annual reports of the old foundation, from 2014 to 2016, the donation income was 300,000 yuan, 460,000 yuan, and 270,000 yuan respectively, and the corresponding public welfare expenditures were 25,000 yuan. Ten thousand yuan, 220,000 yuan, 360,000 yuan. But by 2017, both donation income and public welfare expenditures were 0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the huge &quot;membership dues&quot; of the old foundation did not go through the foundation&#39;s public account, but were transferred privately through personal bank accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If a lawsuit is filed and we check the public account of the Old Foundation, we will find that there is no money from us in the account. The public account of the Old Foundation only accepts donations. Depositors&#39; money cannot be added to it. Even if it’s a donation,” a county-level head of an old foundation told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Huge sums of money flow into real estate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a province-wide perspective, the difficulties faced by the old foundation in repaying funds are concentrated in the second half of 2021. But there are early signs of bank-run difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, guarantee companies and investment companies in Henan Province went bankrupt on a large scale. &quot;As soon as they closed down, the old foundation was also affected.&quot; An insider close to Guo Jianxin told Southern Weekend reporters that one year after the establishment of the old foundation, the capital chain began to break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person revealed that from August to September 2015, depositors began to withdraw money from the county offices of the Old Foundation on a large scale. &quot;Not only the customers were panicked, but the directors and volunteers of the Old Foundation offices were also panicked.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of a county-level office recalled that in October 2015, Guo Jianxin, the head of Herong Group, said at a meeting with county-level leaders that the company had debts and that the funds could not be paid temporarily. , let everyone go back and wait, and protect themselves first. &quot;We didn&#39;t tell the depositors when we got back, thinking it would be fine after a while.&quot; In order to repay the interest to the depositors, we also asked relatives and friends for help, did not hesitate to borrow money, and even sold the house, paying more than 1 million yuan in interest to the depositors. It wasn&#39;t until 2021 that he couldn&#39;t survive anymore, then he confessed to savers and stopped paying interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is no way, in order to encourage depositors to continue depositing. If we stop (payment), we will have to go to (jail). Will ordinary people be willing to not pay interest?&quot; The person in charge of the office said that if we continue to do so, Those who went down were paupers and were in debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 20, 2023, Herong Group issued the &quot;Explanation on the Inability to Redeem the Funds Raised by the Henan Elderly Cultural Foundation on Time&quot;, saying that it held a meeting to study and decide that the payment will be made from the end of February 2023. 10%-15% of the funds will be paid, and 20%-25% of the funds will be paid at the end of February 2024; 30%-35% will be paid in February 2025, and the rest will be paid at the end of 2025. However, the above promises have never been fulfilled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where did the money go? This is the mystery lingering in the minds of savers and &quot;volunteers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Jiadong is the legal representative of Herong Group. He confessed in a criminal verdict that &quot;Herong Group invested in two real estate projects in Mengzhou City in Jiaozuo and Yuanyang County in Xinxiang , invested in an apartment project for the elderly in Zhengzhou Port District, and also invested in a real estate project in Shangqiu City. All the social funds raised by the Lao Foundation were used in these projects.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Zhengzhou Port District project is Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Health Care Park&quot;) is considered to be the benchmark project of Herong Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Kangyangyuan is located at the southwest corner of the intersection of Yingang Avenue and Ruyun Road, Airport District, Zhengzhou City. The total land area is 41,398.22 square meters, the total construction area is 76,754.40 square meters, and there are 2,000 designed beds. It mainly constructs 6 elderly apartment buildings, 1 comprehensive service building, 1 elderly research center building, and 1 elderly medical care center building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai is the head of a county-level office of the Lao Foundation. On September 15, 2022, he was elected as the director of Kangyangyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the elderly care projects in the port area are positioned as high-end and have received the attention of many local leaders. There is a lot of room for imagination in the future. In addition to construction subsidies, bed subsidies, and nursing subsidies, the land price also has advantages compared with other investors. &quot;I heard that the land price in Zhengzhou Port District was more than 2 million yuan per acre, but here it was only a few hundred thousand. At that time, the house price was 10% per year. growth, this alone will not make us lose anything.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, its construction was not smooth. Feng Chunlai said that the construction of Kangyangyuan started in 2016, but due to environmental problems such as dust and noise, the superior authorities asked it to stop construction. It was not until December 18, 2019 that the first phase of the park was successfully opened. According to the Henan branch of CCTV, Lu Dawei and Guo Jianxin also delivered speeches at the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai revealed that the main construction of the nine buildings of the senior care project in Zhengzhou Port District was completed in 2018, but due to financial constraints, there has been no renovation. At the beginning of 2019, eight county-level offices under the old foundation established project promotion teams to continue to collect deposits from the society and provide loans to renovate Buildings 5 ​​and 4. The remaining seven buildings have not yet been renovated due to funding problems. &quot;If we don&#39;t renovate the building, this place will collapse long ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, about 80 elderly people live in the No. 5 complex. However, as of now, the Kangyangyuan has not yet been inspected and has not obtained a business license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Multiple people familiar with the matter confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that in the second half of 2022, Guo Jianxin and several company managers were arrested by the public security organs for involvement in other cases. Subsequently, the offices of the Old Foundation and Herong Group were moved from No. 8 Shangdu Road, Zhengdong New District to Kangyangyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Now almost no one is working in the Old Foundation and Herong Group. They come if they have something to do, but they don&#39;t come if there is nothing. They basically go back to their homes.&quot; An insider of the Old Foundation said that No. 5 in Kangyang Garden The second floor of the complex building was originally the office space of the bosses, but now it is hard to find anyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted an external relations director of Herong Group as an investor. He said that Kangyangyuan currently still has debts of more than 200 million yuan, of which the construction work is in arrears. The team&#39;s project payment is less than 100 million yuan, and the other more than 100 million yuan is funds collected from some elderly customers before the epidemic and needs to be refunded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai said that Kangyangyuan currently has 30 employees and spends 200,000 to 300,000 yuan a month. The largest expense is water and electricity bills. Although we can collect 3,700 yuan per month from each elderly person, &quot;it&#39;s basically not enough, and we are trying every means to delay and owe money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can this retirement apartment make money to replenish the principal of the old foundation’s depositors? They can&#39;t think that far ahead. At the moment, the operations here are barely surviving on the money of the elderly living in retirement apartments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Zhang Shihe, Zhang Fenglan, Lu Zhiqiang, Guo Fenghua, and Liu Cuiyun are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[消失的课间十分钟，学校何以成樊笼：“绝对安全”发生学丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260132]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to the &quot;disappearing ten minutes between classes&quot; for primary and secondary school students in some places, the Ministry of Education stated that it will resolutely correct it to &quot;ensure The practice of simply restricting students’ necessary recess and activities on the grounds of “student safety”. Subsequently, some schools began to respond, such as media reports: The bell rang, and Dang Xinlong, the vice principal of Shanhaitian Experimental Primary School in Rizhao, Shandong Province, kicked out the students who were still in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this chronic disease has been infiltrated for a long time, is widespread and deep, and I am afraid it cannot be cured by a single statement. Article 8 of the &quot;School Protection Regulations for Minors&quot; that will be implemented on September 1, 2021: Schools shall not set up management measures that infringe on students&#39; personal freedom, and shall not impose any restrictions on students&#39; legitimate communication, games, or activities during recess and other non-teaching time. Unnecessary restrictions are placed on freedom of speech and behavior such as classroom activities. The target is the &quot;disappeared ten minutes between classes&quot;. The problem is that it is difficult for students to make their own decisions. No school believes that it is &quot;unnecessary&quot; to restrict students from leaving the classroom, the teaching building, and the playground during recess. So, the problem remains to be solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqing.com recently reported that a parent said: If children want to leave the classroom during recess, they can basically only go to the toilet and get water. They are not allowed to talk loudly or run or jump on the way; some &quot;loose&quot; schools , the child will be allowed to walk in the corridor and cannot go up or down stairs or to the playground; in more serious cases, the child can only stay in the corridor of his own group and cannot cross the boundary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another media reported in July this year that in Beijing, primary schools generally strictly limit the scope and intensity of students’ recess activities. The reporter randomly visited 27 schools in the central city and found that at least more than 20 schools have strict restrictions on students’ recess activities. restrictions on activities during the period. In addition, some schools in Zhengzhou, Henan, Baoding, Hebei and other places have adopted similar regulations, including not being allowed to leave the teaching building, not leaving the classroom, and not allowed to speak loudly or play around inside or outside the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a child born in the 70s and 80s, I could go out for ten minutes between classes to skip rope, play shuttlecock, hopscotch, play freely and even chase each other, letting go of my nature; outdoors, in the playground, be quiet or active No matter what, it is always suitable, with the blue sky above your head, your feet on the earth, let the sun hit your face, let the breeze blow on your face, and be close to nature, which can instantly rejuvenate and heal the body and mind, and also cultivate simple, strong and resilient character and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And now, while restricting or even prohibiting children from leaving the classroom, leaving the teaching building, or going to the playground for even ten minutes between classes, they still naively ask: Why are our children so mentally fragile? Why are our boys so fragile? A general lack of masculinity? Isn&#39;t this funny? How can we become strong physically and mentally if we are not even allowed to chase, play and fight? Where does masculinity come from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did this distorted philosophy and practice come to be? On June 1, 2021, the Director of the Department of Physical Health and Art Education of the Ministry of Education responded to CCTV: &quot;We are afraid that students will be easily injured once they move. Now all schools put safety first... This can also be said to be a failure to eat due to choking. .&quot; Viewed in this way, the pursuit of &quot;absolute safety&quot; and its mechanism are worthy of analysis and reflection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, some parents have problems and believe that the school should be responsible for any personal injury to their children while in school. This imposes unlimited liability on the school. Not to mention that schools can’t do it, parents themselves can’t do it either. Theoretically, there is no one in the world who is more concerned about the safety of their children than parents, but under the care of parents, there are endless incidents of children being injured or even killed. No one wants to see something like this happen, but the world itself contains various known and unknown risks, and we cannot make anti-human demands on schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, identifying risks, preventing risks, responding to risks, and coexisting with risks are an integral part of everyone&#39;s life, and they are also the basic education that every child must learn to grow up. Very young children do not know what risks are. Of course, they must be kept away from risks and isolated as much as possible. However, children are constantly growing and need to learn the skills to identify, prevent and respond to risks as they grow. This is the most important survival skills education. In a way, it is much more important than knowledge education. And so many schools actually succumb to the ideas of some parents of students and strive to build schools into an absolutely safe space that is isolated from any risks. To this end, they do not hesitate to suppress children&#39;s love of freedom and love of play. This is anti-education in itself and also In vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there will always be some weird parents who want to blackmail the school financially when their child has an accident at school, even though it is clearly not the school’s responsibility. But this is not the crux of the problem. The key lies in how schools, education authorities, public prosecutors and law respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these three parties can handle the matter according to its merits and legal principles, it will not be the responsibility of the school. The school will not shoulder the responsibility, and the school will not let the school shoulder the responsibility. He Xini will resolutely fight back those who mess around. In this way, righteousness can rise and decent values ​​and correct incentives can be established. Does the school still need to engage in &quot;absolute security&quot; that is anti-education and anti-human? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously it was not the school’s responsibility, but due to the parents’ unreasonable fuss, the school had to compensate the loss on its own or under the pressure of superior departments. This is a bad incentive for some parents who have evil intentions or like to shirk responsibility. In order to avoid another hemorrhage, the logical approach for schools and education authorities is to restrict children&#39;s freedom of movement, confine them to the smallest possible space, and approach the &quot;absolute safety&quot; that isolates all risks. This is the root of the problem. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, this is a social issue and a conceptual issue: children who cry have milk to drink. Whoever has a louder voice and can make more noise will get greater benefits. This phenomenon is still prevalent in public opinion and in all walks of life. &quot;I am weak and I am reasonable&quot;, &quot;I am making trouble and I am justified&quot; and &quot;I am loud and I am justified&quot; have become unspoken rules. Pretending to be weak, being miserable, and using the weak to bully the strong has created another jungle. The children locked up in the classroom are just another group of victims of this jungle law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[记者节之思：新闻理想的坚守与开拓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260074]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The annual Journalists’ Day is here. This is also the time for reporters who are working non-stop and running around all year round to stop and reflect. , an important moment for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is full of chaos, the century-old changes are accelerating, the media field is deeply integrated and reconstructed, instability and uncertainty factors are significantly increasing, internal and external factors are stirring in the hearts of journalists... At this moment, Journalists&#39; Day, Perhaps each of us journalists should ask themselves the question: Do you still have journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a journalist, the news ideal is the &quot;beacon light&quot; that guides the direction; the news ideal is the &quot;engine&quot; that drives forward; the news ideal is the &quot;ballast&quot; &quot;Stone&quot; has the function of calming the mind; news ideal is the &quot;regulator&quot; and has the function of prompting and warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, today, the traditional journalism industry is facing an unprecedented industry shock: the circulation of newspapers and periodicals and radio and television ratings have declined, and the influence of the media has declined; the media industry has operating difficulties, and the income of news practitioners has decreased. ; The number of people leaving their jobs has increased, and people quitting the industry have been heard from time to time; the number of enrollment in journalism and communication majors in colleges and universities has been reduced, and the employment situation of graduates has become tighter... There is no shortage of comments on the Internet about candidates who plan to apply for the journalism and communication major. Although it is not without bias, This is by no means groundless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the founding words of &quot;Xiangjiang Review&quot;, Mao Zedong enthusiastically asked: &quot;What is the biggest problem in the world? The biggest problem is the problem of food.&quot; When the traditional journalism industry is climbing up and over the hurdles, a group of people who are confused and emotionally anxious have emerged. Psychological Inevitability – Will Traditional Journalism Die? Is there a future for journalism? Do we still need journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as we carefully study the history, reality and future development trends of journalism, we will find that traditional journalism will not disappear. Journalism still has its own future, and we still need journalistic ideals. This is because: From the perspective of the origin of journalism, news originates from people’s curiosity. As long as people’s curiosity does not die, journalism will not disappear. From the perspective of the evolution of journalism, although the carrier of news is constantly changing, the functional role of journalism has not disappeared. However, compared with the traditional ways of reading newspapers, listening to radio, and watching TV in the past, people now obtain news in a different way. It’s just a new carrier such as a mobile phone. From the perspective of audience needs, news focuses on meeting people&#39;s communication needs. As long as people&#39;s communication needs exist, the demand for journalism will always exist. From the perspective of journalism production, the authoritative news, in-depth reports, news reviews, elegant programs and other products provided by traditional media cannot be replaced by the vast number of new media and self-media. Therefore, traditional journalism is unlikely to disappear in any of the above senses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is impossible for traditional journalism to disappear, it is impossible for journalists to disappear. The ideal of journalism will inevitably accompany and advance together with journalists. Otherwise, we will lose our way and lose our way. Without motivation, lack of soul, and chaos, you will be at a loss, useless, muddle along, and do nothing. Therefore, in such a special context of the times, each of us journalists must still have journalistic ideals in mind, promote journalistic ideals, adhere to journalistic ideals, and practice journalistic ideals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always have a loyal heart. Loyalty means that as a journalist, don’t ask what the country has done for me, but ask what I have done for the country; loyalty means not being confused in the face of major events, not wavering at critical moments, and being able to withstand various complex situations and problems. The test; loyalty means being indifferent to fame and wealth, willing to work as a coolie, working hard, sweating, and traveling thousands of miles for the cause of journalism, and striving to become an excellent journalist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always maintain a keen sense. Sensitivity is an essential quality for professional journalists. Only journalists who are sharp-minded, have unique vision, are good at seeing the subtleties, respond quickly, and have a sharp eye can effectively improve the dissemination, guidance, influence and credibility of news and public opinion work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must always practice seeking truth. The world-famous journalist Farage once said: &quot;The duty of a reporter is to reveal the truth.&quot; In an era of widespread media communication, despite the excess of news information, real news is always valuable. We should always maintain the spirit of truth-seeking, practice truth-seeking skills, and provide the public with truth, true knowledge, true feelings, and truth in a timely and rapid manner in the turbulent world of massive information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always hold the ruler of justice. Some people say: &quot;The reporter&#39;s pen contains countless fortunes, reputation and reputation, loyalty and villainy, right and wrong, and life and death.&quot; This shows how heavy the journalist&#39;s pen is. Therefore, we reporters should be very clear about why we write, what we write, how we write, and to what extent we write. We must always grasp the yardstick of &quot;fairness&quot; and must not be influenced by some kind of power, money, or interest relationship. Those pens soaked in grease and booze can&#39;t possibly do them justice. This is why we need to always be in awe of &quot;justice&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of Journalists’ Day, I wish every journalist’s journalistic ideals to be evergreen and never wither! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is from the media in Hebei)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; 163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[森林消防“全覆盖”31个省份]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260136]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce Progress in the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the progress of the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Firefighting work and the construction of fire rescue teams have undergone all-round and profound changes.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, at the State Council At a press conference held by the Information Office, Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management and director of the National Fire Rescue Bureau, introduced the construction and development of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in its fifth anniversary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and were formally placed under the Ministry of Emergency Management to form a national comprehensive fire rescue team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in the past five years, nearly 200,000 teams have successfully completed transfers of subordinates, identity changes, rank changes, title changes, and official positions. work, establish the National Fire Rescue Bureau, implement unified leadership and hierarchical command, clarify the major principles of central construction and local use, and establish a dual management system that combines sections and focuses on sections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 is the sixth year for open recruitment of firefighters after the establishment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team. Li Shangyu, head of the Education and Training Department of the Ministry of Emergency Management, said that there was a plan to recruit 15,000 people in 2023, but nearly 110,000 people signed up, marking the fourth consecutive full recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shangyu introduced that the average age of new firefighters is 21.8 years old, and 52.6% have a college degree or above. They are currently undergoing a one-year induction training. So far, the total number of firefighters recruited after the transformation has reached more than 94,000, accounting for 65.3% of the total number of existing firefighters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Forest firefighting adds more than 8,200 people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National firefighting After the rescue bureau was officially established, a new mobile team was formed. Xu Zhongshun, deputy director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, said that this is &quot;a major decision made based on the basic national conditions of my country&#39;s frequent natural disasters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as a critical force in national emergencies and major disasters, the mobile team is mainly responsible for forest and grassland firefighting duties, supplemented by flood fighting and earthquake and geological disaster rescue. Responsibilities, task arrangements focus on fire fighting in winter and spring, flood control in summer and autumn, year-round disaster relief, seasonal cross-regional garrison, and implementation of preparatory operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Fire and Rescue Administration has integrated the forest fire corps and related fire and rescue mobile detachments, forming 10 cross-regional fire and rescue mobile corps and several detachments, brigades, and squadrons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the original establishment of forest firefighting teams is 25,000, mainly deployed in 10 provinces including Inner Mongolia, Jilin, Heilongjiang, Fujian, and Sichuan. On this basis, the Central Organization Office has approved the establishment of more than 8,200 forest firefighting teams, mainly to strengthen the first-line firefighting and rescue mobile forces in key forest areas, national parks, seven major river basins and surrounding areas across the country, and to achieve comprehensive coverage of 31 provinces. &quot;Full coverage&quot; of all administrative regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as of now, 17 provinces in the first batch of additional mobile teams have basically completed their deployment, and are now organizing the second batch of additional mobile teams. There are teams stationed in 3 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;All disasters, major emergencies&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Firefighting After the rescue team was reformed and transformed, its functions have also been expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se introduced that on the basis of the original fire fighting and emergency rescue focusing on rescuing people&#39;s lives, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau focuses on &quot;all disaster types&quot;. The comprehensive rescue expansion of &quot;big emergency&quot; covers urban and rural and forest and grassland fire fighting, as well as disaster accident rescue such as floods, earthquakes, geology, typhoons, building collapses, and hazardous chemical leakage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking 2022 as an example, fire rescue teams across the country received reports and handled 2.092 million disasters of various types, including 824,000 fire rescues and 469,000 emergency rescues. , 597,000 cases of various types of social assistance, 126,000 cases of official duties, and 76,000 cases of other dispatches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this total number of rescues, fire fighting is still the main type of accident that the fire rescue team responds to. At the same time, police situations involving water areas, mountains, production and equipment failures, trapped elevators, and traffic accidents accounted for 87.4% of the total number of rescues. &quot;They are the main types of rescues and are also the key directions for the expansion of functional tasks after the reform and restructuring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in response to these situations, in recent years, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau has vigorously strengthened the construction of professional forces and established a total of high-rise buildings, underground spaces, large commercial complexes, etc. There are more than 3,500 professional firefighting teams in the body and petrochemical enterprises, as well as earthquake, water, air, and rain, snow and ice rescue teams. Relying on the forest firefighting team, 12 special disaster rescue brigades and 55 affiliated rapid response teams have been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[中山二院乳腺外科多人患癌？医院通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:35:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 7, 2023, our hospital noticed that &quot;Zhongshan Second Hospital Breast Cancer The surgical team is suspected of being affected by the experimental environment and reagents, causing many people to develop cancer.&quot; The hospital quickly organized an investigation and verification, and initially learned that: 3 people who worked and studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center in recent years have suffered from cancer, 2 of whom are now breast surgeons in our hospital and are working in clinical practice; the other 1 is not from us. The employees or students of the institute are those who come to the institute for further study from other places and have returned to work in their original units. No current student in this laboratory has contracted cancer. The specific situation is as follows: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Huang, female, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2017 to 2022, during which she studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center, and graduated with a doctoral degree in July 2022 Later, he joined the Breast Surgery Department of our hospital and engaged in clinical work. He was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in October 2023 and underwent surgery. His current condition is stable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu, male, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2013 to 2018. During this period, he studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center. He joined our hospital after graduating from the Ph.D. in August 2018. Breast surgery, engaged in clinical work. In June 2023, he was diagnosed with synovial sarcoma and underwent surgery. He recovered well after the operation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the above two employees became ill, the hospital has been caring about their health and organized expert consultations, visits and condolences. Another researcher is a doctoral student who graduated from a foreign hospital. In 2021, he came to our hospital for a year of further study and worked in the laboratory of the Breast Tumor Center. He completed his further study in April 2022 and left Guangzhou. In 2023, he was diagnosed with breast cancer at his place of work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Breast Cancer Center Laboratory was opened in 2009 and has trained more than 200 students so far. Since its establishment, the laboratory has been managed in strict accordance with the regulations, and all experimental personnel have been trained on safety and standardized operations before experiments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to public concerns about laboratory safety management, our hospital will continue to maintain safety red lines and consciously accept inspections and supervision from superior authorities. We also thank netizens for their opinions and suggestions. . Regarding concerns about linking cancer to laboratory or reagent exposure, given that the causes of individual cancer are extremely complex, relevant departments are sincerely welcome to organize third-party agencies to conduct assessment and investigations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Finally, I would like to thank all sectors of society for their care and attention to the health of medical workers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;November 8, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[炮弹落在畹町镇：一座边陲小镇活在缅北战火旁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia photographed the war situation in Myanmar from the roof, blue in the distance The house on the roof is in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1131&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia took pictures of the war in Myanmar from the rooftop. The houses with blue roofs in the distance are in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the fifth day of the civil war in northern Myanmar, Wu Xia, who lives in the border town of Wanding, was so scared when she heard the sound of gunfire not far away that she turned off the iron Snack bar, hiding in a home made of reinforced concrete. Having lived in Wanding for more than 20 years, she told the Southern Weekend reporter that there had been wars on the opposite side before, with mostly gunshots, but the fighting in 2023 was the most fierce, all with heavy shelling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia climbed to the roof of her house, where she could see Myanmar across the river. In a 39-second video she shot, the sound of gunfire and artillery continued from the valley, and helicopters circled the top of the mountain. At the foot of the mountain were dense houses, stretching from Myanmar to the eastern town of Ruili City, Yunnan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, government army strongholds in many places in northern Myanmar were attacked by armed forces and exchanges of fire broke out. The fighting was fierce and the stalemate has continued to this day. On the national border, Wanding Town, which borders Bangsai Town in Myanmar, is a Chinese town that has been greatly affected by the war. Stray bullets have fallen into this town of about 10,000 people many times. In order to ensure the safety of residents, the local government arranged for school closures and mobilized residents to leave the town to avoid the war. The town implemented a &quot;only exit, no entry&quot; control policy, and even the town government staff evacuated to work in safe places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Map by Liang Shuyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Drawing by Liang Shuyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Don’t come out of your home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 28, a shell from Myanmar hit a residential building in Wanding Town, destroying the top four floors. A big hole was blown out of the building. A few hours after the explosion, Mr. Yang, who sells aluminum doors and windows, rushed to the scene out of curiosity. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the shell had exploded and there were no casualties. “An old lady told me that when the shell exploded, It was so shaken that she couldn&#39;t hear anything for two hours.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Peng Qi first heard the sound of shells and gunshots, she didn&#39;t know what they were. She thought someone was setting off fireworks. In June 2023, she was transferred from Ruili City to Wanding Town and worked as a store manager in a chain milk tea shop. The locals told her that it was the sound of war in Myanmar and comforted her: &quot;It&#39;s okay, we hear this sound every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals who are used to the sound of gunfire seem to be also attracted by it. This time the battle was frightening. At two or three o&#39;clock in the morning on October 29, Wu Xia was awakened by several gunshots while she was sleeping. That day, she listened to the sound of gunfire outside and judged that the exchange of fire between the two parties was fierce. The windows of a house about 200 meters away from her home were shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuxia Snack Shop sells some local specialty snacks, such as Pauluda, fried bait cubes, etc. It is only about 200 meters away from Wanding Port. Children in the third grade of primary school are afraid that artillery shells will penetrate the iron sheet and will go home when they hear the sound of artillery fire. Wu Xia believes that hiding at home is not necessarily safe. &quot;If there are really shells coming, you can&#39;t hide anywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan, who lives by the boundary river, seems to be at greater risk. She once saw a picture of a helicopter bombing on the other side of the river on a short video platform. The community administrator also kept telling her not to come out of the house. However, She works at Wanding Town Health Center and still needs to report to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that on October 31, she was at work when she was suddenly informed that a large crater had been blown up near her home, and her son, who was in primary school, was staying at home alone. &quot;It was really urgent at the time. I called my husband and ran home. When I got home and opened the door, I saw that my son was taking a nap.&quot; Tao Wan looked at her son sleeping soundly and felt, &quot;My heart is going to be broken.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan told Southern Weekend reporters that when she was a child, the sound of fighting on the other side of the river could be heard in Wanding Town. The most intense year.&quot; The scene of community workers and street broadcasts telling residents to retreat and avoid the fighting made Tao Wan feel panic like never before, &quot;I felt like I had to leave this home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that on October 27, the night when the war broke out, community members came to persuade them to leave: “If you have family and friends in Ruili, go to Ruili. &quot;Not only that, the community also informed that if you hear the sound of gunfire, please do not go out, and immediately find shelter to take shelter. Do not wait and see out of curiosity, and avoid exposing your body in open spaces to avoid being hit by stray bullets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, an on-duty staff member of the Wanding Town Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the staff in the government building had moved to a relatively safe place to work, leaving only a few on-duty staff, and the new place was still open. Within the Wanding area, it is five or six kilometers away from the town government building. The reason why they moved out of the town government building was because the building was &quot;directly opposite Myanmar and posed a major safety hazard.&quot; The person on duty said he was unclear about how many people were transferred in Wanding Town and when students would resume classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The fourth floor of a residential building in the town was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Town The fourth floor of a residential building was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The watermelon business chain is broken&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Residents living in Wanding noticed that this war was different from usual signals. In addition to the fierce gunfire, there were also Students are completely suspended from classes. The milk tea shop where Peng Qi works is only a few hundred meters away from Wanding Middle School. She discovered that on the evening of Friday, October 27, all the high school students who were originally on holiday on Sunday were taken home by their parents. Wu Xia&#39;s snack bar is not far from the middle school. She saw many parents driving to the school gate to pick up their students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili, a 21-year-old girl who grew up in Wanding, recalled that there was an emergency in the local area a few years ago when classes were suspended due to the war in Myanmar, but she could not remember the time clearly. She only remembered that it was the same time at that time. There are stray bullets flying into the territory. &quot;The most serious thing in recent years is the two incidents of stray bullets flying over. The situation in Myanmar has always been unstable. Once war starts, Wanding&#39;s geographical location is destined to be affected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cai In Lily&#39;s impression, there is only a boundary river two or three meters wide, and there are frequent exchanges between Wanding and the Myanmar town of Bangsai on the other side. She recalled that when she was five or six years old, it was easy to travel to Myanmar from the border crossing. When she was in primary school, seven or eight of the more than 40 students in her class were from Myanmar. &quot;We all studied Chinese courses and we all played together.&quot; The boundary river is also one of her recreational areas. She often goes fishing and picnicking by the river with her family and friends. A walking trail is built close to the boundary river, and Wanding residents often go for walks by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that some Wanding residents were indeed accidentally injured, mostly with skin injuries. &quot;After we debridement, we will ask them to go home quickly, because the hospital is located on a relatively high ground and is not safe. Some people were also transferred to higher-level hospitals by ambulances.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia discovered that since the beginning of the Northern Myanmar War Later, there were fewer and fewer people on the streets, especially tourists. As a famous border town and border port, there are endless tourists here all year round. Her snack bar is not far from the national gate and has about a hundred customers every day. But after the war broke out, only a few old customers who lived nearby came to the store, and &quot;there was no one on this street.&quot; Not only that, on October 30, the &quot;only go out, no go in&quot; rule was implemented in the central area of ​​Wanding Town. However, according to locals, the rule was only implemented for two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Qi also obviously felt that the flow of people had dropped sharply. In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter at 16:00 on November 2, Peng Qi said that the store&#39;s turnover that day was only more than 100 yuan, which is the price of about 10 cups of milk tea, and most of the customers were from nearby shops. Before the war, the store&#39;s daily turnover was about one thousand yuan. There are also brave tourists who go to the border to shoot short videos. Wu Xia said: &quot;Many men and women may also be afraid. They basically just take pictures and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the men and women Wu Xia saw, Perhaps there is also Zhou Feng, a melon seller. On November 2, 37-year-old Zhou Feng also visited the national gate of Wanding, but his destination was the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market. As the largest watermelon market in Southeast Asia, from the end of October to May of the following year is the time when Myanmar watermelons are on the market and exported to China. Zhou Feng revealed that during peak periods, the market could have 1,000 vehicles a day, each carrying 16 tons of watermelons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of October 2023, the price of Myanmar watermelon that has just been launched can reach four or five yuan per kilogram, which is not low. After the war broke out, Wanding&#39;s national gate was closed and watermelon could not enter the territory. Zhou Feng analyzed that the most affected people in the watermelon industry chain are melon farmers. The price of contracted land in Myanmar is relatively low, only three to four hundred yuan per mu, so most of the people who plant watermelons on contracted land in Myanmar are Chinese. Zhou Feng has been engaged in this industry for 13 years. He is grateful that it is the early stage of the watermelon market. &quot;If it takes more than a month to start the war, I will be annoyed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In previous years, at the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market, melon stalls were filled with watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In previous years, the watermelon wholesale market in Wanding was full of melon stalls Watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Eerily Quiet&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all Wanding residents were affected by the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 3 communities and 3 administrative villages within the jurisdiction of Wanding Town. 26-year-old Guo Yu lives with his family in Hunban Village, which is about 5 kilometers away from the border port and one or two kilometers away from Myanmar. Guo Yu runs a B&amp;B. Since the war started, there have been no guests staying. Fortunately, the shells did not fall near them, and the family&#39;s food, clothing, housing and transportation were not affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Yu’s mother is from Myanmar, and his father’s ancestral home is in Baoshan City, Yunnan Province. When they were young, they came to Wanding to buy land and build a house, and settled here. Guo Yu told Southern Weekend reporters that his grandmother&#39;s house was not affected by the war and was relatively safe for the time being. Guo Yu also feels safe and has no plans to move away. However, if the shells hit nearby, the family may move to Ruili, 20 kilometers away, and stay with relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan was not prepared to evacuate, but sent her youngest son back to her husband&#39;s hometown in Dehong Prefecture overnight. &quot;We all buy a house and a car on our own. This is my home. If I leave, it won&#39;t even have its roots.&quot; Since October 27, Tao Wan has felt uneasy every day. She is afraid that if an accident occurs, the house will be lost. . &quot;I don&#39;t know what to do in that situation. When I think of this possibility, I almost burst into tears.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan came to Wanding Town with her mother when she was 5 years old. Now she has Is 40 years old. Because she had to take care of her mother who didn&#39;t want to leave Wanding, Tao Wan, who went to college abroad, came back here again, until now. After the war broke out, Tao Wan placed her mother in a village far away from the border. She planned to wait until the war calmed down before taking the old man home. Tao Wan said that there are some elderly people in the town who have inconvenient legs and feet who are unwilling to move. They have deep feelings for Wanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dai language, Wanding means &quot;the place where the sun is at the top&quot;. Today, the town&#39;s shine is no longer dazzling. In Tao Wan&#39;s impression, Wanding was prosperous 20 to 30 years ago. Later, due to road planning, administrative divisions and other reasons, Wanding was slowly declining. Tao Wan felt aggrieved for the small town where she lived, &quot;There was an epidemic in the past three years, and now there is this war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili never felt that she was a girl who came out of a small town. She felt that Wanding was more like a small city. She remembers that Wanding Town was very lively around 2007, with people coming and going, and the shops on the street would sell Myanmar specialties, such as hot and sour noodles, milk candies, etc. Now, some of the shops that impressed Cai Lili have been closed, and many shops on the street are empty. &quot;After its decline in recent years, I gradually felt that it was really just a small town.&quot; Cai Lili said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this town is facing another test. On November 6, Peng Qi told Southern Weekend reporters that compared with the chaotic sound of gunfire in the past few days, the streets in Wanding are now &quot;eerily quiet&quot;. Except for the occasional pedestrian passing by, only military green trucks are left on the street. patrol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan has not heard the sound of gunfire recently, but she feels that the government departments and schools have shown no signs of relaxing. The school has not notified the resumption of classes, teaching is conducted in the form of online classes, and the community still counts every day and has not evacuated. resident information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“局外人”到“第一个人”：加缪110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRmVSmK7F8E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRm VSmK7F8E. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Albert Camus (November 7, 1913 - 1960 January 4), French writer and philosopher, born in Algeria. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature at the age of 44 and died unexpectedly at the age of 47. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, 1913, Albert Camus was born. On January 4, 1960, he died in an accidental car accident at the age of 46. Today, it has been 110 years since Camus was born and more than sixty years since his death, but people do not feel that Camus belongs to a distant era. He used his short writing career to create a series of distinctive contemporary images. , is still closely related to our living situation today. The embarrassment, discord, and sense of powerlessness of &quot;outsiders&quot;, the repeated hard labor in &quot;Sisyphus&quot;, and the struggle and dignity of people facing disaster in &quot;The Plague&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus is both a writer and a thinker. He does not capture readers with the splendor of his words, but shocks them with his postmodern understanding of life. He is the youngest winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature. one. Camus&#39;s enduring popularity is symptomatic. Just like Kafka, he wrote a &quot;clinical diagnosis&quot; of contemporary people&#39;s mental dilemma; just like Lu Xun, he does not provide bright answers, or even It&#39;s a bit dark and cold, but at the end of the coldness is a philosophy of resistance and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus once worked as a journalist. On January 1, 1940, he wrote an editorial for the last issue of the &quot;Republican Evening News&quot;. You can get a glimpse of his restraint, coolness, and calmness with a sense of power. Words: &quot;This year, hoping for happiness will be in vain, building it through work is the key. Don&#39;t hope for anything, but do something. Don&#39;t wait for others to build your destiny from beginning to end, especially when destiny It is still in our hands. The Evening Republican will not wish you happiness this year, knowing that you are going through a severe physical and mental trauma. But it will ask you to maintain the necessary strength and sobriety to strive to maintain your own tranquility and dignity. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the darkest moment of World War II. Shortly after Camus wrote this dedication, while fleeing on the border of France and Spain, Benjamin failed to get a pass and came to the end of his life. At the end, although Zweig fled to Brazil, he still committed suicide in despair. Camus belongs to a new generation of young people. He once joined the French Communist Party, fought and resisted, and condensed the power of his resistance into continuous writing. If the deaths of Benjamin and Zweig marked the spiritual boundaries of yesterday&#39;s world, Camus established the starting point of his writing on the wasteland of war and post-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The postwar world is neither a wasteland nor a new heaven and a new earth. His arguments with his friend Sartre and his ambivalent attitude toward the Algerian War made Camus increasingly lonely while receiving literary honors. When he returned to autobiographical writing and the &quot;first person&quot;, an accident caused this sharp soul to bid farewell in advance. For a writer like Camus, commemorating him at any time is both our condolences and an invitation for him to return. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;France’s “outsider”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 2 a.m. on November 7, 1913, her mother Catalina gave birth to Camus, who was the first child in the family. second son. The next day, at the Mondovi Municipal Government in Algeria, the father registered the birth of his child. He was 28 years old and worked as a wine cellar manager. The mother was 31 years old and filled in the occupation column as a housewife. The birthplace of Saint-Paul Farm is located 8 kilometers south of the city of Mondovi. The nearby city of Bonny is the most important port in French Algeria, not far from the Tunisian border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Algeria became a French colony in the 19th century, most of the immigrants who immigrated here were poor people from all over France, as well as Spain, Italy and other European countries. New immigrants were granted residence rights under French protection and lived among the overwhelming majority of locals. “The French in Algeria are of mixed race. Spaniards, Alsatians, Italians, Maltese, Jews, Greeks gather there,” Camus later wrote. Camus is a mixed-race child, his mother is Spanish, and he believes that his father comes from Alsace, the battlefield where France and Germany have fought for generations. The reason for &quot;thinking&quot; is that my father&#39;s exact ancestral home has been lost and difficult to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus had never met his father before he could remember. My father is 1.8 meters tall, with brown hair and blue eyes. He works in a wine company, supervising the grape pressing, winemaking, storage, and shipment to the Port of Pawnee for shipment. Not long after Camus was born, World War I broke out, and his father was conscripted into the French army. Almost as soon as he entered the battlefield, he was injured in the Battle of the Marne to prevent the German army from advancing towards Paris. He was hit by shell fragments and was sent to a rear hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 1914, my mother received the bad news by telegram, as well as a small piece of shrapnel removed from her husband&#39;s head that the widow had asked to keep. His father was mysterious to Camus. He often asked his mother: &quot;Am I really like my father?&quot; &quot;Oh, you look exactly like your father.&quot; During the four years of World War I, his mother received no After passing a penny in France, it was only a few months before the end of the war that I received official notification of her husband&#39;s death and a pension check. An accountant next door helped her fill out the pension application form because no one in her family knew how to fill it out. In order to make a living, my mother sorted warheads in an ammunition manufacturing factory until she suffered from rheumatism and was unable to continue this work, so she began to work as a domestic helper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 8 months to 17 years old, Camus lived with his mother and grandmother under the same roof in Algiers, the capital of Algeria. It was Belku, the workers&#39; district of the city, home to people who worked hard in small workshops and port equipment factories, craftsmen, small traders, grassroots civil servants and clerks. As an adult, Camus returned to the house frequently, sometimes to visit the elderly and sometimes as a temporary haven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in middle school, football fascinated Camus. He was very brave and liked to tackle from the feet of his opponents, so he was often injured. Camus described a fierce football match, on a pitch adjacent to a cemetery, in which the opposing players pressed forward mercilessly. They “were all on top of me, spikes on my shins, knees on my crotch, squeezing me against the goal post…” “I quickly learned that the ball doesn’t come from where you expect it to. This was very helpful in my life, especially in France, where not everyone is honest,&quot; Camus later wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Camus came to settle in Paris in early 1940, he felt that &quot;I am not from here, nor from anywhere else. The world is just a strange scenery, and my spirit is helpless here. Everything It has nothing to do with yourself.&quot; He was stuck between France and Algeria, between Paris and impoverished Bercoux across the Mediterranean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;969&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Camus (first from right) is backstage with two actors during the performance of his drama &quot;Martial Law&quot; in Paris in 1948. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sisyphus&quot;: The victorious loser&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While Sartre, who came from a middle-class background, was dreaming of a literary hero, and Beauvoir was enjoying her books and the gifts in the candy shop window, Camus was in a home without electricity, running water, newspapers and books, and no Growing up in the world of radio, he once wrote in his diary: &quot;Living in poverty for a few years is enough to create all the sensitivity.&quot; Tuberculosis plagued Camus throughout his life, but it also exempted him from military service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1942, &quot;The Outsider&quot; and &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; were published one after another. The former tells the story of a French-Algerian named Meursault who experienced two deaths. The first was his mother&#39;s death. He couldn&#39;t even remember the date and didn&#39;t shed tears. The second was when he had an affair with a holdover on the beach. There was a conflict with the Arab about the knife. Meursault happened to be holding a friend&#39;s gun. When his eyes were dazzled by the reflection of the sea and the blade, he almost subconsciously shot the man. After being arrested, Meursault told the judge in confusion that the reason he shot was the sun. Meursault did not defend himself, and the court also lacked interest in the murder case and focused on investigating his personal life. Indifference became the biggest evidence of crime and was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of the essay collection &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; is taken from a story in &quot;Homer&#39;s Epic&quot;. King Sisyphus disobeyed God and was sentenced to push a huge boulder up a mountain for eternity, each time the boulder approached the top of the mountain. When the time comes, it will slip from his hand and roll down again, and he can only go back again, starting over and over again. Camus used the myth of Sisyphus, just like Freud through the Oedipus complex, to make the mythical figure deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts again. The most famous sentence in &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; may be: &quot;There is only one philosophical question that is truly serious, and that is suicide. To judge whether life is worth living or not...&quot; Camus said in the preface of an English translation many years later , wrote this book because &quot;even within the borders of nihilism, it is possible to find ways to move beyond nihilism.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play Caligula, published in 1944, discusses freedom and meaninglessness pushed to the extreme by recreating the story of the assassinated Roman Emperor Suetonius. These three books are collectively called Camus&#39; &quot;Trilogy of the Absurd.&quot; They were written and published in the critical state of war and occupied Paris, where everything was compromised and everything was lost. From Kierkegaard&#39;s existential philosophy, Camus saw Abraham, who sacrificed his son, as &quot;infinitely He gave up everything, and then took it all back with the help of absurd power.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus took the initiative to get to know him during the rehearsal of Sartre&#39;s play &quot;The Fly&quot;, and the two hit it off. Previously, Sartre had written an article for Camus&#39;s novel &quot;The Stranger&quot;, and Camus had commented on it. The special &quot;Disgusting&quot;. Beauvoir and Sartre found that Camus was a simple, happy man who was always funny and vulgar in his conversations, very emotional, and would even sit on a snowy street at two in the morning and talk about his love troubles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don Juan went from one woman to another not because of a lack of love, but because he loved them with equal passion and devoted himself to them every time. He must repeat this talent and harmony. Explore... Why do you have to love less to love well?&quot; &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; reads. Camus had two marriages. His first wife, Simone, was unable to quit morphine, which caused him great psychological trauma. After remarrying Francine, Camus maintained semi-public intimate relationships with many women. , including theater actress Maria Casares, who exchanged more than 800 love letters. It is as if Don Juan became an incarnation of Sisyphus pushing the boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Plague&quot;: End and Resistance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II and the liberation of Paris, the reputations of Sartre, Beauvoir and Camus were at their peak, and the Left Bank The Flower Goddess and the Double Sole Cafe in Shanghai have shrouded the halo of existentialist writers, and the radius of the halo extends to the United States on the other side of the ocean. All three of them received invitations to visit from New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From March to May 1946, Camus traveled around the United States. He was more nervous than Sartre and felt that he was always affected by endless little troubles. He&#39;s also a careful observer, noting that Americans drink juice in the morning, drink scotch and soda across the country, and are passionate about animals, from gorillas at the Bronx Zoo to taxidermy at the Museum of Natural History. , death and the dead can be dressed up as quickly as possible, &quot;die and leave the rest to us.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only place that made Camus feel familiar and at ease was the Bowery Street in New York. At that time, it was still an abandoned area, full of cheap bars and run-down hotels, with the elevated railway running from the height of the second floor. Passing by, shadows covered everything below. Camus was disgusted by the United States and felt that there was a lack of pain and tragedy, but in the eyes of many critics, &quot;The Stranger&quot; is a parody of American noir novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, the novel &quot;The Plague&quot; was published and was so popular among readers that it was reprinted eight times in two years. After that, &quot;The Plague&quot; and &quot;The Stranger&quot; were at the top of the French literary bestseller list for a long time. From 1941 to 1942, the plague was prevalent in Algeria, which was the starting point for Camus to prepare &quot;The Plague&quot;. The reason why this novel is so thrilling is because the plague is described as both real and terrifying, and it is also symbolic. It alludes to World War II. During this period, the harsh reality of the Nazis in Germany was wreaking havoc. Nazism and fascism are also a political and spiritual plague. Its military power, spy system, autocracy and racism sweep across everything like the god of death. After being manipulated by it, they either succumb to it, cooperate with it, or know that it is impossible. Those who resist for the land are like all living beings in the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Camus highlighted three symbolic situations of life. One is the situation of separation, including the separation of relatives, separation of husband and wife, and separation of lovers, which means isolation, blockade, imprisonment, and exile. , concentration camp... The second is that there is no condition of any woman in the novel, which means imbalance, deformity, bitterness, and lifelessness... The most terrifying atmosphere and situation is death...&quot; Liu Mingjiu, the translator of the Chinese version of &quot;The Plague&quot; Said, &quot;&#39;The plague is lurking in everyone, because no one, yes, no one in the world is immune to it&#39;... In this way, Camus also put his philosophy about the absurd world in &quot;The Plague&quot; It greatly broadens and deepens the story, and points the absurd roots to human faults and human society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the desperate situation of World War II, Camus was not the only one who chose to write about a critical state through the background of the plague. , the German playwright Brecht also created &quot;The Life of Galileo&quot;, in which Galileo also experienced a narrow escape from the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I tried to use the plague to express the suffocation we suffer and the environment we endure that threatens and drives people into exile.” Camus said. In the apocalyptic city of Ahlan, the protagonist of the novel, Dr. Bernard Rieux, became an ordinary hero because of his dedication to his duties. Camus reshapes heroes in the form of anti-heroes. When disaster strikes, what we can expect is not a hero falling from the sky, but every ordinary person resisting evil through the smallest efforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Resistor, a collection of essays published in 1951, is where Camus clearly proposed the philosophy of resistance after the philosophy of the absurd, &quot;What is a rebel? A person who says &#39;no&#39;. However, although he He refuses but does not give up: he is also the person who says &#39;yes&#39; from the very beginning.&quot; However, this book with a huge amount of information put him in a situation where he was surrounded by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Back to &quot;First Man&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Rebel&quot; involves a commentary on Surrealism and was immediately criticized literary by the group. Refute. More intense criticism came from leftist thinkers. Because he disagreed with Camus&#39;s many views on the revolution and Soviet history, the magazine &quot;Modern&quot; edited by Sartre published a fiercely criticized article by its editor, Francis Chanson. Camus had to respond and wrote an open letter to Sartre to defend himself. This led to Sartre&#39;s &quot;Reply to Camus&quot;, which was extremely harsh and mean, calling Camus &quot;a bourgeois&quot; and &quot;abandoned history&quot;, and the publication of &quot;The Resistance&quot; was a counter-revolutionary &quot;Thermidor Coup&quot;. . Their long-standing friendship was ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike many writers who only define their writing by &quot;pure literature&quot;, Camus has always been an organic intellectual. It was the strong &quot;political nature&quot; of &quot;The Resistance&quot; that stirred up the hornet&#39;s nest. The break between Sartre and Camus, the pair of existential writers, and the subsequent breakup between Godard and Truffaut, the twin stars of the French New Wave of cinema, became sensational and intriguing events in the postwar cultural history. Sartre stood in a more radical position. Even when it came to the Nobel Prize, he was more radical and rejected it outright. What is depressing is that Camus, a writer who has always been in the progressive camp, was denounced as conservative because he was more moderate on certain issues, or did not follow a certain principle or dogma and put forward his personal understanding and judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1949, Camus created a play &quot;The Just&quot;, in which a group of &quot;terrorists&quot; debate whether innocent people can be harmed when carrying out political assassinations. Camus made it clear that this was wrong. When Algeria&#39;s independence struggle broke out in 1954, he also believed that the rebels&#39; planting bombs and killing innocent people were equally unfair as the French government&#39;s violence and execution. This view made him controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a speech celebrating Camus&#39;s winning of the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1957, Camus was asked to explain why he did not support the Algerian uprising against colonialism. He said: &quot;Now people are going to Algeria. put bombs on the tram tracks. My mother might have been on one of the tracks. If that was justice, I would have chosen my mother.&quot; Camus called for the creation of an Arab, Berber, Blackfoot nation in Algeria A coalition government in which Frenchmen (European immigrants) governed as equals made everyone hate him. French nationalists feel that he sympathizes with Algerians, and Algerians feel that he represents white French people. However, his father died needlessly at the age of 29, and his mother was an extremely poor and illiterate woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 4, 1960, the car driven by publisher Michel Gallimard with Albert Camus in the back seat crashed into a tree, rolled and struck another. In the tree, Camus was thrown out of the back window. In the mud not far away, people found a briefcase containing Camus&#39;s diary and an unfinished novel &quot;First Man&quot;. This book is based on his childhood life in Algeria and imagines him. &#39;s father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Camus passed away, although Sartre did not forgive him, he wrote an obituary full of praise in the &quot;Osservatore Française&quot;: &quot;He was the heir to the ethical school of anti-historical trends in the 20th century. , his works are perhaps the most original of all French literati. His stubborn, narrow-minded, simple and simple humanitarian feelings launched an unreasonable challenge to the widespread and ugly orders of our time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the news of Camus’ death over the phone, Beauvoir took sleeping pills that had been discontinued for a long time, but still couldn’t fall asleep, so she got out of bed and braved the biting January drizzle in Paris. Wandering the streets. The next morning, she was still in a daze: &quot;He can&#39;t see this morning.&quot; But in fact, Camus not only did not pass away, but because of the strong impact of the car accident, he became the center of the world&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last few pages of &quot;Camus&#39; Notes&quot;, there are these words: &quot;In the short daylight given to you, keep warm, illuminate, and don&#39;t deviate from your track. ... Millions of other suns come to accompany you to rest. ... Under the happy slate, sleep for the first time. ... The wind sows, the wind harvests, but the creator is human, passing through the times, with a moment of life Proud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(References: Herbert Lotman&#39;s &quot;The Biography of Camus&quot;, Sarah Bakewell&#39;s &quot;The Existential Café&quot;, &quot;The Complete Works of Camus&quot; edited by Liu Mingjiu and &quot;Camus&#39; Notes: 1935-1959 (Selected Collection)&quot; translated by Guo Hongan)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[再访“山地之王”：高仙芝的西域足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260116]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hijri 133 (&lt;em>;Ten years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty, AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;751 &lt;/em>;), the month of pilgrimage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hajj month is the 12th month of Muharram. This year&#39;s pilgrimage month is in midsummer. On the edge of the Central Asian steppes, a black flag army knelt down and prayed in the direction of the Holy Land on the right bank of the Talas River, completed the morning ritual, and then set up its formation facing the rising sun. : At the front are light cavalry equipped with large horses. They hold Damascus scimitars and stand on foot to harness their power; then there is an infantry group mainly composed of Khorasan and Tocharian people, and behind them are archers and long-range soldiers. Spearmen; on both wings are Sogdian cavalry from the river countries. Although they are high-spirited, they have not been naturalized for a long time, and they are pagans. Their combat effectiveness is still questionable, so they are used to protect the flanks of the Islamic army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opposite the black flag army are the enemy forces from the mysterious silk country in the east. They were much smaller in number, so they placed their infantry in front in a defensive formation. These infantrymen are uniformly holding Eastern-style long-handled swords, which are bladed on both sides, reflecting dazzling light in the morning sun. The huge stainless steel blade is extremely sharp, no less than the cannibal&#39;s scimitar. With its weight Able to split a galloping horse in half, and as strong as a spearman to withstand the impact of cavalry. These infantrymen are also equipped with horses for marching, but these pack horses are now scattered along the Talas River behind the enemy&#39;s side. Behind the infantry were crossbowmen equipped with powerful crossbows, and on both sides were Qarluks Turkic cavalry from the northern steppes. Behind the main force of these infantry and cavalry are their commanders, divided into main generals, deputy generals and special generals, as well as vassal troops from Bakhna as reserves - I heard that those guys started this war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commander-in-chief of the Black Flag Army, Abu Muslim, is The great food in black &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(currently translated as the Abbasid Dynasty)&lt;/span>; is the leading founding father and a military genius who became a monk on the way. He was born as a slave of Persian descent and had been preaching at the bottom of the Great Food Empire for a long time. He returned to his homeland of Persia six years ago and raised an army to resist the white-clothed Food Empire&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(now Translated by Umayyad Dynasty)&lt;/span>;. Last winter, he led his army into Mesopotamia. In the Battle of the Zab River, he won with a small number and a large number. He first used an array of spearmen to withstand multiple rounds of attacks by the opponent&#39;s cavalry, and then launched a cavalry charge to defeat the enemy who had lost their fighting spirit. The infantry forced into the river with floating ice floes, defeated the enemy that was at least three times their size, hammered the last nail in the coffin of the white-clothed food that had enjoyed the country for ninety years, and established a more than 500-year-old army in Baghdad. Years of black food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year he once again set out from Persia on an expedition to Central Asia to face the Chinese army who also came from afar. The commander of the other side heard that he was a handsome man named Gao Xianzhi. However, the origin of this battle has to start in Persia a full hundred years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Talas Valley in Kyrgyzstan. The location where the Battle of Talas took place is no longer known, but the battle took place at the mouth of the valley, and the terrain will be relatively flat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Barbarians of the West&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大In the second year of Yonghui of the Tang Dynasty (&lt;em>;AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;651&lt;/em>;), the young &quot;Tian Khan&quot; Li Zhi met in Chang&#39;an with an envoy sent for help by the last emperor of the Persian Sassanid Empire Yi Siqi. . The envoy said that a group of barbarians from the west were attacking Persia: they asked us to choose one of three situations: either accept their faith, pay a poll tax, or go to war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The envoy did not know that when he begged Tang Gaozong to send troops to rescue Persia, Yi Siqi had already died on the way to escape. The surviving prince Belus &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Persian means &quot;Victor&quot;)&lt;/span>; suffered repeated defeats and finally fled to China. , and died here, buried in Luoyang, the eastern capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;barbarians&quot; who destroyed the Sasanian Dynasty were called &quot;Tachik&quot; by the Persians, but they were actually Arabs. The name &quot;Dashi&quot; comes from the Tayyi tribe in eastern Arabia. It was regarded by the Persians as a collective name for Arab Muslims. After it was spread to the Tang Dynasty, because they used white flags, Chinese history books called it &quot;Dashi in White&quot;. . After the Persians converted to Islam, they were called Tachik by the Turks. This is probably the origin of the name of the Tajik people who also speak Persian today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhi, who had been on the throne for less than three years, had no interest in rescuing Persia, which was far away. At that time, the Tang Dynasty had not yet completely pacified southern Xinjiang, and its limited military resources had to be used to control the four towns of Anxi to the east of Congling, and were beyond its reach to the west of Congling. After Dashi conquered Persia, the expansion momentum in the east was suspended due to domestic battles for throne. It was not until the 60th year that the rear sent the famous general Qutaybah ibn Muslim to the east to attack the Transoxiana region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hezhong&quot; area, as the name suggests, is the Amu Darya River, the two largest rivers in Central Asia&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (called Wuhu River in ancient times)&lt; /span>;The plain area between the Syr Darya River (ancient name Yaoshashui), it borders the Central Asian grasslands to the north, the Tianshan Mountains and the Hindu Kush Mountains to the southeast, two long and high majestic mountain ranges, and Persia to the southwest plateau. Business travelers who walked out of Congling along the two rivers gathered here, and the goods changed hands here and continued to the Mesopotamia and Asia Minor through the Persian Plateau. Therefore, the Transoxiang area has been an important hub of the Silk Road since ancient times. During the Han Dynasty, the Yuezhi people migrated here from the Mongolian Plateau under the attacks of the Xiongnu and Wusun. After merging with the locals, they formed the Sogdians. They established many oasis countries such as Kang, Shi, An, and Shi in the arid river area. Chinese history books call them the Nine Surnames of Zhaowu. Because the Sogdians lived on the trade route, they became an outstanding commercial nation that integrated trade between the East and the West in the Middle Ages. A large number of merchants moved to the Central Plains to work as businessmen. The image of the Hu people on the camels and horses in the Tang Sancai is the Sogdians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; >;In the first year of Xiantian of the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(712 AD)&lt;/span>;, Qu Dibo marched into the river from Khorasan in northeastern Persia, and successively Capture Samadan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now translated as Samarkand)&lt;/span>;, and the Kingdom of Shi , STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Tashkent)&lt;/span>;, Bakhna&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s translation of Fergana)&lt;/span>; and other countries. At that time, Li Longji, Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, had just ascended the throne and was plotting to overthrow his aunt Princess Taiping, who was involved in politics. They were as indifferent to the killings west of Congling as his grandfather Li Zhi was. Two years later, Qu Dibo, who was militarily unstoppable, was accidentally killed during civil strife. The white-clad army retreated as quickly as it came. Tubo, which had coveted this place for a long time, took advantage of the opportunity and established the new king Ada in Bukhanna. This move immediately aroused great vigilance in the Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samarkand, Uzbekistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中Sub-geopolitics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bahanna&quot; is an ancient name, now it is called &quot;Ferg&#39;ona&quot;, and its consonant &quot;g&quot; was still given by Russian colonists In addition, I heard that the local people actually pronounce it as Fer&#39;ana, and the pronunciation is close to &quot;Fuana&quot;. It is a basin at the end of the West Tianshan Mountains. It was called Dawan in the Han Dynasty and the famous sweat-blooded horse was produced here. During the Soviet era, in order to divide the Turkic tribes so that they could divide and rule, the Russians forcibly subdivided five ethnic groups in Central Asia and built five intertwined &quot;Stans&quot;. Especially in the small Fergana Basin, they actually divided them It was divided among the three union republics of Uzbekistan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan, and a large number of enclaves and even enclaves within enclaves were carved out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fergana Basin map, enclaves within enclaves, can be seen intertwined. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna in the Tang Dynasty did not have these disputes. It was a single-ethnic Sogdian country. It was located in Between Suiye, an important town in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty, and the Hezhong countries, it was the key point from the Anxi Protectorate to the Hezhong area via Congling. What&#39;s more important is that the Tang Dynasty could accept the food control of Bukhana, but it could not sit back and watch Tibet enter the Central Asian grasslands - this involved the geopolitics among the four major countries in Central Asia at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna is surrounded by great powers, with Turks in the north, Tubo in the south, Dashi in the west, and Tang in the east. The Turks were traditional conquerors of the grasslands, and used their strong fighting power to collect protection fees from the riverine countries; the White Food was an emerging empire that combined politics and religion, but in the early stages of its expansion, it was neither for war nor for wealth, but for &quot;Find an outlet for the warlike spirit of each tribe&quot; - Turks and Dashi are a zero-sum game between the old and new conquerors, which cannot be reconciled; Tubo arose in the bitter cold land of Qinghai-Tibet, and always aimed at the rich Central Plains, but suffered from Unable to open the tightly-knitted fences of the Tang Dynasty, they detoured to Congling, hoping to join forces with the Turks in the north to carve up the western regions of the Tang Dynasty, and then enter the hinterland of the Central Plains along the Hexi Corridor; and the Tang Dynasty was the only one of the four great powers to be dominated by farming. The political power established by the nation, the primary goal of opening up the Western Region is to use offense as defense to defend its own territory: from Guanzhong via Longxi and Hexi to Anxi, and finally reach Congling, the western border of the Tarim Basin. Just defend the towering Congling. Block external forces from entering the Central Plains. Therefore, the Tang Dynasty’s pursuit was not to plunder land and colonize&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(大食)&lt;/span>; or to exploit the natives&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Turkic)&lt;/span>;, opening up channels&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Tubo)&lt;/span>; or protecting trade routes ——The trade routes were just a by-product of the expansion of the Tang Dynasty, not the purpose. Instead, they simply defended themselves and blocked the north-south passages to prevent powerful enemies from forming alliances to deal with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, Tubo and Turks from the south and north seek to join forces to attack the common enemy Tang Dynasty, while Datang Dynasty and Dashi Dynasty occupy both sides of Congling, one from the east and the other from the west. Once Tibet crossed this east-west equilibrium line and was expected to enter the northern grasslands and join the Turks, Datang&#39;s &quot;red alert&quot; was triggered. In the third year of Kaiyuan of the Tang Dynasty (715 AD), Qu Dibo was killed, the food army withdrew, and the Tubo army In the year when they conquered Ba Khanna, Zhang Xiaosong, the supervisory censor who was inspecting the Anxi Protectorate, made a decisive decision. He marched across the Daidai territory and commanded the vassal army of the slave country to march thousands of miles straight, crossed the Congling Mountains and arrived at the Ba Khanna Basin, where he defeated the heavy Tibetan army. Eight hundred years after Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty conquered Dawan, he occupied this place again and blocked the Tibetan entrance to the Central Asian grassland through the Congling West Road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Tubo tried to open up the Congling East Road through Taobolu, but was also frustrated by Zhang Xiaosong, who was the governor of Beiting at the time: in the tenth year of Kaiyuan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(722 AD)&lt;/span>; Zhang Xiaosong sent 4,000 cavalry to rescue Xiao Bolu and defeated the Tibetan army. This matter has been mentioned in the previous article &quot;Visiting the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot;: Gao Xianzhi&#39;s Plateau Footprints&quot; and, so I won’t go into details. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Expedition to Congling West Road&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Eight Years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (749 AD)&lt;/span>;, two years after Gao Xianzhi regained Xiaobolu, he returned to Boxian &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Qiemo, Xinjiang)&lt;/span>; span>;Destroy Tubo. The Tibetan army, which suffered a bloody blow on the eastern front, had to turn around and head to the Congling West Road on the western front to find the weaknesses of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s Western Region defense system. After receiving the information, Gao Xianzhi could have gone to Bahanna, where he would have been waiting for the Tibetan troops who had been on an expedition to come and give them a head-on attack. However, Gao Xianzhi, who had been pursuing the initiative on the battlefield all his life, did not do that: since the Congling West Road was still passable. , then I will cut it off completely! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Chitral, Pakistan, the seat of the ancient Shishi Kingdom. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianbao Nine Years&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (A.D. 750)&lt;/span>; Gao Xianzhi sent troops to Congling for the second time and came to Xiaobolu again. From there, he followed the Suyi River (Today&#39;s Gilgit River)&lt;/span>;Go upstream, cross the Shanduer Pass, and head to the Kingdom of Shishi at the eastern foot of the central Hindu Kush Mountains ;&quot;>;(now Chitral, Pakistan)&lt;/span>;. Some historians have verified that the Kingdom of Shishi was the end point of Alexander the Great&#39;s Eastern Expedition. The ancient tribes that thrive in the nearby Kalasha Valley are said to be the descendants of the Greek expeditionary force. The distance from Xiaobolu to Yushi is more than 700 miles. Now it takes two full days to travel by road. The road conditions are very good on the first day, and there are long-distance buses available. On the second day, we can only take the local four-wheel drive with the villagers. It is possible to travel west along the Mastuj Valley, with the continuous snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Kush to the north and the 6,542-meter-high snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Raj to the south. Peak Buni Zom. The Mastuje River cuts deeply into the dense loess at your feet, forming a T-shaped towering platform, which is reminiscent of the Tuolai River Valley outside Jiayuguan. The soldiers under Gao Xianzhi must have drank by the Tuolai River on their way from the Central Plains to the Western Regions via Hexi. Let&#39;s cross the horse, I believe they also discovered the similarities between the two places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Toolai Valley outside Jiayuguan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two Tang Books&quot; &quot;&quot; does not record how long Gao Xianzhi went on the expedition against the Xu division, and &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot; only mentions the winter march of the Tang army. According to my estimate of the terrain along the route of our division, it would have taken an ancient army at least half a month to carry its baggage. It was even more difficult for the Tubo army: since the Tang army had controlled Xiaobolu and the Suyi River Valley three years ago, the Tubo army had to detour through the high mountains in the south. Whether they could reach Yushi in a month was a problem. The Kingdom of Yushi is an ally of Tubo. It is located at the midpoint of the West Congling Road. After passing Yushi, you can cross the Hindu Kush Mountains, then follow the Panchi River through the Alai Mountains in the west of Congling and the West Tianshan Mountains, and finally arrive at Bakhna Basin - that was another more than a month&#39;s journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Gao Xianzhi made a surprise attack on the Chu army and cut off the west road of Congling, the extremely tired Tibetan soldiers who had come from afar no longer had to cross the four great mountains of Hindu Lage, Hindu Kush, Congling and Xitian Mountain. Mountains, not to mention struggling to attack the fortress jointly guarded by the Tang army and the Sogdians in the scorching Bukhan, you can return to the cool Qinghai-Tibet Plateau all in one piece - isn&#39;t this the peace dividend brought by General Gao of the Tang Dynasty? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, after losing the important relay point of Xushi Division, Tubo completely gave up the idea of ​​opening up the east and west roads of Congling. Zai and Thirteen were defeated by Gao Xianzhi&#39;s successor Feng Changqing on the two eastern fronts, so that the Tibetan army was unable to pose a major threat to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty for the next ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi successively put down the Tibetan offensive on the east and west fronts, and pushed the Tang Dynasty&#39;s military control line from the east of Congling to the west of Congling, achieving the strategic goal of stabilizing the Western Region and defending the Central Plains. It can be said that it has achieved reached the pinnacle of personal military achievement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at this moment, he received a letter of request for help from Ba Khanna, asking him to stop by the army to attack the Shi Kingdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Traditional teahouse in the Fergana Basin&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;&quot;All the Hus are angry&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna was first destroyed by the White-coated Eaters, and then was supported by Tubo as a puppet regime. Finally, the country was restored with the aid of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s reinforcements, so it was China&#39;s The most loyal vassal state in Asia to the Tang Dynasty can be compared to Goryeo to the Ming Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So why did Bahan call on the Tang army to attack Shiguo? There is a lack of clear historical records on this matter. It is generally believed that there may be three reasons. First, there is a gap between Bukhanna and Shiguo. Bukhanna is located in the basin upstream of Yaoxishui, while Shiguo is located downstream of the basin where Yaoxashui flows out. , its capital city, Toshkent, is today&#39;s capital of Uzbekistan, Tashkent. &quot;Toshkent&quot; means &quot;Tosh&quot;, which means &quot;stone&quot; in Turkic language. The two countries are both Sogdian countries. The Shi State blocked the exit of Bukhanna to the Central Asian grasslands, while the Bukhanna blocked the water source of the Shiguo. There may be grudges between the two countries; secondly, Bukhanna showed his loyalty to the Tang Dynasty. Take advantage of the power vacuum in the Hezhong area to control it; thirdly, the Shi Kingdom is located at the frontier of the Hezhong area and the Central Asian grasslands, and has good relations with Tuqishi, the successor of the main Turkic tribe Tuqishi, surnamed Huang, and Tuqishi It has long been a threat to Datang and has stepped on Datang&#39;s red line. In short, Gao Xianzhi adopted Ba Khanna&#39;s suggestion, led the army northward into the Fergana Basin, and then followed Yaoshashui to the Stone Kingdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shi Kingdom belongs to the nine surnamed states of Zhaowu in the Hezhong area. It is the land controlled by the Tang Dynasty. They regard the Tang Dynasty as their suzerain state and pay regular tribute to the Tang Dynasty, but they have no practical administrative, financial and military capabilities. Manage and control relationships. The name of Gao Xianzhi&#39;s crusade against Shiguo was &quot;no vassal courtesy&quot;, but the specific crimes were not listed in the history books. The weak Shi Kingdom proposed peace, but Gao Xianzhi pretended to agree, but imprisoned Naju Chebishi, the king of Shi Kingdom who came to negotiate in person - he had used a similar strategy in the Battle of Xiaobolu to trap his relatives with property. After the Tubo nobles came out of the city, they arrested and beheaded them - and then captured Tuozhe City without any bloodshed. After the city was broken, Gao Xianzhi sent his troops to massacre and plunder a large number of treasures from the Shi Kingdom. He himself received &quot;more than ten dendrobiums, five or six golden camels, many good horses and precious jade, and his family was rich in millions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Sese&quot; mentioned here is one of the most expensive minerals in the Middle Ages: lapis lazuli. It originates from the Badakhshan region in the upper reaches of the Wuhu River &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now northeastern Afghanistan)&lt;/span>;, and is re-exported and trafficked through the river area to All over the world, it is not only a precious gemstone, a &quot;magic medicine&quot; for treating diseases, but also a rare blue and purple pigment. The turquoise tone that became popular in the 2022 New Year&#39;s Eve dance &quot;Only This Green&quot; originated from the handed down treasure &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot; painted by Song Huizong with precious lapis lazuli from the palace collection for the young painter Wang Ximeng, and Bai Juyi&#39;s famous saying &quot; &quot;Half the river is rustling and half the river is red&quot;, what is chanted is also the color of lapis lazuli that the river emits under the setting sun. Gao Xianzhi plundered a large amount of lapis lazuli from the Stone Kingdom, which must have been treasures accumulated in his treasury over the years, especially before gold, so its value can be imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi captured the King of Shiguo, the King of Yushi, the Tubo chief and the Tuqi Shi Khan surnamed Huang who was probably captured in Shiguo during this expedition&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(This may explain why Gao Xianzhi massacred Tuozhe City to punish Shi Guo&#39;s collaboration with the enemy)&lt;/span>; All of them were sent back to Chang&#39;an to offer prisoners, and their military exploits can be described as outstanding. But he His betrayal of trust and cruel massacre aroused the public indignation of all the countries in the river except Ba Khanna. According to the &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot; record, &quot;The prince of Shiguo fled to the barbarians and accused Xianzhi of deception, corruption and violence.&quot; . All the barbarians were angry, and they lured Da Shi to attack the four towns.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the historical records of Da Shi, the cause of the war was that Ba Khanna was hostile to the Shi Kingdom and asked for help from the Tang Dynasty; the Tang army surrounded Shi Kingdom, the king of Shi Kingdom surrendered and was not persecuted; after Dashi learned about this, he sent troops to fight against Tang Dynasty - this narrative lacks logic and it is difficult to explain the reason why Dashi sent troops. In my opinion, Dashi sent troops that year The change of dynasty has just been completed, and the black-clothed food has replaced the white-clothed food. A victory in the external war is needed to heal the internal divisions. The commander-in-chief Bingbo Xilin has just suppressed Anguo&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style, italic style _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Bukhara, Uzbekistan)&lt;/span>;&#39;s rebellion freed up his hands to use Anguo as a base to send troops to invade the Hezhong area that his predecessor Qudibo had conquered. Now the Hezhong countries take the initiative He came to submit and fell into his trap. Bo Xilin then took over and annexed all the land in the river, and then led the high-spirited army of Dashi and the vassal armies of the river countries to march eastward along the Central Asian grasslands, with a straight front. Refers to Suiye City, the outpost of the Tang Dynasty in the Western Regions.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Gao Xianzhi learned of the great changes in the river, he led the main forces of the four towns of Anxi and the vassal armies of Geluolu and Bahanna to cross Congling for the third time. Heading to the river to quell the rebellion, the two armies met at Talos between Tuozhe City and Suiye City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the map of the Battle of Talas, Ningyuan is Bakhna. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Battle of Sekigahara in Central Asia&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&quot;Taluosi&quot; is the name of the city in the eastern part of the Stone Kingdom. It is named after the Talas River, which is an intermountain river in the remnants of the Western Tianshan Mountains. Although the water volume is not large, it has a long history and is more than a thousand miles long. The lower reaches of the Talas River flow northwest along the valley and finally enter the grassland area. Today, the mountains within the valley belong to Kyrgyzstan, and the plains outside the valley belong to Kazakhstan. There is a Kyrgyz town called Talas in the valley, and a large Kazakh city called Taraz on the grassland outside the valley. During the Soviet era, the Kirov Reservoir was built at the pass of the Talas Valley in 1975, which blocked the small amount of river water. The reservoir was only 7 meters deep and was used for agricultural irrigation in the valley. Therefore, the Talas River entered Kazakhstan. After the border of Stan, only a trickle remained, forming a thirsty oasis, and finally stopped in the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Kirov Reservoir built in the Soviet era&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of It has been so long that it is now impossible to confirm whether Talos City in the Tang Dynasty is today&#39;s Talas Town or Talaz City, or somewhere in between. Because we are located on the border between Kyrgyzstan and Kazakhstan, as a foreigner, I cannot go to the exit of the Talas Valley—the place where the Talas War is most likely to take place—to conduct inspections, nor can I fly a drone from the air. Overlooking this river valley. But what is certain is that the Datang Allied Forces with fewer troops occupied the inner side of the valley with a slightly higher terrain, using mountains and rivers to protect their flanks; the Dashi Allied Forces with superior strength attacked the valley from the grassland side. The battlefield was opened on the north bank of the Rath River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taras River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About the comparison of the military strength of the two sides , historians have different opinions. Currently, it is generally believed that the strength of the Allied Forces of the Tang Dynasty is 20,000 to 30,000. Considering that the strength of the entire Anxi Protectorate does not exceed 30,000, and they have to guard the huge southern border, it is impossible to transfer all of them to the front line. I am inclined to According to the records of &quot;Zi Zhi Tong Jian&quot;, Gao Xianzhi&#39;s total troops for this expedition were about 30,000. It is estimated that half of them were Tang troops, mainly infantry, and the rest were vassal armies of Geluolu and Bahanna. Among them, Geluolu army As cavalry, Bakhna&#39;s army was also dominated by infantry. There is another theory that the Tang army had as many as 60,000 to 70,000 troops, which means that most of them were vassal troops. This is not consistent with the actual situation in the Tang Dynasty when all the people in the Hezhong area rebelled against their relatives and only Bukhanna followed, while Geluo As a newly emerging Turkic tribe, Lu could not provide so many troops. There is even less historical data on the Great Eclipse. It is generally believed that there were 70,000 to 100,000 people, and some believe that it was as high as 200,000 to 300,000 people. I think that the logistics support conditions at that time could not support such a huge force on the grassland expedition, so I tentatively think that this The first battle was a field battle between 70,000 Dashi Allied Forces and 30,000 Datang Allied Forces on the banks of the Talas River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;History records that this battle lasted for five days. In the first four days, the Dashi army attacked, but failed to break through the tight defensive formation formed by the Tang army. But on the fifth day, the battlefield situation changed dramatically. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some Japanese scholars likened this battle to the &quot;Battle of Sekigahara in Central Asia&quot; - the Battle of Sekigahara was the largest battle in Japan&#39;s Azuchi Momoyama era. The main force of the Western Army was outnumbered. When the enemy was about to take the initiative on the battlefield, the friendly Kobayakawa Hideaki tribe who had been stationary at the top of the flank suddenly switched sides and cut into the rear of the main force of the Western Army, which was fighting fiercely with the Eastern Army, forming a pincer attack on it. The Western Army collapsed. Although this analogy is not exact, it is quite similar to the reversal of the Battle of Talos: The Tang Army&#39;s elite Mo Dao team blocked multiple rounds of attacks from the Food Army. It was expected to replicate the opponent&#39;s coach and Bo Xilin&#39;s victory last year. A successful example in the Battle of Zab River, using cavalry countercharge to crush the enemy&#39;s fighting spirit. It&#39;s a pity that the cavalry troops of the Tang coalition were vassal troops of Geluolu. At this critical moment when the Tang army was about to take the initiative on the battlefield, the Geluolu people, who had a tacit understanding with Dashi, counterattacked and instead cut into the fierce battle with Dashi&#39;s army. The Tang Army&#39;s rear area formed a pincer attack on it, and the main force of the Tang Army fell into a tight encirclement and bitter fighting, suffering all casualties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commander-in-chief Gao Xianzhi was unwilling to fail. He also hoped to use the reserve force to stabilize the position, collect the defeated troops on the front line, and then fight the enemy for a showdown. His lieutenant, Li Siye, a fierce general who had made extraordinary achievements in the battle of Lianyunbao, persuaded him to retreat at the critical moment: The general went deep alone without reinforcements, and the surrounding Hu people and other countries were just followers of the victor, and they would definitely be against us. A group formed a siege. Once our entire army is wiped out, who will go back to defend southern Xinjiang? Although I am a reckless man, I can clearly see that the situation is critical, and the general can no longer be rigid and stubborn! &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Old Book of Tang Dynasty·Li Siye Biography&quot;: A fool may have a chance to gain, but the situation is so dangerous that he cannot glue the pillar)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Li Siye dragged Gao Xianzhi to abandon the main force of the surrounded Tang army and retreat eastward along the Talas Valley.地势渐高，山道渐窄，作为预备队最先调头撤退的拔汗那附庸军把道路堵得严严实实，后面的唐军无法通过，眼看就要被大食追兵赶上。这时李嗣业放下陌刀，抡起大棒向拔汗那友军左右开弓，“人马应手俱毙”，拔汗那军纷纷向左右避让，高仙芝得以逃出生天；而唐军的第三把手、别将段秀实挺身而出，责备上司李嗣业为了自己逃命而杀害友军，“惮敌而奔，非勇也；免己陷众，非仁也”，李嗣业这才羞惭地停止杀戮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是唐军在怛逻斯大败后的惨状。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省的入口拱门&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;怛逻斯战役结束后，两军各自回国，大唐与大食仍以葱岭为界，战略均衡并未发生根本改变。之后的五年里，黑衣大食向大唐先后派出了八批使臣，表明双方仍然维持着密切的外交关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;葛逻禄：临阵倒戈的突厥部族，在怛逻斯之战后与吐蕃结盟，继承了突骑施的角色，成为草原上新一代的突厥征服者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那，葱岭一隅的西域属国，在怛逻斯惨败和杀戮后依然效忠大唐，“事唐最谨”。 “安史之乱”爆发后，拔汗那响应唐肃宗邀请，不远万里发兵援助中原。时至今日，费尔干纳仍是世界丝绸重镇，生丝出产量列全球第三，这便是唐代丝路花雨对这个酷热盆地的千年遗泽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河中诸国，大国博弈下的粟特城邦，大唐在“安史之乱”后退出西域，这些波斯化国家在大食与突厥的影响下又陆续发生了伊斯兰化和突厥化的历史性转变。根据历史学家考证，造纸术早在怛逻斯战役爆发前就已经传播至此，它助力昭武九姓中的安国逐步成为穆斯林世界重要的文化中心，被誉为“伊斯兰支柱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉伊斯兰文化中心的象征：Mir-i-Arab经学院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并波悉林，奴隶出身的战神统帅，在三年后卷入了黑衣大食夺位之争。他支持第二代哈里发打败了对手，却于三个月后被这位哈里发虐杀——诚所谓“飞鸟尽，良弓藏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段秀实，直言极谏的儒将，撤回安西后被遭他斥责过的李嗣业提拔为判官，两年后又辅佐封常清攻克大勃律，在平定“安史之乱”和抗击吐蕃前线也屡立大功，64岁高龄时因反对叛臣朱泚而殉国——文天祥《正气歌》中的“或为击贼笏”说的就是他誓死讨贼的典故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李嗣业，身高两米的猛将，在“安史之乱”中回军中原勤王，曾与中兴名将郭子仪联手，以弱敌强，连战连捷，陆续收复关中平原和东都洛阳，成为积弱唐军中的“救火队员”。大唐乾元二年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元759年）&lt;/span>;，他在作战时中流矢，“出血数升，注地而卒”——每当说到李嗣业，我首先会想起“当嗣业刀者，人马俱碎”的勇武场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省奥特莫克山口，一千二百多年前的“山地之王”没准路经此地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝，胆识超凡但贪功爱财的名将，怛逻斯战役四年后“安史之乱”爆发，高仙芝与封常清受命统率临时纠集的乌合之众抵挡精锐叛军主力，只得依据坚城死守潼关，却因此被唐玄宗下诏双双斩杀。接替他们俩的另一位名将哥舒翰被迫出兵与叛军野战，结果全军覆没，潼关失守，长安沦陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝临死前曾有机会翻盘：当时向玄宗进谗并奉旨到潼关处决高仙芝的太监边令诚率领百余名陌刀手为自己壮胆，却不曾想这些精锐军士齐声高呼：高将军冤枉！ “其声殷地”。高仙芝本可借助于这些忠诚的士兵收捕边令诚，或可迫使玄宗收回成命。但他最终没有这么做，而是望着老战友封常清的尸首慨然长叹，束手赴死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位盛唐名将，最终随盛唐一并化为泡影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:26:40 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>