<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[陷入“以貌取人”困境的普通人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Weight, height, skin color, appearance... not only celebrities in the entertainment industry, but also ordinary people are increasingly falling into In anxiety about appearance. Some people invest a lot of money and energy in medical beauty, and some even suffer from &quot;eating disorders&quot; because of dieting. The reasons include not only the scrutiny of people around you, but also the evaluation standards of society. How to combat such an anxiety? &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张艺谋都没拍成的犯罪片，被他拍出来了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259238]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Watching &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; for the first time , still in Cannes. It was raining lightly in the early morning. Director Wei Shujun thanked everyone for coming to watch the movie before the movie started. He said that it was also raining in the first scene of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/92420c0a65a420316ddf9fdfdb6c6732.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;923&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/92420c0a65a420316ddf9fdfdb6c6732.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255188&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The opening rain scene of the film takes us back to the southern town in the 1990s. The cold weather, dilapidated buildings, dim light, and cramped alleys, the space presented in the film The texture is distant yet familiar. A series of bizarre murder cases lead the pursuers of the truth into the abyss of madness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a shortlisted film in this year&#39;s Cannes &quot;Un Certain Regard&quot; section, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; scored a high score of 3.5 points in the Cannes program&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;. As the opening film of the just-concluded Pingyao International Film Festival, this film once again received high praise from many film critics. &lt;span>;Since the short film &quot;Yanbian Boy&quot; debuted in Cannes in 2018, in just 5 years, every feature film directed by Wei Shujun has been favored by Cannes. Such excellent results are rare among the post-90s generation of directors. Its right. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wei Shujun’s first two works, &quot;The Parting of the Wild Horse&#39;s Mane&quot; and &quot;Stories of Yong&#39;an Town&quot;, have a very obvious personal color, not only in terms of plot, but also in the story. This kind of personal experience narration also includes a preference for meta-film narrative. Cannes&#39; favor is undoubtedly a recognition of Wei Shujun&#39;s creative talent and potential, but these two previous works are still young and immature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/076b56ce199a61d4ff049d4328a9f286.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;725&quot; height=&quot;321&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/076b56ce199a61d4ff049d4328a9f286.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255186 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;Mistake by the River&quot; shows a self-contained temperament, marking Wei Shujun&#39;s maturity in creation. Of course, on the one hand, this is due to the original novels with more humanistic value and interpretation space provided by Yu Hua. On the other hand, it is also the more professional and skilled performance of the creative team under the control of industrialization and commerciality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bdd362b284cc8f585bda60da8f8bef25.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/bdd362b284cc8f585bda60da8f8bef25.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255185 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is a pioneering experimental novella, published in 1988, and is Yu Hua&#39;s early work. Yu Hua mentioned in the interview that Lu Xiaoya and Zhang Yimou both wanted to adapt this work, but neither of them came to fruition, which proves the difficulty of adapting this novel into a movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When describing the creative process of &quot;Alive&quot;, Wang Bin mentioned that the first thing he recommended to Zhang Yimou was &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; by Yu Hua. At that time, &quot;Alive&quot; Not fully published yet. After reading it, Zhang Yimou worried that the characters in &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; were too symbolic. In the process of continuous discussion, Zhang Yimou also constructed an almost brand-new story, with more realistic characters and plots, and obviously more Zhang Yimou&#39;s style - this story has a female as the protagonist. It&#39;s just that this idea went nowhere. Zhang Yimou was later completely attracted by &quot;Alive&quot;, thus creating a classic in Chinese film history. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than thirty years, in the hands of a younger generation of creators, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; has taken on a new glory. Wei Shujun and screenwriter Kang Chunlei&#39;s adaptation has no concerns of the times or historical considerations. Baggage is a bold addition, deletion, disassembly and reconstruction based on the original work. It not only grasps the absurd nature of the original work, but also injects it with an expression that is closer to the current mental state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5fe8b80026b408a31f2ac5ae24f08669.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5fe8b80026b408a31f2ac5ae24f08669.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255190&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The pursuit of the truth in Yu Hua&#39;s original work is the author&#39;s analysis of madness and civilization during the cultural renaissance wave in the late 1980s. The protagonist Ma Zhe was eventually diagnosed as a &quot;madman&quot;. It is an ironic social naming. In the movie version, as Ma Zhe gradually becomes a madman, he encounters individuals being crushed by authority, the uncertainty of memory, and black humorous coincidences in the process of solving crimes. Near the end of the movie, a change of viewpoint in one shot shows that Ma Zhe has finally become a madman, and is even more proactive than Ma Zhe in the novel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In that era in my memory, lunatics were common. Some liked to sing in the yard late at night, and some liked to tease others on the street. In today&#39;s era, we almost no longer see lunatics in public places, but more and more people entertain themselves as &quot;mentally ill.&quot; The different understandings of the symptoms of &quot;madman&quot; in the two eras may correspond to the different spiritual cores displayed by the two generations of creators in their treatment of novels and film texts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9d3a92c4251420384063fe14d67f7c51.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9d3a92c4251420384063fe14d67f7c51.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255189 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Hua said, &quot;Only fools are loyal to the original work.&quot; The movie &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is a smart and successful adaptation. The realistic texture created by Wei Shujun visually highlights the absurdity and the eerie atmosphere that makes people think deeply. The 16mm film shooting gives the film a retro tone, presenting the sense of small town space of that era, with occasional out-of-focus lenses, and even provides a stylistic expression for the theme of uncertainty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The film&#39;s representation of the people and events in the unit of that era, as well as scenes such as the poetry meeting, is by no means a realistic reproduction. The director uses a slightly exaggerated satire, but more subtly conveys the reality of the times that makes people laugh. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ma Zhe, played by Zhu Yilong, also provides a wonderful screen image for this retro realistic texture. In order to interpret this role more accurately, Zhu Yilong went to Nanfeng, the filming location, to experience life in advance. He found inspiration for his appearance from an old photo of Yu Hua, and first gained weight and then lost weight for this role. His experiential performance created an amazing character. A convincing image of Ma Zhe. So far, this role is the biggest screen breakthrough for Zhu Yilong, who is still labeled as a traffic star, and will lay the foundation for his future as a big screen actor. In other words, we see one thing from him: acting skills are more important than traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4d2519bd4e8e9a251834b9bc08856dba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4d2519bd4e8e9a251834b9bc08856dba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255187&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Wei Shujun, who prefers meta-movies, said that &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; is no longer a meta-movie. &lt;/span>;However, in the film, a movie theater that is about to be demolished is used as the working space for handling the case. The gaze and being gazed created by the camera&#39;s perspective, as well as the presentation of the chaos of dreams and reality, all demonstrate the director&#39;s meta-cinematic interest. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Similar to the original work, &quot;The Mistake by the River&quot; has a detective-themed genre shell, but the direction of the plot and the author&#39;s stylized treatment broke the expectations of genre suspense. . Moreover, it also abandons the avant-garde nature of the original work and uses a linear narrative as the main line, but it is by no means in line with the public&#39;s imagination. Therefore, we need to look at the market performance of this movie with caution. But regardless of whether it&#39;s good or bad at the box office, this is a work with a unique temperament. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙一钿：即将到来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259484]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/lAsQWMSOeodnf7QCdK12dexC0WyrUcK0OvPbqZTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/lAsQWMSOeodnf7QCdK12dexC0WyrUcK0OvP bqZTe. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Andrea Rossetti/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the &quot;post-90s&quot; who are active in the contemporary art circle, Sun Yidian is undoubtedly the lucky one who has a good hand. She is the kind of international artist favored by galleries and academic institutions. The creator is also the darling of fashion brands and the collection market. Her works involve painting, installation, performance, and fashion cross-border... In her twenties, not long after leaving the Central American School, she was named &quot;Outstanding Youth Under 30&quot; by Forbes Asia &quot;, and in the past two years, he has won the &quot;Young Artist of the Year&quot; from The Best of Best in 2022 and the &quot;Outstanding Creator of the Year&quot; from the Chinese version of the Wall Street Journal in 2022-2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 will be an intense year for Sun Yidian. She returned to school and studied for a doctorate in literature and art at Tsinghua University. She has continued domestic group exhibitions and overseas exhibitions. In April, she held a solo exhibition in Berlin. Portrait&quot; opens, followed by the solo exhibition &quot;Once Upon a Time&quot; in Paris on October 17th (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Once Upon a Time&quot;&lt;/span>; ). Her iconic plastic dolls come from Western pop culture, but also contain Eastern codes. They have formed a unique accent in the old building of the landmark Place Fontaine in Paris: foreign viewers will smell the familiarity of the illustrations. A subtle touch of exoticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ph.D. supervisor Wang Minan once suggested that she complete her doctoral studies in a dual-thread approach: painting during the day and studying at night. But in fact, it is difficult to operate. &quot;Painting is still very brain-burning. After painting for a whole day, it is really difficult to read academic works at night.&quot; So she divided the time into different intervals: before the exhibition, she would retreat and paint intensively. , and then start the academic mode after all the paintings have been shipped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/IPytwWYqQQjX4FS4Yis8WejWuPCzF83Bh8eRStto.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/IPytwWYqQQjX4FS4Yis8WejWuPCzF83Bh8eRStto.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018, &quot;A twinkle&quot;, Shanghai, BANK Gallery&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Wu Ren Studio in Beijing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September, Wu Hongce In the &quot;Crossing Boundaries - Possibilities and Echoes&quot; exhibition at the Yuz Museum, Sun Yizhen met again with her previous work &quot;Pink Dinosaur with Blue Wings&quot;, which was her work around 2017. The entire &quot;man-made object&quot; &quot;The representative work shortly after the series started, &quot;I have never seen it again after the exhibition.&quot; When I met face to face in the exhibition hall five years later, &quot;it was exactly the same as seeing a long-lost friend or child. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You will recall the scene when you painted it, and even recall every stroke you drew. That moment was 3 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, and when you drew that stroke, the sun happened to shine. The place where you put down the pen, yes, suddenly, that memory was retrieved from your subconscious...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The memories all came back in an instant, and a painting opened the door to the past for her. A wormhole, not only about that painting, but also a whole set of life wrapped up in that painting: At that time, she was still in graduate school, and she shared a studio in Feijia Village with her friends at the time. There was an artificial pond there. In summer, the pond is crowded with lotus leaves and lotus flowers, and people living around it are all engaged in art. The next door neighbor is a dancer and a photographer. They visit each other all day long, go fishing in the pond, and eat big pot rice: stewed turtle, spicy crayfish... …spent many lively nights, like a utopia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is an elegy for collective life, which died out almost simultaneously with the student days. &quot;Now I have no collective life, only work is left.&quot; On the wall of the studio with small sketches, you can see the work Traces of madness: The exhibition schedule is accurate to every day, and is made into a list and posted in a conspicuous place; in an inconspicuous place, a whole row of &quot;45&quot; is densely written in pencil, and many of the &quot;45&quot; have been crossed out. ——This is the way good student Sun Yidian forces herself to focus on painting. She believes that every 45 minutes is a period of concentration. This is how the school&#39;s classes are set up. After every 45 minutes of serious painting, she will She crossed it out and allowed herself a small recess: she once liked using highly saturated fluorescent colors, which overloaded her eyes after long hours of homework and staring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BaVQHStk7Nt3jSUleSOHrwNw0XOXUbTuUiNWbfRY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BaVQHStk7Nt3jSUleSOHrwNw0XOXUbTuUiNWbfRY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255434&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Crossing Boundaries: Possibilities and Echoes&quot; exhibition view, Yuz Museum, Shanghai, 2023&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Alessandro Wang, Yuz Museum/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Sun Yidian’s fifth studio in Beijing, and it is also the one she considers “the most luxurious”. The so-called luxury means that it has heating and air conditioning, and has a high roof, ceiling windows, which bring in stable natural light, and large-open doors to facilitate the transportation of large-scale works. The second and third floors are storage rooms and bedrooms. There is a shelf large enough to store her past works, and a bed where she can lie down when she stays up late to paint - this is all an easel artist desires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other studios before can only be described as crude and displaced. She would count them on her fingers: the first studio was in Ark Court, a residential building next to Central Academy of Fine Arts. The space and light were cramped, and it was impossible to display large paintings. The size of the painting was slightly larger, and the relationship between colors was inconsistent. The depth is just not right. The second one was in Feijia Village. It was a happy time, but it was demolished and a group of artists were driven away as if they were being expelled. The third studio was near the turkey factory. One summer there was a sudden flood and most of her paintings were soaked. So she fled there and moved to the mainland. The fourth studio has no heating in winter and no air conditioning in summer. She spent three winters in this ice cave, painting with her feet on a small electric carpet. Her hands became cold and stiff after a while, so she could only put them under her buttocks to warm them up before continuing to paint. Her mother came to see her from Wenzhou and felt the extremely cold weather that had never been seen in the south. At night, the surroundings of the studio were pitch black and there were no street lights. She couldn&#39;t help shouting: Daughter! What kind of sin have you suffered here? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/XgzliM17Uhji4QMm2nlJC71KUgC9DGMrnP5WQ8VH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;738&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/XgzliM17Uhji4QMm2nlJC71KUgC9DGMrnP5WQ8VH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Once upon a time&quot; Acrylic on canvas, 205cmx158cm, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A painting can be painted this way, or it can be painted that way&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mother He was probably the first person to provide artistic support to Sun Yidian. When she was a child, her parents enrolled her in many interest classes. She was the child who cried when she saw she was about to play the piano, but she was very active in painting. She started studying painting at the age of 4. When she was in elementary school, her parents let her attend Wenzhou Youth Art School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other provinces in China, this kind of professional art school for primary school students is extremely rare, which corresponds to the strong demand for folk art education in the southeastern coast. These primary school students are cultivated by an almost omnipotent art concept. They have to learn Chinese painting as well as Western painting. Sketching, coloring, and sketching are all necessary basic skills. They have to go to the countryside to sketch, and they have to hand in calligraphy homework every week. &quot;Our primary school has actually trained many people. For example, the Asian Games torch was designed by our seniors, including architects and artists currently active in Zhejiang. If you ask, many of them came from this primary school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the art circle, it is very strange to praise a person with &quot;top student&quot;, but Sun Yidian has indeed been a top student all the way. Her elementary school does not relax its requirements for cultural courses just because it majors in art. Many students will later go to ordinary middle schools and comprehensive universities, and not all of them may be bent on becoming art students. Sun Yidian was admitted to Wenzhou Middle School, the best local high school, but at the same time, she also received admission notices from the National High School Affiliated to the National Academy of Arts and the Central American High School Affiliated to the Art Examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tlKnhoKUFJ4monMgkf7h5D6BTlFtFh8FzkurTiM0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;732&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tlKnhoKUFJ4monMgkf7h5D6BTlFtFh8FzkurTiM0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Simple Shed&quot; watercolor on paper, 25.3cmx19.1cm, 2009&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She chose the High School Affiliated to Central Academy of Fine Arts because she could go to Beijing and legitimately &quot;leave&quot; Parents stay away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Sun Yidian, the High School Affiliated to Central Academy of Fine Arts is a free and magical place. She seemed to be suddenly opened up to a whole new world and new senses to match it. She is still amazed that she watched so many niche movies and so many esoteric books that were inappropriate for her age when she was in the attached middle school. &quot;There are many big boring movies that I can&#39;t stand now, but I actually watched them wholeheartedly at that time. Many of them In fact, I only know a little about philosophy books, so I just read them hard to pretend to be cool. People around me don’t listen to pop music. They all listen to very literary and niche things to show that they are different.” In the attached middle school, not being mainstream is a kind of mainstream. These hard-to-eat nutrients have unknowingly become part of her background. “The biggest inspiration for my art is that I am willing to try anything and be interested in everything. After a person is suddenly opened up at that age, he realizes , It turns out that a painting can be done this way or that way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She still keeps a collection of sketches from when she was in the attached middle school. At that time, she had to submit a large number of sketches every week, and the teacher would write on the handed-in homework. The stamp indicates that it has been read, preventing students from submitting previous works for submission. In order to catch up on the huge amount of homework, they would go to Beijing Railway Station to stay up all night and paint the passengers who stayed at the station overnight. Foreigners from all over the world come in all shapes and sizes, and they don&#39;t move even after falling asleep due to fatigue. They are ready-made models at your fingertips. When she returned home during the summer vacation, while her mother was taking a bath, she was doing sketches of human figures. Her mother calmly let her do the painting without any hesitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from the High School Affiliated to the Central Academy of Fine Arts, she was recommended to the Central Academy of Fine Arts. Her college entrance examination scores in cultural subjects were surprisingly high among art students. After graduating from Central America, he was directly recommended to graduate school at Central America. Sun Yidian said that she is the kind of person with strong self-motivation, and her academic career is just &quot;going with the flow&quot;. It was also out of self-consciousness that after working as an artist for several years, she went to Tsinghua University to study for a Ph.D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BGK6BCcuRR8Ks5wz3wSVfM4ulvO5VlLwx2jScva5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BGK6BCcuRR8Ks5wz3wSVfM4ulvO5VlLwx2jScva5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ken&quot; acrylic on wood, 45.5cmx38cm, 2019&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Natural objects and man-made objects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian is well-known and has the best market performance The series is &quot;artificial objects&quot;, and most of the pictures are inflatable or plastic toys, but she also has a secret &quot;natural objects&quot; series, which she started to create when she was 16 years old, a series oriented &quot;from the deep&quot;, including flowers and fruits. , mountains, rivers, and trees have all become the objects of her gaze and representation. But the &quot;natural objects&quot; have never been exhibited. Sun Yidian hangs them on the wall of his studio, like a private archive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Man-made objects&quot; are dazzling floats above the water, and &quot;natural objects&quot; are like anchors underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people came to my studio and liked the &#39;Natural Objects&#39; series. Last time a sister came over and said that this group of small paintings made her cry.&quot; She incorporated a lot of elements into this series. For media experiments, I like to use some children’s handmade materials, such as a kind of baby foam beads called “pearl mud”, which can be used for shaping and is also a common raw material in toy factories. Later, I discovered a Japanese paper pulp clay that has excellent modeling power and durability, and can create a spatial effect similar to a bas-relief on the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/RSyN0FWPkp9junVXBGZKFsIqxs7A2MxJSf78DO2v.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;639&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/RSyN0FWPkp9junVXBGZKFsIqxs7A2MxJSf78DO2v.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Let Me Hug&quot; Acrylic on canvas, 200cmx133cm, 2015&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Artificial Objects&quot; series made her famous in one fell swoop. The smooth, plump, grotesque and falsely sweet toys she draws have won her a steady stream of attention and collectors, and their prices have skyrocketed. As a child in Wenzhou, her childhood memories are all kinds of man-made objects. &quot;When I was a kid, when we said we were going to play at a classmate&#39;s house, what we actually meant was: go play in your family&#39;s factory.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost every household has a factory, including a shoe factory. , glasses factory, plastic products factory, lighter factory... Occasionally there are toy factories. There are not many toy factories, but the visual impact on a child is huge. These small commodity factories all retain a simple production layout. The factory building often has several bedrooms attached. The home is also the same as the factory. After the reform and opening up, materials, and the production brought about by materials, sprouted up everywhere in Wenzhou like bamboo shoots after a rain. What’s interesting is that her international collectors are also very sympathetic to these things she painted. They told Sun Yidian: The era when the artificial objects you painted suddenly exploded in abundance, maybe the 1990s in China. But in Europe and the United States, it was our 1960s. It is precisely because of this that they feel the same complex flavor of nostalgia and reflection in Sun Yidian&#39;s paintings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of commonality is not uncommon in Sun Yidian’s paintings, like a hidden cultural code. She paints huge idols. Their appearance and facial features are common in Western pop culture. However, the curved eyebrows and single eyelids come from traditional Chinese painting. The angle of the lips, which seems to be smiling but not smiling, is her classic image based on Buddhist sculptures. drawn. This image appears on the exhibition wall, facing the viewer in a overlooking manner. Regardless of whether the viewer is an Easterner or a Westerner, they will be slightly stunned and realize that something seems wrong in a sense of déjà vu. The &quot;Porcelain Mother&quot; she painted is a small white porcelain statue with hands clasped together, standing silently among the roots of the trees. This is a common porcelain Madonna ornament in Western families, but strangely, it also Much like the Dehua white porcelain Guanyin worshiped in Chinese households. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian said that in her hometown, the belief system is complex. When she was a child, her family worshiped Buddha and worshiped Guanyin all year round. However, when she came to her uncle&#39;s house, he believed in Catholicism and kept a statue of the Virgin Mary in his home. As a child, she often felt confused. In her eyes, there was no essential difference between the kind and compassionate female faces. The localization of handicrafts has deepened this aesthetic mutual reference. A priest often came and went from her uncle&#39;s house. Apart from his detached and indifferent expression, she could not see any difference between the priest and ordinary neighbors. The same is true for local churches, which are European in form but with a strong Chinese decoration style. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is keen to examine these common clues in different cultures out of curiosity about images. She painted Medusa and looked through Caravaggio and other classic paintings in the album. The snakes on Medusa&#39;s head were all live snakes. The artist had to focus on painting the twisting and entangled violence, lifelike, that is culture. Classic output to her symbols. In her private memory, Medusa only saw the logo on her mother&#39;s Versace bag when she was a child. She was surprised at that time. Why use the head of a strange woman as a label? In order to draw her own Medusa, she bought a bunch of rubber and plastic coiled snakes online as a reference. Their ferocity and beauty were just a bluff - &quot;I just wanted to draw them all as fake snakes, realistic fake ones.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her workbench is filled with these artificial toys, which have also become the prototypes in her paintings: original Barbie, pirated Barbie, Ken with his head ripped off, naked Ken... The first time she drew Ken with only a head, she shocked everyone and triggered a big discussion including hot words such as &quot;feminism&quot;, &quot;female revenge&quot;, &quot;consumer men&quot;, and &quot;female reverse gaze&quot;, but she Frankly speaking, I painted my friend as Ken just for visual reasons, which is like playing house on the canvas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/88ewe2kyK2hNwTUJjLor3sygbg00B5xHTLl3i9k8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;956&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/88ewe2kyK2hNwTUJjLor3sygbg00B5xHTLl3i9k8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Evening&quot; wood board composite material, 20cmx20cm, 2016&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The world is seven centimeters shorter&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian has always been interested in gender issues All are there. When she was in college, she asked acquaintances in her hometown to let her go to the obstetrics and gynecology hospital to observe women giving birth. It was the largest obstetrics and gynecology hospital in Wenzhou and the place where she was born. She saw groups of women rolling and moaning on the delivery bed. Their faces were blurred, and all their female characteristics were hidden. What mattered was the huge bulge in the middle of the body and the birth canal that was about to burst, as if that was their only thing at the moment. Biological attributes, their common identity and destiny. She turned this feeling into a series of works, titled &quot;Coming Soon.&quot; That year, she was 22 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;coming&quot; may be new life, or the adult life she is about to enter. But for Sun Yidian, &quot;coming soon&quot; is more like a moment in nature, &quot;In my hometown, there are many thunderstorms in the south, the kind of heavy rainstorms that suddenly fall, and the sky is so dark that the day seems like night, The raindrops were huge, pouring, and then there was lightning and thunder. I have many such memories when I was a child. I stood under the window of my house and looked at the heavy rain outside. The sky suddenly lightened up, and then there was a burst of thunder from the distance. . My &#39;coming soon&#39; is the moment when the lightning has flashed and the thunder has not yet come. I am nervous and scared, but I am also looking forward to that moment coming.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She did not explain her scene, no matter how It’s up to the viewers to draw their own interpretations, whether it’s gender issues, pop culture issues, material issues, consumerism issues... She is at ease with everything. Just like her painting &quot;Porcelain Mother&quot;, those who believe in Guanyin see Guanyin and the Mother of God. What the viewer sees is the Virgin. She believes that any viewing will first reflect the viewer’s cultural memory and information reserve, rather than the creator’s intention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As her doctoral thesis was about to be started, Wang Minan suggested that she write about consumerism. The implication was that it was related to the topic she drew, and it would be easier for her to gain insights when writing. She also thought it was reasonable. She is just worried that her logical ability is not strong - the academic construction of writing a paper and the picture composition that she is so familiar with are completely different things. Teacher Wang sometimes asks her from the perspective of &quot;consumption&quot;: I heard that one of your paintings has sold for millions? She was so frightened that she only waved her hands: Teacher, teacher, let’s never talk about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UfQY7vrtFQzxgrxEuiFVap805CGeMwvUOhSpJIQB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UfQY7vrtFQzxgrxEuiFVap805CGeMwvUOhSpJIQB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Porcelain Mother&quot; Acrylic on wood, 54cm x 45cm, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Ailing said that you must become famous as early as possible. Sun Yidian agreed with both hands, but her reasons were different from Zhang Ailing. What she worries about is not that success comes too late and the taste is not sweet enough, but she believes that becoming famous at a young age can give people a valuable sense of relaxation and allow them to do art more calmly and comfortably. Those artists who have been tortured by fate for too long and have struggled to overcome all kinds of struggles are sometimes inevitably distorted by the desire for success and the pressure of survival, leading to deformed movements and making incredible choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Only the income from selling paintings in my first exhibition was meaningful to me, because it meant that I could support myself and become an independent artist. Before that, I had always followed My parents were vaccinated and asked to be mentally prepared that I might not have a job after graduation and would have to go home to grow old. That money gave me great freedom. The happiness from money ended here. After that, I sold Any high price offered is just a number to me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She naturally realized that as long as the female artists of her generation made some progress in their careers, they would inevitably work for all women. speak out. &quot;When a female artist becomes famous at a young age, it is easy for others to say: Is it because of your appearance? Is there someone behind you who is helping you raise the price?&quot; Is it impossible for women to achieve success based on their strength alone? Is it hard to acknowledge the excellence of women? Sun Yidian&#39;s way of fighting back is to use more comprehensive self-strength to shut them up. This is the self-confidence she built up as a top student from childhood to college, and it is also one of the motivations for her to return to school to study for a Ph.D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the many sketches nailed to the wall of her studio, there are several sketches of powerful high-heeled shoes. The toes of the scarlet high-heeled shoes are joined together and formed into two separate heels. The shape of the female pelvis. Sun Yizhen always remembers a poem by a Taiwanese male poet that he read when he was a girl. He wrote about the feelings of girls when they wear high heels - &quot;The world is seven centimeters shorter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yidian is 1.72 meters tall. He wears 7cm artificial high heels and is taller than many men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a world seven centimeters shorter, she continued to move forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the artist, BANK Gallery and Galerie Schipper Berlin/Paris/Seoul, Yuz Museum)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“潇湘”作为地名传进日本，竟然是因为一位禅宗大画家的加持？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Not long ago, I had a gathering with two old friends. During the dinner, I accidentally talked about the misfortune of Nie Er, the composer of &quot;March of the Volunteers&quot; The place of drowning - the coast of Shonan in Fujisawa Prefecture, Japan. Wang Zhongyi, the editor-in-chief of &quot;People&#39;s China&quot; magazine, asked me about the relationship between Shonan and Naito Hunan and Hunan Province. I knew what was going on but didn&#39;t know why. I was questioned on the spot. So, after returning home and doing some homework, I came up with this fake &quot;place name test&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iAnaBLpu5DQSiWI3mbKe9wYDfzszNsGMp2b7u9wI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;891&quot; height= &quot;1185&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iAnaBLpu5DQSiWI3mbKe9wYDfzszNsGMp2b7u9wI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese Sinologist Naito Konan (1866-1934). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about the latter first. The relationship between Naito Hunan and Hunan Province is simple, so simple that there is no half-cent relationship. Naito&#39;s halo as a sinologist is so dazzling that when Chinese people talk about this legendary figure, they often make associations: the &quot;Hunan&quot; in Naito&#39;s name must have been &quot;taken&quot; from Hunan Province, and it is intentionally or unintentionally reminiscent of When it comes to the &quot;theory of cultural center movement&quot; and the &quot;theory of changes in the Tang and Song Dynasties&quot;, it seems that if you don&#39;t even &quot;roll&quot; your name, you can&#39;t be called a great scholar. However, Japanese intellectuals are mostly limited by the concept of regionalism and take it for granted. Since he is a leader of the Kyoto School, the name &quot;Hunan&quot; must come from Hunan City in Shiga Prefecture adjacent to Kyoto Prefecture, but this lake is not Dongting Lake, but Lake Biwa. In fact, neither of these two arguments is correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Naito Hunan&#39;s name is Tiger Jiro, whose courtesy name is Bingqing and whose nickname is Hunan. 1866年，生于陆奥国马毛内村（今秋田县鹿角市十和田马毛内）。鹿角位于秋田县的最北端，与青森县之间隔着界湖“十和田湖”，“湖南”即十和田湖的南边之意。十和田湖是由十和田火山喷发而形成的二重式火山湖，风光旖旎，是东北地方的名湖，作为特别名胜列入“国家文化财”。在东京都中心的国会议事堂，环绕中央大厅四周的墙上，悬挂着描绘日本列岛四季风景的巨幅油画。其中，夏季的作品即田中仪一所绘《十和田湖与奥入濑》。如此，因了内藤湖南和京都学派的影响力，原本八竿子打不着的湖南省硬是被扯出关联，连全无干系的滋贺县湖南市也被附会了与内藤的某种连结，而内藤生长的故土十和田湖，却偏偏不被世人提起了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Wvjin72u69Lnqd8pGj5ChHbXG2N2MlN21dU2dMKS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;580&quot; height=&quot;403&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Wvjin72u69Lnqd8pGj5ChHbXG2N2MlN21dU2dMKS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;日本国会议事堂中央大厅中所悬挂的油画《十和田湖与奥入濑》。奥入濑是从十和田湖流出的一条河。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再聊回前者。关于湘南与湖南省的关联，其实并无定说。 《广辞苑》（第五版）对“湘南”的释义虽有所指涉，但语焉不详：①位于中国湖南省、注入洞庭湖的湘江以南一带风景名胜地的称谓。 ②将古相模国南部的“相南”，附会①而写成“湘南”，作为对相模湾沿岸地带的称谓。那一带包括叶山、逗子、镰仓、茅崎等区域，夏季多海水浴场，是京滨的避暑地，冬季则比较温暖。作为住宅用地，被广泛开发。如“湘南电车”，系连结东京和（静冈县）沼津的中距离旧国铁的总称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过这条释义，我们了解到，没有中国的湖南，便没有日本的湘南。接下来的一个问题：这种空间上的“链接”到底是何时以及如何发生的？在日本，“湘南”的表述最早见于平安时代中期的辞书《倭名类聚抄》（简称《和名抄》或《倭名抄》），语源是长沙国湘南县。据《资治通鉴大辞典》（吉林人民出版社，1994）的解释：湘南县为“西汉置，治所在今湖南湘潭市西南。东汉改为湘南侯国。三国吴复为湘南县。南朝齐废”。不过，《倭名抄》中的“湘南”，仍是单纯的中国古地名，并不等于今天日本的“湘南”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各种证据表明，湘南真正的“越境”，与禅宗有关。葛兆光先生在《中国禅思想史》中谈到，南方禅学在地理上分两支，其中的第二支，便是“以荆州、衡岳为中心的禅师集团”：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如荆州天皇寺的法懔、法忍，长沙寺的法京、智远，襄阳景空寺的法聪，庐山法充等。当然，最重要的是先在光州大苏山，后至衡岳，开后来天台一脉的慧思（515—577）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而天台宗，正是对日本佛教、禅宗产生了决定性影响的教派。公元804年，最澄禅师作为遣唐使入唐学法，翌年回国后，在比叡山（别称天台山）的延历寺传法，继而创立了日本天台宗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋末元初的画僧牧谿法常（法常是法号，生卒年不详），少时曾在名僧无准法师门下修禅，后成为西湖六通寺的开山祖师。其画作于镰仓时代末期（14世纪），随中日禅师的交流，批量流入日本，顷刻受到上流阶层的狂热追捧。那种用水墨晕章和大量余白来表现乾坤幽趣的技法，高超圆熟，是日人眼中文人对自然山川之理想国“憧憬的象征”（日本学者山下裕二语），也深刻影响了日本的南画。桃山时代日本画宗师长谷川等伯、表屋宗达等人，都曾向牧谿画作中寻求水墨画技法的根本；狩野派艺术中也有很多临摹牧谿的作品。牧谿的画，是日本公卿、大名和富商争相收藏的对象，是国宝中的国宝。如室町幕府足利家族所藏绘画珍品的记录《御物御画目录》中，全部280件庋藏中，牧谿作品占三成，多达103件。在14世纪中期的日本文献中，如只写“和尚”的话，便是对牧谿的尊称。牧谿的画在中国几近绝迹（仅故宫博物院和台北故宫博物院各藏一件），据说日本现存134幅，均藏于内阁府文化厅和全国一流美术馆的珍品库中。而牧谿作品的“天花板”，公认是《潇湘八景图》。全八卷中七卷在日本，余下的一卷《山市晴岚》，至今所在不明，日本保有摹本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Cpej7mByBiUAd7Aqq2Ejiw6c3nmf2eEu7a3P27DL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;3197&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Cpej7mByBiUAd7Aqq2Ejiw6c3nmf2eEu7a3P27DL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;牧谿法常《潇湘八景图》之《渔村夕照》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓“潇湘”，《辞海》的释义为：①湘江的别称，因湘江水清深得名。 《山海经·中山经》：“交潇湘之渊。”《湘中记》：“湘川清照五六丈，是纳潇湘之名矣。”又或专指湘江中游与潇水会合后一段，即“三湘”之一。 ②泛指湖南地区。郑谷《淮上与友别》诗：“数声风笛离亭晚，君向潇湘我向秦。”③古镇名。五代时置，在今湖南永州市西北。因当潇湘二水合流处得名；亦称潇湘关或湘口关。据此而顾名思义，“潇湘八景”即湘江并入了潇水后，一路向北的湘江沿岸至洞庭湖一带的八处佳胜。北宋以降，代有画家以之为题创作，寄情山水，“潇湘八景”几成一种艺术范式。著名者有宋迪作同名画卷，后被沈括写入《梦溪笔谈》，分别为远浦帆归、平沙落雁、烟寺晚钟、山市晴岚、江天暮雪、洞庭秋月、渔村夕照、潇湘夜语——“八景”的名目，自此“出圈”。不过，与宋迪等人的作品相比，日人显然独钟牧谿。至于个中缘由，哲学家韩炳哲认为：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;牧谿受禅宗启发创作的《潇湘八景图》，也是“空”之图景，笔墨简淡含蓄，一片空无，意境幽玄，寥寥数景隐没于无限疏阔的余白中，谨慎的笔法让物象浮动在实与虚、黑与白之间，不道尽其中意蕴。物象相融相依，彼此映照，而非驱离、分割彼此。空仿佛成了友善的中介。水住，山流，天地合。空寂并未将画中静物湮没，而是反衬出静物之雅。 （《禅宗哲学》，第35页）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如此，从镰仓时代到江户时代，从足利将军家族（足利义满、义政）到织田信长、丰臣秀吉，从德川将军家族（德川家康、吉宗）到松平不昧、村田珠光，牧谿的《潇湘八景图》在这些人物之间流转，其价值已不能用金钱来估评。日人实在是太爱“潇湘八景”了，恨不得移景于日本。果然，后来日人在武藏国仓城郡六浦庄村（今京滨急行电铁的金泽八景站）一带，“发现”了“金泽八景”——整个是“潇湘八景”的“箱庭”版。妙就妙在每处佳胜，竟与潇湘的原风景一一对应，且被歌川广重搬上了浮世绘，计有《乙舻帆归》《平潟落雁》《称名晚钟》《洲崎晴岚》《内川暮雪》《濑户秋月》《野岛夕照》和《小泉夜语》，共八幅。元禄7年（1694），从大明亡命东瀛的东皋心越禅师为“金泽八景”各题汉诗一首，有了中国大儒的七言绝句背书，金泽俨然潇湘矣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据说江户时代初期，泽庵和尚把江之岛一带开始称为“湘南”。同一时期，室町时代从中国移居日本的中国人后代、小田原的祛痰药商崇雪，在大矶的鴫立庵建一石碑，碑上刻“著尽湘南清绝地”七字。此碑今犹在，被视为湘南地名的起始。而近代之前，汉学始终是日本的显学，故出于某种文人趣味也好，或说附庸风雅也好，用“湘南”作雅号的禅僧、诗人所在多有，如禅僧湘南淙、诗人大久保湘南等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湘南电车通车后，被称为“湘南”的区域进一步扩大，连三浦半岛都被归入其区划。明治29年（1896）5月，德富苏峰为双亲在逗子海滨购置一栋别墅，然后把照料二老的任务交给弟弟德富芦花，自己便踏上了周游世界之旅。彼时，芦花正身心交瘁，对放浪生活感到厌倦，决定暂去父母的别墅隐居，同时考虑未来的进路。他在致胞兄的信中写道：“东京的空气，对我来说太冷了。我想在湘南住些日子。”彼时的湘南，已成为上流人士的住宅区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是差不多同一时期，夏目漱石和铃木大拙各自在位于北镰仓的圆觉寺跟随禅师释宗演参禅。漱石参禅是为自我疗愈，而大拙则为了学法。时空交错，二人的目的既不相同，也未相遇。从镰仓幕府时代起，因幕府统治者得宗家族的庇护，禅宗得以在此地生息、发育，历经五个世纪的发展，及至漱石和大拙禅修时，已蔚为大观，镰仓这座古刹林立、禅意十足的古城，也成了如假包换的禅宗“麦加”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就这样，从牧谿法常的《潇湘八景图》到“金泽八景”，从泽庵和尚到亡命东渡的中国禅师，可以说，正是因了禅宗的加持，这个以江之岛为中心、沿相模湾向东西延展的狭长的海岸地带，才从古地名的“相南”变成了今天世人眼中的“湘南”，自带一种迥然不同于其他地域的浪漫风情。譬如，住在首都圈的人，周末开一辆挂“湘南”车牌的车，跑在134号国道上，哪怕只是一台再普通不过的轻型机动车，也不失为一件拉风的事，车牌的“含金量”甚至碾压东京都内高级住宅区“品川”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（原题“何处是湘南”，现标题为编者所拟）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[学术期刊为何能收那么贵的版面费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259320]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，湖北省一会计类期刊《财会通讯》发布通知称，对养育三孩家庭的作者免收版面费。这本来是一个非常小众的学术期刊，通知本身能够触达的人群也比较少，但还是迅速在网上引起了热议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;引起热议的原因，可以归结为这么几个方面：首先是一篇文章六七千元的版面费，价格并不便宜；其次是这个期刊的定位，由湖北省会计学会主办，湖北省社科联主管，收取高价版面费给人感觉更像是一种商业行为；最后才是这个优惠措施，调子起得很高，实际上受益人群可能寥寥无几，几乎可以忽略不计，给人感觉这更像是一个促销活动。几个因素叠加，成为热点也就不奇怪了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然我一直知道在学术期刊发论文要收版面费，但是一篇文章收费这么高，多少还是有点意外。从其官网上看，最新一期目录上有31篇文章，这个期刊是半月刊，就按每篇文章6000的版面费来计算，他们每月的收入就可以达到372000元，一年就是4464000元。一份期刊近500万的年收入，这妥妥的是一门好生意啊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中很重要的一个原因是，最近几十年全球都在“高等教育大跃进”，以及背后伴随的“论文通胀”。中国因为人口基数大，经济发展速度快，这方面的问题尤其突出。只不过参与其中的大都是“文化人”，或多或少都是其中的“受益者”，即便是看到了问题所在，也不会轻易去戳破这层窗户纸。毕竟看破不说破，也是一种广为人知的生存智慧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学历通胀背后，是本科生、研究生、博士生的扩招。而各大高校对论文数量的看重，基本上都会要求研究生毕业之前发表相应数量的论文，通常越好的学校对论文层次的要求也就越高。每年都会有学生因为没有完成论文的发表而申请推迟毕业，论文发表对研究群体来说就是一种刚需。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，本科、研究生的扩招，必然伴随着教师数量的扩招。而在整个教育系统，都有着对发表论文数量考核的传统。老师职称晋升、申请科研项目或者申请各种科研基金，都有必须发表论文的硬性规定。而且不仅是大学里边对论文有要求，就是中小学现在也有要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不光是教育系统，还有的比如医院，甚至一些不是科研机构的单位，也会把发表论文数量作为是否晋升的一个重要考察指标。其中一个考量，大概是因为这样看上去显得很公平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个考量则是某种意义的“学术崇拜”，或者说“科学崇拜”，就好像发表论文就是为科学学术作出了贡献。实际上长期以来，我们很多地方和高校都在奉行和宣传“唯专利和论文数量论”，论文和专利数量一直都是他们宣传的重点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年8月初，日本文部科学省的研究所发布一份报告。报告显示，中国论文总数占全球份额的24.6%，比第2位的美国高出8.5个百分点。而在衡量论文质量的引用次数上，中国“受关注论文”和“顶级论文”的全球占比分别为28.9%和29.3%，也都是世界第一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们倒是不必妄自菲薄，把这种数据排名看得一文不值。客观地看，一方面这个数据说明，中国的科研学术影响力正在逐步扩大，这是好事。但另一方面，我们也要看到，这种数量和现实之间的反差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们常说“量变引起质变”，但是当论文和专利数量被错误的激励制度扭曲的时候，量变未必能够导向高质量的质变。相反，更可能会导致低层次、低水平的重复，还会产生一些奇葩的“学术研究”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如前几年某学术期刊刊登了《通过靶向肠道菌群调控人体的物质需求欲望有望提高廉政文化建设效率》。这类文章还有很多，完全是不加掩饰地搞“伪学术”，完全是为了凑数去的。在不当的激励制度下，论文发表成为了很多人的刚需，而且是一个非常大的“市场”。需求旺盛，而供给有限，刊物就那么多，版面就那么多，所以基本上形成了一个“卖方市场”，版面费要高价也就不奇怪了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高价暴利之下，一定会有更多的人参与其中，于是这就形成了一条“论文产业链”。有写手、有中介，有人负责出钱、有人负责刊发，各种渠道，你只要出钱基本上都能找到。当然，这个“市场”并不是完全自发的，而是畸形的激励制度催生的。而且这种畸形之下，很有可能还会滋生腐败。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，湖南省社会科学院《求索》杂志社原主编乌东峰因严重违纪问题被立案审查。问题正是出在版面费，后来经法院认定乌东峰收取的论文“版面费”共近千万元。在《求索》杂志发表一篇论文的“版面费”最高达到5万余元，还有中介机构专门负责勾兑这些事。当时这个案件引起了学术界很大震动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了这类腐败案件和问题外，“论文产业”还有个问题，那就是“虹吸效应”。这条“产业链”上的人本来是应该去创造财富了，结果却沦为“论文掮客”，帮助别人发表毫无价值的文章来获利。而有的版面费是公费报销的，除却那些真正有价值的文章，恐怕大多数垃圾文章，本质上都是很多人在“合谋分赃”，其中某些人恐怕就是在瓜分纳税人的钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想要改变现状，恐怕不是头疼医头的问题。不是要问为什么版面费这么高，而是要问，为什么那么多没有价值的期刊和文章，竟然还能活得那么滋润。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[那些在互联网买“情绪”的年轻人，拜托醒醒吧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259422]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/a7605c3b1df672a8ea3cc792da571f45.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;957&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/a7605c3b1df672a8ea3cc792da571f45.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不少人可能听过“爱情买卖”的旋律，却不知道如今也有了“情绪买卖”这门生意。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“情感树洞”“好运喷雾”“骂醒恋爱脑”“虚拟蚊子”“爱因斯坦的脑子”……现在，不少年轻人热衷于在网上购买情绪类产品，只要花费几块钱就能购买的情绪产品也越来越多。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比如情绪崩溃时，网购一份聊天服务，向陌生人倾诉一下，吐槽几句，负面情绪仿佛就释放了出去；下单一份“虚拟蚊子”，会有卖家角色扮演不定时“嗡嗡嗡”地来吵你；分手后买一份“骂醒恋爱脑”，便会有陌生人来担任“聊天搭子”，对你晓之以理、动之以情……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;年轻人为什么热衷于在互联网上买情绪？购买情绪，就真的能够提供情绪价值了？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;年轻人“emo”了&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;购买情绪背后，是很多年轻人的情绪遇到了一些“问题”，用时下的流行词来说，就是“emo”了。emo曾入选2021年的年度网络词汇，仅仅在这一年里，哔哩哔哩用户就发送了330万次“emo”弹幕。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“emo”来自英文单词“emotion”，这是情感、情绪的意思。在20世纪90年代，欧美流行音乐领域里出现了“emotional hardcore”，这是一种情感细腻、忧郁感伤的摇滚音乐。在简化为“emo”后，emo也就有了冲动、敏感、忧郁等色彩。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如今作为流行词汇的emo，延续的正是这一内核与情感色彩，代表了年轻人一种颓废、沮丧、无语、纳闷的心情。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;emo成为流行词汇，不仅仅是因为“语言经济学”原则——这个短小的词汇很精准地概括了年轻人的心态，也不仅仅是流行词汇传播中的“羊群效应”——你用他用于是我也用，还在于，emo确实是一种普遍性的时代情绪。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;emo是以前流行的“佛系”“丧”“躺平”等流行词汇的新变体，它背后关联着时代的一些新变化。比如后疫情时代，全球经济恢复缓慢，经济下行周期，年轻人的工作压力更大了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“内卷”之下很多人感到非常疲惫；忙碌的都市生活中，很多年轻人没有太多的时间去社交，下班了就待在出租屋里，成为“空巢青年”的他们难免感到孤独寂寞冷……除了这些普遍性的困境外，年轻人在各自的人生中也有不同的、具体的困惑，多多少少影响着年轻人的情绪。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;总之，年轻人万事皆可emo。找不到工作，emo了；工作压力大，emo了；跟对象闹矛盾了，emo了；单身没对象，emo了；考试没准备，emo了；方案被甲方毙掉，emo了……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;跟丧、躺平等词汇相比，emo带有一丝苦中作乐的自嘲意味，它没有那么消极悲观，而是在吐槽“我真是emo”了之后，仍然会收拾好生活的烂摊子，继续前行。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“情绪价值”的抚慰&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;emo之后，仍然要拥抱生活。所以，年轻人会努力地让自己的情绪更快地平复，让自己的情绪需求得到满足，他们会寻求“情绪价值”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那么，什么是情绪价值？简单地说，情绪价值=积极情绪（收益）-消极情绪（成本）。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一件东西、一个人是否拥有情绪价值，就在于TA能够给人带来正向的情绪力量，比如让人感到快乐、安心、平静、温暖、治愈……换言之，情绪价值是一种能够给我们的情绪带来正向影响的能力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;它可以是陪伴，是分享，是倾听，是鼓励……最终都变成对emo情绪的一种抚慰。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;社交媒体上，年轻人也经常使用一些与情绪价值密切相关的词汇，比如“情绪稳定”，这成为很多年轻人挑选伴侣的第一标准。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一个情绪稳定的伴侣，遇到事情总能平静沉稳处理，不失控，不甩锅，不相互责怪，而是努力去解决问题。伴侣情绪稳定，自然也就能给人带来强大的情绪价值——你会被一种安全感包裹，不论世界如何慌乱，都有人与你携手走过。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这样的背景下，我们就能够理解为什么很多年轻人在互联网上购买情绪了，他们实质上购买的是“情绪价值”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如果一个人学习没有动力，就加入“虚拟自习室”，大家一起学习更有氛围；如果想要一种好运的幻觉，就购买“好运锦鲤”；如果想要摆脱孤独，获得一种陪伴感，可以下单一份“虚拟蚊子”，会有卖家角色扮演蚊子，不定时“嗡嗡嗡”地来“吵”你；分手后买一份“骂醒恋爱脑”，与其说是真的骂你，毋宁说是陪伴你、跟你说话、听你倾诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/66f81e258e4ce4cd84843e25edeb22f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/66f81e258e4ce4cd84843e25edeb22f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo / 图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不是想买就能买&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;人们都喜欢能够提供高情绪价值的人和事，这是人之常情。敏锐的商家也抓住了这个商机——年轻人需要情绪价值，我就来贩卖情绪价值。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;问题是，情绪价值真的是想买就能买吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如果情绪价值是如此轻而易举就能够获得的东西，它也就不会如此稀缺了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;诚如前文所言，情绪价值是一种“能力”，它要真正击中你emo的点，带给你力量，给到你抚慰，帮你跨越那种消沉的情绪。这不是你在对话框里一通输出，对方说几句心灵鸡汤，就可以实现的；不是你买了“好运锦鲤”或“爱因斯坦的脑子”，你就如有神助，好运就从天上掉下来了；也不是对方“煽动情绪”，你就情绪解放了……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;所以，互联网上那些几毛钱、几块钱出售的“情绪”，出售的只是一个噱头，出售者并不具备提供情绪价值的素养与能力，他们甚至比一些商家的客服更套路、更敷衍。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;年轻人购买的也只是几分钟的新鲜感，给emo情绪带来几分钟的乐子，新鲜感一过，该emo还是得emo，问题没解决的话还是没解决。把“情绪买卖”当作调侃可以，较真了可能会上当受骗，让你更加emo。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;说到底，如果没有人或事可以依靠，那么能够给自己带来正向情绪价值的，就只有你自己。你如果长时间没学习，觉得自己堕落了，你会感到emo，你认为加入“虚拟自习室”会给你带来动力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;实际上，如此的他律也是形同虚设，如果你多一些自律，每天完成定下的目标，完成的那一刻你会感到真正的快乐——越自律越自由；你如果平时不努力，考试前就会感到emo，你认为购买“好运锦鲤”就会好运，可考试时你不会还是不会，如果你努力学习、专心备考，你的付出会在考试中体现，你收获的是真正的踏实感与成就感……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;情绪价值终究不是想买就能买，购买情绪当个乐子可以，可走出emo不能只靠精神胜利。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《芭蕾舞复仇曲》：韩影越来越套路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259234]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;在新一代的韩国女演员中，全钟瑞是个另类的存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她发迹于李沧东的《燃烧》，从上千人的海选中脱颖而出，且在银幕首作就上演大尺度戏份。全钟瑞脸上的狡黠和疏离，不经意间的闪躲，外加一丝怯懦，构成了她丰富的脸部美学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在新作《芭蕾舞复仇曲》中，再次展现了这种极富辨识度的表现风格。这是她和新锐导演李聪贤的第二次合作，两人首次联袂，是2020年的犯罪悬疑片《电话》，曾在影迷圈引起热议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/94cb079e77d0483c939911d74b3cbf15.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/94cb079e77d0483c939911d74b3cbf15.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《芭蕾舞复仇曲》里，全钟瑞虽然不似《电话》中那般癫狂，但她饰演的女孩玉珠，同样是个不好惹的主儿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玉珠曾在安保公司做保镖，专门保护高层重要人员。她那超一流的身手和敏锐的头脑，在开场的超市抢劫戏里就表露无遗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f3a9ec1f3da4106b7a1d835c84f48513.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f3a9ec1f3da4106b7a1d835c84f48513.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许长时间保持高度警惕，玉珠对生活毫无兴趣，整日丧气满满，直到邂逅了老同学敏熙。后者天然的亲和力，将玉珠从枯燥的生活泥淖中解脱出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了表现氛围上的反差，影片在展现敏熙带着玉珠过生日、拍大头照和到海滩散心时，特地以五彩斑斓的柔光，捕捉两个女孩松弛曼妙的友情。这和全片大量的夜景戏、室内戏形成反差，后者基本以高对比度、低调打光的方式，营造危险不安的情境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eeaf31229575a54a62fa9148e156c55f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;447&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eeaf31229575a54a62fa9148e156c55f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故事的转折点，出现在敏熙突然自杀，留下遗言希望玉珠帮她报仇。玉珠顺着线索，找到一个叫“崔主厨”的男人后，她发现敏熙的自杀大有文章。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;崔主厨家中不少“SM”的道具，以及柜中大量分门别类的U盘，都在表明：在“猎艳”过程中，他往往采用变态的手段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0d1f535dabea0dc186b64630653fd1d4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;444&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0d1f535dabea0dc186b64630653fd1d4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而敏熙，就是在被崔主厨盯上之后，一边被迷药迷奸，一边被拍下视频。崔主厨这么做，不单单是为了满足畸形欲望，更是通过视频威胁像敏熙这样的女孩，强迫她们“接客”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这条犯罪链，并非崔主厨一人所为，他还拥有固定合作的药剂师，所以每次都能用“听话水”这样的迷药得逞；手下还经营着桃色宾馆，专门干招揽嫖客的勾当。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6d74c7ae51907124c4f2612d454f78b0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6d74c7ae51907124c4f2612d454f78b0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但最让人后怕的，还是崔主厨身后的势力。进一步来说，表面凶神恶煞的崔主厨，不过是黑帮组织下的一个小头目，这背后是一个庞大的黑色产业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3b9fa39ae346614fe6e4adea29bae5a6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;585&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/3b9fa39ae346614fe6e4adea29bae5a6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9588ac4b4e3c43c214228f05c4f44c86.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/9588ac4b4e3c43c214228f05c4f44c86.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《芭蕾舞复仇曲》里的这一设定，来自于前几年在韩国闹得沸沸扬扬的“N号房”案件。案件中的犯人赵主彬，便是在网络平台建立付费“房间”，将被威胁的女孩作为筹码，从中获利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只不过，本片将黑帮势力引入其中，让性犯罪变得深不见底，目的是放大这种绝望和愤怒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前段时间，改编自真实事件的《自由之声》，则是将鲜有人提及的儿童拐卖和性交易摆到台面上。该片质量虽然不佳，但对这一话题的探讨，值得肯定，它让我们看到了深藏地下，荼毒甚广的一种犯罪现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到《芭蕾舞复仇曲》中，随着玉珠对崔主厨及其背后组织的调查加深，她也从一开始只为闺蜜复仇，逐渐转变为替受害女性复仇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/268593f73416414dfafc55f5eebe2d6a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/268593f73416414dfafc55f5eebe2d6a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此，杀戮戏份、动作场面，成为本片的第二大看点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全钟瑞当然不可能像史泰龙、杰森·斯坦森那样，靠身体的对抗和撞击制造视觉刺激，也不可能如李连杰、甄子丹那般，以实打实的功夫路数展现赏心悦目的身段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《芭蕾舞复仇曲》的动作设计，吸收了《疾速追杀》系列的风格，即充分发挥“枪械形”动作片的优势，让热兵器和拳脚功夫交替使用，枪支弹药可以营造火爆场面，而拳脚和刀斧的正面相迎，又能凸显惊险效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49c05f887c4da2835039b1202d553252.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;447&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49c05f887c4da2835039b1202d553252.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这在高潮戏份中，玉珠以两把手枪对抗整个黑帮团伙体现得最明显。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，光凭这一点，显然无法弥补全钟瑞在动作戏份上的补足，于是，镜头语言和剪辑手法成为了必要的辅助手段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迅速的甩镜手法、和出拳方向同步的运镜，以及近景、特写镜头的大量使用，搭配快速凌厉的剪辑风格，让整部电影凡是进入动作桥段，节奏明显加快，氛围也显得肆意张狂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f93216844dc743bab519ed1dbdda4762.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f93216844dc743bab519ed1dbdda4762.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，导演李聪贤对香港的《导火线》、印尼的《突袭》和韩国本土的《犯罪都市》这些动作片如数家珍，才能游刃有余地打造这些动作戏码。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，倾斜失衡的镜头画面，色彩反差极大的霓虹美学，都让《芭蕾舞复仇曲》更靠近这些年好莱坞犯罪片的路数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/78b1fd2e8b7e5919d612333b29603ec0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/78b1fd2e8b7e5919d612333b29603ec0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总的来说，剥削女性身体的犯罪题材，不错的打斗戏码，以及全钟瑞时而保守内敛，时而敏感愤怒的人物弧光，让本片拥有及格线以上的爽片娱乐感。只是，当我们看罢《芭蕾舞复仇曲》，还是能察觉到它那基于大数据算法的讨巧和轻浮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玉珠这个角色，虽然在复仇过程中情绪不断深入，但这种细腻的内心变化，更多依仗于全钟瑞的出色表演。她为什么会做保镖这一行？又为什么在生活如此丧感？影片从未交代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49aca55250b8bad1121f2886af777652.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/49aca55250b8bad1121f2886af777652.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于她被敏熙感染，内心逐渐融化，则如同走过场一样，拍得刻板套路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最让人费解的，还是黑道团伙的装腔作势，外强中干。满口黑帮传统的老大，在对崔主厨训话后，你看不到他有什么作为，既没有识破崔主厨的谎言，也没有展现对组织的运筹帷幄。只有在“死于话多”的反差桥段中，发挥了点作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/290aa6cfac3b8cb644611e61892284ca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/290aa6cfac3b8cb644611e61892284ca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此，《芭蕾舞复仇曲》提供了一个女性复仇的框架，尤其在替闺蜜复仇上，它和暑期档爆款《消失的她》如出一辙。可一到具体的犯罪心理、社会生态等层面，则仿佛泄了气一般。它不像罗泓轸的《黄海》，将那些肮脏、愤怒和躁动的人物心理掰扯开，细细地让你看，而是提供了一种即时消费的视觉快感，迎合大众的情绪快餐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是网飞等流媒体进军韩国市场的必然结果，它带来了大数据精算法，也带来了更套路化的公式，而这也可能会成为接下来几年，韩国电影质量全面下降的信号。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[深圳欢乐谷过山车追尾，有游客称前一天已遇故障]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259498]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 10:19:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project promotion picture. Picture from Shenzhen Happy Valley official website&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ca65ce211c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;646&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/28/ca65ce211c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;&quot;Snowland Eagle&quot; project promotion picture. The picture comes from the official website of Shenzhen Happy Valley&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 18:27 on October 27, 2023, a vehicle collision occurred in the roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; in Happy Valley, a well-known theme park in Shenzhen, injuring 8 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I was sitting on the second roller coaster at the time. The speed was very fast and the impact was very strong.&quot; At 22:17, Yu Qing, who witnessed the experience, just came out of the University of Hong Kong Shenzhen Hospital. Her test result was mild. Concussion, bruises and skin injuries on hands and feet. She recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that she didn’t know exactly what happened at the time of the incident. “I just felt that my car was sliding backwards, and finally I realized that it had hit the previous car that was discharging passengers.”&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At 23:25, Shenzhen Happy Valley officially issued a situation report stating that the injured have been sent to the hospital for treatment and are in stable condition with no life-threatening injuries. &quot;The cause of the incident is under investigation. The equipment has stopped operating. We will further conduct a comprehensive inspection of all equipment in the park.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the 28th, Shenzhen Happy Valley reported again that from the 28th to the 29th, The park will be closed for two days and a safety inspection of the entire park will be carried out. Visitors who have purchased tickets can receive a full refund through the original purchase channel. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Tourists said there was a &quot;system problem&quot; the day before&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I heard a loud noise at that time, and many staff members ran in and asked us to give way. We didn&#39;t know what happened at first What happened? I found out later that it was a car crash.&quot; Zhao Xin, a student who was queuing at the scene, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Xin said that several students from Shenzhen Huitong School were on the roller coaster where the accident occurred. “Several of them went up to play together. One of them had some stomach injuries because he didn’t have time to get off, and the other one It’s more serious and I passed out.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 23:00 on the 27th, a Southern Weekend reporter called the customer service of the University of Hong Kong Shenzhen Hospital. A staff member on the line said he was unclear about the situation, but said that the current queue time in the emergency department would be It&#39;s very long. &quot;There are more people waiting in the emergency department now.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Shenzhen Happy Valley, &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; has a five-star thrill level. It is a catapult roller coaster built with a huge investment of 200 million and is the tallest and longest catapult roller coaster in Asia, with a total length of 550 meters. &quot;Speed ​​up in 2 seconds, galloping at 135 kilometers per hour, falling vertically from 60 meters, heart-poundingly crazy for 90 seconds, 4G maximum acceleration, the experience of going to the sky, going to the ground, and going into the sea is thrilling to the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is It is a relatively popular event, and there were a lot of people queuing up today.&quot; Zhao Xin recalled that she had been queuing for nearly two hours. If nothing had happened, it would have been her turn to get on the next bus. Finally, she left around 19:00 At the scene, &quot;When my friend went over to play, he found that the project had been closed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, the day before the incident, Chen Yuangang played &quot;Snow Land&quot; with his friends. Eagle&quot; project. She told Southern Weekend reporters that there was a problem with the system at that time: &quot;The Snow Eagle made a loud sound when it ejected, but I didn&#39;t hear it at the time, and then I found that the car had returned to the starting position. After a while, , the roller coaster ejected again, and returned to the starting position after a normal run.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yuan recalled that the vehicle system activated the emergency protection device at that time, and tourists on the roller coaster were unable to get off. &quot;The staff used the microphone to inform the remaining people in line that there was a problem with the system and needed to be repaired, so they could not continue playing. They also issued speed passes to the remaining people in line.&quot; Chen Yuan said that everyone stayed on the stalled roller coaster again. After about ten minutes, the staff adjusted and the emergency braking mode was released and we were able to get out of the car. &quot;About two hours after the emergency repairs, Happy Valley notified Snow Eagle to resume operations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Maintenance is done every day&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Shenzhen Happy Valley has been open since 1998 and is a new generation of large-scale theme park of OCT Group. Among them, the catapult roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project was officially opened in July 2012. Its vehicle structure includes two trains (orange car and green car), each train has 6 carriages, and each carriage can accommodate 4 people. There are 24 people in the whole car and 48 people in the two cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, a rear-end collision involving an aerial sightseeing train occurred in Happy Valley. On November 1, 2018, while two &quot;Happy Main Line&quot; sightseeing trains were running over the Overseas Chinese Town tourist resort, the front train stopped due to a system failure, causing a slight rear-end collision with the rear train. There were about 20 passengers on the two trains, causing 2 People get hurt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to information from the China Bidding and Bidding Public Service Platform, on March 21, 2023, Shenzhen OCT Happy Valley Tourism Company issued a bidding announcement for the overhaul service project of the Shenzhen Happy Valley Snowy Eagle Project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bidding announcement shows that the overhaul service project of Shenzhen Happy Valley&#39;s &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; project includes professional evaluation of the overall operation situation, carrying out Snowy Eagle&#39;s service status evaluation, safety and reliability evaluation, large-scale Repairs, condition monitoring systems and other work will be carried out, and it will pass statutory inspections, regulatory filings, etc. The planned construction period is from April 20, 2023 to June 30, 2023. Finally, on April 25, 2023, Shenzhen Runchang Amusement Culture Group Co., Ltd. won the bid with an amount of 7.09 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have not done major repairs, we only do daily maintenance.” A person in charge of the bidding project told Southern Weekend reporters, “The daily conditions are normal and there are no problems. Maintenance is done every day. Weekly maintenance is done every week, monthly maintenance is done every month, and maintenance is done every year. It is impossible to say that there is any rust.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked about the cause of the accident, the person in charge said : &quot;Our company has a unified response to this aspect, and everything is now waiting for investigation and technical analysis.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(should be At the request of the interviewee, the interviewees in the article are all pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“美容腐败”Vs从“表哥”到低调腐败：性别偏好影响腐败模式丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, according to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, a former member of the Party Group and Vice Chairman of the Beijing Yanqing District Committee of the CPPCC Chen Guifen was expelled from the party and public office, and the suspected criminal issues will be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law. The notice specifically mentioned that Chen Guifen &quot;violated regulations in accepting gifts and arrangements for beauty activities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, expressions such as &quot;accepting beauty activities&quot; and &quot;addicted to beauty&quot; have appeared many times in official review reports on dismissed female officials. Chen Guifen&#39;s defeat this time has further brought the new term &quot;beauty corruption&quot; to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;beauty corruption&quot; refers to cases of corruption and bribery that occur due to accepting beauty activities. Among the typical cases reported in recent years, the high amount of money involved and the bizarre corruption projects of &quot;beauty corruption&quot; have been breathtaking. The former director of the Anshan Municipal Taxation Bureau Liu Guangming’s “500,000 butt plastic surgery fee”, the latter the former mayor of Manzhouli City Xu Ailian’s “150,000 yuan for a beauty needle”, and the former vice president of North China University of Technology Shen Zhili’s “single consumption of 690,000 yuan” &quot;An astonishing number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to infer from the term &quot;cosmetic corruption&quot; that certain types of corruption are indeed related to gender. Due to the different preferences of men and women, it is not difficult to understand that bribers will cater to them in a targeted manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;willfulness&quot; of power will find an outlet, just like life, to satisfy the individual desires of those who abuse power. Cash and real estate, gold and silver jewelry, luxury cars and watches, antique calligraphy and paintings, there is always something suitable for fallen officials, which is also a common feature of corruption among male and female officials. However, the difference in preferences between male and female officials in the form of corruption is also a visible phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, the ostentatious culture of men showing off their success also had an impact on the officialdom. There were many incidents where people were arrested for corruption based on photos. In view of this, in recent years, the corruption of male officials has mostly been &quot;low-key&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;, which is the &quot;lesson&quot; learned from certain &quot;cousins&quot; and &quot;brothers&quot; who were dismissed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, in terms of forms of corruption, the &quot;indirect&quot; and &quot;confusing&quot; characteristics of male officials are becoming more and more obvious, such as &quot;setting up offshore accounts&quot;, &quot;accepting bribes after retirement&quot;, &quot;shadow companies&quot;, &quot;option corruption&quot;, etc. There are endless means. The ancient &quot;elegant bribery&quot; has not completely gone into history. The high-end bribery and acceptance of bribes with the help of antique calligraphy and painting are still common in the corruption details of fallen male officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, male officials are also trying to hide their wealth and keep a low profile. They are no longer easily caught because of their public image as usual. Regarding the details of corruption, male officials also try their best to cover up and leave no traceable information, such as the &quot;$300,000 gift box&quot; codenamed &quot;Little Seafood&quot; received by Sun Lijun, and Zhang Qi, former member of the Standing Committee of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee and former Secretary of the Haikou Municipal Party Committee. The secret method of &quot;filling the home with 13.5 tons of gold bars&quot;. Male officials can often use their special interests and hobbies to satisfy their greed while hiding the fact of corruption: Yang Hongwei, former deputy secretary of the party group and deputy director of the Chongqing Municipal Administration for Market Regulation, is known as the &quot;ball secretary&quot; and is keen on playing basketball during working hours. , using playing ball to cover up his corrupt behavior of giving and receiving privately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to see that playing ball and other hobbies are more common among men. Judging from some female officials who have been dismissed in recent years, corruption that combines power and the love of beauty is not uncommon. From accessories, clothing and bags to luxury goods consumption, to the so-called &quot;beauty corruption&quot;. Just like the corruption record of Bai Hong, the former chairman of the labor union of the Beijing Municipal Health Bureau, &quot;the praise and jealousy of the people around him made Bai Hong immersed in the pleasure of a successful woman.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For bribers to pay for beauty treatments on their behalf, or to give high-priced beauty salon membership cards, this can constitute bribery of female officials, and even the development of novel money laundering methods. In real life, it is not uncommon for &quot;ordinary people to pay exorbitant prices for beauty treatments.&quot; However, once a female official&#39;s love for beauty is empowered by her desire for power, the resulting corruption will become even more like a torrential flood. &quot;Power keeps people young forever&quot; is not only a symbolic statement for female officials, but also a realistic statement that can be realized with the help of beauty consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not just officials who are corrupt. People in key positions can still be corrupt, and corruption tends to be younger. Young people tend to be bolder and more reckless in their corruption. Zhang Yujie, a &quot;post-1995&quot; clerk at the Chuzhou Real Estate Registration Center, embezzled nearly 70 million yuan in public funds, tens of thousands of which were spent on game cards. After the incident, this card was auctioned for more than 80 million yuan. His hobby is playing games. In the 2016 &quot;Accounting Corruption Case of Four Young Women in Yangzhou, Jiangsu Province&quot;, Bai Ling, the former cash accountant of the Gaoyou Municipal Agricultural Committee, misappropriated 10.51 million yuan in public funds, of which more than 8 million yuan was used for beauty consumption. At the time of the case, she was only 29 Years old, it is really shocking to embezzle such a huge amount of money just for beauty consumption. Their preference is to love beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 34 of the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishment for Public Officials&quot; stipulates that &quot;those who accept or provide arrangements for banquets, travel, fitness, entertainment and other activities that may affect the fair exercise of public power will be given a warning, A demerit or a major demerit will be recorded, and if the circumstances are serious, the person will be demoted or dismissed.&quot; Beauty corruption, in terms of form, is a relatively hidden &quot;entertainment and other activities&quot;, and the amount involved is often in compliance with the &quot;Applicable Laws on Handling Criminal Cases of Corruption and Bribery&quot; of the two high authorities. The &quot;extremely huge amount&quot; standard in &quot;Explanation of Certain Issues&quot; can be called hidden corruption in the gray area. Therefore, to combat beauty corruption, we need to start from the source of corruption and curb the room for arbitrary power. This point is gender-neutral. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家数据局揭牌，年内落马中管干部达39人丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259490]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/26cYbymIzOStR24cc3LlYF4O4UW02DgWUpAEzt6F.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;617&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/26cYbymIzOStR24cc3LlYF4O4UW0 2DgWUpAEzt6F. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255790&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 25, 2023, the National Data Administration was officially launched. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than seven months of preparation, on the morning of October 25, 2023, a group of members of the preparatory team Witnessed by representatives from other ministries and commissions, the National Data Agency was officially unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So far, the two newly established departments in the ninth institutional reform of the State Council have been completed. Previously, the newly established State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau had completed its listing on May 18, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new round of institutional reform plan of the State Council shows that the National Data Administration is managed by the National Development and Reform Commission and is specifically responsible for coordinating and promoting the construction of data infrastructure systems, coordinating the integration, sharing and development and utilization of data resources, and coordinating the promotion of digital China, digital economy, Digital society planning and construction, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exploring the Blue Ocean of Data&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before the National Data Bureau announced its establishment, the importance of data had been emphasized many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the &quot;Overall Layout Plan for the Construction of Digital China&quot; was issued. Earlier, at the end of 2022, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Building a Data Infrastructure System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements.&quot; Both documents include content to accelerate the development of the digital economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong, deputy director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission, was more direct. In an exclusive interview with the media in April 2023, he once proposed that by the end of the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, the size of China&#39;s data element circulation market will reach one trillion yuan, which is a huge blue ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Existing data has confirmed this statement. The &quot;Digital China Development Report (2022)&quot; released by the Cyberspace Administration of China shows that the scale of China&#39;s data digital economy will reach 50.2 trillion yuan in 2022, ranking second in the world, accounting for 41.5% of GDP, and will continue to remain the same. With a high growth rate of 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Zhang Xianghong, a professor at the International Research Center for Information Management Theory and Technology at Beijing Jiaotong University, the current level of development of China&#39;s public data, corporate data and personal data is still low, and the level of utilization is not high. Problems of insufficient motivation and insufficient utilization of vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, unified data resource management and activation of data efficiency have become high hopes for the National Data Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a previous interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, Yuan Lizhi, a partner at Jingtian &amp; Gongcheng Law Firm and an expert in data law, mentioned that in January 2023, after a seminar on the circulation of data elements, the state Staff from the National Development and Reform Commission once worked with him to communicate on practical issues regarding the circulation of data elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two leaders made their early appearance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;They have clear development goals, which is also reflected in the personnel arrangements of the National Data Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 18, 2023, Liu Liehong, the first director of the National Data Administration, made his first public appearance at the high-level forum on digital economy of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resume shows that Liu Liehong was born in 1968 and has worked in industrial electronic information institutions for a long time. Since joining the workforce in 1990, Liu Liehong has served as an assistant engineer and engineer. In November 2004, Liu Liehong was appointed as the deputy general manager of China Electronics Technology Group Co., Ltd. through open recruitment. He later served as the president of China Electronics Information Industry Development Research Institute and president of Beijing Saidi Information Industry Group Co., Ltd., and director and general manager of China Electronics Information Industry Group Co., Ltd. , director and general manager of China Electronics Technology Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2018, Liu Liehong entered politics from business and was appointed deputy director of the Central Cyberspace Administration. During his tenure, he promoted the development of the mobile industry and 5G network applications. After becoming the chairman of China Unicom Group in August 2021, he also promoted China Unicom&#39;s transformation into a digital pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Liu Liehong, who actively embraces digitalization, Shen Zhulin, deputy director of the National Data Administration, who was appointed on October 11, also has extensive experience in digital economy, electronic information and big data promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Shen Zhulin has worked at the National Development and Reform Commission for a long time. He has served as deputy inspector of the High-tech Industry Department, deputy director of the High-Tech Department, and director of the Innovation and High-tech Development Department of the National Development and Reform Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, Shen Zhulin proposed at a symposium held by the Central Cyberspace Administration of China that data resources should be truly treated as an important economic resource and some measures should be taken to truly open and share data. measure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to selecting &quot;professional counterparts&quot; for bureau leaders, the National Data Bureau also has relatively clear requirements for basic talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Recruitment Brochure for Civil Servants Recruited by Central Agencies and Their Directly Affiliated Agencies for the 2024 Examination&quot; published on October 15, 2023 shows that in this round of recruitment, the National Data Bureau has opened a total of 12 recruitment quotas in 5 units. Applicants are required to have at least 3 years of grass-roots work experience, and a master&#39;s degree or above in electronic science and technology, information and communication engineering, computer science and technology, applied economics, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the recruitment requirements, these talents will participate in research on data governance and development policies, international cooperation in the data field and digital economy, research on data basic systems and policies, and the formulation of development strategies, plans and policies related to the digital economy. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Li Shangfu and Qin Gang were dismissed State Councilor&#39;s Position]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;News Network&quot;, according to the decision of the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of the People&#39;s Republic of China on October 24, 2023 , removed Li Shangfu from the posts of State Councilor and Minister of Defense, and removed Qin Gang from the posts of State Councilor. Previously, on July 25, the fourth meeting of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress voted to remove Qin Gang as Minister of Foreign Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The new leadership of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation was elected, and 14 people including Zhang Guimei were elected vice-chairmen]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 25, 2023, the first meeting of the 13th Executive Committee of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation was held. The meeting elected the Chairman, Vice Chairman and Standing Committee members of the Women&#39;s Federation by secret ballot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the elected chairpersons of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation are State Councilor and Director of the State Council Working Committee on Women and Children Chen Yiqin, Huang Xiaowei, Sangding Dorjepam Deqing Quzhen, Zhang Xiaolan, Ge Xiaoyan, Yu Yanhong, Xu Xiaolan 14 people, including Ma Lu, Lin Yi, Feng Ling, Zhang Dongmei, Chen Hualan, Meng Man, Zhang Guimei and Wang Yaping, were elected vice presidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resumes show that the 14 vice-chairmen of the Women&#39;s Federation are outstanding female representatives in various industries. Among them, Xu Xiaolan is the vice minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, and Zhang Guimei is the principal of Huaping County Women&#39;s Senior High School in Lijiang, Yunnan. They are known as As the &quot;principal mother of a mountain girl&quot;, Wang Yaping is China&#39;s first female astronaut to perform extravehicular activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Xie Fuzhan, former Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, was elected chairman of the China Human Rights Development Foundation]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency, the first meeting of the fourth council of the China Foundation for Human Rights Development was held in Beijing on October 25. Xie Fuzhan was elected as the new chairman of the board of directors, Zhou Shuchun, the former president and editor-in-chief of China Daily, was elected as the executive vice chairman, and Zuo Feng, Huang Jin, Li Cheng Tenzin Nyima was elected as the vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Xie Fuzhan was born in Tianmen, Hubei in August 1954. He has a postgraduate degree, a master&#39;s degree in engineering, a researcher, and a doctoral supervisor. He enjoys special government allowances from the State Council. He joined the Communist Party of China in November 1974. , joined the work in March 1973. He served as Secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee and former President of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/smX6GQKoiebtiNYeiTFpK6drDIsiTuqN9Pn2YA8g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/smX6GQKoiebtiNYeiTFpK6drDIsiTuqN9Pn2YA8g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xie Fuzhan, former secretary of the Henan Provincial Party Committee, was elected chairman of the China Human Rights Development Foundation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【Tibet The Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region concurrently serves as the Principal of the Party School]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, the website of the Party School of the Tibet Autonomous Region Party Committee (Autonomous Region Administrative College) updated the &quot;Leader Introduction&quot; column. Wang Junzheng, Secretary of the Party Committee of the Tibet Autonomous Region, is currently concurrently serving as the President of the Party School The position of president of the Party School of the Autonomous Region Party Committee (Dean of the Autonomous Region Administrative College). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Transfer only one month, scholar type Leading cadres quit]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report from the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision on October 23, 2023, Cai Lecai, a first-level inspector of the Sichuan Provincial Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center, is being investigated for serious violations of discipline and law. Accept disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resume shows that Cai Lecai has worked in Sichuan universities for a long time, and has served successively as Secretary of the Party Branch of the Computer Science Department of Sichuan Institute of Technology, Director of the Science and Technology (Industry) Division, and Vice President, and Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee and President of Yibin University. Party committee secretary and other positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Cai Lecai had just transferred from school to serve as a first-level inspector of the Sichuan Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center, assisting a deputy director of the Intellectual Property Service Promotion Center. By the time he was investigated, he had only been in office for a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ling Chengxing, the former director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was investigated, and the number of dismissed cadres increased to 39]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported that Ling Chengxing, the former party secretary and director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. Becoming the 39th central management cadre to be dismissed in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resume shows that Ling Chengxing was born in Jiangxi in 1957 and has worked in Jiangxi for a long time. He has served as mayor of Fengcheng City, deputy director of Jiangxi Provincial Economic Commission, director (manager) of Jiangxi Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), Assistant to the Governor of Jiangxi Province and other positions. In 2001, Ling Chengxing served as the vice governor of Jiangxi Province. In 2013, he was transferred to a member of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration until he resigned in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection concentrated on reporting the investigation and punishment information of four &quot;insiders&quot;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 21, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission reported information on the investigation and punishment of four cadres of the discipline inspection system. They are the former party secretary and director of the Legal Affairs Office of the Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, and the former director of the Hainan Provincial Department of Veterans Affairs. Wang Zhiqiang, member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director, Long Guangzhi, former deputy secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Qujing City, Yunnan Province, former deputy director of the Municipal Supervisory Committee, and second-level inspector, and Fan Renfu, former leader of the inspection team of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investigation information shows that, except for Fan Renfu, who is still under investigation, the other three were &quot;disloyal and dishonest to the party&quot;, resisted organizational review, and were unable to truthfully explain problems. At the same time, behaviors such as concealing stolen money, making wishes or platforms for others, intervening in economic disputes or engineering projects, and living a luxurious life are also common. Among them, Long Guangzhi also informed criminal suspects and provided conveniences to help them avoid punishment when he was responsible for cracking down on criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The former deputy governor of Hubei Province leaked insider information, causing others to make tens of millions of profits]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, the case of Cao Guangjing accepting bribes and leaking inside information was heard publicly in the first instance of the Intermediate People’s Court of Xuzhou City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Court information shows that in 2014, Cao Guangjing resigned as chairman of China Three Gorges Corporation and became deputy governor of the Hubei Provincial Government. During his tenure, Cao Guangjing was mainly responsible for industry, transportation, state-owned assets supervision, and provincial investment and financing platforms. He once led the bailout and reorganization of the holding company of a listed company in Hubei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, Cao Guangjing disclosed the inside information about the bailout and restructuring to others, causing others to buy the shares of the listed company before the inside information was made public, and then sold the shares for a profit of more than 10.42 million yuan. . In February 2022, Cao Guangjing announced his resignation, and the following month, Fu Limin, then party secretary of the Hubei Provincial State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, also announced his resignation. A follow-up report from the Hubei Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision stated that Fu Limin acted arbitrarily and made illegal decisions during the restructuring of state-owned enterprises, resulting in huge losses to public property and the risk of major losses to state-owned assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the trial, the public prosecution requested that Cao Guangjing be held criminally responsible for the crime of accepting bribes and leaking inside information. Cao Guangjing expressed his guilt and repentance. The court adjourned the hearing and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;p>; Fair access to education]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the regular policy briefing of the State Council Information Office held on October 25, 2023, the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Education introduced that currently, efforts are being made to provide financial assistance to students from families with financial difficulties. Achieve &quot;three improvements&quot;, that is, improve coverage, improve accuracy, and improve independent standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the country’s cumulative funding amount reached 292.273 billion yuan, and a total of 161 million students were supported. In the next step, the Ministry of Education will organize and implement the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; special education development and improvement action plan to address the issue of school security for students with disabilities in special groups, include more children with disabilities in the special education security system, and increase public funding per student for special education students. Increase to 7-10 times that of ordinary students, reaching 7,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology held the third symposium on manufacturing enterprises]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology held the third symposium for manufacturing companies, and 12 chain owners were invited to participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, regarding the development and difficult issues of key manufacturing industries, Jin Zhuanglong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, presided over and listened to the opinions and demands of business representatives, and deployed plans to promote the high-quality development of key manufacturing industry chains. Focus on work. &lt;p>; >;On October 24, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted and passed relevant resolutions, clarifying that the central government will issue an additional 1 trillion yuan in 2023 national debt in the fourth quarter to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and improve disaster prevention and reduction. Disaster relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance, although the budget has arranged relevant regular disaster relief and disaster prevention and reduction funds at the beginning of this year, it is still difficult to meet the needs for improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day after the news was released, on October 25, the Ministry of Finance launched a bidding and issuance of 16 billion yuan of treasury bonds to professional investors in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate announced the first three quarters of the country&#39;s Main case handling data of procuratorial organs]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate released the main case handling data of procuratorial organs nationwide in the first three quarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to September 2023, procuratorial organs across the country approved and decided to arrest a total of 520,000 criminal suspects of various types, of which 392,000 were not arrested, with a non-arrest rate of 43%; a total of 118.2 people were decided to prosecute. Of the 10,000 people involved, 411,000 were not prosecuted, with a non-prosecution rate of 25.8%. Among all prosecution cases, the number of cases concluded under the leniency system for plea guilty and punishment accounted for more than 90% of the number of cases concluded during the same period, and the procuratorial organs’ recommendations on sentencing and sentencing accounted for more than 95% of the number of sentencing recommendations made. Among them, the number of people who adopted the court’s adoption accounted for more than 95% of the number of sentencing recommendations made during the same period. 97.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the person in charge of the Supreme People’s Procuratorate’s Case Management Office, my country’s criminal structure has undergone major changes over the past two decades. The proportion of sentences sentenced to three years or more in prison has dropped from 45.4% in 1999 to 2023. 17.2% from January to September, the crime structure shows a clear misdemeanor, and social governance has entered a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【114,000 economic crime cases investigated in the first three quarters】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 On March 24, the State Council Information Office held a series of press conferences with the theme of &quot;The Beginning of Authoritative Departments&#39; Talks&quot;. Yang Xin, director of the Research Office of the Ministry of Public Security, introduced that since the 26 measures to ensure high-quality development of public security services were announced to the public in August this year, the threshold for settling in various regions has been further lowered, and 29 provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities have achieved &quot;inter-provincial transfers of all types of household registrations&quot;. In the past two months, a total of more than 500,000 household registration transfers have been processed across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Vice Minister of Public Security Wang Zhizhong also stated at the meeting that this year, public security agencies across the country will focus on building a high-level socialist market economic system and severely crack down on various economic crimes. From January to September, public security agencies across the country investigated a total of 114,000 economic crime cases and successfully recovered economic losses of 18.37 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors&quot; was released]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October On the 24th, my country&#39;s first specialized comprehensive legislation on the online protection of minors was passed. The &quot;Regulations on the Internet Protection of Minors&quot; will be officially implemented on January 1, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant persons in charge of the Ministry of Justice and the Cyberspace Administration of China mentioned in answers to reporters’ questions that the formulation of regulations follows the overall ideas of problem orientation, social co-governance, and legislative coordination, focusing on the online protection of minors. The outstanding issues faced by the work clarify the responsibilities of relevant government departments and enterprises, schools, families, industry organizations, news media, etc. in the online protection of minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[70 years of establishment, Buckley Award Welcome Chinese winners for the first time]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, Beijing time, the American Physical Society announced that Xue Qikun, academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, professor of Tsinghua University, and president of Southern University of Science and Technology, won this year’s Buckley Award. . This is also the first time in the 70 years since the award was established that a Chinese scientist has won the Buckley Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, the Buckley Award was established to commend scientists who have made outstanding contributions in the field of condensed matter physics, and is recognized as the highest award in the international field of condensed matter physics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2009, Xue Qikun has joined forces with multiple research groups from the Department of Physics of Tsinghua University, the Institute of Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, and Stanford University in the United States to form a research team to conduct experimental observations of the quantum anomalous Hall effect. At the end of 2012, Xue Qikun and his team successfully overcame the difficulty and experimentally observed the quantum anomalous Hall effect for the first time in the world. The result was published in the American &quot;Science&quot; magazine in March 2013 and was called &quot;a landmark work in the field of condensed matter physics.&quot; Xue Qikun won the Buckley Award for this breakthrough research result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/jTgEU3YHSfataawS5yi421C64yY9mqj3FuUUsz0u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/jTgEU3YHSfataawS5yi421C64yY9mqj3FuUUsz0u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xue Qikun, professor at Tsinghua University and president of Southern University of Science and Technology, won this year’s Buckley Award. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（People&#39;s Vision/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【Shenzhou The launch of the Shenzhou 17th manned spacecraft was a complete success]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 11:13:59 on October 26, Beijing time, the Shenzhou 17th manned spacecraft was ignited and launched from Jiuquan, Gansu. This manned mission consists of astronauts Tang Hongbo, Tang Shengjie and Jiang Xinlin, and still adopts the strategy of &quot;leading the new with the old&quot;. The second batch of astronauts Tang Hongbo serves as the commander. At the same time, this is also his second time to carry out the mission. Flying mission. In 2021, Tang Hongbo was selected as the first astronaut crew member to carry out the space station phase mission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, during this mission, the three astronauts will also conduct experimental maintenance operations outside the space station for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region: 97.02 issued in two years 100 million yuan to build high-standard farmland】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, the Department of Finance of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region announced that in 2022 and 2023, the autonomous region’s finance will issue a total of 97.02 yuan in subsidy funds for the construction of high-standard farmland. billion to support the construction of 7.95 million acres of high-standard farmland. Statistics show that the high-standard farmland that has been built in Inner Mongolia accounts for less than 40% of the region’s permanent basic farmland, but it produces nearly 70% of the region’s grain, providing the basis for building an important national agricultural and livestock product production base. Assure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sichuan: China&#39;s first natural disaster dynamic risk early warning platform is operational]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;According to Chengdu Daily, since July this year, the Pengzhou Municipal Committee of Social Affairs and Management and the Chengdu High-tech Disaster Reduction Research Institute have established a smart disaster reduction emergency warning project in Longmenshan Town, which has risks of earthquakes, flash floods, debris flows and other disasters. The platform is based on the results of the natural disaster risk census completed simultaneously in Pengzhou City and across the country this year, and integrates multiple disaster warning functions such as flash flood warnings, debris flow warnings, and earthquake warnings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;试运行以来，该平台共产出风险预警信息100余次，报警2次，预警准确性逐渐增加。 10月26日，项目通过验收，成为中国首个正式运行的自然灾害动态风险预警平台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【青海：首批129名兼职督查员获聘】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据青海日报消息，10月26日，青海省政府兼职督查员聘任仪式在西宁举行，聘任首批129名兼职督查员。报道提到，此次受聘的省政府兼职督查员来自各市州政府、相关厅局以及人大、政协、参事等领域，聘任期为2年。任职期间，他们将负责监督党中央国务院、省委省政府重大决策部署落实落地，推动全省经济社会高质量发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【中国宏观经济研究院研究员邢伟：调休比不调休好，而且是不得不调】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，2024年假期放假安排公布，除夕当天不放假的安排引发热议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月25日，国家发展改革委员会在其官方微博上发表了中国宏观经济研究院研究员邢伟撰写的解读文章。邢伟解释，2024年春节法定假期为初一至初八，为史上最长假期，如此安排也是考虑到7个法定节假日的确定标准存在差异，如果不做调休便会造成节假日“碎片化”，到时便不是“累觉不爱”，而是“累且不爱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“总体而言，调休比不调休好，而且是不得不调。”邢伟写道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（综合自人民日报、新华社、央视新闻、中央纪委国家监委官网、教育部官网、工业和信息化部官网、澎湃新闻、青海日报、成都日报等）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡杨林：大漠深处，最美金秋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259424]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-28 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;金秋时节，内蒙古自治区阿拉善盟额济纳旗的胡杨林进入最佳观赏期，层林尽染，色彩斑斓。作为全国胡杨林分布最为集中所在地，“如花秋叶惹人怜”的美景吸引游客前来感受大漠深处最美秋色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/dFC6dONkeVmBNgT85OraD2CS1nkyrIs7mUA7xbDT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/dFC6dONkeVmBNgT85OraD2CS1nkyrIs7mUA7xbDT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255745&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，羊群在胡杨林里觅食。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社记者刘金海/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/hEY7P0OCQTUTsuniN56duKLZbuIQn4N6mc32qgxj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/hEY7P0OCQTUTsuniN56duKLZbuIQn4N6mc32qgxj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255744&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月24日，羊群在胡杨林前饮水。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社记者王楷焱/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/xCm3Gf9vN1opoVcD0bBqwEXQdfh3fg3hzTbIEEno.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/xCm3Gf9vN1opoVcD0bBqwEXQdfh3fg3hzTbIEEno.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日在内蒙古自治区阿拉善盟额济纳旗拍摄的胡杨林。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/王崔荣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/CA4SDVYkxefpwjywpaaVurbPi71FgJSmlJSYt9yA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/CA4SDVYkxefpwjywpaaVurbPi71FgJSmlJSYt9yA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255742&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日在内蒙古自治区阿拉善盟额济纳旗拍摄的胡杨林。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/王崔荣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/NgEcWNZ6xpv84varQpMHiu2aBSQzCjirhd7PmKkj.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/NgEcWNZ6xpv84varQpMHiu2aBSQzCjirhd7PmKkj.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日在内蒙古自治区阿拉善盟额济纳旗拍摄的胡杨林。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/王崔荣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/6Gy0j0xCiWryRXK8CDO4atIWVbRJAN7lYxrKLpJ4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;816&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/6Gy0j0xCiWryRXK8CDO4atIWVbRJAN7lYxrKLpJ4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255739&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是黑河岸边的胡杨林（2023年10月24日摄，无人机照片）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社记者连振/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/Hhz9W7Hksem7HLs5fvQOLOOgjt4Rc3uDXnw1NcCA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/Hhz9W7Hksem7HLs5fvQOLOOgjt4Rc3uDXnw1NcCA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这是2023年10月24日拍摄的胡杨林。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社记者王楷焱/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/kMOxJkYWD01t2SgZCx272B5qIhiFxz9dxhxUAodc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;1903&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/kMOxJkYWD01t2SgZCx272B5qIhiFxz9dxhxUAodc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日在内蒙古自治区阿拉善盟额济纳旗拍摄的胡杨林。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/王崔荣/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 28 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>