<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[呼伦贝尔：一抹秋颜，油画里的童话 | 眼睛在旅游①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[篁岭“晒秋”丨指尖华夏①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, during the harvest season of fruits and vegetables, Huangling Village Villagers used bamboo plaques to hold harvested red peppers, corns, pumpkins, beans and other crops, and placed them on wooden racks in Hui-style houses for drying, outlining pictures of &quot;autumn sun-bathing&quot; in mountain villages with a bumper harvest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;801&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Huangling Village, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一身都是月 | 中秋国庆“悦”读专题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257720]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:23:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;This is Southern Weekend’s “Joy” reading special topic, and I’ll see you again. At this moment, maybe you are already on the road. go home? Visiting friends? Or run all the way to poetry and the distance. The meaning of reading is to make time more valuable and make the journey no longer long and lonely. So, please keep these selected contents, take an 8-day long vacation, blow out the reading lamp, and be covered with moon. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在故乡普洱茶山，醉茶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257357]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;The temptation of spring tea is greater than the virus&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;On the sixth day of the first lunar month of 2020, because Due to the novel coronavirus pneumonia, the county has been closed down. I sent a message to my older cousin in the countryside early in the morning to ask how my relatives in my hometown were doing. My cousin said everything was fine. He has asked his family not to wander around outside unless they have nothing to do; and for his uncle who likes to hunt wild animals in the mountains, he has been strictly forbidden to go hunting in the mountains again. &quot;My uncle is quite honest,&quot; my cousin said. This makes me a little bit unbelievable. My uncle has always been fiery, but now he is willing to listen to his cousin. It seems that his dignity as the head of the family has already been established. My cousin is very busy. He leaves early and comes home late every day. He is the barefoot doctor in the village. He has to go to the monitoring point at the entrance of the village to measure the body temperature of outsiders every day. He has a heavy responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a special period, there are still outsiders coming, for no other reason than that my hometown is one of the best producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea in Yunnan, and March and April are the time to start picking spring tea. In previous years, before the spring tea was picked, many foreign merchants would come to the village early to reserve tea trees and tea farmers, so that the first crop of spring tea could be purchased, packaged, and transported as soon as it was roasted. Although there are not so many people coming this year, for some people, the temptation of spring tea is still greater than the virus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Spring in Pu&#39;er Tea Mountain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu&#39;erbanna area belongs to the middle and low mountains and hilly areas, with interspersed large and small mountain basins and The valley flats pushed out by the Lancang River and its tributary water systems in the area are the main human settlements. Because it is located inland, surrounded by mountains, and has a high quiet wind rate, the cold lake effect is prone to occur in winter. This is especially noticeable when driving on a winding mountain road. It will become hot and cold as the terrain changes, and you will also see the cold lake effect in the winter. There is thick fog at the bottom of the basin and white clouds lingering in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xishuangbanna-Menghai-Huimin line is one of the main producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea. Mangzhi, Manzhuan, Mansa and Youle produce Pu&#39;er tea with excellent quality, and Yiwu tea is produced in Mansa. Menghai Huimin belongs to the six new tea mountains outside the Yangtze River (on the west bank of the Lancang River) - Nannuo, Hekai, Mengsong, Jingmai, Brown and Bada. The well-known Pu&#39;er tea brands &quot;Brown Mountain&quot; and &quot;Lao Banzhang&quot; are Produced in Brown Mountain, Menghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;549&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Schematic diagram of the distribution of ancient Pu&#39;er tea mountains. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Pu&#39;er is known as the source of tea in the world and is a famous Pu&#39;er tea town. The good Pu&#39;er tea is in Lancang, and the Jingmai-Mangjing-Manghong area in Huimin Township is one of the important producing areas of Lancang good tea. The largest ancient tea garden of 10,000 acres among the twelve major tea mountains is here here. The ancient tea garden was planted in 696 AD and has a history of more than 1,300 years. There are also many semi-wild ancient tea trees in the area. The age of the trees is unknown, but according to locals, the oldest tea tree is 1,600 years old. These ancient tea trees still produce a certain amount of output every year and are a cash cow for local villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;My hometown is in a village of the Blang ethnic group&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In the spring of about three years ago, I went back to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown is in Manghong, a village inhabited by the Bulang people. According to the tea mountain classification, it belongs to Jingmai Mountain. The Bulang people living here are good at planting, picking and making tea. Since ancient times, Tea is not only their daily necessities, but also an important commodity in exchange for supplies. Bags of Pu&#39;er tea carried on horseback are transported from Jingmai Mountain to Pu&#39;er Prefecture, Myanmar, and Thailand. Ma Gudao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I rarely go back to my hometown. When I was a child, transportation was inconvenient—my hometown was hidden in the mountains, and the roads used to be difficult. To get from the village to the county seat, one had to walk over mountains and ridges for most of a day, catch a shuttle bus in the countryside, and then take a four- to five-hour ride. When I grew up, I had little time to go home because I studied and worked outside, let alone my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Spring Festival holiday that year, when they heard that I was coming back, my brother-in-law and cousin sent me a message asking me to go back and have a look. The Blang people celebrate the Water Splashing Festival in the Dai calendar year and don’t pay much attention to the Spring Festival, so I didn’t go back during the Spring Festival. Instead, I went back to my hometown with my brother and sister-in-law after Powu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I entered Mangjing from Huimin Township, I found that the road conditions were much better than a few years ago. This was all because of the Pu&#39;er tea. Anyone who sells tea knows that Pu&#39;er tea in this area is good. During the tea-picking season, merchants from all over the country come to collect tea. In order to facilitate the transportation of trucks, the government funded the construction of a road, which greatly improved the efficiency of logistics and transportation. The Blang people who grew tea became rich as a result, and the place became a well-known wealthy town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a checkpoint at the bridge that must be passed when entering Tea Mountain. Cars going out are basically ignored, but cars entering are checked very strictly. It is said to be to prevent someone from smuggling in Pu&#39;er tea of ​​average quality from other places and passing it off as local Pu&#39;er tea before selling it. Although they are in a remote area, people here have already had brand awareness and cherish their tea and brand very much, and do not allow anyone to ruin the reputation of their tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pu&#39;er scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the road conditions are completely different from those in the past, it still took four hours to reach Mang. It was already past 11 noon when we arrived at Hong Laozhai. The uncle came out from the stilted building and waved us into the house. The old house is a traditional Blang wooden house with a history of several decades. Last time I came back, my grandpa and grandma were still alive. They have passed away for a few years now, but the old house still maintains the layout and layout of the past: there is still a fire pit in the kitchen. Although the village has long started to use electricity and biogas, The fire pit still dances with flames day and night. The old people use the fire in this fire pit to bake their favorite cup of roasted tea. On winter nights, they sit around the fire pit to warm themselves up, drink tea, smoke hookahs and chat. The firepit is the soul of the home and cannot be thrown away at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is almost noon, only my uncle is at home. My cousin goes to school and has lunch at school and doesn&#39;t come back until the afternoon; my aunt goes to the mountains to pick tea and doesn&#39;t come home until the afternoon. Although the ancient tree tea has not yet reached the best time to pick, the first batch of platform tea has already begun to be picked. From this time until the end of April, it is the busiest time for the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Platform tea refers to Pu&#39;er tea cultivated in recent decades. Although the taste is not as mellow as accumulated through a long history, it is still a fine quality tea. No artificial fertilizer is applied, and the tea is made by the soil itself. It is nourished by the fallen leaves of ground forest trees, sunlight, rain and dew, and is also called ecological tea. A Taiwanese friend of mine once told me that Taiwan has very strict requirements for tea imports, and only completely ecological tea is allowed to be imported. The tea from my hometown is very popular among Taiwanese businessmen. A considerable part of the tea is bought by Taiwanese businessmen every year, which shows the superior quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Use Red Bull to relieve tea drunkenness&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Although the layout of the old house has not changed, I still found two more things. One is a huge tea table - made by my uncle himself. Judging by its size, the tree must be quite old. With the entry of tea merchants from other places, a different way of life has been brought to the village, such as drinking tea. In the past, when drinking tea, you would take a copper kettle sitting on the fire pond to boil water, grab a handful of tea in a small earthenware pot, and roast it by the pond fire. When the water boiled, the tea would also be roasted and fragrant. When you pour some water into the jar, you will have a jar of fragrant tea, with a strong and wild fragrance. This cup of tea is very fragrant, but it is also very bitter. After the bitterness, it becomes sweet again. The power of tea is also very overbearing. First-time drinkers will become drunk if they are not careful, causing shortness of breath and palpitation, which is very similar to the symptoms of hypoglycemia. The local method is to grab handfuls of uncooked rice and chew it, which is said to be very effective. Canned roasted tea is easy to get drunk when you first drink it, but it can become addictive if you drink it for a long time. In the past, people in the village rarely went outside the mountains. Traffic was one reason, and they also thought the tea outside was weak. If you have to go out, you must bring your own pre-roasted tea leaves. After drinking the tea, no matter how things go, you must go back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the old people also pay attention to the tea ceremony when drinking tea, including tea sea, tea wash, teapot, tea rules, aroma cup, host cup, tea tasting cup, etc., and there are many of them, paying attention to water temperature and water quality. , pay attention to making soup. One move after another, the ancient village is also absorbing new knowledge and changing with the changes of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another change in the old house is the addition of a disinfection cabinet one person high. The Blang people themselves are a nation that loves cleanliness. As for my old house, although it is old, it is kept very neat and clean. The open-air palm (the local name for the terrace of the stilted building) is spotless, which makes people feel simple and friendly. Nowadays, the villagers are paying more and more attention to hygiene when making raw Pu&#39;er tea. Not only the houses, but also the roads in the village are still very clean, although they are still dirt roads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After welcoming us into the old house, my uncle was not busy with anything else. He first invited us to drink tea - during the tea-picking season, almost everyone was busy in the tea mountains all day long, and there was no concept of lunch at all. The tea is spring tea that has just been picked and roasted. Although it is not ancient tree tea, it is still top quality. The uncle poured boiling water into the teapot, closed the lid and let it simmer for five or six seconds, then poured the tea into the sea of ​​tea and distributed it to us. In order to see the color of tea, my uncle specially bought a small transparent glass cup. After pouring the tea, I saw that the tea soup is clear and fresh green in color. There is a fresh bitterness in the mouth. After two cups, the sweetness comes back, and the sweetness overflows in an instant. It fills the space between the lips and teeth, and expands in waves in the mouth, like a young girl who is shy and timid when she first met, but is enthusiastic and lively after getting to know her better - I think she must be a girl from the Brown ethnic group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that drinking Shenpu shaving oil is very powerful. I arrived home at noon, and the breakfast in my stomach was almost digested, and my uncle was giving me a cup of tea on the left and right. Soon I had symptoms of hypoglycemia, and I slumped on the sofa and shouted for food. The uncle then suddenly realized it and patted his head and said, &quot;You are drunk with tea!&quot; Then slowly arrange the cooking. He first cooked the rice in the rice cooker, then set up a large pot on the fire pit, poured water in, pulled off a strip of bacon, chopped it into several pieces and threw it into the pot. While waiting for the water to boil, he went out like a gust of wind. After a while, my uncle came back like a gust of wind, brought back a pile of Red Bull and put it in front of me and said, drink some first, and you will not be drunk after drinking tea. I opened a can and drank it, and I felt better - it seems that Zuicha no longer chews uncooked rice, but drinks Red Bull instead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My uncle thrust Red Bull into my hand and ran out to get lunch. He grabbed a chicken from the chicken coop and killed it, then chopped it into pieces. When the water in the pot boiled, he poured them all into the pot, added seasoning salt, stirred a few times, covered the pot and continued to simmer. ; He also took out a large bowl of water pickled vegetables from the pickled vegetable jar, mixed some with soy sauce and chili for cold dressing, and chopped some into pieces and stir-fried with the turtle dove meat. At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, we finally had a belated lunch - free-range chicken cooked with bacon, mixed with pickled vegetables, and stir-fried turtle doves with pickled vegetables. The food cooked over a firewood was particularly fragrant. I ate it with gusto and kept enough to eat. Two bowls of rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Our ancient tree tea&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;After dinner, my eldest cousin happened to come back from get off work at the village clinic. He said hello to his uncle and said to me, Sister, do you want to see our tea garden? I said yes. The cousin and his uncle went downstairs to start the motorcycle. Manghong Village is built in the mountains. The roads in the village are not wide and the slopes are very undulating. It is not possible to ride bicycles. The daily means of transportation is motorcycles. Every household has at least one or two motorcycles. My cousin drove me along a thin yellow winding dirt road toward the mountains, followed by my brother-in-law and my brother. When we reached a slightly flat spot halfway up the mountain, my cousin stopped the motorcycle and led me to the roadside. He pointed to me not far down the mountain and said, &quot;Sister, look, that&#39;s our village!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is early spring at 4:30 in the afternoon. The sun has turned slightly yellow, the sky is clear and the light is soft. Under the blue sky, stilted buildings with sloping roofs on all sides are scattered in an orderly manner, among the smoky bamboo canopies and banana trees. Under the cover, it undulates intermittently and extends to the mountains on the opposite side, showing a quiet rural style. My cousin said that this is his favorite place. He usually stops to take a look when he passes by the tea farm. When nothing happens, he will also come here to stand for a while. &quot;This is the village where I grew up. Our ancestors were all born and buried here. There is no better place than here,&quot; the cousin said. We looked at it for a while, then my cousin waved me into the car and continued driving up. After turning a few more turns, my cousin stopped the car again and said, &quot;We&#39;re here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6mf3ZfyfGJVc6B.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6 mf3ZfyfGJVc6B. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mountain village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a hillside that looks like an undisturbed mountain forest, with thick and thin trees growing intricately. Trees, shrubs and some vines of varying heights. Between the tall trees and low shrubs, there are tea trees about 2 meters high. Among the dark green adult leaves, new green pointed leaves are piercing out like swords. They will be picked in a few days; Qiu The curved branches are covered with mottled layers of moss, as if they are the sedimented remains of time; the moss grows and withers season after season, and a thin layer of moss soil accumulates on the tea branches, becoming a place for parasitic plants to settle down. Here, as long as the Pu&#39;er tea trees grow to a certain age, there will be a parasitic plant called &quot;crab legs&quot;. The scientific name of crab legs is liquidambar mistletoe, which is very effective in treating rheumatic joint pain, lumbar muscle strain and acute cystitis. When tea leaves sprout, it is also the flowering and fruiting stage of crab legs. They grow in clusters among the tea branches, often causing the tea buds to fail to grow. Yunnan ancient tree Pu&#39;er tea is a large-leaf tree tea with tall plants. It is not easy to remove crab legs. Therefore, in the past, it was an annoying parasitic plant for tea farmers. Nowadays, crab legs are widely sought after, and the price is more expensive than ordinary Pu&#39;er tea, which can easily cost one thousand yuan per catty. Tea farmers often regard crab legs as a by-product of tea, which is another considerable income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My cousin proudly pointed to these tea trees and said: &quot;Sister, these are our treasures, ancient tea trees! Look at these tea trees with particularly strong branches. This one is more than 300 years old. , that one is 500 years old, and that one over there is the &quot;Tea Soul Tree&quot; of this tea field. The old people in the village said it is at least 800 years old. They said they were planted when the tea field first opened... These tea trees I They are all numbered, picked separately every year, and fried separately, which can be sold at a very good price.&quot; The so-called &quot;tea soul tree&quot; is the first tea tree planted in each tea field. How old is the tea garden? No matter how old it is, the tea garden has disappeared, but maybe the tree is still there... The tea soul tree is the soul of the tea garden. It transforms into a god and protects the tea garden. Therefore, a tea festival, called &quot;Tea Soul&quot;, is held every April. , not only does each family have to sacrifice their own tea soul tree, but the village also invites the Big Buddha and respected old people to preside over a grand ceremony to sacrifice the tea soul and call the tea god. In addition to these ancient tea trees, which are hailed as &quot;treasures&quot; by my cousin, the &quot;main force&quot; of this tea land is composed of tea trees that are about 200 years old. The scattered small tea trees are made from cuttings of the branches of ancient trees. They inherit It has the characteristics of the mother tea tree and has a consistent flavor. All it lacks is the experience of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sister, do you know the name of this mountain?&quot; I shook my head. &quot;This is Aileng Mountain, named after Pa Aileng!&quot; said my cousin proudly. Pa Aileng was an outstanding leader of the Blang tribe more than 1,800 years ago. Legend has it that in order to find an ideal place to live, he led the Blang tribe across mountains and rivers. After going through untold hardships, they finally found a place full of wild tea trees. , the soil here is fertile, the streams are gurgling, the vegetation is lush and lush, birds and animals roam here, and it is surrounded by mountains. It is an ideal place to build a village. So Pa Aileng led the tribe to settle here, and guided the tribe to domesticate tea trees and open tea gardens. This is the origin of Brown Village and tea gardens in Mangjing Manghong area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The water and soil in Lengshan are the best, and the tea in Lengshan is also the best tea!” My cousin said to me with an unquestionable and firm attitude. The Blang people believe that their leader Pa Aileng has found the best home and the most fertile land for them. They also believe in the principle of harmonious coexistence between man and nature. Therefore, except for necessary care, the Blang people never use artificial fertilization when growing tea. Needless to say the use of chemicals. The tea trees in the mountains suck the mist and dew, extract nutrients from the soil and dead leaves of weeds, and convert them into tea substances little by little, forming the characteristics of Jingmai Mountain tea, which is bitter and astringent, sweet and refreshing, and orange-yellow in color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, my cousin suddenly turned around and faced me, and said seriously: &quot;Sister, I always think that my ancestors left me such a precious tea land, I must protect it, no matter what The quality of tea trees and tea leaves must not be destroyed in my hands.&quot; I understood what my cousin meant. His main job is as a rural doctor, but he spends almost all his spare time on tea. The Brown people are originally a very clean people. When my cousin came here, he also brought in the professional habits of doctors. When his family picks and roasts tea, he insists on &quot;three things not falling to the ground&quot;, that is, picking the tea does not fall to the ground, withering the tea does not fall to the ground, and frying the tea does not fall to the ground. As for the final pressing of the tea cakes, he does it himself without any help. &quot;I will definitely continue to make tea well, and Pa Aileng will bless us.&quot; The cousin cast his eyes to the sky in the distance. There, the sun that was about to set was covered by a cloud, and the light came out from behind the cloud, giving the clouds a bright golden edge, like some kind of hint and approval from nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[名字最有梗的小城，凭什么又翻红了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257896]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[墨西哥公布“外星人”遗骸，网友：长得太符合刻板印象]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 12, local time, the Mexican Congress held its first public hearing related to &quot;unknown anomalies.&quot; At the meeting, shortly after two scientists played several videos showing &quot;UFOs and unknown anomalies&quot;, they displayed the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot;, and related topics quickly became a &quot;hot search&quot;. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252807&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico, the remains of suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; were displayed at a hearing. Source/Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to local media reports, Mexico plans to promote relevant legislation through hearings, and the country may become the first country in the world to recognize &quot;alien creatures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Do you believe in the existence of aliens? Believe it or not, I can’t tell Submit&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Netizen: They look too human, so I don’t believe it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to public information, the two remains were discovered in Peru in 2017. 1800 and 700. Judging from the footage released at the scene, the appearance of the remains is similar to that of humans, with a slender head and three fingers on each hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers said at the meeting that these specimens had been studied by scientists from the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM). After comparing with other DNA samples, it was found that more than 30% of the specimen DNA was &quot;unknown&quot; of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252809&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, fingers of the remains of suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; were found in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico. Source/Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;X-rays of the specimens were also shown at the hearing. One of them had &quot;eggs&quot; inside its body, and both had implants made of very rare metals. , such as Osmium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the news came out, it sparked heated discussions, and most netizens were skeptical:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It looks too human, so I don&#39;t believe it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Very It fits the human stereotype of aliens!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How is this different from the ones seen in science fiction movies? It looks very &#39;expected&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The universe is so It&#39;s really not surprising that there are aliens. It&#39;s just that the appearance of this alien is too consistent with the previous fantasy...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1052&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252810&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yong, a researcher at the National Space Science Center of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and aerospace science ambassador, said in an interview with Southern+ reporters that aliens The existence of is a &quot;probabilistic event&quot;. &quot;There are about 300 billion stars in the Milky Way alone, not to mention more than 2 trillion galaxies like the Milky Way in the universe, so alien life will exist even if the probability is very small.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for Mexico this time Liu Yong believed that the announcement of the remains was not credible and even &quot;nonsensical.&quot; In his opinion, on the one hand, there are many possible forms of aliens, but the possibility of them being like humans is very low; on the other hand, he believes that due to technical and other reasons, the possibility of humans finding aliens is very small at present. , only by developing from the &quot;Canoe Age&quot; to the &quot;Sailing Age&quot; can we discover further civilizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why are aliens and UFOs so popular? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Regardless of whether this is true or not, recently, news about aliens and UFOs at home and abroad have been flooding the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Mexico released the remains, in early August, a Harvard professor also claimed that he &quot;may have discovered evidence of extraterrestrial life.&quot; It is said that the team is analyzing the remaining fragments from the unidentified object that crashed into the Earth in 2014. The professor believes that the fragments contain remnants of alien technology and may have been modified. He and his team are compiling their findings into a paper that they hope to release publicly in about a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, on the evening of September 7, the Jinan Seven Star Observatory released a video showing a &quot;luminous falling&quot; UFO in the monitoring screen on September 6. On September 1st and 5th, the Seven Stars Observatory also photographed traces of UFOs twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Niu Guihua, vice chairman of the Shandong Astronomical Society and secretary-general of the Jinan Astronomical Society, believes that due to the existence of suspected power, we can only know that the UFO is not a falling object such as a meteor, but it is not clear what the actual object is. What. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252808&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Left picture: On September 13, 2023, local time, in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico, the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; were displayed at a hearing. Right picture: The movie &quot;ET&quot; &quot;The alien image in &quot;. Picture Source Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About a week later, on the evening of September 13, “UFO” became a “hot search” on Weibo again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weibo netizen &quot;Xiao Xiyu&quot; posted a video saying: &quot;Does anyone know what the two lights in the sky to the northwest of Caoxian County are? UFOs? When the video was recorded, the light pillars disappeared, and only this smoke remained. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many netizens said in the comment area that they had also seen the same UFO, with coordinates involving Beijing, Jiangsu, Shandong, Tianjin and other places, and posted photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are humans so fascinated by UFOs and aliens? Liu Yong believes that &quot;searching for extraterrestrial civilization&quot; has gone beyond a simple scientific issue and has become a philosophical issue. Exploring the mysteries of the universe and the origin of life may also be exploring people themselves and their meaning in the world and in the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, human beings are constantly accelerating their exploration of the universe. From the two &quot;Voyager&quot; detectors launched in 1977 to the &quot;China Sky Eye&quot; built in Guizhou, various detection methods have become more complete. Taking the &quot;China Sky Eye&quot; as an example, its experimental goals include receiving signals from extraterrestrial civilizations, pulsars, rapid electrical storms and other signals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in Liu Yong’s view, humans are still a long way from finding extraterrestrial civilizations. “Perhaps it will only be possible on a time scale of thousands or ten thousand years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[音乐家李海鹰：月光流淌在珠江上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021849850177&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;People Weekly Li Haiying&#39;s manuscript video.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/G8hfqzJQv3VepINkT0VCcndx1kDzyd2fW3QrQgrz .jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, in the Pearl River On Shazhou Ersha Island, Li Haiying is rehearsing the symphony &quot;China 1921&quot; composed by him. This composer has turned to the creation of large-scale musical works in recent years. In addition to the symphony he is rehearsing, he is also working on the music for a major TV series. When we walked into the rehearsal hall of the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra, it was like stepping into a flowing stream just as the orchestra was playing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When you walked in, you happened to reach the section about Guangzhou.&quot; Li Haiying said that a dozen meters away from the rehearsal hall is the Pearl River flowing eastward. The river flows further down, where he grew up when he was a child. place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As someone who grew up by the Pearl River, Li Haiying’s music has a strong sense of flow. Thirty years ago, he wrote &quot;Curved Moon&quot; and asked Liu Huan, who had a &quot;very floating voice&quot;, to sing it. He felt that the song had &quot;the feeling of being drenched by rain&quot;, even though the &quot;root-seeking craze&quot; was leading the culture at that time. world, &quot;Xintianyou&quot;, &quot;Nothing&quot;, etc. are blowing the northwest wind and sand throughout the mainland music scene. He also composed the music for &quot;Song of Seven Sons&quot;. In the song about Macau, he used the melody to simulate the crashing of the waves on the rocky shore. This song followed China&#39;s first lunar exploration satellite &quot;Chang&#39;e 1&quot; to space. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although I live in Beijing, many of my creative commissions are from Guangzhou.&quot; 69-year-old Li Haiying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Haiying&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Li Lewei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1970, 16-year-old Li Haiying Entered the Guangzhou Cantonese Opera Troupe and became a violinist and composer. Five years later, he became a violinist and creator of the Art Troupe of the Political Department of the Chinese Navy&#39;s South China Sea Fleet. From the end of 1982 to March 1997, he worked as a composer in the Guangdong Music and Art Troupe and wrote works such as &quot;The Crooked Moon&quot;, &quot;Song of the Seven Sons&quot; and &quot;I Don&#39;t Want to Say&quot;. He is good at integrating folk song elements into the melodies of popular music, so his works have a vivid sense of place, such as &quot;The Crooked Moon&quot; with Cantonese tune, &quot;Crossing the River&quot; with Northeastern duo style, and &quot;Crossing the River&quot; with Shandong music characteristics. Traveling everywhere”. He has also written a lot of pop music, such as Eason Chan&#39;s &quot;Where to Start&quot; and Sun Li&#39;s &quot;Love is Like Air&quot;, and has also scored for film and television works such as &quot;Bright Sword&quot; and &quot;The Devil Is Coming&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symphony has always been his dream. At the age of 49, Li Haiying began to study conducting under conductor and music educator Professor Xu Xin. At the age of 54, he re-learned composition lessons in the classroom of the Central Conservatory of Music. In his fifties, he re-learned and practiced conducting and composing music, and he sat in the classroom with undergraduate students. &quot;Actually, they are all very basic courses, just undergraduate courses.&quot; He is happy to learn and to be a newcomer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Li Haiying became a newcomer to the symphony orchestra. He wrote and conducted the large-scale symphony work &quot;Our Sun Yat-sen&quot;, plus later &quot;Ode to the Sixth Ancestor&quot;, &quot;Symphony No. 1 (Pearl River)&quot; and &quot; China 1921&quot;, he composed a total of four symphonic works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The grand historical themes are very concretely presented in Li Haiying&#39;s music. He uses different musical styles to correspond to different cities. He uses Peking Opera to depict Beijing, Dragon Boat Tune to depict Wuchang, and Changsha to use Flower Drum Opera. ...His music has always maintained a local feel, which may come from his familiarity with folk songs and his research into related content during creation. In the children&#39;s musical &quot;Cat God in the Forbidden City&quot;, Li Haiying did a lot of research in order to fully grasp the atmosphere of Beijing, hoping to use music to depict the history and modern vitality of a city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 2023, Li Haiying and the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra performed &quot;China 1921&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Li Lewei/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Li Haiying’s dictation:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Symphony and Pop: A Living Sense of Place&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Before this show, I actually had a day or two of anxiety. &quot;China 1921&quot; is premiering in 2021. It has been performed for the seventh time this year alone. Is there anything else I can do? Can I make the orchestra perform better this time? If I want to do an operation that is not innovative, then I simply don’t do it, so during this rehearsal I was still changing the music and deleting bars. Of course, these were things I thought up at home, not a sudden inspiration on the spot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the rehearsal, I had two roles, one was the composer and the other was the conductor. , equal to the player. When playing with an orchestra, I think about the music from another perspective and re-interpret the work. Moreover, you need to have an ability to make symphonies, and you need to have a strong memory. Just like playing blind chess, you have to remember the entire chessboard. This is also an ability that is constantly cultivated by making music. Basically, you have to memorize the music, and you also have to think about how to play it. Should it be more lively or soft? When I was a conductor, I had to modify some expression methods, and I also had to listen to the performance and make changes while performing, and I made a lot of adjustments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra commissioned this work from me in 2019, I didn’t expect that I would write such a long piece. For the work, Director Yu Long told me at the time that the first thing to do was to write a beautiful melody, and secondly to focus on the year 1921. I collected information based on this idea and found that from August 1920 to the spring of 1921, early organizations of the Communist Party of China were established in six cities: Shanghai, Beijing, Wuhan, Changsha, Guangzhou, and Jinan. At the same time, among the Chinese in Japan and France, early organizations of the Communist Party of China, composed of advanced elements among overseas students, were also established. Therefore, my earliest design was 9 movements, using 9 musical styles, describing the October Revolution and what happened in Beijing, Wuhan, Changsha, Jinan, Guangzhou, Shanghai, Japan, and France from 1920 to 1921 on the eve of the founding of the Communist Party of China. fragments of history. It was shortened to 5 parts according to the structure of the music, but it still consists of 9 paragraphs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first movement is a passionate Allegro, which describes the outbreak of the October Revolution and is called &quot;The Shock of the Earth&quot; . The second movement begins with a quiet Andante, including two sections: &quot;Beiping Flying Catkins&quot; and &quot;Wuchang Autumn Waters&quot;. The third movement is the waltz, &quot;Eastern Alley&quot; and &quot;Morning Light in Paris&quot;. The fourth movement is Chinese dance music, mainly about Changsha, Jinan and Guangzhou. The last movement came with the convening of the &quot;First Class&quot;. When I arrived in Beijing, I used Peking Opera. In Wuhan, I adapted Dragon Boat Opera. In Changsha, I used Huagu Opera. In the Jinan part, I created a Shandong tune. In the Guangzhou part, I can also hear many elements of Cantonese music. At the end, I used a method often used in symphonies - fugue, stacking different themes together, which symbolized the rolling torrents coming together to form a huge force rushing towards the end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is my fourth large-scale musical work. I am currently cooperating with the China Children&#39;s Art Theater The musical is called &quot;The Cat God in the Forbidden City&quot;. The previous owner of the Forbidden City is no longer there, and now the cat in the Forbidden City, &quot;Dorgon (the cat&#39;s name)&quot; is very popular on the Internet. I am full of expectations for this subject and am working hard to create it. The Forbidden City is a gathering place for Chinese culture. We want to promote Chinese culture, so we created a &quot;cat god&quot; of the Forbidden City. I hope that the writing will be more trendy, with many modern elements, but also contain Beijing culture, such as Beijing nursery rhymes, Beijing Qinshu, Pingju opera, etc. I think this is very important. What kind of works can be recognized by the public? First of all, it must have roots and learn from the best cultures around the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Creation still requires continuous learning. I feel that I am in the sprint period now, but I am also inert. I told those students that everyone goes down the path of inertia. You know this is a weakness of human nature, so you might as well try going the other way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Only through continuous creation can society accept me. At least for my musical collaborators, everyone’s expectation is that I will continue to improve. If one day I find that Li Haiying has stopped, the cooperation will basically be over. Only by constantly surprising others can I continue to make the music I want to do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Haiying&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Changing times中, the forever new musician&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, my ideal since I was a child is to be a symphony performer. In the 1980s, I went into the pop music industry. After rolling a few times, I also made film and television soundtracks, such as &quot;Bright Sword&quot;, &quot;Foreign Girl&quot;, &quot;Happiness Like Flowers&quot;, etc., and I also participated in &quot;The Devil Is Coming&quot;. In the end, I felt that I had to go back to my childhood dream and realize it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I was a child, I once played Saint-Saëns&#39;s &quot;Introduction and Rondo Caprice&quot; at home. It was the first time I was moved by symphony. My father used to be the deputy director of Guangzhou Huangpu Shipyard. Many engineers in the factory studied in the Soviet Union, and many of them like music. So my family had a record player in the 1950s. It played &quot;The Blue Danube&quot; and also played a lot of Cantonese music and Cantonese opera. My musical initiation was this record player and another Baltic radio. When I was about 14 years old, I forced my mother to buy me a Qinqin. As soon as I got the Qinqin home, I immediately played all the Cantonese music I had ever heard. Later, the radio was playing the music of the Red Detachment of Women, and I picked up the violin and played along. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I was 16 years old, the Guangzhou Cantonese Opera Troupe came to our school to recruit students, and I was selected because I was the only student in the school who could play music notation and a little violin. Later, I entered the composition training class of Guangzhou Xinghai Conservatory of Music for a year and a half. By the 1980s, some record companies came to me to do composing, which was equivalent to an invitation to write music, and I started to become a freelance musician from then on. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first time I wrote lyrics was for &quot;The Curved Moon&quot;, and I had a few notes first , then I wrote the music and lyrics overlapping each other, and I finished it in half an hour. At that time, what was popular in the music world was the high-pitched and hard-hitting &quot;Northwest Wind&quot;. &quot;Curved Moon&quot; was a typical Cantonese tune. I said it had the &quot;feeling of being drenched by rain.&quot; It was many years later that I realized that this song recorded the life of the Dan family who lived on boats on the Pearl River. It was not only the description of the words themselves, but also the rhythm of the song was the rhythm of the Dan family&#39;s oars. This inspiration comes from the fact that I lived by the Pearl River when I was a child. I crossed the river in a boat rowed by the Dan family. The Dan family even carried a baby on their backs and rowed the boat. The boat could seat four people. I was sitting on the boat and heard them calling Gillian. Gillian is the most common name for girls from the Dan family. It’s just that the Dan family can no longer be seen on the Pearl River. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I wrote this song, there was no commission from a music company, and I was not sure what I wanted to do. The singer comes to sing. The first person I found was Chen Rujia. After Chen Rujia came to record, I felt it was inappropriate as soon as I heard it, so I called Liu Huan and asked him if he was in Beijing and asked him to record the song tomorrow. Liu Huan didn&#39;t even listen to the song, so she agreed on the phone. I went to Beijing the next day, and he came to record in the afternoon. At that time, the commercial market based on stars had not yet formed, so the interaction with singers was that simple. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Guangdong in the 1980s and 1990s was also a golden age to some extent, because everything was It&#39;s new and changing with each passing day. Maybe everyone is nostalgic and feels that the past era was the golden age. In fact, the entire economic foundation was not at a very high level at that time, but the momentum and passion shown by people on the wave was quite rare. This wave played a great role in promoting Guangzhou. At that time, Guangzhou was not only in the music, but also in the media, such as TV stations, radio stations, newspapers, advertising, and film and television dramas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Huan&#39;s &quot;The Curved Moon&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Curved Moon&quot; was composed in the late 1980s, when the northwest wind was blowing fiercely in the music industry, so when everyone heard it, they felt that this song Why is it so special, so southern, so soft. Of course, most people accepted it quickly. Only a few people in the industry felt it was inappropriate and that it was different from the trend of the entire era. At that time, it was all about &quot;My Hometown Is Not Beautiful&quot; and the like. Behind this trend all point to the &quot;root-seeking craze&quot; in the 1980s, such as the oil painting &quot;Father&quot; and the movie &quot;Red Sorghum&quot;. All of these belong to the root-seeking culture, and everyone is digging into the soil. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because of Jiang Wen&#39;s movie &quot;The Devils Are Coming&quot;, I went from Guangzhou to Beijing to do the soundtrack. The filming has been completed and editing has begun. Cui Jian, Liu Xing, and I are responsible for the soundtrack. I didn&#39;t leave after arriving in Beijing that time, and began to devote more energy to film and television soundtracks. From &quot;Betrayal&quot;, &quot;Black Ice&quot; to &quot;Bright Sword&quot;, some people asked, why did you write the soundtracks for all the dramas? I didn&#39;t, it just happened to be those dramas that became popular. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After writing &quot;Song of the Seven Sons&quot;, I kept writing it for several years. Can&#39;t write well. A friend told me, Li Haiying, that you haven&#39;t released a song for a long time. His words made me realize that this is a problem. If you haven&#39;t had a popular song for a few years, people will think that your songs can&#39;t be released. Until the song &quot;Love is Like Air&quot;, I wrote the melody alone for a month and a half. It turned out well and became the theme song of the TV series &quot;Happiness is Like a Flower&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have always wanted to do symphony. Because of some work opportunities, I started to study with conductors in 2003 Teacher Xu Xin studies conducting. In 2007, I started to study composition systematically again. In 2008, a group of undergraduate students and I went to the Central Conservatory of Music to take classes. Once the head of the composition department of the Central Conservatory of Music stopped me and said, Li Haiying, what are you doing here? I said go to class. He said, who are you taking classes with? Don&#39;t be a bad learner. If you are a bad learner, it will be over. I still attend class honestly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From Cantonese opera, Cantonese music, pop music, to film and television soundtracks, to symphony, I am interested in music Always have something fresh, always be a newcomer. Times are turbulent, and I often do other things before the tide recedes. For example, I was doing film and television soundtracks, and later I was doing classical music. I didn’t wait until the wave ended and left me desperate, so I left long ago. I am a newbie in classical music calculation, and it was only in 2016 that I started writing large-scale works. As long as I maintain this state of learning, humility, and devotion, including now writing musicals and operas, I also hope to be innovative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Music is written directly for people, it is a dialogue. Another point is that I do not advocate my own ideas. I will write your thoughts and feelings. Everyone feels that artists always emphasize themselves, but why do they separate &quot;I&quot; and &quot;you&quot;? I thought I was unimportant, I had long known that I was limited. This concept may make me seem very personalityless on the surface, but the more I go on, the more I feel that my music is not about me. What my music wants to express is this era, and it is about you and them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[铜绿山，大地深处的楚国秘密]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Climb up the steep steps. At the top of the mountain, there is a flat area. On the flat side, I saw that long-known plant. It is not eye-catching, slightly similar to the common broom grass in Sichuan, but shorter; it is also a bit like orchid grass, but with thinner leaves. It has not yet reached the flowering period, and there is no purple-red color like the clouds in the picture. If you look closely, it does look like a toothbrush. No wonder it is called toothbrush grass among the people. In fact, its scientific name is Haizhou Xiangnuo, and its other name is more widely known: Copper Grass Flower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine how excited the ancestors who were looking for it were when they saw the coppergrass flowers all over the mountains and plains on this gentle hillside three thousand years ago. They were even ecstatic with excitement. Because the copper grass flower is a symbol of an important metal - wherever it grows, deep in the earth, there must be copper mines...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/5ofLItqyHH0Tl7WRalCsMJW6VkUfNdzcaSj4GY5C.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/10/28/5ofLItqyHH0Tl7WRalCsMJW6VkUfNdzcaSj4GY5C.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tonglushan ancient copper mine site is located in Three kilometers west of Daye City, Hubei Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Gifts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The banquet was over, and King Chu Cheng gave it to those who came to see him Zheng Wengong gave a generous gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This generous gift is estimated to be worth about 20,000 to 30,000 yuan based on today&#39;s market price. However, in the distant Spring and Autumn Period, its value could not be measured in terms of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is copper. When Zheng Wengong returned to Zheng State with a thousand kilograms of copper, King Chu Cheng regretted it more and more. He sent an envoy to catch up with Zheng Wengong - he must have wanted to take back the copper, but doing so would not only offend Zheng State, but also make people in the world joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Chu Cheng’s regret had very clear practical considerations. In the pre-Qin period, the ancients classified the major affairs of the country into two things, namely &quot;the major affairs of the country are sacrifice and military affairs&quot; as stated in &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. Although the original meaning of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; refers to sacrificial rituals and military rituals, later generations further extended it and believed that the most important things in the country were sacrifices and wars. Both sacrifices and wars are inseparable from copper - sacrifices require a large number of bronze vessels to be cast; as for wars, copper is a necessity for making weapons. Compared with the stone, bone and wooden weapons of the Stone Age, copper weapons are invincible and have unparalleled superiority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bronze originated in the Longshan Culture period. The Xia Dynasty began to enter the Bronze Age, while the Shang Dynasty and Zhou Dynasty reached the peak of bronze civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called bronze is an alloy of copper and tin or lead. It was called gold and lucky gold in ancient China. Among the chemical elements that make up bronze, the most important is copper, which accounts for more than 80%. Without copper, there would be no bronze; without bronze, there would be no bronze civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For King Chu Cheng, his regret was not about the thousand catties of copper. Copper, he had plenty of it. He was worried that Zheng Guo would take the copper back to make weapons. Therefore, he asked Zheng Wengong to promise that the copper donated by the Chu State could only be used for ritual vessels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to the origins of Chu State, it was once so humble that it could be ignored. In terms of level, among male princes, Bozi belongs to the fourth level: Zi. Regarding the initial land enfeoffment, it was only fifty miles away. There is a story that illustrates the weakness of the Chu people when they founded the country: After Xiong Yi was named the son of Chu, he built a temple. After the temple was completed and the first sacrifice was about to be held, it was discovered that they were so poor that they didn&#39;t even have a sacrificial cow. This &quot;country&quot; is so big, but it can&#39;t even produce a single cow, which shows how small and shabby this &quot;country&quot; is. Out of poverty, Xiong Yi took people to the neighboring country of Bo to steal a calf. After the calf was stolen back, Xiong Yi was afraid that the owner would come to visit him, so he had to kill the calf overnight to sacrifice it - and the rules at that time were that sacrifices were held during the day. Since then, the Chu people have formed a unique custom: all sacrifices are held at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like a trickle of water can gather into a mighty river, as long as enough time is given, a miracle may be born. For the Chu State, if it was like an unobtrusive flame in the wind when it was founded, then, after hundreds of years of continuous development, by the time of Xiong Tong, the son of Chu in the early Spring and Autumn Period, the Chu State had risen. Become an important presence among the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 704 BC, which was the thirty-seventh year of Xiong Tong&#39;s reign, he sent his followers to ask the Emperor of Zhou to promote him to a noble title. However, Emperor Zhou flatly refused. Xiong Tong was furious and proclaimed himself king, calling him King Wu of Chu. Although the Emperor of Zhou has lost his former authority since King Ping of Zhou moved eastward, the princes who dared to brag against the disapproval of the world and claim the title of king began with Xiong Tong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiong Tong dared to fight against the Emperor Zhou. On the one hand, due to the hard work of more than ten generations, the Chu State was no longer the small country with a lot of obstacles; on the other hand, after many years of hard work, the Chu people gradually controlled One of the most important strategic materials has the material basis to challenge Emperor Zhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is copper, copper from the Coppergreen Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/HnrOGxJiZOSdrgXR10zG7Zpr8MN4jXcLRwGTIToa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/HnrOGxJiZOSdrgXR10zG7Zpr8MN4jXcLRwGTIToa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Azurite mine in Tonglu Mountain&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the northeast To the southwest, after crossing the Yangtze River via the Qijia Expressway, it enters Huangshi City, Hubei Province. To the north of the highway, there is a lake of tens of square kilometers, which is Daye Lake connected to the Yangtze River. The westernmost end of Daye Lake is Daye under the jurisdiction of Huangshi. Heading west out of Daye, the road twists and turns, passing through undulating low mountainous areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tonglu Mountain is hidden deep in this low mountainous area. The &quot;Daye County Chronicle&quot; published by Tongzhi in the Qing Dynasty explained the origin of the name Tonglu Mountain: &quot;The top of the mountain is high and flat, with huge rocks facing each other. Every time it rains, there are bronze greens like snowflakes and adzuki beans dotted on the earth and rocks. Hence the name. It stretches for several years. Zhang, the soil color is purple and red, and they are all Guanshan. It may be the place where copper was produced in ancient times.&quot; This green snowflake adzuki bean is actually malachite, which is a copper-containing carbonate mineral that is often associated with copper. The large amount of malachite washed out of the surface after a shower shows that the copper mine in Tonglushan is shallowly buried and of high grade, making it a rare rich mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as China is concerned, copper resources are widely distributed and relatively concentrated. In general, the main copper mines are in the south. There is a rich copper ore belt in the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River - from Tonglu Mountain to Ruichang, more than 100 kilometers away, and to Tongling, more than 300 kilometers away, there are dots of large copper mines, with reserves accounting for one-third of the country. Two or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of Chu State was also invincible due to the blessing of Tonglu Mountain. As the first metal mastered by human beings, a steady stream of high-grade copper ore is put into burning furnaces to smelt out massive amounts of copper, which is then combined with tin or lead to be upgraded to bronze - ritual vessels cast in bronze, lingering in the smoke. The temples made of bronze became a bridge between the Chu people and their ancestors and gods; the agricultural tools made of bronze allowed the vast land in the south to be reclaimed, and more food was enough to feed a larger population; the weapons made of bronze accompanied the Chu people who were brave and good at fighting. Charge into battle, expand territory...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conquest&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from Tonglu Mountain, a three-hour drive, nearly 300 kilometers away to the northwest is Suizhou City, Hubei Province. In Suizhou, the sensational tomb of Zeng Houyi was discovered. The most important cultural relic unearthed from the tomb of Zeng Houyi is now stored in the Hubei Provincial Museum, which is the bronze chime that can still play beautiful music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Hou is the king of Zeng State; and Zeng State is another name for Sui State, which was enfeoffed by Zhou Dynasty. Thousands of cultural relics were unearthed from the tomb of Marquis Yi of Zeng, among which the total weight of bronze products exceeds ten tons - the bronze chime alone weighs four tons. So much copper, where does it come from? In the past few years, professionals used chemical and spectral analysis on Zeng Houyi&#39;s chime bell, and compared it with the copper mine data unearthed from the Tonglushan archeology, and concluded that the copper material of Zenghou Yi&#39;s chime bell came from Tonglushan. ——Using the same method, it was also proved that the raw materials of the bronzes unearthed from Fuhao&#39;s tomb in Yinxu, Anyang, also came from Tonglu Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/BUDkuuqJntNhn6I4gZ4OhMcUTYdeKFDanhoC1Wnb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/BUDkuuqJntNhn6I4gZ4OhMcUTYdeKFDanhoC1Wnb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Houyi Bronze Chime Bell&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These conclusions are actually Within reason. Not only did the large amount of copper material in the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi come from the Tonglu Mountain, but even when the Emperor of Zhou was enfeoffed to follow the country, a very important reason was for copper. During the Shang and Zhou dynasties, there was a busy and important copper-tin road in the hinterland of China. That is what the bronze inscriptions call &quot;the path of gold and tin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the National Museum of China, there is a bronze vessel named Zeng Boyun. The 簠 is a utensil used to serve rice during sacrifices or banquets. It is also called the 簋, the square one is called 簠 and the round one is called 簋. Zeng Boyun was used by the king of Zeng (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sui&lt;/span>;). The inscription on it contains the following sentences: &quot;...Kedi Huaiyi, suppress the Xiefan Tang, move the golden road and tin, and use all the tools to prepare the way.&quot; It means: (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zeng Bo&lt;/span>;) punish the Huaiyi , the transportation hub Fantang and the copper and tin channels have been stabilized and have returned to normal. This is the origin of Jindaoxixing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shang Dynasty moved its capital many times, but generally speaking, they were all in today&#39;s Central Plains region; the Western Zhou Dynasty made its capital Haojing, now Xi&#39;an; the Eastern Zhou Dynasty moved its capital to Luoyi, now Luoyang. During the heyday of the Bronze Age, the demand for copper and supporting tin for thousands of years during the Shang and Zhou dynasties was undoubtedly astronomical. In the vast north or the Yellow River Basin, only Zhongtiao Mountain and other places had copper mines, but the output was small. . The copper and tin needed by the Shang and Zhou Dynasties could only be transported thousands of miles from the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The general route of the Jindao Tin Line, which mainly transports copper and tin, is as follows: Hunan&#39;s tin and Tonglu Mountains and northern Jiangxi&#39;s copper, after being collected in the present-day Wuhan area, arrive in Suizhou via Xiaogan, along the Suizao Corridor. It entered the Nanyang Basin, then passed through present-day Fangcheng and Ye County to Luoyang, or continued westward to Guanzhong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an extremely difficult transportation line. Two or three thousand years ago, when roads and railways were scarce and there were only rugged trails, the ancients could only rely on animals and manpower in addition to ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long transportation lines mean more risks and more uncertainties. Especially when the transported items are copper that determines the fate of the country, the risks increase sharply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to ensure the smooth transportation of copper and tin from Tonglu Mountain and other places to the capital, Emperor Zhou enfeoffed more than a dozen small countries in important areas north of the Han River and south of the upper reaches of the Huai River. Most of these small countries have the surname Ji, or are related to the surname Ji, so they are called the Ji of Hanyang. The concubines of Hanyang had two tasks. One was to guard against Huaiyi in the south; the other was to ensure the smooth flow of the copper and tin road. After the decline of Huaiyi and the rise of Chu, the first task of Zhu Ji changed from guarding against Huaiyi to guarding against Chu. However, things are unpredictable. Not only did the concubines of Hanyang fail to curb Chu&#39;s northward and eastward advance, but even the copper-tin road they guaranteed and even the Tonglu Mountain that produced copper mines fell into the hands of the Chu people. In the end, &quot;Hanyang&quot; All concubines, the state of Chu is complete.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The countries established by the concubines of Hanyang are dotted in the intersection of north and south China, including Tang, Cai, Ying, Xi, Shen, Sui, etc. Among the concubines, Sui Guo is the most powerful and is the leader of them all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanyang Basin and Jianghan Plain are separated by a series of low and gentle mountains. Among them, there is a long and narrow plain between Dahong Mountain and Tongbai Mountain, both running northwest to southeast, which becomes the link between Nanyang Basin and Jianghan Plain. traffic channels between. This tunnel is bounded by Suizhou in the south and Zaoyang in the north, so it is called the Suizao Corridor. As the eldest among the concubines in Hanyang, Sui Guo follows the gateway of the Zao Corridor and connects to the Yangtze River through the Jianshui River. Copper from Tonglu Mountain and more distant places such as Ruichang and Tongling can be traced up the river, passing through the Sui Zao Corridor and then north. Transport to the Central Plains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/27/0db5OdAetgUKAOX0yDkVnWKje30RWBDgAHTMIkrd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1331&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/27/0db5OdAetgUKAOX0yDkVnWKje30RWBDgAHTMIkrd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The war between the Chu State and the Chu State for the Tonglu Mountain was The era of King Wu kicked off; the main target of the war was Sui Guo - before this, King Wu of Chu annexed Quan State and established counties in Quan State&#39;s territory, which was the beginning of China&#39;s county system. At this time, the power of the Chu State penetrated deep into the Jianghan Plain, and the fertile Jianghan Plain was being eroded bit by bit by the Chu people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the set goal, King Chu Wu showed great patience - he has been waiting, looking for opportunities while waiting - King Chu Wu waited from his middle age until his twilight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 706 BC, Sui suffered from a drought, resulting in a massive reduction in grain production and a lack of food for the soldiers and civilians. King Wu of Chu took the opportunity to attack Sui. The Chu army came to the city, and the princes knew that they were no match, so they had to send people to King Wu of Chu to ask for peace. King Wu of Chu accepted the peace talks, and one of the conditions was that he would ask the Emperor of Zhou to be promoted to the title of Chu Kingdom. The first expedition against Sui and the establishment of an alliance under the city with the country meant that the Chu people had already gotten involved in the road of copper and tin, and from then on they could obtain a steady stream of high-quality copper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, Sui, who had an alliance with Chu, refused to attend the alliance led by Chu. King Chu Wu used this as an excuse to attack Sui for the second time. This time, the Chu army was defeated and the Sui army fled. Even the chariot was captured by the Chu army. Also in this year, Suihou informed King Wu of Chu that the Emperor of Zhou refused to promote him to the title. Therefore, King Wu of Chu became angry and proclaimed himself king. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next three years, Chu State defeated a series of countries including Yun State, Jiu State, Zhou State, Deng State and Liao State. These countries either became vassals of Chu State or had to fight with Chu State. Make an alliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in 699 BC, when attacking Luo State, Chu State general Qu Xia was conceited and underestimated the enemy. He was defeated by the coalition forces of Luo State and Lu State. Qu Xia committed suicide. ——Since then, the Chu State has formed an unwritten rule: any commander who leads troops to fight must commit suicide to apologize once he is defeated. This determination, soaked in the bones and blood of Chu people, was passed down to the last commander-in-chief, Xiang Yu, the overlord of Western Chu who would rather commit suicide than return to Jiangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Wu of Chu had to slow down his campaign. For the next eight years, King Wu of Chu did not raise any more troops to attack his followers. He concentrated his efforts and swept away Luo, Lu, Yan, Zhou and Liao, and firmly controlled the Jianghan Plain. It should be during this period that the Tonglu Mountain also belonged to the Chu State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When everything came to pass, King Wu of Chu attacked him for the third time. Because Suiguo is not only an important stronghold on the copper-tin road, but also a springboard for Chu to fight for hegemony northward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of the expedition, he felt heart discomfort during the sacrifice and knew that his days were numbered. Sure enough, when the Chu army crossed the Han River and King Wu of Chu was sitting under a sycamore tree by the roadside to rest, he could never stand up again - this king who advocated force and was determined to expand his territory died like this. On the journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of King Chu Wu, the Chu army continued to advance towards the capital of Sui without announcing the funeral. When Suihou saw the army approaching the border, he was frightened and sent people to sue for peace. From then on, Suiguo, who was originally loyal to the Emperor of Zhou and monitored the south for the Emperor of Zhou and guarded the copper and tin road, became a vassal of Chu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of King Chu Wu, King Chu Wen came to the throne. The first thing King Wen of Chu did when he came to power was to move the capital from the remote Danyang to Ying. The Chu State had moved its capital many times. After the first move to Ying, the subsequent capitals were all called Ying or Yingdu. The place where King Wen of Chu moved to Ying is said to be Jingzhou or Yicheng. No matter who is right, the indisputable fact is that the power of Chu State has crossed the Han River from west to east. During the reign of King Chu Wen, he successively destroyed the State of Shen, Xi and Deng, repeatedly defeated the State of Cai, and made a northern expedition to the State of Zheng - this was also the beginning of the Chu State&#39;s quest to dominate the Central Plains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After King Chu Wen, King Chu Cheng went to a higher level and successively annexed more than ten small countries such as Er, Gu, Huang, Ying, Jiang, and Fang. The State of Zheng, which borders the State of Chu, was on the fence between Jin and Chu. This is how Zheng Wengong went to see King Chu Cheng, and King Chu Cheng gave him a thousand catties of copper. However, King Chu Cheng was born at the wrong time - he met Duke Huan of Qi, the most powerful of the Five Hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period. In order to teach the Chu State a lesson, Qi Huangong led the coalition forces deep into the Chu territory. Although the two sides did not decide the winner, the Chu State had to admit its mistake to the coalition forces and recognize Qi State&#39;s dominance. By the time of King Chuzhuang, the grandson of King Chu Cheng, this soaring and blockbuster King of Chu defeated the northern superpower Jin, thus becoming one of the five hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The history of the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period is a history of princes fighting against each other. In the merger of big fish eating small fish and small fish eating shrimps, small countries continued to disappear and big countries grew bigger like a snowball. Among the princes, the Chu State destroyed the most, with more than fifty people. At its peak, Chu State ranked first in territory, equivalent to the sum of other princes. It can be said that if it were not for the incompetence of several generations of Chu kings in the late Warring States Period, it would have been more likely to be the Chu State that wiped out the heroes, rather than the Qin State located in the northwest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the Chu people’s illustrious military exploits, Tonglu Mountain was the silent and lasting first driving force, creating the miracles of the Bronze Age. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ruins&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Tonglushan Ancient Copper Mine Ruins Museum is located on the hill where coppergrass flowers sway. There are few tourists, and the copper grass flowers are looking at themselves in the wind. On the other side of the hill, I saw a huge pit like a funnel embedded between the peaks. The pit sank hundreds of meters below the surface and was hundreds of meters in diameter. A road winding like a snake passed by a factory with thick smoke. Reaching into the pit, trucks crawled like beetles. This is the open-pit copper mine that is still being mined today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/9uJBUw2mJkQOkjCfGS5hm1oryhTPWo0UgpL6g2iZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1441&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/9uJBUw2mJkQOkjCfGS5hm1oryhTPWo0UgpL6g2iZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213166&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tonglushan Open-pit Copper Mine&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1973, the It was while working in this open-pit mine that the miners of the Nonferrous Metallurgical Company dug out thirteen rusty copper axes from the ground. Later, using thirteen copper axes that had been dormant for thousands of years as clues, archaeologists followed the clues and unearthed seven open-pit mines, 18 underground mining areas, more than 50 ancient smelting sites and More than ten smelting shaft furnaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reappearance of ancient copper mines under the earth not only reveals the secret of the rise of Chu State, but also proves that Chinese bronze culture is not foreign, but originated from the mainland. Archaeological evidence shows that the mining of Tonglushan copper mines began in the late Shang Dynasty, and continued through the Western Zhou Dynasty, the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period to the Han Dynasty, which lasted for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the museum, large and small copper slags are displayed in glass cabinets - things that look either slightly yellow or slightly green. Archaeologists estimate that there are as many as 400,000 tons of copper slag in the entire Tonglushan site. Based on rough calculations based on copper slag, Tonglushan produces about 120,000 tons of copper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The figure of 120,000 tons is a bit empty. If you convert it, you will know how huge it is: the Shang Dynasty Stepmother Wu Ding unearthed in Anyang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Simuwu Dafang Ding&lt;/span>;) is the heaviest bronze in China so far, weighing more than 800 kilograms. 120,000 tons can be used to cast 140,000 statues. Some people have made another calculation: the main equipment of soldiers in the Spring and Autumn Period was copper ge, each weighing about half a kilogram and 120,000 tons, enough to make 240 million pieces. Of course, not all of the 120,000 tons of copper from Tonglu Mountain is exclusively owned by the Chu State. However, in the mining history of more than a thousand years from the late Shang Dynasty to the Western Han Dynasty, Chu State accounted for about half of the mining time. This was the golden age of Tonglu Mountain. The Chu people obtained at least tens of thousands of tons of high-quality copper from the depths of Tonglu Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When King Zhuang of Chu aspired to conquer the Central Plains, he proudly said to Wang Sunman, a minister of Emperor Zhou, &quot;The beak of Chu&#39;s broken hook is enough to make nine tripods.&quot; This means that as long as the sharp edges of Chu&#39;s weapons are taken off, it will be enough to be melted into Jiuding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The massive amount of copper in Tonglu Mountain proves that King Chuzhuang was not exaggerating at all. His Chu country, whether it is the civil governance of the alliance princes or the martial arts of conquering cities and territories; whether it is the stubborn and domineering character of the Chu people or the Chu music of Hong Zhongda Lu; whether it is the gloomy Chu Feng that respects ghosts or the soul-stirring Chu Ci—— They are all based on copper, with copper as their bones, and with copper as their foundation...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10 /28/TngRunAON2E2ufuol8qlegxPuW9w8r9SziHNBJWV.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/TngRunAON2E2ufuol8qlegxPuW9w8r9SziHNBJWV. jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;213164&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Viewers look at the early Spring and Autumn shaft furnace model unearthed from Tonglu Mountain in the National Museum of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tonglu Mountain, those long-standing mines go deep underground and extend in all directions like a maze. Some of the wood that was laid down two to three thousand years ago to support the tunnels has not yet rotted. Walking cautiously in the restored mine, the tunnel is narrow and damp. I can&#39;t help but think of the Chu miners who worked all day long with a torch in the belly of the earth in Tonglu Mountain more than 2,000 years ago. Whether they are swinging a heavy copper ax to hit the hard rock formation, or dragging a bamboo basket full of copper ore along the tunnel, the labor day after day and year after year makes them like worker bees dying. The power and glory of the Chu State, the hegemony of King Wu and King Wen, and the grand plans of King Cheng and Zhuang, they have contributed a lot, but history will not leave their names. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Main reference books: &quot;Historical Records&quot;, &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Chu History&quot;, &quot;A Brief History of Chu State&quot;, &quot;Spring and Autumn History&quot; China&#39;s Pre-Qin Copper Mines&quot; &quot;Metallurgical Archeology&quot; &quot;Chinese Bronze&quot; &quot;Loess and Bronze&quot; &quot;Daye County Chronicles&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访陈冲：我没有强大的自信，只有强大的欲望]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 09/22/wZhQcinkVpws8y7jI3ZKp7XYc6l6VWrqUGmQWVtU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1439&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/wZhQcinkVpws8y7jI3ZKp7XYc 6l6VWrqUGmQWVtU. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;209385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1981, Chen Chong studied film production in the United States and directed his first film in 1998 &quot;Heavenly Bath&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an actor, Chen Chong is well known, and as a director, Chen Chong is well known. few. Chen Chong is one of the three directors of the movie &quot;Her in the World&quot; to be released on September 9, 2022, the other two are Sylvia Chang and Li Shaohong. The film tells an emotional story under difficult circumstances, involving mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, couples and lovers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2020, Chen Chong received a call from producer Dong Wenjie, hoping to invite several well-known female directors to jointly shoot a movie. She finally decided to tell the story of a pair of lovers separated in two places, &quot;to explore the closest expression of the oldest theme of love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like all previous works she directed, Chen Chong wrote the script herself. She repeatedly looked at the real photos taken by her colleagues. There was a supermarket scene in the movie, so she found many supermarket CCTVs and watched them, wanting to know details such as the denseness of the crowds. The script was originally written to rain, and the rendering of rain was used to increase the atmosphere, but later she learned that there was no rain in reality on the day set in the movie, so she removed this setting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Without the rain, wouldn&#39;t the story have happened? Wouldn&#39;t the feelings be conveyed? So, whether there is rain or not is not important, but whether there is the conveyance of emotions is important.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Her in the World&quot; was originally scheduled to be released on the May Day holiday in 2021, but was later postponed to the Mid-Autumn Festival in 2022. During the editing of the film, a Southern Weekend staff writer interviewed Chen Chong in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Love and loss are eternal&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;The setting of this movie sounds a bit like Love in the Time of Cholera. When you were approaching this story, did you have a clear setting from the beginning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After receiving the invitation from the producer, I searched online for a week and finally found this story about lovers who were exiled in two places. Touched me. The girl returned to Beijing to visit her parents during the Spring Festival, but she has not been able to see her boyfriend who was locked down in Wuhan since then. This melody of love, loss, and exile resonated with me—I too am unable to travel home to visit my elderly parents due to the pandemic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For lovers who are blocked in two cities, the mobile phone screen is something that arouses their infinite desire and is warmer than real life. In fact, this is also the relationship between most people and their mobile phones. Especially during the epidemic, people’s interactions with others and their understanding of the world come from mobile phones. The contradictions and conflicts in human nature also come from people&#39;s different interpretations of online messages. We all seem to be living on isolated islands in our mobile phones. The more attractive &quot;reality&quot; on the screen seems more &quot;real&quot; than life itself. The themes of love and loss, life and death are ancient and timeless, and my challenge was to give it a new screen narrative for today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you ever considered adding a paragraph about their love history? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Absolutely no flashbacks. This story is that these two people are always in different frames, and it wants you to be deeply moved by them. These are the rules I set for myself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the era of the epidemic, two people can only use mobile phones What love words can a lover say during a video call? What excites you about the process of writing a screenplay? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Their conversations are actually very simple conversations, the most daily and common conversations. My husband and I often do this too. Video communication. These two people are in love. They video chat when they wake up in the morning, before going to bed at night, and while cooking and brushing teeth. They chat casually in separate places, but it makes people feel the joy and love of two people together. , this is my excitement point. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the emotional tone expressed in this story? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a story about true love. If a person can love like this once, he is very lucky. Not everyone can love like this. Because he has had real happiness, and the sadness of loss is sublimated into the beauty in the black mirror. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people in the world are actually not satisfied with love in their hearts. So I believe it, but the desire and demand for love still seems very strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After we finished filming, several of the main creators climbed Xiangshan Mountain. After climbing to the top, they saw many people writing blessing signs. . I said let’s hang one too, and we wrote our blessings for the movie and hung it there. I looked through it carefully, and there were hundreds of tags, and there were countless love words in them. They were all &quot;So-and-so loves so-and-so&quot; and &quot;So-and-so will be with so-and-so forever.&quot; More than half of them, you can Did you say that love is gone? impossible. When you fall in love, can you stop yourself? Even this bit of vitality is gone, and your life has been in vain. This thing is different from desire. It is really a gift from God to you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Princess Sissi is the Empress of Austria. She has extremely happy resources and unlimited money, and her husband loves her very much. He has worshiped her and been obsessed with her all his life, but she is not happy. I don’t know how the paradox in life is formed. Is love the greatest value of happiness in life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this is a gift. You don’t need to be good enough or work hard. You don’t need to do your homework. You don’t need to move bricks. You don&#39;t need anything, it will come to you. Maybe love won&#39;t be important in the future, I don&#39;t know, I can&#39;t imagine it. Why refuse such a gift? I can&#39;t imagine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The role starring Yi Yang Qianxi, at the beginning Is it just set at the age of two or three years after graduating from college? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Absolutely. We met in college, have been in love for four years, and are about to get married. He is the happiest young man after graduating from college. period. The simplest dream of having this simple college sweetheart is to get married, the girl can wear a wedding dress, and the boy can put a ring on her. The definition of disaster is when the simplest dreams are destroyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From a distant perspective, love is a An ordinary story is about a man and a woman falling in love. Your film is set in a specific time and space. What happened in this love story? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, movies are such a thing. There is no need to make sense, and there is no reason to make love. It’s not that you think this person is a good match for this person, that has nothing to do with it. I&#39;m going to give you something that I believe you will believe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/AyDbJY0ejP1bgC5wplwp0rFOdfYLmKYPeg1imHQZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1439&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/AyDbJY0ejP1bgC5wplwp0rFOdfYLmKYPeg1imHQZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;209384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Chong directed a short film in &quot;Her in the World&quot;, telling the story of a pair of lovers who were separated in two places during the epidemic. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I can see clues of my dishonesty”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you studied directing in the United States? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I studied TV production and took some directing classes, but that directing class was completely useless. In fact, film is an apprenticeship, and film school comes later. When the movie first started, everyone was learning on the spot, apprentice-style. The kind of learning from a master should be more useful. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You directed the first film &quot;Tianba&quot; When you were young, you cut it yourself. By then, did you already have strong confidence to complete it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no strong self-confidence, only strong desire. I&#39;m not a particularly confident person, and self-doubt is a big part of my thinking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But outsiders see that you have many successes, which proves that you Be qualified to do it yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will always think that it is a coincidence, that it is a misunderstanding, that it confuses people. I think so, In fact, this may be the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you ever gone to the cinema to watch your own movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Very few. I&#39;ve seen it, but it&#39;s quite unbearable. I actually have a very sensitive radar. I can see the clues of my own dishonesty. Maybe others can’t see it, but I can definitely see it. So watching your own movies is not an easy task. Movies are not a tool for actors, but for directors, so you are a pawn in it, and if you see your own problems, it does not affect your feeling that the movie is pretty good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The films you directed are all because of yourself Do you have the desire to create, or do you have to find funds or outside sources? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Both. If funds come to me and I don’t have the desire, I will definitely not go. Because being a director is quite hard for me and not an easy thing. I am not a genius director, nor am I a technical director. I have limited talent and limited skills. If I don’t have a strong narrative desire, then I simply can’t do this. So you must have a strong narrative desire to do it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The movies you direct are all written by yourself ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I must, because it is not difficult for me. Of course I hope to get opinions and tips from like-minded creators, as well as a lot of information that everyone has worked on together, because I think information is the best thing for me to write a script. But the script is actually the movie I see in my mind when I close my eyes. I write it down first, and it will definitely change after all the main creators come in. But the first thing you write down is the movie you see in your head, so it&#39;s not that difficult. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When was the first time you stood on the Oscar stage? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;The Last Emperor&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did you feel a great sense of satisfaction at that moment? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, when I was young, I didn’t particularly care about work or these things. I only cared about falling in love. In fact, work gives me a chance to buffer, and it saves me from the whirlpool of emotions time and time again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said that your main business at that time was negotiating When you are in love, do you now feel that those times were a waste? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No waste. I don’t know what is wasteful. It may be a bit wasteful to keep doing things you don’t want to do. For example, if you are in love, if you do something you want to do, but that thing is ridiculous or wrong, or it brings you a lot of losses, I think it still cannot be considered a waste. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you ever been on stage? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t dare. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because I am afraid of crowds, I am especially afraid of crowds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is true that Chinese domestic movies rarely look older Do you have a female character with a solid concept? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Very few, too few, especially in the current film culture, which advocates youth, and the requirements and standards for women are still... You know it. Your richness, your soul, your complexity, it does not have a carrier, because your body is not accepted, where does it find its home? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you subconsciously try to please female audiences when making movies? , consider what they think, and not offend them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Your responsibility is to be honest, your responsibility is not to please, your responsibility should be to express yourself. When I make movies, I never think about the fact that I should make movies about women. I don’t have that burden. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;If you put this scene in a reality show, no matter how you perform it, it will be like chewing wax&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Media reporters sometimes subconsciously connect your characters, such as Wanrong and Hong Rose. Maybe those strong people in the characters who can fight for their own rights think that They are feminist heroes, do you have that connection? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was playing Wan Rong or in &quot;Red Rose and White Rose&quot;, or in Jiang Wen&#39;s movie, I never thought about women. Rights, women&#39;s status, women&#39;s anything, were never considered. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You filmed &quot;Red Roses and White Roses&quot; Did you like Zhang Ailing when you were young? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I like Zhang Ailing, but I am not a Zhang fan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Who do you like among female writers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Marguerite Duras, who wrote &quot;The Lover&quot; and &quot;Gone with the Wind&quot; are some old ones, and Polish author Olga Tokarczuk is the 2018 Nobel Prize-winning writer. I especially like &quot;Fireworks in March&quot; written by Li Bihua. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lu Wei talks about the movie &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot; , Li Bihua’s original novel is a second-rate novel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes a first-class novel really cannot change a movie. If you think about it, it is already first-class, what else can you do to it? It just takes second- and third-rate talent to turn it into a movie and take it to a higher level. I don&#39;t really like Li Bihua&#39;s books, but I read &quot;Fireworks in March&quot; and was very shocked. A friend gave it to me and I started reading it on the train. When I got to pages 60 and 70, I said it was a bit difficult and this was a bit too painful. She said if you persist, you will be rewarded. I persisted in reading it, and it was a great reward. Only long novels can give you such a sense of satisfaction. You can&#39;t get it anywhere else. It&#39;s satisfying but also regretful at the same time. Why did you finish reading it? It&#39;s so good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You wrote that when your daughter was 9 years old, The birthday gifts you want are books and swimming. Is this tradition of reading a result of your family environment when you were a child? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, when I was a kid, I didn’t have many books or anything interesting to read. My grandma has a small box, which contains some things brought back from abroad, including some comic books and other biographies of Dong Cunrui and Jiao Yulu. There are actually very few things to read. My grandmother had a set of Chekhov&#39;s short stories, but they were no longer complete at that time, so I read them piecemeal. Because they like to read, and I also like to read. My mother stopped me from reading at that time because she thought it was not good and it was better to do some homework, do housework, and go out to play. My mother is a medical scientist. After retirement, she only reads novels. She likes to read novels. In the past two days, I have been looking at her bookshelf, which contains a wide range of Chinese and foreign books, including Wang Anyi, Chi Li, Chen Zhongshi, Nabokov&#39;s &quot;Lolita&quot; and Hemingway&#39;s &quot;The Old Man and the Sea&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is your own reading like? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no standard thing. I have read some romance novels, for example. I was shocked when I read Marquez&#39;s book. My English was not good at that time. Not long after I arrived in the United States, I was very tired from reading &quot;One Hundred Years of Solitude&quot;. I couldn&#39;t look it up in the dictionary and explain it to you with just one click. I was very confused. Tired and very slow. I was shocked. Is this what the book says? So it’s very, very complicated. I read it when I was in China. I don’t know where I found Kafka and also read it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What role does writing play in your life? proportion? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Not a heavy proportion. During the epidemic, because we are locked up at home, having such a luxury is not the norm, and it does not mean that we have to write every day. But I love words, and I write when I’m in quarantine. I didn&#39;t study much when I was in elementary school or middle school. I went to Shanghai Film Academy less than one semester after middle school. I have never read any domestic classical books. The real education comes after studying abroad. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, there have been several domestic performances. Have you ever been to a reality show? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I participated in one and it didn’t make me die of embarrassment. Once in a show, someone was asked to play a scene in which I played Wanrong before, and then I was asked to comment on it. I said, how can I comment on this? I cannot comment on this, because countless masters have created such an environment and atmosphere for me. Without the magic of the movie itself, putting this scene in a live-action show would be like chewing wax no matter how you play it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20岁的她会是中国女子网球的希望吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257924]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 15:00:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuYzsro5qS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuY zsro5qS. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, in the women’s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen won 2 Defeated Zhu Lin 0-0 and won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s tennis at the Asian Games that ended on September 29, 2023 In the singles final, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated teammate Zhu Lin in straight sets 6:2, 6:4 and won the gold medal in the women&#39;s singles tennis event at the Hangzhou Asian Games. This is the first time that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in the Asian Games. With Zheng Qinwen and Zhu Lin winning both the championship and runner-up, the Chinese women&#39;s tennis team achieved its fifth consecutive Asian Games title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, Zheng Qinwen reached the top 16 at the French Open, setting a new age for a Chinese female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam event, and attracted the attention of the world&#39;s tennis community. In the first half of 2023, her state had some ups and downs, but she recovered at the US Open and reached the top 8, once again setting a personal best. Zheng Qinwen, who only turned 21 in October this year, has just begun his career. The excellent results have given fans high expectations for this Hubei girl: After Li Na, the representative Chinese female tennis player, retires, will she, who is also from Hubei, be the next hope for Chinese women&#39;s tennis? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, Zheng Qinwen returned the ball in the women&#39;s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Rocket Girl&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, tennis player Li Na officially retired. In her 15-year career, she reached the WTA women&#39;s singles finals 21 times and won a total of 9 WTA and 19 ITF singles championships, including the 2011 French Open and the 2014 Australian Open women&#39;s singles championships. She is Asia&#39;s first Grand Slam women&#39;s singles champion. She was once ranked second in the world&#39;s women&#39;s tennis singles rankings, with a total career record of 503 wins and 188 losses. When she retired, she was ranked sixth in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Na&#39;s retirement has left an insurmountable peak and a huge vacuum for Chinese women&#39;s tennis. She has retired for more than nine years. At least so far, there has not been a player in Chinese women&#39;s tennis who can surpass her or even be on par with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, when Li Na lifted her first Suzanne Langland Cup at Roland Garros in Paris, 9-year-old Zheng Qinwen was receiving tennis training in Wuhan under Li Na’s former coach Teacher Yu Liqiao. In her memory, it seemed that people all over the country were paying attention to Li Na&#39;s game that day. &quot;Li Na&#39;s victory planted a dream in me. One day I will also win a Grand Slam.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was the third year that Zheng Qinwen officially started tennis training. In 2008, Zheng Qinwen&#39;s father took her to Beijing to watch the tennis match at the Olympic Games. Zheng Qinwen thought quietly. After the game, she and her father repeatedly discussed the details on the court and told her father that she was very interested in tennis. His father was once an athlete. He took Zheng Qinwen to play table tennis, badminton, basketball, and volleyball... His daughter was able to get started, but she was not outstanding. This time, he decided to let Zheng Qin play tennis. The coaches at Zheng Qinwen&#39;s hometown Shiyan Sports Center recognized her talent very much and believed that the power bursting out of her body was much higher than that of her peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, Zheng Qinwen participated in the 12-year-old category of the National Youth Tennis Ranking Tournament and won the singles and doubles championships in one fell swoop. In the same year, the Shiyan Tennis Team she led participated in the 14th Hubei Provincial Games and won 2 gold medals. Her serving speed reached 169 kilometers per hour, which was outstanding in the country and the world at that time. Therefore, she was hailed as a &quot;genius girl&quot; by many domestic sports commentators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen successfully entered the Beijing Wheel of Ingenuity Tennis School and received the guidance of Li Na’s mentor Carlos. Zheng Qinwen gradually grew from a talented player to a mature player with no shortcomings and comprehensive skills. In 2015, Zheng Qinwen won the championship in the 14-year-old group (12 to 14 years old) of the European Youth Tennis Tour. She has participated in many national and world tennis events and achieved outstanding results. When she was 16 years old, she participated in the French Open, Wimbledon, and US Open youth competitions, reaching the top 16 in each of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, my father contacted Spanish male tennis player Pere Riba, who had just retired as a coach, and the two parties decided to cooperate. Zheng Qinwen started training in Spain under the care of his mother. From Monday to Saturday, he had 2 hours of tennis training in the morning, 1 hour of physical training, and 2 hours of tennis training in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, tennis competitions that were temporarily suspended due to the new crown epidemic resumed, and Zheng Qinwen began to participate frequently. In an interview with the media, Zheng Qinwen recalled that in order to more conveniently compete in Europe, the team would drive around Europe, driving from Barcelona to Germany, Italy and the Czech Republic. The furthest trip took 22 hours on the road. She didn&#39;t want to be eliminated in the first round and have to take a 22-hour drive home, so she worked very hard after playing. In order to maintain the best competitive condition, she hardly used the Internet during the competition, and even turned off her mobile phone when she arrived at the competition venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, 19-year-old Zheng Qinwen participated in the French Open for the first time. She defeated Zanievska, Halep, and Koné successively, reaching the top 16 of the tournament, refreshing China The youngest age for a female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam tournament. In the fourth round, she faced Swiatek, ranked No. 1 in the world and the last French Open champion. The first set took more than 80 minutes. Zheng Qinwen broke Swiatek&#39;s 37-day record of no opponent winning a single set. He won the &quot;tiebreak&quot; 7-5 and won the first set with difficulty. In the second set, Zheng Qinwen suffered from a right thigh injury that affected his performance. In the end, he lost 1:2 and missed the top 8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Zheng Qinwen unfortunately stopped in the top 16 of the French Open, but the comprehensive skills and playing temperament she displayed made fans all over the world remember &#39;Chinese Zheng&#39;. The potential shown by Zheng Qinwen makes us believe that this season She will also bring more surprises!&quot; People&#39;s Daily reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, when Zheng Qinwen first entered the professional arena, he was ranked 630th in the world. In the following more than two years, Zheng Qinwen won 8 ITF championships. He made history in his first Grand Slam tournament, reaching the second round of the Australian Open, the top 16 of the French Open, the top 32 of Wimbledon, and the top 32 of the US Open. WTA named him the &quot;Best Rookie of the 2022 Season&quot;. Because of her extremely fast rise in rankings, Zheng Qinwen was called the &quot;Rocket Girl&quot;. At the beginning of 2022, she promised to enter the top 30 in the world rankings, and at the end of the season, her ranking rose to 27th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 23, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles final of the Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) 250 Palermo Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Italian player Paolini 2-1 and won The first tour championship in her career &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) official social account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Queen Wen&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the new season starts in 2023, Zheng Qinwen vows to enter the top ten in the world rankings. In the first half of the year, she went through a difficult downturn. In the 2023 Australian Open and French Open, Zheng Qinwen failed in the second round one after another. Before the start of Wimbledon, Zheng Qinwen changed coaches, replacing Spanish coach Riba with famous Belgian coach Wim Fiset, who has coached Naomi Osaka, Azarenka and other famous players. However, the grass court season was still hard for her to win, and Wimbledon ended with a first-round trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;Although I didn&#39;t play well in the grass-court season, I don&#39;t think my (strength) will decline. I will still work hard and prepare for the next stop. Change. The team must have had an impact, but I don’t think the loss was due to the coach.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in the US Open, Zheng Qinwen went to Italy to participate in the WTA250 Palermo Station. She went all the way and won her first WTA tour-level championship in her career, and began to get out of the slump. &quot;This championship is hard-won. After experiencing failures, tears, regrets and disappointments, I finally tasted the taste of victory. I believe this is just the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a series of games before the US Open, Zheng Qinwen defeated Venus Williams and other famous players. After the start of the US Open, she quickly entered the state. Compared with before, she appeared calmer and more patient, with more swings and more frequent changes in long and short balls. She successfully broke into the top 16 of the US Open and expressed emotion in the interview: &quot;At the beginning of the year, I thought that reaching the second week of a Grand Slam was a basic operation, but I didn&#39;t expect that I would not have such a result until the last Grand Slam of the year. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, she defeated the 2022 tournament runner-up and No. 5 seed Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, creating the best Grand Slam record in her career and becoming the sixth woman in the Open era to enter the Grand Slam singles. /China Tennis Association players in the 4 finals. And this is only the second year that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in a Grand Slam event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles tennis semifinals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen signed autographs for fans&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen’s experience is a sample of the new generation of tennis players - he started playing tennis out of interest, received professional and international training since childhood, made independent choices, and did not take any detours. A relatively smooth growth process shaped her confident attitude and unruly temperament. During interviews, she often makes some sharp remarks. On August 12, 2022, in the third round of women&#39;s singles at the WTA1000 Toronto Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Andreescu 7-5, 5-7, 6-2 and entered the quarterfinals of the WTA1000 competition for the first time. When asked if he would celebrate after reaching the top 8, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;I will only celebrate after winning. I will be sad if I don&#39;t win.&quot; After the game, he talked about the match with former US Open champion Andreescu. , Zheng Qinwen responded domineeringly: &quot;I am stronger than her.&quot; When asked if he would work hard to win the US Open seed, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;It really doesn&#39;t matter. My philosophy has always been that no matter who my opponent is, I Just do your best and strive to win.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her speech became an indicator of the player&#39;s personality, and she was called &quot;Queen Wen&quot; by fans. At the US Open, fans called her &quot;Queen Wen&quot; from the sidelines. Zheng Qinwen enjoys this title very much, &quot;Of course I know, I like the name Queen Wen very much. After all, this is the Queen!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than half of the 2023 season has passed, and Zheng Qinwen is far from the top 10 in the world. There is still some distance. In an interview, she was asked why she always sets her goals very high, and why she always likes to speak out and take the initiative to withstand scrutiny from the outside world? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, in the fourth round of the women&#39;s singles match at the 2023 US Open, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated Tunisian player Jabeul 2-0 and advanced to the eighth round. Qiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen replied: &quot;Sometimes pressure is actually necessary and can motivate me to do better. . If there is no pressure and you always stay at the same level, you will not be able to keep moving forward. I play tennis because of my love. I hope that I am always in a state of progress. Top players are also constantly improving, which I admire very much. A little bit of them. I can’t imagine the pain it would cause me to stand still.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[菜鸟“单飞”：一半收入在海外，离不开阿里]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257910]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/EDsF1CaArx . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252755&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cainiao launches self-operated local express delivery business in Spain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Cainiao official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, Cainiao submitted IPO application documents to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. This is Alibaba The first spin-off and listed business after launching the &quot;1+6+n&quot; organizational reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus disclosed that Cainiao achieved 20% revenue in the fiscal years 2021, 2022 and 2023, as well as in the three months from March 30 to June 30, 2023 (hereinafter referred to as the most recent quarter). Revenue was 52.733 billion yuan, 66.867 billion yuan, 77.8 billion yuan and 23.164 billion yuan, and net profits were -1.688 billion yuan, -2.004 billion yuan, -2.325 billion yuan and 391 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, its cumulative losses in the three full fiscal years before listing exceeded 6 billion yuan, and it only turned a profit in the most recent quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s current business mainly includes three major sectors: international logistics, domestic logistics, technology and other services. From fiscal year 2021 to 2023 (ending March 30) and the most recent quarter, its international logistics revenue accounted for 55.1%, 52.3%, 47.4%, and 48.1% respectively, which are all higher than domestic logistics revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Alibaba Group, Yintai Group, Fosun Group, Fuchun Group and other Zhejiang capital circle tycoons, together with domestic express logistics companies SF Express and &quot;Three Communications and One Express&quot; jointly established Cainiao . At that time, Shen Guojun, the founder of Yintai Group, was the CEO of Cainiao Network. However, just one year later, Shen stepped down as CEO and became vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Current CEO Wan Lin joined Cainiao in 2014. Previously, he served as a senior manager of Amazon’s global logistics department. In 2017, Wan Lin officially took charge of Cainiao and made Cainiao one of Alibaba&#39;s fastest-growing business segments. Thanks to this, Wan Lin appears on Alibaba’s latest list of partners disclosed in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Betting on the international market&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Also in 2017, Cainiao’s overseas logistics ambitions began to emerge. This year, Cainiao launched its first e-Hub plan (comprehensive e-commerce logistics hub) in Kuala Lumpur, which became the gateway to the Southeast Asian e-commerce market. It mainly provides express delivery services for cross-border merchants on AliExpress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of June 30, 2023, Cainiao has established two logistics hubs with an area of ​​over 15,000 square meters around the world, located in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia and Liège, Belgium. It is expected to build a third logistics hub in Hong Kong hub. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s performance in cross-border logistics services is inseparable from Alibaba’s cross-border e-commerce AliExpress. AliExpress was established in 2010 and is known as the international version of &quot;Taobao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cross-border e-commerce practitioner in the women&#39;s clothing industry told Southern Weekend reporters that the platforms available on the market include Amazon, AliExpress, Shopee, Dunhuang, and E-bay. Due to their low cost, , early cross-border e-commerce entrepreneurs tend to choose AliExpress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amazon has the fastest transportation speed due to its large number of overseas warehouses. The goods can arrive in major European and American countries in about a week, while in remote areas it takes half a month to a month. &quot;After the express arrives at the local area, it still chooses to cooperate with the local post office, and the delivery time is determined by the local post office.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides express services to AliExpress merchants in the form of third-party services. &quot;For example, Di Sifang is owned by Cainiao express delivery company,&quot; she said. Tianyancha shows that Cainiao Network holds 45% of the shares in Shenzhen Di Sifang Information Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the prospectus, in 2022, Cainiao’s international logistics service revenue will increase by 20% compared with the previous year, and the most recent quarter increased by 41% compared with the same period last year. The main reason is AliExpress’s cross-border express service Significant growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to serving the e-commerce platform within the Alibaba ecosystem, Cainiao has also established local logistics services in Hong Kong and some overseas markets such as Spain, France, Poland and other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chishi Consulting data cited in the prospectus mentioned that the compound annual growth rate of cross-border e-commerce logistics from 2018 to 2022 will exceed that of China. In particular, China’s cross-border e-commerce far exceeds cross-border e-commerce in other regions. business. Europe and the United States are expected to become the main destinations for cross-border e-commerce products from China. In addition, Southeast Asia and Latin America are also expected to grow rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhuoshi Consulting, in 2022, Cainiao will become the world&#39;s largest cross-border e-commerce logistics company by package volume. Among the top five, there are two Chinese companies, Cainiao and EMS (China Postal Express Logistics), and the remaining three companies are from Germany, France and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the international market, Cainiao will also face challenges from SF Express and Jitu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jitu, which was just listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on September 15, has also set its sights on the global market. Jitu is a logistics company born in Indonesia. As of 2022, its express delivery services cover 13 countries, with the highest market share in Southeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, SF Express announced that it would go public in Hong Kong for a secondary listing. Before the news was released, SF Express made a large-scale acquisition of 10 subsidiaries of Kerry Logistics that engage in express delivery services in the Asia-Pacific region and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to previous media reports, since 2019, SF Express has been making continuous progress in overseas expansion, and has successively invested in Flexport, a US freight logistics service provider, and 100% equity interests in two companies, DHL Hong Kong and DHL Beijing, owned by the German DHL company. Myanmar logistics company KOSPA Limited has also established a joint venture with Indonesian Triputra Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Build the world&#39;s largest logistics network&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; According to the Cainiao prospectus, the gross profit margin in the latest quarter has increased compared with the same period in 2022, rising from 10.6%. to 13.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Its operating costs mainly include contract fulfillment costs (transportation routes, distribution, warehousing processing and other procurement and management services, that is, third-party services) and labor costs. Labor costs include employee welfare expenses and outsourced labor services, which basically account for about 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In its prospectus, Cainiao used &quot;the price of a cup of coffee to be sent around the world&quot; to evaluate the solutions it provides in cross-border logistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A cross-border e-commerce practitioner told Southern Weekend reporters that the price of sending a T-shirt is 20 to 30 yuan, which is almost the same as China Post, but compared with foreign logistics companies Lower cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being cheap, the logistics solution provided by Cainiao for AliExpress merchants has also shortened the delivery time from one or two months to ten days, and some international express products only take five days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day that Cainiao submitted its IPO report, AliExpress and Cainiao launched the &quot;Global Five-Day Delivery&quot; international express product, with the first batch landing in the United Kingdom, Spain, the Netherlands, Belgium and South Korea. In other words, consumers in these five countries can receive packages from China in just five days as long as they order products with the &quot;five-day delivery&quot; logo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned practitioners said that five-day delivery of goods requires merchants to provide package online information within 48 hours of the customer placing an order. If your Internet access rate reaches the standard, you can apply to join Five-Day Delivery, and the platform will automatically allow merchants to join. It is not difficult for merchants to achieve Internet access rates. Usually after a link is created, they will stock up on some goods. Buyers can send out orders as soon as they place an order, and rookies will come to collect goods every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to reduce costs and increase transportation speed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus quoted information from Chishi Consulting. Cainiao has established the largest logistics network in the world, including two logistics hub centers of over 15,000 square meters, more than 1,100 warehouses and more than 380 warehouses. Sorting center. In June 2023, there will be an average of about 170 charter flights and board flights per week, more than 2,700 transportation routes, more than 4,400 outlets and more than 17,000 stations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology is also playing a role. For example, artificial intelligence AI algorithms can improve sorting accuracy, improve inventory management, optimize route planning and vehicle scheduling, etc. In terms of smart hardware, there are RFID, smart IoT devices, automation and self-driving technologies, including AVG (automated warehousing technology) and the electric unmanned delivery vehicle &quot;Little Man Donkey&quot;. At the same time, it also provides a digital supply chain to facilitate monitoring, identifying problems, and improving efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, the autonomous driving business of Alibaba Damo Academy was merged into Cainiao Group, and some personnel were transferred to Cainiao. That is to say, both &quot;Damanlu&quot; (self-driving truck) and &quot;Xiaomanlu&quot; Return to rookie. According to the prospectus, as of March 30, 2023, more than 800 Xiaoman Donkeys have been put into use, delivering more than 10 million packages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/NzgzSpXJJwKMnxPPEpFsrvXwbWv21GI7T4uovkjt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/NzgzSpXJJwKMnxPPEpFsrvXwbWv21GI7T4uovkjt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252756&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cainiao Global Headquarters. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cannot live without Alibaba&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before IPO , Cainiao has gone through three rounds of equity financing. Alibaba Group holds a total of 69.54% of Cainiao&#39;s shares through three wholly-owned subsidiaries: Ali CN Investment, Ali KB&amp;nbsp;Investment, and Alibaba International. Currently, Cainiao is still a subsidiary of Alibaba Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao disclosed in detail its inextricable ties with Alibaba in its prospectus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba is Cainiao’s largest customer. From fiscal year 2021 to 2023 and the most recent quarter, revenue from Alibaba accounted for 29.2%, 30.8%, 28.2%, and 29.7% of total revenue respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides logistics services for multiple e-commerce platforms such as Tmall, Taobao, and AliExpress under the Alibaba ecosystem. After 2021, Cainiao will also serve merchants on well-known international e-commerce platforms and online channels (such as Kuaishou, etc.) outside the Alibaba system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prospectus also states that due to the strategic synergy between Cainiao and Alibaba, Cainiao’s ability to maintain its ecosystem with Alibaba, or the development of Alibaba’s ecosystem itself, will have an impact on Cainiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The existing resource cooperation between Cainiao and Alibaba Group has been fixed in the form of signing a business cooperation framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Includes certain intellectual property rights related to certain software and technologies used by Alibaba and Cainiao in their respective business operations. Alibaba Group provides certain backend, administrative support and shared services to Cainiao. Alibaba Cloud provides basic cloud computing services to Cainiao, and Best Logistics provides freight services to Cainiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao provides hardware and technical support services, warehousing and management services, comprehensive supply chain solutions and logistics services to Alibaba related parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in terms of management, rookies can still maintain a certain degree of independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Cainiao’s eight board members, Cai Chongxin, Dai Shan and Jiang Fan are respectively the chairman of the board of directors of Alibaba, the CEO and board member of Taotian Group, and the CEO and board member of Alibaba International Digital Business Group. . These three people are all non-executive directors of Cainiao Group. They do not participate in daily business management and operations and only provide professional opinions and judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the CEO of Cainiao Group, Wan Lin is also a member of the senior management of Alibaba Group, but does not hold other management positions in Alibaba Group. The remaining four members of Cainiao&#39;s board of directors also do not hold any positions in Alibaba Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>