<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[被烈犬咬伤募捐200万争议：医院称未开证明，轻松筹称家属自估金额]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259389]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爱囤“破烂”的老年人：怀旧、孤独、渴望被关注……]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259181]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My mother lives in her hometown in the countryside. She has the habit of hoarding garbage when she comes across cans, mineral water bottles, and cartons. Cardboard boxes, scrap wires, and even scraps from the village mosquito net factory were all picked up and taken home. She didn’t see much of them sold, so they were all piled up in the yard. My sister and I spend a long time cleaning up every time. Before long, she picks up so many things that they pile up like a mountain, and the small yard is like a garbage dump. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, there are a lot of old things stored in the two rooms of my mother, including clothes, shoes and hats from many years ago, rusty iron pots, shovels, farm tools, and even old things that my father brought to her from Xinjiang when he was still alive. The cotton felts, blankets, and sheepskin jackets were in tatters and a mess. We have to clean her out, and mother protects her like a baby, for fear that we will throw her away as garbage when she is not paying attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some villages and towns, old people with my mother’s habits are quite common. Some store less and put them in categories; some store more and put them in disorder; some garbage is mixed with daily necessities and they simply eat and sleep in the garbage pile. It is understood that this is mostly done by lonely elderly people. Very little of the garbage they pick up can be sold. Since they are unable to move it out, they have to coexist with the garbage over time. There are also elderly people who have children and also like to hoard rags. Their behavior and habits are often disgusted by their children, and they are even ridiculed as &quot;nostalgia mania&quot; and &quot;crazy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do these elderly people like to hoard &quot;rags&quot;? Investigating the reasons, I found through investigation that they are nothing more than the following:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it is based on frugality and cannot bear to throw away old things. The elderly are used to living a hard life, and they can make do with the old things at home, and seldom buy new clothes or new supplies. Even if their children buy them, they are often not used to them. They still think the old ones are better and are reluctant to throw them away. Some old people do not want to sell the rags they pick up for money, but feel it would be a pity to throw them away. Old man Wang in his hometown village likes to collect old furniture discarded by young people. It is often seen that he uses a tricycle to transport it home. Someone asked him: &quot;You have saved so much, can you use it yourself?&quot; Old Man Wang said: &quot;They are all high-quality wood. Where can I find this before! I can dismantle it and it can be used.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The second reason is based on nostalgia. There is warmth and emotion in the rags. Many elderly people are nostalgic for old things. Many of their clothing items have been with them for decades. Old things have memories, stories and feelings. In my family, my mother had a deep affection for the rags that filled two rooms, especially my father’s relics. She kept some of them when he was buried. Every time I wanted to dispose of them, my mother always said, “You throw them away as garbage.” &quot;Where can I miss your dad? I took out these things, rubbed them, and talked about them, as if talking to him...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is based on loneliness, to relieve loneliness. This situation is more common among the elderly who like to hoard rags. According to my mother, Aunt Zhang&#39;s three children all work in developed areas and earn a lot of money. They send her money on time every month. It should be said that Aunt Zhang has no worries about food and clothing. But she got up early and stayed up late at night, rain or shine, picking up trash everywhere. Aunt Zhang explained the reason: &quot;My children all know how to be filial, and I don&#39;t lack anything. But they rarely come back throughout the year, and I feel empty. I don&#39;t pick up rags all for the sake of selling them, but I just have something to do and feel at ease.&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is based on being noticed and longing for short-term happiness. When my friend was chatting with me, he mentioned that his relative, Granny Li, who lives in the city, had a unique reason for picking up garbage. Her old courtyard is rarely visited by people, and only during holidays and New Years are the children and grandchildren reunited. The small courtyard is filled with laughter and joy. Those are the happiest and happiest days of the year for Granny Li. Later, Granny Li discovered that whenever the house was messy, her children would come to clean it, so she had an idea and deliberately picked up garbage and made the yard messy and dirty, so that the children would come back to clean it up, which made the house more popular and lively. , it’s lively. The two daughters-in-law couldn&#39;t stand her behavior and said that Granny Li was a little mentally disturbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elderly are keen to hoard rags and rags, which is not only unsightly and affects the sanitation of the family environment, but more importantly, the elderly have more or less problems with their mental health. As a child, you should not only clean up regularly, persuade and comfort them, and return them to a normal life track, but you should also look for the reasons at a deeper level. As the saying goes: To untie a bell, you must tie the bell. Children should not only pay attention to material support, but also pay attention to spiritual support. Just like the old song &quot;Go Home Often and See&quot; sings, &quot;Find some free time, find some time, take your children, and come home often; Bring a smile, bring blessings, accompany your loved ones, and go home often...&quot; Give the elderly more spiritual comfort and let them feel the deep family affection and the warmth of home. To a certain extent, this is richer than simply giving them Material support is more important! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a staff member of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Tancheng County, Shandong Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions . Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访吴慷仁：“演员到底可以演多久戏，在我心里是个问号”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/3yTGMRWbT24vi0h8pG6nJ75fKKe7NbWv4bULWYte.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3yTGMRWbT24vi0h8pG6nJ75fKKe7Nb Wv4bULWYte. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Kangren has no agent or company. He entered the industry late and had 50 jobs before becoming an actor. work. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren&#39;s voice came from the other end of the receiver. Like an old-fashioned man, he carefully confirmed the name of the newspaper and the reporter&#39;s name, and his tone sounded gentle and gentle. He is on vacation. When he is not working, he spends his time in the same way as ordinary people. He passes the time by watching anime such as &quot;Spells Come Back&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, Wu Kangren may have been the actor with the broadest role map in the Chinese-language drama market. His images in movies and TV shows are so varied that it&#39;s jaw-dropping. In 2021, he dressed up in women&#39;s clothing, put on lipstick, and played the role of Mama Sang &quot;Baby&quot; in the highly acclaimed drama &quot;The Lights Are Coming&quot;. The character photo was published in Taiwanese newspapers, but no one reacted, &quot;It took two days to be discovered by others. Isn&#39;t this Wu Kangren!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2022 drama &quot;Her and Her Her&quot;, he plays A pervert who is sexually harassed in the workplace has a female fan who is so angry that she wants to &quot;quit her fans&quot;. Wu Kangren is very calm about this. He told Southern Weekend reporters that he is not worried about the loss of fans of the drama and movies. &quot;The next role will be different.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These roles are a huge departure from the &quot;flower boy&quot; image he played early in his career. At the age of 27, he played Hana Takuya in the classic idol drama &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; - affectionate, broken, and in line with all the settings of a tragic male lead. But in the following years, he continued to break away from that image full of romantic arcs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, on the 54th Taiwan Golden Bell Awards stage, Wu Kangren took the stage as the award guest. Everyone looked at the thin actor with sunken cheeks and a bald head with some suspicion. &quot;Isn&#39;t this a bald man?&quot; A barrage floated across the video. At that time, for the new drama, he lost weight to only 64 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has become routine for him to adjust his body shape, skin color and accent according to the requirements of the role. Someone made an Excel polyline table of Wu Kangren&#39;s weight data from &quot;Termites&quot; to &quot;Love&quot; and found that his weight suddenly went up and down, showing a steep W shape. A reporter from Southern Weekend asked him if he was not afraid of physical damage caused by drastic changes? He smiled and replied: &quot;I&#39;m still alive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fight&quot; is the key word that many people first think of when they mention Wu Kangren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Wu Kangren changed his appearance again in the Taiwanese drama &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; broadcast exclusively on Station B. He put on a Hawaiian shirt, revealing his dark skin, and became the 41-year-old frustrated middle-aged Gao Jiayue. As the eldest son in his family, he has been drifting away for a long time, running a restaurant named &quot;One Million&quot; with a rating of only 2.8 in Xiaoliuqiu. After several years of bleak business, his girlfriend couldn&#39;t bear the island life and cheated on him and left. His career went bankrupt, his love failed, and he tried to hang himself in a restaurant, but the rope broke. Dive to the bottom of the sea, take off your oxygen equipment, and prepare to drown yourself. He suddenly remembered that the oxygen equipment might be eaten by sea turtles and was not environmentally friendly, so he had no choice but to surface and returned home dejectedly to meet his family and have a &quot;long farewell.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My parents ran a breakfast shop in Taipei to support their three sons. The mother struggled to endure her father&#39;s mental infidelity and continued to live under the same roof with resentment. The second son is an adopted son. He lives a regular life as an office worker and takes the initiative to take over the responsibility of taking care of his parents. The younger son is older and unmarried, and helps in the breakfast shop. The whole family is stuck in the inertia of the old life and is stuck in moving forward. Everyone is in a &quot;stuck moment&quot; in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren said that he doesn’t have much in common with the character, but as a peer of Gao Jiayue, he has also experienced Kaka moments in real life. &quot;What&#39;s the hardest time for an actor? The role you want to take is taken away, or people don&#39;t like your good performance when it comes out.&quot; Wu Kangren told a reporter from Southern Weekend. His response was simple and clear: keep eating, sleeping, and trying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 will be a harvest year for Wu Kangren. Two of his films, &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; and &quot;May You Live Forever&quot; were screened at the film festival. Both films focused on the bottom class. &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; was filmed in Malaysia, with Wu Kangren playing a deaf-mute illegal immigrant. After getting off the plane, he intuitively felt the gap between him and the character. At first glance, he was a &quot;white and clean civilized person&quot;, while the character he played lived in a dirty place all day long. He began to starve and continued to bask in the sun until his skin was tanned by ultraviolet rays and the locals in the market stopped looking at him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 First Youth Film Festival, he won the best actor for this role. The organizing committee commented on his performance: &quot;Faced with unconventional character settings, Wu Kangren used all available physical resources such as expressions, body parts, movements, and eyes to perform, interpreting the emotions and emotions of the film extremely vividly. Hearing thunder in silence reflects the actor&#39;s great empathy for the character&#39;s situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Kangren has a rare sense of relaxation. He has no agent or company and works for himself. Lasted nine years. There are no personal restrictions or team control. It&#39;s all up to you to decide what kind of scenes to take on, what roles to play, how much to talk to the media, and what the standards are. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He asked a Southern Weekend reporter which episode of &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; he had watched. After getting the answer, he conveyed his preferences as if he were a friend: &quot;Look further down, the back is really better. I really like it.&quot; I like it.&quot; Faced with the reporter&#39;s &quot;problematic&quot; question, he also bluntly said: &quot;This question is too broad.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the outside world, the different types of roles over the years have brought Wu Kangren Emboldened. But he said that when he was young, his sense of self-identity was very low and he felt that he was just a &quot;nobody&quot;. He entered the industry late and had 50 jobs before the age of 20. He worked as a rough laborer on construction sites, ran a street stall, and also worked in cafes and bars. Now that I am in my forties this year, the feeling of insecurity has subsided, and new questions have arisen in my heart. He said that in recent years, he feels that his life as an actor will not be too long, so he cherishes it more and increases the frequency of taking roles. This year, he has at least seven film and television works released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the interview, he almost subconsciously revealed his expectations for his subsequent career. He said: &quot;I want to continue acting until I am old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iNugJUjNXgJjxodcmTCYsmf9VQCWG6XI7zrO9Neb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/iNugJUjNXgJjxodcmTCYsmf9VQCWG6XI7zrO9Neb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot; In &quot;In This Lifetime&quot;, Wu Kangren plays Gao Jiayue, a frustrated middle-aged man. After his career went bankrupt and his love failed, he tried to commit suicide but failed and returned home in despair. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, Wu Kangren accepted an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. The following is a self-narration compiled based on the interview content:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;It would be good to grow this big in my lifetime&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After receiving the invitation from &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; At that time, I had just finished filming the movie &quot;May You Live Longer&quot; in Hong Kong. When I finished filming, I only weighed 53 kilograms, which was too light. So before joining the set of &quot;In This Life Time&quot;, I ate as much as possible and weighed 66 kilograms when I returned. Last year I went to Malaysia and Hong Kong to shoot a movie respectively. I was made thin and dark. I came back to play the role of Gao Jiayue, a kid who came back from the island. In fact, he looked quite similar. In addition, director Xu Zhaoren is here, and I also like the script. I knew beforehand that Brother Xixiang (Xi Xiang, who plays the father) and Sister Guimei (Yang Guimei, who plays the mother) would take the role, so I also wanted to act together in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director took the sad story very lightly, and made the sad things somewhat funny, even humorous. Gao Jiayue is a person who really wants to die. But if you take what Gao Jiayue said to his nephew, &quot;I jumped into the sea, I wanted to die, but I saw turtles again, and I was afraid that the turtles would eat my equipment and it was not environmentally friendly.&quot; People say that he must think you are lying or joking. But when the audience actually saw the picture, all this became no longer such a joke: it was true, he wanted to die. I think this is where life is ridiculous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In My Lifetime&quot; is not about university knowledge. My own interpretation is, &quot;It would be good to grow this big in your lifetime.&quot; This sentence reflects a lot of feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When things don’t go as planned, it’s always a “stuck moment.” In our lives, sometimes things go against our expectations, and sometimes hard work may not necessarily pay off. This is a very cruel thing. You can’t get what you want, and you can get what you don’t want. How you can stabilize your mood, continue to live, continue to love the people around you, or make the people you love live happily is all a matter of subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people choose to escape, such as the parents in the play who have marital problems. Gao Jiayue came back to tell them not to continue evading. Some people tried to persuade them to make peace but not to leave. Gao Jiayue tried to persuade them to leave but not to make peace. Some people are always in his comfort zone, such as his two younger brothers, who complain about life but are unwilling to step out. How can a character like Gao Jiayue push them, but in such an annoying way? He has the courage to be hated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Real-life family dramas are not as easy as genre dramas. It is very difficult to act in a very real-life way. We actors have been acting for so long and are very familiar with rhythm, technique, and movement. We are also very familiar with how to perform well on camera. But when we try too hard to show the good side, the sense of drama will be stronger and the audience can see it. Xu Zhaoren hopes to adapt it to life, so we revised the lines in the direction of life. Chatting with the director and imagining the characters every day before going on stage is actually very brain-burning and tiring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The script of &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; is very well structured, and the relationship between everyone is clearly written. But we didn’t act according to the relationship between everyone in the script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We feel that we have put a lot of effort into it. In fact, at that time, I was so thin that I deliberately imitated Brother Xixiang. Since I wanted to play his son, did I have any similarities with him? We looked at his posture and sometimes imitated him in jumping and sitting. At that time, I had a lot of discussions with the director. Since you want to play a son and a brother, do you have the same attitude towards each family member, or is it a little different? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, when you are getting along with your younger brother, you just love to bully him. How to bully him? The screenwriter will not teach you to hit them with your hands in the play. This kind of action must be designed by yourself. And it has to be connected to when you were a kid. The second brother in the play is not your biological brother. Your attitude towards your biological brother (reporter&#39;s note: third brother) may be different from that of the second brother. In fact, it is very subtle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the relationship with his father was not good in the script, but in fact when we acted it out, Brother Xixiang felt that he loved his eldest son the most because he was his first son. Child. It is a very straightforward way for parents to express their love for you verbally. Brother Xixiang’s method is the kind of love in which he scolds you the harshest and hits you the hardest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original way of quarreling with my father was to talk to each other, but now as the show continues, it has become that I can actually have a good chat with my father. You are a rebellious son, but you are always unwilling to take what adults say seriously, which means we are acting the other way around. So in the first episode at the beginning, the father guarded the drunk Gao Jiayue from getting up, saying that he was afraid that you would spit it out and choke to death. Therefore, the relationship between Gao Jiayue and his father was not a quarrel at the beginning, but a show of weakness, that is, I was homesick and came back to see it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the script, there is no drinking in the scene of returning home. We discussed with the director and couldn&#39;t imagine what kind of state Gao Jiayue was in before he dared to step into this home again. A failed person, a person who is unwilling to start over, a person who dares not face himself again, but is so arrogant and thinks that I will succeed when I go out to start a business, and then returns to this home penniless, at this time, what should I do? How to do it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So what I thought of was, otherwise we would have a drink, and he would have to get himself drunk before he dared to return to this house shamelessly. In the end we decided to use this method. How on earth would he face the truth? You can only get yourself drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that scene, I really drank sorghum wine. I&#39;m not that good at drinking, but I drank in a situation that I could control. After filming, I fell asleep, and the actors called it a day, leaving me alone on set. When I woke up, the only thing left was the lighting crew taking out the lights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3ijT0Y9zockqo3BFBZxZtn4NO0EUMTVl8Cf8Zc2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/3ijT0Y9zockqo3BFBZxZtn4NO0EUMTVl8Cf8Zc2C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In recent years, Wu Kangren&#39;s film and television image has been very varied, and he has played many impressive supporting roles. In 2023, he will have at least seven film and television works released. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of tvbs)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;At that time, I only wanted to take supporting roles&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;In recent years, Taiwanese dramas have become more varied in genre. Since they are so varied, of course actors have the opportunity to be varied. They just complement each other, from early idol dramas to later craftsman dramas, police and gangster movies, ghost movies, and now back to life. It&#39;s a big test for actors. You can&#39;t use your past skills to perform every play. When you encounter different plays, you have to make different adjustments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no particular pursuit to play various types of characters, I just want to accumulate different acting experiences. It should be said that I think the life of an actor will not be too long. I dare not say that for everyone. I think it is a question mark in my mind how long an actor can act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was in my early 30s, I began to realize this, which may have something to do with my upbringing. In the past, my self-identity was not so high. The so-called self-identity refers to self-confidence and even the value of existence. You may feel that you are just a nobody, a child who grew up on a construction site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I really felt that I could only work hard, otherwise what would I do? That’s why I got so many roles later. The reason I take on so many roles is not because I want to make a lot of money. In Taiwan, I can’t make much money from film remuneration. I hope that within a limited time, I can see my own possibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after I turned 35, I started to play different roles quite quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She and Her Her&quot;, &quot;The Lights Come on&quot; and &quot;Mom, stop making trouble!&quot; ” were probably all filmed at the same time, and during that time I only wanted to take on supporting roles. Because I think the burden of the protagonist is too heavy. The protagonist sometimes shoots for three or four months at a time. He is always immersed in a role or a long period of work. He is very tired and easily tired. I might as well play a supporting role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the epidemic was also going on at that time, I felt that filming supporting roles could be more fun and not be so stressful. You may say it&#39;s good to have more fun, but I have also reviewed it myself and found that those characters were really overplayed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Her and Her Her&quot; was a guest appearance to help, and I didn&#39;t think too much about it, because the role had to be played in a perverted way. I remember that the producer and director couldn&#39;t find anyone at that time, so they called me later. I had some friendship with the producer, so I went to help. I didn&#39;t want to attract everyone&#39;s attention, I just went to serve, serve. That role. I&#39;m not worried about losing the audience. The next role will be different. I&#39;ve never worried about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The First Light&quot; is another story. It was really because of good luck. I had a good role as the &quot;baby&quot; and he had a lot of space. He found me only after the filming started. I was free at that time and even Director Yi Qi asked you to act, and I said yes. I said you have to give me time to prepare, because I need to find a teacher to practice high heels and dance. In fact, we prepared everything in private, chatting with those drag queens, eating and drinking with them, and imitating their looks and voices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So sometimes taking a role is not so calculated, sometimes it’s just a feeling, because the director is right, I go because the script is right, I go because there are certain actors, or I feel that If it helps this drama, I will do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;When you are not acting, you are just a nobody&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;In This Lifetime&quot; has helped me a lot in my life. I&#39;m really lucky to be able to film &quot;In This Life Time&quot; at this age. Xu Zhaoren is a very good director, and it is very difficult to perform his scenes well. It was the third time I worked with him that this time I seriously felt that I might actually have done a good job. In the past, I didn&#39;t feel like I was able to add points to his dramas, but this drama did a little bit, and I felt like I was finally worthy of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, I take myself very seriously. Sometimes the success of a drama is the result of the team, sometimes it is the credit of the marketing, and sometimes it is the accumulation of credits between the characters. It is absolutely impossible to do it because of one person. Man, this drama is hit or miss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always been confident in my life as an actor. The so-called confidence means that I am willing to do it, not that I am very good. This is a concept. In the past, it was a very simple and clear thing to work hard and be rewarded. This thing has a profound impact on me. If you work, work hard, and sweat for the construction site, you will get the salary you deserve. This is a must-have condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And be responsible. You really have to do your job well, otherwise the boss will scold you, fire you, or ask you to pack up and leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acting is the same for me. Sometimes why you are so fat and why you are so thin is because no one has done it, and no one knows what can be gained from it. I want to know what I can gain from the state of mind of being hungry or obese. I think this is irreplaceable and is self-cultivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s hard for you to tell others that I was hungry for 4 months from May to August last year. From &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; to &quot;May I Live Longer&quot;, I lost 53 kilograms. I was so hungry. , how I lived. People just say, wow. But it’s not because my character has to be so thin that you can see how great I am, no. It’s about putting the characters there and seeing the finished product in the end. Even if the movie doesn&#39;t go well, people will think you&#39;re just thin, so what&#39;s the big deal? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because you will really experience it after you do it. We are not like the protagonist of the anime. Why is he almost defeated in the end and still able to wake up? Because he thinks about his family and friends. Like Luffy in &quot;One Piece&quot; and Goku in &quot;Dragon Ball&quot;, he suddenly doesn&#39;t know where he came from. strength. We are human beings, and we still have our own limits. Limits can only be reached through self-examination again and again. If people don&#39;t make mistakes, they won&#39;t know that they will make mistakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was acting, I often made mistakes, and I still make them now. It&#39;s just that sometimes someone will correct your mistakes, sometimes not, but I always hope to meet a director who can deny you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of each actor is different. Some talented actors need to retain their energy. I consider myself to be mediocre and I need to accumulate that energy. The growth process of each actor cannot be compared. Since it cannot be compared, there is no repetition. The lack of repetition means that only I understand what I am going through, and you will not understand. Only after each finished product comes out will you see the difference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an actor is not acting, you are just a nobody. At most, you will be exposed to fashion or commercial performances, and you will see the glamorous star appearance. In fact, if you take away those appearances, who you really are is very vague. Celebrities have a popular persona, and that persona is the persona that the audience likes, because now everyone likes to see good things, kind people, and even people with high moral standards. The actor&#39;s appearance is very blurry, and there&#39;s nothing wrong with being blurry, it&#39;s just a different experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always felt that actors are people living in the past, and the works you see are all me from the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Acting has never been free&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Actually, I have always felt that my work experience, having worked 50 jobs before I was 20, was not of much help to me. big. The accumulation of work experience is very life-like, but sometimes drama does not require you to perform life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, &quot;Copycat&quot;. It is a genre drama, and genre dramas are not life-like. If you want to stick to a life-like performance and conform to the rhythm of the camera and the director, when should you react? This is the pull between you and yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing Guo Xiaoqi in &quot;Copycat&quot; was very difficult for me, very difficult, extremely difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The skeleton of the genre drama is better written, but the portrayal of the characters may not be outstanding. Because it serves a crime and captures the real culprit, it takes the audience to see the reaction of each character. After watching it, the protagonist is actually empty. The so-called empty means that you can only accumulate some plots to serve the audience. How to put your own human flavor into it requires a lot of thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, you want to play him very smart, but you don’t want to play him too handsome, a little quirky, but you don’t want to make him too mythical. If you just look at the ferocity of the supporting characters, the main character will easily disappear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If &quot;Copycat&quot; is about using all the things accumulated in the past into one film, &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; is about forgetting all the things that I know. This is a transition between very skillful and unskillful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acting has never been free. How can acting be free? Acting is very scientific, including lenses, camera positions, performances, types, and even opponents. Acting is very unfree but very organic. Any situation may affect the whole body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called lack of freedom is that you cannot perform exactly the way you want, sometimes because of the orientation of the camera, sometimes because of the rhythm, sometimes because of the opponent actor, and sometimes because of what the character wants to present. situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do you think you have to take on so many roles? Because I think acting is a very passive profession, I just hope to put some of my own initiative into acting work in a passive situation as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The passivity of an actor is to be chosen. You will be there only after the script is written. If the script is not written, you will not exist. You may just act in another play. What space is there to be able to choose and take the initiative? That means to become thinner or fatter, to make the character more internal or more external, it doesn&#39;t matter. No matter what method you use, show your initiative. Those initiatives will affect the director&#39;s thoughts on the character, or the character can have a chemical reaction with other actors. This is the initiative that I think is valuable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s what acting is, you bring out your own life experience. If you don&#39;t have this life experience, you need to rely on a lot of field research and investment. Except for a few who can&#39;t do it, others can rely on self-study and hard work to accumulate the short one or two seconds on the screen to deceive everyone and say that I look like me. But when you go deeper, whether the performance is good or bad depends on each actor&#39;s own interpretation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, I like many senior actors, such as Mr. Li Xuejian from Mainland China, who can act at that age, or Mr. Jin Shijie, etc. Actors who grew up in Hong Kong in the 1980s and 1990s, such as Tony Leung Ka Fai, Tony Leung Chiu Wai, Nick Cheung Ka Fai, and Andy Lau, each actor has accumulated hundreds of dramas, leaving his own place. But for me, that kind of accumulation is very difficult. If I follow the current pace of actors, I will never be able to achieve it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nine years without an agent&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;I haven’t had an agent for about nine years. In the early years, I was still looking for one, but because of one job after another Come, I will keep acting. If there is a job, I will take it, if I get it, I will act, and if I act, I will go on stage. If someone says hello, I will applaud. I will say thank you, and I will keep acting like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After four or five years, it seems that people (agents) no longer come to me. They seem to think that I can do this. But in fact, I am very busy and have many things to deal with, including contracts and work. Time, schedule. I haven&#39;t taken on so many commercial projects, and shooting commercials isn&#39;t too complicated. Relatively speaking, my acting life is pretty simple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back now, I feel that every decision I made before was good. I did not sign for a big company, but signed for a small company, and I will live a happier life. Later, he left the protection of his original agent, and finally became an agent by himself for no apparent reason. I also have to be an assistant and carry my own bag, which contains travel supplies and stomach medicine. Be your own driver and drive to the scene, finish work by yourself, and borrow clothes by yourself. There are things to do and things not to do. There are some jobs that you can choose, and there are some jobs where you don’t have to make this money. If you don’t make this money, you won’t have so many burdens and baggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am an actor, and what we talk about is what actors do. In fact, I rarely talk about conditions, because if you talk about conditions, it will be complicated and waste a lot of thought. Being able to act well is the first condition. I&#39;m not a person who likes to compare. I don&#39;t compare myself to actors of the same age and tell them what they are like. If you don&#39;t think about it, nothing will happen. If you think about it, something will happen. You feel you are at a disadvantage because you have a value standard and judgment: my salary must be so high, or my conditions must be so high. If you don&#39;t have this value standard, there is no such thing as suffering a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, last year&#39;s &quot;Fudu Youth&quot; and &quot;May You Live Forever&quot; were both very low-cost movies, so why were they filmed? Because I like the script of &quot;Fudu Youth&quot;, I want to try to go out and experience life. Different environments will have different sparks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I did go, it was very worthwhile, and I made a great movie. &quot;May I Live Longer&quot; is from Hong Kong, so it&#39;s the same. I just read the script and said I would go. I didn’t talk about where I would live, and I didn’t even talk about my salary. The producer was surprised and said, &quot;Don&#39;t you ask about the price?&quot; I said I don’t need to ask about the price, just call the contract. He called over the contract and it was this price. I laughed. I know they don&#39;t have money. If I think I can accept it, I will go, and I will be very happy in my heart, and you will be very relaxed, because you have nothing to ask for, so you will go, just asking for a good performance in the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2015 to now, I don’t want everyone to think that because my life has become easier, I am not willing to make progress. I also hope to accumulate something. At least the stuff coming out this year is above the level, and I don’t want to deal with the performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s hard to say fate. It’s unlikely that you will have a breakthrough in every drama, really. This is a market. To survive in this market, we can only rely on each drama and how to play the role well after joining. In fact, there is not much that actors can do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清远一所学校七百多名新生退学，官方回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259407]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 18:48:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to Qingyuan Desheng Health Vocational and Technical School’s blind expansion of enrollment in the fall semester of 2023 without approval and replacement with online courses In the case of face-to-face teaching, the Qingyuan Municipal Education Bureau has set up a city and county joint working group to station in the school, ordering the school to actively respond to the concerns of students and parents, conscientiously rectify problems, effectively safeguard students&#39; legitimate rights and interests, and ensure normal education and teaching order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingyuan Desheng Health Vocational and Technical School is a private secondary vocational school with 3,981 students currently enrolled (including: 1,215 in the 2021 grade, 837 in the 2022 grade, and 1,929 in the 2023 grade). After a preliminary investigation, it was found that the school expanded its enrollment without authorization, resulting in insufficient teaching staff and an inability to meet teaching needs, resulting in online classes replacing face-to-face classes.经工作组督促，该校秋季学期招聘的新教师陆续到位，基本满足教学需求，网课教学问题已整改，教育教学秩序正常。目前，该校已对退学的730名学生全额退费。清远市教育局指导该校依规办理2023级新生的学籍录入备案工作，督促学校加强师资培训和管理，确保教学质量。同时，为保障学生及时转校就读，清远市教育局提供市内有富余学位的中职（中技）学校信息供退学学生参考报读。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，清远市教育局将督促该校加快整改落实，依法依规办学。同时，对该校2023年秋季学期违规扩招问题进行立案调查，依法严肃处理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清远市教育局&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月26日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[2024国考大数据：先考公，还是先考研？丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://nfcms-cos02.infzm.com/__asset/e4daf879f3/24c0231f40.jpg?t=1698290703661&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（下）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259266]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/1O6gFp3jfetG9KS1ecdoaHUmtMhhrC1Xfl5P4qmW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/1O6gFp3jfetG9KS1ecdoaHUmtMhhrC1 Xfl5P4qmW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The expansion of the United States in Asia and the Middle East&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The impact of the two Vietnam Wars on the United States was actually greater than that of the Korean War Even bigger. The United States lost about 4.5 million soldiers in the Korean War, which was unprecedented in American history; and the United States did not get any benefits from the two Vietnam Wars. The two Vietnam Wars lasted for almost thirty years together. It lasted for a long time, especially the second time the United States retreated from Vietnam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Poison gas is not used in war. This is an international convention. During World War II, this principle was observed between the United States and Germany and between the United States and Japan. However, the Japanese often used poison gas on the Chinese battlefield. The United States also used poison gas during the Vietnam War. Today, among Vietnamese children, there are deformed and dystocia babies. The poison gas that the United States spread in the forests of Vietnam is still permeating the air. This is all evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/F8msmxBku7WtZAiXfoW8laKteCWCkYzH6GhMGWV2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;587&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/F8msmxBku7WtZAiXfoW8laKteCWCkYzH6GhMGWV2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Soviet control Within the scope, some countries in Eastern Europe, Northern Europe, and Southern Europe made several attempts to break away from the Soviet bloc. Every time this happened, the CIA was deeply involved, causing turmoil. Some of the consequences were national restructuring and the emergence of new regimes, but the only regimes that could maintain stability were the Hungarian Spring and the Polish Spring (the Poznan Incident in June 1956 and the Hungarian Incident in October 1956). In addition, the &quot;color revolutions&quot; in a string of Muslim countries on the Mediterranean coast in the Middle East, such as Egypt, Algeria, and Libya, have always destroyed the original order; and the economic construction that those countries had started has almost stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a geopolitical perspective, the Middle East is a battleground, and this region is also the largest oil-producing area in the world. The United States has tried its best to control it, starting with controlling Saudi Arabia. Saudi Arabia was an independent emirate that the British separated from the Persian Empire. Later, it became a &quot;wealthy rich man&quot; with a hereditary chief, but it became the &quot;beloved baby&quot; of the United States - for their bases and oil resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1948, when the Jews returned to their homeland, they actually carved out a piece of land next to Jerusalem to rebuild Israel - could the exiled Jews alone have such power? In fact, it was the UK and the US that were behind it. Britain was in ruins after the war, and Israel&#39;s main supporter was the United States. This country has its admirable features. It &quot;made something out of nothing&quot; and quickly built the country into a decent one. The level of Hebrew University is no less than the top universities in China and no less than the top universities in the United States. Taiwan&#39;s military research institute often asks Israeli consultants to help solve missile problems and also asks them to help solve problems of building nuclear power plants. These people are top experts. I have been to Israel several times and the people are very disciplined, live a simple life and are hardworking. But over the past few decades, Israel&#39;s courage and mentality to try and learn when it built the communes have been lost. However, the United States must defend Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States has deeply intervened in Middle East politics and launched three wars: the Gulf War/Kuwait War, the Iraq War, and the Afghanistan War. Then right after that, came the Iran War. Only recently did the U.S. military retreat from Afghanistan in disgrace. At the end of each war, the ruins were left in ruins, and the place was devastated beyond recognition. More than thirty years of war by the United States have devastated the Middle East. Countries on the southern coast of the Mediterranean and the northern coast of Africa have not recovered their strength to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are the consequences of the extension of the &quot;containment policy&quot; - the United States is addicted to expansion, and every president has a group of generals who want to expand. Blackwater International, which has close ties with those in power in the United States, specializes in the mercenary business. They have killed thousands of people and destroyed countries one after another. They are not responsible. The United Arab Emirates in the Middle East is also a product under the leadership of the United States: several small sheikhs in this area were united to establish the &quot;United Emirates&quot; - there are the most luxurious hotels in the world and the most luxurious cruise ships in the world are docked there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, post-war Japan was equivalent to a &quot;colony&quot; of the United States. During the Korean War, Japan provided logistical supplies and maintenance support to the United States, and also took the opportunity to completely update old equipment from World War II. In the 1970s, Japan&#39;s industry was at its peak and its productivity was the highest in the world. Japanese goods are everywhere in the world, including Toyota cars, Panasonic, Westfield Department Store, etc. Where Japanese businessmen are located, local housing prices can double or triple. The economy of East Asia has also grown along with Japan. The so-called &quot;flying geese theory&quot; - the coastal areas of mainland China has also played a part in this wave of economic prosperity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States cannot accept this situation: &quot;I supported you, and now you are riding on my head and taking away all my business.&quot; So it tightened money, increased tariffs, patent claims, etc. Using a combination of methods, Japan was driven underground within three years, and it has still not gotten up to this day. All famous Japanese brands, American companies have shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taiwan is smarter than Japan. It did not use American brands in construction back then. Companies like Taiwan Integrated Circuit Manufacturing Co., Ltd. applied for patent rights themselves - TSMC produced 80% of the world&#39;s chips. When Taiwan&#39;s economic model was originally designed, the lessons learned from Japan were taken into consideration. Taiwan&#39;s Evergreen Marine Corp. is one of the world&#39;s largest shipping companies. Greece&#39;s large fleet is now &quot;stuck&quot; by the United States, and Norway&#39;s large fleet cannot be blocked by the United States. Therefore, this &quot;leader&quot; does not talk about loyalty. The leading boss in China&#39;s arena is that the boss suffers and the younger brothers take advantage. The boss of the United States is: &quot;If you become my little brother, you have to listen to me and do whatever I want.&quot; How can such behavior not be disappointing? Recently, the United States has been raising tariffs on China and threatening the mainland with the Taiwan issue. From the East to the West, such behavior by the United States has caused complaints in the international circles led by it. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Beauty wanes&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Over the past few decades, we have also seen the prosperity of the United States, which lasted for hundreds of years. When I arrived in the United States in 1957, I happened to read in the newspaper that an African-American primary school student was blocked from entering a white school. The country mobilized the state&#39;s self-defense forces to suppress the people&#39;s resistance with the power of the government. This dispute between &quot;black and white&quot; has never stopped. Because the black group is still stuck at the bottom of society, no matter how hard Martin Luther King, Jr. tried, it will not help - racial disputes have now become &quot;racial inertia&quot;, and disadvantaged races no longer fight for their rights. Instead, fight for government unemployment benefits. Judging from the numbers, the United States is short of 1.2 million workers, with only 250,000 unemployed people. Almost 1 million people are receiving government unemployment benefits and are unwilling to go out to work. If there are few people to live and many people to eat, the economy will go downhill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;American science and technology is developing rapidly. Today, digitization, automation, and artificial intelligence have reached such an extent that there are no lower-level workers in factories, only engineers and inspectors. In 1970, I came from Taiwan to teach at the University of Pittsburgh. There was a general strike, the White House was shaken, and the country didn&#39;t know what to do. If the same thing happened again today, would it shake the country in the same way? If a country has a quarter of the population, it is essentially supported by the national &quot;social welfare fund&quot;. When the government&#39;s tax revenue is not enough, it can only rely on money printing to solve the problem. The real power supporting the US dollar should be international trade and domestic income taxes - but in fact it is a mess. Many American companies have their income elsewhere and their excess money in international accounts. Today, the U.S. economy is shaky, and all economic laws such as currency issuance limits are not obeyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1980 to 2008, two huge economic crises were caused by credit problems, corruption problems, false mortgages and other issues. Originally, these were problems that the capitalist system did not allow to occur, because a healthy capitalist market economy relies on credit commitments. Two economic crises nearly brought the U.S. economy to collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SnXMoQYx0RoIF2HMbbwDZ0Den6Mxw13zZapINkNc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SnXMoQYx0RoIF2HMbbwDZ0Den6Mxw13zZapINkNc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255339&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearest United States The economy, when it was supposed to be a period of great panic and recession, actually saw price rises and stock prices rise again - we all could see that there was something fake about it. This situation shows that the United States is deceiving itself. But there are so many disadvantaged groups in the country who rely on state subsidies to survive. What should we do if things continue like this? What should we do about these vulnerable groups who support the unreasonable and fierce right wing? The &quot;four freedoms&quot; advocated by Roosevelt were right, but now the &quot;fifth freedom&quot; has appeared: the freedom of &quot;don&#39;t mess with me&quot;. Whether you want to work, go to school, etc., everyone thinks it is a personal matter - such an &quot;independent spirit&quot; is not a healthy independent spirit. I hope that young people in China will not &quot;lie down&quot; - but the trend of the world seems to be developing like this, which is not worrying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than ten years ago, I wrote an article about reflection on American society, which later developed into a book: &quot;Sixty Years of Vicissitudes in the United States: A Chinese&#39;s Insights.&quot; At that time, I criticized the crisis that the United States was about to face: government bureaucracy, social disorganization, and extravagance and waste—especially waste on the military and national defense. However, the government has not fulfilled its responsibilities in what it should do: many of the country&#39;s hardware facilities, including bridges, airports, roads, and water pumps, are broken, but no one is taking care of them. In current American society, the most important issue is the national laxity: what the government is arguing about every day is whether abortion is legal, the rights of transgender people, etc. - This is not to say that these issues are not important, but that these topics occupy everyone&#39;s attention. The power has been reduced to a grandstanding project for politicians, and matters that are truly related to the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood are left unattended. This country is hollowing out its own spiritual culture and economic strength. This country is moving towards waste, laziness, consumption and hollowing out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;9·11&quot;, the United States used the slogan of revenge against terrorists to intervene in numerous disputes in the Middle East. In order to punish them, how much did the United States spend on foreign wars? How much of a bad reputation does it get? How much of the country&#39;s strength is spent on killing people? Spend it on hired guns? Spending money on drones? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most arrogant and extravagant Roman Empire in history, the most wasteful French King Louis XIV, and the most barbaric Russian Czar, their arrogance and waste are not as serious as those of the United States. If the big ship of the U.S. economy sinks, people like us living in the United States will drown along with it, and the world economy will also collapse. How to recover from such a crisis is a question that keeps people awake all night and unable to think of a way out. But it is indeed difficult to make up for such a failure in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been many books criticizing American capitalism, but American politicians are unwilling to listen to these critical voices, or are too late to listen - for them, the most important thing is how to capture votes and enter the country. Lord White House. When I started writing &quot;Sixty Years of Vicissitudes in America: A Chinese&#39;s Insights&quot;, there were at least twelve books and a large number of articles critical of the United States available - today I checked, and these self-critical books are gone. However, people of insight are still criticizing, and a few reporters and commentators in the New York Times, Atlantic Monthly, and Saturday Review constantly remind us that a crisis is coming. &quot;The fire is about to start,&quot; but no one noticed. This incident not only made me feel sad, but also sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I would also like to advise the “aestheticists” in China not to value only “beauty”. &quot;Beauty grows old&quot; will affect all parts of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have seen Americans working hard and seeing that the operation of American democracy is the accumulation of many people’s efforts. I have seen the United States’ assistance to poor countries and small countries, and even the support and support provided by churches to local believers in various places. Education is something I admire. Moreover, I once hoped that the American political system would continue to improve and be modified over time. Therefore, today we see that American society is disorganized, its politics is vulgar, and it is so arrogant and ignorant in international relations. You can imagine that American society has changed from a beautiful image in memory to a broken one in reality. Broken mirror, my mood is self-evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州地铁安检要求乘客试喝自带水，被索赔4.8万元，判了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 16:51:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Subway stations are public places, and the subway company, as the person in charge of management, has the obligation to ensure public safety. Is &quot;taking a sip&quot; of bottled water, a common security inspection method, suspected of infringement? Recently, the Guangzhou Railway Transport Intermediate Court disclosed the trial details of a related case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Passengers said they felt unwell after trying to drink their own water&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Taking Guangzhou Metro to court for compensation of 48,100 yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On December 14, 2022, because Zhang entered the station with liquid, the security personnel asked Zhang to undergo a liquid test. Zhang drank the bottled water he brought, and then the security personnel released him into the subway. car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Zhang claimed that the bottled water he drank was self-bottled boiled water, and he himself suffered from gastrointestinal diseases, which caused him extreme discomfort after drinking water, and this incident also caused him severe mental illness. Because of the irritation and distress, the defendant filed a lawsuit with the court, claiming that the defendant Guangzhou Metro Company had infringed the law and requested compensation for medical expenses, lost work expenses, nutrition expenses, mental losses, etc., totaling 48,100 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;[Judge’s statement]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;There is no fault in the security personnel’s request for “drink tasting”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Passengers should cooperate and support subway security inspection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Guangzhou Railway Transport Court held that this case is a dispute over the rights to life, health and body. In this case, Zhang claimed that the violation of his physical and mental health was caused by the security inspection behavior of the defendant Guangzhou Metro Company, and corresponding evidence should be provided to prove it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the Guangzhou Metro Company sets up security checks at the entrance and requires passengers to pass liquid detectors or &quot;take a sip&quot; if they carry liquids. This is because it is an urban rail transit operating unit. Therefore, the security personnel required Zhang to test the liquid he carried, and there was no fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, Zhang failed to provide evidence to support his claims of medical expenses, lost work pay, nutrition expenses, mental loss expenses, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The examination report form, outpatient medical records and other evidence provided by Zhang also show that he had been diagnosed with gastrointestinal diseases as early as the end of 2020 and the beginning of 2022 and had multiple examinations and medical visits. He was diagnosed with a sleep disorder due to insomnia symptoms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Zhang cannot prove that the subway security inspection’s request for him to “take a sip” of his own water has a causal relationship with the damage he claims. Zhang claims that Guangzhou Metro Company has infringed upon him and should be liable for compensation. Please, lack of factual and legal basis, the court will not support it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The presiding judge of the Guangzhou Railway Transport Court stated that security inspection is a necessary means for the subway company to fulfill its safety obligations, and passengers should support and cooperate as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Civil Code clearly stipulates that operators and managers of subway stations, railway stations, airports and other places who fail to fulfill their safety obligations and cause damage to others shall bear tort liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Urban Rail Transit Operation Management Regulations&quot; promulgated by the Ministry of Transport also clearly stipulates that passengers are prohibited from carrying toxic, harmful, flammable, explosive, radioactive, corrosive and other hazards that may endanger personal and property safety. Items coming in and taking the bus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a vicious incident occurs on a means of transportation, the space is very limited and it is difficult to evacuate in time to reduce injuries. Therefore, security inspection, as the most effective preventive measure that public transportation managers can take, is reasonable and If necessary, passengers should understand and cooperate as much as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To claim infringement, it is necessary to prove the existence of a causal relationship between the infringement behavior and the damage results. A general tort must include an infringing act, a damaging result, a causal relationship between the infringing act and the damaging result, and the perpetrator&#39;s subjective fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, Zhang claimed that the security check behavior caused physical discomfort and mental stimulation. However, the existing evidence can only prove that he had suffered from illness and insomnia before, but could not prove that he was physically injured after the security check behavior. Or the disease worsened, so Zhang’s claim for infringement and compensation from the subway company has no factual and legal basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“老实人”成了贬义词：语义嬗变背后是对消费和情绪的无度索求]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259338]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is generally believed that &quot;honest&quot; as an adjective has two levels of semantics in Chinese, one of which refers to morality. Honesty and reliability on one level, and secondly, law-abiding and orderly behavior on the other. Before the 1980s, &quot;honest&quot; was definitely a positive evaluation of a person. Whether in the workplace or in the marriage and mate selection market, the evaluation of &quot;honest people&quot; was similar to some kind of quality assurance and played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that honesty, reliability and law-abiding are out-and-out excellent qualities in any society with normal moral tendencies. However, starting in the 1990s, the semantics of &quot;honest person&quot; changed rapidly, and gradually became associated with negative connotations such as &quot;poor interpersonal skills&quot;, &quot;cowardly&quot;, &quot;stupid&quot; and &quot;low economic ability&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the Internet age, &quot;honest people&quot; have been infinitely deconstructed, especially in the marriage and love market. &quot;Honest people&quot; are directly linked to &quot;low emotional intelligence&quot;, &quot;cannot provide emotional value&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;, and become With the out-and-out &quot;minus points&quot;, &quot;honest people&quot; have been completely marginalized in the marriage and love market. A 2017 study showed that &quot;honesty&quot; surpassed &quot;poor economic conditions&quot; and &quot;no formal job&quot; to become the second largest reason why young people over 35 years old in a certain place become &quot;singles&quot; (the first reason is illness or physical disability) ). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a live broadcast not long ago, an online anchor became furious because he was called an &quot;honest person&quot; by his fans. Perhaps he could not accurately grasp the changes in &quot;honest people&quot;. Complex semantics, but he instinctively felt insulted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the quality assurance of character to the infinitely deconstructed stigma in the Internet society, what have &quot;honest people&quot; experienced in the development and changes of modern society? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Honest people&quot; wandering in the midst of social changes&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early days of reform, the semantic change of &quot;honest people&quot; from praise to derogation is actually not difficult to understand. In the rapidly changing social environment at that time, the market economy and industrial civilization were rapidly changing all aspects of society. The life experiences that &quot;honest people&quot; who tend to follow the rules and practice in the traditional social life model are quickly overturned. And because they fail to make adaptive changes and responses to social changes in a timely manner, they will naturally be at a relatively disadvantaged level and position economically within a period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, drastic social changes have created considerable &quot;grey areas&quot; in the economic field. In such chaos and prosperity, &quot;the bold will die of hunger and the timid will starve to death&quot; once became a popular survival creed in society. There are indeed a group of people who have made their first pot of gold in these fields. The cautious and lawful side of &quot;honest people&quot; determines that they are destined not to be one of these trend-setters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the above two points, the series of changes in the semantics of &quot;honest person&quot; at the end of the last century are actually a normal manifestation of the changes in individual value evaluation standards during social changes, and it is not difficult to understand. . After the social and economic order stabilized, the reputation and reputation of &quot;honest people&quot; took a positive turn. Especially during the period of rapid growth in the first decade of the 21st century, &quot;honest people&quot; were under construction and development. Showing a series of work characteristics gives honest people an aura of being &quot;down-to-earth, hard-working and willing to work&quot;, which improves the image of &quot;honest people&quot; to a considerable extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, the reasons for the infinite deconstruction and image decline of the meaning of &quot;honest person&quot; in the Internet society are much more complicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Honest people&quot; who are excluded and marginalized by cultural capital&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the end of the last century to the beginning of this century, first television and then the Internet had a major impact on social values. With the popularization of television and the Internet, the cultural center effect of modern society has begun to become prominent. A cultural paradigm based on the cultural center&#39;s lifestyle and values ​​has been created and introduced to the public through countless movies, television, entertainment and variety shows. spread throughout society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When countless young people living in the seventh and eighth tier cities, the urban-rural interface and the vast rural areas are immersed in the cultural products produced in Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen, they are actually unknowingly Accept the life patterns and values ​​advocated by these cultural products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, cultural capital uses a modern approach to reduce the vast majority of people to spectators, consciously or unconsciously watching a few people at the center interpret their lives. Most of the joys, sorrows, joys, sorrows and hatreds on the screen take place in the reinforced concrete forests of Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen. When &quot;small town youth&quot; and &quot;small town youth&quot; watch the screen as viewers, it means that they have subconsciously accepted the &quot;central paradigm culture&quot; expressed and conveyed by these cultural products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This cultural paradigm based on the super city has quite distinctive characteristics - the social environment of a highly developed commodity economy, the values ​​of consumerism and hedonism, and the concept of love and mate selection of the urban middle class. Way. The cultural center effect is so strong that when some film and television works try to change the subject matter or scene, they often fall into embarrassing situations. In a certain film and television work, the protagonist from a poor background wears a down jacket from a North American brand worth more than 10,000 yuan, using seven The fact that the 8,000-yuan iPhone is considered a joke is obviously the result of the screenwriter being trapped in this cultural paradigm and unable to extricate himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, cultural capital spares no effort to promote the central lifestyle and values; on the other hand, it marginalizes and excludes other lifestyles and values. The core of this cultural paradigm promoted by cultural capital is actually the basic feature of postmodern society, that is, the desire for consumption and the emotional demand anytime and anywhere. The former is the most ideal state of material satisfaction that an individual can achieve in a highly developed commodity economy society, while the latter is the basic requirement to combat individual loneliness in a highly atomized society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, under this cultural paradigm, a typical successful social individual either has endless money or the ability to please others anytime, anywhere, preferably both. Of. The problem with &quot;honest people&quot; is that they often have neither such economic standards nor such character conditions. Therefore, it is natural for them to become an excluded and marginalized group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In film and television works and entertainment and love variety shows, &quot;romantic, humorous, rich&quot; are the &quot;perfect characters&quot;, and the advantages of &quot;honest people&quot; are ignored or forgotten intentionally or unintentionally. On the contrary, &quot;honest people&quot; often become the ones who are ridiculed and ridiculed because they are &quot;dull&quot;, &quot;low in emotional intelligence&quot; and &quot;cannot provide emotional value&quot;. This stereotype created intentionally or unintentionally actually changes public perception in a subtle way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned at the beginning of the article, honesty, reliability and law-abiding are out-and-out excellent qualities in any society with normal moral tendencies. A society that regards consumer desires and emotional demands as the highest values ​​must be a society where speculation is everywhere and scammers are rampant. After all, the places where the romantic, humorous and wealthy &quot;perfect individuals&quot; mentioned above are most common, except in Korean dramas, are The pig is being slaughtered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[湖北省原副省长曹广晶受贿、泄露内幕信息案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259393]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 17:05:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 26, 2023, the Xuzhou Intermediate People’s Court of Jiangsu Province held a public hearing of the first instance against the Hubei Provincial People’s Government The case of former party member and deputy governor Cao Guangjing accepting bribes and leaking inside information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/6ffc4b22d9f960091bb13be24853dc6b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/6ffc4b22d9f960091bb13be24853dc6b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255666&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;720&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xuzhou Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate charged: From 2004 to 2022, the defendant Cao Guangjing used his position as deputy general manager of China Three Gorges Engineering Development Corporation and deputy general manager of China Three Gorges Corporation. General manager, chairman of the board, deputy governor of Hubei Provincial People&#39;s Government and other positions, as well as convenient conditions for the formation of authority or status, to provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, project contracting, project development, job promotion, etc. , illegally receiving property from the above-mentioned units or individuals, equivalent to a total of more than 216 million yuan. In addition, while serving as the deputy governor of Hubei Province, Cao Guangjing led the bailout and reorganization of the holding company of a listed company in Hubei Province. In January 2021, Cao Guangjing disclosed the inside information about the bailout and restructuring to others, causing others to buy the shares of the listed company before the inside information was made public, and then sold the shares for a profit of more than 10.42 million yuan. The public prosecution agency requested that Cao Guangjing be held criminally responsible for the crime of accepting bribes and leaking inside information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the public prosecution agency presented relevant evidence, the defendant Cao Guangjing and his defender conducted cross-examination, and the prosecution and defense fully expressed their opinions under the auspices of the court. Cao Guangjing made a final statement and expressed his guilt in court. Repent. At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 40 people including deputies to the National People&#39;s Congress, members of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and people from all walks of life attended the trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改革开放45周年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259361]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The reform and opening up that began 45 years ago brought ancient China to a turning point in changing itself. In the grand narrative commemorating the 45th weekend of reform and opening up, we return to the historical scene with respect, look for the promoters, experiencers, and witnesses of reform and opening up, and return with readers to that moment when passion and vitality regenerated.</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[詹安泰、王季思与张仲浦的一段文字因缘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259332]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-26 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5EJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;751&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eczHkaTEY1QFFMuIIjQEwbNVBHJ5zUlWPoh0T5 EJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I recently obtained from Mr. Zhang Zhongpu’s philosophical heir, Mr. Zhang Yan, his collection of sages’ books and artifacts, including Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi. There are one lost letter each to Mr. Zhang, and each of them is accompanied by a note of poems and a note of music. Following the elegant wishes of Teacher Zhang Yan, Hui Yu compiled and published it, writing a short essay and a brief explanation, for the benefit of others, and at the same time, it can be used to preserve the origins of a passage written by a senior scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhongpu (1912-1987), courtesy name Zhanyun and nickname Oubo, was born in Yugan, Jiangxi. He studied engineering at an early age and studied at Jiangxi Polytechnic College, determined to save the country through science. He then changed his studies to law and graduated from the Law Department of Peking University in 1937 with a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. He then specialized in literature, loved classical literature and was good at writing poetry. Dedicated to education throughout his life, he served as a Chinese language teacher at Nanchang Normal University, Linchuan Simple Normal University, and Yuqian Yuting Middle School. In 1934, he taught at the former National Zhejiang University, Zhejiang Normal University, and Hangzhou University, mainly taking charge of modern Chinese literature courses. He is the author of &quot;Guo Moruo&#39;s Historical Drama &quot;Qu Yuan&quot;&quot; (Shanghai Literature and Art Publishing House, 1959), &quot;Analysis of &quot;The New Story&quot;&quot; (co-authored with Wang Rongchu, Zhejiang Literature and Art Publishing House, 1983), &quot;Yan Milou Poetry Manuscript&quot; ( Northern Literature and Art Publishing House, 2004), &quot;Notes on Xia Wanchun&#39;s &quot;Ode to the Great Sorrow&quot;&quot; (Threadbound Book Company, 2016), &quot;Modern Patriotic Poet Huang Zunxian&quot; (Tianhe Press, 2016), etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth volume of &quot;The Complete Works of Zhan Antai&quot; contains nine letters from Zhan to Long Yusheng, Chen Zhongfan, Yang Shuda, Luo Xianglin and Liu Baiduan. &quot;The Complete Works of Wang Jisi&quot; contains nearly 50 letters by Wang. At the end of his letter to Zhang Hanqing in October 1987, he wrote: &quot;I used to occasionally write some prose, but lately I have been immersed in ancient books and have rarely experienced new life experiences, except for relatives and friends. Outside of letters and letters, they rarely write.&quot; It can be imagined that Mr. Zhan Antai and Wang Jisi still have a lot of letters and letters lying around, waiting to be compiled. The two lost letters disclosed in this article can be regarded as a source of inspiration, or they can be regarded as A little bit of celery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;804&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/e6YB0i4iq3BTklJMlxLz0Qr0K9bOPi21KNDlq5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhan Antai&#39;s letter and words to Zhang Zhongpu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Letter from Zhan Antai to Zhang Zhongpu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Zhong Pu Written by: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hui Shufeng It is reported that the great work is pure and healthy, and the workmanship is greatly admired. &quot;If you avoid the soldiers, you will face the water of Aotang. When you leave the country, you will still have new willow shoots.&quot; I recite it repeatedly, but there is still pain left. On the first day of the Yuan Dynasty, I occasionally wrote small words, and recorded them on separate sheets of paper to beg for correction. After many years of neglect, thorns grew on my hands. I took a photo of Huanghuagang and sent it to Brother Qu Chan. I hope I have conveyed it to you. At this moment, I would like to pay tribute&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chun Qi. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp ; &amp;nbsp; nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Diantaitonshou&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; on the second day of the first lunar month&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send Brother Qu Chan a piece of paper begging to be conveyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A brief examination of the writing time of this letter shows that it was February 1, 1957, the second day of the first lunar month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The letter involves Xia Chengtao (Qu Chan). According to the &quot;Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, Mr. Xia and Zhang Zhongpu went to Guangzhou to participate in a scientific research seminar at Sun Yat-sen University on January 5, 1957. On January 14, the two of them, accompanied by Zhan Antai and Wang Jinguang, visited Huanghuagang. The diary stated that they were &quot;majestic&quot; and &quot;taken a photo&quot;. This is the so-called &quot;Photography in Huanghuagang&quot; in the lost letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the previously published lost letters and the relevant contents of &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot;, it can be seen that after Zhang Zhongpu returned to Hangzhou from Guangzhou, he wrote to Zhan Antai and attached his own work. Check his &quot;Yan Mi Lou Poetry Manuscript&quot;, the sentence &quot;avoiding the soldiers and leaving the water in the Aotang, leaving the country is still the new willow shoots&quot; comes from Zhang&#39;s 1944 work &quot;The accumulated rain uses the Du Gongbu Hall to form a rhyme&quot;, the whole poem is: &quot;The accumulated rain and moss cover the grass, and the barbarian suburbs are temporarily stagnated by the smoke. The soldiers are left facing the water of the Aotang, and there are several new willow shoots in the country. The flying kites in the sky are startled by the meteorites, and the Peng in the clouds laughs at the nest. Zilan Ning It has the meaning of curing hunger, and the spirit of Yanjian Mountain is full of laughter.&quot; However, in the &quot;Poem Manuscript&quot; version, &quot;Yue Kun&quot; was changed to &quot;Ji Kun&quot;, which made the emotion even more intense. Zhan Antai said that &quot;it is pure and healthy, and it is extremely admirable for workmanship&quot; and &quot;it is still painful to recite it over and over again.&quot; Of course, he has the ancient etiquette of the older generation of scholars, but he also has a gaze like a torch, which illuminates the advantages of Zhang&#39;s poems. In his letters to Zhang Zhongpu in the 1960s, Miao Yue repeatedly said that &quot;great poems are fresh and elegant, and can integrate new ideas while maintaining the style and charm of old poems.&quot; , &quot;Great poetry can reflect reality, express new thoughts, and be admired after reading it.&quot; The two contrast each other, and the style and characteristics of Zhang&#39;s poetry can be seen better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Yuan Ri Occasionally Small Ci&quot; written in the poem &quot;Begging for Correction on a Separate Paper&quot; also survives in Teacher Zhang Yan&#39;s home. &quot;Yuan Day&quot; is January 31, 1957, the first day of the first month of the Dingyou year of the lunar calendar. &quot;The Complete Diary of Xia Chengtao&quot; mistakenly refers to New Year&#39;s Day of the &quot;Renshen Year&quot; of Xia Zheng. The full text of the Ci is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qi Tianle&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It would have been twenty years since I had talked with Qu Chan. Guests come from the south in winter, but don&#39;t leave in a hurry. At the beginning of the new year, I have memories, so I wrote this tune and sent it to Hangzhou and Zhongpu, Cambodia. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;廿年怅断南飞雁（三六年瞿禅将游广南，余有诗迎之），重逢遽成今古。凭吊丰碑（偕瞿禅、仲浦游黄花岗及广州公社），低佪浅汊（同日共泛荔湾），还对桄榔高树。懵腾醉去。又画里江城，百龙翻舞。见说芳村，野花团簇竞箫鼓（拟赴芳村花埭不果）。 &amp;nbsp;堪夸胜游处处，故人千里外，能再来否？岭峤平亭，湖滨点勘，未是流光虚度。思量共汝。要气派新开，声华豪举。小试牛刀，且昂头四顾。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;仲浦先生诲正。弟安泰俶稿，丁酉元日。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比对《詹安泰全集》第四卷所收《无庵词》卷五此词，序中“快谈”作“倾谈”，“兼柬”作“并柬”，词中惟阙“三六年”两句自注，其它皆同。自注中所涉之诗即《闻瞿禅（承焘）将有广南之行诗以迎之》：“看山我兴已难豪，绝爱君居傍怒涛。（瞿禅教授之江大学，门对钱塘江。）兼作毗邻有西子，几从舒啸忆东皋。投荒文字能生健，阅世肝肠试及骚。何日韩苏还过岭，春风搔首野云高。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;函中“抛荒多年，不觉手生荆棘矣”云云，虽系谦辞，亦是实况。 《詹安泰全集》卷六附录三有郑晓燕《詹安泰先生年谱》，于1956年条詹氏因夏承焘广州之行而连填三词后评曰：“时，先生赋笔已不多。”翻阅《无庵词》，可见1949年后詹安泰作词极少，平均每年不到两首，故这通佚函与词札也弥足珍贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/Vpnngr5arg5KE3jozSk9lsrSUGAIpFRDjMnKOhTn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王季思（右图）致张仲浦函。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;王季思致张仲浦函&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;仲浦先生：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;七日惠书收悉。浙师送行诸作，美不胜收。此间黄、陈诸老亦有诗送下乡同志，如能油印，当寄上一册。起近写散曲一套，兹附上请正。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《文学史》稿从第二次大放大鸣后，即已搁笔，不知何日方能完稿。 《桃花扇注》约二三月间可以出板。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中大干部下放二百人，中文系计13人，此后工作繁重，诗词将更少写了。此颂&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;教安。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;王起上&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1.20&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此信当作于1958年1月20日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1957年夏，浙江师范学院开始反右斗争，历时三个多月，120名教师、干部及一批学生被错划为右派分子，中文系的任铭善教授更被错划为“极右”分子。 10月份后，转入整风运动，即以大鸣、大放、大讨论、大字报为主要形式的整改阶段。接着，在贯彻“教育必须为无产阶级政治服务，教育必须同生产劳动相结合”的方针下，大批师生下乡劳动。 《夏承焘日记全编》1957年12月20日记载中文系开庆祝会，庆祝吕漠野、高厚载、余湜三人被批准下乡，提及当日第一批批准下乡者56人（《杭州大学校史1897—1997》称首批下放教职工144名），夏先生还撰联语“能下乃能大，到乡才到家”为贺。王季思函中所云“浙师送行诸作”，张仲浦《稊米楼诗稿》中有《送友人下放农村》一首：“山移九仞寻常事，千载愚公望不奢。道在稗稊勤格物，手栽桑柘好安家。戡天红雨翻春浪，报国丹心照晓霞。何用寻源问陶令，东风阵阵放奇葩。”夏先生12月12日日记也有《下乡》三首，序曰：“农村劳作如放牛、养鹅鸭、收稻诸工作，予力尚能胜任，各成一诗，以表下乡决心。”诗云：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;牛背归来胜据鞍，弦歌声里劝加餐。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;农村繁胜凭君看，看赛家家黑牡丹。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不是搴旗草檄才，下乡意兴尚豪哉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;竹鞭在手如军令，将得一群鹅鸭来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新仓高庾乐秋成，南亩东阡趁月明。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;辛苦当年龙战地，绿云万顷听蛙声。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夏先生1958年1月11日将《下乡》三首投寄《文汇报》，17日刊出，27日又在该报见到章太炎夫人汤国梨女士“和予《下乡》三诗”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;799&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/bZ2Ei54Cm0w1gwfNDPhhmU3ATfSTBnB91w3bta99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王季思寄给张仲浦的散曲。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中山大学当时的情况，较之浙江师范学院也不遑多让，詹安泰、董每戡等也被错划为右派。王季思函中提到“中大干部下放二百人，中文系计13人”，“此间黄、陈诸老亦有诗送下乡同志”，黄当指黄海章（1897-1989）先生，陈应是陈寂（1900-1976）先生。王氏所作“散曲一套”，内容如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;南吕一枝花散套&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;王季思&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;欢送中山大学第一批下乡同志&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔南吕〕〔一枝花〕几天来康乐园掀起了一阵风，过道上高挂起光荣榜；上贴着簇金花簸箕大双喜字，下写着正楷体泥金字十几行。沸沸扬扬，还有那“路边社”传情况，看谁是第一批上战场；你看这小伙子早准备好行装，便是那老教授也不甘退让。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔梁州第七〕正全国空前团结，喜中华国运方张，十五年赶上英国非空想。南连两广，北到龙江，东通东海，西过西康；雪山里开辟着林场，沙地里长出了青秧；不许那黄河水浊浪滔天，要叫那太行山让开大路，早已在长江上架起飞梁。上山，下乡，更看这新人千万向前方涌，翻得江，过得浪，改造了自然改造思想，百炼成钢。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;〔尾声〕下去的要把连村庄稼勤培养，留下的要使桃李花枝开满墙，康乐园早出现新气象。咱们要一吹一唱，锣鼓敲响，叫那些幸灾乐祸的右派先生气得肚皮涨。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;附注：康乐园是中山大学所在地，“路边社”是中山大学学生在整风运动中组织起来的一个快报社。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《王季思全集》第六卷《韵文集》失收此曲。又该曲字迹与前述书函迥异，当出两手。王季思1986年所作《半间书室小沧桑》中说：“前爱人徐碧霞是我生活上美好的伴侣，除料理家务外，还帮助我接待宾客，誊清手稿。”就像陈寅恪先生晚年写信签字常由唐筼夫人代笔，王氏此曲也可能是徐夫人手抄。但同篇文章中他又写道：“好景不长。1957年以后，由于众所周知的事实，我在课堂里称道前代诗人交谊的&#39;友朋之欢&#39;，介绍前人爱情作品的&#39;闺房之乐&#39;，受到了批判。碧霞不久因病去世，家庭里丧失了欢趣。政治上的避嫌带来了朋友的疏远。这是半间书室的又一次小沧桑。”徐夫人1957年初查出罹患恶疾，1958年9月不幸去世。所以这篇散套的抄写者是徐夫人抑或其他家人、学生，尚存疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《文学史》稿从第二次大放大鸣后，即已搁笔，不知何日方能完稿”，王季思参与其事早在数年之前，夏先生则稍有涉及。据《夏承焘日记全编》1953年9月8日：“得季思中山大学信，谓暑假中去北京，在北大浦江清家遇何其芳，说北大文科研究所欲集中力量，在两三年内编成《中国文学史》初稿。季思已由中大派往工作一年，何君并欲调予往参加此工作。季思望予能去工作一二年。”1955年9月30日：“步奎交来季思所撰文学史宋元部分。阅论苏、梅、欧诸家各节，颇多新意。”1957年12月24日：“接文学研究所《中国文学史》编委会游国恩、何其芳、余冠英函，嘱写《词的兴起》一章，八千字。”1958年5月25日：“午后寄《词的兴起》与北京大学余冠英。此综合大学《文学史》教科书初稿，本定三月交稿，逾期两月矣。”这部由游国恩、王起（王季思原名）、萧涤非、季镇淮、费振刚五人署名主编的《中国文学史》于1963年由人民文学出版社出版，是多年来国内发行量最大、全国高校中文系流传最广的一部中国文学史教材。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“《桃花扇注》约二三月间可以出板”，王季思等注的《桃花扇》于1958年5月由人民文学出版社出版，1959年4月又新出一版，纳入“中国古典文学读本丛书”，影响深远，不断重印，以至于今。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>