<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“骂醒恋爱脑”服务：当情感变成生意，爱真的能骂醒吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256554]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvljJ6IFmUtgobDkg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;950&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvlj J6IFmUtgobDkg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The TV series &quot;Xue Pinggui and Wang Baochuan&quot; broadcast in 2012 has recently been reinterpreted by netizens. The plot In the novel, Wang Baochuan and Xue Pinggui ate wild vegetables to satisfy their hunger for eighteen years, and are known as the &quot;originators of the love brain&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Come on, how do you want to scold me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just joined the Southern Weekend reporter Go to a friend and Z sends a message in the chat box. After confirming the request of &quot;be more direct&quot; and &quot;don&#39;t use curse words&quot;, without even asking about the gender, Z began to type:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She doesn&#39;t love you, why do you love her?&quot; , no one wants to talk to you, but you still act like an ATM machine?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Followed by a yin and yang emoticon, and then asked politely: &quot;Do you listen? If not, I will change it. species.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z asked about the specific situation only after the Southern Weekend reporter informed him of his gender and gave a negative answer. In this chat world, the Southern Weekend reporter is a &quot;love brain&quot; who gave up the postgraduate entrance examination for her boyfriend. Now she is deeply in the pain of &quot;being broken up&quot; and longs to be &quot;scolded to wake up&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, why keep it and give him money to fall in love?&quot; After listening to this &quot;story&quot;, Z tried his best to persuade him to break up and launched a series of questions: &quot;Why don&#39;t you understand, why are you still looking forward to it?&quot; , Why should you expect from him, he is handsome? Rich? Will he be gentle to you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paying money to scold you may sound a bit unbelievable. Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, this service, known as &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain,&quot; became a booming business on e-commerce platforms, and then became popular on social platforms such as Xiaohongshu and Douyin. Many users took orders on their own and paid for scolding. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;767&quot; height= &quot;1695&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In a Taobao store with over 10,000 sales, a Southern Weekend reporter ordered the &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot; service. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Rongrong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who originally coined the term &quot;love brain&quot; may not have expected that after countless interpretations , spread, this label may make some people who are already in emotional struggle more suffering, intensify their self-denial, and even declare it to the people around them becomes difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, with the release of the movie &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot; and the launch of the TV series &quot;My Earthly Fireworks&quot;, the protagonist&#39;s series of &quot;love brain&quot; behaviors aroused active discussion among the audience. Nowadays, &quot;anti-love brain&quot; has evolved from a word of mouth to a business, and many people who are stuck in the mud are reaching out, eager for some stranger to pull them out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can find many stores that provide services by searching for &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; on Taobao. In a Taobao store with tens of thousands of sales, different levels of escorts correspond to different prices. The Southern Weekend reporter selected a &quot;blind box&quot; that could only specify gender, and was assigned female escort Z. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z provides services using WeChat text or voice, charging 15 yuan for 20 minutes. Her avatar is that of a beautiful female Internet celebrity, and her circle of friends looks very life-like, sharing her feelings and thoughts. In this short chat, Z left a motto: &quot;Put away your tears, no one will like a girl who likes to cry, and he will not feel sorry for you crying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Southern Weekend After the reporter expressed the pain of not being able to escape, Z persuaded him to &quot;put a filter on him&quot; and &quot;sick&quot;, and then reminded him that the time was up. Z started timing the moment he added a friend, regardless of the fact that the conversation actually started five minutes later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can do it, believe me. All the love brains I talked to before said it&#39;s okay.&quot; The 15 yuan service came to an abrupt end. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Take the initiative to place an order, &quot;Love Brain&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Qing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Half awake&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the store owner Li On the price list provided by Yu, the large characters &quot;Eliminate Love Brain&quot; are very eye-catching on the pink background, and a line of small characters underneath reads: &quot;Online guidance from the emotional master&quot;. The price list shows that &quot;Love Brain&quot; is divided into three levels: light, medium and heavy. Customers can choose according to their own level. The service time of an escort ranges from 15 minutes to 1 hour, and the price ranges from 20 yuan to 180 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu is 26 years old. After graduating from high school, he worked as a game companion and managed the companions and companions under his guild. Later, the guild was disbanded, and she found that there was a huge market for chatting. At the end of 2021, she opened a Taobao store to provide chatting and emotional counseling services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, the news about &quot;cursing to wake up the love brain&quot; caught her attention. According to reports, this service can earn tens of thousands of yuan a month. Li Yu, sensing a business opportunity, changed the name of his existing emotional counseling service and launched a new business called &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the official launch of the service, Li Yu went to other stores to place orders and experience it. She placed two orders. One of the escorts started scolding her as &quot;too stupid&quot; before she finished telling her story. Li Yu felt that her emotional intelligence was too low and wanted to leave a bad review at the first reaction; the other almost Just chatting, not helping with analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these experiences, Li Yu told the customer service staff in his store to try their best to send orders to escorts who are experienced in emotional counseling. They can get started quickly. In addition, the escorts are reminded to pay attention to their emotional intelligence. Although it is called a &quot;scold wake-up&quot; service, they must also be careful about their attitude, unless the client demands straightforwardness and toughness. In general, Li Yu concluded that it is a type of &quot;relatively strong emotional counseling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Lu is one of the first batch of shopkeepers to carry out &quot;cursing to awaken the love brain&quot;. In April, short videos of emotional persuasion became popular on Douyin, usually accompanied by provocative music. Bloggers were excited and launched a series of questions: &quot;To be sentimental is to humiliate oneself&quot; and &quot;If you are not proactive, you don&#39;t like it.&quot; It’s almost meaningless to hang you up.” Xiao Lu was inspired to try to develop a &quot;scolding to wake up love brain&quot; service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escorts in his store have different backgrounds, including full-time mothers, corporate HRs, and professional psychologists. He lets them watch Douyin videos to learn the &quot;waking up&quot; technique. In this industry, the voice of the chatter is very important. Xiao Lu pays more attention to emotional intelligence and experience. Those who are older and experienced are usually not too bad in chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many shop owners interviewed denied that this service can earn tens of thousands a month. At its peak, Meng You&#39;s Taobao store could receive forty or fifty &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; orders every day. At its peak, it earned several thousand yuan a day, but it only lasted a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many stores that engage in &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; are derived from the chatting business, and are provided by the original chatting teachers. Meng You claims that there are about 600 escorts in the store, most of whom work part-time, and the male to female ratio is about 2:8. The escorts in Meng You&#39;s store are divided into six levels: blind box, gold medal, town store, male and female goddess, chief, and koi. They are arranged according to the frequency of orders, academic qualifications, customer preference and other conditions. The higher the level, the higher the charges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Meng You’s observation, more than 90% of the customers who placed orders for “cursing to wake up your love brain” are women. Most of the customers are between 18 and 28 years old. About half have relationship problems themselves, and the other half order for friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Meng You’s view, if a customer can take the initiative to place an order, his “love brain” is already half awake. “People who are not awake can’t order because they don’t want to be scolded.” Meng You said Southern Weekend reporter said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1972&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; has become a prosperous business on e-commerce platforms. Some shop owners said that at the peak, the daily income was several thousand yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Whether it has any effect or not, he said it&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Just started&quot; During the service of &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot;, Li Yu tried to take an order in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The client is a girl. She discovered that her partner has been chatting with others on other social software. After the two broke up, she has been unable to get out. After hearing this, Li Yu did not scold her. She felt that the other party was already feeling very uncomfortable and &quot;there is no need to attack others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu helped analyze with a straightforward attitude: The girl&#39;s partner just likes to chat everywhere. If the girl can accept it, then go to retain him and continue to be together; if not, then love yourself well. The girl did not give an answer on the spot and said she would go back and think about it. Later, the girl found the store&#39;s customer service and left a reward for Li Yu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escort, Xia Lin, has a neutral and steady voice. She is studying for a Ph.D. and her expressions are very logical. In life, she is good at giving advice to friends and dealing with emotional problems. She has been working part-time as a chat companion for more than three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to have a strong &quot;sense of separation&quot;. Although she can empathize with customers when &quot;scolding her to wake up her love brain&quot;, she is more accustomed to rational analysis, &quot;What I want to do is to help you solve the problem.&quot; . Li Yu also emphasized that you can&#39;t just scold, you should focus on the other person&#39;s situation, and you can&#39;t give strong suggestions right from the beginning. You should at least listen to their story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlene will usually first understand the basic situation of the client and let the other party talk. &quot;If this girl or boy has something he wants to talk about, he doesn&#39;t need you to guide him, and he will want to talk for two hours.&quot; Charlene said that it is important to guide the other party to explain the details clearly, which is helpful for analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She received an order. A boy had been dating online for a year, and they started talking about marriage without ever meeting him. Only after they broke up did he realize that he had been cheated. He places orders with Charlene almost every day. Charlene advised him not to compete with her. Although the other party cheated during the relationship, she did not defraud him of money and provided a lot of emotional value, hoping to make him feel relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Frankly speaking, many people are willing to listen to the truth, not necessarily to hear lies.&quot; Charlene told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Escortist Chen Qing has been engaged in escorting since January. When she first heard stories from customers who were &quot;scolding to wake up their love brain&quot;, her mood was also affected. Sometimes she just couldn&#39;t persuade her. &quot;Move&quot;, she felt a little weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As she received more and more orders, she gradually became disinterested, &quot;That is their life, and their life has nothing to do with me. I am just a bystander, so I can&#39;t go there no matter how powerless I am.&quot; Help them do anything. That&#39;s their life, choice and attitude.&quot; Chen Qing said, &quot;That&#39;s his life, why do you want to interfere? Tell him that you must break up. If something goes wrong, you still have this responsibility. I can&#39;t afford it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xiao Lu&#39;s view, &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; actually only provides a supporting role. Many orderers just want to find someone to talk to and vent their inner emotions. &quot;Actually, it&#39;s just a confession.&quot; He said, &quot;No matter whether it has any effect or not, he said it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking orders for a long time, Charlene found that most of the cases were similar. &quot;The commonality is that they may all have obsessions, and they may have suffered emotional harm, mental control, and PUA. They may have it all, but they refuse to give up.&quot; She said, &quot;Thinking and doing are two different things. You can&#39;t get rid of emotions.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Charlene once took on a case where a forty-year-old woman fell in love with a married man who was over seventy years old and could not get away for several years. Charlene felt that the other party was not going to give up, so she did not ask the other party to give up. &quot;Respect individual feelings. She has her own choice. She is an adult.&quot; She said, &quot;She just needs to reconcile with herself. She does not have to be responsible to anyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Charlene It seems that it is useless to analyze the general principles. &quot;Can you not know the general principles?&quot; A customer once said to her that after finding so many people, Charlene was the only one who could consider it from his point of view. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“When it’s time to be in love, you’re also in love”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Yu has been a companion for five years and has heard many other people’s love stories. She considers herself to be quite smart and gentle in relationships. cautious. But she hasn&#39;t always been like this. &quot;When it&#39;s time to be in love, she&#39;s also in love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her last relationship, in her words, &quot;just lost her IQ.&quot; During that period of foreign love, when the relationship was still ambiguous, the other party suddenly disappeared for two months. During that time, she often called the other party, but the other party never hung up or picked up the phone. Her friends advised her that she had met a &quot;scumbag&quot; who cheated on her feelings. She couldn&#39;t believe it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One time, the other party finally picked up the phone. Faced with Li Yu&#39;s questioning, he explained that he was traveling on vacation and knew that Li Yu had been trying to contact him, but &quot;just didn&#39;t know what to reply to.&quot; After Li Yu believed and forgave him for his &quot;disappearance&quot;, they were officially together. A few months later, when the boy returned to China, Li Yu discovered that he had another girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu feels the same way for people who place orders to &quot;swear to wake up their love brain&quot;. She knew that the process of coming out &quot;would be very sad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, emotional problems are difficult to control rationally, &quot;I think everyone is a love brain. In a relationship, no one is so rational, and emotional emotions lead to love. Brain tendencies.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the breakup, Li Yu couldn&#39;t get out for a long time. When talking to her friends, she pretended to be cool and did not dare to confess her pain. Because her friends have already tried to persuade her many times, but &quot;there is nothing to be persuaded&quot;, they may decide that she deserves it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu can only order online and ask someone to &quot;scold her&quot; to wake her up. She doesn&#39;t dare to go to the escorts in her store. They all know her. &quot;You can&#39;t lose this face in your own home. You have to find some strangers to throw it away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu told the unfamiliar escort that if she felt her behavior was silly or had other feelings, she could tell her true thoughts directly without worrying too much about hurting her. Some escorts directly scolded her for being stupid, &quot;There are so many men in the world, why do they hang on a tree?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hearing this, Li Yu was torn in her heart. In fact, she knew these truths very well, but she just couldn&#39;t get out of them. She could calm down temporarily only when she was scolded. She placed the order many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after Zhou Ningning broke up, she tried to find someone on Douyin to &quot;scold&quot; her. She feels that her ex doesn&#39;t like her very much, but she still wants to keep him. The escort analyzed all the shortcomings of her ex, and for a moment she felt that she was &quot;sick&quot; and would actually put down her dignity to save him. But a few days later, she couldn&#39;t help but send another message to her ex to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a staged thing, and it cannot be solved once or twice.&quot; Li Yu said that maybe the customer figured it out at the time, but then &quot;went into the abyss of emotion.&quot; There may be many recurrences, which are normal, and the &quot;wake up&quot; service cannot be solved once and for all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking out may be just the first step. In Li Yu&#39;s view, the most important thing to get out of the love brain is to rely on yourself. It took her half a year to really get out of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After a person is tempted, it takes time to get out of the relationship. Time is a necessity.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Xiao Lu and Meng You are the names in the industry, Li Yu, Xia Lin, Zhou Ningning, Chen Qing (pseudonym)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日防卫费“12连涨”，“美国因素”占几何]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256562]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1ThU2oKSzZDmUl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1 ThU2oKSzZDmUl. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 28, 2023 local time, Japanese Defense Minister Hamada Yasuichi was in the Cabinet The 2023 version of the &quot;Defense White Paper&quot; was released at the meeting. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the shadow of Fukushima nuclear contaminated water being discharged into the sea, the Japanese government has proposed the highest level of defense in history Budget. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Japan&#39;s &quot;Mainichi Shimbun&quot; report on September 5, 2023, Japan&#39;s Ministry of Finance announced the budget application amounts for fiscal year 2024 of various government departments on the same day. Among them, the budget application for fiscal year 2024 submitted by the Japanese Ministry of Defense More than 7.7 trillion yen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with 6.82 trillion yen in the previous year, the new defense budget increased by nearly 1 trillion yen in one fell swoop, an increase of 13.5%, setting a historical record since World War II. At this point, Japan’s defense budget has increased for 12 consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is one of Japan&#39;s steps to implement &quot;doubling the defense budget&quot; and also brings the Kishida Fumio government one step closer to the goal of &quot;total defense expenditures reaching 43 trillion yen in five years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;As early as the Abe administration was in power, Japan has been seeking to get rid of the label of a &#39;defeated country&#39; in World War II, break through the constraints of the &#39;post-war system&#39; on the development of its military power, and become a true &#39;political and military power&#39;. A big country.&quot; According to Sun Wenzhu, associate researcher at the Asia-Pacific Institute of the China Institute of International Studies, the substantial increase in Japan&#39;s defense budget is not surprising. &quot;Given that the Liberal Democratic Party holds a majority in the Japanese Congress, the probability of the budget passing review is very high. In the next few years, if there are no major changes in the political arena, Japan&#39;s defense budget will continue to maintain high growth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Benchmarking NATO&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;In recent years, Japan&#39;s economic development has been sluggish, but its defense budget has been rising. If this budget is passed, Japan&#39;s defense spending will set a record of &quot;12 consecutive increases&quot; since 2013. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 1960s, Japan’s defense expenditure has remained below 1% of GDP. The situation began to change in fiscal year 2016, when Japan&#39;s defense budget exceeded 5 trillion yen. In the next seven years, Japan&#39;s defense fee application amount has exceeded 6 and 7 consecutively, and the interval has continued to shorten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysts pointed out that on the road to military expansion, the Japanese government has shifted from &quot;running in small steps&quot; to &quot;running in big steps.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Japan’s defense expenditure exceeded the “GDP1% framework” for the first time, becoming a landmark event. However, Japan&#39;s ambitions are not satisfied with this. According to the plan of the Kishida Fumio government, Japan must not only break through the &quot;red line&quot; but also achieve &quot;doubling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Japan officially adopted three security policy documents: the new version of the &quot;National Security Strategy&quot;, &quot;National Defense Strategy&quot; and &quot;Defense Force Preparation Plan&quot;, clearly proposing to step up efforts to build &quot;outside defense capabilities&quot; , increasing the total defense expenditure in the next five years to about 43 trillion yen, reaching about 2% of GDP. What needs to be emphasized is that the 2% figure is exactly what the United States proposes to NATO member states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The year-on-year increase in defense expenses essentially reflects that Japan&#39;s defense policy and national strategy have seriously deviated from the &#39;peaceful line&#39; pursued after the war.&quot; Sun Wenzhu pointed out that Japan&#39;s military strength building has clearly &quot;shifted from defense to defense.&quot; &quot;offensive&quot;, and continues to strengthen its ties with the United States, trying to re-realize its ambition of being a military power that can &quot;offend and defend&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aligning the defense budget with NATO is just the tip of the iceberg in Japan’s efforts to move closer to NATO, led by the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Fumio Kishida took office as Prime Minister, Japan and NATO have continued to deepen their cooperation mechanisms, with frequent high-level interactions between the two sides. NATO Secretary-General Stoltenberg made no bones about it and said that no Asian partner is closer to NATO than Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the deep connection in the cooperation mechanism, the two sides have also continued to shift the focus of cooperation to the field of military security. In 2022, Japan’s three major Self-Defense Forces will go to NATO to participate in military exercises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan intends to further strengthen its military and expand its armed forces by following the United States&#39; strategic thinking of maintaining its hegemony through &#39;group politics&#39;.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, faced with a series of severe challenges such as economic downturn, high inflation, depreciation of the yen, and soaring prices, rising defense costs will become an unbearable burden for the Japanese economy. According to the &quot;Japan Times&quot; report, in order to pay for expanding defense costs, the Japanese government may consider selling its shares in Japan&#39;s largest companies, but it is difficult to reach an internal consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;U.S. strategic priority? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan’s record-breaking defense budget includes a “package plan” such as the procurement of naval warships, F-35 fighter jets and armored vehicles, and the development of new hypersonic interceptor missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s increase in defense budget not only intends to build a strong defense system, but also highlights the ambition to accelerate the development of military strategy toward offensiveness.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng, a military expert, told Southern Weekend reporters that this is fundamentally It stems from Japan&#39;s desire to &quot;become a political power&quot; and also the strategic need to cooperate with the United States&#39; deployment in the Western Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Japan released a new version of the &quot;Defense White Paper&quot;, continuing to reiterate that it must have &quot;counterattack capabilities&quot; and listing &quot;outside defense capabilities&quot; and &quot;joint air and missile defense capabilities&quot; as part of the Japan Self-Defense Forces The top two capabilities that need to be fully developed in the next five years. Relevant requirements are reflected in the fiscal year 2024 defense budget. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has finalized an investment of approximately 380 billion yen to build two &quot;Aegis system carrier ships.&quot; The two ships are 190 meters long, 25 meters wide, and have a standard displacement of 12,000 tons. They will become &quot;Japan&#39;s largest post-war surface combat ships.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;Aegis System Carrier Ship&#39; is not a simple defense platform. It has powerful maritime combat capabilities after being equipped with the &#39;Type 12 Coast-to-Ship Missile Phase II Improvement&#39; and the &#39;Tomahawk&#39; cruise missile. &quot;Zhang Xuefeng analyzed that this is actually Japan building a cruiser with both offense and defense under the guise of a &quot;ballistic missile defense ship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While building an anti-missile shield, Japan has also taken a multi-pronged approach to improve its off-zone strike capabilities. According to the US &quot;Defense Post&quot;, Japan plans to spend approximately 750 billion yen on enhancing the country&#39;s &quot;standoff&quot; combat capabilities, mainly involving the development and procurement of missiles that can be launched beyond the range of enemy firepower, including the &quot;Type 12&quot; &quot;Second-stage improved shore-to-ship missile&quot;, Jasm AGM-158 joint standoff air-to-surface missile, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These measures by Japan are to implement the goal of having a &#39;counterattack capability&#39; in the &#39;New Three Security Documents&#39;, and then make up for its own shortcomings in the offensive field.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in fact, deploying medium- and long-range missiles and extending the range of existing missiles is not only necessary for Japan&#39;s &quot;counterattack capability&quot;, but also the &quot;missile chain&quot; that the United States is eager to build on the first island chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the United States contacted Japan and planned to deploy medium-range missiles in Japan, greatly enhancing its ability to launch attacks from the first island chain. Japan&#39;s Sankei Shimbun said that the missile planned to be deployed may be the &quot;Long Range Hypersonic Weapon&quot; (LRHW) or &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missile being developed by the US military. Coupled with the missiles Japan plans to deploy to enhance its &quot;counterattack capabilities,&quot; the United States and Japan may join forces to build a &quot;medium-range missile network.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the United States’ wishful thinking is being realized step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 28, the U.S. State Department approved the sale of &quot;Jasm&quot; missiles to Japan, with an estimated value of 15.2 billion yen. As early as the 2023 defense budget, Japan earmarked 211.3 billion yen to purchase 400 US-made &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The range of the &#39;Tomahawk&#39; cruise missile is only about 1,600 kilometers. If deployed in the second island chain, there will be a problem of insufficient range, so the United States has always wanted to deploy it in the first island chain.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng pointed out that Japan, which is determined to follow the United States, is naturally the best choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;From Japan&#39;s perspective, the Japan-U.S. alliance is the absolute cornerstone of Japan&#39;s security, and its own security is inseparable from the maintenance of U.S. hegemony in the Western Pacific.&quot; Sun Wenzhu believes that relevant measures are to maintain the U.S.&#39;s hegemony in the Western Pacific. relative military advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Everyone has their own plans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Kishida Fumio proposed doubling Japan’s defense budget, in January 2023, US Secretary of State Blinken gave a press conference Publicly praised it and said, &quot;Japan&#39;s strategy is closely related to our own national security strategy.&quot; U.S. President Biden even said in his speech that &quot;I convinced&quot; Fumio Kishida to increase defense spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the United States is one of the main beneficiaries of the defense cost &quot;package plan&quot; announced by Japan. In the defense budget for fiscal year 2024, Japan will not only purchase a large amount of US-made equipment, but also plans to jointly develop new interceptor missiles with &quot;hypersonic weapons&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Selling weapons to Japan allows U.S. military industrial companies to earn huge profits, but more importantly, Japan’s military strength continues to increase and it is more capable of becoming a pawn in the U.S.’ Indo-Pacific strategy. .&quot; Zhang Xuefeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2022, the U.S. military decided to withdraw all two squadrons of F-15C/D fighter jets from Kadena Air Base in Japan, directly reducing the fighter force of the U.S. Air Force in Japan by half. The reason given by the United States is that the fighter planes are old and retired, but the American &quot;Stars and Stripes&quot; stated that the reason why the U.S. Air Force withdrew the F-15 fighter jets is because &quot;they cannot avoid China&#39;s attacks in the first island chain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;As defense difficulties continue to increase, the United States hopes that Japan will continue to enhance its military strength, play more roles, and reduce its military pressure on the first island chain.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan is also actively integrating into the &quot;group politics&quot; of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Fumio Kishida attended the NATO summit again, regardless of domestic public opposition, to facilitate NATO&#39;s opening of a liaison office in Tokyo. In August just past, US President Biden, South Korean President Yoon Seok-yue, and Kishida Fumio held a summit meeting at Camp David. The Associated Press stated that the Camp David Agreement signed by the three parties consolidated the &quot;Asia-Pacific Mini-NATO&quot; and deepened the security and economic ties between the United States, Japan and South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan is well aware that promoting &#39;military power&#39; and &#39;normal nationalization&#39; must be recognized and supported by the United States, so it must dress itself up as the United States&#39; support for the so-called &#39;free and open international order&#39; &#39;Right-hand assistant&#39; or even &#39;equal partner&#39; in exchange for Western countries recognizing their status and influence in the security field.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Japan also has its own little thoughts. In the defense budget for fiscal year 2024, the Japanese Ministry of Defense included a budget of more than 50 billion yen to develop new domestically produced missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Wenzhu pointed out that after the United States withdrew from the &quot;Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty&quot;, it once intended to deploy missiles to Japan, but Japan was not willing to passively accept it, but hoped to develop or purchase medium- and long-range missiles. &quot;Once a crisis breaks out, Japan can retain some room for maneuver based on the actual situation and its own interests.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the longer term, Japan&#39;s ultimate goal is to try to get rid of US control and regain its autonomy. &quot;If the United States relaxes its vigilance against Japan and allows its military expansion, it is likely to end up in a situation where it is out of control, which may not be a good thing for the United States.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[非婚女性可申领生育保险：非婚生育会瓦解婚姻制度吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256520]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More and more places have relaxed restrictions on non-married women applying for maternity insurance. Recently, the Guizhou Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Improving the Maternity Security System&quot;. From October 1, 2023, the maternity insurance benefits of insured persons will be fully decoupled from personal marital status; the Chongqing Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Optimizing Maternity Insurance&quot; &quot;Notice on Matters Related to Handling Services&quot;, starting from September 1, for insured persons applying for maternity insurance-related benefits, maternity service certificates, reproductive service certificates, and marriage certificates will no longer be collected. Currently, mainstream public opinion interprets this relaxation as the decoupling of marriage and childbearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the five insurances, maternity insurance used to be an independent insurance type but has now been integrated into the urban employee basic medical insurance. The special thing about this insurance is that individuals do not have to pay, only the employer pays. However, whether payment is made in the name of an individual or an organization, it is actually part of the unit&#39;s labor cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All five insurances are compulsory, but compulsory purchase is also purchase. Since an individual has purchased maternity insurance, of course he should enjoy corresponding maternity leave, maternity allowance and maternity medical services when giving birth. . If there is a prerequisite for having children after marriage in order to enjoy these benefits, then those who are not ready to get married but want children and those who are neither married nor have children should be given the option not to purchase maternity insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, allowing unmarried women to apply for maternity insurance is, in a sense, just returning to them the rights they should have enjoyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the decoupling of marriage and childbirth does not start with localities allowing non-married women to apply for maternity insurance, nor does it start with localities liberalizing birth registration, but begins on June 26, 2021. The &quot;Decision on Optimizing Fertility Policies to Promote Long-term Balanced Development of the Population&quot; issued by the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council is a programmatic document for the implementation of the &quot;comprehensive three-child policy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This provision applies to both married and unmarried persons. From then on, having children out of wedlock was free from financial penalties and would not affect one&#39;s personal future. Decoupling fertility from marriage. Under this general principle, it is logical to relax the restrictions on non-marital childbirth and restore the rights that unmarried women should enjoy during childbirth, which will further decouple marriage and childbirth in both directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that decoupling marriage from childbirth in terms of policies and systems will reduce the willingness and rate of marriage, and even disintegrate marriages and families. This statement is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, as long as the essence of marriage is that men and women form a family to cooperate in raising children and transfer survival resources to the next generation, then marriage will never disappear, only a certain form of marriage will disappear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t have a narrow understanding of marriage. Marriage usually has two meanings. One is marriage in the sense of natural law and customary law. A man and a woman hold a wedding in accordance with the customs, rituals and terms recognized by both parties, form a family, get the approval and blessings of their parents, relatives and friends, enter each other&#39;s social circle, and then have children. Raising children and enjoying various customary rights is very ancient. This is the essence and source of marriage. The other is marriage registration, the main and substantive part of which establishes the common property relationship between husband and wife, which is a practice only in the era of nation-states. In many people&#39;s minds, marriage is the second type, but obviously the first type is more fundamental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, &quot;couples born in the 1990s do not get a certificate after three years of marriage&quot; has caused heated discussion. It tells the story of sleepy and Zhang Shuo, a couple born in the 1990s, who went from college to getting married. It has been three years since their wedding but they still haven’t received their marriage certificate. Wang Sleepy said it was because something bad happened at the wedding that made her hesitant about Zhang Shuo, so she &quot;dodged&quot; the certificate the next two times with the excuse of not bringing a photo. Looking back at Zhang Shuo&#39;s attitude But he didn&#39;t seem to care. He admitted that he could understand Wang Sleepy&#39;s approach and he didn&#39;t value this certificate very much. Is this considered married or unmarried living together? The word used by the media is &quot;couple&quot;. Apart from not establishing the joint property relationship between husband and wife through marriage registration, are there any substantial differences between them and being married? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, even if a single child is born, it does not mean that one person is raising the child, it only means that the marriage is not registered. Even if a single person has a child and raises the child alone, this model will not become mainstream at least in the foreseeable future. Marriage and family are still the mainstream, and the more common marriage and family model is still that men are the main economic source of the family and provide transfer payments to their wives and children. This is still the lowest social cost way to raise children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if a woman with good family conditions or high personal income enters into marriage, she may be financially stronger than the man. As long as both parties do not think there is any problem, then there is no problem; if the decision is made If you have a single child and raise your children alone, as long as you don&#39;t think there is any problem, then there is no problem. Reproduction is a basic right, and it is important that everyone enjoys this right; as for whether a specific individual will exercise this right, it depends on the individual&#39;s economic conditions and values. More choice rights and range of choices are always good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, from the perspective of rights, whether it is marriage or childbirth, it is ultimately a matter of values. If anything can pose a challenge to marriage, family and childbirth, it must be values. A good value should be friendly to marriage, family and childbirth, friendly to mothers and babies, and should also see the dedication of the father. The foundation should be full of vitality, exuding strong vitality and abundant virtues. From the individual to the family, from the family to the country, life and death are endless and endless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[揭开岳飞初葬之谜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256548]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On December 29, the eleventh year of Shaoxing, Emperor Gaozong of the Song Dynasty (January 27, 1142), Yue Fei was murdered In the prison of Dali Temple. Twenty years later, Gaozong ascended the throne and the month after Xiaozong ascended the throne, on July 13, the 32nd year of Shaoxing (August 25, 1162), an edict was issued to rehabilitate Yue Fei. Later, Yue Fei was moved to Qixialing on the bank of the West Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Qixialing Yue Tomb has become a place of interest. But where Yue Fei was buried has become an eternal mystery. The author recently sorted out the Yue Temple documents of the Song and Yuan Dynasties and made some discoveries, so I wrote them down to share them with others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Review: Outside Qiantang Gate and in Dali Temple&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;First, let’s review the known historical data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the edict of restitution was issued, the whereabouts of Yue Fei&#39;s body were unknown.八天之后，七月二十一日丙辰，临安府传来消息，找到了岳飞葬地。监察御史周必大在日记《龙飞录》里写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;临安访求岳飞坟，在钱唐门外，当时私号“贾宜人坟”。今将以一品礼葬之。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/On3gRoyh69DODwdZt38o7ze2zwoBQAgpUc9ukjBq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;407&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/On3gRoyh69DODwdZt38o7ze2zwoBQAgpUc9ukjBq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;周必大《周益文忠公集》卷一百六十四《龙飞录》，清金氏文瑞楼抄本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是最早的信息。它表明，作为罪臣的岳飞，是被秘密埋葬的，借“贾宜人坟”之名，以避人耳目。遗憾的是，周必大所记过于简略，只有大致方位——钱塘门外。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年，考古部门在西湖六公园发现钱塘门遗址，并修建了一处别致的景观。遗址前的简介说，这是南宋钱塘门，始建于绍兴十八年（1148）。其实，北宋就有钱塘门了，倒是未见有绍兴十八年建造钱塘门的记载。由于考古发掘报告未公开发表，不知其根据为何。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/1jbO33jumNVpNHNCu6noJRy5HLmAmPnX2mNLbXLV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/1jbO33jumNVpNHNCu6noJRy5HLmAmPnX2mNLbXLV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钱塘门遗址。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一条线索见于最早的岳飞传记《岳侯传》，作者不详，撰写于宋孝宗时期，收录在南宋史书《三朝北盟会编》里。其中说：“（岳）侯中毒而卒，葬于临安菜园内。天下闻者，无不垂涕。”没有葬地具体位置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，《宝庆四明志·史浩传》讲：“岳飞忤秦桧，死于棘寺，蒿葬墙角。”蒿葬是说草草埋葬。棘寺即最高审判机构大理寺。现在大都根据明代郎瑛《七修类稿》的说法，指大理寺“在车桥西”，即今小车桥一带。这完全失实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳飞被害于大理寺，作为见证历史的重要遗迹，有必要多说几句。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南宋绍兴初，高宗驻跸临安，中央机构随之迁来，大理寺被安置在钱塘县治，县治则迁往纪家桥。大理寺丞游佀《重修大理寺记》说：“六飞（编者注：皇帝车驾六马，疾行如飞，故名）初驻跸，寺以钱塘县治为之。”由于距城门、城墙非常近，所以大理寺司直（官名）陈璧《大理寺新渠记》说：“南渡初，寺在今钱塘门内，枕城一隅。”其地在城门内路北，路南对面是金祝庙，约建于建炎四年（1130）。北边是绍兴十一年兴建的太一宫，再北是十三年兴建的景灵宫。两者都是皇家祭祀重地，尤其景灵宫，供奉历朝先帝，每月都要举行先帝正装出巡的“原庙”仪式。作为刑狱部门，大理寺与之相邻，甚不和谐。于是，绍兴二十年八月五日，高宗下诏将大理寺迁走。诏曰：“大理寺刑狱所在，与景灵宫、太一宫相近，令临安府择空地移置，如法修盖。旧基拨入景灵宫。”后来，大理寺迁到仁和县治之西，景灵宫在此建了一座车马门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/VmiggOLKK4fezrez5RftT9QO6zXjS2qGvY5YpTAM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1065&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/VmiggOLKK4fezrez5RftT9QO6zXjS2qGvY5YpTAM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《咸淳临安志》卷首《京城图》，宋咸淳刻本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《咸淳临安志》不仅卷首《京城图》有明确标注，卷五十四还有具体记载：“钱塘县：县治旧在钱塘门里三十步（今景灵宫车马门里是也）。”宋韩淲《涧泉日记》所记略同。步是长度单位，五尺为步。宋代官尺合今31.4厘米，浙尺合27.4厘米。 30步约合47或41米。如果现在的钱塘门遗址是南宋初城门的话，则大理寺可以精确定位。六公园北边的风波亭，实在应该迁到这里。只是，遗址简介说城门始建于绍兴十八年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“蒿葬墙角”的说法与周必大日记的“钱塘门外”不符。也许，岳飞被害的当时，曾临时掩埋于大理寺的墙角下，亦未可知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;演绎：九曲丛祠的演绎&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再往后，《朝野遗记》有一段生动的记载：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;其毙于狱也，实请具浴，拉胁而殂。狱卒隗顺负其尸出，逾城至九曲丛祠中。故至今九曲五显庙尚灵（旧在大理寺墙下）。 （隗）顺葬之北山之漘。身素有一玉环，顺亦殉之腰下，树双橘于上识焉。及其死也，谓其子曰：“异时朝廷求而不获，必悬官赏。汝告言曰：棺上一铅筒，有棘寺勒字，吾埋殡之符也。”后果购其瘗不得，以一班职为赏。其子始上告官，悉如所言，而尸色如生，尚可更敛礼服也。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《朝野遗记》成书于宋理宗时代，是一部记录社会传闻的杂记，不能视为信史。比如，作者说二十年后，岳飞的遗体仍然面色如生，收殓时还能穿戴礼服，不合常理。毕竟，作者记载此事时，已是百年之后。而淳熙六年（1179）岳飞之子岳霖在《赐谥谢表》中，有“葬以孤仪，起枯骨于九泉之下”的表述。它与可靠的记载“贾宜人坟”，也无法联系起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/dwX3xCSaviCfY539saYk6H9IGAYvUn2D5XqCAnPf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;789&quot; height=&quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/dwX3xCSaviCfY539saYk6H9IGAYvUn2D5XqCAnPf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《朝野遗记》，明末刻《说郛》本。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个故事充满了英雄主义和传奇色彩。且不说背负要犯的尸体逃匿，单单私自翻越城墙，即是流放二千里的重罪。但事件也有合理因素，当时临安城墙已破败不堪，“城壁剥蚀，日就摧毁”，“久不修治，颓损至多”，因此绍兴十二年十月下诏筹备重修。此时负尸逾城，确有很大的成功机会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明万历年间的《杭州府志》《钱塘县志》，都收录了隗顺和九曲丛祠的故事。通常，地方志会记录一些传说，以示重视。而清乾隆年间内府刊刻的史书《御批历代通鉴辑览》也记入此事，意味着中央政府认可为信史。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“北山之漘”和“九曲丛祠”，都是范围较大的地理概念。北山指西湖北山。 “漘”即水边。 “丛祠”是“草木茂盛的祠庙”，司马迁《史记》就有使用。 “九曲”则迄今不甚明晰。南宋文献提到钱塘门外有“九曲下湖”“九曲城”“九曲墙下”“九曲路”。对此有两种解释：一是钱塘门外有一座名为“九曲”的城池。二是它指西湖东北、一堤相隔的下湖水系，东边沿城墙向北蜿蜒至余杭门（即武林门），故称“九曲下湖”，沿水的城墙称“九曲城”。无论如何，至少可以确认，“九曲”指钱塘门外一直到宝石山后的一大片地域。南宋行政区划有“钱塘县履泰乡九曲里”，应该就是这里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nYIKZwN3OhROeKQjNochTMbZVeWq8Zi9QWA5baTq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;684&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nYIKZwN3OhROeKQjNochTMbZVeWq8Zi9QWA5baTq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《西湖清趣图》（局部），佚名绘，华盛顿弗利尔艺术馆藏。有人认为，左上部的树林及建筑即九曲城，颇有些望图生义。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;九曲有众多祠庙、寺院，有些特别冠以“九曲”二字，以区别于其他同名祠寺。 《朝野遗记》的五显庙，供奉婺源五显神，又称灵顺庙，南宋临安近郊有七座，九曲即为其一。但作者只是说此庙至当时仍然灵验，并未指岳飞葬于此处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;寄托：众安桥下&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;近七百年后，清道光十二年（1832），一位出差杭州的官员——桐城人吴廷康，偶然听说九曲丛祠的初葬墓仍然存在，在杭州城内众安桥下。随后在咸丰九年募资购得其地。浙江巡抚胡兴仁闻说，决定在此修建一座岳飞祠，并带头捐款。岳祠的建设断断续续，直到同治末，方完成主要建筑，是为忠显庙，现已不存，故址在今岳王路岳飞公园一带。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/l6xvbXfimIGoGcUIb2Yy6jn0PBBice1Kww6NU1C6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;675&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/l6xvbXfimIGoGcUIb2Yy6jn0PBBice1Kww6NU1C6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭城西湖江干湖墅图》（局部），清佚名绘，大英博物馆藏。岳庙上方，即清初所修满营城城墙。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这处九曲丛祠的确定，依据是本地父老的口耳相传。宋人记载的“贾宜人坟”“临安菜园”，在这里得到影影绰绰的继承。咸丰九年，杭州知府江士松胡《募修墓祠小引》说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;九曲丛祠，在今城内众安桥下螺蛳山扁担岭，或呼为扁担衖，或呼为下瓦巷，或呼为菜园是也，相传为王墓。旧有石碑，题“宋贾宜人坟”。今碑虽失，而核之志史及故老传闻，均皆确凿可征。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此地在南宋的临安城内，与宋人的“钱塘门外”不符。口耳相传，显然不能作为依据。当然，这无妨立庙于此，寄托民众对岳飞的景仰与怀念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/sIXZHG8pZ27oZR5WLEQdIxFzeiXHC1haYEvaoaey.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;856&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/sIXZHG8pZ27oZR5WLEQdIxFzeiXHC1haYEvaoaey.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭州岳王真坟》明信片，民国间杭州二我轩发行。此即众安桥忠显庙内岳坟，咸丰十年改长冢为圆坟。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;发现：《中兴礼书》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;新发现的信息见于《中兴礼书》。这部古籍，历尽坎坷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中兴礼书》是淳熙七年（1180）孝宗皇帝下诏，命礼部和太常寺编纂的，成书于淳熙十一年（1184），汇编了建炎至淳熙年间关于礼制的中央文件，共三百卷，它从未刊刻，一直以抄本形态存于内府。清代以后失传。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所幸，明永乐年间编写《永乐大典》时，几乎抄录了全部《中兴礼书》，分散在各卷中。 《永乐大典》现存仅约4%，其中抄录《中兴礼书》只有4处，远无法看到原书的面貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又所幸，清嘉庆年间，翰林院编修、上虞人徐松参与编纂《全唐文》，借机从《永乐大典》中辑录出《中兴礼书》。后来他将抄校稿交给文渊阁校理、顺德人龙元任，因为龙家有一副木活字，承诺摆印出版。此后，龙氏调任四川，携书稿至任所，不久故世，书稿遂下落不明。道光十六年（1836），嘉兴钱聚仁改任四川彭山知县，赴任途经重庆府，在书肆发现书稿。他曾担任武英殿校录，见过此稿，知道它的珍贵，于是“急购以归”。可最终，钱聚仁的藏书也失传了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再所幸，海宁藏书家蒋光焴，从钱聚仁处借抄了一部，海盐藏书家沈炳垣帮助作了整理编排。咸丰二年（1852），沈炳垣作跋，记录了手稿流传的经过，附在书前。这部抄本现藏中国国家图书馆，计32册、247卷。此外，国家图书馆还收藏有据蒋本抄录的另一个抄本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/fGInILAWypqGeinzDELsX17Xw5040hyYyzQmdWbV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;507&quot; height=&quot;1010&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/fGInILAWypqGeinzDELsX17Xw5040hyYyzQmdWbV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《中兴礼书》，清蒋光焴抄本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;涉及岳飞初葬的记载，见《中兴礼书》卷二百九十八《凶礼》六十三《诏葬》二，原文如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（绍兴三十二年八月）八日，礼部言：“准都省札子，奉圣旨：&#39;故岳飞起自行伍，不逾数年位至将相，而能事上以忠，御众有法，屡立功效，不自矜夸。余烈遗风，至今不泯。去冬出戍，鄂渚之众师行不扰，动有纪律，道路之人，归功于飞。飞虽坐事以殁，而太上皇帝念之不忘，今可仰承圣意，与追复元官，以礼改葬，访求其后，特与录用。&#39;本部寻下太常寺勘会。去后，据本寺申：&#39;寻会到所属本官元系少保、武胜定国军节度使、万寿观使，见在临安府钱塘门外宝叔塔后、地名霍山墓园内埋葬。本寺契勘，本官依令系正一品，今欲乞令临安府奏官一员，踏逐高原之地，依丧葬令格式，以正一品礼如法改葬。&#39;”诏：依。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是绍兴三十二年八月八日礼部上奏的请示，称为“申状”。 “礼部言”之后即申状全文。 “准都省札子”，意思是“遵照尚书省下发的通知”。以下引用通知内容，即七月十三日为岳飞平反的圣旨。接着说：本部随即通知太常寺商议。随后引太常寺商议后的请示，要点是：岳飞葬地已经找到，请求命临安府派员勘访一处墓地，以正一品官员的规格改葬。最后是孝宗皇帝批示：同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  礼部掌管礼乐制度和相关重大事务；太常寺则负责办理具体事宜，级别低于礼部。这份文件的性质，决定了它的内容毋庸置疑。它也可与周必大日记互为印证。只是，日记里是最初得到的消息，此件是履行程序后正式上奏的公文及批复，日期在其后第十六天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太常寺状明确提到，岳飞葬地在“钱塘门外宝叔塔后、地名霍山墓园内”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;徜徉：古今霍山&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;那么，霍山在哪里？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍山是座很小的山，在宝石山东北，属宝石山余脉，也是西湖北山的东北尽头。其名最早见于北宋初的《吴越备史》，历代杭州方志都有明确记录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山上有一处天然泉水，叫“涌泉”。后晋天福五年（940），旁边建起一座寺院，北宋治平二年（1065），敕赐庙额“清心院”。这是岳飞被害那年，山上唯一有记载的寺院。涌泉从清心院门前的石缝中涌出，“味极清甘，亢旱不竭”，高宗每天都要派人到此取水煮茶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/LNv1gr5Dot1j1jLIHXDTiAa11h0Z8QOg55fwBKj2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;745&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/LNv1gr5Dot1j1jLIHXDTiAa11h0Z8QOg55fwBKj2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《咸淳临安志》卷首《西湖图》，宋咸淳刻本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乾道四年（1168），清心院东创建了一座广惠庙，供奉广德王张渤，又称张王庙、霍山祠，落成于绍熙五年（1194）。广惠庙盛极一时，给霍山带来巨大声誉。每年二月初八，士女倾城而出，到此游拜，各色游艺活动争奇斗艳，《武林旧事》《梦粱录》都有详尽的描写。当时诗人也多有歌咏之作。 《西湖图》在极其逼仄的空间里，不但标注了张王庙，还画出图示。可惜庙废于元代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元代，山上建了一座庆忌塔，高丈余，形制似壶，俗称“壶瓶塔”。因此山又被称为“庆忌塔山”。明人认为它是春秋时吴王子庆忌的墓塔。 《西湖游览志》将它与《咸淳临安志》记载的庆忌宅混为一谈，大误。康熙三年（1664）庆忌塔倒塌，里面有数千枚“擦擦”（Tsha-Tsha，藏语对梵语的音译，藏传佛教的模制小泥塔）。 《康熙钱塘县志》认为是元代番僧所造，用以镇水怪，“庆忌”是水怪之名，很有道理。此塔应是元至元十四年（1277）番僧杨琏真珈担任江南释教都总统，藏传佛教在杭州流行以后的产物。壶形塔，也是藏传佛教的特征。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/JYTS8ecrWD7mri6EjCQ6GlcQepcvhEMpf43ggJZR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/JYTS8ecrWD7mri6EjCQ6GlcQepcvhEMpf43ggJZR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《万历钱塘县志》卷首《钱塘县疆图》（局部），明万历刻本，日本内阁文库藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《万历杭州府志》对有一段稍详的描述：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;霍山于湖北诸山最小，山形多骨，石笋鳞起，与巨石山类。濒湖诸山，至此为断壤矣。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明《成化杭州府志》记载，山北崖下有石潭，水色澄莹，深不可测。后人又称有三个石池。其一方圆三四亩，以回声称奇，声如小儿啼哭，俗称“哇哇宕”。清康熙年间，山又改称“棋盘山”，最早见康熙十年（1671）张岱的《西湖梦寻》。稍后，陆次云《湖壖杂记·棋盘山哇哇荡》也有描写，绘声绘色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/6PtfxGrKTVs5CimpDDh83zOS2Cf9VYvxI8oShOtR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;931&quot; height=&quot;573&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/6PtfxGrKTVs5CimpDDh83zOS2Cf9VYvxI8oShOtR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭城西湖江干湖墅图》（局部），清佚名绘，大英博物馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;光绪三年（1877）秋，般若庵僧人释妙然化缘募资，购下山北地段，拟刻《弥陀经》于崖壁。次年春刚有眉目时，不幸病逝。信士沈善登、许灵虚，护国寺释成方、上虞旌教寺释玉峰等继其业，光绪七年刻成。字大六寸，涂以泥金，蔚为壮观。山门、大殿、僧舍等陆续至光绪十八年完工。随后，欲入京请赐额“光寿讲寺”，以不得其人未果，大家便称之为弥陀寺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nFp59703FtnRFjmWINvB4mkGl0BvIQQsuKR8bVbT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;899&quot; height=&quot;543&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nFp59703FtnRFjmWINvB4mkGl0BvIQQsuKR8bVbT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;弥陀寺摩崖石刻《弥陀经》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;弥陀寺香火甚盛，以至于霍山再次更名，被称为“弥陀山”，并沿用至今。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/rEhCxnticabzioA6eEwtN026n37UnzDdGjxxUDMX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;951&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/rEhCxnticabzioA6eEwtN026n37UnzDdGjxxUDMX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《实测杭州西湖图》（局部），1929年上海商务印书馆出版。图中弥陀山标高64米，系按1916年浙江省陆军测量局确定的、以杭州紫微园天文点为海拔50米假定高程计算，折合现行海拔标准22.9米。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/F2Dkh38H0dEkyegHmKKbeEcfvAGoynws6eH0DOn6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/F2Dkh38H0dEkyegHmKKbeEcfvAGoynws6eH0DOn6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;今日弥陀山。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在的山体，呈西北、东南走向，海拔22米。东西约六十米，南北约二百米，只是百年前的一半，更远非绍兴十一年的面貌了。明代的“石笋鳞起”，尚略略可见。凸起的制高点巨石上，有“南无阿弥陀佛”几个大字，刻于光绪二年，已是山上最久的遗迹。它的旁边，近年重建了庆忌塔。西北的弥陀寺被修葺一新，成为开放式的弥陀寺公园，崖壁上的《弥陀经》完好无缺。三个石池尚存其二，包括山北的哇哇宕，但规模已小，回音亦不可闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3BAFp8lIIwlGDqJm3G9bg1SMCnaGPmKCWhkfhMXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;959&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3BAFp8lIIwlGDqJm3G9bg1SMCnaGPmKCWhkfhMXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;山北石池——哇哇宕。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一代英灵，曾安厝于此21年。流连山中，忽然想到，霍山在南宋也属“九曲”的范围。那一刻，我觉得隗顺的传说一定是个真实的事件……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 22:25:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“克重比黄金还贵”，国货越算越贵？回顾8年彩妆品牌销售趋势]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256550]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 20:27:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[预防出生缺陷日 父母究竟能给孩子怎样无“陷”的爱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256552]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 20:38:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;从宝宝呱呱坠地的那一刻起，就承载起全家殷切的希望，他/她能平安顺遂地从咿呀学语到蹒跚学步、从天真稚儿到追风少年、从漫步校园到成家立业……而这些美好憧憬，都建立在宝宝拥有健康体魄之上。健康的身体，是父母给予下一代最美好的祝福！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，命运的无常总在不经意间发生。中国作为人口大国，出生缺陷发生率约为5.6%，意味着每20个新生儿里就有超过1个孩子患有出生缺陷相关疾病。出生缺陷患儿的降临，如同折翼的天使，给一个家庭带来了沉重的考验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正值9月12日“中国预防出生缺陷日”来临之际，一位来自广东的母亲，用她的真实经历告诉我们，当面对一个有缺陷的新生命时，她走过了怎样曲折的路，想告诉未来的准爸爸妈妈一些什么……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021054116523&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;《守护宝贝让爱无缺》SMA公益科普片（压）-20230908.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/9d7a879f5576678021054116523/9fJxnbhkLGEA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/9d7a879f5576678021054116523/9fJxnbhkLGEA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;SMA公益科普片《守护宝贝让爱无缺》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我希望有一天我能够自己走路，我就一直想，我可以走路，这样我可能很快就可以走路……”仅仅6岁的乐乐，饱受脊髓性肌萎缩症(Spinal Muscular Atrophy,SMA)的折磨，他不能跟其他小朋友一样，尽情地嬉笑打闹，只能依靠轮椅生活，令人心疼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我的精神无时无刻都在考虑着他……”乐乐的爸爸妈妈用无限的爱，付出比普通家庭更多的时间和精力照料乐乐，不厌其烦地配合医生的康复治疗。乐乐小小的身躯里绽放出极大的毅力，他虽然不能蹦蹦跳跳，却在绘画方面表现出过人的天赋，绘制出灿烂的生命奇迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SMA是一种导致肌无力和萎缩的运动神经元性疾病，运动神经起源于脊髓，控制着人体进行呼吸、爬、走、头颈控制以及吞咽等活动的肌肉，是一种具有高致亡性、致残性的常染色体隐形遗传病。它是一种相对常见的“罕见病”，据美儿脊髓性肌萎缩症关爱中心、香港中文大学深圳研究院共同发布《中国SMA患者生存现状报告白皮书（2020年）》 统计，SMA在新生儿发病率约为1/6000～1/10000，人群携带率为1/40～1/50，相当于每40-50人中就有1名SMA基因的携带者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/xx2fKcEesVrS8T3INvUIAmuGQEFlCfzkzmPQRL4W.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;746&quot; height=&quot;582&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/xx2fKcEesVrS8T3INvUIAmuGQEFlCfzkzmPQRL4W.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;SMA基因遗传方式&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SMA致病变异在人群中的携带率高，患者病情严重、花费大、预后差，生存和生活质量低下，造成家庭不堪重负。因此，涵盖婚前、孕前、孕期、新生儿和儿童各阶段的SMA预防，既能提高出生人口素质，还能为患儿的身心健康提供有效的帮助和保障。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;SMA三级预防指南明确：SMA筛查先行&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年5月，由中华医学会神经病学分会神经遗传学组牵头国内多学科专家讨论并撰写的《脊髓性肌萎缩症中国三级预防指南》（简称《指南》）正式发布，提出“SMA三级预防策略”：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一级预防：针对高危人群和一般人群进行扩展性携带者筛查（expanded carrier screening，ECS），并进行干预，避免SMA出生缺陷的发生；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二级预防：通过产前诊断减少SMA患者的出生；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三级预防：通过对新生儿/儿童期筛查，实现早期发现，早期诊断，早期干预。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/Pg1urEsxVEpswU96FAupfzB92I7UraRwDb1dWK45.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/Pg1urEsxVEpswU96FAupfzB92I7UraRwDb1dWK45.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“SMA三级预防策略”目标人群：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;重点人群：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;确诊为SMA患者的家庭成员；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SMN1致病变异携带者（SMA携带者）及其配偶；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生育过SMA患儿的夫妻；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有SMA临床表现的患者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2、一般人群：未发生SMA临床事件的所有育龄人群。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《指南》指出，目前在国内一级预防的意识还非常薄弱，现行的常规婚检（非强制性）和产检中均不包括对SMA等常见遗传疾病的筛查。建议准爸妈们在孕前进行SMA筛查，可考虑SMA基因筛查、单基因遗传病携带者筛查等检测。备孕女性检查正常，后续可进行正常产检。若其为携带者，则配偶也要进行筛查，如配偶正常，后续可进行正常产检。如夫妻双方同为SMA携带者时，每次怀孕都有25%的概率会生下患儿，则孕妇应及时进行生育前遗传咨询及产前诊断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相信随着社会大众、临床医生对SMA 疾病的认知水平不断提升，更多区域将逐步把婚前、孕前、产前人群的SMA基因检测列入民生项目实施，SMA携带者筛查率必会逐步提升，有效降低SMA发生率，提高出生人口素质。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;构建好“三道防线”预防出生缺陷&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除了SMA以外，出生缺陷疾病还包括先天性心脏病、多指（趾）、唇裂、神经管缺陷、先天性脑积水、唐氏综合征等，目前已知的出生缺陷病种至少有8000-10000种。据《中国出生缺陷防治报告（2012）》统计，我国出生缺陷发生率在5.6%左右，每年新增出生缺陷数约90万例。出生缺陷已成为我国严重的公共卫生问题，影响儿童的生存和生活质量，给患儿及其家庭带来巨大痛苦和经济负担。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何预防出生缺陷悲剧的发生？世界卫生组织WHO倡议，构建好“三道防线”是关键：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一级预防是在婚前、孕前和孕早期进行健康教育、优生检查和咨询指导，预防出生缺陷的发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二级预防是在孕期开展产前筛查和产前诊断，减少致死、严重致残缺陷儿的出生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三级预防是对新生儿进行先天性疾病筛查和诊断，对出生缺陷患儿进行治疗康复，减少儿童残疾，提高患儿生存质量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为进一步加强出生缺陷防治健康教育，深入推进出生缺陷综合防治和健康中国建设，国家卫生健康委组织编写了《出生缺陷防治健康教育核心信息》20条，当中特别指出，地中海贫血高发地区的夫妇双方应当接受地贫筛查；孕妇首次产前检查时应当接受艾滋病、梅毒、乙肝筛查；孕中期应当接受超声产前筛查,及时发现严重胎儿结构畸形；孕期应当接受唐氏综合征产前筛查；新生儿出生后应当及时接受苯丙酮尿症、先天性甲状腺功能减低症和听力障碍等疾病筛查……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多出生缺陷相关的疾病基本都可以通过基因检测实现早发现。基因检测能做到分析个体基因的情况，明确个体有无发生基因突变以及基因突变后引起的疾病风险高低，临床医生可以根据基因检测报告结合个体临床情况，及时了解致病性基因携带情况。对于高危夫妇可以在孕期进行针对该基因的产前诊断，从而预防患儿的出生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预防出生缺陷，科学健康孕育，需要准父母们的重视和行动！只有做好三级预防，为新生命筑牢三道健康防线，才能有效预防出生缺陷，孕育健康生命！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[两家金融机构被高额处罚：国内反洗钱罚单翻番]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256540]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;8月31日，中国人民银行广东省分行公布其自挂牌以来首批行政处罚信息，广州银行股份有限公司、广发证券股份有限公司和广州合利宝支付科技有限公司3家辖内机构和13名负责人上榜。其中，因涉违反反洗钱等相关规定，广州银行和广发证券分别被罚896.9万元和486万元。这是人民银行全国系统2023年以来开出罚金最高的两大罚单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人民银行广东省分行有关人士向南方周末新金融研究中心研究员确认，上述罚单已落地执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末“牧羊犬”——中国金融业合规云平台（下称“牧羊犬平台”）监测数据更显示，2023年前8个月，人民银行全国系统累计开出行政罚单1176条，其中111条涉及违反反洗钱业务管理规定，49家机构和62名个人因此被罚，罚款合计3850.61万元，同比分别增长122%、104%、138%和30.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融机构和从业人员哪些行为违反了反洗钱规定？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;广州银行领10张罚单，8张涉反洗钱&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;人民银行广东省分行自2023年8月18日正式挂牌。不到两周时间，人民银行广东省分行发布首份行政处罚信息公示表。其中，行政处罚决定书文号为“广东银罚决字〔2023〕1号”的罚单归属广州银行股份有限公司，2号至10号分别归属该行9名业务部门时任负责人。换言之，广州银行一次性收到人行广东省分行10份罚单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/2Fngl21GuFuTtRQtSgP1YYcSWczM7BpKwwRcsK8f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/2Fngl21GuFuTtRQtSgP1YYcSWczM7BpKwwRcsK8f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该行此次受罚的违法行为包括七项。其中，违反反洗钱业务管理规定的行为格外受到关注。上述十张罚单中有八张涉及违法反洗钱业务管理规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分细项看，除广州银行违反反洗钱业务管理规定外，该行受罚负责人来自合规部（法律事务部）、授信审批部、会计结算部、金融科技部、公司金融部、零售金融管理部、普惠金融部（消费金融中心）和信用卡中心八个一级部门，涵盖该行前中后台各大要害部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被罚的九人中，除一人是部门总助外，另外八人均为时任各部门总经理。其中，张某和侯某雄均为该行时任合规部（法律事务部）总经理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从违法行为类型看，九人中有七人对该行违反反洗钱业务管理规定的行为负直接责任。其中，六人次涉及“未按照规定履行客户身份识别义务”或“未按照规定重新识别客户”，四人次涉及“未按规定报送大额交易报告或者可疑交易报告”，两人次因“未按照规定保存客户身份资料和交易记录”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于上述违法行为，人行广东省分行对广州银行及其中两名负责人予以警告，并对广州银行罚款896.9万元；9名部门负责人分别被罚款2.6万元至14万元不等，合计罚款金额67.5万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州银行对南方周末新金融研究中心称，本次处罚基于原人民银行广州分行对广州银行开展综合执法检查中发现的问题作出，所涉事项主要是2021年及此前年度的存量业务问题。广州银行高度重视，诚恳接受处罚与监督，积极推进整改落实，并已按监管要求完成整改。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;广发证券领4张罚单，全部涉反洗钱&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;广州银行受罚同日，广发证券也因违反反洗钱业务管理规定收到人行罚单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据人行广东省分行公布的“广东银罚决字〔2023〕11号”行政处罚决定书，广发证券违反反洗钱业务管理规定，“未按照规定履行客户身份识别义务”和“未按规定报送可疑交易报告”，罚款486万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该机构时任运营管理部总经理、合规与法律事务部副总经理和信息技术部副总经理3人，也因违反上述反洗钱业务管理规定的行为而分别被罚3.7万、3.5万和4.4万元，合计罚款金额11.6万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/BoIFho9NWgVV28q1F0N7C8FGAmIJ1KLPYBe3UmI5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1161&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/BoIFho9NWgVV28q1F0N7C8FGAmIJ1KLPYBe3UmI5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250451&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;反洗钱罚单同比翻番&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;组织协调反洗钱工作并对涉嫌洗钱的资金进行监测，是人民银行的法定职责之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末“牧羊犬”平台监测数据显示，在人行系统2023年前8个月发布的1176条行政处罚信息中，涉及反洗钱的罚单共有111条，占比9.4%；与2022年同期相比，罚单数量增长122%，占比提升6.1个百分点。这显示人民银行系统在反洗钱工作方面愈加有力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;111条处罚信息中，包括49家机构和62名个人，其中机构被罚款金额合计3693.71万元，个人被罚金额156.9万元，两者合计3850.61万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与2022年同期相比，受罚机构和个人的数量分别增长104%、138%，机构和个人罚款金额分别增长27.9%和148%，总罚款金额增长30.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从反洗钱罚款金额排名观察，此次公布处罚的广州银行和广发证券分列第一和第二，江苏江阴农村商业银行、新疆乌鲁木齐农村商业银行和广东开平农村商业银行也因反洗钱不力而被罚百万以上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/t0gyieQHpPZsXnvDdp6EcHWSqwFtukovLRs0CWnK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1417&quot; height=&quot;1181&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/t0gyieQHpPZsXnvDdp6EcHWSqwFtukovLRs0CWnK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人民银行2023年反洗钱工作会议要求，2023年要加快构建反洗钱工作新格局，着力推动反洗钱工作高质量发展。其中，2023年要持续提升反洗钱监测分析能力，进一步完善反洗钱数据使用和管理。2023年8月1日，中国人民银行、国家外汇管理局在2023年下半年工作会议上再次强调全面强化反洗钱工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，作为反洗钱的主战场，金融机构应该严格遵守《中华人民共和国反洗钱法》和《金融机构反洗钱规定》《公安部、中国人民银行关于可疑交易线索核查工作的合作规定》等法律法规的相关规定，进一步强化数字金融系统，提高合规水平，加大反洗钱力度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3个月6名教师自杀，韩国教师为何总被告“虐童”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256528]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;被压抑的韩国教师界开始反抗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月4日，被韩国教师界命名为“停止公共教育日”，数万名韩国教师请假罢课，前往首尔国会大厦前，悼念首尔瑞草区自杀教师金某（警方为保护隐私，未公布死者姓名）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一天，是金某逝世的49天祭日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自7月18日，24岁女教师金某自杀后，韩国社会便掀起讨伐滥用“学生权利侵犯教师权威”的巨浪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三个月来，在首尔、釜山、京畿道等地，数万名教师身着黑衣将政府大厦周边的道路“染”成了黑色。他们举牌称“寻找真相就是纪念”“不要放任教师死亡”，呼吁教育部保护教师权威。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾经众人敬仰的韩国教师，成了极易被家长投诉的危险职业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月5日，又一名韩国小学教师A某（警方为保护隐私，未公布死者姓名）选择结束生命。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三年前，该教师被家长控诉“虐待儿童”。经司法调查发现，A某不存在虐童行为，可家长仍在恶意投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据韩国教育部统计，过去五年至少有100名老师走上轻生之路，其中一半以上是小学老师。他们中的大多数，均遭遇过不同程度的学生暴力、家长恶意投诉和校方压制问题等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/Au0iXORjt0gq8qXUPSpO35bOo6EigdWe5D15939Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height=&quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/Au0iXORjt0gq8qXUPSpO35bOo6EigdWe5D15939Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月2日，韩国首尔永登浦区国会大路，数万名教师身着黑衣，呼吁“恢复教师权威”。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不断离世的教师&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;韩国教师界的怒火，始于24岁首尔女教师之死。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月18日早上，金某倒在了瑞二小学的教务室里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金某两年前从教育类大学毕业，成为首尔瑞草区瑞二小学的一名小学老师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了探明自杀原因，首尔教师工会在授权后公开了金某的个人日记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我总是喘不过气。吃饭的时候手会发抖，眼泪也差点流了出来。”在7月3日，她很大篇幅提及教学工作压力大和一项“铅笔事件”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《首尔经济新闻》报道，“铅笔事件”是指金某班上一女生用铅笔戳前排男生书包，男生的额头不小心被铅笔划伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;校方记录称，“铅笔事件”经双方家长和学生沟通，已和解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金某去世两日后，瑞二小学校长则称“金某班级没有校园暴力的举报”。韩国警方在最初甚至将“金某自杀归咎为恋情不顺”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但事发后韩国教师论坛多则帖子称：“金某自杀是因为某些家长的恶意投诉。家长说她没有处理好，甚至一天打几十个电话威胁她。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截止到9月2日，韩国警方已调查了10名家长、相关教师，他们在金某通话记录中发现“铅笔事件”涉事家长与金某通话时确实出言不逊，但该行为不构成刑事指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方尚未确认金某是因对学校不满或与家长矛盾而自杀的。她也没有留下遗书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金某去世后，越来越多的人前往瑞二小学一年级教室区献花、悼念。在教学区的走廊上，彩色的便利贴上写满了控诉、安慰、惋惜和怒吼，一条留言刺眼地写着：一定要有人死才能改变社会吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当教师权威被侵犯时，学校和教育部门更多选择沉默，或是偏袒学生一方。”多名韩国教师向南方周末记者表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在当地看来，家长指控老师“虐童”、频繁骚扰，已经严重影响了教师的身心健康。南方周末记者统计韩国媒体报道发现，过去三个月里，首尔、京畿道、全罗北道等地有6位教师离开了这个世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“我们讲课时不敢大声说话”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;尽管韩国教育部以“教师集体行动违反《国家公务员法》”为由，敦促教师不要参与抗议。但随着多起教师自杀案、教师被霸凌案浮出水面，前去参加金某追悼会的教师越聚越多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在9月4日停止公共教育日里，我们学校有三分之一的老师都请假了。”仁川木乡小学老师印浩然告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据韩联社报道，在两天前的9月2日，首尔永登浦区国会大路附近举行的集会上，20万教师一同抗议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韩国，公立学校老师亦是政府公务员。在编的小学老师必须毕业于教育类大学，再通过“百里挑一”的地方公务员聘用考试，才能成为特定地区的老师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印浩然在2021年从首尔教育大学毕业，只花一年就考上了仁川教育厅的教师编制。“我的同学还有考三年没考过的，他们只能暂时当临时教师”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我小时候是被老师打大的。”1994年出生的印浩然调侃，“可现在韩国教师的整体文化水平和素质都很高。”他当年考入首尔教育大学时，与首尔大学的录取分数差不多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国小学老师是全科老师，工作繁杂且琐碎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金车明在京畿道一所公立小学工作了15年，他每学年要负责班上的韩文、数学、艺体等各项课程。“还要负责教科书采购、座椅定制、摄像头管理等事务，以及与家长沟通的工作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“瑞草教师自杀案”后，多位韩国教师及家属陆续揭开韩国社会对教师的恶意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月19日，一位六年级女老师的爱人在匿名网站上称：“我的妻子三周前被六年级的学生辱骂、殴打。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国CBS广播电台报道显示，仅在2022年，京畿道教育厅便接到了八百多起“侵犯教师权威”的报案。“侵犯教权的行为不光是言语暴力、身体暴力，还有互联网上对教师的性骚扰、诽谤内容。”京畿道教育厅厅长林泰熙在采访中透露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韩国教师教育工作者工会和绿色医院《2023年教师职业相关心理健康调查结果》中发现，超过63%的韩国教师有抑郁症状，38%为重度抑郁症状。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如今摆在我们面前的困境是，要人身安全还是要做教师的职业理想？”金车明向南方周末记者坦言。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数教师的职业难题，来源于班上的“问题学生”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2023年5月韩国教员团体总联合会的一份问卷调查中，超过30%的教师苦于“如何指导问题学生”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;印浩然对于如何处理调皮的学生感到头疼。在他执教的小学里，学校每学年会重新分班，将“重点关注生”（问题学生）打乱到各个班级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年秋季学年，他二十多人的班级里分到了五个“重点关注生”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正常情况下，印浩然遇到调皮学生，会主动告诉他（她）哪些行为应该改正，并制定规则。可如果学生不听话，印浩然也无法强制管教学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多韩国教师苦恼于2015年韩国《儿童福利法》增加的“不得对儿童造成精神痛苦”规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这条本意是阻止对未成年人言语与精神霸凌的法规，逐渐异化成家长恶意投诉老师的“利器”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“去年一个班级的空调坏了，家长就以此指控一名班主任&#39;虐待儿童&#39;。”印浩然感到很无奈。工作才两年半，他所在的学校已经有四名老师被家长投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们讲课时不敢大声说话，也不敢随意触碰学生。否则就有可能被学生家长以&#39;虐待儿童罪&#39;起诉。”印浩然认为，教学环境变得压抑、乌烟瘴气。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;皮学生&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;富家长&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;与《虐童法》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/SsivgDBUHaVMaphUDUuxa8EAwdNpX6fGmHL3Ml3m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1007&quot; height=&quot;566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/SsivgDBUHaVMaphUDUuxa8EAwdNpX6fGmHL3Ml3m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;韩联社报道，2023年9月2日，首尔永登浦区国会大路的教师集会，人数高达20万。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年韩国进步派推动了“减少打骂教育”“提升学生人权”的教育改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国《朝鲜日报》报道，以首尔市政府为代表，各地陆续颁布了《学生人权条例》。该条例强调学校尊重学生个人发展、背景、性别认同及个人隐私。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而反对派则认为，《学生人权条例》执行起来会让老师“不知如何管教学生、维持班级秩序”。例如，老师不能在上课时间没收学生手机，以免侵犯学生的通信自由与隐私权；老师不能要求犯错学生写悔过书，因悔过书内容可能侵犯学生的表达自由。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;久而久之，学生人权便成了调皮学生的挡箭牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;削弱韩国教权的法律则是2012年《校园暴力防治法》和2015年《儿童福利法》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了遏制校园霸凌，韩国政府在《校园暴力防治法》中规定“保留施暴学生的霸凌记录”。因霸凌记录会影响学生的大学入学资格，学校对学生的过度行为往往采取“睁一只眼闭一只眼”的态度，而教师则被夹在中间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国教育部统计显示，近五年来，因触犯《儿童福利法》，“教师虐待儿童”被起诉、告发的案件有1252件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韩国小学里，一些家长会将录音机放入孩子的书包中，截取声调较高的片段，“恶意起诉”老师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“被告教师会陷入长期的法律纠葛中，他们必须从同事、其他家长处收集大量证言，以证清白。”印浩然告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接受调查期间，被告老师不得与当事学生接触，他们往往会选择停职、收集证据。法律流程通常会持续一年多，被告老师没有薪资补贴，还要承担极大的心理压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月20日，韩国教育部副部长张商允前往瑞草案发小学献花时提到，在教师权威和学生人权之间寻求平衡是当务之急。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这不只是一名老师的教权遭到侵害，而是整个教育系统的崩坏。”瑞草教师自杀案后，韩国教师团体总联合会一则声明称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河善英是京畿道一所公立小学的老师，她很庆幸自己职教生涯中尚未发生过师生矛盾。“只有少部分学生会直接指责老师，教师被霸凌，更多事件的发起者是家长。”河善英告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国成为低生育率国家后，独生子女愈发受到家长的保护。《朝鲜日报》报道援引一位首尔小学校长的话，“部分家长无法忍受孩子在学校受到一丝一毫的伤害。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，首尔江南区、瑞草区是教师争相前往的学区。如今，这些富裕学区已经成为教师们“第一个要躲开的学区”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“家长关心孩子是人之常情。而富人区的家长总是以自己的权威和地位威胁老师。”金车明向南方周末记者坦言，因为学龄较小，低年级学生家长过度关注学生表现，也会要求老师做得更多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自杀教师金某所在的瑞二小学就在首尔瑞草区，这里是韩国知名的富人区，住着政客、富豪和明星。“铅笔事件”涉及学生是警察家庭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国教师通常用教育类软件与家长沟通，他们很少将自己的私人联系方式告知学生。“大多数情况下，我下班后不会回复工作消息。”印浩然说，他所在的小学均用Hi&amp;nbsp;Class软件与家长联系。“如果出现突然学生闯祸的特殊情况，我才会在下班后用软件打电话”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可有的家长总能从“特殊渠道”找到老师的私人电话。“如果你的号码被老师屏蔽了，那就用你家人和朋友的手机再打过去。”一名匿名家长向媒体称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在韩国私立学校或补习学院，有财力的家庭更是校方的“摇钱树”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘芸曾在一所韩国补习院担任汉语老师，她告诉南方周末记者，“我在教一名富裕人家的学生时，院长不断提醒，&#39;要多多鼓励他学习，不管犯了什么错都不要骂他&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何保护老师？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;金车明把小学老师看做“梦想家的工作”，“我们喜欢与小朋友相处，才会成为一名老师”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，韩国社会讲求尊师重道，俗语常告诫后辈“（你们）连老师的影子都不要踩”。近十年来，网络舆论对教师的恶意开始增长，金车明发现，“每当媒体爆出一条师生矛盾的新闻，负面评价都向我们涌来”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为防止侵犯教权、提高教师地位和保护教学氛围等，韩国政府在2019年修订了《教师地位法》。该法提到，因伤害、暴力、恐吓、诽谤和性暴力而受到侵犯的教师，可要求学校成立教权保护委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可即使启动教权保护委员会的程序，教师的权益也很难被保证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，韩国全罗北道一名小学班主任在黑板上写错了学生姓名，该生无故被罚打扫卫生。班主任被家长起诉，后者要求更换班主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，该小学启动教保委员会程序，要求该家长停止“侵害教学氛围”的行为，而家长再诉教保委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;漫长的诉讼流程后，全州地方法院驳回了家长的诉讼请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《朝鲜日报》揶揄，《教师地位法》有名无实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据《教师地位法》，学生侵犯教权后，教保委可就情节严重程度，对其进行心理治疗、停课、班级交替、转学或退学处分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，校方很少给义务教育阶段的学生退学处分。“举报我的转学生曾在其它学校以类似理由举报过别的老师。”庆南地区一名“被控虐童罪”的中学教师告诉韩国《中央日报》，他认为，这些问题学生就像“转炸弹”一样往返于不同学校之间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当教育部门和校方陷入困顿时，韩国保险界给了教师一个解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年起，韩国保险界开始推出了专为中小学老师设计的“教师被告责任险”，其涵盖内容包括面对家长提告的法律费用、调查停职的薪资补偿和遭受霸凌后的心理咨询费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瑞草教师自杀案正在改变韩国政府的态度。7月26日，尹锡悦政府决定积极推进并修改《教师地位法》《中小学教育法》《虐待儿童处罚法》等法律，旨在恢复教权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过到了9月7日，韩国朝野仍未对上述法律达成一致意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;韩国执政党国民力量党和在野党民主党有两点意见分歧，其一是“是否将暴力行为记录在学生档案中”，其二是“是否对虐童案设立单独的判决委员会”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;执政党认为，需要将侵犯教权的学生行为记录在案；而民主党则认为，保护教权和虐童是两个问题，应该成立单独的委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上述法律修订问题将于9月14日再次讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我承诺将与老师们一起努力，让他们不再独自面对困难。”9月4日的瑞草教师49日祭，韩国副总理兼教育部长官李柱浩在背诵追悼词时流下了眼泪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，韩国教育部希望“学校恢复正常”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月8日，韩国教育部和保健福祉部成立联合工作组，支持启动教师心理健康措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护受访者隐私，刘芸为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿里新任CEO：要让85后、90后作为主力管理者，你有感到职场危机吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256516]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;阿里巴巴集团新任CEO吴泳铭9月12日发布全员信，提出了管理团队年轻化的明确目标——4年内，要让85后、90后作为主力管理者刷新业务管理团队，创造让更多年轻的阿里人成为阿里的核心力量的机制和文化环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一发言再次引发了众多关于职场年龄的议论。1985到2019年间，中国劳动力人口平均年龄从32.2岁上升到38.8岁。劳动人口平均年龄升高，职场用工存在潜在年龄限制，这增加了一些中年求职者的就业压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有网友表示，在欧美国家，用人单位往往认为“35岁+”的员工性价比相对更高，因为这个阶段的员工项目经验多、技能成熟，虽然工资多一点，但在培训方面投入少，生活状态相对稳定。反而是新人在刚开始找工作时更容易遭遇就业难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你在工作环境里有遭遇职场危机吗？又是如何看待的呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快来评论区发表你的看法，马上送你上热评！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年国家网络安全宣传周启动 顶尖产品展示突出成果]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256526]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021046141289&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;2023年国家网络安全宣传周启动&amp;nbsp;顶尖产品展示突出成果.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/4b60abe75576678021046141289/Z8cZV3RTBoQA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/4b60abe75576678021046141289/Z8cZV3RTBoQA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由中央宣传部、中央网信办、教育部、工业和信息化部等十部门联合举办的2023年国家网络安全宣传周，9月11日在福建福州开幕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本届网络安全宣传周以“网络安全为人民，网络安全靠人民”为主题，9月11日至17日在全国范围内统一开展，其间将举办网络安全技术高峰论坛、网络安全博览会、分论坛和校园日、电信日、法治日、金融日、青少年日、个人信息保护日等主题日活动，围绕网络安全协同治理、汽车数据安全、工业互联网安全、云计算服务安全、青少年网络保护等议题，研讨展望网络安全领域产业发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;广东广州：网络安全博览会展现多项成果&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;以“网络安全为人民，网络安全靠人民”为主题的2023年广东省网络安全宣传周活动在广州开幕，同期也举办了网络安全博览会，展览面积近1万平方米，37家参展单位多角度展现了广东在网络安全技术创新、产业发展、人才培养等方面的成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e98f2bf0532106061d5f9ffd44aea76.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3e98f2bf0532106061d5f9ffd44aea76.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;广东台记者吴柳倩：&lt;/strong>;不到2秒钟，我手中的小黑盒就破解了智能门锁，可见网络安全的重要性，在本届博览会上展出了一系列有关网络安全的顶尖产品，也展示了近年来广东大力发展网络安全产业的突出成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/f4bd702fd9a92a3db91b795ccf31e0c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/f4bd702fd9a92a3db91b795ccf31e0c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;四川眉山：网络安全宣讲进景区&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a4931c6003e8dc953e7a3cced05754e3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a4931c6003e8dc953e7a3cced05754e3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在四川眉山，为提升景区游客和商家的网络安全意识，当地景区开展了网络安全宣传专题活动。工作人员结合典型案例，生动讲解了常见电信网络诈骗的犯罪伎俩，防止群众上当受骗。活动还设置了有奖问答环节，在互动中让群众将安全知识内化于心，切实提高群众自身防范意识，&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;江西乐平：开展国家网络安全宣传周展览活动&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a92c7fee3a29b54c010be461b8c11cd3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/a92c7fee3a29b54c010be461b8c11cd3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250418&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天，江西省乐平市在为民服务中心开展了国家网络安全宣传周展览活动，现场展板分别介绍了《网络安全法》《数据安全法》《个人信息保护法》等重要法律法规、政策文件，志愿者向市民发放宣传手册，进一步提升大家的网络安全意识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“反诈宣传服务令”：“现身说法”的缓刑人员社区矫正]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256510]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/eF8TMXQdL82vXstBfCQLXXAnDGa2bRTl9J1T77k2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;917&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/eF8TMXQdL82vXstBfCQLXXAnDGa2bRTl9J1T77k2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月10日，北京市海淀区民警在指导市民下载全民反诈App。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“希望大家提高警惕。”2023年8月30日，四川的肖某某（化名）在朋友圈连续转发了5条推文，以及一条发布在他本人抖音账号上的视频链接，内容有一个共同的主题——“反诈”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在反诈风潮席卷互联网的当下，这样“现身说法”的反诈方式看似稀松平常，但少有人知的是，它们的发出者是一群曾近距离接触诈骗行为的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年2月，在一名网友介绍下，肖某某萌生了偷渡到缅甸的想法。筹划半年后，肖某某和妻子、表哥在蛇头带领下，爬山、过河，一路逃避边防检查，到达缅甸小勐拉，并在山上“科技园”内的一网络公司谋到一份工作。四十天后，因工资不高且不自由，肖某某等3人选择回国。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日前，四川省广安市前锋区法院作出判决，肖某某因犯偷越国（边）境罪被依法判处拘役四个月，缓刑五个月，并处罚金六千元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件并未到此为止。2023年8月21日，法院还向肖某某发出了一份“反诈宣传服务令”，责令其在缓刑考验期内依法进行社区矫正，矫正内容包括在微信等社交媒体平台转发反诈内容，“现身说法”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开介绍中，这是四川省内首份反诈宣传服务令。在此之前，福建、江西也发布过此类反诈劝导令或服务令，2022年3月，福建省平和县出台的《关于“电诈”缓刑人员执行“反诈劝导令”的指引》（以下简称《“劝导令”指引》）还被视为全国首创。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“判处一个，教育一片”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;明知他人利用信息网络实施犯罪的情况下，卢某还出售银行卡为犯罪提供帮助。2023年5月8日，江西省贵溪市人民法院作出判决，认定卢某构成帮助信息网络犯罪活动罪（简称“帮信罪”），被判处拘役四个月，缓刑八个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同日，贵溪法院还发出了江西省第一份反诈宣传服务令。卢某须在缓刑考验期内每月至少从事一次反电信网络诈骗宣传活动，时间不少于2小时，同时利用微信或其他自媒体转发反诈宣传信息，每月不少于10条。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵溪法院综合办公室主任孔德明向南方周末记者介绍，发出反诈宣传服务令的想法来自卢某案件的承办法官及分管副院长，不过启发确实是来自福建法院，“它们是全国首个”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平和县人民法院工作人员则向南方周末记者确认，平和在全省范围内首创了“反诈劝导令”的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年3月4日，平和县人民法院、检察院、公安局、司法局联合发布《“劝导令”指引》，当中提到，“反诈劝导令”的适用主体包括诈骗罪、侵犯公民个人信息罪、帮信罪、掩饰、隐瞒犯罪所得、偷越国（边）罪等涉“电诈”案件的犯罪分子，他们当中犯罪情节较轻、有悔罪表现且被判处缓刑、依法实行社区矫正的人需要参与到反诈宣传劝导公益活动中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体到服务内容上，平和法院发布的指引比贵溪法院更为严格，每人每月不仅要完成不少于10次的网络平台宣传，还需要完成30人次的“国家反诈中心App”推广下载工作，并在所在乡镇发放反电信网络诈骗宣传册或向他人推送反诈信息、视频不少于100人次并留痕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者注意到，前述四川省广安市前锋区法院发出的反诈宣传服务令中，对于缓刑人员的服务要求与贵溪法院完全一致。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年6月5日，贵溪法院还联合贵溪司法局出台了一份《电信网络诈骗犯罪等“四类案件”缓刑人员执行&amp;lt;法院服务令&amp;gt;的工作指引》（以下简称《“四类案件”指引》）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;工作指引中提出，除了涉电信网络诈骗案件，法院还将道路交通安全、赌博、传销案件这3类案件中，犯罪情节较轻、有悔罪表现，经法院裁判宣告缓刑，依法实行社区矫正的犯罪分子列入服务令的适用对象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为国内率先实践反诈宣传服务令的省份，福建则试图在更大范围上将这一方式推开。公开资料显示，福建省内，除了平和，云霄、周宁等县市也都曾发布过反诈服务令。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月1日，云霄市人民法院发布消息称，日前，法院联合县社区矫正管理局组织了一批涉“电诈”社区矫正对象，前往人民公园参与反诈宣传。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现场图片中，矫正对象们统一身着志愿者红马甲，向来往人群发放红色宣传单，他们的脸部则被打上马赛克。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;云霄法院介绍，矫正对象现身说法起到了“判处一个、教育一片、引领全部”的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“全国都在抓”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，取材于真实诈骗案例的犯罪电影《孤注一掷》上映，之后反诈宣传在各地不断推开。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，尝试反诈宣传服务令也是近年来反诈宣传工作不断加码的表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时我们做这项工作时，全国都在抓反诈宣传。”孔德明坦言，江西发布首份反诈宣传服务令也是和当下的工作重点相结合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月30日，全国打击治理电信网络新型违法犯罪工作电视电话会议召开，公布数据显示，过去一年，各地区各部门以前所未有的力度和举措，狠抓电信网络新型违法犯罪，全国公安机关共破获电信网络诈骗犯罪案件46.4万起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而据央视新闻报道，庞大的案件量中，有60%发生于缅北地区。而据一位南方某地公安局驻云南民警初步估计，在缅甸，勐能、勐平、邦康、大其力、南邓、老街、木姐等地加起来至少有1000个诈骗园区，“差不多有数十万人在那边敲键盘”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;福建平和法院工作人员向南方周末记者介绍，自第一份劝导令发出后两个月左右，法院就先后发出十余份劝导令，它们所针对的矫正对象大部分曾去缅甸，参与了电信诈骗中的单个环节，如提供银行卡帮助犯罪等，从而构成帮信罪或掩饰、隐瞒犯罪所得罪，因而被判处缓刑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了围绕工作重点，孔德明还提到，之所以特别为涉“诈”人员制定宣传服务要求也与此类案件的特征有关，受案比例高、社会关注度高，“从办案效果和社会效果考虑，对社区矫正对象提出具体的反诈公益活动要求，有利于降低重复犯罪率并预防犯罪。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;三个多月过去，贵溪法院已陆续发出了12件服务令，其中反赌博服务令4件，反传销服务令1件，其余7件均为反诈服务令。“而在反赌博服务令中，绝大多数（缓刑人员）都是犯有帮信罪。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;监测与管理&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;服务令发出后，该如何对矫正对象的行为进行监测管理？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;福建平和法院在指引中提到，发出劝导令后，应由社区矫正机构、公安部门接着进行落实。后二者应当在20个工作日内规划形成具体的时间表、路线图、任务数，组织矫正对象参加公益活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，社区矫正机构还需在相关政务App上，对矫正对象参加“反诈”宣传公益活动进行定位打卡、照片传输与序时监督管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但不为人知的是，福建平和县法院发出反诈劝导令的行为在当年即被叫停，合计发出数量不超过20件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位当地司法系统内部人员向南方周末记者透露，叫停原因在于劝导令实行过程中，负责发放的法院与负责实际落实监督的司法部门有了分歧，“司法部门认为这个有超过社区矫正的嫌疑”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;服务令的发放与执行分属法院和司法局为常规做法，孔德明介绍，“服务令要求的内容是社区矫正的一部分，司法局是社区矫正主管部门，他们落实，效果怎么样，我们不见得会长期跟踪。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据孔德明观察，首份服务令发布以来，“有两个效果是肯定的”，一是解决普法人员不足的问题，二是缓刑人员“现身说法”，可以提高普法效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但他感到遗憾的是，近几个月来，贵溪市的帮信罪受案数并没有明显减少。“仅靠着一个地方、一个辖区去做宣传，可能这么几个月是体现不出来效果的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个受公众关注的问题是，积极完成服务令要求的缓刑人员是否可以减刑？南方周末记者注意到，不同地方规定亦不同。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在福建平和，《“劝导令”指引》明确，对成效突出的或有其他对社会公益及安定稳定特别表现的矫正对象，在符合减刑条件的情况下，社区矫正机构应该及时抄送检察院，征求其意见后，可呈报市司法局向市中级人民法院提出减刑建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而据孔德明介绍，贵溪目前未有因缓刑人员反诈成效突出而减少其缓刑考验期的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，进行社区矫正是对缓刑人员的法律要求，服务令的发放仅仅是对其社区矫正内容的明确，而非额外的任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果不发出反诈宣传服务令，判了缓刑（的犯罪分子），也要进行社区矫正，要去扫地。”孔德明说，“除非有特殊的贡献，从法律依据上来说应该也是可以（减刑的）。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在最新发出反诈宣传服务令的四川，前锋区法院提出，假若社区矫正对象未履行服务令要求，矫正机构还将视情节严重，依法给予相应处罚，以推动服务令落到实处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>