<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[记者节之思：新闻理想的坚守与开拓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260074]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The annual Journalists’ Day is here. This is also the time for reporters who are working non-stop and running around all year round to stop and reflect. , an important moment for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is full of chaos, the century-old changes are accelerating, the media field is deeply integrated and reconstructed, instability and uncertainty factors are significantly increasing, internal and external factors are stirring in the hearts of journalists... At this moment, Journalists&#39; Day, Perhaps each of us journalists should ask themselves the question: Do you still have journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a journalist, the news ideal is the &quot;beacon light&quot; that guides the direction; the news ideal is the &quot;engine&quot; that drives forward; the news ideal is the &quot;ballast&quot; &quot;Stone&quot; has the function of calming the mind; news ideal is the &quot;regulator&quot; and has the function of prompting and warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, today, the traditional journalism industry is facing an unprecedented industry shock: the circulation of newspapers and periodicals and radio and television ratings have declined, and the influence of the media has declined; the media industry has operating difficulties, and the income of news practitioners has decreased. ; The number of people leaving their jobs has increased, and people quitting the industry have been heard from time to time; the number of enrollment in journalism and communication majors in colleges and universities has been reduced, and the employment situation of graduates has become tighter... There is no shortage of comments on the Internet about candidates who plan to apply for the journalism and communication major. Although it is not without bias, This is by no means groundless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the founding words of &quot;Xiangjiang Review&quot;, Mao Zedong enthusiastically asked: &quot;What is the biggest problem in the world? The biggest problem is the problem of food.&quot; When the traditional journalism industry is climbing up and over the hurdles, a group of people who are confused and emotionally anxious have emerged. Psychological Inevitability – Will Traditional Journalism Die? Is there a future for journalism? Do we still need journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as we carefully study the history, reality and future development trends of journalism, we will find that traditional journalism will not disappear. Journalism still has its own future, and we still need journalistic ideals. This is because: From the perspective of the origin of journalism, news originates from people’s curiosity. As long as people’s curiosity does not die, journalism will not disappear. From the perspective of the evolution of journalism, although the carrier of news is constantly changing, the functional role of journalism has not disappeared. However, compared with the traditional ways of reading newspapers, listening to radio, and watching TV in the past, people now obtain news in a different way. It’s just a new carrier such as a mobile phone. From the perspective of audience needs, news focuses on meeting people&#39;s communication needs. As long as people&#39;s communication needs exist, the demand for journalism will always exist. From the perspective of journalism production, the authoritative news, in-depth reports, news reviews, elegant programs and other products provided by traditional media cannot be replaced by the vast number of new media and self-media. Therefore, traditional journalism is unlikely to disappear in any of the above senses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is impossible for traditional journalism to disappear, it is impossible for journalists to disappear. The ideal of journalism will inevitably accompany and advance together with journalists. Otherwise, we will lose our way and lose our way. Without motivation, lack of soul, and chaos, you will be at a loss, useless, muddle along, and do nothing. Therefore, in such a special context of the times, each of us journalists must still have journalistic ideals in mind, promote journalistic ideals, adhere to journalistic ideals, and practice journalistic ideals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always have a loyal heart. Loyalty means that as a journalist, don’t ask what the country has done for me, but ask what I have done for the country; loyalty means not being confused in the face of major events, not wavering at critical moments, and being able to withstand various complex situations and problems. The test; loyalty means being indifferent to fame and wealth, willing to work as a coolie, working hard, sweating, and traveling thousands of miles for the cause of journalism, and striving to become an excellent journalist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always maintain a keen sense. Sensitivity is an essential quality for professional journalists. Only journalists who are sharp-minded, have unique vision, are good at seeing the subtleties, respond quickly, and have a sharp eye can effectively improve the dissemination, guidance, influence and credibility of news and public opinion work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must always practice seeking truth. The world-famous journalist Farage once said: &quot;The duty of a reporter is to reveal the truth.&quot; In an era of widespread media communication, despite the excess of news information, real news is always valuable. We should always maintain the spirit of truth-seeking, practice truth-seeking skills, and provide the public with truth, true knowledge, true feelings, and truth in a timely and rapid manner in the turbulent world of massive information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always hold the ruler of justice. Some people say: &quot;The reporter&#39;s pen contains countless fortunes, reputation and reputation, loyalty and villainy, right and wrong, and life and death.&quot; This shows how heavy the journalist&#39;s pen is. Therefore, we reporters should be very clear about why we write, what we write, how we write, and to what extent we write. We must always grasp the yardstick of &quot;fairness&quot; and must not be influenced by some kind of power, money, or interest relationship. Those pens soaked in grease and booze can&#39;t possibly do them justice. This is why we need to always be in awe of &quot;justice&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of Journalists’ Day, I wish every journalist’s journalistic ideals to be evergreen and never wither! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is from the media in Hebei)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; 163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[森林消防“全覆盖”31个省份]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260136]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce Progress in the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the progress of the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Firefighting work and the construction of fire rescue teams have undergone all-round and profound changes.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, at the State Council At a press conference held by the Information Office, Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management and director of the National Fire Rescue Bureau, introduced the construction and development of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in its fifth anniversary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and were formally placed under the Ministry of Emergency Management to form a national comprehensive fire rescue team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in the past five years, nearly 200,000 teams have successfully completed transfers of subordinates, identity changes, rank changes, title changes, and official positions. work, establish the National Fire Rescue Bureau, implement unified leadership and hierarchical command, clarify the major principles of central construction and local use, and establish a dual management system that combines sections and focuses on sections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 is the sixth year for open recruitment of firefighters after the establishment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team. Li Shangyu, head of the Education and Training Department of the Ministry of Emergency Management, said that there was a plan to recruit 15,000 people in 2023, but nearly 110,000 people signed up, marking the fourth consecutive full recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shangyu introduced that the average age of new firefighters is 21.8 years old, and 52.6% have a college degree or above. They are currently undergoing a one-year induction training. So far, the total number of firefighters recruited after the transformation has reached more than 94,000, accounting for 65.3% of the total number of existing firefighters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Forest firefighting adds more than 8,200 people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National firefighting After the rescue bureau was officially established, a new mobile team was formed. Xu Zhongshun, deputy director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, said that this is &quot;a major decision made based on the basic national conditions of my country&#39;s frequent natural disasters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as a critical force in national emergencies and major disasters, the mobile team is mainly responsible for forest and grassland firefighting duties, supplemented by flood fighting and earthquake and geological disaster rescue. Responsibilities, task arrangements focus on fire fighting in winter and spring, flood control in summer and autumn, year-round disaster relief, seasonal cross-regional garrison, and implementation of preparatory operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Fire and Rescue Administration has integrated the forest fire corps and related fire and rescue mobile detachments, forming 10 cross-regional fire and rescue mobile corps and several detachments, brigades, and squadrons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the original establishment of forest firefighting teams is 25,000, mainly deployed in 10 provinces including Inner Mongolia, Jilin, Heilongjiang, Fujian, and Sichuan. On this basis, the Central Organization Office has approved the establishment of more than 8,200 forest firefighting teams, mainly to strengthen the first-line firefighting and rescue mobile forces in key forest areas, national parks, seven major river basins and surrounding areas across the country, and to achieve comprehensive coverage of 31 provinces. &quot;Full coverage&quot; of all administrative regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as of now, 17 provinces in the first batch of additional mobile teams have basically completed their deployment, and are now organizing the second batch of additional mobile teams. There are teams stationed in 3 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;All disasters, major emergencies&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Firefighting After the rescue team was reformed and transformed, its functions have also been expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se introduced that on the basis of the original fire fighting and emergency rescue focusing on rescuing people&#39;s lives, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau focuses on &quot;all disaster types&quot;. The comprehensive rescue expansion of &quot;big emergency&quot; covers urban and rural and forest and grassland fire fighting, as well as disaster accident rescue such as floods, earthquakes, geology, typhoons, building collapses, and hazardous chemical leakage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking 2022 as an example, fire rescue teams across the country received reports and handled 2.092 million disasters of various types, including 824,000 fire rescues and 469,000 emergency rescues. , 597,000 cases of various types of social assistance, 126,000 cases of official duties, and 76,000 cases of other dispatches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this total number of rescues, fire fighting is still the main type of accident that the fire rescue team responds to. At the same time, police situations involving water areas, mountains, production and equipment failures, trapped elevators, and traffic accidents accounted for 87.4% of the total number of rescues. &quot;They are the main types of rescues and are also the key directions for the expansion of functional tasks after the reform and restructuring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in response to these situations, in recent years, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau has vigorously strengthened the construction of professional forces and established a total of high-rise buildings, underground spaces, large commercial complexes, etc. There are more than 3,500 professional firefighting teams in the body and petrochemical enterprises, as well as earthquake, water, air, and rain, snow and ice rescue teams. Relying on the forest firefighting team, 12 special disaster rescue brigades and 55 affiliated rapid response teams have been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[中山二院乳腺外科多人患癌？医院通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:35:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 7, 2023, our hospital noticed that &quot;Zhongshan Second Hospital Breast Cancer The surgical team is suspected of being affected by the experimental environment and reagents, causing many people to develop cancer.&quot; The hospital quickly organized an investigation and verification, and initially learned that: 3 people who worked and studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center in recent years have suffered from cancer, 2 of whom are now breast surgeons in our hospital and are working in clinical practice; the other 1 is not from us. The employees or students of the institute are those who come to the institute for further study from other places and have returned to work in their original units. No current student in this laboratory has contracted cancer. The specific situation is as follows: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Huang, female, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2017 to 2022, during which she studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center, and graduated with a doctoral degree in July 2022 Later, he joined the Breast Surgery Department of our hospital and engaged in clinical work. He was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in October 2023 and underwent surgery. His current condition is stable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu, male, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2013 to 2018. During this period, he studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center. He joined our hospital after graduating from the Ph.D. in August 2018. Breast surgery, engaged in clinical work. In June 2023, he was diagnosed with synovial sarcoma and underwent surgery. He recovered well after the operation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the above two employees became ill, the hospital has been caring about their health and organized expert consultations, visits and condolences. Another researcher is a doctoral student who graduated from a foreign hospital. In 2021, he came to our hospital for a year of further study and worked in the laboratory of the Breast Tumor Center. He completed his further study in April 2022 and left Guangzhou. In 2023, he was diagnosed with breast cancer at his place of work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Breast Cancer Center Laboratory was opened in 2009 and has trained more than 200 students so far. Since its establishment, the laboratory has been managed in strict accordance with the regulations, and all experimental personnel have been trained on safety and standardized operations before experiments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to public concerns about laboratory safety management, our hospital will continue to maintain safety red lines and consciously accept inspections and supervision from superior authorities. We also thank netizens for their opinions and suggestions. . Regarding concerns about linking cancer to laboratory or reagent exposure, given that the causes of individual cancer are extremely complex, relevant departments are sincerely welcome to organize third-party agencies to conduct assessment and investigations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Finally, I would like to thank all sectors of society for their care and attention to the health of medical workers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;November 8, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[炮弹落在畹町镇：一座边陲小镇活在缅北战火旁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia photographed the war situation in Myanmar from the roof, blue in the distance The house on the roof is in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1131&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia took pictures of the war in Myanmar from the rooftop. The houses with blue roofs in the distance are in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the fifth day of the civil war in northern Myanmar, Wu Xia, who lives in the border town of Wanding, was so scared when she heard the sound of gunfire not far away that she turned off the iron Snack bar, hiding in a home made of reinforced concrete. Having lived in Wanding for more than 20 years, she told the Southern Weekend reporter that there had been wars on the opposite side before, with mostly gunshots, but the fighting in 2023 was the most fierce, all with heavy shelling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia climbed to the roof of her house, where she could see Myanmar across the river. In a 39-second video she shot, the sound of gunfire and artillery continued from the valley, and helicopters circled the top of the mountain. At the foot of the mountain were dense houses, stretching from Myanmar to the eastern town of Ruili City, Yunnan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, government army strongholds in many places in northern Myanmar were attacked by armed forces and exchanges of fire broke out. The fighting was fierce and the stalemate has continued to this day. On the national border, Wanding Town, which borders Bangsai Town in Myanmar, is a Chinese town that has been greatly affected by the war. Stray bullets have fallen into this town of about 10,000 people many times. In order to ensure the safety of residents, the local government arranged for school closures and mobilized residents to leave the town to avoid the war. The town implemented a &quot;only exit, no entry&quot; control policy, and even the town government staff evacuated to work in safe places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Map by Liang Shuyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Drawing by Liang Shuyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Don’t come out of your home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 28, a shell from Myanmar hit a residential building in Wanding Town, destroying the top four floors. A big hole was blown out of the building. A few hours after the explosion, Mr. Yang, who sells aluminum doors and windows, rushed to the scene out of curiosity. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the shell had exploded and there were no casualties. “An old lady told me that when the shell exploded, It was so shaken that she couldn&#39;t hear anything for two hours.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Peng Qi first heard the sound of shells and gunshots, she didn&#39;t know what they were. She thought someone was setting off fireworks. In June 2023, she was transferred from Ruili City to Wanding Town and worked as a store manager in a chain milk tea shop. The locals told her that it was the sound of war in Myanmar and comforted her: &quot;It&#39;s okay, we hear this sound every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals who are used to the sound of gunfire seem to be also attracted by it. This time the battle was frightening. At two or three o&#39;clock in the morning on October 29, Wu Xia was awakened by several gunshots while she was sleeping. That day, she listened to the sound of gunfire outside and judged that the exchange of fire between the two parties was fierce. The windows of a house about 200 meters away from her home were shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuxia Snack Shop sells some local specialty snacks, such as Pauluda, fried bait cubes, etc. It is only about 200 meters away from Wanding Port. Children in the third grade of primary school are afraid that artillery shells will penetrate the iron sheet and will go home when they hear the sound of artillery fire. Wu Xia believes that hiding at home is not necessarily safe. &quot;If there are really shells coming, you can&#39;t hide anywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan, who lives by the boundary river, seems to be at greater risk. She once saw a picture of a helicopter bombing on the other side of the river on a short video platform. The community administrator also kept telling her not to come out of the house. However, She works at Wanding Town Health Center and still needs to report to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that on October 31, she was at work when she was suddenly informed that a large crater had been blown up near her home, and her son, who was in primary school, was staying at home alone. &quot;It was really urgent at the time. I called my husband and ran home. When I got home and opened the door, I saw that my son was taking a nap.&quot; Tao Wan looked at her son sleeping soundly and felt, &quot;My heart is going to be broken.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan told Southern Weekend reporters that when she was a child, the sound of fighting on the other side of the river could be heard in Wanding Town. The most intense year.&quot; The scene of community workers and street broadcasts telling residents to retreat and avoid the fighting made Tao Wan feel panic like never before, &quot;I felt like I had to leave this home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that on October 27, the night when the war broke out, community members came to persuade them to leave: “If you have family and friends in Ruili, go to Ruili. &quot;Not only that, the community also informed that if you hear the sound of gunfire, please do not go out, and immediately find shelter to take shelter. Do not wait and see out of curiosity, and avoid exposing your body in open spaces to avoid being hit by stray bullets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, an on-duty staff member of the Wanding Town Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the staff in the government building had moved to a relatively safe place to work, leaving only a few on-duty staff, and the new place was still open. Within the Wanding area, it is five or six kilometers away from the town government building. The reason why they moved out of the town government building was because the building was &quot;directly opposite Myanmar and posed a major safety hazard.&quot; The person on duty said he was unclear about how many people were transferred in Wanding Town and when students would resume classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The fourth floor of a residential building in the town was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Town The fourth floor of a residential building was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The watermelon business chain is broken&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Residents living in Wanding noticed that this war was different from usual signals. In addition to the fierce gunfire, there were also Students are completely suspended from classes. The milk tea shop where Peng Qi works is only a few hundred meters away from Wanding Middle School. She discovered that on the evening of Friday, October 27, all the high school students who were originally on holiday on Sunday were taken home by their parents. Wu Xia&#39;s snack bar is not far from the middle school. She saw many parents driving to the school gate to pick up their students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili, a 21-year-old girl who grew up in Wanding, recalled that there was an emergency in the local area a few years ago when classes were suspended due to the war in Myanmar, but she could not remember the time clearly. She only remembered that it was the same time at that time. There are stray bullets flying into the territory. &quot;The most serious thing in recent years is the two incidents of stray bullets flying over. The situation in Myanmar has always been unstable. Once war starts, Wanding&#39;s geographical location is destined to be affected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cai In Lily&#39;s impression, there is only a boundary river two or three meters wide, and there are frequent exchanges between Wanding and the Myanmar town of Bangsai on the other side. She recalled that when she was five or six years old, it was easy to travel to Myanmar from the border crossing. When she was in primary school, seven or eight of the more than 40 students in her class were from Myanmar. &quot;We all studied Chinese courses and we all played together.&quot; The boundary river is also one of her recreational areas. She often goes fishing and picnicking by the river with her family and friends. A walking trail is built close to the boundary river, and Wanding residents often go for walks by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that some Wanding residents were indeed accidentally injured, mostly with skin injuries. &quot;After we debridement, we will ask them to go home quickly, because the hospital is located on a relatively high ground and is not safe. Some people were also transferred to higher-level hospitals by ambulances.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia discovered that since the beginning of the Northern Myanmar War Later, there were fewer and fewer people on the streets, especially tourists. As a famous border town and border port, there are endless tourists here all year round. Her snack bar is not far from the national gate and has about a hundred customers every day. But after the war broke out, only a few old customers who lived nearby came to the store, and &quot;there was no one on this street.&quot; Not only that, on October 30, the &quot;only go out, no go in&quot; rule was implemented in the central area of ​​Wanding Town. However, according to locals, the rule was only implemented for two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Qi also obviously felt that the flow of people had dropped sharply. In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter at 16:00 on November 2, Peng Qi said that the store&#39;s turnover that day was only more than 100 yuan, which is the price of about 10 cups of milk tea, and most of the customers were from nearby shops. Before the war, the store&#39;s daily turnover was about one thousand yuan. There are also brave tourists who go to the border to shoot short videos. Wu Xia said: &quot;Many men and women may also be afraid. They basically just take pictures and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the men and women Wu Xia saw, Perhaps there is also Zhou Feng, a melon seller. On November 2, 37-year-old Zhou Feng also visited the national gate of Wanding, but his destination was the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market. As the largest watermelon market in Southeast Asia, from the end of October to May of the following year is the time when Myanmar watermelons are on the market and exported to China. Zhou Feng revealed that during peak periods, the market could have 1,000 vehicles a day, each carrying 16 tons of watermelons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of October 2023, the price of Myanmar watermelon that has just been launched can reach four or five yuan per kilogram, which is not low. After the war broke out, Wanding&#39;s national gate was closed and watermelon could not enter the territory. Zhou Feng analyzed that the most affected people in the watermelon industry chain are melon farmers. The price of contracted land in Myanmar is relatively low, only three to four hundred yuan per mu, so most of the people who plant watermelons on contracted land in Myanmar are Chinese. Zhou Feng has been engaged in this industry for 13 years. He is grateful that it is the early stage of the watermelon market. &quot;If it takes more than a month to start the war, I will be annoyed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In previous years, at the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market, melon stalls were filled with watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In previous years, the watermelon wholesale market in Wanding was full of melon stalls Watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Eerily Quiet&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all Wanding residents were affected by the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 3 communities and 3 administrative villages within the jurisdiction of Wanding Town. 26-year-old Guo Yu lives with his family in Hunban Village, which is about 5 kilometers away from the border port and one or two kilometers away from Myanmar. Guo Yu runs a B&amp;B. Since the war started, there have been no guests staying. Fortunately, the shells did not fall near them, and the family&#39;s food, clothing, housing and transportation were not affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Yu’s mother is from Myanmar, and his father’s ancestral home is in Baoshan City, Yunnan Province. When they were young, they came to Wanding to buy land and build a house, and settled here. Guo Yu told Southern Weekend reporters that his grandmother&#39;s house was not affected by the war and was relatively safe for the time being. Guo Yu also feels safe and has no plans to move away. However, if the shells hit nearby, the family may move to Ruili, 20 kilometers away, and stay with relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan was not prepared to evacuate, but sent her youngest son back to her husband&#39;s hometown in Dehong Prefecture overnight. &quot;We all buy a house and a car on our own. This is my home. If I leave, it won&#39;t even have its roots.&quot; Since October 27, Tao Wan has felt uneasy every day. She is afraid that if an accident occurs, the house will be lost. . &quot;I don&#39;t know what to do in that situation. When I think of this possibility, I almost burst into tears.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan came to Wanding Town with her mother when she was 5 years old. Now she has Is 40 years old. Because she had to take care of her mother who didn&#39;t want to leave Wanding, Tao Wan, who went to college abroad, came back here again, until now. After the war broke out, Tao Wan placed her mother in a village far away from the border. She planned to wait until the war calmed down before taking the old man home. Tao Wan said that there are some elderly people in the town who have inconvenient legs and feet who are unwilling to move. They have deep feelings for Wanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dai language, Wanding means &quot;the place where the sun is at the top&quot;. Today, the town&#39;s shine is no longer dazzling. In Tao Wan&#39;s impression, Wanding was prosperous 20 to 30 years ago. Later, due to road planning, administrative divisions and other reasons, Wanding was slowly declining. Tao Wan felt aggrieved for the small town where she lived, &quot;There was an epidemic in the past three years, and now there is this war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili never felt that she was a girl who came out of a small town. She felt that Wanding was more like a small city. She remembers that Wanding Town was very lively around 2007, with people coming and going, and the shops on the street would sell Myanmar specialties, such as hot and sour noodles, milk candies, etc. Now, some of the shops that impressed Cai Lili have been closed, and many shops on the street are empty. &quot;After its decline in recent years, I gradually felt that it was really just a small town.&quot; Cai Lili said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this town is facing another test. On November 6, Peng Qi told Southern Weekend reporters that compared with the chaotic sound of gunfire in the past few days, the streets in Wanding are now &quot;eerily quiet&quot;. Except for the occasional pedestrian passing by, only military green trucks are left on the street. patrol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan has not heard the sound of gunfire recently, but she feels that the government departments and schools have shown no signs of relaxing. The school has not notified the resumption of classes, teaching is conducted in the form of online classes, and the community still counts every day and has not evacuated. resident information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“局外人”到“第一个人”：加缪110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRmVSmK7F8E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRm VSmK7F8E. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Albert Camus (November 7, 1913 - 1960 January 4), French writer and philosopher, born in Algeria. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature at the age of 44 and died unexpectedly at the age of 47. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, 1913, Albert Camus was born. On January 4, 1960, he died in an accidental car accident at the age of 46. Today, it has been 110 years since Camus was born and more than sixty years since his death, but people do not feel that Camus belongs to a distant era. He used his short writing career to create a series of distinctive contemporary images. , is still closely related to our living situation today. The embarrassment, discord, and sense of powerlessness of &quot;outsiders&quot;, the repeated hard labor in &quot;Sisyphus&quot;, and the struggle and dignity of people facing disaster in &quot;The Plague&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus is both a writer and a thinker. He does not capture readers with the splendor of his words, but shocks them with his postmodern understanding of life. He is the youngest winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature. one. Camus&#39;s enduring popularity is symptomatic. Just like Kafka, he wrote a &quot;clinical diagnosis&quot; of contemporary people&#39;s mental dilemma; just like Lu Xun, he does not provide bright answers, or even It&#39;s a bit dark and cold, but at the end of the coldness is a philosophy of resistance and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus once worked as a journalist. On January 1, 1940, he wrote an editorial for the last issue of the &quot;Republican Evening News&quot;. You can get a glimpse of his restraint, coolness, and calmness with a sense of power. Words: &quot;This year, hoping for happiness will be in vain, building it through work is the key. Don&#39;t hope for anything, but do something. Don&#39;t wait for others to build your destiny from beginning to end, especially when destiny It is still in our hands. The Evening Republican will not wish you happiness this year, knowing that you are going through a severe physical and mental trauma. But it will ask you to maintain the necessary strength and sobriety to strive to maintain your own tranquility and dignity. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the darkest moment of World War II. Shortly after Camus wrote this dedication, while fleeing on the border of France and Spain, Benjamin failed to get a pass and came to the end of his life. At the end, although Zweig fled to Brazil, he still committed suicide in despair. Camus belongs to a new generation of young people. He once joined the French Communist Party, fought and resisted, and condensed the power of his resistance into continuous writing. If the deaths of Benjamin and Zweig marked the spiritual boundaries of yesterday&#39;s world, Camus established the starting point of his writing on the wasteland of war and post-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The postwar world is neither a wasteland nor a new heaven and a new earth. His arguments with his friend Sartre and his ambivalent attitude toward the Algerian War made Camus increasingly lonely while receiving literary honors. When he returned to autobiographical writing and the &quot;first person&quot;, an accident caused this sharp soul to bid farewell in advance. For a writer like Camus, commemorating him at any time is both our condolences and an invitation for him to return. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;France’s “outsider”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 2 a.m. on November 7, 1913, her mother Catalina gave birth to Camus, who was the first child in the family. second son. The next day, at the Mondovi Municipal Government in Algeria, the father registered the birth of his child. He was 28 years old and worked as a wine cellar manager. The mother was 31 years old and filled in the occupation column as a housewife. The birthplace of Saint-Paul Farm is located 8 kilometers south of the city of Mondovi. The nearby city of Bonny is the most important port in French Algeria, not far from the Tunisian border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Algeria became a French colony in the 19th century, most of the immigrants who immigrated here were poor people from all over France, as well as Spain, Italy and other European countries. New immigrants were granted residence rights under French protection and lived among the overwhelming majority of locals. “The French in Algeria are of mixed race. Spaniards, Alsatians, Italians, Maltese, Jews, Greeks gather there,” Camus later wrote. Camus is a mixed-race child, his mother is Spanish, and he believes that his father comes from Alsace, the battlefield where France and Germany have fought for generations. The reason for &quot;thinking&quot; is that my father&#39;s exact ancestral home has been lost and difficult to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus had never met his father before he could remember. My father is 1.8 meters tall, with brown hair and blue eyes. He works in a wine company, supervising the grape pressing, winemaking, storage, and shipment to the Port of Pawnee for shipment. Not long after Camus was born, World War I broke out, and his father was conscripted into the French army. Almost as soon as he entered the battlefield, he was injured in the Battle of the Marne to prevent the German army from advancing towards Paris. He was hit by shell fragments and was sent to a rear hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 1914, my mother received the bad news by telegram, as well as a small piece of shrapnel removed from her husband&#39;s head that the widow had asked to keep. His father was mysterious to Camus. He often asked his mother: &quot;Am I really like my father?&quot; &quot;Oh, you look exactly like your father.&quot; During the four years of World War I, his mother received no After passing a penny in France, it was only a few months before the end of the war that I received official notification of her husband&#39;s death and a pension check. An accountant next door helped her fill out the pension application form because no one in her family knew how to fill it out. In order to make a living, my mother sorted warheads in an ammunition manufacturing factory until she suffered from rheumatism and was unable to continue this work, so she began to work as a domestic helper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 8 months to 17 years old, Camus lived with his mother and grandmother under the same roof in Algiers, the capital of Algeria. It was Belku, the workers&#39; district of the city, home to people who worked hard in small workshops and port equipment factories, craftsmen, small traders, grassroots civil servants and clerks. As an adult, Camus returned to the house frequently, sometimes to visit the elderly and sometimes as a temporary haven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in middle school, football fascinated Camus. He was very brave and liked to tackle from the feet of his opponents, so he was often injured. Camus described a fierce football match, on a pitch adjacent to a cemetery, in which the opposing players pressed forward mercilessly. They “were all on top of me, spikes on my shins, knees on my crotch, squeezing me against the goal post…” “I quickly learned that the ball doesn’t come from where you expect it to. This was very helpful in my life, especially in France, where not everyone is honest,&quot; Camus later wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Camus came to settle in Paris in early 1940, he felt that &quot;I am not from here, nor from anywhere else. The world is just a strange scenery, and my spirit is helpless here. Everything It has nothing to do with yourself.&quot; He was stuck between France and Algeria, between Paris and impoverished Bercoux across the Mediterranean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;969&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Camus (first from right) is backstage with two actors during the performance of his drama &quot;Martial Law&quot; in Paris in 1948. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sisyphus&quot;: The victorious loser&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While Sartre, who came from a middle-class background, was dreaming of a literary hero, and Beauvoir was enjoying her books and the gifts in the candy shop window, Camus was in a home without electricity, running water, newspapers and books, and no Growing up in the world of radio, he once wrote in his diary: &quot;Living in poverty for a few years is enough to create all the sensitivity.&quot; Tuberculosis plagued Camus throughout his life, but it also exempted him from military service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1942, &quot;The Outsider&quot; and &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; were published one after another. The former tells the story of a French-Algerian named Meursault who experienced two deaths. The first was his mother&#39;s death. He couldn&#39;t even remember the date and didn&#39;t shed tears. The second was when he had an affair with a holdover on the beach. There was a conflict with the Arab about the knife. Meursault happened to be holding a friend&#39;s gun. When his eyes were dazzled by the reflection of the sea and the blade, he almost subconsciously shot the man. After being arrested, Meursault told the judge in confusion that the reason he shot was the sun. Meursault did not defend himself, and the court also lacked interest in the murder case and focused on investigating his personal life. Indifference became the biggest evidence of crime and was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of the essay collection &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; is taken from a story in &quot;Homer&#39;s Epic&quot;. King Sisyphus disobeyed God and was sentenced to push a huge boulder up a mountain for eternity, each time the boulder approached the top of the mountain. When the time comes, it will slip from his hand and roll down again, and he can only go back again, starting over and over again. Camus used the myth of Sisyphus, just like Freud through the Oedipus complex, to make the mythical figure deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts again. The most famous sentence in &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; may be: &quot;There is only one philosophical question that is truly serious, and that is suicide. To judge whether life is worth living or not...&quot; Camus said in the preface of an English translation many years later , wrote this book because &quot;even within the borders of nihilism, it is possible to find ways to move beyond nihilism.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play Caligula, published in 1944, discusses freedom and meaninglessness pushed to the extreme by recreating the story of the assassinated Roman Emperor Suetonius. These three books are collectively called Camus&#39; &quot;Trilogy of the Absurd.&quot; They were written and published in the critical state of war and occupied Paris, where everything was compromised and everything was lost. From Kierkegaard&#39;s existential philosophy, Camus saw Abraham, who sacrificed his son, as &quot;infinitely He gave up everything, and then took it all back with the help of absurd power.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus took the initiative to get to know him during the rehearsal of Sartre&#39;s play &quot;The Fly&quot;, and the two hit it off. Previously, Sartre had written an article for Camus&#39;s novel &quot;The Stranger&quot;, and Camus had commented on it. The special &quot;Disgusting&quot;. Beauvoir and Sartre found that Camus was a simple, happy man who was always funny and vulgar in his conversations, very emotional, and would even sit on a snowy street at two in the morning and talk about his love troubles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don Juan went from one woman to another not because of a lack of love, but because he loved them with equal passion and devoted himself to them every time. He must repeat this talent and harmony. Explore... Why do you have to love less to love well?&quot; &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; reads. Camus had two marriages. His first wife, Simone, was unable to quit morphine, which caused him great psychological trauma. After remarrying Francine, Camus maintained semi-public intimate relationships with many women. , including theater actress Maria Casares, who exchanged more than 800 love letters. It is as if Don Juan became an incarnation of Sisyphus pushing the boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Plague&quot;: End and Resistance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II and the liberation of Paris, the reputations of Sartre, Beauvoir and Camus were at their peak, and the Left Bank The Flower Goddess and the Double Sole Cafe in Shanghai have shrouded the halo of existentialist writers, and the radius of the halo extends to the United States on the other side of the ocean. All three of them received invitations to visit from New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From March to May 1946, Camus traveled around the United States. He was more nervous than Sartre and felt that he was always affected by endless little troubles. He&#39;s also a careful observer, noting that Americans drink juice in the morning, drink scotch and soda across the country, and are passionate about animals, from gorillas at the Bronx Zoo to taxidermy at the Museum of Natural History. , death and the dead can be dressed up as quickly as possible, &quot;die and leave the rest to us.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only place that made Camus feel familiar and at ease was the Bowery Street in New York. At that time, it was still an abandoned area, full of cheap bars and run-down hotels, with the elevated railway running from the height of the second floor. Passing by, shadows covered everything below. Camus was disgusted by the United States and felt that there was a lack of pain and tragedy, but in the eyes of many critics, &quot;The Stranger&quot; is a parody of American noir novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, the novel &quot;The Plague&quot; was published and was so popular among readers that it was reprinted eight times in two years. After that, &quot;The Plague&quot; and &quot;The Stranger&quot; were at the top of the French literary bestseller list for a long time. From 1941 to 1942, the plague was prevalent in Algeria, which was the starting point for Camus to prepare &quot;The Plague&quot;. The reason why this novel is so thrilling is because the plague is described as both real and terrifying, and it is also symbolic. It alludes to World War II. During this period, the harsh reality of the Nazis in Germany was wreaking havoc. Nazism and fascism are also a political and spiritual plague. Its military power, spy system, autocracy and racism sweep across everything like the god of death. After being manipulated by it, they either succumb to it, cooperate with it, or know that it is impossible. Those who resist for the land are like all living beings in the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Camus highlighted three symbolic situations of life. One is the situation of separation, including the separation of relatives, separation of husband and wife, and separation of lovers, which means isolation, blockade, imprisonment, and exile. , concentration camp... The second is that there is no condition of any woman in the novel, which means imbalance, deformity, bitterness, and lifelessness... The most terrifying atmosphere and situation is death...&quot; Liu Mingjiu, the translator of the Chinese version of &quot;The Plague&quot; Said, &quot;&#39;The plague is lurking in everyone, because no one, yes, no one in the world is immune to it&#39;... In this way, Camus also put his philosophy about the absurd world in &quot;The Plague&quot; It greatly broadens and deepens the story, and points the absurd roots to human faults and human society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the desperate situation of World War II, Camus was not the only one who chose to write about a critical state through the background of the plague. , the German playwright Brecht also created &quot;The Life of Galileo&quot;, in which Galileo also experienced a narrow escape from the plague. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I tried to use the plague to express the suffocation we suffer and the environment we endure that threatens and drives people into exile.” Camus said. In the apocalyptic city of Ahlan, the protagonist of the novel, Dr. Bernard Rieux, became an ordinary hero because of his dedication to his duties. Camus reshapes heroes in the form of anti-heroes. When disaster strikes, what we can expect is not a hero falling from the sky, but every ordinary person resisting evil through the smallest efforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Resistor, a collection of essays published in 1951, is where Camus clearly proposed the philosophy of resistance after the philosophy of the absurd, &quot;What is a rebel? A person who says &#39;no&#39;. However, although he He refuses but does not give up: he is also the person who says &#39;yes&#39; from the very beginning.&quot; However, this book with a huge amount of information put him in a situation where he was surrounded by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Back to &quot;First Man&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Rebel&quot; involves a commentary on Surrealism and was immediately criticized literary by the group. Refute. More intense criticism came from leftist thinkers. Because he disagreed with Camus&#39;s many views on the revolution and Soviet history, the magazine &quot;Modern&quot; edited by Sartre published a fiercely criticized article by its editor, Francis Chanson. Camus had to respond and wrote an open letter to Sartre to defend himself. This led to Sartre&#39;s &quot;Reply to Camus&quot;, which was extremely harsh and mean, calling Camus &quot;a bourgeois&quot; and &quot;abandoned history&quot;, and the publication of &quot;The Resistance&quot; was a counter-revolutionary &quot;Thermidor Coup&quot;. . Their long-standing friendship was ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike many writers who only define their writing by &quot;pure literature&quot;, Camus has always been an organic intellectual. It was the strong &quot;political nature&quot; of &quot;The Resistance&quot; that stirred up the hornet&#39;s nest. The break between Sartre and Camus, the pair of existential writers, and the subsequent breakup between Godard and Truffaut, the twin stars of the French New Wave of cinema, became sensational and intriguing events in the postwar cultural history. Sartre stood in a more radical position. Even when it came to the Nobel Prize, he was more radical and rejected it outright. What is depressing is that Camus, a writer who has always been in the progressive camp, was denounced as conservative because he was more moderate on certain issues, or did not follow a certain principle or dogma and put forward his personal understanding and judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1949, Camus created a play &quot;The Just&quot;, in which a group of &quot;terrorists&quot; debate whether innocent people can be harmed when carrying out political assassinations. Camus made it clear that this was wrong. When Algeria&#39;s independence struggle broke out in 1954, he also believed that the rebels&#39; planting bombs and killing innocent people were equally unfair as the French government&#39;s violence and execution. This view made him controversial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a speech celebrating Camus&#39;s winning of the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1957, Camus was asked to explain why he did not support the Algerian uprising against colonialism. He said: &quot;Now people are going to Algeria. put bombs on the tram tracks. My mother might have been on one of the tracks. If that was justice, I would have chosen my mother.&quot; Camus called for the creation of an Arab, Berber, Blackfoot nation in Algeria A coalition government in which Frenchmen (European immigrants) governed as equals made everyone hate him. French nationalists feel that he sympathizes with Algerians, and Algerians feel that he represents white French people. However, his father died needlessly at the age of 29, and his mother was an extremely poor and illiterate woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 4, 1960, the car driven by publisher Michel Gallimard with Albert Camus in the back seat crashed into a tree, rolled and struck another. In the tree, Camus was thrown out of the back window. In the mud not far away, people found a briefcase containing Camus&#39;s diary and an unfinished novel &quot;First Man&quot;. This book is based on his childhood life in Algeria and imagines him. &#39;s father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Camus passed away, although Sartre did not forgive him, he wrote an obituary full of praise in the &quot;Osservatore Française&quot;: &quot;He was the heir to the ethical school of anti-historical trends in the 20th century. , his works are perhaps the most original of all French literati. His stubborn, narrow-minded, simple and simple humanitarian feelings launched an unreasonable challenge to the widespread and ugly orders of our time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After receiving the news of Camus’ death over the phone, Beauvoir took sleeping pills that had been discontinued for a long time, but still couldn’t fall asleep, so she got out of bed and braved the biting January drizzle in Paris. Wandering the streets. The next morning, she was still in a daze: &quot;He can&#39;t see this morning.&quot; But in fact, Camus not only did not pass away, but because of the strong impact of the car accident, he became the center of the world&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last few pages of &quot;Camus&#39; Notes&quot;, there are these words: &quot;In the short daylight given to you, keep warm, illuminate, and don&#39;t deviate from your track. ... Millions of other suns come to accompany you to rest. ... Under the happy slate, sleep for the first time. ... The wind sows, the wind harvests, but the creator is human, passing through the times, with a moment of life Proud.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(References: Herbert Lotman&#39;s &quot;The Biography of Camus&quot;, Sarah Bakewell&#39;s &quot;The Existential Café&quot;, &quot;The Complete Works of Camus&quot; edited by Liu Mingjiu and &quot;Camus&#39; Notes: 1935-1959 (Selected Collection)&quot; translated by Guo Hongan)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[再访“山地之王”：高仙芝的西域足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260116]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hijri 133 (&lt;em>;Ten years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty, AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;751 &lt;/em>;), the month of pilgrimage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hajj month is the 12th month of Muharram. This year&#39;s pilgrimage month is in midsummer. On the edge of the Central Asian steppes, a black flag army knelt down and prayed in the direction of the Holy Land on the right bank of the Talas River, completed the morning ritual, and then set up its formation facing the rising sun. : At the front are light cavalry equipped with large horses. They hold Damascus scimitars and stand on foot to harness their power; then there is an infantry group mainly composed of Khorasan and Tocharian people, and behind them are archers and long-range soldiers. Spearmen; on both wings are Sogdian cavalry from the river countries. Although they are high-spirited, they have not been naturalized for a long time, and they are pagans. Their combat effectiveness is still questionable, so they are used to protect the flanks of the Islamic army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opposite the black flag army are the enemy forces from the mysterious silk country in the east. They were much smaller in number, so they placed their infantry in front in a defensive formation. These infantrymen are uniformly holding Eastern-style long-handled swords, which are bladed on both sides, reflecting dazzling light in the morning sun. The huge stainless steel blade is extremely sharp, no less than the cannibal&#39;s scimitar. With its weight Able to split a galloping horse in half, and as strong as a spearman to withstand the impact of cavalry. These infantrymen are also equipped with horses for marching, but these pack horses are now scattered along the Talas River behind the enemy&#39;s side. Behind the infantry were crossbowmen equipped with powerful crossbows, and on both sides were Qarluks Turkic cavalry from the northern steppes. Behind the main force of these infantry and cavalry are their commanders, divided into main generals, deputy generals and special generals, as well as vassal troops from Bakhna as reserves - I heard that those guys started this war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The commander-in-chief of the Black Flag Army, Abu Muslim, is The great food in black &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(currently translated as the Abbasid Dynasty)&lt;/span>; is the leading founding father and a military genius who became a monk on the way. He was born as a slave of Persian descent and had been preaching at the bottom of the Great Food Empire for a long time. He returned to his homeland of Persia six years ago and raised an army to resist the white-clothed Food Empire&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(now Translated by Umayyad Dynasty)&lt;/span>;. Last winter, he led his army into Mesopotamia. In the Battle of the Zab River, he won with a small number and a large number. He first used an array of spearmen to withstand multiple rounds of attacks by the opponent&#39;s cavalry, and then launched a cavalry charge to defeat the enemy who had lost their fighting spirit. The infantry forced into the river with floating ice floes, defeated the enemy that was at least three times their size, hammered the last nail in the coffin of the white-clothed food that had enjoyed the country for ninety years, and established a more than 500-year-old army in Baghdad. Years of black food. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year he once again set out from Persia on an expedition to Central Asia to face the Chinese army who also came from afar. The commander of the other side heard that he was a handsome man named Gao Xianzhi. However, the origin of this battle has to start in Persia a full hundred years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Talas Valley in Kyrgyzstan. The location where the Battle of Talas took place is no longer known, but the battle took place at the mouth of the valley, and the terrain will be relatively flat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Barbarians of the West&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大In the second year of Yonghui of the Tang Dynasty (&lt;em>;AD&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;651&lt;/em>;), the young &quot;Tian Khan&quot; Li Zhi met in Chang&#39;an with an envoy sent for help by the last emperor of the Persian Sassanid Empire Yi Siqi. . The envoy said that a group of barbarians from the west were attacking Persia: they asked us to choose one of three situations: either accept their faith, pay a poll tax, or go to war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The envoy did not know that when he begged Tang Gaozong to send troops to rescue Persia, Yi Siqi had already died on the way to escape. The surviving prince Belus &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Persian means &quot;Victor&quot;)&lt;/span>; suffered repeated defeats and finally fled to China. , and died here, buried in Luoyang, the eastern capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;barbarians&quot; who destroyed the Sasanian Dynasty were called &quot;Tachik&quot; by the Persians, but they were actually Arabs. The name &quot;Dashi&quot; comes from the Tayyi tribe in eastern Arabia. It was regarded by the Persians as a collective name for Arab Muslims. After it was spread to the Tang Dynasty, because they used white flags, Chinese history books called it &quot;Dashi in White&quot;. . After the Persians converted to Islam, they were called Tachik by the Turks. This is probably the origin of the name of the Tajik people who also speak Persian today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhi, who had been on the throne for less than three years, had no interest in rescuing Persia, which was far away. At that time, the Tang Dynasty had not yet completely pacified southern Xinjiang, and its limited military resources had to be used to control the four towns of Anxi to the east of Congling, and were beyond its reach to the west of Congling. After Dashi conquered Persia, the expansion momentum in the east was suspended due to domestic battles for throne. It was not until the 60th year that the rear sent the famous general Qutaybah ibn Muslim to the east to attack the Transoxiana region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hezhong&quot; area, as the name suggests, is the Amu Darya River, the two largest rivers in Central Asia&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (called Wuhu River in ancient times)&lt; /span>;The plain area between the Syr Darya River (ancient name Yaoshashui), it borders the Central Asian grasslands to the north, the Tianshan Mountains and the Hindu Kush Mountains to the southeast, two long and high majestic mountain ranges, and Persia to the southwest plateau. Business travelers who walked out of Congling along the two rivers gathered here, and the goods changed hands here and continued to the Mesopotamia and Asia Minor through the Persian Plateau. Therefore, the Transoxiang area has been an important hub of the Silk Road since ancient times. During the Han Dynasty, the Yuezhi people migrated here from the Mongolian Plateau under the attacks of the Xiongnu and Wusun. After merging with the locals, they formed the Sogdians. They established many oasis countries such as Kang, Shi, An, and Shi in the arid river area. Chinese history books call them the Nine Surnames of Zhaowu. Because the Sogdians lived on the trade route, they became an outstanding commercial nation that integrated trade between the East and the West in the Middle Ages. A large number of merchants moved to the Central Plains to work as businessmen. The image of the Hu people on the camels and horses in the Tang Sancai is the Sogdians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; >;In the first year of Xiantian of the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(712 AD)&lt;/span>;, Qu Dibo marched into the river from Khorasan in northeastern Persia, and successively Capture Samadan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now translated as Samarkand)&lt;/span>;, and the Kingdom of Shi , STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s Tashkent)&lt;/span>;, Bakhna&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(today&#39;s translation of Fergana)&lt;/span>; and other countries. At that time, Li Longji, Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, had just ascended the throne and was plotting to overthrow his aunt Princess Taiping, who was involved in politics. They were as indifferent to the killings west of Congling as his grandfather Li Zhi was. Two years later, Qu Dibo, who was militarily unstoppable, was accidentally killed during civil strife. The white-clad army retreated as quickly as it came. Tubo, which had coveted this place for a long time, took advantage of the opportunity and established the new king Ada in Bukhanna. This move immediately aroused great vigilance in the Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samarkand, Uzbekistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中Sub-geopolitics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bahanna&quot; is an ancient name, now it is called &quot;Ferg&#39;ona&quot;, and its consonant &quot;g&quot; was still given by Russian colonists In addition, I heard that the local people actually pronounce it as Fer&#39;ana, and the pronunciation is close to &quot;Fuana&quot;. It is a basin at the end of the West Tianshan Mountains. It was called Dawan in the Han Dynasty and the famous sweat-blooded horse was produced here. During the Soviet era, in order to divide the Turkic tribes so that they could divide and rule, the Russians forcibly subdivided five ethnic groups in Central Asia and built five intertwined &quot;Stans&quot;. Especially in the small Fergana Basin, they actually divided them It was divided among the three union republics of Uzbekistan, Kyrgyzstan and Tajikistan, and a large number of enclaves and even enclaves within enclaves were carved out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fergana Basin map, enclaves within enclaves, can be seen intertwined. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna in the Tang Dynasty did not have these disputes. It was a single-ethnic Sogdian country. It was located in Between Suiye, an important town in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty, and the Hezhong countries, it was the key point from the Anxi Protectorate to the Hezhong area via Congling. What&#39;s more important is that the Tang Dynasty could accept the food control of Bukhana, but it could not sit back and watch Tibet enter the Central Asian grasslands - this involved the geopolitics among the four major countries in Central Asia at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bakhanna is surrounded by great powers, with Turks in the north, Tubo in the south, Dashi in the west, and Tang in the east. The Turks were traditional conquerors of the grasslands, and used their strong fighting power to collect protection fees from the riverine countries; the White Food was an emerging empire that combined politics and religion, but in the early stages of its expansion, it was neither for war nor for wealth, but for &quot;Find an outlet for the warlike spirit of each tribe&quot; - Turks and Dashi are a zero-sum game between the old and new conquerors, which cannot be reconciled; Tubo arose in the bitter cold land of Qinghai-Tibet, and always aimed at the rich Central Plains, but suffered from Unable to open the tightly-knitted fences of the Tang Dynasty, they detoured to Congling, hoping to join forces with the Turks in the north to carve up the western regions of the Tang Dynasty, and then enter the hinterland of the Central Plains along the Hexi Corridor; and the Tang Dynasty was the only one of the four great powers to be dominated by farming. The political power established by the nation, the primary goal of opening up the Western Region is to use offense as defense to defend its own territory: from Guanzhong via Longxi and Hexi to Anxi, and finally reach Congling, the western border of the Tarim Basin. Just defend the towering Congling. Block external forces from entering the Central Plains. Therefore, the Tang Dynasty’s pursuit was not to plunder land and colonize&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(大食)&lt;/span>; or to exploit the natives&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Turkic)&lt;/span>;, opening up channels&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Tubo)&lt;/span>; or protecting trade routes ——The trade routes were just a by-product of the expansion of the Tang Dynasty, not the purpose. Instead, they simply defended themselves and blocked the north-south passages to prevent powerful enemies from forming alliances to deal with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this way, Tubo and Turks from the south and north seek to join forces to attack the common enemy Tang Dynasty, while Datang Dynasty and Dashi Dynasty occupy both sides of Congling, one from the east and the other from the west. Once Tibet crossed this east-west equilibrium line and was expected to enter the northern grasslands and join the Turks, Datang&#39;s &quot;red alert&quot; was triggered. In the third year of Kaiyuan of the Tang Dynasty (715 AD), Qu Dibo was killed, the food army withdrew, and the Tubo army In the year when they conquered Ba Khanna, Zhang Xiaosong, the supervisory censor who was inspecting the Anxi Protectorate, made a decisive decision. He marched across the Daidai territory and commanded the vassal army of the slave country to march thousands of miles straight, crossed the Congling Mountains and arrived at the Ba Khanna Basin, where he defeated the heavy Tibetan army. Eight hundred years after Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty conquered Dawan, he occupied this place again and blocked the Tibetan entrance to the Central Asian grassland through the Congling West Road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Tubo tried to open up the Congling East Road through Taobolu, but was also frustrated by Zhang Xiaosong, who was the governor of Beiting at the time: in the tenth year of Kaiyuan&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(722 AD)&lt;/span>; Zhang Xiaosong sent 4,000 cavalry to rescue Xiao Bolu and defeated the Tibetan army. This matter has been mentioned in the previous article &quot;Visiting the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot;: Gao Xianzhi&#39;s Plateau Footprints&quot; and, so I won’t go into details. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Expedition to Congling West Road&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Eight Years of Tianbao in the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (749 AD)&lt;/span>;, two years after Gao Xianzhi regained Xiaobolu, he returned to Boxian &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Qiemo, Xinjiang)&lt;/span>; span>;Destroy Tubo. The Tibetan army, which suffered a bloody blow on the eastern front, had to turn around and head to the Congling West Road on the western front to find the weaknesses of the Tang Dynasty&#39;s Western Region defense system. After receiving the information, Gao Xianzhi could have gone to Bahanna, where he would have been waiting for the Tibetan troops who had been on an expedition to come and give them a head-on attack. However, Gao Xianzhi, who had been pursuing the initiative on the battlefield all his life, did not do that: since the Congling West Road was still passable. , then I will cut it off completely! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Street scene in Chitral, Pakistan, the seat of the ancient Shishi Kingdom. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianbao Nine Years&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (A.D. 750)&lt;/span>; Gao Xianzhi sent troops to Congling for the second time and came to Xiaobolu again. From there, he followed the Suyi River (Today&#39;s Gilgit River)&lt;/span>;Go upstream, cross the Shanduer Pass, and head to the Kingdom of Shishi at the eastern foot of the central Hindu Kush Mountains ;&quot;>;(now Chitral, Pakistan)&lt;/span>;. Some historians have verified that the Kingdom of Shishi was the end point of Alexander the Great&#39;s Eastern Expedition. The ancient tribes that thrive in the nearby Kalasha Valley are said to be the descendants of the Greek expeditionary force. The distance from Xiaobolu to Yushi is more than 700 miles. Now it takes two full days to travel by road. The road conditions are very good on the first day, and there are long-distance buses available. On the second day, we can only take the local four-wheel drive with the villagers. It is possible to travel west along the Mastuj Valley, with the continuous snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Kush to the north and the 6,542-meter-high snow-capped mountains of the Hindu Raj to the south. Peak Buni Zom. The Mastuje River cuts deeply into the dense loess at your feet, forming a T-shaped towering platform, which is reminiscent of the Tuolai River Valley outside Jiayuguan. The soldiers under Gao Xianzhi must have drank by the Tuolai River on their way from the Central Plains to the Western Regions via Hexi. Let&#39;s cross the horse, I believe they also discovered the similarities between the two places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Toolai Valley outside Jiayuguan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two Tang Books&quot; &quot;&quot; does not record how long Gao Xianzhi went on the expedition against the Xu division, and &quot;Zizhi Tongjian&quot; only mentions the winter march of the Tang army. According to my estimate of the terrain along the route of our division, it would have taken an ancient army at least half a month to carry its baggage. It was even more difficult for the Tubo army: since the Tang army had controlled Xiaobolu and the Suyi River Valley three years ago, the Tubo army had to detour through the high mountains in the south. Whether they could reach Yushi in a month was a problem. The Kingdom of Yushi is an ally of Tubo. It is located at the midpoint of the West Congling Road. After passing Yushi, you can cross the Hindu Kush Mountains, then follow the Panchi River through the Alai Mountains in the west of Congling and the West Tianshan Mountains, and finally arrive at Bakhna Basin - that was another more than a month&#39;s journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Gao Xianzhi made a surprise attack on the Chu army and cut off the west road of Congling, the extremely tired Tibetan soldiers who had come from afar no longer had to cross the four great mountains of Hindu Lage, Hindu Kush, Congling and Xitian Mountain. Mountains, not to mention struggling to attack the fortress jointly guarded by the Tang army and the Sogdians in the scorching Bukhan, you can return to the cool Qinghai-Tibet Plateau all in one piece - isn&#39;t this the peace dividend brought by General Gao of the Tang Dynasty? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, after losing the important relay point of Xushi Division, Tubo completely gave up the idea of ​​opening up the east and west roads of Congling. Zai and Thirteen were defeated by Gao Xianzhi&#39;s successor Feng Changqing on the two eastern fronts, so that the Tibetan army was unable to pose a major threat to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty for the next ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi successively put down the Tibetan offensive on the east and west fronts, and pushed the Tang Dynasty&#39;s military control line from the east of Congling to the west of Congling, achieving the strategic goal of stabilizing the Western Region and defending the Central Plains. It can be said that it has achieved reached the pinnacle of personal military achievement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at this moment, he received a letter of request for help from Ba Khanna, asking him to stop by the army to attack the Shi Kingdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;费尔干纳盆地的传统茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“诸胡皆怒”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;拔汗那先被白衣大食灭国，又被吐蕃扶植傀儡政权，最后依靠大唐援军方得以复国，因此是中亚地区对大唐最为忠诚的属国，可以比拟为高丽之于大明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么拔汗那为什么要吁请唐军攻打石国呢？此事缺乏明确的史料记载，一般认为可能有三方面的原因，一是拔汗那与石国有隙，拔汗那位于药杀水上游的盆地中，而石国位于药杀水流出盆地的下游方向，其首都拓折城就是今天的乌兹别克斯坦首都塔什干（Toshkent），“拓折”就是“塔什/Tosh”，乃是突厥语“石头”的意思。两国同为粟特国家，石国扼拔汗那通往中亚草原的出口，而拔汗那则扼石国的水源，两国或有积怨；二是拔汗那向大唐输诚，趁河中之地陷入权力真空之机予以控制；三是石国位于河中地区与中亚草原接壤的前沿，与突厥的主要部落突骑施的继承者黄姓突骑施交好，而突骑施长期是大唐的威胁，踩到了大唐的红线。总之高仙芝采纳了拔汗那的建议，引军北上进入费尔干纳盆地，再沿着药杀水抵达石国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石国属于河中地区的昭武九姓诸国，是大唐的羁縻之地，它们奉唐朝为宗主国，向大唐定期朝贡，但没有行政、财政和军事上的实际管控关系。高仙芝讨伐石国的名义是“无藩臣礼”，但史书上没有列举具体罪状。弱小的石国提出讲和，高仙芝假意应允，却囚禁了亲自前来和谈的石国国王那俱车鼻施——他曾在小勃律之战中使用过相似的计谋，以财货诱捕亲吐蕃的小勃律贵族出城后实施抓捕斩首——然后兵不血刃地占领了拓折城。破城后，高仙芝纵兵大肆杀戮，还掠夺了石国的大量珍宝，光其本人就获得“瑟瑟十馀斛、黄金五六橐驼、良马宝玉甚众，家赀累钜万”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里所说的“瑟瑟”乃是中世纪最为昂贵的矿石之一：青金石。它原产于乌浒水上游的巴达赫尚地区&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今阿富汗东北部）&lt;/span>;，经河中地区转口贩运至世界各地，既是珍贵的宝石、治病的“神药”，也是稀有的蓝、紫色颜料。 2022年跨年舞蹈《只此青绿》而爆火的青绿色调，其缘起就是宋徽宗以宫廷御藏的珍贵青金石供青年画家王希孟绘制的传世珍品《千里江山图》，而白居易的千古名句“半江瑟瑟半江红”，诵咏的也是江水在夕阳照射下泛出的青金石色彩。高仙芝从石国劫掠了大量青金石，想必是其府库历年蓄积的珍品，尤列于黄金之前，其价值可想而知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京故宫珍宝馆的青金石雕松泉人物图山子（清&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝将此次远征所俘虏的石国国王、朅师国王、吐蕃酋长以及很可能是在石国一并捕获的黄姓突骑施可汗&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（或可解释高仙芝为何屠戮拓折城以惩罚石国的通敌行为）&lt;/span>;一股脑儿送回长安献俘阙下，战功可谓煊赫。但他的背信之举和残酷屠杀激起了除拔汗那之外河中诸国的公愤，据《资治通鉴》记载，“石国王子逃诣诸胡，具告仙芝欺诱贪暴之状。诸胡皆怒，潜引大食欲共攻四镇”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而根据大食史料记载，战争的起因是拔汗那与石国敌对，向大唐求援；唐军包围石国，石国国王投降，并未受到迫害；大食得知此事后出兵与大唐交战——这一叙述前后缺乏逻辑，难以解释大食出兵的原因。据我看来，那一年大食刚好完成改朝换代，黑衣大食取代了白衣大食，正需要一场对外战争的胜利来弥合内部的分裂。统帅并波悉林则刚刚镇压了安国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉）&lt;/span>;的叛乱，得以腾出手来以安国为基地出兵侵占他的前辈屈底波曾经征服过的河中地区。如今河中诸国主动前来归顺，正中其下怀。并波悉林遂照单全收吞并了河中之地，然后率领士气正旺的大食雄师与河中诸国的附庸军沿着中亚草原向东进发，兵锋直指大唐在西域的前哨碎叶城。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而高仙芝得知河中巨变，第三次统率安西四镇的主力部队以及葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军越过葱岭，前往河中平叛，两支大军遂在拓折城与碎叶城之间的怛逻斯遭遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;怛罗斯之战地图，宁远即为拔汗那。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“中亚的关原之战”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“怛逻斯”是石国东部城池的名字，得名于塔拉斯河，后者是西天山余脉中的一条山间河流，水量虽然不大但源远流长，长达一千多里。塔拉斯河的下游沿着河谷向西北方向流淌，最后进入草原地带。如今河谷内的山地属于吉尔吉斯斯坦，河谷以外的平原地带则属于哈萨克斯坦。河谷里有一座吉尔吉斯小镇叫做塔拉斯（Talas），河谷外的草原上则有一座哈萨克大城叫做塔拉兹（Taraz）。苏联时代于1975年在塔拉斯河谷山口修建了一座基洛夫水库，拦住了本就不多的河水——水库深度仅7米，用于河谷内的农业灌溉，因此塔拉斯河进入哈萨克斯坦国境后只剩下涓涓细流，形成一片饥渴的绿洲，最后断流于沙漠之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;建于苏联时代的基洛夫水库&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于年代久远，如今已经无法确认唐代的怛逻斯城究竟是今天的塔拉斯镇还是塔拉兹城，抑或位于两者之间的某一点。由于地处吉尔吉斯斯坦和哈萨克斯坦边境地带，作为外国人的我无法抵近塔拉斯河谷出口——怛逻斯之战最有可能发生的地方——开展考察，也无法放飞无人机从空中俯瞰这条河谷。但可以肯定的是，兵力较少的大唐联军占据了地势略高的河谷内侧，用山峦和河流保护自己的侧翼；兵力占优的大食联军则从草原一侧向河谷进攻，双方在塔拉斯河北岸摆开了战场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;塔拉斯河&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于双方的兵力对比，史家众说纷纭，目前一般认为大唐联军兵力为2—3万人，鉴于整个安西大都护府的兵力不超过三万人，还要守备偌大的南疆，不可能悉数调往前线，我倾向于《资治通鉴》的记载，高仙芝此次远征的总兵力约三万人，估计其中一半为唐军，以步兵为主，其余系葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军，其中葛逻禄军为骑兵，拔汗那军也以步兵为主。或有一种说法是唐军兵力高达六、七万人，这就意味着其中绝大部分是附庸军，并不符合当时大唐在河中地区众叛亲离，仅有拔汗那追随的实际情况，而葛逻禄作为初兴的突厥部落也无法提供这么多兵力。大食方面史料更加缺乏，一般认为有7—10万人，也有认为高达20至30万人的，我认为以当时的后勤保障条件，无法支撑如此巨大的兵力在草原上远征，所以姑且认为这场战争是7万大食联军与3万大唐联军在塔拉斯河边展开的一场野战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史载这场战役打了五天，前四天大食军队主攻，但未能突破唐军构成的严密防御阵形，可到了第五天，战场形势发生了戏剧性的逆转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有日本学者把这场战役比喻为“中亚的关原之战”——关原之战是日本安土桃山时代投入兵力规模最大的一场战役，西军主力以寡敌众，即将赢得战场主动之际，原本按兵不动驻扎在侧翼山顶的友军小早川秀秋部突然倒戈，切入了正与东军激战的西军主力后方，对其形成夹击之势，西军遂土崩瓦解。这一类比虽然不尽确切，但确与怛逻斯之战的逆转颇有相似：唐军精锐的陌刀队挡住了大食军的多轮攻击，原本有望复刻对方主帅并波悉林去年在扎卜河战役中的成功范例，用骑兵反冲锋压垮敌军斗志。只可惜大唐联军的骑兵部队是葛逻禄附庸军，在这个唐军即将赢得战场主动的关键时刻，与大食早有默契的葛逻禄人反戈一击，反而切入了正与大食军激战的唐军后方，对其形成夹击之势，唐军主力遂陷入重围苦战之中，伤亡殆尽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主将高仙芝不甘心就此失败，还指望用预备队稳住阵脚，收拢前线败兵后再与敌军一决雌雄。他的副将、曾在连云堡战斗中立下奇功的猛将李嗣业在危急关头劝他撤退：将军孤军深入，没有援军，而周围胡人诸国都是追随胜者的墙头草，一定会对我们群起围攻。一旦我们全军覆没，还有谁回去守卫南疆呢？我虽然是个莽汉，也看得清形势危急，将军可不能再拘泥固执了！ &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《旧唐书·李嗣业列传》：愚者千虑，或有一得，势危若此，不可胶柱）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，李嗣业拽着高仙芝放弃了被包围的唐军主力，沿塔拉斯河谷向东撤退。地势渐高，山道渐窄，作为预备队最先调头撤退的拔汗那附庸军把道路堵得严严实实，后面的唐军无法通过，眼看就要被大食追兵赶上。这时李嗣业放下陌刀，抡起大棒向拔汗那友军左右开弓，“人马应手俱毙”，拔汗那军纷纷向左右避让，高仙芝得以逃出生天；而唐军的第三把手、别将段秀实挺身而出，责备上司李嗣业为了自己逃命而杀害友军，“惮敌而奔，非勇也；免己陷众，非仁也”，李嗣业这才羞惭地停止杀戮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是唐军在怛逻斯大败后的惨状。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省的入口拱门&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;怛逻斯战役结束后，两军各自回国，大唐与大食仍以葱岭为界，战略均衡并未发生根本改变。之后的五年里，黑衣大食向大唐先后派出了八批使臣，表明双方仍然维持着密切的外交关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;葛逻禄：临阵倒戈的突厥部族，在怛逻斯之战后与吐蕃结盟，继承了突骑施的角色，成为草原上新一代的突厥征服者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那，葱岭一隅的西域属国，在怛逻斯惨败和杀戮后依然效忠大唐，“事唐最谨”。 “安史之乱”爆发后，拔汗那响应唐肃宗邀请，不远万里发兵援助中原。时至今日，费尔干纳仍是世界丝绸重镇，生丝出产量列全球第三，这便是唐代丝路花雨对这个酷热盆地的千年遗泽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河中诸国，大国博弈下的粟特城邦，大唐在“安史之乱”后退出西域，这些波斯化国家在大食与突厥的影响下又陆续发生了伊斯兰化和突厥化的历史性转变。根据历史学家考证，造纸术早在怛逻斯战役爆发前就已经传播至此，它助力昭武九姓中的安国逐步成为穆斯林世界重要的文化中心，被誉为“伊斯兰支柱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉伊斯兰文化中心的象征：Mir-i-Arab经学院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并波悉林，奴隶出身的战神统帅，在三年后卷入了黑衣大食夺位之争。他支持第二代哈里发打败了对手，却于三个月后被这位哈里发虐杀——诚所谓“飞鸟尽，良弓藏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段秀实，直言极谏的儒将，撤回安西后被遭他斥责过的李嗣业提拔为判官，两年后又辅佐封常清攻克大勃律，在平定“安史之乱”和抗击吐蕃前线也屡立大功，64岁高龄时因反对叛臣朱泚而殉国——文天祥《正气歌》中的“或为击贼笏”说的就是他誓死讨贼的典故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李嗣业，身高两米的猛将，在“安史之乱”中回军中原勤王，曾与中兴名将郭子仪联手，以弱敌强，连战连捷，陆续收复关中平原和东都洛阳，成为积弱唐军中的“救火队员”。大唐乾元二年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元759年）&lt;/span>;，他在作战时中流矢，“出血数升，注地而卒”——每当说到李嗣业，我首先会想起“当嗣业刀者，人马俱碎”的勇武场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省奥特莫克山口，一千二百多年前的“山地之王”没准路经此地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝，胆识超凡但贪功爱财的名将，怛逻斯战役四年后“安史之乱”爆发，高仙芝与封常清受命统率临时纠集的乌合之众抵挡精锐叛军主力，只得依据坚城死守潼关，却因此被唐玄宗下诏双双斩杀。接替他们俩的另一位名将哥舒翰被迫出兵与叛军野战，结果全军覆没，潼关失守，长安沦陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝临死前曾有机会翻盘：当时向玄宗进谗并奉旨到潼关处决高仙芝的太监边令诚率领百余名陌刀手为自己壮胆，却不曾想这些精锐军士齐声高呼：高将军冤枉！ “其声殷地”。高仙芝本可借助于这些忠诚的士兵收捕边令诚，或可迫使玄宗收回成命。但他最终没有这么做，而是望着老战友封常清的尸首慨然长叹，束手赴死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位盛唐名将，最终随盛唐一并化为泡影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:26:40 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一家经营不善的公司，承建了佳木斯5年就垮的体育馆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:36:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOo Bpgrqzc. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huannan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 19:20 on November 6, 2023, an incident occurred in the National Fitness Gymnasium of Yuecheng Square, Huanan County, Jiamusi City, Heilongjiang Province Collapse accident. At that time, seven junior high school students were playing basketball inside. One student noticed an abnormality in the roof and ran to the door. Then the roof collapsed, with a total collapse area of ​​675 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 7 students, 3 escaped on their own, 1 was rescued and sent to hospital, and 3 died. A friend of the victim told the media that he was a young man who loved playing basketball since he was a child and was called the &quot;Ball King&quot; by his classmates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 24, 2023, the Magistrate of Huanan County went to the gymnasium to inspect the safety work, and emphasized that cultural market operators must fulfill their main responsibilities for safety production and always tighten the string of safety production. The day before, the roof collapsed in the gymnasium of No. 34 Middle School in Qiqihar, Heilongjiang Province - that accident killed 11 teachers and students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, the discipline inspection and supervision agencies at the Jiamusi City and Huanan County levels immediately intervened and set up an investigation team to investigate. The Huanan County Government Information Office said that the operator of the collapsed venue was Huanan County New Sunshine Fitness Club. The person in charge, Men Yanan, has been controlled by the police, and the cause of the accident is under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The building owner of the gymnasium once leased the venue to others for operation, but starting from December 2022, it will be transferred to the management of the New Sunshine Fitness Club run by Men Yanan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Men Yanan is Yuecheng&#39;s &quot;old friend&quot;. She established Yuecheng Sports and Fitness Club in April 2021, canceled the company eight months later, and established New Sunshine Fitness Club in July 2022. She also serves as a supervisor at Hunan County Yuecheng Cinema City Co., Ltd. The actual controller of the company is Yang Jinli, who is the actual controller and beneficial owner of Hunan County Yuecheng Commercial Building Co., Ltd. established in August 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuecheng Plaza is a project that the Huanan County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Department vigorously attracts investment. Beijing Deyiyintong Technology Co., Ltd. invested 380 million yuan to register Heilongjiang Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. to build an urban commercial complex and a high-end residential community in the original shanty town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2015 to 2022, three companies, Yuecheng Real Estate Development Co., Ltd., Yuecheng Commercial Building Co., Ltd., and Yuecheng Sports Culture Development Co., Ltd. were established in Hunan County. Many of the shareholders and executives overlapped, but this Three companies have been deregistered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Huanan County Government Information Office, Building 7 of the Yuecheng Plaza complex where the accident occurred was built by Heilongjiang Haifeng Weiye Construction and Installation Engineering Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Haifeng Weiye&quot;) in July 2017. Construction started and was completed in July 2018. The supervision unit is Jiamusi Sanjiang Construction Supervision Company. It passed the acceptance inspection in July 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, Haifeng Weiye was established in Hegang City with investment from Zhu Hai and Zhu Bo (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Er Zhu&quot;). In May 2016, Er Zhu quit the company and 26-year-old Yue Chengqi took over. One year later, the construction of the Yuecheng Plaza complex began, and Haifeng Weiye&#39;s market entity type was changed from &quot;natural person investment or holding&quot; to &quot;natural person sole proprietorship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A civil judgment with the case number &quot;(2018) Black 0822 Minchu No. 272&quot; shows that before 2016, Haifeng Weiye, who mainly worked on projects in Hegang, was heavily in debt, so he paid annual interest rates Borrow money from Yue Chengqi at 6% interest. In 2016, Erzhu completely gave up Haifeng Weiye and transferred it to Yuecheng Qi. At this time, Zhu Hai and Zhu Bo still owed the Hegang Gongnong District Local Taxation Bureau and the National Taxation Bureau a total of 2,059,920.94 yuan in taxes plus late payment fees. They borrowed money from Yue Chengqi and paid the taxes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2018, Yue Chengqi sued Erzhu for repaying the loan and interest, and received support from the court. However, Erzhu said that he had no money and could not repay it for the time being. This loan totaling 2.42 million yuan was not enforced until 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first took over Haifeng Weiye, Yue Chengqi tried many ways to make money, such as purchasing resettlement housing that had been delivered but was resold several times. Later, the court believed that he was purchasing a house. He failed to verify the situation of the actual residents at the time, which constituted a gross negligence. Therefore, his claim for physical ownership of the relocated house is not supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also participated in gambling and ended up with 7,500 yuan in gambling capital. After losing all, he borrowed 10,000 yuan on the spot, with interest of 300 yuan per day. Later, he was caught on the spot by the public security organs on December 2, 2016, his gambling funds were confiscated, and he was subject to administrative penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yue Chengqi&#39;s social software avatar is a picture that says &quot;Life depends on oneself&quot;, and the signature is &quot;What parents give is called background, what one works hard for is called country, there is a kind of hard work called relying on oneself&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking over Haifeng Weiye, Yue Chengqi had no experience in managing construction companies or large-scale construction projects. But through hard work, he used a Hegang construction company that was being enforced for debt arrears to take over the Yuecheng Plaza, a star project in Hunan County with an investment of 170 million yuan. After that, Haifeng Weiye became a major tenderer of Huanan County Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the public bidding information, &quot;Southern Weekend&quot; concluded: &quot;(Haifeng Weiye) has participated in a wide variety of projects. In terms of municipal engineering, it has undertaken the construction of public parking lots, roads, high-speed rail parking lots, etc., as well as medical projects There are the county CDC, the infectious disease area of ​​the county hospital, and the 120 emergency center, as well as the beautiful rural infrastructure construction in Huanan County, the material reserve warehouse of the county power supply bureau, and the black soil transfer earthwork in the pig slaughtering plant area of ​​​​Huanan Economic Development Zone. In addition, we also won the bid for the county&#39;s affordable housing project.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the night of the accident, Yue Chengqi gave a brief interview to Southern Weekend. He said that he was already aware of the stadium collapse incident, but was not sure if it was his own project. &quot;I need to go back and check the information.&quot; The next day, Yue Chengqi&#39;s mobile phone continued to go unanswered. In the afternoon of the same day, Jiamusi issued a notice confirming that Haifeng Weiye was responsible for the stadium collapse. Construction side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huanan County Yuecheng Plaza National Fitness Gym Collapse Accident Site&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heilongjiang Huayou Construction Engineering Co., Ltd., another developer that once undertook the Yuecheng Plaza complex, is actually the second shareholder of Yuecheng Real Estate and is also a major tenderer for local government projects. It once undertook the renovation of the Jiamusi Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital. Yongfang, the cultural facilities construction project of Huachuan County Culture, Radio, Television, Press and Publication Bureau and the dilapidated house renovation project of Huannan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the incident, a staff member of the Propaganda Department of Huanan County Party Committee responded in an interview with the media that the roof collapse was related to snowfall. Huanan County issued a red snow warning signal at 16:47 that day, prompting the suspension of classes and businesses (except for special industries) if necessary. According to meteorological monitoring, the snowfall in Hunan County, where the incident occurred, reached 44 mm in 24 hours on the 6th, breaking the November snowfall record. Just two days ago, the county held a working meeting on preventing and responding to the current extreme weather, requiring various industries and fields to do their own safety precautions according to the division of responsibilities and minimize the occurrence of secondary disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访港交所前行政总裁李小加：互联互通是香港资本市场成功的基石]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Li Xiaojia is known as &quot;one of the earliest practitioners of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial securities industry.&quot; While working at the famous Wall Street law firm Davis Polk &amp;amp; Wardwell and Brown &amp;amp; Wood, he was invited by &lt;span>;China&#39;s Ministry of Finance&lt;/span>; to participate in China&#39;s first global sovereign debt transaction. Issuance work; when he served as Chairman of Merrill Lynch China and Chairman of JP Morgan China, Li Xiaojia took the lead in the cross-border listing of the first batch of central state-owned enterprises such as CNOOC and China Mobile; he participated in the planning and initiation of the China National Offshore Oil Bid for Unique, and was He believes that &quot;created a new era for Chinese enterprises&quot;; after more than ten years in charge of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, he successfully promoted a number of strategic initiatives that were crucial in the history of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, including &quot;Shanghai-Hong Kong Stock Connect&quot; and &quot;Shenzhen-Hong Kong Stock Connect&quot;. What impressed the market even more was the implementation of the reform of the different rights listing system for the same shares in 2018 and the acquisition of the London Metal Exchange in 2012. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, he started a business called &quot;Drip Irrigation Connect&quot; and established and operated the &quot;Drip Irrigation Connect&quot; ASX in accordance with the relevant administrative orders of the Macau government, hoping to &quot;connect international capital with China&#39;s small and micro enterprises.&quot; This is a revolutionary financial experiment on a global scale. After 7 months, on October 26, 2023, Drip Tong ASX was certified by the Sharia Regulatory Commission and complied with Islamic teachings such as the prohibition of interest collection. &lt;span>;This certification includes&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Islamic Finance&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s confirmation that the income sharing product created by Diguantong is not a loan interest collection model, and recognizes that Diguantong’s investment is based on sharing of risks. Way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did China issue its first global sovereign debt more than thirty years ago? Why did China&#39;s first batch of state-owned enterprises land in the U.S. capital market more than 20 years ago? Twenty years ago, how was the first overseas bidding done by a central enterprise? Over the past ten years, how has the Hong Kong Stock Exchange broken the ice and achieved interconnection with A-shares? In an exclusive interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend, Li Xiaojia reviewed these major events closely related to China&#39;s financial reform and opening up. He said that internationalization, embracing the new economy, and realizing interconnection are still the cornerstones of the success of Hong Kong&#39;s capital market today, and are also the reform and innovation for China&#39;s capital market to go global. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height= &quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Xiaojia: former CEO of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange and current founder and chairman of Drip Tong Group&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The overall benefits of promoting reform through overseas listing are multilateral&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once took the lead in participating in China&#39;s first issuance of global sovereign bonds. What are the main difficulties in this issuance of global sovereign bonds? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Issuing bonds first requires a major rating agency to provide a credit rating to China’s sovereign. The more than two months I was involved in the rating work were very stressful. If the rating is not appropriate, China will not issue sovereign debt at all. There are many stories happening in it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hard work, China obtained an A-level sovereign rating in 1993 and successfully issued bonds early the next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You also took the lead in presiding over the first batch of cross-border listings of central state-owned enterprises. What problem is it mainly intended to solve? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The appeal at that time was very simple, which was to relieve the difficulties of state-owned enterprises. At that time, a large number of state-owned enterprises were in great difficulty and had severe triangular debt. The main motivation is the reform of state-owned enterprises, which requires financing and relies on funds to carry out reforms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of state-owned enterprises requires truly entering the market and operating in accordance with the laws of market economy. In this process, everyone quickly felt that it was easy to unify everyone&#39;s thoughts through financing through the listing itself. Then use overseas listing as a catalyst. If you want to raise funds overseas, central state-owned enterprises must make various reforms and separate government functions, social functions and corporate functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These reforms have gradually become important in the process of overseas listing of central state-owned enterprises. It relies on financing to unify everyone&#39;s understanding. In order to achieve this goal, everyone slowly accepts some of the costs, some impacts and impacts that the reform must bear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Has promoting reform through overseas listing achieved the expected goals? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course. First, the purpose, or overall benefit, is multilateral. The business itself raised large sums of money at the most critical time. In 1993, the first batch of 9 companies was launched, and soon there were 22 companies. These companies have used overseas financing to make large capital expenditures and solve a large number of funding problems needed for development. It was a very timely solution to an urgent need for funds at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cross-border listing of central state-owned enterprises has really sounded the clarion call for the reform of state-owned enterprises, driving and urging the reform of various aspects of systems and mechanisms that were originally very difficult to initiate. After listing overseas, the reform of state-owned enterprises slowly entered the main track. Everyone began to fully accept the reform of state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, the cross-border listing of central state-owned enterprises quickly gave birth to the development of China&#39;s capital market. It is impossible for all of our companies to be listed abroad, and with so much capital in China, the people also have money. Why can&#39;t our capital be invested in our own businesses? From the perspective of issuers and investors&#39; desire to participate in the development dividends of reform and opening up, it has promoted the birth and development of China&#39;s capital market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another point that is also very important is that for the first time, a central state-owned enterprise has gone global. The outside world is beginning to understand Chinese companies and the Chinese economy. Then foreign capital has deeply cared about, participated in and experienced China&#39;s economic modernization due to their investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How much room do you think there is for improving the internal governance efficiency of central state-owned enterprises in my country? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is a state-owned enterprise or a central enterprise, it is just a form of ownership. Singapore also has a sovereign fund, but its operation method is completely market-oriented. Except for the identity of the investor, the other operating modes are the same as those of private enterprises. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some central enterprises are also very efficient. When it comes to improving efficiency, is the incentive mechanism for managers the same as that of other companies? We cannot simply say which is more efficient and which is better in terms of business ownership. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;It is basically impossible for the world to decouple&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now, a group of central state-owned enterprises may have to be delisted from the New York Stock Exchange. What do you think of the current situation? Is it possible to move toward “capital decoupling”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Even if delisting, decoupling from capital is still too far away. They are a very small minority of international capital participating in the development of the Chinese market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the amount of foreign capital invested in China from all over the world is so large, including major private enterprises and central state-owned enterprises listed in Hong Kong. In addition to the obvious decoupling in the technology field, there will be some decoupling in other aspects. But it’s not at all to the point where we’ll never see each other again until we die. We have become accustomed to mutual penetration and connection with a highly developed capital market. The connection is much weaker now than it was in its heyday. If we look at the present from 20 to 30 years ago, it is basically impossible to decouple the connection in today’s world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole world is like a plane. How can the two largest engines of the world economy be decoupled? After 20 years of extremely deep and close cooperation, there is currently some pullback. Even after the withdrawal, the economic ties between the two countries are far from being described as decoupling. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Two core considerations for the reform of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Historical value and practical significance to the mainland&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the 10 years since you have been in charge of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, you have led a number of far-reaching reforms. . Which reforms are you more satisfied with? Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I usually don’t think about things this way. In the tide of history, a person happens to be very lucky to be in a very important and suitable position, and then he does something under the right time, place and people. These cannot be said to be the things of one person. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which reforms have had the greatest impact during my tenure at the Hong Kong Stock Exchange? Does the mainland have more historical value and practical significance? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiaojia Li:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;These are the two most important core considerations for all reforms of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The big theme is that Hong Kong, as an international market for a long time, should help the mainland capital market internationalize and help the international market become more integrated into the mainland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, everything must be solved systematically. After all, these two markets are two completely different systems. They have great motivation to integrate and interconnect with each other, and they also have very powerful internal mechanisms and forces. This makes interconnection very difficult. In other words, the two markets each have their own management systems, market systems, and operating methods. They are willing to integrate, but they are unwilling to significantly change their own institutions and systems for the sake of integration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to take advantage of Hong Kong’s extremely unique position? We fully understand which aspects of the markets on both sides can be changed for the sake of interconnection, which aspects are impossible to change, and which aspects are necessary. Find a greatest common divisor and least common multiple, and find the maximum interconnection at the minimum cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In all reforms, we have to consider many issues. Perhaps some form of interconnection would be most effective and best, but it may be too costly. No one is willing to bear it; some things may be easy to reform, but they don&#39;t mean much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, we started to want to choose very small things, such as the trading time periods of the two exchanges are different, and the opening and closing are different. It may seem like a small thing, but reform is not easy. It involves different living and working habits in the two places. It seems that this reform should not be controversial, but it was actually one of the most difficult reforms at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back, the following reforms have great historical value and practical significance for the Hong Kong Exchange. First of all, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange cannot just be in the mainland market of Hong Kong. The Hong Kong Stock Exchange is not only in Asia, it should break through to Europe and the United States, because the mainland hopes to go international through the Hong Kong market; it cannot be just in the stock market, but also to the bulk commodity market that the mainland needs most. breakthrough. Therefore, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange merged and acquired the London Metal Exchange, and also tried to acquire the London Exchange, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the Hong Kong Stock Exchange stock market itself. Chinese technology companies have been unable to go public because of regulatory rules. They represent advanced productivity, but they can only be launched in the United States. It’s not that the previous regulatory logic was wrong, but when the whole world is competing, why do we cling to the original things without changing them? The regulatory logic of the United States is originally consistent with that of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, but it can find very practical reasons and allow changes. We will finally carry out reforms, and Xiaomi, JD.com, Alibaba, etc. can all return to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market value of A-shares ranks second in the world. How can such a huge market be interconnected with the Hong Kong market and the international market without changing the respective rules and systems of both parties? Therefore, a series of reforms and innovations such as Shanghai-Hong Kong Stock Connect, Shenzhen-Hong Kong Stock Connect, Bond Connect, and Bond Swap Connect have been launched one after another. The two markets have achieved basic interconnection functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internationalization, embracing the new economy, and realizing interconnection are still the cornerstones of the success of the Hong Kong market to this day, and are also the reform and innovation of China&#39;s capital market to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you still have any regrets about your work at the Hong Kong Stock Exchange? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiaojia Li: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Now the Internet is a secondary market, that is, Shanghai-Hong Kong Stock Connect and Shenzhen-Hong Kong Stock Connect can be traded southward or northbound. Stocks on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange or the Shanghai Stock Exchange. However, the interconnection has not extended to the primary market to the &quot;New Stock Connect&quot;. This is my regret. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I used to use &quot;New Stock Connect&quot; as the name of this product. The new Northbound Trading Connect allows the Chinese market to finally connect with world resources. Achieving interconnection in Hong Kong can achieve tremendous development. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Let international&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;capital&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;And China&#39;s small and micro&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;enterprises fully&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;China Unicom&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span >;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Farewell to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange , you started your business with one of the world&#39;s latest investment models and trading models - Drip Tong ASX will be officially operated in August 2023. Drip Tong ASX aims to solve a global problem - financing difficulties for small and micro enterprises. Why can Drip Connect ASX solve this problem? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiaojia Li:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Driptong ASX is the world’s first licensed revenue sharing product (DRO) exchange. The vision and mission of Diguantong is to fully connect international capital with China&#39;s small and micro economy, and to achieve interconnection and interoperability between the two very incompatible operating systems of international traditional finance and China&#39;s small and micro economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foundation and prerequisite for this breakthrough is the comprehensive spread of China’s digital revolution. A cashless society provides the possibility for a new and revolutionary form of financing. With this revolutionary premise and the addition of our own Drip Tong ASX, we have accomplished this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we don&#39;t do it, or if we don&#39;t do it well, someone else will soon do it. Just like when there was no Internet, Jack Ma jumped into the sky and couldn&#39;t do anything. After the advent of the Internet, he started Taobao, but soon there were also JD.com, Meituan, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s not that we brought a panacea and solved everyone’s problems all at once. It can only be said that we are the first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you become the first? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Most people engaged in finance look down on small and micro businesses and think it is impossible; those engaged in the Internet or digitalization Most people do not understand the nature of finance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can it be done? We know that capital markets around the world mainly solve two problems. One is that investment information is accurate and authentic, and the other is that the safety of investment money and goods entering and exiting is guaranteed. Specifically, investors around the world will only invest in stocks or bonds, and only stocks and bonds of large companies, because the above two core issues that investors care about are the prerequisites for investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to solve these two problems, traditional exchanges rely on a large number of professionals to make research reports, annual reports, etc.; settlement security relies on the endorsement of a series of institutions such as banks, securities firms, and exchanges to ensure the entry and exit of funds. Safety and security. But both events are extremely expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, small and micro enterprises will not raise funds through listing and bond issuance. But in the current era of China&#39;s digital revolution, these two core problems can be solved at low cost. The income of a small store is fully reflected in the payment system, that is, the accuracy of the information. Let’s make a fuss about income. Can I invest in you and buy your income? Is it okay to take a share of the income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the issue of investment in and out security, we deduct money directly in the payment system and directly in the bank&#39;s separate ledger system. The issue of delivery security is solved. We can solve the two core functions of the Wall Street financial system through small chips. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To solve this problem is not to do charity, but to actually get the rewards back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Someone has recently questioned this business model. At about the same time, ASX received certification from the Sharia Regulatory Commission. Liu Xingjuan, a member of the Executive Committee of the Monetary Authority of Macau, also said that the ASX will be monitored on a daily basis in accordance with the &quot;risk-based&quot; regulatory principle. What does the legal regulation of this innovative model look like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Xiaojia:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The investment chain is very clear: Drip Irrigation Tong raises funds through overseas institutions and jointly operates and opens stores in the mainland through foreign direct investment. The supervision currently involved includes relevant laws of four countries and regions: Mainland China has relevant laws and regulations as a civil legal relationship, supervision of the Securities Regulatory Commission of Hong Kong, China, relevant provisions of the Financial Supervision Regulations of Macau, China, and international investors who subscribe for products , regulated by UK law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师被扣手机己归还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:42:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxRVLml.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxR VLml. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After Chi Susheng fell unconscious in the court, the court called an ambulance. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The cause of the headache remains to be investigated.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, after Chi Susheng received the hospital’s certificate of condition, he still needed to continue hospitalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Susheng, 67, is a lawyer at Heilongjiang Susheng Law Firm and was re-elected as a representative of the Ninth to Eleventh National People&#39;s Congress. On November 6, a gang-related case she represented was heard publicly in the Xuanwei City People&#39;s Court of Yunnan. Before the trial, Chi Susheng was considered to have violated court discipline because he took two photos in the court, and his mobile phone was detained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 6 p.m. that day, the presiding judge adjourned the trial. Chi Susheng asked for the return of his mobile phone and fell unconscious in the court after communicating with court staff to no avail. An hour later, she was sent to the emergency department of Xuanwei First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 4 p.m. on November 7, Chi Susheng told Southern Weekend reporters that Chen Yongfu, president of the Xuanwei Court, visited her in the hospital at around 1 p.m. that day and returned her phone at around 3 p.m. cell phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two photos&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At around 8:40 am on November 6, 2023, 20 minutes before the trial started, Chi Susheng arrived at the court. She recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that there was only one clerk at the scene, and the members of the collegial panel, prosecutors and other lawyers had not yet arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the twenty-first day of the first trial of a gang-related case. Previously, the case had gone through the first and second trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 10, 2021, the Xuanwei Court made a first-instance judgment and determined that Liu Shunping and the 10 people involved in the case did not constitute a crime of a mafia nature, but there were cases where Liu Shunping was the ringleader and members of the organization often gathered together to jointly commit crimes. Carrying out acts of provocation, extortion, and illegal detention, it was identified as an evil criminal group. Liu Shunping was punished concurrently for all the crimes committed by the group, and the remaining personnel were punished according to the criminal acts they participated in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the first-instance verdict, Liu Shunping and others were dissatisfied and appealed. The prosecutor&#39;s office did not protest. On December 9, 2022, the second instance of Qujing Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the original verdict on the grounds that “some facts were unclear” and remanded the case for retrial. During the retrial of the case, the Xuanwei City Procuratorate added three additional charges and still accused Liu Shunping and others of being involved in underworld crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the court, Chi Susheng noticed 10 black iron interrogation chairs placed side by side on the defendant&#39;s seat, with devices for fixing hands and feet. Before this day, during the trial of this case, the defendant had been sitting on a conventional wooden chair with a backrest, and his hands and feet could move freely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her experience, this situation is not common. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Court Rules of the People&#39;s Court of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Court Rules&quot;), unless the defendant is considered to be in great personal danger and may endanger the safety of the court, the court shall not treat the defendant during court hearings. Use a ring. Chi Susheng subconsciously raised his phone and took two photos of the interrogation chair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, she walked out of the court and stored her mobile phone in a metal cabinet outside the court in preparation for the hearing. At this time, other lawyers representing the case entered the scene one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Susheng and two other lawyers representing the case said that from the first day of the case, the court verbally asked them not to bring mobile phones into the court. Some lawyers once objected to this, arguing that the court rules only stipulated that no making or receiving phone calls were allowed, and did not prohibit the carrying of mobile phones. The court did not respond to this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4 communications&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chi Susheng did not expect that her mobile phone would be impounded by the court because of the photos taken before the trial. Throughout the process, she communicated with court staff four times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the trial, Chi Susheng was called outside the court by the bailiff shortly after he put his mobile phone in the metal cabinet. She recalls a court employee asking her to delete the photo. She declined the request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Court rules stipulate that all personnel are not allowed to record, videotape, take photos of, or use mobile communication tools to disseminate court proceedings during court proceedings. Anyone who violates this provision may be temporarily detained by the court. Equipment and storage media, delete content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Susheng believed that the trial had not started when he took the photo, so he did not violate court discipline. She later returned to court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 10:20 a.m., the trial took a 20-minute intermission. Chi Susheng was asked to stay in the court, and the other lawyers were not allowed to enter the court. She remembered that the presiding judge asked to temporarily seize her mobile phone, and the clerk took notes at the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third communication occurred during the court session. During the afternoon hearing, it was Chi Susheng&#39;s turn to speak, and she continued to apply for the return of her mobile phone. She emphasized that she took the photos before the court was announced and the seizure of her mobile phone was unreasonable. She also said that if the court wanted to seize her mobile phone, it would need to provide written materials. The presiding judge said that if there are any violations of laws and regulations in the collegial panel, Chi Susheng can report the situation to the superiors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 6:15 p.m., the court adjourned. When Chi Susheng went to the metal cabinet outside the court to pick up his mobile phone, he found that the mobile phone was no longer in the cabinet. At this point she has not used her phone for a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last week, Chi Susheng received a notice that the trial of the gang-related case, which was originally scheduled to end on November 8, would be extended for one month. She was anxious to coordinate the court session with other courts. &quot;I was very anxious and shouted to the presiding judge, &#39;Give me your phone back.&#39; The presiding judge said, &#39;If you lose it, call the police.&#39;&quot; Both lawyers present said to the south Reporters over the weekend confirmed hearing the conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chi Susheng returned to the court, hoping to find someone to negotiate the matter again. Later, she felt &quot;all over and couldn&#39;t stand&quot; and lay down on the chair at the lawyer&#39;s table. At 7:30 that night, Chi Susheng was sent to the emergency department of Xuanwei First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, the criminal case involving Liu Shunping and others continued to be heard. Chi Susheng failed to appear in court. She was discharged from the hospital that afternoon and planned to rest for a while to check her physical condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小金眼中的大金丨人来人往]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260080]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDTusi9UKvZB3J0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDT usi9UKvZB3J0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jin Shenghua and Jin Yaoji at the translation seminar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin Yiuji, former president of the Chinese University of Hong Kong, has reached his ninth year and has been retired for nearly two decades. Ten years later, I am still strong and full of energy. While admiring me, I think of the past. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in 2004, between the administration building and the library of the Chinese University, everyone on campus unanimously called On the steps of the Central Steps, I met a colleague who was about to retire. She has served the school for many years. Starting from Li Zhuomin, the founding president of CUHK, she has worked with five presidents. She can be said to be a veteran of the past dynasties. Chatting with her, she mentioned her retirement and that Principal Jin Yaoji was leaving soon. She felt deeply sad to leave. She suddenly said: &quot;Principal Jin is such a nice person, I&#39;m not afraid of him!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not afraid of him? Who would be afraid of Principal Kim? However, if you think about it further, why are subordinates not afraid of their supervisors? According to common sense, isn&#39;t it common for subordinates to be afraid of their supervisors? This made me have an image of this &quot;member&quot; in my mind - affable, smiling, humorous, witty, and talented; treating everyone equally, from the school director to the co-workers; when running the school, Accept advice and learn from it, follow the good as a rule; smoke a pipe when you are free, and enjoy yourself. Such a gentle and kind-hearted supervisor will of course make people &quot;respect and love him&quot; rather than &quot;keep him at arm&#39;s length&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have known Professor Jin Yaoji for decades. At the beginning, there were not many teachers named Jin in the school. Since both of us were affiliated with New Asia, our colleagues mostly used &quot;Da Jin&quot; and &quot;Xiao Jin&quot; to distinguish each other, and we also called each other &quot;the family&quot;, adding Professor Jin&#39;s There is only one character difference between his name and my eldest brother&#39;s name, so I naturally regard him as an elder brother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met Professor Jin, it was still in the 1970s. I still remember that back then, this &quot;member of the family&quot; had just returned to Hong Kong from the United States. He was very handsome, young and promising. Not long after, he held important positions many times, and was later elected as the president of New Asia. At that time, Jin Yaoji was only in his early forties, and he was not from New Asia. These two factors may have caused him to encounter some obstacles when he first took charge of important tasks. However, with his outstanding intelligence and amazing courage, all difficulties were in his hands. , can all be easily solved. Since then, Professor Jin has been at CUHK for decades, and as he has moved up the ladder, he has more and more affairs and heavier responsibilities, but has anyone seen him looking sad and overwhelmed? In everyone&#39;s mind, Jin Gong always talks, laughs, and fights, and does everything lightly. Because of this, whenever the school has &quot;difficult and complicated diseases&quot;, they will naturally entrust them to him, hoping that he can &quot;prescribe the right medicine&quot; and rejuvenate them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2003, the CUHK Faculty and Staff Association held a Christmas dance, and Principal Jin was also invited. At the party, the host asked me to say a few words to pay tribute to him. I said: &quot;There are two kinds of leaders in the world: the first type, others respect and fear him; the second type, people respect and love him. Professor Jin certainly belongs to the second category.&quot; These words were recognized by everyone. That night, Principal Jin, who is usually not good at dancing, actually danced very happily surrounded by everyone. He is such a considerate and easy-going person. Over the years, whenever colleagues ask for advice, no matter how busy he is, he will put everything aside and listen attentively. This makes people feel that in Professor Jin&#39;s mind, you are the most important person and your affairs are the most important things. He is listening, he is thinking, he is sharing your burdens and resolving your worries. He is busy with everything, so he will stop time, accompany you, and protect you. No matter how bumpy the road ahead is, he will help you and solve your problems. How can such a supervisor not make people convinced? When colleagues work hard and serve the school wholeheartedly, he not only hears and sees them, but also expresses his gratitude through actions. On the eve of the degree awarding ceremony every year, colleagues in the public relations team are often extremely busy and stay up all night. One time, near midnight, Principal Jin actually visited the class in person and brought chocolates to express his condolences! Such a sincere leader can make the whole school work together as one, regardless of each other, to strive for a common goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin is most praised for his outstanding eloquence and excellent articles. He is a person who speaks well and writes well. On important occasions such as international conferences, commemorative celebrations, opening ceremonies, etc., as long as Jin Gong is present and he opens the mouth of Jin, both the guest and the host will be happy and everyone will be moved. Jin Yaoji&#39;s eloquence is not just about his brilliant tongue and spitting jade. What is unmatched is his humor, his wit, his ability to talk and laugh freely, as if everything in the world is ready at any time. As long as he waved and nodded, he would arrange the formation and send the generals out in formation. I remember one time, Professor Jin was going to the city to host a banquet. In the car, he asked me a few questions casually and got a brief grasp of the information about the guests. As a result, he used it vividly in his speech at the banquet. After my country&#39;s first astronaut Yang Liwei successfully launched into space, Principal Jin quoted the words &quot;feeling good&quot; on different occasions, but he used it just right every time and the effect was amazing. Another time, the Department of Translation held an international seminar and invited Jin Gong to preside over the opening ceremony. He asked me to draft the lecture notes in advance. On the opening day, Jin Gong came as scheduled and spoke according to the script. Halfway through the reading, he suddenly said: &quot;I did not write this elegant speech, it was drafted by Jin Shenghua.&quot; He was humorous, calm and comfortable, It can be seen. The most recent one was a speech at the launch of my new book (&quot;Heart-to-Heart-Eighteen Years with Brigitte Lin&quot;) on September 24, 2022. On that day, Shanheng College of Chinese University held a dialogue between Qingxia and I. During the meeting, Jin Gong was specially invited to make comments after the conversation. As soon as he came on stage, he asked the audience seriously if they could take off their masks. At that time, Hong Kong was still implementing epidemic prevention measures. Of course, it was not possible. So, he went on to say: &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if I don&#39;t take off the mask. Brigitte Lin wears a mask. Everyone will suffer a lot.&quot; .&quot; As soon as this statement came out, it immediately caused a roar of laughter and heated up the atmosphere of the entire venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also remember that at the dinner of the Second Global Chinese Youth Literature Award in 2003, President Jin once said that the stars were shining that night, and stars of both big and small literary genres descended on CUHK. , Bai Xianyong, Yu Guangzhong, Lin Wenyue and other famous artists, as well as many minor literary stars such as the young students who won awards in each group. In fact, President Jin himself is an out-and-out literary star. On the one hand, he writes books and lectures in the field of sociology to teach future generations; on the other hand, he writes narratives and expresses his feelings in the field of literature. During his visit to the University of Cambridge in 1975, Professor Jin was impressed by the aura and beauty of Cambridge. In addition to writing major works, he also began to write short prose pieces. During his one year at JNU, through rain, fog, snow, spring, summer, autumn and winter, Professor Jin’s inspirational words came out and he completed the book &quot;Cambridge Silk&quot;. Ten years later, when he was a visiting professor at the University of Heidelberg, he put his thoughts and feelings into writing and wrote the book &quot;Heidelberg Silk&quot;. The two volumes complemented each other and became a praised &quot;gold-style prose&quot;. In 2007, after Jin Gong retired, he made another trip to his hometown. One of them was a pilgrimage to Dunhuang, the desert art capital. After returning, he published the book &quot;Dunhuang Silk&quot;, which echoed and connected the previous two volumes of &quot;Yu Silk&quot;. It is the work of the three famous &quot;Yusu&quot; sisters. Looking at Professor Jin&#39;s life, he could not only use a huge pen like a rafter, but also use the dignity of a mountain to write large articles about governing the country and criticizing the current ills, which are very resonant to read. , the true feelings of the world come from the heart, and it is deeply touching to read. No matter whether it is a masterpiece or a short piece, there is emotion in the theory, and reason in the emotion. The two blend together without leaving any trace. The author looks down at the heaven and the earth, travels between China and the West, traces the past, discusses the present, and explores the secrets. He can not only analyze and find out the clues in the vast sea of ​​knowledge, but also find new ways and write strange works in the literary world where hundreds of flowers are blooming. . The reason is actually closely related to his personal qualities, endowments, temperament and character. In addition to his professional field, Professor Jin has a profound understanding of literature, history, philosophy, and education. In addition, he is a reasonable person in life. As the saying goes, &quot;Knowledge of worldly affairs is knowledge, and understanding of human feelings is writing.&quot; Therefore, he can not only talk about poetry and art At that time, he was outstanding, and he was also good at twisting and turning in the intricate tangle of personnel and affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Kim Yao-kee has served at CUHK for a total of thirty-four years. During his two years as president, he has experienced many difficult and difficult moments under extraordinary circumstances, including the outbreak of SARS and the government-controlled Fortunately, Principal Jin worked hard and dealt with the accidents such as salary cuts due to capital cuts, and finally overcame the difficulties one by one. During his tenure, President Jin completed many tasks, not only established the School of Law, raised huge donations for the university, and introduced new mechanisms to improve the university&#39;s governance structure. When President Jin took office, he once humorously claimed: &quot;I have a long way to go!&quot; Indeed, two years is not a long time, but President Jin&#39;s achievements in running the school are obvious to all and are highly praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of June 2004, on the eve of President Jin Yaoji’s retirement, CUHK held a farewell banquet. That night, the house was full of guests and the event was unprecedented. All the guests who were supposed to come came, and unexpected friends also came, including colleagues from all walks of life and departments in the school who usually do not like to have banquets. The dinner was held very successfully. There were no lengthy speeches or sensational scenes. Everything was simple and natural, just like Principal Jin&#39;s traditional style. The president said in his speech: &quot;I am the youngest dean and the oldest president in the history of CUHK. People ask me what I can do after retirement? I think, Ronald Reagan 71 I only became president at the age of 18, so I&#39;m probably qualified enough to be elected president!&quot; The fun and humor are still the same, this is Principal Kim&#39;s true character! In the middle of the dinner, there suddenly appeared a scene where everyone came forward to invite Principal Jin to take a group photo: one table after another, in good order, came forward spontaneously, with a look of reluctance in their eyes. This is A sight never seen before. From school directors to secretaries, from professors to clerks, it is hard to tell them apart. Regardless of high or low, at this moment, everyone only has in their minds the outgoing Principal Jin, the gentle, elegant and generous Principal Jin! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last program of the dinner was a choir formed temporarily by CUHK alumni to sing the song &quot;Blessings&quot; for President Jin. This famous song originally sung by Ye Qianwen, with lyrics adapted by the talented Professor He Wenhui, sings the voice of everyone: &quot;Ling Yun is talented, everyone sees it, and the principal Jin Gongyi banishes him to an immortal. He is funny, handsome, and very friendly to others. He has a large belly and can punt a boat.&quot; . People who practice benevolence can contribute, and their sincerity feels far away. Sincere and fraternal love nurtures talents without getting tired, and thousands of spring breezes blow gently and warmly. Ah! The spring breeze blows in my face again. I wave my hands gently, and the sadness of parting is still deep. Listen to me Tell me carefully, I will be happy in the future. I will have my beloved wife by my side, a pipe, and thousands of smoke rings...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Principal Jin retired, compared to the busy years in the past, his life was lighter. The wind is light, but still full and more elegant than before. In addition to his continuous writings, Jin Gong was also diligent in writing calligraphy. Jin Yaoji has worked hard to practice calligraphy under the supervision of his father since he was a child, but he never expressed his hardships. According to his self-statement, &quot;My exploration and pursuit of the art of calligraphy and calligraphy began after I retired from the Chinese University and was seventy years old.&quot; Therefore, Jin Gong, who was graceful and comfortable in his seventies, not only followed his heart&#39;s desires, but also enjoyed peace of mind. The joy of playing with grandchildren also continued the relationship between calligraphy and calligraphy that started in childhood, and carried it forward, becoming a &quot;golden calligraphy&quot; that has been praised for a while and is popular among the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Lin Qingxia kept hearing about Jin Gong’s name and various anecdotes from me, and she read his masterpieces and admired his calligraphy from Ming Pao Monthly. One day, this talented woman who was thirsty for talents, He offered to meet with Principal Jin and ask him for tips on writing and calligraphy. On September 24, 2021, I hosted a banquet at the Shanghai General Assembly. As a result, the leaders in academic circles and the entertainment industry finally got to know each other in a state of mutual appreciation. That night, although the two met for the first time, they felt like old friends at first sight. During the dinner, Qingxia talked about how not long after she started learning Peking Opera, friends asked her to sing a cappella song. The words were not finished yet, but she had already spoken cheerfully and boldly. He stood up and sang &quot;Su San Qi Jie&quot; (Hua Dan) and &quot;San Jia Dian&quot; (Lao Sheng) without any shyness. When Jin Gong heard this, he cheered and shouted &quot;You are so bold&quot; in a loud voice! When the whole audience heard this, they couldn&#39;t help but burst out laughing and applauded with great joy! After that, friends often used the term &quot;bold&quot; to describe Lin Qingxia, the &quot;desperate Sanniang&quot; who is now able to do everything with ease and go all out. Qingxia herself also thought that Jin Gong&#39;s gift was remarkable, even to Jin Gong&#39;s words. When I proposed to give a calligraphy treasure as a gift, I specifically asked him to mention these words and hang them high in the living room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after, Principal Jin presented Qingxia with a long calligraphy painting entitled &quot;The Wine Will Be Entering&quot;. This calligraphy was written with great joy, unrestrained and smart, and perfectly set off the famous work of the poet Li Bai. Qingxia asked the art master Zhang Shuping to help her frame it and hang it on the wall for viewing every day. Who knew that in July 2022, a &quot;fire&quot; incident occurred in the big house. Qingxia was far away overseas. At that time, what she was thinking about was not jewelry, clothes and other external objects, but Are you worried about whether the &quot;Will Enter the Wine&quot; hanging on the wall will be safe under the raging fire and billowing smoke? It&#39;s strange to say that&amp;nbsp;The third-level fire burned down famous paintings and furniture, but it stopped abruptly before &quot;The Wine Will Be Entered&quot;. It was separated by a wall,&amp;nbsp;but it didn&#39;t burn into Qingxia&#39;s room behind the wall. Paintings and clothes. Afterwards, Jin Yaoji sighed: &quot;I knew that Brigitte Lin was invulnerable to water and fire, Brigitte Lin is Brigitte Lin!&quot; Brigitte Lin believed that Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy treasure was a treasure of the house and had magical powers to prevent fire and disaster. Seeing the two of them admiring and boasting about each other, I couldn&#39;t help but feel how elegant and interesting the sympathetic friendship between them was! Nowadays, &quot;About to Enter the Wine&quot; has been moved to Qingxia&#39;s mid-level study. Whenever a scholar comes to visit, the hostess will definitely invite them to take a photo in front of Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy as a souvenir. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brigitte Lin and Kim Yao-kee took a group photo in front of &quot;The Wine Will Come&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new crown is raging, and the epidemic has been severe in the past three years, but Principal Jin is calm and calm, and his wife Yuan Zhen is even more angry After calming down, he said: &quot;Life and death are destiny, there is no point in being afraid!&quot; Principal Jin continued to pursue the aesthetics of life, saying: &quot;Food and wine are never deliberately avoided. In a dangerous epidemic, if you have good friends and confidants, you can share them with others.&quot; Drunk, a toast, it&#39;s life!&quot; With such a broad mind and such a state of mind, he is no less generous than the free and easy Dongpo layman! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Yaoji, as his name suggests, is like a golden glow in the eyes of his friends, shining warmly on everything around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[业委会成员向开发商索要好处费：监督业委会还需业主亲力亲为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260056]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two members of the owners’ committee of a residential area in Guang’an, Sichuan, demanded 130,000 yuan in benefits from the developer, suspected of illegal The crime of accepting bribes by a state employee was investigated by the public security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that Chen Moubing was elected as the director of the first owners committee of a community in Guang&#39;an with high votes, and Chen was appointed as the security coordination committee member and greening and sanitation committee member. At the end of May 2020, the government inspected the commercial buildings in the community and prepared to build a kindergarten. However, the developer of the community had set up some of the houses on the fourth floor as property offices and property committee offices. Chen Moubing found the developer of the community and asked for a benefit fee of 130,000 yuan, claiming that You can ask the property management committee, owners, etc. to agree to the office relocation. In June 2020, after the developer negotiated with Chen Moubing about the office relocation, he paid 80,000 yuan to Chen Moubing and 50,000 yuan to Chen Moubing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actions of Chen Bing and Chen have violated the provisions of Article 163 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China and are suspected of accepting bribes by non-state personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For 130,000 &quot;benefits&quot;, Chen Bing and Chen were able to turn a commercial building in the community into a kindergarten. This shows that as members of the property committee, they have considerable &quot;power&quot;. Several key points remain to be clarified in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, Article 30 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot; promulgated by Sichuan Province stipulates that the owners&#39; committee shall regularly announce the following information and information to the owners in the property management area: the use and operation of the common parts of the property Income and expenditure status. Has the owners&#39; committee announced relevant information to the owners&#39; meeting as soon as possible regarding the relocation of neighborhood committees and owners&#39; offices and the conversion of original houses into kindergartens? Have the owners reviewed this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if Chen Bing and Chen deliberately delayed or even concealed the report, it would be difficult to guarantee the community owners’ right to know about this important matter. This involves the second issue. According to the &quot;Guiding Rules for Owners&#39; Meetings and Owners Committees&quot; promulgated by the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the owners&#39; committee is elected by the owners&#39; meeting and consists of an odd number of 5 to 11 people. Why did the other members of the property committee, who accounted for the majority, not raise any objection to this decision and let Chen Moubing and Chen make the decision? This also reflects the inaction of other owners committee members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This points to a deeper question: Who will supervise the owners&#39; committee? The owners&#39; committee is the embodiment of community autonomy. Within the property management area, all owners form an owners&#39; meeting and elect the owners&#39; committee as the executive body of the owners&#39; meeting. However, the establishment process of the owners&#39; committees has been interfered with or even manipulated, and after the establishment of the owners&#39; committees, it has been reduced to a private area for a few members to seek personal gain. Such incidents have occurred frequently, making the independence and impartiality of some owners&#39; committees almost impossible. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as employment committee elections are concerned, some developers or property companies, in order to protect their own interests, interfere, block or even manipulate the elections of owners&#39; committees. The community where I live held a general election for the property owners committee this year. Unfortunately, the surrounding shop owners, who accounted for nearly 10% of the total property area of ​​the community, did not cast a single vote despite being notified and invited multiple times. This resulted in this The first general election failed to meet the requirement that &quot;owners accounting for more than two-thirds of the exclusive area participate in the vote&quot;, and the new property committee was therefore difficult to produce. Some owners who participated in the preparations for the new property committee reported that the property management company promised to reduce the rent to the shop owners in exchange for the other party not participating in the voting. The purpose was to hinder the election of the property committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if a homeowners committee is finally established through numerous obstacles, community owners will face more challenges. Since the owners&#39; committee exercises part of the power of the owners&#39; meeting, once it lacks professional ethics and sense of responsibility and only focuses on its own interests, regardless of the rights and interests of other owners, it will inevitably use public tools for private use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the ways in which owners&#39; committee members guard against self-stealing, there are roughly three types. First, turn public maintenance funds into your own “money bag”. According to a report by Beijing Evening News in 2018, owners of Zhujiang Junjing Community in Beijing reported that more than 4,000 yuan was spent on their public maintenance fund accounts as early as 2013 without any knowledge. Some owners also discovered that their public maintenance funds had been misappropriated. to the owners committee account. The owners&#39; committee said that this move was for everyone&#39;s benefit and investment, and it was not made public because it was afraid that someone would come to &quot;pick trouble.&quot; But this argument is unconvincing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second method is to &quot;expand financial resources&quot;, fully developing and commercializing various public facilities in the community, so that the profits that should be shared by all owners can be divided between the members of the property committee and the property management. &quot;Chongqing Evening News&quot; reported in 2010 that the property management company of Dibochundun Community in Shipingqiao, Jiulongpo District signed a contract with the property owners committee, and the public revenue was divided &quot;30-70&quot; (30% for the property owners committee and 70% for the property management party), but many The owner was unaware. In addition, the director of the owners&#39; committee also receives a monthly remuneration of 3,000 yuan from the property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third method is to reach out to the property company for replacement. Members of the owners&#39; committee use the excuse of changing the property to make the existing property company pay &quot;protection fees&quot; to them, or to replace it with a new property company that has an interest in them, thereby making a profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at many cases, we can conclude that the moral self-discipline of owners’ committee members is unreliable and third-party supervision is indispensable. According to Article 39 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot;, if the decisions made by the owners&#39; meeting or the owners&#39; committee violate laws and regulations, the sub-district office (township people&#39;s government) or county (city, district) people&#39;s government where the property is located shall Within thirty days from the date of receipt of the complaint or discovery, the urban and rural development department shall make a decision in accordance with the law and notify all owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, as the owners of the community, the majority of owners must also realize that autonomy is not only a right, but also a manifestation of responsibility and ability. Owners should spend more time and energy to actively participate in community governance and strengthen the supervision and management of owners&#39; committees through election of owners&#39; committees, participation in owners&#39; meetings, and formulation of management regulations. At the same time, for major community matters announced by the property owners committee, such as public benefits, etc., professional auditing agencies can also be hired to audit, so as to effectively protect their own rights and interests and improve the quality of the community with stronger public awareness and legal concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>