<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[蒙冤入狱29年获787万多元国家赔偿：“追责必须落到责任主体”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257505]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Tan Xiuyi, who was wrongfully raped and murdered and imprisoned for 29 years, recently received more than 7.87 million yuan in state compensation. Examining this case, which was selected for inclusion in the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate&#39;s work report to the National People&#39;s Congress, may help prevent unjust, false and wrong cases from recurring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Red Star News, what led to Tan Xiuyi’s injustice was a massacre that occurred in the summer of 1993: On the evening of July 16, 1993, Tan Hong, a villager in Qiantan Village, Tanzhuang Town, Shangshui County, Zhoukou, Henan Province ( A family of three (pseudonym) and his parents were murdered, and Tan Xiuyi, a 39-year-old fellow villager at the time, was identified as a suspect. At the end of 1999, the Zhoukou Intermediate Court made a first-instance verdict on the case and sentenced Tan Xiuyi to a suspended death sentence for intentional homicide. The first-instance verdict shows that the court found that: at about 22:00 on the evening of July 16, 1993, when Tan Xiuyi went home to relieve himself in the toilet, he saw Tan Hong, who was staying at his home that night, and became malicious and raped her. Fearing that the matter would be exposed, Tan Xiuyi had the idea of ​​killing Tan Hong&#39;s parents. At 1 a.m. on July 17, Tan Xiuyi sneaked into Tan Hong&#39;s home with the tools of the crime and killed his parents. Later, Tan Xiuyi was afraid that Tan Hong would doubt him after learning that his parents had been killed, so he killed Tan Hong after she got up and returned home, and hung her body from the beam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Tan Xiuyi appealed, in May 2000, the Henan High Court ruled to revoke the original verdict and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the facts were unclear. In January 2002, the Zhoukou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a retrial judgment. In addition to intentional homicide, Tan Xiuyi was also found guilty of rape, and his sentence was maintained with a suspended death sentence. Tan Xiuyi appealed again, but this time the Henan High Court rejected the appeal in 2003 and upheld the original verdict. Ten years later, this tragedy seems to have become an &quot;iron case&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Tan Xiuyi did not give up. He kept appealing and had his experience rejected: In December 2017, the Henan Provincial High Court ruled that &quot;the facts found in the original judgment were clear, the evidence was indeed sufficient, and the conviction and sentencing were not inappropriate.&quot; dismissed the complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until 2018, after the Henan Provincial Procuratorate filed the case for review, it believed that the facts determined in the original trial were unclear, the evidence was unreliable and insufficient, and the judgment was wrong. On June 18, 2020, it filed a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate lodged a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Court on March 16, 2022. Four months later, the Supreme People&#39;s Court made a retrial decision and ordered the Henan High Court to retrial. This time, the Henan High Court changed the verdict of Tan Xiuyi to not guilty. At this time, Tan Xiuyi had been &quot;released&quot; two months ago and had been imprisoned for more than 29 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trial process of this case is full of doubts. The case occurred in 1993, but the first-instance verdict was issued more than six years later, and the second-instance verdict was found to be &quot;unclear.&quot; It can be inferred that the investigation process of the case was not smooth and the evidence based on which the case was decided was not sufficient. In this regard, the criminal protest letter of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also stated: In this case, except for Tan Xiuyi&#39;s partial guilty confession, which is consistent with the investigation transcripts and autopsy reports, there is no objective evidence to prove that Tan Xiuyi committed the crime; for the crime of rape, the time of Tan Xiuyi&#39;s rape cannot be determined, and the rape behavior It is also impossible to prove; regarding the crime of intentional homicide, some of the crime tools are unclear and the conclusions of criminal technical appraisal are not unique. In addition, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also found that Tan Xiuyi&#39;s several guilty confessions were inconsistent and contradicted other evidence. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate believes that the case also contains problems such as guilty confessions and interrogation transcripts that violate legal provisions and whose authenticity is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the evidence in the case basically only consists of Tan Xiuyi’s confession, and there is no objective evidence. Even the authenticity of the confession is doubtful, and the confession may have been illegally coerced. During the second trial, the Henan High Court determined that the facts of the case were unclear and remanded the case for retrial. It can be seen that the second instance also believed that there were problems with the evidence. However, it took just over a year for the retrial to reach another verdict, which not only upheld the crime of intentional homicide, but also added the crime of rape (this is also a doubtful point: since Tan Xiuyi was found to have raped Tan Hong in the first trial in 1999, why was he not punished? Convicted of rape?), and the retrial second instance also upheld the first instance judgment of the retrial. It took six years to obtain enough evidence, but why did it take just over a year to add new evidence that was sufficient to establish the crime? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not to mention that homicide cases require sufficient evidence to be determined, rape cases only rely on oral confessions, which is difficult to understand. Regardless of whether it was forced, at least it must be proven that there was sexual intercourse between the victim and the suspect. Although the victim was dead, the rape and murder were only a few hours apart. At that time, the police also mastered DNA comparison technology. Through forensic identification, it was completely possible to find out whether the victim had had sex with the suspect before his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the Henan Provincial High Court find that the facts were unclear in the initial second instance, but the second instance of the retrial, as well as the subsequent appeal, all believed that &quot;the facts were clearly found and the evidence was indeed sufficient&quot;? Are the judges who handle retrials, second trials and appeals under pressure from other parties? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case occurred in 1993, and many trials were held around 2000. Although the Internet was not very developed at that time, a major extermination case that killed a family of three still had a very large impact, and the public prosecutor and the law were bound to be under considerable pressure. What is particularly noteworthy is that Henan was one of the first provinces to propose &quot;murder cases must be solved&quot; at the beginning of this century. In 2004, it was recognized by the Ministry of Public Security as a national slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 National People’s Congress, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate stated in a report that in the past five years, 26 major criminal wrongful convictions, including the Wuzhou case and the Zhang Yuhuan case, had been corrected in accordance with the law; Protests or prosecutorial recommendations for retrials were made in 10 major unjust cases in which the original verdict lasted for more than ten years, and the court changed the verdict to not guilty in all cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these unjust, false and wrong cases, in addition to redressing the grievances and compensating the parties concerned, should the investigators at the time also bear responsibility? In 2013, the Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission issued guidance on effectively preventing unjust, false and wrongful convictions, requiring judges, prosecutors, and people&#39;s police to be lifelong responsible for the quality of case handling within the scope of their duties, and to establish and improve the accountability mechanism for unjust, false and wrongly convicted cases. In 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, Zhang Jun, once stated that at the beginning of 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate launched a comprehensive investigation into the cases of correction of wrongful convictions since 2018, and has listed and supervised 22 cases of wrongful convictions that were wrongly detained for more than 10 years, and all of them have proposed serious accountability. Opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate put forward, &quot;Correction cannot stop at state compensation, and accountability must fall on the responsible party.&quot; Correcting unjust, false and wrong cases cannot stop at overturned cases and compensation, so that there is a sense of justice in the investigation and trial process of the case. Only when responsible personnel take responsibility can judicial fairness and justice be demonstrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[换个角度看大学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Why does school start on September 1st? What does an Olympic champion’s academic profile look like? Do you still need to make a resume when looking for roommates in college? There is another group of &quot;special&quot; freshmen this year, have you seen them? Come, look at university from a different perspective today.</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个好演员的样子丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257370]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQwr4ZgUOK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/OugasTfNJ5ML9yNbtsKg8Ese6jTVvmFQ wr4ZgUOK. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250583&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256835 &quot; title=&quot;Ka-Tung Lam: We must capture the soul and heart of the character&quot;>;Ka-Tung Lam: We must capture the soul and heart of the character&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kat-Tung Lam is one of my favorite Hong Kong actors . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 8 pm in early September 2023, I was waiting for the interview in the hotel suite and sat on the floor with the film’s publicity staff. A large &quot;The Eighth Suspect&quot; roll-up banner divided the space into two, and a media conducted an interview, asking Lin Jiadong about the cooperation between &quot;The Eighth Suspect&quot; and the director and starring actors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because the appointment took the longest, my interview was scheduled as the last one of the day. I&#39;m worried that he will be tired after the intensive announcements during the promotion period, or his desire to express will weaken (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is very normal&lt;/span>;). but no. When the staff and I walked around the roll-up banners, Lin Jiadong turned to look out the floor-to-ceiling window, looking very interested. Outside is the night view of Beijing&#39;s Third Ring Road. There are office buildings with lights on in the darkness, which may be very similar to Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He likes to observe other people&#39;s lives. He said that he likes to sit in a tea restaurant and listen to people gossiping - he imitates how guests and waiters shout in a tea restaurant where people are crowded around tables. He said that if others looked at him, he would look back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lin Jiadong, I saw what a good actor looks like. He is not particularly handsome, but the environment in which he lives allows for diverse creations. There is no need to have the appearance of an idol, and there is no need to expose a lot of private life. As a profession, the life of an actor can really be very long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that there is no age anxiety in him. When he played a supporting role in &quot;Infernal Affairs&quot; 21 years ago, he was already in his thirties (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;he was born in 1967&lt;/span>;), Abandoned the stable path of starring in TVB. Later, he said that it was unbearable to film so many TV series in a year. He has played golden supporting roles in many movies, such as two &quot;Underworld&quot; and &quot;Exile&quot;, &quot;Ip Man&quot;, and &quot;Chill&quot;. He has built a solid foundation step by step. In past interviews, he has always said that he is a boring and boring person. Apart from acting, he rarely talks about his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It would be better to end this article with a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the appointed time, the interview was coming to an end. After asking the last question, I couldn’t help but ask how they rehearsed the positioning of the long shot in &quot;Hand-Rolled Cigarettes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a work in which Jack Lam starred for free and supported new Hong Kong directors. He plays Guan Chao, a former Chinese-American British soldier who is completely unsuitable for the new era. There is a nearly 10-minute long shot at the end of &quot;Hand-Rolled Cigarettes&quot;, which is extremely exciting. The camera looks far away on the rooftop. The gangster Guan Chao worked for before discovered that his betrayal was not just about money, but also hiding the person who stole the gangster&#39;s goods worth tens of millions. Extreme violence occurs in this long shot, where Guan Chao is beaten by a group of thugs. Everyone&#39;s fight was not good-looking, using brute force and deadly strikes. Guan Chao got into a scuffle with someone and was beaten badly. He stumbled from one room to another and was beaten violently by two people from the other party he had offended. He was already dying (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The camera recorded Guan Chao&#39;s death in real time&lt;/span>;), Guan Chao used his last bit of strength to rush to the camera , and immersed the person who was lying on top of him to restrain him into the water tank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our action director arranged it first. His martial arts actor did it once. He filmed it and cut it out for me to see. He said, can you do it like this? I remember at that time I said, Director , I’m not young anymore.” Lin Jiadong smiled and repeated, and the director said, “You can do it, Jiadong!”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Okay. Lin Jiadong watched the long shot twice, and everyone rehearsed it twice more. The shooting started. When he shot the first shot, his eye was injured. He went to the hospital and came back to continue filming. He happily recalled the scene at the end of the long scene where Guan Chao dragged the person to the water tank and submerged him. It was very enjoyable. &quot;For this character, he only has these 10 seconds in his life (to fight back like this). That should be his response to life.&quot; Roaring.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我放弃改造“扫兴”父母：“人教人很难，事教人一次就会”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When we were young, our parents took us to know the world; when we grow up, we also hope to take our parents to see the world. But our parents’ response often disappoints us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I take them on a trip, they mumble along the way, saying, &quot;You spend money to find trouble.&quot; When you take them to enjoy delicious food, they say, &quot;It&#39;s not as good as the food at home.&quot; You buy them down jackets and furs. A coat, they say, is &quot;not as light and warm as a cotton-padded jacket&quot;... Every time I happily do this or that for my parents, I always get thrown cold water on it, which makes me feel annoyed. Sometimes I will show it out and quarrel with my parents, saying, &quot;The dog bites me.&quot; Lu Dongbin——I don’t know the good heart.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the discussion on the Internet about &quot;parents who are not a spoiler&quot; has attracted a lot of attention. The negative example is my parents. The positive teaching material is to happily accept the kindness of their children, and their children will take them to eat. Enjoy it and say &quot;It&#39;s delicious.&quot; When your children buy clothes for them, they put them on immediately and say &quot;It looks good.&quot; Your children order takeout and happily follow it to taste... Some people even pull their parents to &quot;swear&quot; before taking their parents shopping: &quot;I am determined not to waste money, I am determined not to spend money to find trouble, and I am determined not to eat junk food again...&quot; I feel very sad! So I forwarded these short videos to my mother to see, hoping that she would change. She immediately said, &quot;You have to pretend to like it even if you don&#39;t like it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I really had nothing to say. I have to admit that she is right. Rational analysis shows that these short videos, on the one hand, capture the emotions of adult children who are disappointed by their parents; on the other hand, for the sake of traffic, they create an image of &quot;parents who are not disappointed&quot; and please the adult children who occupy the mainstream of the Internet population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is indeed a generation gap between us and our parents. First of all, we have different growth backgrounds and different views on money. My parents’ generation experienced an era of insufficient material wealth, so they are very frugal. Although many people have pensions that exceed their adult children’s salary and have less expenses, they are still reluctant to spend money. As my mother’s famous saying “Saving money is the key to saving money” My greatest pleasure.” In this way, we can understand why uncles and aunts are willing to line up for two hours to receive 10 eggs, and why old people who live in high-end communities are keen to collect scraps and sell them, not only because they have free time, but also because they are used to being frugal. What&#39;s more, the characteristics of their generation have been accurately grasped by scammers, and they often succeed under the guise of &quot;free&quot;. I once advised my mother not to fill in personal information in order to receive the free small fans, small mirrors, and low-quality tissues, so as not to receive countless phone calls or even encounter telecom fraud. But she firmly believed: &quot;It&#39;s free, don&#39;t give it up!&quot; &quot;I just Without spending money, what can he deceive me about?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the behavior of our parents to discourage us is due to their different views on money. Our generation has become accustomed to buying houses with loans, spending with credit cards, and spending money on spending money. &quot;Baitiao&quot;, look for housekeeping and cleaning, and be more frugal, earn ten yuan and spend five yuan... As long as you are comfortable and happy, you should spend money. But they would rather walk five streets under the scorching sun than spend two yuan to take a bus. They can spend two hours taking a bus and wander slowly, so they won&#39;t spend 10 minutes taking a taxi to get there. Therefore, the essence of their disincentive to us is that they are afraid that we will spend money, because we are one family with them. They have experienced a period of material scarcity, have richer life experiences, and understand the ups and downs of life better. They often say that &quot;a penny can stump a hero&quot;, &quot;a long stream of water will keep you from worrying when encountering disasters&quot;, &quot;thinking ahead and looking ahead, you will always have food and clothing&quot; &quot;If you don&#39;t have enough food, you won&#39;t have enough clothes. If you don&#39;t calculate, you will be poor.&quot; &quot;Three years for the new, three years for the old, and three more years for mending.&quot; They save money not only out of habit, but also to fully support us when needed. , let us borrow less when buying a house, pay less every month, and have more money...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two generations have different views on money, and it is difficult to distinguish the pros and cons. Although my mother is also aware of the benefits brought by another consumption concept, it is still difficult to overcome the hurdle in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Think about the changes in our generation&#39;s consumption outlook. It has gone through almost twenty years. From college, we started accepting credit cards, mobile payments, and e-commerce. After working, we started to make rapid progress, buying, buying, buying, and now live broadcasting. After grabbing time, we began to reflect again, burst the consumption bubble, and became more rational... Now we force our parents&#39; generation to immediately keep up with our pace and support our consumption concept 100%. It is really unrealistic. The transformation of parents also needs to be done step by step. We have stepped on the consumption &quot;pits&quot; that we have stepped on before, bought a bunch of cheap and unused small items, been deceived several times, returned the goods several times, and been injured several times. Only then can the mind slowly become enlightened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother rented out the house and persuaded her to install new furniture. She was not willing to spend money, so she moved the &quot;old antiques&quot; that were no longer needed at home to the rental house. She was not fashionable at all. As a result, many tenants came and did not It looks like it has never been rented out. So, she asked someone to move the &quot;old antiques&quot; and install new furniture. Moving around, owing favors, and delaying renting, I indirectly lost a lot of money, which was far more than the money for new furniture. &quot;It&#39;s hard to teach others, but you can teach them everything once.&quot; She was convinced after he calculated the economic accounts for her through his words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, I saw in my circle of friends that they were going on a &quot;travel&quot;. The so-called &quot;travel&quot; meant visiting various towns and villages under the jurisdiction of our county. They happily told me that due to preferential policies, local residents over sixty years old can ride the bus for free. If they bring a bottle of boiled water and two boiled eggs, they can go out for a day without spending a penny. I suddenly realized that for us, Lijiang, Xinjiang, Tibet, Maldives, and Iceland are poetry and distance, but for them, the surrounding towns and villages are their poetry and distance, and this is a travel experience that is more suitable for their &quot;physical constitution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our parents grew up with us and took the trouble to teach us to understand and experience small things one by one. As we grow older with our parents, we must also change our mentality, stop being harsh, and patiently accompany our parents to &quot;grow&quot; together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, I gave up trying to reform my &quot;disappointing&quot; parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a middle school teacher in Tianjin)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[死亡失踪上万人的水灾和卡扎菲倒台后的利比亚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257425]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/o0ZuyjkGuA3rVspRSN5TLDaXB5H10ip7SjvqNBsG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/o0ZuyjkGuA3rVspRSN5TLDaXB5H10ip7S jvqNBsG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251351&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 14, 2023, Derna, Libya, rescuers worked on the ruins of a building &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 10, 2023, the Mediterranean hurricane &quot;Daniel&quot; hit many cities in northeastern Libya. Heavy rains of 150 to 240 millimeters caused severe flooding in many cities. The port city of Derna was particularly severely affected. The wind waves in the city center were as high as 20 feet. Two old dams on the Wadi Derna river in the upper reaches collapsed. After the floods raged, almost no intact building could be found in the entire city, and some residents were swept into the Mediterranean Sea with their houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations stated on September 16 that the local death toll has exceeded 11,300, and another 10,100 people are still alive and dead. 40,000 people are homeless. There are still dead bodies soaked in the sea and no one has salvaged them. The number is bound to rise again. Libyan state-run media stated on the 17th that it is currently known that 891 buildings in Derna were completely destroyed, 211 buildings were partially destroyed, and 398 houses were soaked in mud after being flooded. The mayor&#39;s office speculated that the death toll could eventually reach 20,000 - equivalent to a fifth of the city&#39;s population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 17th, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs cited data from the World Health Organization and published a report, revising the death toll caused by the Libyan floods to 3,958, with more than 9,000 people missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Derna is a city with a long history. &lt;/span>;) already exists. Amid the 2011 anti-government demonstrations in Libya, the city broke away from the control of Gaddafi&#39;s government on February 18. In 2014, the city was occupied by Islamic State militants, during which it was subjected to multiple air strikes by the Egyptian military. In 2015, the Derna Mujahideen Shura Council, a militia considered close to Al Qaeda, defeated the Islamic State and regained control of the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, General Khalifa Haftar, regarded as the main authority in eastern Libya, has led the siege of Derna, the last territory in eastern Libya that has resisted his rule, with intensive bombing and brutal The ground fighting inflicted heavy losses on the city. In 2018, Haftar finally captured Derna. Haftar did not order a large-scale reconstruction of Derna out of distrust of its residents. It was not until 2022 that the eastern Libyan government formulated a reconstruction plan for Derna. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to years of war, Derna City does not have unified central government management, its infrastructure is old, and its ability to prevent and control floods is very weak. In recent years, global warming has caused the waters of the Mediterranean to expand, and rising sea levels have eroded coastlines and caused flooding, especially in low-lying coastal areas like Derna. On September 10, 2023, Hurricane Daniel made landfall on the Mediterranean coast of eastern Libya. The hurricane had already caused serious damage in Greece, Turkey and Bulgaria along the Mediterranean coast, resulting in more than a dozen deaths. However, the Libyan authorities did not seriously formulate a monitoring plan. There was no plan to warn or evacuate residents of the dam situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Libyan National Meteorological Center said it had issued warnings through emails and media 72 hours before &quot;Daniel&quot; made landfall, urging local governments to take preventive measures. However, the National Meteorological Center of Libya is affiliated to the Government of National Accord in the west, and Derna is an area controlled by the eastern government. Local residents said that they did not receive warning before the flood hit, and the authorities did not have any evacuation plan. They only heard the loud noise of the dam breaking. Only then did everyone realize that the flood was coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The World Meteorological Organization pointed out on September 14 that if the Libyan authorities had an early warning system for storms and floods, the vast majority of the victims could have been prevented from dying. In other words, this disaster appears to be a natural disaster, but is actually a man-made disaster. In the future, after floods wash away, landmines and unexploded bombs left over from years of war may surface, and secondary disasters may occur where people accidentally touch landmines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than ten years since the fall of former Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi, Libya has experienced one war after another and political crisis after another. To this day, it is still in a situation of confrontation between the eastern and western governments. . Many people have long forgotten this long dispute, but the floods that occurred in Derna, causing tens of thousands of deaths and missing people, once again drew people&#39;s attention back to this ill-fated place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pviUluMz4LwOxQ6Ahu3w4waO28itNzjeEPzguqay.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/pviUluMz4LwOxQ6Ahu3w4waO28itNzjeEPzguqay.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 25, 2007, Tripoli, Libya, Libyan supreme leader Muammar Gaddafi (right) welcomed visiting French President Sarkozy&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A divided country&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Libya has an area of ​​1.76 million square kilometers and a population of 6.7 million. It is located in northern Africa and the southern coast of the Mediterranean. To the east is Cyrenaica, to the west is Tripolitania, and to the southwest is Fezzan. There is a desert barrier between the three, making communication inconvenient. They have been separated for a long time in history. Due to the separation of the natural geographical environment, the eastern and western regions of Libya are closely connected with the surrounding Egypt, Tunisia and Algeria, but have little contact with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya historically belonged to the Roman Empire, the Arab Empire and the Ottoman Turkish Empire, but these rulers regarded the above three regions as independent plates, so Libya has never been integrated into a unified entity in history. political community. Therefore, like most countries in the Middle East and North Africa, Libya is also a typical tribal country, and people identify with the tribe more than the country. During the period when it was ruled by the Arab Empire, it experienced the process of Islamization. Today, most people in Libya are Sunni believers in Islam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the 20th century, the unified Italy also joined the ranks of colonial expansion and began to look for its own territory in Africa. It took a fancy to Libya under the rule of the Ottoman Empire, so it brazenly launched a war of aggression. In 1912, Italy defeated the Ottoman Empire in the Italian-Turkish War, making Libya an Italian colony. At the same time, the Senussi Order in eastern Cyrenaica launched a large-scale resistance movement in the name of &quot;holy war&quot;. The secular forces in the western region also actively resisted Italian aggression and even established the Republic of Tripoli in 1918. It was later banned and disbanded by Mussolini. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II, in July 1949, the leader of the Senussi Order, Idris, declared the independence of Cyrenaica and served as the emir. In December 1951, Idris won the support of nationalist forces and tribes in three regions and finally established the United Kingdom of Libya. The three regions of Cyrenaica, Tripolitania and Fezzan were each a state with autonomy. right. The three colors on the current Libyan flag represent these three federal states and are symbols of federalism. In 1963, Libya&#39;s new constitution abolished the federal system and divided the country into 10 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 1969, Gaddafi, the leader of the &quot;Free Officers Organization&quot;, launched a coup, overthrew the Idris dynasty and established the Libyan Arab Republic. Gaddafi, who was born in the Bedouin tribe of the Fezzan region, has ruled Libya for 42 years, relying mainly on strongman politics and centralization, coupled with distribution policies supported by oil revenue, to barely suppress tribalism and localism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya first discovered oil in 1958 and officially started production in 1961. Its oil reserves are approximately 47.1 billion barrels, ranking first in Africa and ninth in the world, accounting for 2.9% of the world&#39;s total. Crude oil has good quality and low sulfur content. It is a high-quality oil and is very popular in the international market. After 1973, with the sharp rise in international oil prices, the Gaddafi regime gained a lot of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid a recurrence of the tragedy of the fall of the Idris dynasty, and at the same time gain public support for his radical anti-imperialist stance, Gaddafi significantly increased investment in housing, health care, education and other fields, and increased workers&#39; wages. , and provide free public housing to the poor; the land originally belonging to the Senussi Order and Italian farmers will also be distributed to farmers, and farm tools and livestock will be provided at extremely low prices; new housing in rural areas can also be financed by government-controlled banks subsidy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But starting in the 1980s, due to the decline in international oil prices, Libyan oil revenue dropped sharply from US$21 billion in 1981 to US$5.4 billion in 1986. After the Lockerbie air crash in 1988, Libya was identified as the mastermind behind the crash and was subject to sanctions and embargoes by Western countries. In addition, oil field facilities are aging and oil production is ups and downs. There is no excess oil revenue to exchange for public support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, 95% of Libya’s export revenue, 75% of government revenue, and 25% of GDP came from oil. At the same time, Libya’s domestic unemployment rate was as high as 30%, and most important infrastructure construction projects and crude oil extraction Projects are completed through international tenders and are completed by foreign companies and technical personnel, while a large number of Libya&#39;s own young labor force is unemployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2010, the &quot;Arab Spring&quot; broke out in the Middle East, and Libya was also affected. Anti-government demonstrations occurred, and the government responded with force to suppress them. On February 27, 2011, the opposition established the &quot;National Transitional Council&quot; in Benghazi, Libya&#39;s second largest city. On March 19, Britain and France launched air strikes in Libya in accordance with United Nations Security Council Resolution 1973. On September 16, the United Nations General Assembly passed a resolution to replace Libya&#39;s seat in the United Nations by the National Transitional Council. On October 20, Gaddafi was killed on his way to escape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2012, in protest against a movie that insulted Islam, the U.S. Consulate in Benghazi was attacked by an Islamic armed group. U.S. Ambassador Stevens was killed. The worst damage in years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/mzpx5TBpSLxfSfJJCWEvZMjsOtQwHjc2lgRNNRre.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/mzpx5TBpSLxfSfJJCWEvZMjsOtQwHjc2lgRNNRre.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251352&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 16, 2023, the disaster-stricken area of ​​Derna, Libya&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Post-Gaddafi era&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Libyan opposition is a group that includes defectors from the original Gaddafi regime, pro-Western liberals, eastern tribal leaders who are dissatisfied with Gaddafi and the dictatorship of western tribes, former Id A hodgepodge of supporters of the Reese royal family, the only thing they have in common is their dissatisfaction with Gaddafi. When the revolution has not yet succeeded, because the common enemy is still there, everyone has to seek common ground while reserving differences and work hard to cooperate. However, when the overall situation is determined, interests emerge, and the struggle for power is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To avoid infighting and division when sharing the fruits of the revolution, a leader with high moral integrity and the ability to reconcile various factions is necessary. However, during the 42 years of Gaddafi&#39;s rule, Libya had no president, no prime minister, no parliament, no cabinet, only Colonel Gaddafi. The imagination and passion of a generation were limited by the ubiquitous &quot;Green Book&quot;. How could it be possible? Such a politician appeared in a short period of time? In addition, after Gaddafi&#39;s army was disbanded, Libya failed to form a new national army. The existing militia groups strengthened their own forces and expanded their territory, causing the country to fall into a state of disorder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During Gaddafi’s rule, Cyrenaica in the east was suppressed by him for a long time, and the locals were always very dissatisfied. After the &quot;Arab Spring&quot; took place, this was the first place where trouble broke out and started anew. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Libya was divided: the Government of National Accord and its armed forces recognized by the United Nations controlled most of western Libya, while the &quot;National Army&quot; led by Haftar controlled eastern and western Libya. Central Region. The two sides have clashed several times since 2014, and Libya has descended into civil war. The civil war continued until 2020, and the two sides finally reached a ceasefire. However, until now, the general election originally scheduled for 2021 has not been held, and sporadic fighting between the western armed forces and the eastern armed forces continues. Just last month, at least 45 people were killed in fighting between the two sides in Tripoli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An important reason why the situation in Libya cannot be stabilized is the intervention of external forces. The Western Government of National Accord recognized by the United Nations has Turkey, Qatar and Italy as its backers, as well as Egypt, Russia, Jordan, the United Arab Emirates, and France. It supports the Haftar regime that controls the center and east. Italy wants to maintain the &quot;face&quot; of its former colonial master, Turkey wants to restore the glory of the &quot;Ottoman Empire&quot;... Each &quot;player&quot; has different reasons for entering the game. However, they seem to have the same goal behind them, which is the oil and natural gas resources in the Eastern Mediterranean. In the past ten years, a large amount of natural gas and oil have been discovered in this sea area. Libya and even the entire Eastern Mediterranean region have once again become a &quot;powder keg&quot; for various countries to engage in energy competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consequences of Libya&#39;s disorder are not limited to the current out-of-control floods. After the fall of Gaddafi, the rebels looted the weapons arsenal of the government forces, and many weapons were transferred to other surrounding countries, especially extremist organizations. Chadian President Deby believes that the rise of extremist organizations such as the Nigerian terrorist organization &quot;Boko Haram&quot; , has a great relationship with the situation in Libya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[共赴亚运之约！杭州第19届亚洲运动会开幕式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257509]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 20:09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[水为串联、潮为意向 亚运会开幕式主题定名《潮起亚细亚》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257473]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will open tonight. All parties will attend the Asian Games and look forward to showing the world Presenting an Asian Games event with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style, and excitement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opening ceremony performance of this Asian Games has also attracted attention. Come and listen to the interpretation of the opening ceremony by the chief director of the opening ceremony at the press conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021557728823&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Water is series, tide is The intended theme of the opening ceremony of the Asian Games is &quot;Tide Asia&quot; (3).mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.j pg&quot; data-url=&quot; http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/HOjpX1ZfB6wA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://12514 34507 .vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d8e9a4b35576678021557728823/HOjpX1ZfB6wA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theme of the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou is named &quot;The Rise of Asia&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/fe8a003ef7ca83a47aaf866b6ea7a72f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/fe8a003ef7ca83a47aaf866b6ea7a72f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251701&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sha Xiaolan, Chief Director and Chief Producer of the Opening Ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;Simply put, tide is the most representative of Zhejiang’s regional characteristics. Everyone knows about the spring tides in the Qiantang River. When talking about tides, these are the first things that come to mind.亚细亚是我们亚洲的全称，所以《潮起亚细亚》大家最终定的就是这个主题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f5de2de2068c6c27a25eb4523eb8c370.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f5de2de2068c6c27a25eb4523eb8c370.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251702&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;潮，是钱塘的记忆，是体育的跃动，是浙江的精神，是时代的脉搏，因其前赴后继的形象，在中国文化中被寓以特殊的含义。以《潮起亚细亚》为开幕式总主题，彰显出地域的自然标识、人文的独特魅力、运动的蓬勃力量和时代的发展趋势。整场开幕式上篇为“国风之潮”，中篇为“体育之潮”，下篇为“人文之潮”，而呈现的方式则体现了“科技之潮”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/baddd5973c0ddaefa7de14439ad5bfc9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/baddd5973c0ddaefa7de14439ad5bfc9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251703&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杭州第19届亚运会开幕式总导演总制作人沙晓岚：&lt;/strong>;在创作的时候，我们把宋韵文化作为上篇的核心表达，有5000年的良渚，到了近千年的杭州的宋韵，再穿越到当今的现代杭州，大家也可以看到一个通过拱宸桥连接了古今的杭州。还有通过第二篇章里面的体育之潮，把体育元素充分地展现，包括体育运动的标识、运动符号、一些球类的表演，到了下篇叫做人文之潮，绿水青山就是金山银山，幸福的生活，绿水青山在这个当中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/d31a261a4dee475746f7ff9eeb715355.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;496&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/d31a261a4dee475746f7ff9eeb715355.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251704&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整场开幕式的仪式及表演以水为串联、潮为意向，通过“潮起亚细亚”展现新时代中国与亚洲、与世界的交融激荡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开幕式演出中“绿色”理念将贯穿始终&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于杭州第19届亚运会的开幕式，导演组还重点介绍了绿色、智能、人文元素。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-1&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021562274795&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;水为串联、潮为意向亚运会开幕式主题定名《潮起亚细亚》 (1).mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/bFeOaHUOWJ8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/38f6c4535576678021562274795/bFeOaHUOWJ8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本届亚运会的办赛理念是“绿色、智能、节俭、文明”，开幕式的演出也将“绿色”理念贯穿始终，首先就是不燃放烟花。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杭州第19届亚运会开幕式总导演总制作人沙晓岚：&lt;/strong>;大家知道，只要放烟花，空中一定会有烟尘粉尘等等一些污染，通过不放烟花来表达我们的理念、想法、包括环保的意识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在科技的运用上，沙晓岚透露，本次点火采用的是数字点火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f0091e63e7c73739527586697c6cd1c4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;498&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f0091e63e7c73739527586697c6cd1c4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251705&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;杭州第19届亚运会开幕式总导演总制作人沙晓岚：&lt;/strong>;这一次我们就想回归到体育的本体，体育的本体是什么？强身健体，强身健体绝不是几个人或者几群人的事情，是全民的事情。就想说，如果是有更多的人参与到点火里面，几百万人、几千万人、上亿人参与到点火上面，一是世界首创，二是最大限度让全民来参与，三是体现了世界亚洲共此时，最终一条，是人类命运共同体具体的实践。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家植物园将扩容，已有候选园“自宣”丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:59:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/PRrN12aHKcGG9UyEpq6I7vlxJeOFScwkEftCKhEh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/PRrN12aHKcGG9UyEpq6I7vlxJeOFScwkEftCKhEh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251744&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月16日，国家植物园北园，樱桃沟水杉林栈道喷雾开启。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2035年，中国的国家植物园有望增加到10个左右。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家林草局、住建部、国家发改委、自然资源部、中国科学院联合近日联合印发《国家植物园体系布局方案》，确定在已设立2个国家植物园的基础上，再遴选14个国家植物园候选园，纳入国家植物园体系布局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据方案提出的国家植物园体系建设目标，到2035年，力争设立10个左右国家植物园，使80%以上的国家重点保护野生植物、70%以上珍稀濒危野生植物得到有效迁地保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与普通的植物园不同，国家植物园由国家批准设立。其核心功能包括植物科学研究和迁地保护，定位是国家植物科学研究和交流中心、战略植物资源储备库、濒危植物的迁地保护基地以及植物科学传播中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国目前已有的2个国家植物园，分别是国家植物园、华南国家植物园。前者于2021年12月28日经国务院批准，依托中国科学院植物研究所和北京市植物园设立。位于北京西山的国家植物园开放面积约300公顷，收集植物1.7万余种。后者依托中国科学院华南植物园设立，2022年5月30日经国务院批复同意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此番再遴选14个国家植物园候选园，标准是什么？14个候选园分别有是哪些？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者查询国家林草局、住房和城乡建设部、国家发展改革委、自然资源部、中国科学院和中央人民政府网站，暂未查询到《国家植物园体系布局方案》全文。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，加快国家植物园体系建设的行动仍然有迹可循。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月12日，《生物多样性公约》第十五次缔约方大会领导人峰会上，中国提出本着统筹就地保护与迁地保护相结合的原则，启动北京、广州等国家植物园体系建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年5月20日举办的国际生物多样性日中国主场宣传活动上，生态环境部、国家林草局相关负责人就表态，将加快国家公园和国家植物园体系建设，当年力争再新设立一批国家公园，编制完成国家植物园体系建设规划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然《国家植物园体系布局方案》全文暂未公布，但就国家植物园体系建设的核心要素和建设方式，新华社的报道称，将采取整合与新建相结合的方式，稳步构建以代表国家形象的国家植物园为核心，以代表典型气候带和典型植被特征的区域国家植物园为主体的国家植物园体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另据浙江省委、省政府官方新闻网站浙江在线报道，国家植物园的创建设立，将按照“成熟一个、设立一个”的原则，推进国家植物园体系建设。对确实无法达到设立要求的，不得设立为国家植物园；对评估不达标的，启动黄牌机制，通过公示公告、限期整改，对整改不力、整改不到位的要采取退出机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管此番再遴选14个国家植物园候选园的详细信息未公布，但已有植物园“自宣”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科学院植物研究所南京中山植物园官网2023年9月21日消息，该园已作为国家植物园候选园纳入国家植物园体系布局，下一步将按照国家植物园体系布局方案和相关要求，结合创建任务与实际，有序推进“南京中山国家植物园”创建、设立和建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除植物园自宣已纳入候选园体系，还有部分地区明确提出了建设国家植物园的计划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，上海提出创建上海辰山国家植物园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月，杭州明确提出，杭州第二植物园将打造国际一流的植物园，最终目标为纳入国家植物园体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;人事动向&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【程凯当选中国残联主席，张海迪卸任】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据新华社消息，中国残疾人联合会第八次全国代表大会2023年9月20日上午在京闭幕，程凯当选中国残疾人联合会第八届主席团主席，张海迪卸任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，程凯，男，汉族，1964年11月出生，中共党员，研究生学历，文学博士学位，肢体残疾，此前担任中国残联党组成员、第七届主席团副主席、执行理事会副理事长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【国家卫健委领导班子调整】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家卫健委官网“委领导”栏目更新信息显示，曾益新、雷海潮已任国家卫健委党组副书记，曲孝丽已任国家卫健委党组成员、中央纪委国家监委驻国家卫健委纪检监察组组长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾益新，男，1962年10月出生，湖南娄底人。曾益新于2018年3月任国家卫生健康委员会副主任、党组成员，中央保健委员会副主任，2022年5月明确为正部长级干部。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷海潮出生于1968年4月，山东德州人，曾任北京市卫健委主任等职，于2020年10月升任国家卫健委副主任、党组成员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曲孝丽，女，1963年9月生，山东昌邑人，曾任河南省委常委、省纪委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【海南省新增一位副省长】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海南省第七届人民代表大会常务委员会第六次会议通过，决定任命巴特尔为海南省人民政府副省长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，巴特尔，男，蒙古族，1967年2月出生，研究生，经济学硕士，中共党员。巴特尔早年长期在国土资源部工作，2015年前往海南任职，历任海口市委常委、副市长，海南省国土资源厅党组书记、副厅长，海南省国土资源厅党组书记、厅长，海南省应急管理厅党组书记、厅长，海南省交通运输厅党组书记、厅长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年4月，在海南省委领导班子换届中，巴特尔当选为海南省委常委，随后兼任省委秘书长、省委办公厅主任职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【中纪委国家监委驻中央社会工作部纪检监察组组长人选确定】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月18日消息，刘钊已任中央纪委国家监委驻中央社会工作部纪检监察组组长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘钊，男，1963年12月生，陕西扶风人。刘钊曾任公安部交通管理局局长，2018年出任公安部党委委员、政治部主任，2020年7月被任命为公安部副部长，近日卸任公安部副部长职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;反腐纪事&lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【西宁原市长孔令栋被双开】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;落马8个月之后，青海省西宁市委原副书记、市长孔令栋被“双开”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔令栋，男，1970年12月出生，甘肃武威人。孔令栋长期在青海省会西宁市工作，曾任西宁市发展改革委主任。2021年3月，孔令栋任西宁市委副书记、市长人选，次月当选西宁市市长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年1月，孔令栋被查。经查，孔令栋不正确履行职责，脱离实际制定并强行要求完成经济指标任务，致使统计数据造假，造成不良影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【嫖娼、赌博的贵州厅官刘文新被“双开”，被点名“玩物丧志、痴迷刀具”】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央纪委国家监委网站通报，2022年10月被查的贵州省委政法委原副书记刘文新被“双开”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘文新，男，汉族，1967年8月出生，江西萍乡人。他长期在贵阳市工作，历任贵阳市常务副市长、贵阳市市长等职务，2017年任黔西南州委书记，2022年调任贵州省委政法委员会副书记（正厅长级）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经查，刘文新廉洁底线失守，违规收受礼品礼金，道德败坏，生活极其腐化堕落，大搞权色、钱色交易，长期与他人发生不正当性关系，嫖娼、赌博；玩物丧志、痴迷刀具。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;部委信息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【自然资源部：《森林公园管理办法》等4份规章废止】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自然资源部网站9月20日消息，自然资源部部长王广华签署第10号部令，公布《自然资源部关于第五批废止的部门规章的决定》。《森林公园管理办法》《林业标准化管理办法》《国家级森林公园设立、撤销、合并、改变经营范围或者变更隶属关系审批管理办法》《国家级森林公园管理办法》等4份规章废止。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【“全国文物犯罪线索举报平台”上线】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月19日召开的西北警务协作区第十三届联席会议暨黄河流域、西北地区打击防范文物犯罪警务协作会议上，“全国文物犯罪线索举报平台”从即日起正式上线运行。该平台是基于微信打造的小程序，广大群众和网友无需下载App软件，即可进行涉及文物犯罪线索举报。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;法治播报&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【8名部级干部获聘最高检咨询委员】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据最高检官网， 2023年9月18日，最高人民检察院召开咨询委员工作会议，新聘8位咨询委员。 最高检新聘孙谦、徐显明、苏德良、万春、张志杰、李琪林、刘华、贺恒扬担任最高检咨询委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙谦、徐显明曾任最高检副检察长。苏德良曾任最高检党组成员。万春、张志杰曾任最高检副部级专职委员。李琪林、刘华、贺恒扬曾任地方省份（自治区）检察长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【“两高”、海关总署开展惩治非法引进外来入侵物种犯罪行动】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最高人民检察院网站9月19日消息，近日，海关总署、最高人民法院、最高人民检察院决定在全国范围内联合开展为期一年的依法惩治非法引进外来入侵物种犯罪行动，坚决防范外来物种通过口岸进境入侵。三部门将联合开展行动，依法追究刑事责任，查办一批典型案件，形成司法震慑；建立健全案情通报、案件移送机制，联合开展重大案件督查督办。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【最高检、住房和城乡建设部：规范城乡历史文化保护传承行政公益诉讼】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最高检、住房和城乡建设部日前联合印发了《关于在检察公益诉讼中加强协作配合依法做好城乡历史文化保护传承工作的意见》，强化城乡历史文化保护传承领域执法司法衔接。《意见》聚焦侵害国家利益或者社会公共利益，特别是情节严重、影响恶劣、拒不整改的违法行为，重点关注历史城区整体管控、历史文化街区和历史地段保护、历史文化名镇名村保护以及历史建筑保护四个重点领域。《意见》要求，规范城乡历史文化保护传承行政公益诉讼办案工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;地方政情&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【雄安新区取消商品住房预售】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央视新闻客户端报道，雄安新区取消商品住房预售，实行现房销售，实现“所见即所得、交房即交证”。同时，雄安新区支持有意愿的人才，通过租房解决住房问题，并在教育、医疗、就业等公共服务领域“租售同权”。雄安还要求，在新建片区市场化项目中，配置不低于30%的“只租不售”型住房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【湖北宣恩狮子关景区被取消等级】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湖北省文旅厅微信公众号9月19日消息，湖北省文旅厅集中以文件等形式发布了2023年A级旅游景区复核处理及投诉较多旅行社处理情况。其中，对宣恩县狮子关旅游区（4A）等6家A级旅游景区予以取消等级处理。通报指出，恩施宣恩狮子关旅游区主体安全意识淡薄，安全管理严重失职，应急处置不当，且对各级文旅部门多次督导检查指出的安全隐患问题未予重视，整改不力，导致2023年5月16日发生商务车从水上浮桥落水，造成5人死亡的较大安全事故。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【上海徐汇发布防治性骚扰行为指南，四种情形不构成性骚扰】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月19日，上海市徐汇区人民检察院召开新闻发布会，联合区公安分局等7家单位共同发布了《上海市徐汇区防治性骚扰行为指南》。《指南》明确，性骚扰主要包括言语、文字、图像、肢体等形式，文字形式的性骚扰主要表现在多次发送带有淫秽、污辱内容的信件、手机短信、微信、电子邮件、传真等。图像形式的性骚扰主要表现在多次通过电子邮件、微博、微信等形式发送或展示色情图片和物品。四种情形则不构成性骚扰：基于双方自愿的交往、约会；不经意地偶然身体接触；偶然或孤立的性语言；其他社会和文化上可接受的言语或行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【安徽省委书记韩俊：怎么支持中科大都不为过】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月20日上午，中国科学技术大学2023年开学典礼举行。安徽省委书记韩俊出席大会并讲话：“安徽省委、省政府对中国科大始终高看一眼、厚爱三分。我们将一如既往地秉持&#39;怎么支持科大都不为过&#39;的理念，全力当好中国科大的后勤部长，把中国科大的事当作安徽省委、省政府的大事，对中国科大的诉求有求必应。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会今晚8时开幕，广东运动员将担任旗手]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:30:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月23日20时，杭州第19届亚洲运动会将在杭州奥体中心体育场开幕。在国际综合性大赛上，开幕式往往被认为是最能体现举办国家特色的一次文化展示。亚运会时隔13年重回中国，广东健儿杨力维担任中国代表团旗手。开幕式上将有哪些亮点？一起来提前看看吧！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/63014c49eb08dc6a7a38c80ad41348f1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/63014c49eb08dc6a7a38c80ad41348f1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杭州奥体中心体育场（右）和杭州奥体中心网球中心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;赛事规模为史上之最&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;杭州亚运会于9月23日至10月8日举行，为期16天，赛会规模和参赛人数都创下亚运历史之最，共产生481枚金牌。亚奥理事会45个成员均报名参赛，很多国家和地区派出史上最大规模的代表团，据统计，本届亚运会共有1.2万余名运动员报名参加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本届亚运会项目中，既有田径、游泳等奥运大项，也有武术、藤球、板球、克柔术等代表不同地域体育文化的特色项目，还有首次成为亚运会正式项目的霹雳舞等，比赛项目数量创下历届亚运会之最。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在开幕式上，观众可以看到来自中国、泰国、日本、韩国、印度、中国香港等6个人数最多的代表团，这6个代表团的运动员报名人数均超过600人。其中，中国体育代表团总人数达1329人，其中运动员886人（女运动员437人，男运动员449人），运动员平均年龄25岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/dabc9eb8a4ec345aa53abe588123905b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;516&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/dabc9eb8a4ec345aa53abe588123905b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杨力维（中）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开幕式上，来自广东的中国女篮运动员杨力维与“蛙王”覃海洋将担任中国代表团旗手。作为中国女篮的队长，杨力维一年多来助力中国女篮夺得世界杯亚军、亚洲杯冠军，“敢于拼、善于战、勇于胜”的广东体育军团精神激励着杨力维不断前行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于出任旗手，杨力维表示，从个人角度来说，非常高兴获此殊荣，但“这个荣誉不是代表我自己，而是对中国女篮的认可，是属于中国篮球的荣誉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;水元素贯穿全场&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;杭州是一个因水而兴、因水而生的城市，杭州的名片钱塘江、大运河、西湖、西溪湿地都与水息息相关。因此，在创作理念上，开幕式以水作为核心元素贯穿全场，开幕式总主题为《潮起亚细亚》，寓意着新时代的中国正与亚洲、世界交融激荡，就像浪潮一样奔涌向前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/97ae74e566e74fa893a8f8ace87d3203.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/97ae74e566e74fa893a8f8ace87d3203.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251745&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;流经杭州的钱塘江。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开幕式将分为三个篇章，通过《国风雅韵》《钱塘潮涌》《携手同行》的呈现，展现国风国潮、自然之潮、科技之潮、体育之潮、时代浪潮的碰撞。 “水”元素的体现，既是中华文明良渚文化的探源，又是浙江文化、杭州文化的溯源，也是亚洲各国山水相依的结缘，表达着对未来美好中国的祈愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;技术与艺术双向奔赴&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在三大篇章中，杭州五千多年文明史、千年宋韵文化与数字之城的特色融合展现。距今五千多年历史的良渚文化，让观众感悟文明之光照亮历史前进的力量；南宋时期的文化精神与现代文明智能的杭州，通过一座拱宸桥连接在一起，形成一场古今文化的对话和穿越；通过3D双威亚技术，气势磅礴的钱塘江大潮在观众面前全新呈现……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;届时，通过地屏、立体透视网幕的配合，加之裸眼3D的视效与虚拟影像的设计，直接把行进的千里江山、江南烟雨、钱塘江潮和绿水青山都“搬”到舞台之上，营造人在画中走，画在景中游的景象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3f2db9212a4b5ea0998548e36ac08a8f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3f2db9212a4b5ea0998548e36ac08a8f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251750&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杭州奥体中心体育场馆群。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后时刻，可以看到古临安和今杭州古今对望的景象，导演组利用虚拟技术，将一幅万家灯火的古今相辉映的场景呈现在大众面前。 “相知无远近，万里尚为邻”，杭州将向全亚洲发出最诚挚的邀请。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;电子烟花期待拉满&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;为体现本届亚运会绿色、智能、节俭、文明的办赛理念，开幕式全程不燃放实体烟花。尽管没有盛大的烟花表演，但开幕式的精彩程度并不会因此而大打折扣。主创团队推陈出新，通过科技的力量，利用三维动画、AR技术等，将烟花展示在电视观众和现场观众之前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/522cc071258c7f54ec6dba0b4830ef76.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/522cc071258c7f54ec6dba0b4830ef76.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251749&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杭州奥体中心网球中心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虚拟技术制作的烟花，甚至比真实燃放的烟花更灿烂，更漂亮。为此，杭州亚运会开幕式总导演、总制作人沙晓岚还给出了观赏指南：大家通过电视、手机等端口观看开幕式电子烟花表演，整体观赏效果优于现场。主创团队将通过数字技术从仰、俯、侧视等角度，360度全景式展现钱江两岸、杭州奥体中心场馆群、“大莲花”的电子烟花表演盛况，这将是开幕式的一个高光时刻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;点火仪式悬念将揭晓&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;点火仪式作为现代大型体育赛事的一项传统仪式，传递了运动会的精神和理念。而杭州亚运会的点火仪式，正是秉承了“绿色、智能、节俭、文明”的办赛理念，遵循“简约、安全、精彩”的办赛要求，环保中不失创意，科技感满满。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本届杭州亚运会推出了亚运数字火炬，首创“亚运数字火炬手”这一概念，邀请全球网民争当亚运数字火炬手，参与线上火炬传递活动，让亚运火种的传递突破了时间、空间的限制。在23日晚的开幕式上，主创团队将以“数实融合”的形式完成主火炬点燃，创造亚运史上首个数字点火仪式。从目前的实时统计数字看，将会有超过1亿名数字火炬手参与进来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/edb657b938fa64cb2f741b5ba6f49727.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/edb657b938fa64cb2f741b5ba6f49727.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;杭州亚运会火种采集仪式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23日晚，每个线上、线下火炬手都是一个小火苗、一个发光点，汇聚在钱塘江上，形成一个具象“数字人”，踏着钱塘潮涌，步履坚定，奔向“大莲花”上空，打破时空壁垒，跃入185米立体网幕，和第六棒火炬手相会，“数实融合”点燃主火炬塔，完成点火仪式。谁将成为最后一棒火炬手，和上亿名数字火炬手共同点燃圣火？让我们共同期待！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一个自称丧失“特权”的北京人想要火成世界巨星]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257417]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/guhqxOKWY9QMsHGiTXOeQpzPUrvIS1FicqkIqi0A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/guhqxOKWY9QMsHGiTXOeQpzPUrvIS1FicqkIqi0A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我照样是个loser，我是北京人但我没房，因为我把本来可以买房的钱拿去出国留学了，我以为我的升值空间比北京房价高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在美国学的专业还是经济学，买房的钱拿去学经济，相当于花了一堆钱，学到我不该花这堆钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑把自己的经历放进短视频，用红底白字标上四个大字“失去特权”，成为玖姑视频账号里最火的内容。她有意为这条短视频添加带来流量的元素，“特权”，指向地域发展的不平衡以及贫富差距；“买不起房”，共鸣因房价而引起的普遍焦虑；“留学”，关联教育内卷和名校光环。她还在视频里抱猫抱狗，并且坦然地说出这一点：“也是为了流量。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在玖姑的讲述中，她将一手“好牌”打得稀烂，但实际上，她不觉得自己的选择是错的，她认为自己所做的事都在朝着一个目标行进——火成世界巨星。这个目标早早设立，从4岁开始，没经过可行性评估，全靠自信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她将自己的网名改为“玖姑要火了”，毫不掩饰自己的野心和欲望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，一个只想说大实话、素颜出镜、观点温和的人，真的能在当下的互联网中火起来吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0eq17pfRpfExYoj6yLeFzpCsLV51ZCoWo5kh4tXw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/0eq17pfRpfExYoj6yLeFzpCsLV51ZCoWo5kh4tXw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玖姑在美国四处游历&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;平均值&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;发现自己作为一个北京人却很难在北京买房这件事，让玖姑意识到自己错失了属于本地人的优势。那时候她从国外留学回来，不想一直和父母住，在北京租房，又碰上二房东卷钱跑路，加之工作不顺，她陷入了人生的低谷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么会选择留学？玖姑认为主要原因是在学校被孤立。从小学到高中，玖姑就读于北京排名前五的公立学校，成绩随着年级的升高变得越来越重要。到了高中，玖姑觉得所有人都特别在乎成绩，只有学霸才会受到尊重，像她这样喜欢参加社团活动的人是不务正业的“异类”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矛盾爆发于一次合唱节，玖姑负责组织排练，但班上同学认为排练挤占了学习时间，对合唱的排斥聚焦于玖姑个人身上，冷暴力像病毒一样传遍全班。玖姑觉得自己没有错，学校里的文科实验班经常有排演话剧、参加文体活动的机会，而普通班学生只能当观众，她不过是也想参与一次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑从小喜欢搞活动，北京话叫攒局，比如在家里办春节联欢晚会，让家里人出节目。她想出国留学，早些年北京许多文艺策划人都有留学背景，以便接触更多的文化资源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是2010年前后，家里原本准备拿积蓄去买房，因为玖姑突然的决定，这笔钱转而用作她留学的费用。“当时觉得买房没有意义啊，何必把自己困在一个空间里面，外面广阔天地，大有作为。”在她的想象中，留学回来后，她会过上光鲜的、梦想的生活，每天攒局，出席活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑没能学喜欢的音乐剧，因为母亲觉得毕业后会找不到工作，于是她选了经济学，考入了美国加州大学戴维斯分校。选择经济学，是因为对营销感兴趣，她想知道，人们会因为什么而决定买一件东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来她发现，经济学学的不是这个，毕业后工作一样难找。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾自己的教育经历，尽管拥有优渥的教育资源，但玖姑觉得自己走了很多弯路。而有些人从小没有太多资源，却明确地知道自己想做什么，白手起家，例如乔小刀，“电焊工出身，在北京办艺术展，做民谣歌手，现在在大理做装置艺术。他是看书自学，一直朝着自己的方向走，不像我们，要先进学校，去考试，学会更多的为考试而学的东西，打压你真正想学的东西。出身在北京是我的特权，可这个环境只是在把我往平均值上拽。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕业回国后，玖姑参与过做创新教育的教辅公司，设计项目制学习课程，启发学生的创造力。她没做太长时间，因为发现国内的创新教育偏向“极端”。“一类是有钱人的特权，即使失败了，也有资源把孩子送到一个好的系统里去；一类是给底层辍学者或打工子弟提供再教育的学校。中间的人都在随大流。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jTMHHDwvhx13OLfolt3PXAd4y77UrZI3vvdkMurM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jTMHHDwvhx13OLfolt3PXAd4y77UrZI3vvdkMurM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;为了拍短视频，玖姑将妆容化成一颗心&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;主流之外&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在美国念大学时，玖姑从经济学转为心理学，并利用选修课机会学习大量感兴趣的语言学、音乐学的课程。学习之外，玖姑找到了更有趣的事情——在嬉皮士社区居住。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪70年代，加州大学戴维斯分校为了探索可持续生活方式，发起了一次社区住房实验，建了一个独特的宿舍区。玖姑第一次看见那些白色半球体的小房子就觉得很酷，房子之间分布着花园、菜地、养鸡棚，她随后申请入住，一共住了三年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社区由居住者共同塑造，每周有一次社区会议，集体讨论公共决策，遵循共识原则，“所有人都同意要做一件事情，那件事情才能做”。每个工作日晚上大家在社区中心的毛毡房里聚餐，轮流做饭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;起初面对强烈的文化差异时，玖姑有疏离感，她用一段长而缓慢的过程来适应，并希望保持更加平等的文化交互，她会在社区里发起中国文化活动，用原创诗歌朗诵（slam poetry）和脱口秀的形式介绍“我是谁”、“中国是什么”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社区第一代居住者大多是参与过嬉皮士运动的青年，到玖姑入住时，社区仍然保留了对主权文化的批判精神，反性别歧视、种族歧视等，“不一样的是没有那么大的对抗性，没有那么激进，而更加持续。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回国后，玖姑保持着对公共事务和平权议题的关心。看到一则一人大笑引发全车厢都在笑的视频后，她发起在地铁上传播笑声的行动，体验过后，她的感受是，“在想要笑的时候不再压制，大方地笑出来，我相信一定会有人回应。”有感于女性摇滚歌手少，她采访从事“非典型”职业的女性，探究职业对性别设立的壁垒。还加入女权主义小组，参与创作并演出了团队根据伊娃·恩斯勒的《阴道独白》原创的话剧《阴道之道》，创作女权相关的说唱歌曲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但玖姑的事业并不顺利，她喜欢更有创意的工作，找的都是创业型公司，例如做创客教育、开发年轻人社交社群，失败率很高，“这些公司本身盈利也不好，最后都在走下坡路。”四年多的时间里，她换了六七份工作，2019年她又一次失业后，大半年没有找到工作，无论是创业型公司还是互联网大厂，她都没被录用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摆在眼前最直接的一份工作是留学中介，一单佣金高达几万，但玖姑无法从心里认同这份工作，觉得没有意义，“它是一个有钱人的捷径，你只要有钱，就可以找人帮你写材料，可以包装自我。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并且，留学归来做留学中介，“很难说明留学有前途”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年初，玖姑找到一份在上海的工作，母亲说她是北京的叛徒，“北京那么多工作你一个都找不着吗？”玖姑把这句话改成段子，“偌大的京城就容不下你了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份工作也没能持续很久，两个月后她又被开除了。她不再找工作，自己开营销工作室，打造个人账号展示创意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了提升热度，她决定成为一个网红。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O05PXWYwVL73B42xg3PqMdxE8guoB35VPgt4PLOR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/O05PXWYwVL73B42xg3PqMdxE8guoB35VPgt4PLOR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;玖姑在线下脱口秀的舞台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;保持真实&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刚开始写文章、做视频时，玖姑发现很难吸引流量，一个视频只有几十个播放量。她转而在上海讲脱口秀，积累线下的人气。此前她一直在讲英文脱口秀，想出来的梗更贴合英语的语感和幽默，她要重新培养中文的语感，费了好一番功夫。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一次玖姑在线下的开放麦讲砸了，下台碰上李诞，问他怎么克服语言困境。李诞建议她多听郭德纲，她于是把德云社的综艺节目看了一遍，练口音，练语感，学习脱口秀的技巧，研究文字结构。她的脱口秀商演从仅有8个人看，逐渐变成30人、60人、700人，收入开始超过本职工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她把自己的失业、脱单失败和所有世俗标准里的不成功写入脱口秀段子，通过自我消解来引发观众对负面情绪的共鸣。但她自称没有为过去后悔过，如她在视频中所说，“我说这些失败的经历并不意味着我不自信，我正是因为自信，才敢把这些失败的经历都拿出来当素材。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，以脱口秀演员的身份，玖姑参与拍摄一档线下相亲纪录片。或许是为了增加冲突感，节目组给28岁的玖姑安排了一位61岁的男相亲对象老邬，比她爸年纪还大一岁。节目播出后，玖姑的片段引发了大量争议和讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打招呼时，老邬故作幽默地说“好久不见”，问她“你觉得今天黄浦江美吗？”玖姑直接回，“在这看不见江。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老邬摆出一副说教的态度，“你觉得女性要独立吗？”玖姑反问，“什么叫独立？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老邬引经据典，“你看过西蒙·波伏娃的《第二性》吗？他们在实验，如何把女性从第二性变成女性为第一性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑不接招，“我不觉得波伏娃在女权这个话题上比我更懂，我也不觉得我比她更懂。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;节目中的表现让玖姑小火了一把，她开始坚持每日更新视频，趁着时机做红账号。相亲时谈到的女权，成为她的第一个流量点。玖姑不谈理论，不讲学术，有出版社给她寄女性主义书籍，在拍短视频时，她直言自己没看，“对于女权的理解，我都是从我的生活经验中亲自提炼出来的，我也不觉得这些所谓社会地位比我高的权威，比我更懂我的女权诉求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管玖姑认为自己主张的是性别平权，甚至写过“男女平等的油腻”“爱干嘛干嘛，媚男也可以，媚女也可以”这样的段子，但是她的性别权利观点不断引来争议，有网友指责她是“女权”，也有网友骂她“媚男”。玖姑时不时地会“回击”这些评论。她发现“性别对立”的确是流量密码，有对立就会有争议，有争议评论数就会高，就容易被算法推荐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而当她使用“平权”时，却被视频平台认定为“不符合社区规范”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最吸引流量的还是追热点，“平台推流量跟热点直接相关，只要是热点，甭管你说得多差都有，有热点跟没热点是质的区别，流量至少相差10倍。”2023年9月份，玖姑所追的热点包括“秀才直播间被封”“茅台咖啡”“李佳琦直播间翻车”等等，虽然追热点，但她表示不说一句违背内心意愿的话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中老年阿姨打赏秀才，玖姑说，“咱们女人操劳了半辈子，就应该花钱让自己爽。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拉踩他人也是引流的一种方式，“可以让他们粉丝来骂你，增加我的热度。”比如玖姑拉踩过另一个网红曲曲，“她还是不如我，因为她教你取悦别人，而我教你自洽……虽然我单身没钱皮肤还差，但我很自洽，我想说什么就说什么，而且还能火。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对蹭流量、拉踩的指责，玖姑非常坦然，“对啊，那就是一种营销手段，做营销人必须要做的事儿，我还摆在明面上呢。”拉踩曲曲的那则视频封面上就写着四个大字——“拉踩同行”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“保持真实吧，我发现大家都太不真实了。”玖姑说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3van6XHDJ2rAF6FAJ3i56jKkLcrL9GsFYAI2T7v0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/3van6XHDJ2rAF6FAJ3i56jKkLcrL9GsFYAI2T7v0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;线下相亲纪录片《想要问问你敢不敢》&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;成为世界巨星&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;玖姑视频最大的特点之一是素颜出镜，并且不加滤镜。她的理由也很真实，“我可是日更啊，每天化妆30分钟多累啊，我又化不好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎每一期视频下方都有对她外貌指指点点的言论，“化上点什么吧，看不下去了。”几乎没有女性网红不化妆，这塑造了网络的审美和礼貌准则，有的网友即便不从美丑的角度去评判，也会指责玖姑对人不尊重，“公共场合，化好妆，收拾利索点，是对自己也是对别人的尊重。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑坚信这不是自己的问题，用短视频回击，“如果你觉得我不化妆就是不尊重你，那你根本就不值得被尊重，如果你看别人不顺眼还非得说出来，那是你眼睛有问题，喜欢评论别人外貌的人本身都没什么教养。”视频最后她又用自我调侃来消解严肃的气氛，“不像我，不化妆也超美丽，化完妆后还不如不化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;评论区或许还算得上是言语温和的地方，私信里的网络暴力泛滥成灾，玖姑收到过无数条带着脏话和黄色笑话的辱骂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;单从他们的名称、头像和账号内容上看，很难想象他们平时会对人如此不客气，有叫“温柔知进退”的人说“你爸妈怎么敢把你生出来啊”，有头像是学士服照片的人反复说她“丑逼”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑的自信让她没有感到受伤害，但也不想沉默，她几次发视频，主张用“网抱”抵制“网暴”，“我无法控制别人对我评论的恶意，我也可以选择不被他们影响，而是主动传播善意，把世界往我想要的样子推一把。”因为一个谈论女性主义的视频引起过评论区“性别对立”的争吵后，为了不制造对立，她用“平权”来替代“女权”，因为想做“解决问题的人”，她将视频整理出一个合集，名称是“解决男女对立”，解释关于性别和权利的偏见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑在网上的人气为她的营销工作室带来不少订单，也为她的生活增添了很多乐趣。“我在现实里特别单调，我没有办公室，没有同事，如果不上网，我很少跟人聊天，就去朋友店里坐一坐。”即便在网上会收到大量的负面言论，但在现实里，人和人之间的交流全部被压在了平静之下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玖姑觉得自己现在已经很火了，每天都有四五个人在路上认出她，每条视频的流量数据都不错。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但还不够，她的目标是火成世界巨星。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成为巨星之后呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“影响世界，去做有价值的事，消除贫困，提倡环保，给女性赋能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[运动员如何开启亚运生活？南周记者带你探营运动员村]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257474]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>