<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[李白的《立冬》，竟是冒牌诗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260295]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;November 8, 2023, the beginning of winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Weibo and other online platforms that day, a variety of Beginning of Winter posters occupied the homepages of major official accounts. There is no shortage of ancient poetry and text on these posters. Among them, the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; appears quite frequently: &quot;I am lazy to write new poems with frozen pens, and the wine is warm in the cold furnace. When I am drunk, I look at the white ink flowers and the moon, and I wonder if the village in front is full of snow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems, The situation described in this poem is indeed suitable for the beginning of winter. While retweeting the poetry copy, major official accounts also did not forget to add the poet&#39;s famous name: Li Bai. Perhaps because of these reasons, in recent years, every Beginning of Winter, this poem always &quot;stands out&quot; among other poems and has become a frequent visitor to the Beginning of Winter solar term promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as early as 2016, some Weibo netizens published a post revealing that the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; was not written by Li Bai, but a forgery. On November 7, 2018, the netizen posted on Weibo and wrote: &quot;I have been refuting rumors for three consecutive years, but I still can&#39;t withstand the official big V being so tough... becoming the most powerful official disseminator of &#39;Li Bai&#39;s &quot;Li Dong&quot; fake poem.&quot; Until the Beginning of Winter in 2023, when this netizen posted, he would still include the rumor-refuting entry &quot;Li Bai&#39;s fake poem on the Beginning of Winter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Yu Xianhao, a professor at the School of Liberal Arts at Nanjing Normal University and an expert on Li Bai, also called the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; a forgery in an interview with the &quot;Yangtze Evening News&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this fake poem by Li Bai is not an isolated case. In 2020, Chen Shangjun, a professor of the Chinese Department of Fudan University, gave an example in an interview with Southern People Weekly. The most famous pseudo-poem in Tang poetry is &quot;Qingming&quot;, which is said to be written by Du Mu. He believes that this poem was not written by Du Mu, but by Du Mu. It was written in the Song Dynasty. In the interview, he also cited the statistical results of Japanese scholar Takeo Hiraoka, saying that although the Qing Dynasty&#39;s &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; contains 49,403 poems, there are many fake poems in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/dk0EbDGV3e4H0ZBVkrZBMmNZpZsgyZQV66yC4eH2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257741&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In August 2023, in Beijing, Li Bai’s humanoid robot appeared at the 2023 World Robot Conference. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, where does the poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; come from? How are these pseudo-poems produced? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It suddenly appeared, which is very suspicious”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As an ancient poetry lover who graduated from the Chinese Department, Xu Rongyu has been reading poetry as early as four or five years ago. While paying attention to the phenomenon of pseudo-poetry, she noticed that the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; was actually even earlier. However, at that time, because she had long been accustomed to Li Bai&#39;s many fake poems, she did not think of researching them specifically. It was not until 2022 that many readers and fans asked her some questions about pseudo-poetry, and she wrote a special research article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, the most direct way to check whether a poem is a forgery is to examine the circulation process of the poem - in which book did it first appear? Has it been tampered with by later generations during its circulation? Is the text you see today the original appearance? These are important questions. &quot;For ancient works to spread, they must have a carrier.&quot; Xu Rongyu told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The existing ancient books database provides great convenience. Xu Rongyu first searched for the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; in &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and various existing collections of Li Bai&#39;s poems, but found no results. She turned her attention to the database of modern publications and found that some more rigorous books would include the sources of the poems. Some of them mentioned that the poem &quot;Lidong&quot; came from the &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot; is a printmaking collection of poetry, calligraphy and painting compiled and published by Huang Fengchi during the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty. In &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot;, the so-called poem &quot;The Beginning of Winter&quot; is actually called &quot;Winter Scenery&quot;, and the content of the third line of the poem is also slightly different. The &quot;Winter Scene&quot; version is &quot;Drunk and watching the white plum blossoms and the moonlight&quot;, while the &quot;Beijing of Winter&quot; version is &quot;Drunk and watching the whitening of the ink flowers and the moonlight&quot; - Xu Rongyu feels that although the latter looks very elegant on the surface, if you look closely at the &quot;moonlight whitening&quot;, You will find it difficult to explain the image of &quot;white flowers and moon&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot;, in addition to &quot;Winter Scene&quot;, there are also &quot;Spring Scene&quot;, &quot;Summer Scene&quot; and &quot;Autumn Scene&quot;. These four six-character poems are all falsely attributed to Li Bai. After more detailed research, Xu Rongyu discovered that there were rhyming errors in &quot;Xia Scene&quot;, while &quot;Autumn Scene&quot; had allusions that &quot;travelled&quot;, that is, the allusions used in the poem were decades later than when Li Bai was alive. year, this proves from the side that these poems were not written by Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Moreover) This poem has no carrier or record from the Tang Dynasty when Li Bai lived to the Wanli period of the Ming Dynasty, and this poem has never appeared. Then in &quot;Tang Poetry and Painting Book&quot; , it suddenly appeared, which is very suspicious.&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the media in 2018, Yu Xianhao also mentioned that there were many editions of Li Bai&#39;s poetry collection before the Ming Dynasty. There are 998 poems by Li Bai, and none of the many anthologies and engravings handed down since then include six-character poems. In 1908, the Frenchman Pelliot discovered a Tang manuscript in Dunhuang, in which the Tang Dynasty&#39;s Selected Tang Poems included many poems by Li Bai, none of which were six-character poems. After more than 800 years, so many six-character poems suddenly appeared. It is very likely that booksellers fabricated them in order to sell books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In fact, many of the works in &quot;Tang Poems and Paintings&quot; are forgeries, including those of many well-known Tang Dynasty poets such as Du Mu. They may have been made by (booksellers) by asking some people to make money, because those The poet is well-known and has high traffic. (This bookseller) is a bit like today&#39;s gunmen.&quot; Xu Rongyu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She introduced that the commercial economy of the Ming Dynasty was relatively developed, and the book engraving industry was also very developed. Engraved book printing was one of the hardest hit areas for forgery at that time. &quot;Many of the (forgeries) we see now were created by booksellers at that time in order to make profits and attract traffic. (Those celebrities) were big IPs.&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The ancients have always liked to ask others to write things&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Shangjun once said in a media interview that the main source of about a thousand Li Bai&#39;s poems currently available to the public is It is a collection of Li Bai&#39;s own essays, various poetry selections from the Tang and Song Dynasties, as well as various history books, notes, poems, books, local chronicles, etc. &quot;Some poems are 100% Li Bai&#39;s, and some poems have only a 1% chance of being Li Bai&#39;s. There are at least dozens of pseudo-poems in Li Bai&#39;s name, and each situation is different.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He gave an example of &quot;Puppet Poetry&quot; written by Li Bai: &quot;Carving wood and pulling silk to make an old man, chicken skin and white hair are the same as the real one. After a while, nothing happened, and it still seemed like a dream in life. in.&quot; In &quot;Complete Poems of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, this poem appears simultaneously under the names of Li Bai, Tang Xuanzong and Liang Kun. Among them, the title of the poem under Liang Kun&#39;s name is &quot;Old Man Ying Wood&quot;. It is now generally believed that he is the author of this poem. This poem is indeed a Tang poem, but it was not written by Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Li Bai, there are also many fake works under the names of famous poets such as Su Shi and Xin Qiji. Lin Shan, who was born in the 1980s, is also a lover of ancient poetry and has been creating in this field for about ten years. Since 2022, he has successively conducted research on thirty pseudo-poems that have been widely circulated on the Internet, including the works of famous poets such as Xin Qiji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lin Shan’s view, forgery has a foundation in the history of literature: “The ancients have always liked to ask others to write things for various reasons. Some do not want to leave their own names, and some do. My own thoughts, but I didn’t dare to say them at the time, so I asked the ancients to write them. As for the fake poems, such as forging Li Bai, it may be just to seek fame. Although I am not famous, others mistakenly think that it is really Li Bai’s work, and I feel sad in my heart. It will be very cool. There are also cases like the Ming Dynasty where people deliberately forged (to make money).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the means of forgery, Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters that a relatively common The situation is to piece it all together, such as taking apart the sentences of the couplet and putting them together with other sentences to form a poem. Another option is direct forgery. For example, someone may want to engrave a forged book of Li Bai&#39;s works. Then he may directly ask a scholar to create the book and put it under Li Bai&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two are also relatively typical means that lead to the emergence of many forgeries. As for some cases of false recognition, for example, the poet&#39;s name was mistakenly read when copying, and it has been passed down since the mistake was written; or in some movies, poems that were actually written by screenwriters were mistakenly thought to be really written by a certain poet during the dissemination process. , may also lead to forgery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary readers who do not know much about ancient poetry, it is actually very difficult to identify and verify forgeries. &quot;Ordinary readers basically can&#39;t tell it apart, unless you have some knowledge of meter. But if the ancients compiled it, it&#39;s useless if you have knowledge of meter, because the ancients were all good at writing poetry, so it would be easy for them to forge it. &quot;Lin Shan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, he feels that if some metrical knowledge can be disseminated to students in the compulsory education stage, such as the fact that flat and oblique characters cannot overlap, it will also be helpful, at least for some &quot;particularly outrageous&quot; students. Most people can spot the forgery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Rongyu also believes that it is difficult to identify fakes. “In fact, the biggest reason for the popularity of fakes is (there are problems in the communication link). People with very high influence may not necessarily have professional identification capabilities. Then you can pass the test; but people like us who can identify some things and write some popular science articles do not have such great influence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But she feels that it is still important to have a questioning spirit, at least It&#39;s possible to be closer to the truth. &quot;I think the main thing is to have a sense of questioning: If you think something is wrong, go check it out. If you search on the Internet, you may find some people&#39;s doubts, and you can get closer to the truth. The main thing is to have this kind of&quot; &quot;Ask more, think more,&quot; Xu Rongyu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Shan is a pseudonym)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[CEO被传失联，斗鱼“内忧外患”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260293]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 21:03:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 6, Douyu’s entry confirming that CEO Chen Shaojie was missing became a hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, there were rumors that Chen Shaojie was under investigation and lost contact for three weeks. The 39-year-old CEO has always kept a low profile and rarely appears in the spotlight. The last time he appeared in the public eye was the Douyu 2023 second quarter results conference call held on August 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu (DOYU.&amp;nbsp;Nasdaq), which was born in 2014, has survived the brutal fighting in the early days of China’s game live broadcast industry. It once ranked among the top two players in the industry with its ferocious playing style and Huya, which entered the game earlier than it. male. In 2019, Douyu ushered in a bright moment, following Huya to become a listed company on the US stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the past two years, large comprehensive short and medium video platforms such as Bilibili, Kuaishou, and Douyin have accelerated their attacks, and the game live broadcast track has become increasingly popular. Douyu has also experienced the loss of anchors, weak performance, frequent scandals, etc., and its prospects are not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 25, 2023, Douyu received a compliance warning from the Nasdaq Listing Qualification Department, stating that its closing price had been lower than US$1/share for 30 consecutive trading days and did not meet the compliance requirements. Nasdaq&#39;s minimum share price requirements. Douyu must maintain the closing price of its stock at no less than $1 per share for at least ten consecutive trading days within 180 days, or before April 22, 2024, in order to return to compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Echoing Douyu’s unpredictable prospects, there is also the whereabouts of CEO Chen Shaojie. Douyu told Southern Weekend reporters that Douyu has no official response to this news and the company is currently operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 8, Douyu closed at US$0.82 per share, a decrease of 1.19%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;A person who likes adventure and licks blood&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1984, Chen Shaojie was born in Jinan, Shandong. Looking at his life experience: addicted to games, majoring in computer science, dropping out of college, and starting a business continuously, Chen Shaojie has gathered many characteristics of the trendsetters in the Internet era and successfully turned his hobby into a career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Shaojie himself once said bluntly in a Douyu live broadcast that he had a high school degree and dropped out of college after one year. He believes that spending four years studying does not necessarily mean you have a deep understanding of the Internet. He compared the Three Kingdoms and said that one&#39;s background is not the most important. &quot;Liu Bei originally sold straw mats, Guan Yu sold dates, and Zhang Fei slaughtered pigs. As their respective With their growth, they have become the most awesome generals.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2009, Chen Shaojie and his partner Zhang Wenming sold their first entrepreneurial project, the &quot;Master&quot; battle game platform, to Shanda Games, and Chen became the general manager of Shanda Winger Wuhan Company. The function of the leader is to realize online battles in stand-alone games. Geek Park once reported that Leader is a successful product. One year after it was launched, it has registered a total of 450,000 people and has more than 200,000 daily active users. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Chen Shaojie, who made his first pot of gold, acquired the two-dimensional video website AcFun (referred to as Station A) for about 4 million yuan, and launched the &quot;Shengfang Broadcasting&quot; live broadcast channel. In January 2014, Chen Shaojie independent &quot;Shengbangshu&quot; into a game live broadcast platform with barrage function - &quot;Douyu TV&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following years, China’s game live broadcast industry entered an explosive period. In May 2014, Zhanqi Live, backed by the state-owned enterprise Zheshu Culture (600633.SH), was launched. In November of that year, YY spun off its game live streaming business and established Huya Live. In 2015, Longzhu Live and Wang Sicong’s Panda TV were established. In 2016, NetEase and Tencent successively launched CC Live and Penguin Esports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu has been the darling of capital since its appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qichacha shows that Aofei Entertainment (002292.SZ) made an angel round investment of RMB 20 million in Douyu just after its establishment in 2014. In the same year, Sequoia Capital invested another US$20 million in Series A financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2016, Douyu’s Series B financing was led by Tencent, which invested RMB 400 million, followed by Nanshan Capital and Tianyu Digital (002354.SZ), with the total investment scale reaching US$100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Series C financing five months later, Phoenix Capital and Tencent led the investment, with participation from many institutions. Douyu finally raised 1.5 billion yuan. Before going public in 2019, Douyu received financing every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu, who is backed by financing, plays fiercely, which is also related to Chen Shaojie’s personal character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been media reports that Douyu insiders evaluated Chen Shaojie as &quot;a person who likes taking risks and licks blood at the edge of a knife.&quot; Douyu once poached six anchors from the industry within a month, with a total fee of more than 60 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Feng, founder of YY Game Live, once wrote an article analyzing why Douyu was able to overtake Huya in its early stages. “A big reason for the rise of Douyu is that we spent huge sums of money to sign the top anchors in YY and the industry from the beginning.” Before Douyu, YY game live broadcasts could be relatively controlled by controlling traffic and income distribution. Live anchor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, game anchors are different from entertainment anchors. The former has external effects, does not rely on live broadcast platforms, and has other opportunities to become Internet celebrities (such as e-sports events, Youku game channels, Weibo etc.), has the ability to bring its own fans, and can also bring fans to migrate, so YY Game Live has not signed a contract with the head anchor. This gave Douyu an opportunity to directly use the signing fee instead of the share to obtain top anchors, which became the core reason why Douyu could overtake Huya. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the game live streaming industry went through a period of consolidation after a big wave, forming a &quot;fish and tooth confrontation&quot; pattern in the first echelon. Douyu and Huya shared most of the game live streaming market share. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The problem of profitability is difficult to solve&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On July 17, 2019, Douyu was listed on Nasdaq at an issue price of US$11.5 per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But its stock price only experienced a short period of sustained growth during the epidemic. On February 16, 2021, Douyu once reached an intraday high of US$20.54 per share, and then plummeted to less than US$1 per share now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering 2021, Douyu’s quarterly revenue, except for the fourth quarter of that year, has been negative growth. According to its 2022 financial report, Douyu’s revenue growth relies heavily on paying users and revenue per paying user. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Douyu is losing users. Wind data shows that in the second quarter of 2023, the number of quarterly paying users of Douyu was 4 million, a year-on-year decrease of 39.39%. The number of monthly active users was 50.3 million, a year-on-year decrease of 9.69%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Douyu’s current revenue still mainly comes from live broadcasts and advertising, and its attractiveness to advertisers continues to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2020 to 2022, Douyu’s live broadcast revenue was 8.8522 billion yuan, 8.5966 billion yuan and 6.7973 billion yuan, accounting for 92.2%, 93.8% and 95.6% of the total revenue in the same period respectively. Douyu&#39;s advertising sales revenue was 645.2 million yuan, 464.9 million yuan and 190.3 million yuan, accounting for 6.7%, 5.1% and 2.7% of the total revenue in the same period respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although revenue continues to decline, it will be profitable for two consecutive quarters in 2023. In the second quarter of 2023, Douyu’s net profit was 6.8 million yuan, and the net loss in the same period of 2022 was 38.8 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Douyu’s turnaround from losses to profits is the result of cost reduction and efficiency increase.” Ding Daoshi, a senior Internet observer, told Southern Weekend reporters that he does not think this is a healthy way to make money, but Expressing understanding, &quot;This is also a helpless strategy in extraordinary times.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second quarter of 2023, Douyu’s expenses were 196 million yuan, a decrease of 42% from 340 million yuan in the same period last year. Among them, sales and marketing expenses decreased by 48% compared with the same period last year, research and development expenses decreased by 30.2%, and general and administrative expenses decreased by 48.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sluggish performance of Douyu is due, on the one hand, to the impact of short video platforms on traditional live broadcast platforms; on the other hand, it is also due to the impact of leading video platforms such as Bilibili, Douyin, and Kuaishou on the gaming field. Strong preemption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2019, Station B spent 800 million yuan to defeat domestic live broadcast platforms such as Kuaishou, Douyu, and Huya, and won the exclusive live broadcast of the League of Legends (LOL) Global Finals (S Competition) in China for three years. copyright. In July of the same year, Kuaishou launched the “Million Game Creator Support Plan” and frequently held various competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the unfavorable situation, in July 2020, Tencent tried to lead the merger of Douyu and Huya, but was later stopped by the regulatory agency on antitrust grounds in accordance with the law. As of March 31, 2023, Tencent held 46.7% of Huya’s shares and 37.7% of Douyu’s shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Game industry analyst Zhang Shule told Southern Weekend reporters that although Douyu and Huya are survivors of the game live broadcast melee, the failure of the merger means that both have lost an opportunity to integrate resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Douyu and Huya continue to experience brain drain. In August 2023, Xuxu Baobao, the head anchor who had been live broadcasting on Douyu for 5 years, announced that he would switch to Douyin. In March before this, Huya outdoor anchor Mu Yingying also joined Douyin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Anchors are like migratory birds, they go wherever it’s warm.” Zhang Shule said that anchors have no loyalty to the platform and are now jealous of selling products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ding Daoshi’s view, Douyu and Huya have few moats. In their early years, they relied on the Tencent system and related popular e-sports live broadcasts to rise. In recent years, Bilibili, Douyin, Kuaishou, and even video accounts can also conduct game live broadcasts. “There are so many people sharing the cake, but the growth rate of the cake is obviously not synchronized.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that in this context, traditional e-sports live broadcast platforms represented by Douyu and Huya are in these A year-on-year decline is inevitable and the downward trend will continue. They are all looking for new growth paths outside of games, such as sports live broadcasts, but the results will take time to be verified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shule said bluntly that the overall revenue scenario of Douyu game live broadcasts and short videos is single. Facing the attack of other pan-entertainment platforms, Douyu lacks more effective checks and balances besides relying on Tencent. &quot;The biggest pain point is Profitability is still a problem.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that Douyu’s only moat is Tencent, one of the three giant domestic game companies (the other two are NetEase and MiHoYo). Tencent has a huge control over the field of e-sports, and can use IP licensing and e-sports event licensing to reserve some private space for Douyu. However, opponents can still look for game and e-sports cooperation outside the Tencent system, so the moat is not wide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shule said that the plight of Douyu and Huya is almost the same, but now under the arrangement of Tencent, the two companies cannot merge and try and make mistakes at different times in order to find a way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his opinion, Douyu’s gaming attributes are too strong, and the user portraits in the outdoor, appearance, and two-dimensional areas highly overlap with the gaming area. The real possible direction for Douyu to get out of trouble may be to combine new profit models in e-sports events that are also difficult to make profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Ten Thousands of People Gather to Gamble”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a leading game live broadcast platform, Douyu has frequently received negative news about pornography, vulgarity, and suspected gambling in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, the official blog of the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League published an article saying that the live broadcast room of Douyu anchor &quot;彡彡九屋&quot; (hereinafter referred to as 339) is suspected of hosting tens of thousands of people for gambling, and the daily turnover can reach several million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, the official blog of China Youth Network’s short video stated that the Douyu anchor “Changsha Village Death Squadron” is the “biggest casino in Douyu” and a lottery suspected of gathering gambling will be opened at 10 o’clock every night. , thus forming the public codename &quot;Ten Points Economic Lessons&quot;. In 2020, its turnover was as high as 177 million yuan, and its daily turnover was as high as 13 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, &quot;彡彡九Outdoor&quot; will be characterized as gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sichuan Legal News, 339 member Fu Moulong and three other people &quot;tried to turn their bicycles into motorcycles&quot; through &quot;one card application for 50,000 yuan to take home&quot; between March 2017 and September 2020. &quot;A large number of inflammatory words such as &quot;Encourage live broadcast room viewers to participate in the lottery, and push lottery time and amount information to other people who did not participate in the live broadcast through platforms, WeChat groups, etc., resulting in a large number of people entering the live broadcast room during the live lottery period and paying.&quot; Apply for a card&quot;, swipe virtual gifts, etc. to participate in the lottery. After the draw, winning cash will be distributed to the winners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to the time of their arrest, Fu Moulong and others had organized a total of 4,267 draws (times), with more than 4.42 million people participating, and gambling funds of nearly 120 million yuan. After trial, the Dujiangyan Court held that the actions of the three people constituted the crime of opening a casino, and they were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment ranging from six to three years, and were also fined. This case is also the first gambling case involving a live broadcast platform in the country supervised and handled by the Ministry of Public Security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2021, Qian Xiaojia, the first brother of the former Douyu outdoor anchor, revealed in an interview that although gambling-related activities in 339 and other live broadcast rooms are not officially held by Douyu, the platform is not unaware of it. There will even be internal guidance. In the second half of 2019, Qian Xiaojia was banned by Douyu for violating regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 30, 2023, the Cyberspace Administration of China&#39;s WeChat public account &quot;CyberChina&quot; released the national cyberspace administrative law enforcement and supervision situation in the first quarter of 2023, stating that it will continue to promote the &quot;Qingming&quot; series of special actions , resolutely investigate and deal with all kinds of online illegal activities in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It mentioned that Internet platforms such as Baidu, Sina Weibo, Douyu, and Douban failed to fulfill their main responsibilities and failed to manage the information released by their users, resulting in obscenity, feudal superstition, and solicitation of prostitution. Regarding the spread of harmful information on the Internet such as prostitution, gambling, and loan sharking, the Cyberspace Administration of China instructs the local Cyberspace Administration to conduct interviews, order rectifications, and carry out punitive measures in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 8, &quot;CyberChina&quot; issued another article stating that in response to serious ecological problems such as pornography and vulgarity on the Douyu platform, the Cyberspace Administration of China directed the Cyberspace Administration of Hubei Province to send a working group to station Douyu platform launched a one-month centralized rectification supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Shule’s view, China’s live broadcast craze originated from game live broadcasts. However, game live broadcasts failed to break the barriers of consumption scenarios and failed to become the leader in the trend. It was not until the emergence of live broadcasts to bring goods. A new situation has opened up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The current game live broadcast platform is also looking for its own &#39;live broadcast delivery&#39;, but through crazy trial and error, many problems have arisen.&quot; Zhang Shule said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[100万？300万？想不上班到底要存多少钱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260278]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen in Jiangxi shared his story. She and her husband spent 7 years saving 1 million yuan. After part of it was used to buy a house, the remaining 500,000 yuan was deposited in the bank. Now the monthly living costs can be covered by interest alone. She also shared a series of ways to save money, such as cooking at home for many years, not drinking coffee outside, only buying discounted clothes, taking her children to sunbathe instead of taking interest classes, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the authenticity of this experience has not been verified, in February this year, a Shanghai couple did decide to &quot;retire&quot; with a deposit of 3 million yuan. This news sparked widespread discussion at the time. Just recently, Professor Chen Bingzheng from the Department of Finance at the School of Economics and Management of Tsinghua University was interviewed by CCTV Finance. He mentioned that “a survey found that over 70% of those born after 90 start to think about pension issues.” He said that it is too late to start thinking about pension issues at the age of 35. From work After receiving your first month’s salary, you should start saving for retirement in a planned way. It can be seen that young people’s anxiety about saving money for retirement is not an idle complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much savings do you think you need to retire from the workplace with peace of mind? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[董明珠称孟羽童兼职接广告不合规：非工作时间能否干副业？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260289]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 20:20:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In May this year, Dong Mingzhu’s secretary Meng Yutong resigned, triggering various speculations and discussions. Recently, in an interview with Guangdong Satellite TV&#39;s &quot;Financial Eyes&quot;, Dong Mingzhu responded publicly to the matter for the first time: Internet celebrities do not judge people&#39;s quality, and it is illegal for people to advertise outside Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Dong Mingzhu said Meng Yutong’s part-time job accepting advertisements was illegal” was once a hot search topic. According to a report by the Shanghai Securities News on May 16, the reason for Meng Yutong&#39;s resignation was that he &quot;often missed work to participate in business activities and take on private work&quot; during his time at the company. After the company talked to him, he still carried out related activities without improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure, Meng Yutong did receive advertisements on social media platforms. In the short videos on his Xiaohongshu account, he appeared many times selling clothing, beauty products, electronic products and household goods. In the &quot;Good Things Pocket&quot; column, there are 65 notes included, none of which have anything to do with Gree Electric products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I originally thought that the rights and wrongs of this incident were very clear. However, many netizens believe that the contract Meng Yutong signed with Gree is a labor contract, not an endorsement contract. The time outside the eight hours is her own. Of course, she has the right to control how much she earns through endorsements and part-time advertising. Money is a reflection of her ability. This has also led to some discussions: Is it appropriate for the company to restrict employees from doing side jobs? If the income from your main job is not as good as your side job, will you leave your job? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this point of view and these discussions? First of all, it must be said unequivocally that it is not appropriate to use Meng Yutong&#39;s case to demonstrate the rationality of employees taking part-time jobs or doing side jobs outside of their own jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Yutong did graduate from a prestigious university, has a sweet appearance, and has good looks, but these qualities are not sufficient or necessary to become an Internet celebrity. There are a lot of people with these qualities, but only a few lucky ones are successful. The track for Internet celebrities is very crowded and very winding. If someone says that Meng Yutong’s ability to become an Internet celebrity depends entirely or mainly on his personal abilities, that is undoubtedly not objective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that Meng Yutong became an Internet celebrity mainly due to Dong Mingzhu’s efforts on top of his buildable personal qualities. Dong Mingzhu made her his secretary, and announced that he would train her to be his successor and take her to various occasions. Through the event, many hot searches and topics were created, bringing her countless traffic. Dong Mingzhu is working hard to make her the first person to bring goods to Gree live broadcast. In this sense, Meng Yutong, who has become an Internet celebrity, is an asset of Gree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Dong Mingzhu and Gree are obviously old-school, hoping that gentlemen&#39;s agreement and personal consciousness will have enough behavioral constraints on Meng Yutong, rather than &quot;first Before the company invests resources in an individual, it ensures and locks in potential future earnings, and limits and eliminates the risk of breach of trust of a sparrow that turns into a phoenix and then soars into the sky and escapes control. That is, the contract stipulates the rights and obligations of both parties and improves the The cost of breach of trust should be taken into account before you can safely invest in betting and package marketing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, when it was discovered that Meng Yutong was using the Internet celebrity status created by the company to do private work, Dong Mingzhu and Gree did not immediately send a clear and strong signal saying &quot;this is not acceptable&quot;, but The reason is that there was no timely intervention or the intensity of the intervention was not enough. The mentality may be that the matter can be solved quietly internally, through reasoning and persuasion, so as to prevent the matter from turning into a negative incident or scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if Meng Yutong had been given a clear choice the first time he did private work, either to stop and hand over the proceeds from his private work, or to leave, the problem might have been solved long ago. When Meng Yutong took on more and more private jobs and his income outside of work became higher and higher, it became difficult for him to stop. At a certain stage, Dong Mingzhu could no longer tolerate it and had to resolve it through a final showdown, which brought us to the scene in May this year. Therefore, if there is something wrong with Dong Mingzhu and Gree, it is that they made the above two mistakes one after another. But this does not disprove that it is in line with professional ethics for Meng Yutong to use the Internet celebrity status created by the company to do private work and make big money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is no simple answer to whether employees can work part-time or do side jobs outside of their regular jobs, and it needs to be analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, it depends on whether there are express provisions on this in the labor contract or other types of contracts signed with the company or organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, units within the system generally have some clear restrictions on employees&#39; part-time work, and will regularly conduct inspections on employees in this regard, allowing employees to declare on their own. Of course you can lie or conceal the situation, but if your employer finds out, you will inevitably be punished or even lose your job. In addition, well-regulated companies generally prohibit employees from receiving remuneration from competitors, suppliers or customers. This not only potentially harms the company&#39;s interests, but may also lead to criminal investigation in serious cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, it depends on the nature of your part-time job or side job, and whether there is any conflict of interest with your work in the unit and the business of the unit. You are a salesperson and have accumulated a lot of customer resources. At a certain stage, if you set up a business and go it alone, the company may not be able to do anything to you. But if you are receiving a salary from the company while secretly setting up a business with a similar nature to the company, A company that imports customer resources into its own company is undoubtedly against professional ethics, and the company may not let it go if it finds out. Or if you are a technical R&amp;D personnel and you resell the code you wrote in the company to a competing company or other companies, or take work from a competing company, this will also damage the company&#39;s rights and interests and seriously violate professional ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, &quot;Besides the eight-hour working time, it is all your own time, you can do whatever you want.&quot; This statement must be at least restricted by the above two rules. In the final analysis, it means respecting the contract and Observe professional ethics. As long as it does not violate the contract and company regulations, does not harm the company&#39;s rights and interests, has no conflict of interest with the company, and does not affect the main job, generally speaking, the company has no objection to individuals doing side jobs and part-time jobs to increase their income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 20:25:58 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[桐子故事丨峡河西流去]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/NutlzMHR2UbsNNB6zpzzOTaygMtBDmbXoFeHEPjT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/NutlzMHR2UbsNNB6zpzzOTaygMtBDmbXoFeHEPjT . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tongzi flowers bloom. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;一&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Xiahe to Luanzhuang, we have to cross three ridges. It&#39;s not the three ridge heads, it&#39;s the third ridge head counting from Taoping. Taoping has now been transformed from a township into an administrative village. It is where Santiao Ridge originates and Yitiao Ridge begins. Going further south is the Funiu Mountains and then enters Nanyang. It is not clear why it is called Santiaoling instead of Sandaoling or something else. Indeed, the word &quot;Tiao&quot; is a bit strange, as if it is a ridge rather than a mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The side of Santiao Ridge near Luanzhuang is a ten-mile downhill slope. At the bottom of the slope is the Bada River. After crossing the river and going five miles eastward, you will reach Luanzhuang Town. Luanzhuang Town has been the capital of Luanzhuang since the Republic of China, the so-called economic, cultural, transportation and power center. The ancient town that was more than a hundred years old now has no trace of the past. Instead, there are concrete buildings rising from the ground on both sides of the Luanzhuang River, which is sometimes dirty and sometimes clear. Everything sold on the street is modern. For example, household appliances used for heating in winter are electric braziers instead of charcoal. Even the dogs running on the street have many fashionable hair styles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the side of the ten-mile downhill road, there are all tung trees. Of course, that was a scene more than thirty years ago. Nowadays, it is all pine trees and arrowgrass. The pine trees are domineering, and the arrowgrass is not a fuel-efficient lamp. With them, there is no one else. There are only a few tung trees, and the old-fashioned people have nowhere to stand. In today&#39;s spring and summer, the mountains are green and interspersed with wild flowers of strange colors. Walking through this place gives people the excitement and satisfaction of returning home in rich clothes. In winter, half of the mountains are green and half are withered and yellow, like a failed oil painting. The economy of small places is not good, so traffic management personnel hide in those curves, use the terrain and vegetation to catch illegal motorcycles, and fine them to generate revenue. They catch them accurately. Unless there is an urgent matter, people rarely ride there.要过往，也会选择早晨或晚上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十多年前，我在峦庄镇读初中。那时候大部分同学都不怎么爱学习，上学似乎只是为了完成打发少年光阴的任务。比较起来，我算是较爱学习的一个，但和那些烧脑的文字数字比较起来，我还是更爱那些与成绩无关的东西一些，比如桐子，从桐子花到桐籽都爱，爱得也没啥道理，就是觉得好，觉得它们是我的，我也是它们的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花三月开，这时候很多花已经收尾，桃花、杏花、梨花海棠花们全都香消玉殒了，而更多的夏花们还没有到来。天已经很暖和了，这时候，天突然冷一场，甚至还会下一场雪来，待气温再暖和时，桐子花就开了。大人说，桐花还要寒风冻。桐子花算不上好看，也不难看，朵算不上大，也不小，但它的香气不一样，是一种清香，气味像极了它的颜色和形状：白色花瓣镶嵌着淡红色的蕊，每一朵每一枝都相似，像双胞胎姐妹。桐子花一开一坡，浩浩荡荡，密实得不见其它。远远看，一坡的花，像话痨，谁也插不上嘴，不像别的花，有红有绿有空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候孩子多，如果上学都赶一块儿了，从前到后要排好长的队伍。前面进了桐花阵，后面还在岭那边，前面过了八岔河，后面还在花阵里。上学的人每人提一只网兜，兜里白馍黑馍杂面馍一目了然。女孩子爱虚荣，在馍外面遮一层报纸，只能看见祖国欣欣向荣的景象，看不见馍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花有一个用处，治烫伤。八岔河口，有一个还俗的老道士，很老很老了，弯了腰，须发尽白。他经常上岭来收集凋落的桐子花。凋落的桐子花铺满了一地，像树头一样密实，奇怪的是树上并不见减少，仿佛它们一边凋落一边在生长。他背一只编织口袋，一收集一袋子落花。也不知道他拿回去怎么处理的，掺了别的什么材料，调成膏，装在大大小小的瓶子里，涂在伤者烫伤上，百医百效，几乎不留疤。也不知道哪一年，老道士死了，治烫伤的方子就一同带走了。他没儿没女，传也没人传，再说，治烫伤也糊不了口，一年到头，没有几个烫伤的。他也不靠这个吃饭。再有烫伤的，只能去医院，花好多钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐子花开过两个月，桐子出来了，个个青嫩得要滴水，但其实都坚硬得砸不开。男孩子用它互掷打仗，脑袋上一砸一个包。用石头砸开来，桐籽白白胖胖挤在一块，嚼在嘴里很香，比核桃仁都好吃，但过一会儿头疼、恶心。去了桐籽的壳晒干了是烧火的好材料，冬天正好烧炕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学校食堂只有一种饭，玉米糁糊汤，玉米糁急火慢火熬成的粥，且只有早中两餐，晚上只能吃自带的馍或者干熬到天亮。就饭的菜就显得很重要，要有油水，可大部分没有油水，没有油水也行，有花样也行，但花样也少，就是一桶蒜汁调酸菜，且量也有限，要合理分配。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金锁家门前有一棵漆树，三丈多高，合抱粗，这么大的漆树，不多见。夏天遮天蔽日，到了秋天，漆籽打下来能熬一大盆漆籽油。漆籽油也是食用油的一种，也能点灯，送亡人的路上，点长明灯。但是树太老了，半荣半枯，树杆有一半已经朽了。有一年夏天，下过一场雨，天晴后枯的那边长出一大朵树菇来，颜色又红又黄，像西天一朵火烧云落了下来。漆树菇是上好的树菇一种，鲜嫩鲜美，能上席面。我和金锁把它掰下来，满满一盆，但他家里没有油，翻遍了柜子和墙角也找不到。我说，有办法，去弄桐子炼油。我们上了三条岭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐籽炼油不难。我们摘了一筐桐果，把它砸开，把桐籽抠出来，用蒜臼捣碎了，放进锅里熬，去了渣，竟炼了一碗油。听大人说过，不论什么油，只要放了毒就没事了。桐籽在锅里熬，熬掉了水汽，放了烟，就算放毒了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我俩上吐下泻了一晚上，金锁他爹给我们灌了洗衣粉水，第二天才停下来。也幸亏那天吃得不多，油也放得少。我俩三天没上学，那一年，我俩都初三。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若干年后，金锁上了大学，我上了矿山，从此命运分道扬镳。我没有他的电话，他没有我的联系渠道，从他爹妈死了后，我们彼此更加一无所知，唯一隐约知道的是，他没工作几年就去了欧洲，娶妻安家，他乡变作故乡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三条岭上仅剩的桐子有些年景还会开几枝，零星的桐花躲在万绿丛中，比大片绵延的桐花更好看，一点也不显得孤独。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;桐果通常在十月中下旬成熟，果子由青绿变为淡红，最后变成黑褐色，就可以采收了。桐果的蒂很结实，和枝头连接得很紧密，不像核桃和板栗这些果子容易敲打下来，釆收桐子是非常缓慢辛苦的活，枝头不高的话，女人和孩子用手摘反倒是最快的。男人们爬上树，用竹竿敲打，把树头枝杈棒打成了披发鬼，总有几个桐果纹丝不动，最后只有任它留到来年。桐子身沉，运输也是件费力的事，一个好劳力，背一筐，吃力得弯腰驼背气喘吁吁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;碓的用途十分广泛，几乎任何有关破碎的活都可以用捣的方法解决。把桐果彻底晾晒干了，倒进碓窝里捣，是最有效的出桐米的方法，这项工作一般由妇女和孩子完成。处理干净的桐米又白又嫩，像羊脂似的。我们这些孩子，夹在其中忙前忙后，趁人不备，丢一粒在嘴里，又被大人给抠出来，哇哇吐了一地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐油就是桐籽榨的油，榨桐油的流程和榨花生油差不多。我小时候好事，一身猴气，曾多次参与大人们的榨油劳动，繁琐的细节都不记得了，只记得桐油的透明纯净，那淡黄的颜色找不到对应参照的东西，所以无法描述，用一物去形容和说明另一物，这古老的、无所不能的语言方式在桐油面前彻底失效了。榨出来的桐油装在盆盆钵钵里，有外地人来收购，虽说卖不了多少钱，油盐酱醋钱有了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桐油是最好的漆染家具的漆物，林师傅是最好的漆匠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一般说来，木匠也是漆匠，漆匠也是木匠，很少见谁家请了木匠，打好了家具又请漆匠的。木匠不一定多才，但一定多艺，否则，没法踩百家门头，只有林师傅，偏偏只会漆工，木匠的活一窍不通，但因为手艺太好，哪怕是身怀独技，仍然不愁饭吃。也因为手艺太好，弄得同行常常没了活路，让人慕又招人恨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅也不是当地人，有说是河南的，有说是湖北的，也有说是四川的，他自己不说，别人当然只是乱猜。人们的根据是他的口音，但出门久了的人，吃四方饭，应八方景，乡音早已无存，留下的是两掺三掺的杂糅音腔。林师傅来到峡河时，四十岁了，手艺不是在峡河学的，是从远处带来的，他一到来就是大师傅。他自己说是家传，这一说法大家自然是信的，好手艺大多来自家传。四十岁的林师傅到了峡河，四十一上就娶到了女人，自然也是得益于他的好手艺。女人小他十七八岁，还是个闺女，叫刘兰花。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花她爹是个席匠，一辈子织苇席。出门织，也在自己家里织，需要的人上门来买，或用东西交换。刘席匠的席匠生涯就这两个方式，一半出外上门，一半家庭作坊。刘席匠老了的时候，就不出门了，房后山上养了一片芦苇园子，五六亩，方圆几十里的人家用席也够了。刘席匠织了一辈子席，手里也攒了点钱，在方圆算殷实人家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早些年，人都穷，置不起棺材，大多数人死了，用苇席一卷就入了土，那苇席自然也是出自刘席匠的手。刘席匠东山织到西山，白天织到晚上，织出的席，一半用来晒粮，一半用来卷人。后来，人们日子过得宽松些了，有人开始使用棺板，当然，芦席这时也没有缺席入土为安的事业，再后来，全都改用棺板了，就没苇席什么事了。有了星星想月亮，这时候，又有人开始给棺材上油漆，要让死者在地下长眠得更安然、长久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘席匠织了一辈子席，看到亲手织的席卷了数不清的人，但从内心里，他对席卷人入土的方式是不认可的，他觉得那才真叫草菅人命。同样的，他对后来的人们给棺材刷满从街上买来的化学油漆也深恶痛绝，那玩意不但不防腐，那气味怎么让人安宁？总之，人这一辈子太忙，没睡过好觉，走了，到了另一个世界，一定得睡安稳些踏实些。刘席匠的最大理想，是有一口桐油棺材。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个理想，林师傅帮他实现了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那一天，我们全村老少见证了桐油由生油变熟油的伟大又壮观的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅在刘席匠家的院子里砌了一只齐腰高的土灶台，灶上架起一只大铁锅，用柞木柴火在下面猛烧；先将从河里挑选来的光净石子放在锅中炒，石子炒烫后，倒入生桐油，倒多少，肯定有讲究，林师傅只是倒，嘴里不说。接着锅里翻江倒海，随着温度越升越高，桐油里的水汽逐渐蒸发掉了。空气里有了香味，香味铺天盖地，像一个大毯子蒙住了整个院子，但那个香，是谁也没有闻过的香，浓烈放荡，说不出来是好是坏。此时，大家看到锅中的桐油泛起油花。林师傅快速加入了一铲粉状东西，一会儿，桐油面上泛起一层白色的泡沫，并冒出浓浓的黄烟。林师傅指挥一个青年用木棒奋力搅拌，泡沫迅速地与桐油密合，这时候烟色由黄转黑，浓烟直冲天上，渐渐消散。林师傅用木棍挑出一缕儿桐油，滴在石头上，用手指蘸着桐油往上拉长，拉出很长的细丝来。林师傅命人迅速浇灭锅下的火，大喊一声:成了！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观看的人好奇又紧张，又不得要领，像做了一场梦。觉得林师傅真神，才知道原来桐油可以这么熬成好东西，以前总是把桐油生生卖掉，好可惜。若干年过去，当熬桐油不再是独门绝技，大家才知道，那粉状的东西是土子粉和樟丹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经熟桐油由外到里刷过三遍的柏木棺板，简直像一只多棱的镜子，映照出一群人怪异好奇的嘴脸，映照出天上的太阳和游荡的云彩。为证明桐油的功效，林师傅往棺里倒了一桶水，倒进去时满满一桶，舀出来一桶满满，不多不少。刘席匠说，这狗日的桐油，怕能护人身子一千年！ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;三&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;林师傅和刘兰花生了一个女儿，叫林萍儿。刘兰花一副好身段，两扇好屁股，像一团棉花，要多饱满有多饱满，生多少都不是问题，但不敢生，政策紧，根本承受不起罚款。林师傅走的那年，林萍儿十三岁，还在读初中。满打满算下来，刘兰花和林师傅做了十四年夫妻。对林师傅的走，刘兰花是真的舍不得。下葬的那天，天下着雨，刘兰花从头到脚都湿透了，有人说是雨浇的，有人说是泪浇的，其实两个都是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;满打满算，林师傅在峡河生活了十四年，桐油匠职业生涯十四年，不算长，也不算短，但经他使用过的桐油，刷过的家具，不知道用什么才能计量清楚。他传下的手艺，他有意无意带动的行业，在他离开五年后也戛然而止，按新的经济发展要求，乡村产业转型，上面要求弃桐子改播松树。一种产业、一个行业随着世事的转腾而终于凋落、寂灭了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一年的有一天，林师傅送林萍儿上学去，学校在镇上，星期六接回来，星期天送到校。他骑一辆大杠，车头上挂着书包和干粮袋子，车后座上载着女儿。车下三条岭，桐子花正开，路里的花，路外的花，头连着尾，尾连着头，人车在花中穿行，头上的天，鼻孔里的花香，真叫人快乐啊。林师傅想，今年又是好收成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车到二道盘，那里有一处泉眼，四季清水汩汨，又甘又甜。来往的人、雀鸟、小动物都在这里饮水、歇脚。因为潭在低处，人需要双腿跪下，伸长脖子才能饮到水。有一个传说，说泉眼里有一条鱼精，受人的跪拜时间久了，已经得道，有时晚上会出来清理水潭的脏物，让泉永远清清净净，但谁也没有见过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅有些饿了，他把一只饼分两半，自己一半女儿一半，就着泉水吃起来。在吞第二口时，他感到饼在喉咙里卡住了，上不上，下不下。他掬起一捧水，灌下去，也不管用。他知道这是怎么回事，他想起母亲也是这样的情形，这样卡了几年，走了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅请匠人给自己打的棺是一口泡桐木棺，泡桐木材质松软，不经腐，但好处是得来全不费工夫，一排大树就长在院子边，就地取材。刘兰花说，还早呢，让树再长几年。林师傅说，不早了，早晚都得准备。刘兰花说，也给我备一口。林师傅说，你的还早，让树再长几年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅给自己熬桐油的壮观场面和十四年前在刘席匠院子第一次熬桐油的场面如出一辙，围观者众多，帮忙的也多。虽然这时候这门技术早已不是秘密。在最后退去锅底的柴火时，刘兰花有些慌张，把锅底打了个洞，熬成的桐油倾泻而下，虽然众人奋力抢救，熬成的晶亮的好东西只抢救出三分之一，漏掉的部分化作了一阵冲天大火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅的棺板刷到一半，没有桐油了，另一半，只好去街上买来一桶洋漆完成。林师傅叹口气，说，这都是命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林师傅走了两年后，有一天，刘兰花收到一封信，寄件地址不详，寄件人不详。收信人姓名是林懿德，刘兰花不认得名字里的中间那个字，问女儿林萍儿，林萍儿这时已上了高中，没有不认识的字，说那个字读yì。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花开始以为寄信人把地址和名字写错了，想退回去，丈夫的名字叫林建业，从来没有听说过这个怪怪的名字。乡邮寄员说，没有错，邮政编码都是对的，再说，谁知道往哪里退，退给谁？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘兰花就拆开信读了，说完，才知道寄信的人没有寄错地址和收信人。她读完了信，悄悄抹了一阵泪，就随手把信丟进锅洞里烧了，烧尽的信没有成灰，保持着纸的形状，从灶洞飘出来，飞出了院子，在空中飘飘荡荡。刘兰花心里说，你就落下来吧，我读过了，就是你读过了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林萍儿从房里拿着一件衣服出来，问写的啥？刘兰花说，没写啥，是有人把信寄错地方了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[东西方贵族是如何消亡的？从贵族到精英是身份政治的式微]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260200]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一位自称是“英国礼仪专家”的博主Lucy Challenger，在TikTok上发布了一条视频，教网友如何在正式场合用刀叉吃米饭。她认为在西方环境中，不应该用手、勺子或筷子吃米饭，而应该用餐刀把米饭推到叉子背面顶端处，然后优雅地放进嘴里，这样可以显得更有教养和风度。这一“贵族风”的视频引发各种调侃与群嘲。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多国人也喜欢强调贵族概念，什么房中贵族、车中贵族、服饰品牌贵族……甚至前几天，在建材商店里还看到了乳胶漆中的“贵族”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;言必称贵族，其实多是消费妄想症。贵族这个社会群体，在东、西方社会中，都已经死亡，或接近于死亡。大致了解下东、西方社会的贵族诞生、发展、衰落、消亡过程，也是蛮有意思的历史回顾之旅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在远古的东、西方社会，贵族几乎同时代诞生于文明初期。发展大致可以划分成：古典贵族、古代贵族、近代贵族三大历史阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;古典贵族，在东方始于西周-春秋时代，在西方产生于古罗马共和时代。因其产生于农业社会早期，所以东、西方的古典贵族，都源于大土地占有者。东方的春秋，诸侯就是贵族，分封制是上古大土地所有制。钟鸣鼎食、酒池肉林是贵族区分于平民的生活方式。公、侯、伯、子、男等爵位划分了贵族等级，包括依附于贵族的“士”阶层，构成了上古东方农业社会的统治秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，比古罗马稍早些的古希腊社会，贵族力量不太强。由于巴尔干半岛缺乏大片连绵土地，所以古希腊发展出早期民主体制，体现出城邦商业富裕阶层均分权力的诉求。罗马在其征服地，譬如北非和西班牙拥有大量土地，所以产生了大量土地贵族，他们是支撑罗马帝国的强大基础，在元老院中分享权力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在古典主义时代，东方和西方的贵族，不但垄断了大量土地、财富，而且也垄断了文化、知识、艺术，产生并消费了那个时代惊人的文化艺术成就：古希腊和罗马的雕塑与建筑艺术，东方的《楚辞》、《诗》中的雅、颂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公元4-5世纪，是人类文明变更的大分水岭时代：东、西方的古典文明（东汉与西罗马）均败亡于北方蛮族，人类文明进入长达数百年的黑暗时代（或曰“中世纪”）。古典贵族在这个时代消亡，取而代之的是，东、西方都产生了第二轮次的“古代贵族”（中古贵族），而且，此时代东、西方产生的都是军事领主贵族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西方，日耳曼族群征服了西罗马之后，分疆裂土、大肆封侯，产生了大批蛮族军事贵族，这些中世纪的爵爷们，粗野、颟顸、质朴……几乎全是文盲，他们只强调尚武精神，比谁的胳膊粗、力气大、宝剑长，没事就骑马比武。欧洲军事贵族把读书写字视为羞耻、男子气概不足。在管理层面的文字需求，几乎全部由教士和侍从承担，基督教因此垄断了中世纪欧洲的意识形态与文化艺术。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时代的东方，南北朝和隋唐的士族（类似于贵族）产生了分化：南方士族，因“衣冠南渡”，文化和艺术修养较高，素有清雅文弱之名。而北方贵族，有相当部分胡人血统，文化艺术水准较低，但武力值较高，此即支撑了隋、唐两代的“关陇军事贵族”。公元6-7世纪，北方贵族军队征服了南方士族，华夏进入了第二个大统一时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;统一促进了经济与社会发展，文化艺术亦蓬勃发展。北方贵族的文化水准虽低，但仍在不断进步，其巨大财富，足以供养并消费李白、杜甫、吴道子、阎立本、李龟年等巨匠，盛唐气象创造了国族文化艺术的巅峰时代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文化与艺术发展，似乎不可避免会带来文弱、享乐、颓废乃至腐朽的生活模式，东、西方皆如此。在东方，唐代末年“黄巢大起义”彻底终结了中国的贵族时代，简单说，就是贵族被杀光了，“天街踏尽公卿骨”。自唐代以后，中国就再无贵族，进入庶族地主时代，皇帝和贵戚亦是庶族地主阶层的代表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法国也类似，从“百年战争”之后到“大革命”之前，法国贵族荣华富贵、骄奢淫逸，过了几百年人间天堂般的生活，创造了惊人的世界顶级文化艺术，同时燃尽了国家财富，导致法国社会和经济崩溃。最终，整个法国的近代贵族集团几乎被终结在断头台上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德意志和英吉利作为日耳曼族群的盎格鲁-撒克逊分支，中世纪武德延续较为长久。这俩族群的军事贵族传统，甚至一直延续到20世纪中叶，直到两次世界大战，机枪、大炮、坦克、轰炸机……在战场上终结了大量英、德军事贵族，欧洲的近代贵族终于式微。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影《Kingsman：The Secret Service（王牌特工）》生动地讲述了这一历史过程：由于大量军事贵族亡于战场，天量贵族财富成为无主财产，CEO们（而非Boss）才促进了欧洲社会的现代化转型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代社会，兴起的是精英阶层，而不再是贵族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵族是身份政治、世袭罔替。而精英则强调非身份政治、能力至上、自我奋斗、优胜劣汰。按我们古代的说法是“学而优则仕”，但仅仅学习好还不够，还要善于做事、遵纪守法、有社会担当。现代社会精英：多出自平民阶层，譬如马斯克（Elon Musk），在获得成功之前，还在车库里打过地铺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代精英政治，不像贵族政治那样垄断权力，而是打破阶层固化，开放个体跃升与降维的通道，这对于防止社会僵化、腐化具有重大意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哪怕是坐拥几千亿美金的世界首富马斯克，其儿子里也有不肖的。若不能有效传承、开拓、进取，那就重新归于平庸，而不可能享有贵族的世袭特权，这就是现代精英体制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希望大家尽可能多振奋精神、昂扬上进，尽可能多产生推动社会进步的精英、实现自我价值，少做贵族梦，那概念已经被历史所淘汰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南方周末6件作品获广东新闻奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260282]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 17:29:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月8日，由广东省新闻工作者协会、广东省新闻学会主办的2022年度广东新闻奖、广东省第十五届新闻&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;金梭奖&lt;/span>;金钟奖评选结果揭晓。381件作品获2022年度广东新闻奖，其中一等奖49件、二等奖122件、三等奖210件。10位同志获广东省第十五届新闻&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;金梭奖&lt;/span>;，1位同志获广东省第十五届新闻金钟奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末报社的6件作品获得广东新闻奖。其中，《“文明互鉴·海外对话”汉学家系列访谈》（作者余雅琴、王华震、宋宇、黎衡、朱圆，编辑朱强、刘悠翔、李慕琰）获得系列报道类一等奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末常年关注中华文化的交流互鉴、学术研究、大众传播，该系列报道通过对国际汉学界举足轻重的10位汉学家做长篇访谈，展示其研究成果、学术人生、中国故事等，为其群像立传，向海内外传播其学术成就，促进中外文化交流。这些汉学家来自美、法、德、日等国知名高校和研究机构，治学领域包括文学、艺术、历史、语言学、教育学、哲学社科、科幻等。这是同类选题中少有的成品牌、成系列的深度报道。包含视频在内的该系列报道在南方周末各平台发布，获得良好口碑，并实现了有效国际传播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此外，《“并不容易”的监护权变更》（作者冯皓辰，编辑苏有鹏、钱昊平）获得通讯类二等奖，《总有奋不顾身的相信，总要坚韧恒久的勇气》（作者黎衡、李焱鑫，编辑王巍）获得评论类三等奖，《准确理解科学新闻的科学性和社会性》（作者王江涛，编辑卢文炤）获得新闻业务研究类三等奖，《“红树林之城”的超级造林计划》（作者黄思卓，编辑曹海东、冯飞）获得典型报道类三等奖，《共富征途——迎接党的二十大》（作者谢艳霞、张玥、冯叶、周小铃、梅岭，编辑谢艳霞、张玥、冯叶）获得重大主题报道类三等奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在此之前，由中华全国新闻工作者协会主办的第33届中国新闻奖评选结果11月6日揭晓。来自全国各级各类媒体的377件作品获中国新闻奖，其中，特别奖3件，一等奖73件，二等奖114件，三等奖187件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;南方报业获广东新闻奖作品名单如下：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;一等奖（13件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/G8Y1NCHbMmY72XY7TLY3SQo76yUQuUkKJIa9FqZh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2530&quot; height=&quot;4608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/G8Y1NCHbMmY72XY7TLY3SQo76yUQuUkKJIa9FqZh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257713&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;二等奖（23件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/4Tjx0rxWDt6JLeTmIdcKAPRTCxqC4Pr6t441Ql26.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1678&quot; height=&quot;4608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/4Tjx0rxWDt6JLeTmIdcKAPRTCxqC4Pr6t441Ql26.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257714&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: bolder;&quot;>;三等奖（34件）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/w5cREKCLaVnRcJuXd6Jwue6acaPc7rlWYQq2EOnA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;5334&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/w5cREKCLaVnRcJuXd6Jwue6acaPc7rlWYQq2EOnA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257715&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第33届中国新闻奖获奖全名单：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/eC0eSQ5UHvE6KPytWwufSizNsqJc8BOwgerh5kQY.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1988&quot; height=&quot;1108&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/eC0eSQ5UHvE6KPytWwufSizNsqJc8BOwgerh5kQY.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257717&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/CqbExEjZl6ympnLVG4jwD89ekRNY48BFpg9eu2DV.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;4896&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/CqbExEjZl6ympnLVG4jwD89ekRNY48BFpg9eu2DV.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257721&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6s7kadbWLoOM0ccvBiNpYn9k339ybOXvU4km8Aug.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;5884&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6s7kadbWLoOM0ccvBiNpYn9k339ybOXvU4km8Aug.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257722&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/IxFY5OpQwk4TQ3pbcgVdz0iC4ZuKw5m6Lw9q4NYm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1076&quot; height=&quot;7552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/IxFY5OpQwk4TQ3pbcgVdz0iC4ZuKw5m6Lw9q4NYm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257723&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/PAPDjEYZ2IOzHfIwWT7E2VGFzcjhZEeL1IgwmnXZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;9820&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/PAPDjEYZ2IOzHfIwWT7E2VGFzcjhZEeL1IgwmnXZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257724&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[泷田洋二郎：电影行业是水，我刚好是条鱼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9h3AMYSNdISJmD3mvxw92f5X0YmyeSJJce3L6ypA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;907&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9h3AMYSNdISJmD3mvxw92f5X0YmyeSJJce3L6ypA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256527&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者姜晓明/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;金太郎糖&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年10月30日，电影《我爸没说的那件事》在北京举行了首映礼。该片由日本导演泷田洋二郎执导，张国立、韩庚主演。这是泷田洋二郎第一次执导华语片，改编自辛酉的小说《闻烟》。故事中，柳家世代制作冰晶糕，传到第八代柳见三，父亲柳庭深始终不愿意透露秘方，两人逐渐产生隔阂。直到父亲离世，这一秘方和与之相伴的秘密终于浮出水面。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影早在2018年便杀青，几经波折，终于于近日发布定档海报，官宣11月3日全国上映。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这不是泷田洋二郎第一部遭遇波折的电影。他职业生涯的最高光作品《入殓师》拍摄完成后推迟了一年才得以发行。《入殓师》根据青木新门撰写的《纳棺夫日记》改编，作者将自己多年经历集结成书。在纳棺夫叙述的世界里，逝者与入殓师于殡葬仪式的某个片刻，完成了人类生命的代代相传。电影由此出发，围绕着为逝者尸体整仪的主人公展开一段令人悲伤惆怅的故事。《入殓师》获得了2009年奥斯卡最佳外语片奖，横扫日本电影学院奖——共计13项提名，8项获奖。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泷田洋二郎回忆，电影主人公每天都与尸体打交道，日本人不太愿意接受，更不愿面对死亡。电影的主题因此成为禁忌。因为担心不卖座，没有公司愿意发行。2008年，《入殓师》在中国金鸡百花电影节和加拿大蒙特利尔电影节获奖，消息传回日本，这部电影才在公映时（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2008年9月13日&lt;/span>;）火了起来，拿到票房第一。到了奥斯卡颁奖季，票房虽已下滑，跌出排行榜，但获奖消息一揭晓，又重返票房第一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，泷田洋二郎最知名的作品是2001年执导、由野村万斋和伊藤英明主演的《阴阳师》；1986年执导，由内田裕也、麻生祐未、北野武主演的《不要滑稽杂志》。前者改编自梦枕貘《阴阳师》系列小说，讲述了日本平安时代法术高超的阴阳师安倍晴明运用他的智慧，驱除鬼神、解决难题的故事。后者逼真地再现了1985年日本所发生的许多真实事件，揭示社会阴暗面，谴责传媒失格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在转型之作《不要滑稽杂志》问世前，泷田洋二郎一度以“粉红电影”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指大量出现裸体镜头的电影&lt;/span>;）闻名。1955年12月4日，泷田洋二郎出生于日本富山县高冈市。1973年，从高冈商业高中毕业后，他到东京寻找梦想。20岁时，他进入狮子电影制作公司担任助理导演，1981年执导了处女作《痴汉女教师》，之后的5年里拍摄了21部以“痴汉电车”系列为主的粉红电影。这一类型片虽然以女性裸露和男女性爱为噱头，但主题多样，有严肃剧、轻喜剧，甚至是悬疑推理剧，泷田作品的奇想与妙趣，令他获得了“粉红电影天才”的绰号。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时的日本电影界日落斜阳，观众都不怎么去看电影。粉红电影有人看，但市场要求用很低的成本很快地完成拍摄。许多想拍电影又无处可去的人于是加入这个行列。世界上有太多这种下定决心非拍电影不可的人，我也是其中之一。”泷田洋二郎回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时他每天工作15个小时，成天腻在35毫米胶片里。幼时，泷田洋二郎常与家人去电影院，学校的体育馆也会放电影，他时常看着看着就冒出“这部电影说的不就是我的事情吗”的念头。但他不知道真拍起电影来是这样的境况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/z3AQzEGsca2WVookeTY0oQdMPDJy2LpmngedtBKC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/z3AQzEGsca2WVookeTY0oQdMPDJy2LpmngedtBKC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256532&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《入殓师》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“即便是这样一个充满不安、前途未卜的世界，也愿意只身投入。我认为只有置身于这个世界里，历经艰辛后发现自身一些东西的人才能生存下去。”泷田洋二郎说，“无论什么事都没有规则可循，当时生活在这个世界，看不到梦想，觉得怀有梦想也是一件奢侈的事情，能做的就是将眼前的事情努力去完成。”他记得相熟的一位前辈导演的话——希望自己被胶片缠绕着死去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“胶片缠身中，我深深懂得了胶片、电影意味着什么。还有剪辑，我明白了一帧一帧的重要性。从这些意义上讲，粉红电影的时代是我的原点。虽然当时很苦，但是有很多欢乐的伙伴，我们一起哭、一起大笑、一起喝酒。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泷田洋二郎曾用“金太郎糖”形容自己的作品。金太郎糖是日本小孩在七五三节（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;类似儿童节，庆祝孩子3岁、5岁、7岁的成长&lt;/span>;）食用的糖果，有各种各样的花纹图案，“是甜甜的长长的糖”，要一点一点切下来吃。这个糖不管从哪里切开，横截面都是一样的图案，只有最外层的颜色不一样。他认为自己的作品虽然题材各种各样，但真的切开看，都是一样的电影。作家止庵在与泷田洋二郎的对谈中将这种相似的内核概括为：关于普通人如何通过一个行为来证明自己，来实现自己的价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是在那次对谈中，泷田洋二郎回望自己的职业生涯，感慨自己从前总是谨慎、小心翼翼地挑选工作邀约，拒绝了很多作品。现在则更在意“为什么会找我？选择我做导演的理由是什么？”如果两个问题有一致的答案，他就会欣然接受。接下《闻烟》便是这一思考的结果。这是一部中国电影，全是中国演员，他想玩出一些好玩的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“作为导演我需要东奔西走，忙前忙后，但同时我也在客观地观察自己。比如现在坐在这里接受采访，其实有一个我站在高处，俯视着我自己。脑袋里，一方面有这种时时反观自我的客观性意识，另一方面是猪突猛进，像野猪一样朝着目标笔直向前奔袭的自己。”泷田洋二郎说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍摄临行前，太太没跟他说一句“拍个好电影回来”，而是叮嘱他：“千万别在众人面前发火。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“电影好与坏，人家毫不在意。”泷田洋二郎笑着说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年7月，我们有机会看过电影《我爸没说的那件事》的早期版本，并采访了泷田洋二郎，在采访中他谈到了拍摄中国电影的动力、对传统失序的看法、电影对时代和人心变化的回应等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hlPeUhICHI8ykpivggrbRqJ3WevCr9upoDyNx1bn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hlPeUhICHI8ykpivggrbRqJ3WevCr9upoDyNx1bn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《阴阳师》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下为对话泷田洋二郎：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;关于和解和重生的故事&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;刚才听工作人员说你看完小说《闻烟》之后觉得这个故事其实有点日式，有哪些地方触动你并让你决定拍摄呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中日的家庭构成是很相似的，父亲都是整个家庭的主心骨，那么日常生活、父子关系、文化传承也会有很多相似的地方。原著的设定是在中国一个小镇发生的故事，这个故事照搬到日本乡下也是可以成立的。这让我感觉非常亲切，也是我想尝试去拍这个片子的动力之一。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我个人最喜欢的是，父亲一直在保守秘密，坚持自己，而他的用意在他离世之后才被儿子感受到。这种误会、悲哀，最终的相互体认是最抓住我内心的。换句话说，这是一个关于和解和重生的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;和小说一样，你仍然沿用了儿子的视角来构筑父子间的关系，为什么选择这样的视角？以及为什么在现代来拍这样一个电影呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;直到昨天我还在想这个问题，其实随着年龄的增长，人的思维方式会越来越固定和局限，可能行动范围也会越来越窄。而年轻人的世界更有趣，对生活抱有很多期望，有不完整、不成熟的地方，各种元素碰撞，就会变成故事的发展。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然这也要跟随时代背景和职业设定。日本有非常多一代一代继承的老店，也有很多关于匠人的故事。传统手艺的世界是一个前辈与后辈争斗的世界，因为价值观和时代不一样，而后辈有想超越前辈的想法又是必然的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想知道在中国是否也一样。因此，这个故事被设定在2008年北京奥运会之前，经济在迅速增长，人们的经济活动对世界越来越重要，为了成功地融入现代世界，传统世界正在逐渐失序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么看待这些呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为从价值观的改变以及随之而来的变化来看，这并不是一件好事。现在一切都是数字化，想要快速得到结果。人们总以为做一件事情，结果就在那里，他们很快就能抵达。但传统的匠人式的东西恰恰相反，通过积累，各种技术得以传承，思维方式和感受得以提炼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如这个6cm×6cm的相机（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指着摄影记者的中画幅胶片机&lt;/span>;），它在很早之前就存在了，40年了，很罕见，现在还一直在用，有想坚持的东西在里面吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本是1964年办奥运会，跟中国很像，就是在那之后有一个快速发展。只不过那时候发展的速度是“加法”，现在感觉是“乘法”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;日本奥运会之后过了几年你就高中毕业了，有报道说当时你面临两个方向，是直接就业还是继续读书，所以在加速发展的社会环境中会感到迷茫吗？你那时候是什么样的状态，以及为什么会去东京呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为大学没有考上，说出来也没有关系。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;笑&lt;/span>;）我很迷茫，第一次意识到，那这么多年我是在干嘛呢？我很孤独。和见三（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;柳见三，《闻烟》男主角&lt;/span>;）一样，我也是在小地方长大的，所以我就想不要待在那里了，要去东京，我觉得我去城里会找到一些东西。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去了之后那个繁华程度、人的数量完全不一样，也没有父母在背后唠叨你，觉得简直是天堂。所以我刚开始当导演的时候，拍的都是城市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但随着我结婚生子、整个电影行业环境的改变、交际的深度和广度的改变，我开始意识到，18岁以前的家乡对我来说是无法忘却的东西，包括《入殓师》，也是回到小镇的那种感觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那些难以忘却的东西是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;梯田，河的味道，口感偏清淡的味增汤、乌冬面，父母房子的气味，母亲的味道。作为人类，我们永远不会忘记自己出生在哪里。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/6ahDsSqTs99ejK0oE9lg1oEjU6E7ApHYb7YppmlH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/6ahDsSqTs99ejK0oE9lg1oEjU6E7ApHYb7YppmlH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256526&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《北之樱守》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;对某件事充满热情的人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;到了东京之后，是怎么进入电影行业并且确定自己以后就是要拍电影了呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;完全是机缘巧合，甚至是进到这个行业之后才觉得它变得有趣起来。大家一直认为，包括歌唱在内的娱乐世界和电影世界是少数人或特殊人的领域。差不多半年到一年左右，我发现并非如此，无论是灯光啊还是摄像，其实都只是对某件事充满热情的人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;既然如此，会不会我也可以做这个东西呢？我就很认真努力地工作，也学习了很多有关电影的内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你还记得自己进片场的第一天发生了什么吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我只是茫然地看着，什么也听不懂，一直被骂。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;笑&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;听说那时候当助理导演的待遇是很糟糕的，很多年轻人都离开了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现实是，你周围的每个人都会放弃。很多人进入电影这行是带着憧憬的，可是一到现场，有很多体力啊人际关系上的疲惫。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影行业很长时间都不景气，经费少，收入低，看不到未来，工作又辛苦。但有很多事情，即使退出也无能为力。我不干这个的话能干什么呢？我觉得不干好像只是一种逃避。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用日本的谚语来形容，这个行业是水，我刚好是条鱼，在其中是如鱼得水，就很有趣，我从没想到过要退出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YhKK370FeJh0P5Pc1dcMaEEodrFtVC9I8R9pR8hi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/YhKK370FeJh0P5Pc1dcMaEEodrFtVC9I8R9pR8hi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《我爸没说的那件事》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那时候拍一部电影的成本大概是多少？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;300万日元（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;编者注：彼时正值日本泡沫经济时期，通货膨胀率上升&lt;/span>;），四到五天拍完。后来为什么我想制作各种类型的电影？我想接受更多挑战，而不是只在一个预算很少的世界里。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你第一次转型应该是1990年代产出的一系列喜剧电影，那个时期又是日本泡沫经济破灭的时期，外部环境对你的创作产生了什么样的影响呢？你当时是怎么理解喜剧的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;90年代的日本，正如你所说，发生了很多变化。泡沫经济破灭后，日本又发生了很多大事件，比如阪神大地震。因此，有一段时间，那些很有冲劲的人变得虚无了。虚无，虚无，总之，认为生命和世界都是虚无的。我会思考我们活着是为了什么？那时候的作品也是想问，生存的意义是什么。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人生有时候可能就是一场喜剧。一个人有很多面，取决于看他的视角，有时候这个人很严肃，像学校老师，有时候不是，生活中的人总是两面都有。其实我认为根据电影的内容和剪辑的角度，一切都可以成为喜剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，我真的很喜欢喜剧。看到大家因为这个东西笑了或者感到放松，让我觉得很温馨。毕竟生活往往很困难，不是吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那么历史剧呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;古装剧在某种意义上反而是自由的，想怎么样就可以怎么样。这不是逃避，而是理想的另一种实现形式。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在现实中传统正在消失、已经消失的时候，历史剧常常聚焦于人的美丽、传统和礼仪，这种东西被清晰地拍摄出来，让人们看到文化之美，让他们感到“这就是我们”，或者他们也想成为那样的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你自己在摄制和重看的过程中，是否也会被其中的东西打动？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;泷田洋二郎：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对我来说是另一件事，看自己的电影总是害怕不够好，昨天我在片子里又剪掉了6分钟也是这个原因，是不是这样更好，是不是那样更好，有这样的畏惧感。这还是交给观众吧。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;笑&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考人民网、时光网、一席、红星新闻等相关报道。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[跟文物贩子赛跑十年：她用镜头抢救山西明清乡村壁画]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Uncle, do we still have a big temple in our village?&quot; Yang Ping always asks every time he visits a village This is a problem for villagers. The fellow pointed forward with his hand. Yang Ping asked again: &quot;Are there any paintings on the walls in the temple?&quot; Yang Ping&#39;s Shanxi dialect is a bit different from that of his fellow villagers, but it does not hinder their communication. He had to travel to every corner of Shanxi. Without such a language advantage, Yang Ping really couldn&#39;t take pictures of the &quot;paintings&quot; in the temples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people talk about Shanxi murals, they always think of the exquisite Song and Yuan murals such as Yanshan Temple and Yongle Palace. However, many people don’t know that Shanxi villages, hidden among the mountains and rivers, preserve a large number of village temple murals. Compared with the protection, research and admiration that the murals of the Song and Yuan Dynasties enjoyed, the murals in the village temples seem a bit lonely. They are generally relics from the Qing Dynasty. &quot;These Qing Dynasty murals are not even &#39;village protection&#39;, not to mention &#39;national security&#39;,&quot; Yang Ping said. They quietly serve as the background for the village god statues and are also a touch of interest in the lives of the villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4WPb35vrq7unwyIJyFbvksl88V1sE1awKw9eZ4uA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4WPb35vrq7unwyIJyFbvksl88V1sE1awKw9eZ4uA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the mural on the east wall of a temple in Nancao Village, Shuocheng District, Shuozhou City, Shanxi Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ping has been photographing Shanxi murals for more than ten years. Like many enthusiasts who started taking pictures of murals, Yang Ping also took pictures of Song and Yuan murals at the beginning. After taking more pictures, she found that there were more murals hidden in small temples in the mountains and deserts in Shanxi. &quot;Many people took photos of the &#39;Provincial Protection&#39; That&#39;s all, but I&#39;m different, I want to go to the village,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ping was the editor-in-chief of a travel magazine in her early years. After the magazine ceased publication, she focused entirely on murals and painted sculptures in Shanxi. Over the years, she has photographed more than 400 murals in Shanxi, of which more than 300 were from the Ming and Qing dynasties. &quot;I know about another 20 to 30 murals that I haven&#39;t photographed yet.&quot; &quot;See You Under the Painted Walls of the High Hall—Exploring the Ancient Mural Paintings in Rural Villages of Shanxi, China&quot; is her new book published in 2023. It contains 21 exquisite village temple murals, mostly from the late Qing Dynasty, many of which she discovered for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you open this little book, you will be greeted by an artistic temperament that is completely different from the ancient and grandiose murals of the Song and Yuan Dynasties. The bright colors, the images of gods full of life, and the small and compact compositions, It all shows that this is an aesthetic taste that comes from the grassroots of the folk. Yang Ping wrote 21 short stories for these 21 murals. Most of them were about her chats with the villagers, family stories, and old rural news. They were written in a relaxed and interesting way. However, in the interview, Yang Ping talked more about the behind-the-scenes of the shooting. The joys and sorrows, as well as her worries about the rural murals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The culture left over from each era reflects that era. Rural murals are not just a presentation of art, but also contain a lot of historical information. The implication of this book is actually beyond the murals. &quot;Yang Ping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Almost all the films brought back were scrapped”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Yang Ping’s hometown is Jincheng, Shanxi, which is famous for its ancient buildings. In 2003, Yang Ping spent 360,000 yuan of his own money to start photographing ancient buildings in Jincheng. After taking many photos of buildings, she gradually became interested in the murals inside the buildings. Although she now runs to the village all day long and looks disgraced, she said that she actually loves dressing up. She used to work in fashion travel magazines and liked beautiful clothes. She first fell in love with murals because of their beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Yang Ping got an opportunity to photograph murals and painted sculptures across Shanxi. At that time, she only knew about the murals that were on the cultural relics list. As for how many murals there were in Shanxi, she didn&#39;t know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having no experience in photographing murals at the beginning, Yang Ping cast a wide net in Shanxi: there were eleven prefecture-level administrative districts in Shanxi, and each administrative district sent a photography team with at least three people in each team, led by a photographer. Led by a well-known photographer, plus a light and a driver, they plan to take carpet-like photos of murals and painted sculptures throughout Shanxi. It was a huge project, expensive, but the results were disappointing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Almost all the films I brought back were scrapped.&quot; Yang Ping recalled his &quot;recklessness&quot; at that time and smiled unconsciously. The photographers hired by Yang Ping back then were all &quot;big names&quot; in the industry. &quot;They have their own understanding of how to take good-looking photos. If you say it looks like this, they think that will look good. And many of them don&#39;t look good.&quot; I won’t take pictures.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But faithfully recording and “photographing beautifully” are two different things. To faithfully record the entire picture and every detail of a mural, the pixels of each photo must be large enough, which requires photographing a mural in different areas. However, at least one of the murals printed on the book needs to be complete, which means that the photos taken of each part can be combined. This means that different parts of the same mural are photographed, and their shooting angles and pixels are , light, and exposure should be as consistent as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ruLSclr85wZI8HAUe5EalhAWw0fIVDu2VWY8I9kT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;520&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/ruLSclr85wZI8HAUe5EalhAWw0fIVDu2VWY8I9kT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Full picture of the mural on the east wall of the main hall of Zhulong Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the partial pictures taken are to be combined into a whole picture, hundreds of photos will be combined , the synthesis time takes half a month, and the size of the entire picture is often dozens of G. &quot;They have never filmed like this.&quot; Yang Ping said. The photographers worked on their own, and the photos they took back were of different styles. They were all beautiful, but they just &quot;didn&#39;t add up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some murals that are three to four meters high. If the ladder is not high enough, changes in the camera angle will cause distortion of the picture, and they will not fit together. &quot;When I saw that this picture didn&#39;t work, I went back to training and took another photo. If it still didn&#39;t work, I bought a lot of books for everyone to read...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This unsuccessful carpet shoot cost Yang Ping a lot of money. The equipment, travel, and labor of the eleven photography teams were all wasted. Later, she realized that the more photography teams there are, the higher the efficiency will be. Mastering the shooting principles is the most important thing. She narrowed the camera team down to two, one of which was shot by herself. Facing a wall of murals, a relatively standard shooting process must be formed: ladders of different sizes must be provided, as well as infrared cameras for partitioning the walls, the lens is a standard Zeiss 50, and a small handheld camera is required. &quot;Many The statue is very close to the mural, so I had to put my hand in to take a picture.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to these general equipment, a shovel and a feather duster are also necessary for taking pictures of murals in the village. The latter is used to brush off the dust on the murals, and the former is a tool for road construction, &quot;leading to There are dirt roads in the village, so we can use them.” Once in a village in Luliang, the road conditions were so bad that the photographer used a shovel for more than an hour to shovel out a &quot;road&quot;. For the last three hundred meters, there was really no choice but to carry all the equipment, large and small, into the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The inscription from thirty years ago is still there”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first thing you see when you walk into Yang Ping’s studio is a row of albums of Shanxi temple murals. &quot;Yanshan Temple&quot;, &quot;Kaihua Temple&quot;, &quot;Princess Temple&quot;... these famous temples in the history of murals, Yang Ping has made extremely detailed albums accordingly. These albums are one of the results of her more than ten years of photographing murals. Of course, others had photographed them before her, and many albums had been published, but what she wanted to do was to capture every detail clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This book &quot;Yanshan Temple&quot; took three years to shoot. In 2013, 2014, and 2015, it was shot one after another. Every time it was re-shot, when it was published, I found that a certain part was not clear enough, so I Take it again.&quot; Yang Ping said. The Jin Dynasty murals in Yanshan Temple are known as the &quot;Along the River During the Qingming Festival&quot; on the wall. There are many characters and rich details. The rich flavor of life is hidden in the details of the picture. Yang Ping&#39;s requirement is that the identity of each character in the picture, the allusion of each Buddhist and Taoist story, and even the identification of famous jewelry items must not only have clear images, but also be accompanied by academic text explanations. Therefore, the albums she made were much thicker than those of her predecessors. The large octavo volume &quot;Iwamyama Temple&quot; was more than 300 pages thick. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the winter of 2013, she had almost finished photographing the &quot;national security&quot; and &quot;provincial security&quot; sites such as Yanshan Temple and Kaihua Temple, and Yang Ping began to systematically photograph the murals in village temples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, Yang Ping just took pictures of the village temple murals when passing by, but as she took more pictures, she gradually realized that the Ming and Qing murals in the village were more unique than the Song and Yuan murals. Its value is completely worth searching for again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the ancient villages of Shanxi, there are many common gods in folk belief temples, such as Guandi Temple, Niangniang Temple (Sanxiao Niangniang), Dragon King Temple, Mawang Temple, and Dongyue Temple. They may appear alone. They may also appear in &quot;groups&quot; - that is, distributed in different side halls in a temple. The Dragon King blesses good weather, the Empress blesses childbirth and safety, and Guan Di blesses the education of children with loyalty, filial piety, and justice. “Having children, education, and agriculture are all the real needs of the people,” Yang Ping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nAoCHFdPsyZq5m4VME0tVCyVxjQOKv6ItbDRTd0c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nAoCHFdPsyZq5m4VME0tVCyVxjQOKv6ItbDRTd0c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The female official on the north wall of a temple in a village in Shanxi to the right of the Dragon Queen, two four-value messengers and Feng Po (from right to left). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once, a Dongyue God in a temple blocked the way. The two walls of the main hall of the temple are covered with exquisite colored sculptures, but in the center of the hall stands a colored sculpture of unknown age, hidden in a small wooden pavilion. It is said that it was added by the villagers of later generations. Yang Ping wanted to take pictures of the colorful sculptures on both sides, but the camera was always blocked by the Dongyue God. The photographers went to take pictures five times, but the photos never looked good. In desperation, she discussed with the villagers during the sixth filming: &quot;Can we invite this god outside the temple first?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the old days, this Dongyue god was carried out for parade every year. In recent years, this ritual has gradually disappeared, but the elderly in the village are still worried that carrying it out unconventionally like this will cause bad luck. &quot;They are worried that it will cause heavy rain.&quot; Yang Ping said. A wood-based clay sculpture that has not been touched for decades will probably break if moved carelessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After finally convincing the villagers, Yang Ping himself had no idea how to move. While several people were anxiously circling the statue, an old man from the village stood up. He was holding a thick hemp rope and quickly tied the statue tightly using a knotting method that he had never seen before. , when four people lift it, it will not tilt up or down, nor will it roll over left or right. &quot;Without the help of this old man, we really wouldn&#39;t be able to take such beautiful photos.&quot; Yang Ping pointed to the page of colored sculptures in the album and said. After the filming was completed, the Dongyue God was placed back. Of course, there was no heavy rain in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time is passing, and the murals and painted sculptures are also changing with time. Many murals are completely different from when Yang Ping first saw them. &quot;I know a mural from the Song Dynasty, but the inscriptions were still there thirty years ago, but now some of the inscriptions have been blurred.&quot; And some murals from the Qing Dynasty that no one paid attention to can no longer be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Luoquanbao Village mentioned in &quot;Meet Me Under the Pink Wall Candle in the High Hall&quot; is one of the lucky ones. At that time, the local cultural relics bureau followed Yang Ping&#39;s suggestion and renovated the village temple and reassembled the murals. When Yang Ping paid a return visit in 2021, the murals in Luoquanbao were still intact. But there are too few examples like Ring Castle. As a province rich in cultural relics, Shanxi has a lot of cultural relics that cost money, but murals in village temples don’t seem to be ranked high. &quot;Shanxi&#39;s cultural relics department often jokes that asking them to open two banks may not be enough,&quot; Yang Ping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Gr4E9FQvqA3u9Yl51rIzpBfvLnJ9PrKBCu4VTIUQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;641&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Gr4E9FQvqA3u9Yl51rIzpBfvLnJ9PrKBCu4VTIUQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the mural at the Dragon King Temple in Luoquanbao Village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Culture is supposed to nourish people&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Do you want it or not? Yang Ping had hesitated for a long time before publishing the village temple murals and making them public. In 2016, they were shooting in a village near Taiyuan, and the photographer was kicked out by local villagers. Yang Ping understood the common people&#39;s &quot;vigilance&quot; very well: &quot;There are just too many cultural relic dealers.&quot; Murals in village temples are generally not even cultural preservation sites, and are beyond the reach of the official protection system. Although they are hidden in the mountains, they cannot hide from cultural relic dealers. of &quot;diligence&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a sense, Yang Ping is in a race with cultural relic dealers. “You can’t imagine how diligent they are. In the valley I went to ten years ago, cultural relic dealers walked by. &quot;Yang Ping&#39;s circle of friends was originally completely open. Whatever he saw or photographed, he would post in his circle of friends, but he would not post the specific address. Once, a friend from other provinces chased her over and asked her, &quot;Teacher Yang, can you give me an address for something in your circle of friends?&quot; Yang Ping immediately became wary and said to the friend: &quot;I You cannot take away even a stone from what is in your hand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in this book &quot;Meet Me Under the White Wall and Candles in the High Hall&quot;, many village temples have written detailed addresses. Yang Ping said that this was also a helpless move she made after thinking about it for a long time. On the one hand, no matter how well they are hidden, they may not be able to escape the search of cultural relic dealers. Moreover, even if the cultural relic dealers do not find them, most of the village temples in the book have already half collapsed. If they are hidden like this, the fate that awaits them will be gradual annihilation. &quot;It&#39;s better to disclose their status, attract the attention of the whole society, and arouse the villagers&#39; awareness of protection.&quot; Yang Ping clearly knew that a British banker&#39;s home had a collection of murals from the Qing Dynasty. &quot;Most of our researchers are currently concerned about higher No one cares about the ancient murals of the Song and Yuan Dynasties and the murals of the Qing Dynasty.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xiaoli is a reader of Yang Ping&#39;s book. In September 2023, she followed the route in the book and visited several villages in the book. She found that many villagers&#39; awareness of protection had indeed improved a lot compared to when Yang Ping was filming. For example, in the Dragon King Temple in Wayaotou Village, &quot;the villagers have become aware of protection. They covered the murals with thick plastic sheets. After we finished shooting, we covered them up as they were. This is a gratifying discovery.&quot; Song Xiaoli told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are unfortunate examples. The murals in Beicao Village mentioned in the book include the very vivid &quot;Dragon King Raining Picture&quot;. &quot;The Dragon King Temple in Beicao Village has been renovated, and a cultural heritage monument has been erected in front of the temple. However, the Dragon King&#39;s Raining Pictures on the east and west walls of the Dragon King Hall are missing. The cultural preservation department hung two spray-painted display pictures on the east and west walls respectively.&quot; Song Xiaoli explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XMsmu8OOO2pbwAv8zInikH6YVarxqHxkjN6B2KS6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XMsmu8OOO2pbwAv8zInikH6YVarxqHxkjN6B2KS6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the mural at Xinglong Temple in Beicao Village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sansheng Temple in Xucun cannot escape the fate of annihilation. This is a temple that integrated Buddhism and folk beliefs during the Ming and Qing Dynasties. The temple has three bays and is dedicated to different gods. The scene Song Xiaoli saw was very different from the description in Yang Ping&#39;s book. &quot;The entire mural on the north wall fell off under the erosion of rain, exposing pieces of mud wall under the ground staff. The upper half of the wall in the west room has collapsed. , no murals remain. The only remaining murals on the west wall are relatively complete, but a large hole collapsed in the northeast corner of the west wall.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/22JV6GWSbSGTjjeMLrZqJnhVpgHOVHa8EFrUySFO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/08/22JV6GWSbSGTjjeMLrZqJnhVpgHOVHa8EFrUySFO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The West Second Room of the Three Saints Main Hall—— A complete picture of the statues of Dragon Queen Mother, Five Dragon Kings, Rain Master and other gods on the north wall of Dragon King Hall. The mural was visibly damaged. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;See You Under the White Wall and Candles in the High Hall&quot; sold very well, one thing that surprised Yang Ping unexpected. Compared with her entire publishing plan, this small book shows only a small aspect of her work. &quot;You have done so many things, and no one knows what you are doing. It never sparks or bubbles. Suddenly it became popular in this book.&quot; The color pictures in the book, for those murals that have been annihilated, It is a precious record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The big book that Yang Ping has devoted the most to is the soon-to-be-published &quot;Complete Collection of Shanxi Temple Viewing Art&quot;. The &quot;complete collection&quot; includes &quot;The Complete Collection of Shanxi Temple Viewing Colored Sculptures&quot; (ten volumes) and &quot;The Complete Collection of Shanxi Temple Viewing Murals&quot; (twenty volumes), thirty volumes in total. All the painted sculptures and murals she has photographed over the years will be included. This is truly the first publication to include the art of Shanxi mural painted sculptures as completely as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The audience of &quot;The Complete Works&quot; is professional researchers, while the audience of &quot;See You Under the White Wall and Candles in the High Hall&quot; is ordinary readers. Yang Ping hopes that this small book can become a fulcrum and leverage some public awareness. Know. &quot;Actually, I have a motivation. Culture should not only attract educated people, but also attract more ordinary people. Culture should nourish people. Our current culture only nourishes a small group of people, which is not enough.&quot; Yang Ping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[买了14幅“毒地”？陆家嘴向苏钢集团索赔百亿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260262]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;17 parcels of land purchased 7 years ago at a cost of 8.525 billion yuan, after 6 years of development It was discovered that 14 pieces of land were seriously polluted. A lawsuit announcement by Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Lujiazui&quot;) on November 4 aroused heated discussions among netizens. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This incident is not a simple dispute between companies. As more details were revealed, the case quickly became a hot topic on November 8. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/06c5147bd39693df46185ad16eaff961.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;444&quot; height=&quot;211&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/06c5147bd39693df46185ad16eaff961.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257624 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are three main points that make the majority of netizens &quot;eat melons&quot;:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First, Lujiazui sued five units, among which the most Involving Jiangsu government departments. Lujiazui disclosed in the announcement that due to soil pollution problems, its subsidiaries have transferred Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Suzhou Iron and Steel Group&quot;), Suzhou Environmental Science Institute, Suzhou Suzhou Environmental Technology Co., Ltd., Suzhou National The High-tech Industrial Development Zone Management Committee and the Suzhou Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau went to court and recently received a written case acceptance notice from the Jiangsu Provincial Higher People&#39;s Court;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The second is Lujiazui’s claim amount is as high as 10 billion yuan. According to industry estimates, the litigation costs of this lawsuit may be as high as 50 million yuan;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Third, 14 cases of seriously contaminated land have attracted market attention . The land purchased in Lujiazui was purchased in 2016, but the contaminated land was not discovered until 2022. By this time, a large number of businesses had been built. Did the pollutants affect the construction workers? Why has no problem of excessive pollution been found during construction site operations for 6 years? Have you tried other options before filing a lawsuit? Wait for questions to follow&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;On the afternoon of November 8, the Securities Affairs Department of Lujiazui Company responded to Nandu Bay Financial News: &quot;We have disclosed all matters related to soil pollution disputes in the announcement. , are not accepting interviews at the moment. Regarding the status of the projects such as the Reading School that have been delivered, from the perspective of disclosure, we do not need to disclose it. We will make an announcement if there is any progress in the follow-up matter.&quot; Nanduwan Financial Society also called the above five defendants, but As of press time, the call had not been connected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many industry insiders told reporters from Wancaishe that complex interests are involved behind the &quot;poisonous land&quot;, and the relevant departments of the Shanghai and Jiangsu governments should handle related issues rationally and prevent produce sequelae. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;After spending 8.5 billion in 222 rounds of bidding, &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Lujiazui bought 14 “poisonous sites”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The incident originated from Lujiazui’s strategic decision to “go global” 7 years ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2016, Lujiazui’s designated holding subsidiaries Jiawan Company and Jiaer Company (through a trust plan) formed a consortium and jointly bid for the listing of Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. on the Shanghai United Equity Exchange. 95% of the equity of Green&#39;an Company was transferred. The main assets under the name of Green&#39;an Company are 17 land use rights located north of Sutong Road and east of Sugang Road in Suzhou High-tech Zone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6470f097007bb2896cb1498aab01a0d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/6470f097007bb2896cb1498aab01a0d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257622 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The development history of Suzhou Iron and Steel Group. Source: Suzhou Iron and Steel Group official website. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to public reports at the time, this equity auction attracted more than 30 interested investors, with a total of 19 companies participating. After 222 rounds of bidding, it attracted Greenland, Poly , Shimao, Vanke, China Merchants and many other real estate companies participated in the bidding. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Lujiazui finally won 95% of the equity of Suzhou Green Bank Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. for a total price of 8.525 billion yuan (transaction price of 6.84 billion yuan, debt of 1.685 billion yuan). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Lujiazui, which has defeated many powerful real estate companies, is also quite confident about the success of this auction. At that time, the group publicly stated that the successful joint bid for 95% of the shares of Suzhou Green Bank would be conducive to further increasing the company&#39;s land reserves and expanding the company&#39;s development space. &quot;By actively implementing the &#39;going global&#39; strategy, we will further enhance the brand influence of Lujiazui commercial real estate and enhance The company&#39;s sustainable operating ability and profitability.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, Lujiazui&#39;s bold &quot;going out&quot; investment decision was not so smooth sailing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2021, news spread that Suzhou Green Bank accidentally discovered that some plots of the project had serious pollution risks, and a report was made to the local government departments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In April 2022, the &quot;Processing Status of the Sixth Batch of Letters and Calls Transferred to Our Province by the Second Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection Team&quot; announced on the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial People&#39;s Government mentioned Recently, the test results of a third-party testing agency showed that benzopyrene and naphthalene in the soil of many plots of the Suzhou Green Bank project seriously exceeded the standards and did not meet the land use standards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It also mentioned that the Suzhou High-tech Zone Management Committee attached great importance to it, established a special work team, and quickly started work, requiring Suzhou Green Bank to effectively perform its main responsibilities. Before the end of June, a third-party agency will be entrusted to complete the formulation of a soil pollution investigation plan, and the organization and implementation will be organized and implemented. Related work will be carried out in accordance with the law based on the investigation results. During this period, the above-mentioned plots shall not carry out any activities unrelated to the prevention and control of soil pollution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the same month, Lujiazui also issued an announcement stating that 8 of the 17 plots of land have been developed. It was unexpectedly discovered that plots 2 and 13 where educational facilities have been built and plots 3 and 4 that have not been developed yet have serious pollution risks. Many elements in the soil or groundwater greatly exceed the standards and do not meet the original requirements of these plots. According to the planned land use standards, the total area of ​​the four plots is approximately 118,000 square meters. As of the end of 2021, the cumulative project investment in the four plots is approximately 450 million yuan&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Due to the exposure of land pollution problems, the Lujiazui project had to be stopped. &lt;span>;Public information shows that the above-mentioned land No. 2 and land No. 13, where the pollution was determined, are planned to build Suzhou Reading School and a kindergarten respectively. &lt;/span>;When they were named by the Central Second Ecological Environmental Protection Inspection Group in 2022, the two plots of land had been completed. According to media reports, due to pollution problems, Suzhou Reading School failed to welcome its first batch of new students in September 2021 as scheduled, and the students of the school are transitioning to Suzhou Science and Technology City Foreign Language School. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/d980d31c5b1e354c588b40313463a985.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/d980d31c5b1e354c588b40313463a985.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257627 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Aerial view of Suzhou Reading School. Source: Suzhou Reading School official website. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The announcement pointed out that the company organized a special force to verify and found that during the regulation adjustment and transfer process of Su Di No. 2008-G-6 plot, Suzhou Iron and Steel Group, the environment The testing agency and others are suspected of a series of violations, fraud, etc., which may have caused severely polluted land to enter the public trading market, and they concealed relevant information when listing and transferring 95% of Suzhou Green Bank&#39;s shares. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;If the land pollution identification is falsified, may the defendant face triple risks?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2023, Lujiazui took the relevant parties to court. On November 4, it announced in an announcement that the court had filed the case. Accept relevant cases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/157127c813d9d12713f2711324bbd4ff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/157127c813d9d12713f2711324bbd4ff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257626 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Picture from Lujiazui official website&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the context of relevant cases , Lujiazui said that since 2022, environmental investigations by the company and all parties have determined that 14 pieces of land under the name of Green Bank Company are polluted, and the polluted area and degree of pollution far exceed the pollution conditions disclosed by Suzhou Iron and Steel Group when it was listed for sale. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, the company entrusted a professional agency to verify and found that during the process of regulation adjustment and transfer of the land involved in the case, the defendants committed a series of violations, committed fraud, and failed to perform their duties in accordance with the law. The infringements together resulted in the plaintiff receiving the land involved in the case that was seriously polluted. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Lujiazui requested that the defendant be ordered to pay compensation of RMB 10.044 billion to the plaintiff (if it is subsequently discovered or clear that the actual amount is higher than this amount, the lawsuit will be increased or a separate lawsuit will be filed) Responsibility; request a ruling to order defendants 2, 3, 4 and 5 to bear joint and several liability for the claim in item 1; request a ruling to order that the litigation costs of this case shall be jointly borne by all defendants. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This lawsuit with a claim amount of up to 10 billion yuan quickly aroused heated discussion in the market. According to estimates by industry insiders, based on a fee of 0.5%, the litigation costs in Lujiazui may exceed 50 million. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/24e0ac78e19d13eb4da0c064a2a137f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/09/24e0ac78e19d13eb4da0c064a2a137f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257630 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;As for the reason why Lujiazui sued for large compensation, Wang Yuchen, director of Beijing Jinliu Law Firm, told reporters that the main reason is that it may face pollution problems on the land where the construction project is located. Huge legal risks and legal liabilities, and the Suzhou Iron and Steel Group, appraisal institutions, etc. in this incident will also have corresponding legal risks and legal liabilities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It further stated that as far as Lujiazui Group is concerned, according to the current information, it has a large scale of construction, many types of projects, and a huge amount of capital investment in the land involved in the case. , and related projects were found to have serious pollution in the land during construction, completion, sales and other aspects. Construction suspension, completion acceptance failure, sales suspension, rectification and repair, re-appraisal, etc. are all problems that Lujiazui Group is currently facing or will need to face in the future. Behind this, only in terms of civil liability, there is the risk of breach of contract in various contracts such as construction contracts signed with construction units and house purchase contracts signed with owners. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;A claim of 10 billion yuan, what is the probability of winning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wang Yuchen told reporters that if Suzhou Iron and Steel Group knew about the land contamination of the relevant land parcels at the time of the transfer and had the obligation to know but failed to perform it, it would Intentional concealment, etc. may not only affect the validity of the previous contract, but also face corresponding liability for breach of contract. For the losses that Lujiazui Group needs to bear, Lujiazui Group also has the right to recover from Suzhou Iron and Steel Group; in addition, if the appraisal agency investigates the case There are cases of fraudulent identification involving soil pollution, and they also face legal risks and liabilities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First, it will involve civil compensation risks, and may bear joint liability with Suzhou Steel and other entities; &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Second, it will face administrative The risk of punishment is that you may face administrative penalties such as warnings, fines, confiscation of illegal income, and revocation of corresponding qualifications;&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Third, if the circumstances are serious, the relevant responsible personnel may also be guilty of providing false certification documents, etc. Criminal offenses, criminal liability. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhou Zhengfeng, a lawyer at Guangdong Huashang Law Firm, also told reporters that if the investigation proves that the soil pollution involved in the case was falsified, Lujiazui may win the case. But the case may eventually be mediated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Of course, in addition to the current lawsuit, this case will also require corresponding solutions in the future. Issues such as how to deal with developed land are more worthy of attention. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Lujiazui behind the “poisonous land” case:&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Revenue and net profit dropped&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to paying attention to the case itself, the incident also caused netizens to worry about Lujiazui’s business conditions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As of November 8, Lujiazui’s market value was 44.76 billion yuan. Perhaps due to the huge impact of the case, the company’s stock price fell 0.75% that day to 9.30 yuan per share. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“You can’t recover the cost even if you win the lawsuit” “The claim amount of 10 billion is equivalent to 22% of the market value” “Is there no money for development?” Some investors responded to the incident They have a negative attitude, believing that Lujiazui is also facing operating difficulties during the real estate downturn cycle; but some netizens also have a positive attitude, &quot;Lujiazui&#39;s attitude is not bad. Investors are more assured when such things happen and proactively disclose information.&quot; &quot;Lujiazui still has a conscience. No more false reports were issued to defraud property owners into purchasing their homes.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Regarding whether the case will have an impact on the company’s operations, Lujiazui mentioned in an announcement on November 4 that the case is still in the filing and acceptance stage, and it is temporarily unable to judge whether it will affect the company’s operations. The impact on the company’s profits for the current period or subsequent periods. According to relevant media reports, Lujiazui Chairman Xu Erjin said at the performance briefing on November 6 that the company’s special working group is going all out to carry out disposal and rights protection work, and promote relevant responsible parties to assume subsequent disposal responsibilities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Xu Erjin also emphasized at the performance meeting that in the future, the company will pay close attention to the market situation in the Yangtze River Delta, choose opportunities to participate, continue to actively support the integrated development and construction of the Yangtze River Delta, and continue to strengthen Optimize the company&#39;s main business. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the company still has confidence in investment, it is undeniable that from the data point of view, Lujiazui has experienced a continuous double decline in operating income and net profit. According to the financial report, in 2022, Lujiazui achieved revenue of 11.762 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 15.21%; net profit was 1.085 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 74.84%; revenue in the first three quarters of 2023 was approximately 5.775 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 14.48%; attributable to listing The company&#39;s shareholders&#39; net profit was approximately 837 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 27.75%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The decline in Lujiazui’s performance is not unrelated to the fact that the current real estate market is still at a trough. In the first three quarters of this year, the national real estate development investment was 8,726.9 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 9.1%; the commercial housing sales area was 848.06 million square meters, a year-on-year decrease of 7.5%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Land pollution has devalued, the real estate market has declined, and forced development is unprofitable.” Some people in the industry believe that the main reason for this case to surface is due to multiple factors Impact. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The emergence of this case also triggered a new round of discussion on land development in the real estate industry. &quot;In the past 20 years of working in the industry, I have never seen a lawsuit like the tens of billions of land withdrawals due to soil pollution.&quot; Zhang Hongwei, founder of Jingjian Consulting, said that the lawsuit has involved the two governments, so it is not easy to handle. However, the &quot;poisonous land&quot; has been delayed for seven years. It is hoped that through the coordination of relevant departments in Shanghai and Jiangsu, this problem can be fundamentally solved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;易居研究院研究总监严跃进则猜测，该案件中或还涉及造假腐败等内容，显然需要严查。 “此事也说明，在房地产激进发展的一些年份，一些地块出让没有遵循规范，违规出让，进而产生了很多问题，对于人民群众合法权益造成了侵害。”他进一步指出，行业需要对工业用地的安全性问题提高重视，企业应该对于一些有工业用地开发历史的要审慎，防范产生后遗症。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;11月9日陆家嘴盘中报8.94元/股，跌3.32%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[作家做的事丨昼夜有时]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260204]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-09 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/OPZQPfGmKpkzdhhdwOeMj0xHzukNVQQo1yrwdngS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1303&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/OPZQPfGmKpkzdhhdwOeMj0xHzukNVQQo1yrwdngS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257539&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;母亲的魔力鞋。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更早的时候，我说的是她生病之前，她穿阿珍卖的艾力沛魔力鞋。其实那时候她已经感到不舒服了。她昏昏欲睡、拉肚子和发烧。也许癌细胞正在她的身体里野蛮生长，只是无人知晓。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说那是双神奇的鞋子。一双卖两千两百块马币。阿珍允许她先把鞋子拿回家，试穿一段时间后再付钱。她很满意，也许还觉得自己占便宜了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是她穿着它们出门，到镇上吃早餐，去商店买东西，还穿着去台湾参加她儿子的婚礼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我差点跌倒！”她曾对我说。不知道究竟是因为当时的她太虚弱了，还是那双鞋子导致她的脚很不好受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从来不在意那双鞋。那是个人们会相信豪猪枣、符水和降头术的地方。一双鞋子没什么大不了的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但那不是普通的鞋子。阿珍说那是带有超能磁的能量保健鞋，鞋底藏有精心调配的中药，能开启人体第二心脏，激发人体自愈能量环。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“健康是穿出来的”，鞋子的纸袋上写着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;等我见到那双鞋子时，她已经是一个骨瘦如柴，充满了怨毒的病人。她开始怨恨那双鞋子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说来吊诡，她的朋友秀丽也患癌症了。不过秀丽没有穿魔力鞋，她吃阿珍卖的胶原蛋白粉。她们俩每天都吃。那东西还挺麻烦的，得一起床就吃，而且越早吃越好。有一次，我们去西安旅游，天还没亮她就爬起来烧水沏胶原蛋白粉，喝完了就又回到床上睡觉。旅馆的烧水壶发出的嗡嗡声听得我和二姐心烦意乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她不想见到那双鞋子，于是叫我和妹妹到阿珍的理发厅退货。那天她去理发了，不过她不去阿珍的理发厅，也不去楼下阿莲的理发厅。她独自撑伞走到后面商店楼上的理发厅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和妹妹硬着头皮走进阿珍的理发厅。阿珍一边替一个女人烫头发，一边和我们说话。她让我们看她和她女儿的鞋子。她们都穿着和母亲那双艾力沛魔力鞋一模一样的黑皮鞋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“看，我和我女儿都穿，我一天到晚站着工作，脚一点都不酸！”阿珍说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鞋子当然退不了。 “都穿过了，谁还会买？”阿珍拒绝了我们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几天后，夏木来乌拉港，母亲给他看那双鞋子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我告诉你这双鞋子怎样骗人，你写下来，登在你们的报纸。”她对夏木说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和夏木面面相觑，然后看了一眼那双沉闷、丑陋的鞋子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是她眼中的作家和记者应该做的事。她似乎分不清记者和作家的区别。在她看来，那都是读书人，是写字的人，应该用他们的笔替人发声，为民请命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我跟你讲，你写下来。”当她告诉我她生儿子差点丧命的遭遇时，她就是这么说的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她自己就是这样的人，热衷于伸张正义和替人说话，和她的丈夫完全相反。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一段时日，她除了忙裁缝铺的活儿，还忙着替过港的穷人申请救济金。她从市议会拿了一沓申请表，派给那些生活困顿的人。遇到不识马来文的人，她就请她的马来朋友帮忙填表格，因为她自己也不太懂马来文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还给报馆打电话，替她的朋友申请报馆的救济金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当她告诉我这些时，我对她的能耐与激情感到不可思议。我想起很久以前她说过的话。她说算命佬曾预言如果她继续上学的话，她会成为像李金狮那样的大人物。李金狮是我们从前的卫生部长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她很自豪。她像个乡绅，像个大人物那样在乌拉港走来走去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快她的风光就烟消云散。她怨恨魔力鞋，怨恨她的妹妹，怨恨欺骗她的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在第一次化疗的前一晚，在医院附近的酒店里，凌晨时分，在把晚餐全都吐出来后，她对我娓娓道来一个女人的故事。那个女人通过她的帮助获得了救济金，但她发现原来她并不穷，她和她的丈夫在离乌拉港不远的镇子经营海产的生意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我还有她们的名片。”她说。她决定打电话给报馆揭发那个女人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不到一个月，她自己就成了等待被救济的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲说她可以申请救济金，她应该领救济金。于是市议会的人来了。那个男人也是母亲的朋友，一直以来就是他在处理母亲代人递交的申请表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹敏带着深深的理解与悲悯看着母亲。他当下就作出了决定，建议我为母亲拍张照片。母亲得躺在床上，这样才能将她的病态完完全全地展露出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我没有为母亲照相。夏木也没有为她写揭露骗局的报道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很久以后，在她死了五年后，我才想到应该上网搜搜关于魔力鞋的介绍或新闻。我很快就看到了《南方都市报》的报道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那是2016年的报道。那时她还没有生病。那时我还在学校教书。两年后，我不再是个老师，她成了一个注定会死去的病人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当她让我们看那双鞋时，为什么我们没有想到应该上网搜一搜？这不是我们这些读书人的本能和本领吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也许我并不在乎她花了多少钱买一双鞋子。也许我早已对她上当的事实司空见惯。那是一个人们相信豪猪枣、符水和降头术的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我尊重他人的信仰与生活，我总是这样说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我已经离开乌拉港很久了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们不需要救济金。”我们这几个孩子都这么想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我没有为母亲照相。再说了，母亲也不情愿躺在床上，任由人为她拍下一张耻辱与绝望的照片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她死后，一个周日午后，二姐把那双魔力鞋退还给了阿珍。她用葬礼收到的帛金付给阿珍两千两百马币。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她死后，我在她的抽屉里发现了一张剪报。那是2014年11月29日的《星洲日报》关于“情在人间”助养儿童计划的新闻。剪报上有五个六年级学生的肖像，报道的标题是《以好成绩回报助养人，星洲助养学生UPSR获佳绩》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我还以为那都是过港的孩子，是她曾经帮助过的孩子。不是。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我知道为什么她收藏那张剪报。她喜欢这样的故事，那些关于奋斗、苦尽甘来和知恩图报的故事。曾经她的孩子也凭借优秀的成绩而获得社会的支持，她引以为傲，丝毫没有因为那里面深深隐藏着卑微的气息而面红耳赤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那双魔力鞋或许此刻就在某个女人的脚上。我们也不再提起那些往事。但我从来没有忘记它们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去我没有做一个女儿能够（应该？）做的事，于是现在我做一个作家应该做的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>