<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[锦江：此心安处是吾乡丨月是故乡明⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I have been living in Chengdu for twenty-five years. I keep moving along the Jinjiang River, as if in the fog. I stop and go like a boat, not knowing where my heart is at home. Inadvertently, it moved from the original downstream to the current upstream. It was not until it was close to Huanhua Creek and adjacent to Du Fu&#39;s Thatched Cottage that the fog seemed to gradually dissipate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes, in the past twenty-five years, Jinjiang has been the pillow that accompanies me to sleep every night. I didn’t realize it because it was so familiar. Just in June 2022, when I was able to calm down and look at Jinjiang again, I suddenly discovered that every time I moved before, it was a coincidence that the direction of my door overlapped with my sleeping posture many times, either facing Jinjiang or with my back to Jinjiang. , actually completely consistent. It turns out that all my uneasiness over the years was nothing more than impulsiveness, tossing and stubbornness when I was tossing and turning. The so-called conflict between survival and the so-called poetry and the distance was resolved tonight at the &quot;Hejiang Pavilion&quot; at the intersection of Fuhe and Nanhe, collectively known as Jinjiang River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinjiang, which used to be exclusive to Nanhe River, now also includes Fuhe River. Jinjiang River, whether it is the Nanhe section or the Fuhe section, except for spring tides and summer floods, rarely sees real rapids, and most of the time it always passes through the urban area of ​​Chengdu casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time I followed the famous literary group organized by the Jinjiang District Federation of Literary and Art Circles to revisit Jinjiang, from the December City Museum to the Shuijingfang Museum, and then from Hejiang Pavilion to Dongmen Market and Li Jieren’s former residence on the banks of the Shah River. Walking along both sides of the Jinjiang River, I discovered that it actually has many faces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/VV4GRYkoaUV6cISe3uPg3aUadwhsXxlRWk1AU9mw.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/VV4GRYkoaUV6cISe3uPg3aUadwhsXxlRWk1AU9mw.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;205682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wangjiang Tower on the South Bank of Jinjiang River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Moving like a dragon&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;Rapid, turbulent, moving like a dragon, it should be the first face of Jinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to my fate with Jinjiang, I first read Du Fu’s poem in “Spring Night Rain” when I was in elementary school: “The clouds are all dark on the wild paths, but the fire on the river boats is only bright. At dawn, I can see the red and wet The place is full of flowers.&quot; But I didn&#39;t know at that time which river the &quot;river boat&quot; in the poem was. I grew up on the banks of the Jialing River. Every time I saw a wooden boat passing by the fast-moving Jialing River, I wanted to get on the boat immediately and rush to this &quot;river boat&quot; river written by Du Fu. I wanted to see if it could Also has a turbulent character. In 1997, I came to Chengdu to go to college. I saw the evergreen Du Fu Thatched Cottage by the Huanhua River and read more of Du Fu&#39;s Chengdu poems. Only then did I realize that this river that has been rippling in Chengdu for thousands of years was originally called Jinjiang. Today&#39;s scholars and old Chengdu people often regard Huanhua Creek as the starting point of Jinjiang River, but in Du Fu&#39;s eyes, the source of Jinjiang River is at the foot of Yulei Mountain in Dujiangyan. Therefore, he said in another poem &quot;Climbing the Tower&quot;, &quot;Jinjiang River The spring scenery comes to heaven and earth, and the jade barrier and floating clouds change the past and present.&quot; The water cultural gene of Jinjiang comes from the Minjiang River, which moves like a dragon at the foot of Yulei Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have traveled to Yulei Mountain many times and experienced firsthand the source of the Jinjiang River. The surging Minjiang River is in Dujiangyan. The majestic Puyang River flows out of the Baopingkou not far from the foot of Yulei Mountain. , the river is most unrestrained when it flows through the Dujiangyan South Bridge. From a distance, you can hear the sound of the raging waves hitting each other and violently beating the earth and rocks on both sides. After passing the South Bridge, near the &quot;Tianfuyuan&quot;, the Puyang River split into two, with a Zouma River sloping out from the side. Soon it split into two again, and a cypress river was cut out like a branch, and the Minjiang River flowed straight down. So far, the Zouma River and Baitiao River that branched out have run through the Chengdu Plain, nurturing the people of Shu and achieving the reputation of a land of abundance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diverting the surging Minjiang River water to irrigate the Chengdu Plain, this huge credit certainly belongs to Li Bing, the prefect of Shu County during the reign of King Qin Zhao, who presided over the construction of the Dujiangyan Irrigation Project. When he governed Shu, he first controlled the floods, which solved the survival concerns of the people in Shu during the Qin Dynasty. He also paved the way for Chengdu to become one of the most prosperous industrial and commercial cities in the country during the Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/pQ2pzo7dXnWLSo3PaMNGE813avxx5fwOdX5CLScE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/pQ2pzo7dXnWLSo3PaMNGE813avxx5fwOdX5CLScE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;205680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Source of Jinjiang River: Minjiang River at the foot of Yulei Mountain in Dujiangyan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Peng Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jing Like a Virgin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Calm, elegant, and as quiet as a lady, this is Jin Jiang’s second face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the many sub-rivers of the Minjiang River, the Zouma River, especially the Huanhua Creek where the lower reaches of the Zouma River and the upper reaches of the Jinjiang River are located, are undoubtedly the clearest. Anyone who stops here will be impressed, not least because Huanhua Creek and its 600-acre Huanhua Creek Park have now become the largest green lung in Chengdu. The internal reason is closely related to the poem &quot;washing&quot; in the past dynasties. Especially after Du Fu settled here, Jinjiang gradually evolved into a river of poetry, with clear words and beautiful sentences constantly polishing its body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mighty Minjiang River has passed through the outer city in the west of Chengdu since ancient times and flowed near Du Fu Thatched Cottage, but its eager temper has created a gentle Huanhua Creek. No wonder Du Fu chose this place at the first sight when he came to Chengdu. In his poem &quot;Bu Ju&quot;, he praised &quot;at the west end of the Huanhua Stream, the owner is Bulintangyou&quot;. Later, due to the war in Chengdu, Du Fu, who had to flee the chaos in Zizhou &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now Santai County, Sichuan)&lt;/span>;, was still writing &quot;Post a Question&quot; &quot;Jiangwai Thatched Cottage&quot; explains the original intention of settling by the Huanhua Stream, which is: &quot;I have a wild nature, and I want to escape from nature. I am addicted to wine and love bamboos, and I must live in the forest and springs.&quot; Today, by the Huanhua Stream, the Mian bamboos are slender, and the loving bamboos are kind. , bamboo cages are everywhere, and it is quiet everywhere. Being among them makes you forget your worries. As the upper reaches of Jinjiang River, Huanhua Creek has an ecological aesthetic quality. &quot;Fish come out in the drizzle, and swallows slant in the breeze.&quot; These natural beauties described by Du Fu in the Tang Dynasty can still be experienced frequently today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Tang Dynasty, if you took the waterway, you could take a boat from Huanhua River and turn into the Yangtze River to reach the south of the Yangtze River. Yes, it&#39;s Jiangnan. In his youth, Du Fu traveled to Nanjing, Suzhou, Hangzhou, Shaoxing and other ancient places of Wu and Yue. He has never forgotten the landscape of Jiangnan, such as the Qinhuai River in the sound of oars and the Cao&#39;e River under the awning boat. As the saying goes, &quot;Missing&quot; &quot;Wu Sheng Shi Fan&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Part 2 of &quot;Two Poems on Zizhou Climbing the Tower in Spring&quot;)&lt;/span>;, I often feel that &quot;the Yan River is beautiful and unique, You can’t forget it if you want to stop”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;The Grand Tour&quot;)&lt;/span>;. Even when he came to settle in such an elegant and peaceful Huanhua River, and decided to live here forever, Du Fu would still think about it from time to time, except in the last sentence of &quot;Bu Ju&quot;, &quot;Thousands of miles eastward to enjoy the pleasure, one must go to the mountain shade in a small boat&quot;, In the last sentence of &quot;Quequatrains&quot;, &quot;The window contains the snow of Qianqiu in the Xiling Mountains, and the door is docked with ships thousands of miles away from Dongwu&quot;, I recall the Wuyue landscape rooted deep in my brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the mountains and rivers of Wuyue and Bashan and Shu are the sources of Du Fu’s landscape poetry. In particular, the Jinjiang River in Chengdu and the Yangtze River in Chongqing also helped Du Fu reach the pinnacle of Chinese five-rhythm and seven-rhythm poetry, such as his famous five-rhythm poem &quot;Spring Night Joyful Rain&quot;, &quot;Look at the red and wet places at dawn, and the flowers are heavy in Jinguancheng&quot;, and his seven-rhythm poem. The famous poem &quot;Ascend the High&quot; &quot;The endless falling trees rustle down, and the endless Yangtze River rolls in&quot;. And as soon as he left Chengdu, Huanhua Creek became the most beautiful Jinjiang that Du Fu never forgot in Kuizhou &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Fengjie County, Chongqing)&lt;/span>; on the Yangtze River. , for example, in &quot;Two Poems on Huaijin Water&quot;, one of them says, &quot;The water of Wu Gorge is coming towards Wu Gorge, and the waves of Jinjiang River are far away.&quot; Another example is that in &quot;Five Poems of Generals,&quot; the fifth one also says, &quot;The spring beauty of Jinjiang River drives people to Wu Gorge.&quot; Qingqiu mourns thousands of people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since ancient times, I have been traveling in captivity, why should I be sad?&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(&quot;Chengdu Mansion&quot;)&lt;/span>; made Du Fu let go for a time Ji Lv is sad, thanks to Chengdu and Huanhua Creek in Chengdu. Chengdu and Jinjiang also have to thank Du Fu for his poetic talent of &quot;not surprising even if his words are not surprising&quot;. All this is, of course, because the sparkling Huanhua Creek provided Du Fu with a stable habitat. In the spring of 760, Du Fu was very satisfied with the thatched hut built by Huanhua Stream. He immediately wrote a poem &quot;Tangcheng&quot;: &quot;The back of the Guotang is shaded by white grass, and the road along the edge of the river overlooks the green suburbs. The alder forest blocks the sun and sings in the wind. Leaves, bamboo cages and smoke dripping from the dew tips. The flying crows will stop to count their eggs, and the swallows will come frequently to make new nests. Others mistakenly compare Yang Xiong&#39;s house, and he is lazy and has no intention of making fun of it.&quot; Since childhood, Du Fu said that he had a talent similar to Yang Xiong&#39;s. His talent and poetic talent were no less than those of Cao Zhi. Suddenly someone mistook his thatched cottage for Yang Xiong&#39;s old residence. What else needed to be explained? From then on, in addition to traveling to other places, he basically spent time on the riverside looking for flowers, asking for willows, meeting friends, drinking, farming, and growing medicine. He kept looking at Jinjiang from various perspectives and copying it. From the time I arrived in Chengdu in the winter of 759, I felt uncomfortable writing &quot;Chengdu Mansion&quot; because of &quot;the bustling city, playing the flute and the sheng&quot;. By the time I left Chengdu in the summer of 765, I wrote &quot;Go to Shu&quot; with tears in my eyes. ”, Du Fu wrote more than 200 poems during the 6 years he lived here. Almost every poem will be poetically inspired by Jinjiang. He wrote this repeatedly, and on the day he left, he finally turned Jinjiang into a river of poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/M2eXRG3uRZHUoae2J4hQkpVcalSEhI4McWxY0ezz.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/M2eXRG3uRZHUoae2J4hQkpVcalSEhI4McWxY0ezz.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;205683&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The upper reaches of Jinjiang River: Huanhua Creek&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Peng Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Du Fu’s worship Visitors and followers came from different dynasties one after another, and they were in an endless stream on both sides of the Jinjiang River. The rising and falling sounds of poetry can be heard everywhere. Zhang Ji is here, and his &quot;Chengdu Song&quot; is very lively in Chengdu dialect. The picture is: &quot;The smoke and water are green near the west of Jinjiang River, and the lychees are ripe at the top of the Xinyu Mountain. There are many restaurants near the Wanli Bridge, and tourists love to stay in whoever they want to stay at.&quot; Su Shi is here, After struggling in officialdom for many years, he was demoted to Huangzhou. His memories of Jinjiang are full of nostalgia, such as in &quot;The Red River: Sent to Ezhou Zhu Envoy Jun Shouchang&quot;: &quot;Coming west from Jianghan, the grapes under the tall buildings are deep green. I still bring them with me. Min&#39;e snow waves, the spring scenery of Jinjiang. You are the beloved guardian of Nanshan, and I miss the return guest outside the sword.&quot; Lu You came. He loved Jinjiang, especially the plum blossoms on both sides of Jinjiang. It can be said that &quot;Ten years of horse racing along the Jinjiang River&quot;. For ten years, he was &quot;on Jinjiang Road in front of Qingyang Palace, and I was drunk by plum blossoms for ten years.&quot; In his later years, the lingering aftertaste is still: &quot;Back then, when I walked to the west of Jincheng, I was drunk by plum blossoms. For twenty miles, the fragrance continued. , Qingyang Palace to Huanhua Stream.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinjiang starts from the intersection of Huanhua Stream and Modi River in the northeast of Caotang Primary School, all the way from west to east, passing Baihuatan, Jinguan Bridge, Rainbow Bridge, Wanli Bridge to Hejiang Pavilion, this section of the river is also called Nanhe. This is the only river that Du Fu must pass when leaving Chengdu in his later years, and it is also the spring river that Li Bai sang on the Sanhua Tower in his youth &quot;Building&quot; &quot;Evening rain goes to the Three Gorges, and the Spring River flows around the two streams&quot;)&lt;/span>;, during which time, we go retrograde from the Sanhua Building in Baihua Pond to the Shuangxian Bridge Antique Market on the bank of Huanhua Creek. There are also Yuxian Bridge, Wangxian Bridge, and Wangxian Bridge. Send Xianqiao. The Nanhe River starting from Huanhua Stream winds and meanders without any rush until it meets the Fuhe River running from north to south at Hejiang Pavilion. At the confluence of the two rivers, waves suddenly bloom, gradually returning to their turbulent nature originating from the Minjiang River. From there, he quickly rushed to Jiuyan Bridge, Wangjiang Tower, and Huanglong River, and returned to the mainstream of the Minjiang River near the Jiangkou Chenyin Site in Pengshan, Meishan, and went straight into the Yangtze River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My inspection of Jinjiang this time came along the Fuhe River with a group, and then I went back home alone from the Nanhe River. Although I have witnessed the spectacular confluence of the Nanhe River and the Fuhe River many times before, they are still there. The scene of hugging each other and recognizing relatives in Hejiang Pavilion is still seen often. It made me get to know Jinjiang and myself again. It seemed casual but in fact I was very committed to the original intention of living in Jinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/KdIn6CHecKafSHgXLMXmlpAEABQhI0PHW8DAAGfb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/KdIn6CHecKafSHgXLMXmlpAEABQhI0PHW8DAAGfb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;205679&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;South Section of Jinjiang River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Peng Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jin Ruo Shu Jin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Amazing, tolerant and with a bright future, this is the third face of Jinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First trace the whereabouts of the Baitiao River, a tributary of the Minjiang River. In fact, like the Zouma River, it also goes all the way east and divides many times in the north of Chengdu. The sub-rivers include Pihe, Dongfengqu, Shahe and Fuhe, among which , Fuhe River turns from north to east and then south into Chengdu City. Compared with the Zouma River, the Baitiao River has a greater mission. Especially in the Tang Dynasty, it passed under the Chengdu City and became a moat, protecting Chengdu from good weather and protecting Chengdu&#39;s prosperity for thousands of years. This section of the Baitiao River flows through and protects Chengdu Fucheng, so it is named Fucheng. Li Bai said in No. 7 of &quot;Ten Songs of the Emperor&#39;s Western Tour of Nanjing&quot; that in the Tang Dynasty, this moat was &quot;Jinshui flows eastward around Jincheng, and the star bridge hangs like a star in the north.&quot; This moat, which has been changed many times but still protects the city of Chengdu, is the Fu River that now meets the Nan River at Hejiang Pavilion. Yes, Fuhe was regarded as &quot;Jinshui&quot; by Li Bai, and Nanhe, which originally referred to Jinjiang, was also &quot;Jinshui&quot; in Du Fu&#39;s eyes. For example, &quot;Dan Ge Xing presented Wang Lang Sizhi&quot; said, &quot;The princes from the west drank Jinshui. Where do you want to go to get your pearls and shoes?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuhe River and Nanhe River, the two &quot;Jinshui&quot; surrounding the city, were once collectively known as Funan River. They were the gushing mother river among the Chengdu population. Fuhe and Nanhe, which have the same origin as the Minjiang River, are both &quot;Jinshui&quot;. Since they are collectively called Funanhe, why not call them both &quot;Jinjiang&quot;? Jinjiang, as its name suggests, is a river with a bright future. In 2005, with the approval of the Sichuan Provincial Government, Fuhe and Nanhe in the urban section of Chengdu were officially collectively called Jinjiang. After all, both Fuhe and Nanhe have made great efforts in flowing through, protecting and prospering Chengdu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about another important cultural source of Jinjiang: Shu Brocade. The history of Chengdu&#39;s construction has been more than 2,300 years since Zhang Yi built the city after the Qin State annexed the Shu State. Since Li Bing diverted the Minjiang River into the Chengdu Plain, Chengdu has been constantly changing the course of the river entering the city. It has been accumulating power like water since the Qin Dynasty. This power is the driving force that Shu brocade brings to Chengdu&#39;s economic prosperity. In fact, sericulture and brocade weaving have been the living customs of the ancestors of Shu since ancient times. By the Western Han Dynasty when the brocade industry was developed, the Shu brocade produced in Chengdu was sold all over the country and became famous because of its exquisite craftsmanship, variety of colors, and wide range of uses. In 2012, four Shu brocade Jacquard loom models were unearthed from archaeological excavations at the Laoguanshan Han Tomb in Chengdu. Their dates all point to the Western Han Dynasty. They are the most complete loom models from the Western Han Dynasty discovered in my country so far and the earliest Jacquard loom in the world so far. Model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to legend, as early as the Han Dynasty, the imperial court set up officials in Chengdu to manage brocades full-time and named them &quot;Jin Officials&quot;. During the Shu-Han Period of the Three Kingdoms, Prime Minister Zhuge Liang restored the &quot;Jin Officials&quot; to solve the problems during the war in one fell swoop. Due to the economic and military expenditure problems of the Shu Kingdom, Chengdu gained the reputation of &quot;Jincheng City&quot; and &quot;Jincheng City&quot;. When Du Fu was living in Chengdu, he wrote &quot;The Prime Minister of Shu&quot;, &quot;Where can I find the ancestral hall of the Prime Minister? There are so many trees outside Jinguan City&quot;, and &quot;Spring Night Joyful Rain&quot;, &quot;Looking at the red and wet place at dawn, the flowers are heavy in Jinguan City&quot;, which illustrates the Jinguan City in the Tang Dynasty. The ruins of the city are still there, and its official office is probably on the Jinjiang River between Rainbow Bridge and Wanli Bridge. In the Tang Dynasty, Chengdu, formerly known as Shu County and Yizhou, experienced great development in Shu Brocade and other handicraft industries. In addition, the Chengdu Plain nurtured by the Minjiang River was rich in rice and other grains. It became a more prosperous city than Chang&#39;an and Luoyang. It is known in history as &quot;Yang one benefits two&quot;, which means that Chengdu&#39;s economic power is second only to Yangzhou, which is known as a land of plenty and a canal hub. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I say Jinjiang is as stunning as Sichuan Brocade because it is really brightened by Sichuan Brocade. According to the fifth record of Liu Yuxi&#39;s &quot;Nine Poems on the Waves and Waves on the Sand&quot;: &quot;The flowers on both sides of the Zhuojin River are washed by the spring breeze. The girl cuts off the mandarin duck brocade and sets the sunset glow in the middle.&quot; In the poem, Liu Yuxi vividly describes a Tang Dynasty A scene of Chengdu women washing Sichuan brocade in Jinjiang River. There is also Li Bai. Even when he was sentenced to Changliu Yelang in Xunyang, he still missed the Jinjiang River in Chengdu that was washed by Shu Jinhuan. Sixth of his &quot;Ten Songs of the Emperor&#39;s Western Tour of Nanjing&quot; said, &quot;The Qingjiang River flows thousands of miles.&quot; , Yunfan and dragon sailed down to Yangzhou.&quot; In the Tang Dynasty, the Jinjiang River was wide, running thousands of miles, and full of heroism. Why was the word &quot;毯&quot; added before &quot;Jinjiang&quot;? Because Jinjiang is also known as Zhuojin River and Zhuojin River. Zhuo Jin, the brocade color is fresher and more moist than usual, hence the name. The washing of Shu brocade by the Jinjiang River did not begin in the Tang Dynasty. Since about the Western Han Dynasty, Shu people have loved to wash the Shu brocade cut by textiles in the Huanhua River. Later generations euphemistically called this &quot;Zhuo brocade&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How could Du Fu, who lives in Huanhua Creek in the upper reaches of Jinjiang River, not know the legend of &quot;Zhuojinjiang River&quot;, as stated in &quot;Xiao Baming&#39;s Mansion Really Looking for Peach Plants&quot;, &quot;Although there are countless in Heyang County, the gardens along Zhuojinjiang River are not full.&quot; Zeng explained that during the Anshi Rebellion, there was a shortage of peach trees in Huanhuaxi, so he went to Xiao Baming&#39;s Mansion to find new peaches to plant. When Du Fu first arrived in Chengdu, he mainly made a living by farming and growing medicines, and his family often relied on Lumi from friends such as Gao Shi and Yan Wu. After that, he must also be dressed in brocade clothes, which he often washes in the Jinjiang River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The greatest inheritance today of using Sichuan brocade to wash the Jinjiang River is probably the naming of a county-level district after Jinjiang. In 1990, Chengdu abolished Dongcheng District and reorganized its main part into Jinjiang District. The name of the district comes from the Sichuan culture of &quot;Zhuo Jinjiang&quot; that has been passed down orally for thousands of years in the poems of great poets such as Li Bai, Du Fu, and Liu Yuxi. In the Qin Dynasty, the location of Jinjiang District was called Chengdu County, which was the core urban area of ​​Shu County at this time. In the Tang Dynasty, whether Chengdu County was renamed Shu County or Huayang County, it was still Chengdu Prefecture&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (the capital of the Tang Dynasty &quot;Nanjing&quot; after the An-Shi Rebellion )&lt;/span>;’s core urban area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/mQVSufFdiyFuBN4jinfzt7rVA7pEN5fEb2pQgy54.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/08/18/mQVSufFdiyFuBN4jinfzt7rVA7pEN5fEb2pQgy54.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;205681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Anshun Covered Bridge on Jinjiang River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinjiang River, from The &quot;Zhuo Jinjiang River&quot; that flows from the Min River to wash the city of Chengdu not only incubates Jinjiang District, but also flows southward from Hejiang Pavilion in Jinjiang District into the High-tech Zone, Shuangliu District, and Tianfu New District, continuing to expand Chengdu&#39;s arteries. Even like me, a &quot;Rong Piao&quot; who has lived for 25 years, was able to establish a business in the Jinjiangfu River section and then settle down in the Jinjiang South River section. It can be said that I was first inspired by Du Fu&#39;s poetic Jinjiang, and ultimately it was because of the economic boom. Given by Jinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a summer evening, the colorful clouds turned the face over Chengdu red, and also reflected the Jinjiang River passing through the city red. As the night gradually opened and the lanterns started to light up, I strolled along the Hejiang Pavilion on the Jinjiang River and returned to the upstream Huanhua Stream. I fell asleep on the Sichuan Brocade pillow late at night. I thought that I would never be able to stay away from the Jinjiang River for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走出村小的学生正在服务杭州亚运，让我看到教育的意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday will give you a few days to spare. While watching the replay video of the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games, I remembered that Xiao Yang, who I had been in contact with before and was now in Hangzhou, might be serving the Asian Games as a volunteer at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I immediately sent her a message, but it took a few hours for me to receive her reply: She was on rest during service, not in the library, but still busy... Finally, while she was resting During the break, I learned that she was working with several other volunteers this time to provide information consultation for athletes in the e-sports stadium, issue game passes, arrange for athletes to enter the lounge, and check-in matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at some of the live pictures and work photos of the e-sports stadium that she posted on her WeChat Moments, the more I looked at them carefully, the less I could recall too many scenes of her as a primary school student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She was the first group of students I taught when I became a teacher ten years ago. At that time, compared with other students in the class, she was not necessarily very cheerful and lively, but she was serious, studious, and careful enough. She was selected as a &quot;study committee member&quot; very early. She lived right across from the school. Sometimes she would finish her homework in the classroom after school and then go home. She would also occasionally come to the school after dinner to chat with me and another young teacher who lived in the school. Although her grades in elementary school have always been among the best, even though she occasionally sent me holiday greetings after entering junior high school, and even though she heard my opinions when she filled in her application for the college entrance examination, I never imagined that the person who read the text aloud ten years ago A student who was not very loud and did not perform actively in public classes can now use fluent English to help e-sports players from different countries successfully enter the arena and complete the game and win their praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes me even more moved is that the starting point for her volunteer service for the Asian Games was an extremely ordinary rural primary school, a primary school with less than 300 people, a sports ground on dirt... A student can pass After ten years of study and continuous hard work, I entered the city, entered the university, and entered the Asian Games e-sports stadium with a sense of technology and modernity. I used my enthusiasm and professional ability to contribute to the Asian Games. I have always been in a township school. In my opinion, it is simply a miracle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am not sure whether Xiao Yang could have imagined that he would have such a special situation when he was in elementary school ten years ago, high school five years ago, and college two years ago. But for me, a teacher who has taught her for two years, witnessed her growth, and followed her learning, there are too many surprises and too many gratifications. This surprise and relief was the result of seeing her continue to learn and receive education. It was so beautiful and good. Even the whole process and results were something that neither she nor I, who had experienced it, had ever imagined or expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my tenth year of teaching, many of my students have already entered the workplace early, some are still studying on university campuses, some are still preparing for the college entrance examination, and some have just entered junior high school. Whenever I wonder how much positive role I, as their teacher, have played in their growth and learning, Xiao Yang’s experience in serving the Asian Games should be the best answer I can give at the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a teacher in Suixian County, Suizhou City, Hubei Province)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010 ;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submit your contributions Email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[回故乡之路丨月是故乡明⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OHl0geXE8w.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/29/W55RQ3BBaVoPNKbBJH7xZg43SMqt50OH l0geXE8w. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;203155&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xiaochen 4x/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was born in Liling, Hunan. Since I left when I was very young, I have always regarded Pingxiang, Jiangxi, as my hometown. When I first heard that the capital of Anhui Province was called &quot;Hefei&quot;, I was as surprised as I was when I learned about the history of Pingxiang. Although this coal city in western Jiangxi is called &quot;Pingxiang&quot;, in fact, it has become a well-known industrial and mining city at home and abroad as early as the late Qing Dynasty with the rise of Anyuan Coal Mine; it is not only the birthplace of the Chinese workers&#39; movement, but also the autumn harvest. Why was the origin of the uprising named &quot;Pingxiang&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn’t it just Pingxiang? There are also many cities in China with interesting names. For example, the capital of Hebei Province is called &quot;Shijiazhuang&quot; and the famous porcelain capital of Jiangxi is called &quot;Jingdezhen&quot;. In the 1970s, a flood in the upper reaches of the Huaihe River washed out Henan Province. A prefecture-level city was named &quot;Zhumadian&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is either a town, a village, or a store. It is conceivable that most of these place names come from its history. But the combination of these two Chinese characters &quot;Hefei&quot; makes people feel strange. A cross talk once joked that it was &quot;two fat men sleeping&quot;. Later I learned that it got its name because it is located where the two Fei rivers in the north and south merge into Chaohu Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Anhui, or the first time to Hefei, was in May of 1993, when the flowers were blooming. At that time, I was still working in Pingxiang City. The two places were separated by more than a thousand kilometers. Because of the inconvenient transportation, Hefei felt like a distant existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent two full days on that trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set off early in the morning the day before. After taking the green train for most of the day, I first arrived in Nanchang and stayed at a small hotel near the long-distance bus station. The next day, I took a bus before dawn. Genius 1 bus bound for Hefei. Then, the car passed through countless villages and towns. The road was uneven and had potholes from time to time. After a day of bumps, the bones were falling apart. Lunch seemed to have been served at a roadside shop in Huangmei County, Hubei Province. It was probably the driver&#39;s personal designated restaurant. The food didn&#39;t look clean, and there was a strange taste in the mouth. This is nothing, the worst part is going to the &quot;bathroom&quot;. Although the car stopped twice during the journey, both times it stopped in the wilderness of Qianbuba Village and Hoububa Store; those two places were blocked. The sheds called &quot;public restrooms&quot; were only one person high and had no doors. The passengers were self-conscious at first and lined up at a distance, but the male compatriots who couldn&#39;t wait went to look for trees or grass that could provide shelter. To solve the problem, our female compatriots could only guard the toilet. The dirty floor in the toilet and the flying mosquitoes and flies made me retching uncontrollably. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order not to go to the toilet, I didn’t dare to drink a sip of water or take a sip of food along the way. By the time I arrived in Hefei, it was already dark and I was so hungry that my chest was touching my back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that terrible experience, I did not dare to return to my hometown. It was not until three years later that a railway was built between Hefei and Nanchang, and I began to return to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first, this special line was not included in the national railway system and was only a local railway between Anhui and Jiangxi provinces. It starts from Hefei&#39;s West Railway Station, passes through Feixi, Lujiang, Shucheng, Tongcheng, Qianshan, Susong, and Wangjiang in Anhui Province, passes through Huangmei in Hubei Province, and then crosses the Yangtze River and enters Jiujiang and Yongxiu in Jiangxi Province. , and finally arrived in Nanchang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I do remember that the first time I boarded that southbound train was one morning at the end of 1996. At that time, our financial situation was still very difficult, and all we bought was a seat ticket. When my husband and I got into the car carrying large and small bags, we were surprised to find that there were very few passengers in the car. Although some people started to get on along the way, they were always sparse and there were so many empty spots that people could even lie down and sleep. Looking out the window at the rolling mountains, the sleeping fields under the winter sun, and the fleeting simple farmhouses, I felt mixed feelings. Fortunately, I no longer have to endure the pain of long-distance buses where I dare not even take a sip of water. Switching to a spacious and comfortable train, the time is shortened by nearly half. What is worrying is that there are too few passengers and the passenger flow is so small. Volume, let alone making money, whether the cost can be maintained is a question, and the economies of Anhui and Jiangxi provinces are still underdeveloped. If they are always losing money, can this train be saved? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This train arrived at the terminal, Nanchang, in the evening. Since there were no more trains to Pingxiang that day, we had to stay in Nanchang for one night. I remember we chose a hotel called &quot;Da Guangming&quot; on Zhanqian Road. &quot;Da Guangming&quot; is a small hotel. The rooms are poorly furnished and there is no separate bathroom. A very funny thing happened in &quot;Great Light&quot; that day, and even today, twenty-six years later, I still remember it fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While packing the luggage the next morning, my husband suddenly discovered that an envelope containing 3,000 yuan in cash was missing! The door was locked and the windows were bolted, so it was impossible for outsiders to come in and steal. But after searching every corner of the room, as well as the corridors and public toilets outside, nothing was found. My husband then went downstairs to find the waiter, and soon a hotel security guard came up. He said that only the two of us lived on the entire floor that day, and even if it fell on the corridor, it would not be picked up by anyone. What he meant was that the envelope could only be left in the room. So, in front of him, I took off the quilt cover, lifted the sheets, took out the items in the box one by one, and rummaged through them again, but there was still nothing. At this time, my husband made a request to him, &quot;Maybe I accidentally dropped it into the toilet when I was convenient and it was washed away. Can you take me to the sewer to have a look?&quot; The man did not refuse. He agreed, &quot;It is possible. Not long ago, a traveler dropped a watch and found it in the sewer. There were not many people staying in the hotel last night, and the water from the sewer should still be accumulated downstairs. I will take you Go down and look for it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a glimmer of hope, we followed him downstairs. He took out an iron rod with a hook from a corner, led us around to the small courtyard behind the hotel, and opened two The iron plate, underneath is the sewer. He bent over and rolled up his sleeves, completely ignoring the stench coming from the sewer. He held the iron rod and carefully raked it back and forth little by little. After raking it out three or four times, he still found nothing. He smiled at us apologetically: &quot;Nothing either!&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;If I really can’t find it, I can only admit that I am unlucky. We left &quot;Da Guangming&quot; sadly, took the train back to Pingxiang, and stayed at Dadi&#39;s house at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That year, my eldest brother was allocated a new apartment. This money was originally a gift to him, but unexpectedly something unexpected happened, so he had to owe it first. Unexpectedly, when my husband went to bed at night, he took off the black woolen jacket and something fell from his sleeve, and it was not the envelope containing the money! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for how the envelope slipped into the sleeves, there is no way to verify it; he didn’t even notice it when he was getting dressed, and he didn’t even notice when he put it all the way around, which shows that he doesn’t care about such trivial matters in life. He is a careless person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While I was blaming his Madaha for giving me a false alarm, I was also full of guilt for the Da Guangming Hotel. Think about it, in the middle of winter, I had to dig out the gutter early in the morning, and I still looked unhappy when I left. I always thought that the money was lost in the hotel, and I even suspected that the waiter had picked it up! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the Daguangming Hotel and the tall security guard have been deeply engraved in my mind. Even after our economic conditions improved, I still chose to stay in &quot;Da Guangming&quot; every time I was in transit from Nanchang. Once, my son had a high fever in the middle of the night, but I did not panic and gave him medicine calmly because I believed that this hotel would definitely lend a helping hand if needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years later, this Anhui-Jiangxi line was integrated into the national railway network. The trains from Hefei to Nanchang were also extended from Nanchang to Guangzhou, and a pair of trains to Dongguan were also added. There are many trains to choose from, but both trains depart from Hefei at noon or evening, and arrive in Nanchang either in the evening or in the middle of the night; and the train from Nanchang to Hefei departs in the early morning, either in the middle of the night or in the early morning. When traveling between Hefei and my hometown, I still have to stay one night in Nanchang. I have been riding this kind of train for more than ten years, so I have stayed at the Daguangming Hotel no less than forty times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I don’t have a good impression of Nanchang Railway Station. Every time I leave the station, there will be a number of people holding signs to solicit guests to stay in the hotel, and they will keep pestering you; in front of the station When dining in a small restaurant, if you don&#39;t agree on the price in advance, sometimes you will be charged an exorbitant price, and you will have to consider yourself unlucky if you get ripped off, because those people are very rude and seem to be ready to use their fists at any time. Fortunately, this hotel prevented us from being too disappointed in this city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About 2010, my journey back home changed again: Hefei opened two direct trains to the southwest, one to Kunming and one to Nanning; Both trains pass through my hometown. The former departs in the morning and arrives in the evening, while the latter departs in the morning and arrives in the evening. The time it takes to reach Pingxiang does not exceed twelve hours. From then on, my journey back to my hometown suddenly became very smooth. I no longer needed to change trains midway. I only had to buy a sleeper ticket, get on the train from Hefei after dinner, and sleep all the way to Pingxiang in time for breakfast the next day; or I was still in Hefei in the morning, and before the sun went down, I came to the streets of Pingxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the convenient transportation, the number of times I return to my hometown has naturally increased. It used to be once or twice a year, but now it has become several times. Something happened at home. I got a call the day before and I arrived early the next morning. It used to be difficult to meet my classmates and friends from my hometown, but now it is easy to meet once or twice a year. Whenever there is a school anniversary or class celebration event, as long as I can spare the time, I will rush back to join in the fun. ，虽然离乡二十多年，以前的同学圈朋友圈竟都奇迹般地恢复了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年春节，我和老公回乡探母，通过网络购票时，竟意外地发现，从合肥开往昆明的那趟列车，突然消失了；开往南宁的列车也不在萍乡停车了。但与此同时，我更惊喜地发现，合肥与南昌之间已经通上高铁了！而且，高铁一天就发车六趟，全程只需两个多小时！接着，还发现，过去在皖赣两地之间运营的那趟客车也回来了，只是它也由早先的绿皮火车变成了动车，时间更是大大缩短到了两小时四十分钟！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年初五中午十二点多钟，我和老公登上了这趟动车。望着窗外飞掠而过的旷野和农舍，我的心情一下回到了二十六年前，第一次搭乘回乡的火车时那样的止不住的激动。印象中，那时候的绿皮火车时速只有六十公里，并且，为防止热胀冷缩，每段铁轨的连接处都留有缝隙，车轮驶过时，车下会发出清晰可闻的“咯噔噔—咯噔噔”的响声，每当夜深人静尤为响亮；而现在动车高铁的时速已达到了二百多公里，人坐在车上，再听不到车轮撞击铁轨的声音，平稳得甚至连杯子里的水也纹丝不动，可想而知，如今的铁轨显然做到了无缝对接。前后只有二十六年，二十六年说起来不长，却足以孕育一代人，说它短，仿佛也就弹指一挥间，这二十六年来，中国的铁路交通确实发生了翻天覆地的变化。仅从速度上看，从前只有慢车或普快，二十世纪初，便有了特快和直达；到了二零零八年奥运会，京津之间则出现了第一条城际高铁线，两大直辖市之间实现了高铁公交化，彼此往返只需半小时。再从颜色上看，从前的慢车一律是绿色，过渡到特快直达则有了红色和蓝色，后来的动车与高铁就全是白色；到了现在，高铁已经普及到了全国各地，仅安徽省就做到了市市通高铁。于是，我发现，车的颜色又有了调整：除高铁动车外，所有的普通客车一律恢复成了早先的绿色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;绿色是春天的颜色，看上去就感到清爽，感到生机勃勃。当然，更大的变化，还是今天的轨道交通已由烧煤，变成了用电，这是一个时代的变迁，不仅变得更加快捷，也变得更加清洁，变得环保！于是，我在猜想，猜想未来驱动高铁和动车的动力，又会是一种什么样的新能源呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我饶有兴趣地在网络上搜索了一下，才发现，南昌与合肥之间的这条高铁是今年，即二零二二年元月正式通车的，我算是较早享受这项福利的乘客之一了。那天，车上的乘客也并不多，一如当年第一次乘坐地方铁路时的情景，座位空了一大半。但我却不再有当年的担心，因为这次之所以乘客少，并非客流量上的问题，而是囿于新冠疫情，大家在响应政府的号召，能不出行就尽量不出行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高铁之于普通火车，不仅仅只是在时间上大大地缩短了，换乘的便捷更是其一大优势。我曾在直辖市的天津西站换乘过，也在地级市的蚌埠南站换乘过，都无须再出站就能够解决换乘。这次，动车驶入南昌西站，我们下了车，按照“便捷换乘”的指示牌上了站内天桥的电梯，穿过天桥，直接就进到了候车室。因为从南昌西开往萍乡北的高铁每天多达二十六趟，我们在车站只待了一小会儿，就很从容地完成了换乘，一个小时之后，就结束了回故乡之路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想想，这一切都感到不可思议：从江淮之间的合肥，到赣西煤都的萍乡，从前的行程是两天一夜，现在竟只要花上四小时。这样的速度，从前连做梦也不敢想。很多人都看过《水浒》，知道里面的神行太保戴宗能日行千里夜行八百，大家都觉得那不过是神话，可现在中国的高铁，千里之行哪里需要一日？两三个小时足矣！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今的回故乡之路，可以说简直就成了一种享受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一次历届最火的迷笛音乐节，和乐迷遭遇的65起盗窃案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258172]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:50:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;此次南阳迷笛音乐节流传广泛的经典画面：托举轮椅哥。图片来自迷笛音乐节官方微博&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2b9aee5d26.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;此次南阳迷笛音乐节流传广泛的经典画面：托举轮椅哥。图片来自迷笛音乐节官方微博&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在见证了“泥巴大战”和“托举轮椅哥”两个经典画面后，刘瑞原本可以带着这段迷笛音乐节的专属回忆，满心欢喜结束一年一度的音乐朝圣之旅，没想到最后时刻猝不及防的盗窃事件，几乎毁掉了所有的“现世美好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位资深乐迷和很多朋友一样，“十一”假期去音乐节狂欢，是保持多年的习惯，可之前所有的经历，都没有这次在河南南阳的遭遇让人刻骨铭心：“之前也听说过音乐节上丢东西的事情，都没有这次这么严重，这次太夸张了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“十一”长假期间，河南南阳“中原迷笛音乐节”屡次登上热搜话题榜。其中，据众多乐迷在社交平台反映，10月3日，迷笛露营区发生大规模财物被盗事件，有乐迷提供的视频、图片显示，当地村民闯入迷笛营地明目张胆“洗劫”帐篷，不少电脑、手机、乐器等贵重物品被搜刮殆尽。“上个厕所回来，&#39;家&#39;被搬走了，就很离谱。已经是明抢了。”一位乐迷告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，南方周末记者致电南阳市公安局，一名吕姓警官回应：“我们目前还在登记乐迷丢失物品，具体情况需要对接市公安局宣传口。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，迷笛音乐节官方微博发布公告称，当地警方共接到报案73起，落实被盗案件65起。经过公安机关侦办，现已抓获、拘留一些盗窃者，追回部分财物；当天，微信公众号“南阳广播电视台”发布通报称，根据目前乐迷登记情况，已归还身份证79张、电脑3台、手机17部，其余物品正在核实联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;因为下雨，露营区少人居住&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;这是南阳首次承接迷笛音乐节，于9月29日-10月2日举行4天。为了举办这场音乐节，当地政府在郊区的黄山村辟出一大块空地，培植了大块草坪，并且取了一个叫“绿野独白”的名字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“4天音乐节，下了3天雨。”刘瑞介绍，像迷笛这种户外音乐节，通常会辟出空地，供乐迷带帐篷露营使用。9月29日中午，露营区正式向乐迷开放，但是音乐节这几天，除了9月30日天气还算晴朗之外，其它3天持续下雨。很多乐迷搭好帐篷之后，只是在白天休息时使用，晚上选择到市区的酒店住宿、洗澡。方便起见，很多人并没有随身携带行李，而是按照往常习惯，直接放在帐篷内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘瑞说，露营营地分为A、B、C三个区域，其中，他所驻扎的C区，位置处于里边，被盗情况不算严重，他只是丢失了充电宝、插排这些价值比较低的物品，并没有报警。不过，靠近出口的A区、B区，尤其是挨着围栏的地方，失窃情况十分严重。“好像是深圳乐迷，东西都放在墙根，损失惨重。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他介绍，音乐节前几日，并没有听说“丢东西”的情况，最后一天早晨回到营地之后，很多人发现财物不翼而飞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们是有一个（乐迷）组织，都在一块扎营。”吴思琪来自深圳，这是她第4次迷笛之旅。她向南方周末记者回忆，因为下雨，她只在第二天晚上在帐篷住了一宿，其余时间都住酒店，行李放在帐篷里，然后拉上拉链。10月2日晚上，看完演出后情绪一直比较兴奋，没有发现异常，10月3日从酒店返回露营区时，发现帐篷拉链被打开，很多财物不见了，帐篷旁边还散落了一些物品，明显有被人翻捡过的痕迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过核验，她丢失一部手机、数张银行卡、若干现金，以及一些纪念品。“应该是翻墙进来的。”吴思琪说，乐迷购票后现场可以得到一个手环，入口处有工作人员值守，凭手环才能自由出入。“入口有人看着，里边围墙安保差点。”她说，音乐节场地围墙高约两米，没有保安看守，比较容易翻越。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴思琪和周围一同来自深圳的朋友交流，均有不同程度的损失。她看到有乐迷拍到的视频和图片，有人翻墙跃进露营区，还有的人在营地里翻捡帐篷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乐迷刘铃损失了笔记本电脑、耳机、充电宝，以及用来摆摊的货物。她去派出所报警的时候，碰到一位摊主，声称丢失8万余元的货物。为了找回丢失的物品，她加入3个乐迷互助群，每个群都有四五百人，均表示有丢失财物的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是刘铃第一次参加大型户外音乐节。她大学还没有毕业，坐了十几个小时的绿皮火车，从广州抵达南阳。“家里人还不知道这件事，我现在也在上学，代价很大。”她说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;另一个经典画面“泥巴大战”。图片来自迷笛音乐节官方微博&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/8202470098.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/8202470098.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;另一个经典画面“泥巴大战”。图片来自迷笛音乐节官方微博&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;已抓获多名嫌疑人&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;事发后，有网友在社交媒体发帖称，在音乐节期间，有人在直播时，曾发布音乐节结束后现场帐篷都没有人要的信息，起到了误导作用。对此，中原迷笛音乐节组委会于10月5日发布的公告中称，10月4日上午，因网民陈某违规发布“活动已结束要清理现场”的不实信息，引发附近村民趁乱下手，出现多起露营区财物被盗的案件。公告还透露，发布误导性不实信息的陈某已经被抓获。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不知道他是什么心理，为什么要发这样的信息？”刘瑞说，音乐节第二、三天，便发现有人“拾捡”防潮垫的问题，尚在能接受范围以内，“也就是想捡点小便宜”。转折点发生在倒数第二天演出的晚上，帐篷里的东西开始被大规模偷窃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘瑞说，此前他参加过很多次音乐节，财物失窃的情况时有发生，甚至听说过小偷团伙集体作案的事情，但是都没有这次南阳迷笛音乐节如此夸张。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“偷了就是偷了，我们确实整个营地的人，都被偷了很多东西。”吴思琪说，她在网上看到一些网友为村民们开脱，认为发生在南阳迷笛的不光彩事情，算不上是偷窃行为，而是村民“拿走了”一些活动结束后遗弃的物品，她认为这种论调完全是罔顾事实，“他们就是在否认事实，这不行”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴思琪说，原本这次南阳迷笛之行，给她留下很美好的记忆，但是最后的遭遇让这些体验毁于一旦。她介绍，因为连续下雨，一些乐迷在户外露营的计划泡汤，主办方为部分临时找不到酒店的乐迷提供了免费住宿，淋雨后身体有些着凉，音乐节现场还可以免费领取红糖姜茶。包括交通接驳等细节也都很到位，好感度一度拉满。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她也和当地的居民有所接触，音乐节间隙去市区闲逛的时候，遇到的市民都很热情，因为打车比较难，还遇到过好心乘客和司机“加塞”载了她们一程。“我感到很温暖、很感动，结果，最后一天回到营地，发现被偷家了，被刺了一刀。”吴思琪说，这几天的经历很魔幻，“一下子就把我从乌托邦拉回了现实，让我看到社会险恶”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵坤是一位70后乐迷，因为天气原因，他一直在酒店居住，不过还是目睹到最后的“奇幻”一幕。“感觉就是老乡偷南瓜，或者高速上水果车翻车，抢水果的心理。”他说，刚开始只是占小便宜的心理作祟，“捡”一些不值钱的东西，后来的人看到便宜已被人捡走，干脆就觊觎起帐篷里的物品，最后愈演愈烈，演变成明火执仗的“洗劫”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，南方周末记者致电迷笛音乐节组委会，一名负责人表示，目前已经报警，对于丢失物品的乐迷做了详细的登记工作，公安机关对此次集体盗窃案件也成立了工作专班，目前已经抓获多名嫌疑人。“我们在现场把追回来的东西同我们的登记信息进行比对，目前已经退回了部分乐迷的物品。我们后来也了解到中间有网友陈某在2号晚上结束之后，在网络散布不实信息，表示活动结束，很多东西没有人要，让大家来捡。目前陈某已经被公安机关抓获。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;招商引流遭遇“黑天鹅”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;迷笛音乐节是由北京迷笛音乐学校创办的原创音乐节，在国内属历史悠久的音乐节IP，有着深厚的乐迷基础。近年来，迷笛音乐节频频走出一线城市，到内地的三、四线小城举办，同样具有票房号召力。不过，迷笛音乐节进驻南阳，是南阳地方政府招商引流的主动而为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据当地媒体报道，2023年5月，南阳市卧龙区委领导带队到北京迷笛音乐学校洽谈合作，卧龙区委领导表示，卧龙区拥有足够的发展空间和活动场景，希望双方推动合作，共同点燃城市活力，释放产业潜力，彰显文化魅力，为卧龙区的“城市生长力”注入更多年轻力量。迷笛音乐学校负责人则表示，卧龙区自然环境优美，文旅产业发展前景广阔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月2日下午，北京迷笛音乐学校负责人接受《南阳日报》采访时称，本届音乐节十分成功，创下了迷笛音乐节30年47届的最高票房纪录，现场观众人数也打破历届最高纪录，音乐节前夜观众就有两万多人，其他3天观众人数每天都接近4万人次，音乐节门票均提前卖光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，南方周末记者致电南阳市卧龙区文旅局，该局值班工作人员未提供更多的音乐节举办信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘瑞说，因为大城市限制较多，大型户外音乐节往三、四线城市发展的趋势非常明显，地方政府选择合作，有着招商引资、发展旅游的考虑；过从乐迷的角度看，能到不同城市游玩，看音乐节的同时感受不同地域的风情，也是不错的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，音乐节在10月3日便已结束，但是国庆长假还没结束，此前通常做法是，很多乐迷会选择继续在音乐节举办的城市游玩几天，然后再做返程安排。“这么多人来这里，吃的、喝的、玩的，是可以带动经济的。”刘瑞说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在刘瑞看来，在盗窃事件发生之前，整个活动其实非常成功，基本能够达到主办方的预期。他说，因为音乐节草坪刚刚铺设没多久，连续下雨之后，整个场地泥泞不堪，反倒演变成为大规模的“泥巴大战”，成为在各大社交平台、短视频平台疯传的画面；此外，一位来自河北的轮椅少年，在音乐节现场被众多乐迷托举起来致敬，也成为感动很多网友的经典画面。这众多因素，都让2023年的南阳迷笛音乐节频频出圈，引发外界关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“原来一切都很顺利，没想到出了这么个事。”刘瑞为迷笛和南阳感到遗憾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（文中刘瑞、吴思琪、刘铃为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[特诺奇蒂特兰沦亡五百年祭丨古国多少事⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257368]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;从亚特兰大飞往墨西哥城，沿途风景三变：首先由平坦肥沃的美国南部平原进入海天一色的墨西哥湾上空，随后以45度角纵贯墨西哥湾后进入温润可人、充满热带风情的墨西哥北部海岸，最后抵达粗犷的墨西哥中部高原，那是构成中美洲地峡的漫长火山带北端起点，于太平洋与大西洋之间连接起了南北美洲两块大陆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从飞机的舷窗可以清晰地看到，来自于墨西哥湾的湿润空气被挡在了中部高原北麓，形成连绵云带，最后化为降雨又再次滋润北部海岸。而平均海拔近2000米的中部高原则万里无云，阳光灼热；地面少有植被，非常干旱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;航班抵达墨西哥谷上空，那是首都墨西哥城的所在地，海拔2240米，在全球海拔最高的首都中位列第八。历史上这里叫做特诺奇蒂特兰（Tenochtitlan），中部高原的珍贵降水在这里汇集，曾经形成连绵的高山湖泊。它因此兴盛繁荣，也因此于五百年前归于毁灭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;众神之城&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;虽然墨西哥是中美洲的泱泱大国，西有绵延至北美洲的戈壁荒漠和温润舒适的下加利福尼亚半岛，东有尤卡坦半岛的低地丛林和热带草原，南北海岸有冲积平原和沼泽湿地，地形地貌十分丰富，但它的国名却来自于中部高原上几乎与世隔绝的墨西哥谷（Valle de México）。这是因为十六世纪初西班牙人来到这片地区时，最强盛的城邦特诺奇蒂特兰位于这座山谷，后来这里成为殖民者的首府：墨西哥城，“墨西哥”便成了整个殖民地的名字——西班牙语中&quot;x&quot;发“h”的音，“墨西哥”这个中文译音由此而来，若用英语来念的话成了“墨克西哥”，反而与本地地名不符了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;墨西哥谷其实是个盆地，海拔2200米的盆地周围环绕着海拔高达5000米的火山群，难以逾越。因此这里没有外流河，所有的降雨融水完全汇流至山谷底部，历史上形成了一片罕见的大型高山湖泊——特斯科科湖，其水域面积达到5400平方公里，是我国最大淡水湖鄱阳湖的约1.7倍。由于蒸发强烈，特斯科科湖水深度全年变化很大，形成了被反复淹没再出露的环湖湿地，这一点很像本版今年十月份曾经报道过的洞里萨湖（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《柬埔寨：洞里萨湖的三体世界》&lt;/span>;）。这片环湖湿地是莽莽高原中一块难得的宜居之地，在这里发展出了原始农业，从而成为中美洲古文明的重要发祥地之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Nf39MYflXfYxj5apLbXJpHlupSO19gKxLQIhwXey.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;墨西哥谷位置图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据考古学家发掘显示，一万两千年前这里就有人类居住，公元前1200年左右形成了城市规模，具体位置就在特斯科科湖西岸、今天的墨西哥城西郊——当时的中国尚处于商朝晚期的武丁中兴时期。这座城市后来被大湖西侧的火山爆发所摧毁，老百姓纷纷迁徙到大湖东岸，定居在一个被后人叫做特奥蒂瓦坎（Teotihuacán）的山坳，成就了一座千年文明古城。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎遗址是墨西哥首批世界文化遗产，也是旅行者们的必游之地。我在抵达墨西哥城的第二天就慕名前往拜访，其主体景观是一条叫做“黄泉大道”的南北向城市中轴线，东西两侧是密集的中美洲式梯形金字塔建筑。最大的两座金字塔目测几乎一般高，但位于大道北端的月亮金字塔地势较高，所以其实还是位于大道中部东侧的太阳金字塔更高一些。后者的基座为正方形，边长约225米，目前残存的塔顶高约64米。原本在顶层平台上还建有宏伟的神庙，但由于整个古城在1200年前就已被废弃，神庙早已完全无迹可循，如今既无法知道这座神庙是为了哪位神祇而建，也不清楚这座金字塔在鼎盛时期的确切高度。我们能够确定的是，它是在公元100年前后，在没有金属工具、没有可供驮运的家畜、也没有车辆的条件下，用300万吨巨石建成的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/6VDvlpq1qBNnMXsYZMRHeDeKWNVKF6KeQanjxuBk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中美洲原住民修筑金字塔的想象图&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我于1月中旬来到这里，胖嘟嘟的本地游客们穿着短袖顶着烈日排着长队等待攀登太阳金字塔：塔分四层，每一层都要重新排一次队，才能最终走完248级台阶登上塔顶平台，估计全程需要花2个小时。我叹了口气，放弃了世界第三大金字塔打卡计划，转而爬上了台阶陡峭的月亮金字塔，打开一罐激浪，一边平缓呼吸，一边俯视眼前的黄泉大道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的意思是“众神之城”，它和“黄泉大道”“太阳金字塔”“月亮金字塔”一样，都是后人对这座千年古城的臆测——由于特奥蒂瓦坎文明没有留下语言文字，石头本身又不会说话，历史学家并不掌握它的来龙去脉，只知道它是起源于公元前200年的城邦文明，全盛时代大约有20万以上人口，于公元八世纪前衰亡，只留下了令后人叹为观止的宏伟建筑与精美石雕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1446&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/25/BDcWwdorOlRgNdGuxLJwAIiD4avXQN84Icp0YXyE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特奥蒂瓦坎遗址是墨西哥首批世界文化遗产，图为从月亮金字塔俯瞰黄泉大道。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的第一拨后人是托尔特克人——后人并非后代，而是后来之人。托尔特克人在西北方不远的图拉建立了新的城邦，而将这座空寂无人却令人敬畏的废墟命名为特奥蒂瓦坎，意思是众神建造之地：他们显然无法相信这座中美洲最为宏大的古都是由人类自己建造的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特奥蒂瓦坎的第二拨后人是阿兹特克人，他们给古城的中轴线起了“黄泉大道”的名字，又把最大的两座金字塔命名为太阳和月亮金字塔。他们认为宏伟的金字塔群是天神为先王建造的陵墓，而这些死去的先王正是支撑太阳运行的潜在动力——这是基于一种从特奥蒂瓦坎到托尔特克再到阿兹特克一以贯之的独特世界观，也就是世界的存续维系于人类的献祭：以人的生命滋养世界的运行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人便是这篇故事的主角，特诺奇蒂特兰的缔造者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;湖中之国&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;特诺奇蒂特兰如今往往被称为“阿兹特克帝国”，这个名称从“阿兹特克”到“帝国”其实都不太妥当。先说“阿兹特克”（&lt;span>;Aztec&lt;/span>;），这是传说中来自墨西哥西北部的一个游牧族群，他们沿着荒凉的墨西哥高原南迁，最终抵达水草丰茂的墨西哥谷，在此定居下来，成为托尔特克人的附庸。托尔特克文明消亡后，他们与当地其他族群经过长期融合，构建了三个主要城邦之间的联盟，使用共同的语言，自称为墨西加人（&lt;span>;Mexica&lt;/span>;），也就是住在墨西哥谷中的人，形成了民族认同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果拿中国来做类比的话，这就相当于黄帝与炎帝两大部落结盟，构建了民族认同，其后代自认为炎黄子孙，又以所居住的中土而自称为中国人——这里的“炎黄子孙”和“中国人”可以大致对应“阿兹特克”与“墨西加人”两个概念。但我们如果把中国称为“炎黄国”显然不太妥当，因为“炎黄”是故老相传的上古神话；同理，“阿兹特克”也是存在于远古神话中的族群，将现实中的墨西加人国度称为“阿兹特克国”同样并不恰当。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再说“帝国”，刚才提到，这其实是三个城邦之间的松散联盟，并不存在一个大一统的帝国。因此，所谓“阿兹特克帝国”，其实就是墨西哥谷中由特诺奇蒂特兰主导的城邦联盟。这些原住民自称为墨西加人，自认为是阿兹特克人的后裔，他们建立的文明，如今叫做阿兹特克文明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/lWSWglsDOpKmCPaHu3pYwguCJR01ShDiYqOG5Ijl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特诺奇蒂特兰还原图，上方为东。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么特诺奇蒂特兰是怎样一个城邦呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传说当年阿兹特克人南迁时得到神谕，要寻找一只叼着蛇停在仙人掌上的鹰，那里便是他们新的繁衍之地。当他们经过长途跋涉到达特斯科科湖西岸的一座沙洲时，果然见到了这番景象，便在沙洲上定居下来，并根据酋长特诺奇的名字将沙洲命名为特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人建造了三条长堤，从北、西、南三个方向连接沙洲与湖岸，又在沙洲与湖心之间建了一条长堤，用来隔绝浪潮和来自大湖对面的攻击；他们从西岸引来山泉水，经长堤向沙洲供水饮用；由于火山灰中富含矿物质的缘故，特诺奇蒂特兰周边土壤非常适合耕种，他们以玉米为主粮，也种南瓜、豆类和苋菜；他们还发明了一种叫做奇南帕（&lt;span>;chinampa&lt;/span>;）的浮岛农业，有点类似我国长江中下游流域的圩田，从湖底取淤泥造田，用木桩和柳条固定，形成肥沃的人工岛，扩大种植面积；美洲大陆没有马、牛、羊这些家畜，特斯科科湖里也没什么鱼，他们主要饲养狗、兔和鸡鸭来获得蛋白质，做饭的方式是在石板上烤&lt;span>;——&lt;/span>;因为阿兹特克文明尚处于青铜时代，没有铁锅；他们铺设了排污系统，在管道接口处还会放一口大缸，污水中的垃圾沉淀在大缸里，定期派人清除；他们实施斯巴达式的全民军事教育，而贵族和富人则可以学到文化知识；由于没有铁，他们的武器是黑曜石做的矛、剑以及箭镞——黑曜石是墨西哥的“国石”，是火山熔岩冷却凝结后形成的一种天然玻璃，显然并不十分耐用，我从墨西哥带回的黑曜石匕首回到上海第一天就被儿子把玩时摔断了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/W9JLbcakm7OzBudPVGpVAOBHEaCV2ORjAbGGJAfh.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;黑曜石箭簇&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人将见证神谕的地方定为城邦的中心——在他们看来，这里也是当仁不让的宇宙中心——在此建立他们的神庙。这座神庙后来被西班牙人捣毁，用拆下的石料在其前方建造了墨西哥第一座天主教堂，用于镇压异教徒的“邪灵”，那就是今天的墨西哥城主教座堂（Catedral Metropolitana）。 457年后，市政工人偶然挖出了阿兹特克神庙的重要遗物：月亮女神石像，墨西哥政府遂决定拆掉遗址上方的建筑物，全面发掘这座大神庙，让阿兹特克人的神祇重见天日。于是，我们今天得以在墨西哥城市中心的宪法广场北侧同时看到两座比邻而居的世界文化遗产，西侧是巴洛克风格的主教座堂，东侧是半露天的特诺奇蒂特兰大神庙遗址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宪法广场古已有之，早在阿兹特克时代这里就是大神庙旁边的大型露天市场。西班牙人能把异教徒的首都夷为平地，却没有办法把一座广场摧毁成原始森林，于是就留了下来，作为主教座堂门前的中央广场。到了&lt;span>;1821&lt;/span>;年，为了庆祝墨西哥独立后颁布迪亚兹宪法，这里被命名为宪法广场。政府曾经筹划在广场上建一座独立纪念碑，这事儿由于财政原因只打了个地基就黄了。西班牙语里的&lt;span>;“&lt;/span>;地基&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;叫&lt;span>;zócalo&lt;/span>;，于是这里就被首都各界群众半写实半嘲讽地称为&lt;span>;Zócalo&lt;/span>;广场。没想到后来墨西哥其他城市的中央广场也跟着首都叫这个名字，结果&lt;span>;Zócalo&lt;/span>;这个词在墨西哥西班牙语中竟成了中央广场的意思。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/1NWLimGFx6W6OzjMdzHn66WAlYCl7v1Zl1ln1o44.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;大神庙嵌套模型&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大神庙的主体建筑是一座类似特奥蒂瓦坎太阳金字塔的四层梯形平台，体量上则大为缩水——毕竟特诺奇蒂特兰这座湖畔沙洲的承载能力有限。平台上方原本有两座祭坛，分别用于祭祀阿兹特克人的太阳神暨战神以及雨神，但早已毁于西班牙人之手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;貌似无甚可观？非也。这座神庙的独特之处在于：它外层包内层，里里外外一共包了六层——也就是说，从内到外一共有七座神庙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是怎么回事呢？原来特诺奇蒂特兰是一个尚武的城邦，控制着周边其他原住民城邦与部落。每当君主逝世，下一任统治者都会开展一场加冕战争，重新获得各个属地的忠诚。一旦他再次控制局面，天下布武，就会要求各邦各部派人来到特诺奇蒂特兰参与修建神庙，从基座开始砌个梯形金字塔外墙，把上一代君主修建的神庙包起来，将外墙封顶后形成一个新的平台，重新修建新的双祭坛神庙。这座新神庙的竣工标志着新一代君权的确立，可以视为“国之大事，在祀与戎”的墨西哥版诠释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么一来，大神庙层层嵌套，越修越大。运用简单的工程学原理就可以判断：这种“套娃“工程的土方量是呈立方关系增长的，对于国力消耗极为巨大，也是不可持续的。特诺奇蒂特兰立国近二百年，建造了七层这样的大神庙，所耗费的人力物力，并不亚于太阳金字塔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么这世世代代修建的一系列大神庙用来干什么呢？以活人为牺牲，向天神献祭祈福——简单说来，就是杀人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/Luefy4DQN79nus9nDBOvGxZDUSvecV8ONmvbaEsv.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;查克是人与神之间的信使，用于供奉人心。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;嗜血文明&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人自认为是太阳的后裔，相信日出是太阳神战胜黑暗的结果。他们认为世界已经毁灭过四次，如今正处于太阳神与黑暗群神的第五次较量之中，太阳神需要子民为他提供滋养，那就是人血。因此，阿兹特克人不分男女，从小就习惯于使用尖锐的龙舌兰刺在耳垂、舌头、胸膛乃至生殖器采血祭神，祭司则从自己的太阳穴蘸血作画，敬献给太阳神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，采血祭祀只是个人行为，比采血更神圣的祭祀仪式是公开的活人献祭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已故美国考古学家Patricia R.Anawalt曾在其论文《对阿兹特克人祭的理解》中开章明义地说过：“用活人作祭品，无论在新大陆还是在旧大陆都出现过。这样的例子不仅在中美洲找得到，在美索不达米亚、埃及和中国也都找得到。所不同的是阿兹特克的人祭早已为人所知，而对旧大陆的古老文化的认识则是最近的事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以我国为例，上世纪二十年代末启动的安阳殷墟发掘工作让我们得以了解殷商时期的大规模活人献祭，仅殷墟一地发现的人祭尸骨即达到3684具。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而阿兹特克人的人祭行为在西班牙征服者的渲染之下更让人触目惊心，考古挖掘的新发现则证明西班牙人的记载并非对于失败者的一味抹黑。比如，墨西哥考古学家曾在大神庙附近意外挖出大批骷髅头骨，它们并不像一般的万人坑、乱葬岗，而是朝着同一个方向整齐地排成三维矩阵。经过清理，考古学家奇怪地发现，所有头骨两侧都有破洞，显然是被人为凿穿的。最后当整片遗址发掘完毕，大家才明白是怎么回事：原来这里曾经是一个三十多米长、四米多高的五排石架，架子上插着许多木梁，木梁上穿着成排的头骨——正如西班牙人的记载。后来这里被泥土掩埋，木梁朽坏，便形成了地下头骨矩阵。考古学家用阿兹特克人的语言将这片遗址命名为“骷髅之墙”，挑选了三具头骨用木梁串起来，展示于大神庙后侧的博物馆中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结合文字记录与考古发掘成果，如今已经可以大致还原大神庙的活人献祭：在广大国民的围观之下，被献祭的人牲在大神庙前列成长队，一个个被带上四层平台，仰面躺在双祭坛前的人牲石上；由主祭司手持黑曜石匕首切开人牲的胸膛，掏出尚在跳动的心脏，供奉给太阳神；尸体沿石阶扔下基座，由次一级的祭司将其首级割下，剥去头皮，在头骨两侧钻孔后穿在刚才提到的骷髅架上；人牲的四肢被肢解，交还给他们的提供者，躯干则被遗弃，人牲的鲜血会和玉米饼和在一起作为与神灵沟通的食物，以至于西班牙人来到大神庙时，首先注意到的就是石阶上积累近两百年的血迹和它散发的浓重气味。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;911&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/KtUOhvUnluAvcqX0MBhOTiEKcgtVLhIUHFigtnN7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;马利亚贝奇亚诺手抄本中展示的阿兹特克人祭场面&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克人宰杀的人牲数量相当惊人，常被引证的是1487年的记载，在4天里屠杀了201个400人，也就是80400人。不过这个数字不太可靠，因为当时特诺奇蒂特兰的人口总共也才20万人。考虑到阿兹特克人所说的“400”其实是虚指，意为大量，比如作为大地女神最小儿子的战神就曾经杀死他的400个哥哥成为主神，那么这条记录的意思也许只是杀害了201批人牲。历史学家含糊地把这4天内的受害人数削减到两万人——饶是如此，这也是一个惊人的数字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于上文提到人牲的“提供者”，这涉及墨西哥谷的地缘政治。阿兹特克人近乎狂热地使用活人献祭来维持太阳东升西落，祈求农业风调雨顺，在一片干旱粗粝的高原上维续这座湿地城邦的有限农业资源。但他们并不想耗费自己的人力资源，因此热衷于四出征讨，获得战俘以供祭祀。后来周围部落都被打服了，不愿继续作战，甘心每隔八个月向特诺奇蒂特兰上缴一次贡品。但阿兹特克人依然不肯收手，继续发动其“荣冠”战争，也就是没有宗教、政治、领土和经济诉求，纯粹为了获得人口用于献祭的战争，类似原始部落“猎头族”的行为，最后演变为各个臣服部落定期向特诺奇蒂特兰献出人口，供其屠杀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了上述常规的人祭方式，还有两种特殊的人祭值得一提：一是为了献祭太阳神暨战神，更为“高端”的祭品是俘获的敌国将领，他被绳索拴在一块大石头上无法逃脱，使用羽毛棒与手持狼牙棒和盾牌的本族武士搏斗。如果他能够连胜四人，再与一个左撇子武士搏斗获得胜利，就可以重获自由——当然，这纯属赤裸裸的欺负人；二是为了献祭雨神，使用的祭品是儿童——阿兹特克人相信儿童在祭祀过程中流下的眼泪将会变成灌溉农田的雨水而带来丰收。作为一个父亲，我就不详述这项祭祀的过程了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/VOjzDzuXu2Y8ilgysMO5wzjd5jWj0bdrFK46AXj7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;由两条蛇交织而成的雨神面具，绿松石代表水&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，大神庙博物馆里还陈列着千奇百怪的牺牲：美洲豹、美洲狮、狼、鳄鱼、白鹭、琵鹭，甚至还有大量的石刻头骨——这些或许意味着阿兹特克人正在走出蒙昧，逐步取代野蛮的活人献祭。可惜的是，随着一群现世神祇的降临，他们不再有机会继续演进了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/EZqMPRkG6iEvihm03szFjjQNCSU3g1ahMdrmfF0g.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;石骷髅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;天外飞仙&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;“201个400人”活人献祭后5年，哥伦布抵达加勒比海地区，开始在古巴建立殖民地。西班牙人花了27年站稳阵脚，然后于1519年2月15日派出一支由11条船、550人和16匹马组成的远征船队前往今天的墨西哥，这支船队的首领叫做埃尔南·科尔特斯（Hernán Cortés），被墨西哥人视为史上第一大恶人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科尔特斯首先在尤卡坦半岛东岸的Cozumel岛登陆补给，那里现在是加勒比海邮轮之旅中最重要的港口之一。然后他率领船队沿着尤卡坦半岛向西绕行，被沿途的原住民视为天神下凡：原住民没有见过马，也没有见过骑兵，所以认为骑兵是长着四条腿能够移动如飞的神怪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科尔特斯知道自己人单势孤，无法与人数超过五百万人的整个原住民阵营相抗衡，但他很快发现，这个阵营并非铁板一块，而是由特诺奇蒂特兰主导的三城联盟，统治着一群弱小的部落，对抗墨西哥谷以东的两个敌对城邦。特诺奇蒂特兰的敌国们深知其嗜血本性，坚决不肯屈服；特诺奇蒂特兰的属国们则长期匍匐于其暴政之下，不断付出供品和人牲，同样叫苦不迭。于是，科尔特斯明智地与这两个城邦结盟，共同对付特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在特诺奇蒂特兰这边，阿兹特克人非常崇敬统治墨西哥谷的前辈托尔特克人，全盘接收了托尔特克人的世界观。根据托尔特克人的神话传说，他们离开了墨西哥中部高原，在墨西哥湾下海前往东方追寻羽蛇神——中美洲多个文明所供奉的主神，并将于1519年跟随白色皮肤的羽蛇神从东方回归墨西哥谷。所以，当国王蒙特祖马二世听说一群“漂浮的城堡”从东方蹈海而来，在墨西哥湾登陆，他的第一认知是：神灵回归人间了！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/HOVnY2hvuFt8apVFPXLAO5w6cERjHJcGMepTqhNs.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;特诺奇蒂特兰大市场还原模型&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1519年11月8日，科尔特斯带着人数微不足道的远征军以及六千名原住民盟友在中部高原绕了两个几字形的大弯后从特斯科科湖南岸经长堤进入特诺奇蒂特兰，见到了这座闻名已久的水上圣城，也是当时世界上人口最为稠密的都市之一。他被当作天神一般受到了蒙特祖马二世的隆重接待，被安置于国王父亲的宫殿。大约半年多以后，也许是阿兹特克人看出了西班牙人的野心，也许是西班牙人有意识地捣毁阿兹特克神像，双方发生了冲突，意图息事宁人的蒙特祖马二世在谈判中被科尔特斯扣为人质，随后在双方各执一词的混乱中受伤致死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年后的1521年5月，对特诺奇蒂特兰的地形与弱点已经了如指掌的科尔特斯带着九百名西班牙援军和十万名土著盟军卷土重来。天下苦阿兹特克久矣！过去的属国纷纷反戈一击，形成了墙倒众人推的态势。阿兹特克人孤军奋战，在错综复杂的河网中凭据一座座浮岛、一栋栋房屋负隅顽抗。 93天之后，整座岛城被夷为平地，特诺奇蒂特兰灭亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联盟的中枢败亡后，整个墨西哥都被西班牙轻松控制。殖民者将这里命名为Nueva Espana，意为“新西班牙”。又过了三百年，到了1821年，墨西哥才获得独立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/26/QlzSo1mDuxdcpBoOOPH74SQdPvb657bvpUivQoP4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;172828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;国家宫壁画展示西班牙殖民者攻破特诺奇蒂特兰。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;尾声&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;从墨西哥城机场坐地铁五号线进城，需要在La Raza站换三号线。 La Raza是个换乘大站，差不多相当于北京的东直门站或者上海的龙阳路站，转趟车得步行五六分钟。每次经过这里，我都会在漫长的甬道中部逗留片刻，细细观赏路边玻璃柜里陈列的变形金刚全家福，仿佛被拉回到了九十年代的少年时光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在五百年前，生活在这里的阿兹特克人也像卡通片中的地球人一样迎来了在技术层面足以对他们形成降维打击的变形金刚：西班牙人。只是，现实中并不存在像汽车人那样博爱仁慈的救世主。他们最终退缩到大湖中央的特诺奇蒂特兰，被冷酷无情的威震天所率领的霸天虎们屠杀殆尽，烟波浩渺的大湖也被这些天外飞仙抽干，成了今天持续下沉的墨西哥城。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿兹特克文明就这样完结了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[智力残障女性被标“18.8万，交钱结婚”：婚姻介绍还是人口贩卖？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日有博主发文，称某短视频平台主播发布的征婚视频引人不适，引发舆论关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个网名叫“才哥（全国相亲)”的“婚介主播”长期在短视频平台发布相亲信息，明码标价彩礼价格。被介绍相亲女性中有多位是智障人士，视频中不乏“18.8万，交钱结婚”这种令人严重不适的内容。网友怀疑，该网红是个公开明码标价的人贩子。该主播则表示他们是“正规婚介”，有需求可以到线下婚介所相亲，交完彩礼另付2万元介绍费就可以把人领走，“先结婚后恋爱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事掀起舆论波澜，不少网友认为这是“人口贩卖”。 10月4日晚间，云南省弥勒市政府工作人员告诉《上游新闻》称已关注到此事，当地已经成立多部门组成的工作专班，分组对此事进行核查。细审这起事件，除了令人不适之外，更显露出一些深层次问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，这起事件带来的最大问题是，如此短视频婚介存在哪些法律与道德上的破口？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚姻应该遵循自愿原则。 “自愿”应理解为可以自主表达，有完全民事行为能力，可以做出有法律效力的意思表示。然而，残障人士的情况比较特殊，是否可以行使完全民事行为能力登记结婚，需要分情况看待。如果残障人士只是肢体残疾而不影响辨认自己行为，则具有完全民事行为能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而如果残障人士是精神方面的残障，那么还可以细分为“不能完全辨认自己行为”的限制民事行为能力人，以及“不能辨认自己行为”的无民事行为能力人。限制民事行为能力人只能独立实施纯获利益的民事法律行为，或者与其智力、精神健康状况相适应的民事法律行为，其他的情况与无民事行为能力人一样，需要由监护人来代为行使民事权利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题在于，监护人是否有权代替残障人士行使民事权利，做出登记结婚的重大决定？在这起事件中，“婚介主播”的短视频多遵循“年龄＋智力状况＋广告语＋彩礼”的套路，明晃晃打出“相亲”“闪婚”的广告字眼，一开始就冲着“收钱结婚”去的。残障人士在此期间有无机会表达自己的真实意愿？或者，婚介方与监护人是否会征询残障人士的意见？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些问题的答案当然是大有疑问的。尤其是在有利益驱使的情况下，监护人未必会尊重残障人士的真实意愿。甚至于从人性角度来讲，监护人面临“丢掉一个累赘，收到一笔大钱”的真实激励。在这条婚介产业链上，残障人士成了最没有话语权的相关方，沦为婚介方与监护人的摇钱树。这有悖于起码的人伦道德，也存在法律上的疑问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在2021年的“河南省泌阳县55岁男子娶20岁智障女子”事件中，当事女性父亲的所作所为曾经引发巨大争议。作为智障女儿的监护人，父亲与继母一手做主“包办”了这场“婚姻”。事后官方调查组的结论是，两人同居不违法，但不能办理结婚证。这个案例就显示，类似“婚姻”的法律效力是存疑的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，“人口贩卖”的疑云在事件中挥之不去，尤其是与“彩礼”结合到一起的时候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这名“婚介主播”在接受音频采访时表示，“正常的女孩子彩礼在15万以上，最低也得10多万”“我们要拿两万的服务费”“一对一服务，过来一个成功一个”“两星期内领好证把老婆带回去”。诚如网友所言，挂着彩礼名号的“明码标价”，确实令人直接联想到人口贩卖。这不仅是观感上的不适，也同样涉嫌真正的违法犯罪行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不论这位“婚介主播”多么强调自己的“合法合规”，“拿到彩礼两星期内领证”的操作怎么看怎么都像是变相的人口贩卖，“来一个成功一个”的表述更是让人完全看不到残障女性在其中的发言权，这在根本上已经违背了《中华人民共和国民法典》中“婚姻自愿原则”的法律条文，唯一可以作为补丁的就是监护人的同意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;监护人的意见真的就可以代表残障人士的自主意愿吗？这是存疑的。同时，十多万的高额彩礼，最终可以用来改善残障女性的婚后生活吗？这笔钱最终会落到谁的手里，也是不问可知。如果监护人“收钱给人”，那么这无异于银货两讫的人口贩卖，退一步讲也是不折不扣的强迫婚姻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更有甚者，类似“婚介产业”还开发了针对残障女性的“细分赛道”。因为容易被操控，他们甚至还可以“反复回收”残障女性。 “买家”在结婚生子之后还可以“退回媳妇”，然后再“介绍”给下一家去怀孕生产，“婚介所”从中再收取一笔佣金，这又无异于直接倒退回已经进入历史垃圾堆的“生育奴隶制”了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚姻的基础应该是爱与道德，而不是买卖与算计。但如果加入残障人士这个特殊变量，买卖婚姻甚至买卖人口的性质就加倍地凸显出来。面对如此明目张胆的“标价征婚”，有关部门理应拿出不亚于“泌阳事件”的严肃态度，追查其合规性，保障残障人士合法权益，维护婚姻家庭价值观，不能让残障人士成为一手交钱一手交货的现代奴隶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[读《村上私藏：怀旧美好的古典乐唱片》的乐趣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk9rrT15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/NrHooXfb2YWhgVkmSI2JGOatUMo7qVTKkk 9rrT15. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Haruki Murakami and his new book &quot;Murakami&#39;s Secret Collection: Nostalgic and Beautiful Classical Music&quot; record&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(CFP photo/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese writer Haruki Murakami likes to collect, and one of the things he collects is classical music records, especially Regarding vinyl records, the previously published &quot;Murakami&#39;s Private Collection: Nostalgic and Beautiful Classical Music Records&quot; is a selection of the records he collected. In this small book, the format of which is made like a record cover, he said that he has visited record stores around the world in the past 60 years and bought more than 10,000 old records. He specially selected some of his favorites. , write down why you like it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Murakami stated clearly at the outset that this book &quot;is at best a book of personal preferences and interests, without any systematic or practical purpose, and there is no such thing as &#39;This is a must-listen to this piece of music!&#39;&quot; recommendation intention”. This book is like a continuation of the earlier &quot;Murakami T&quot;. Readers like Haruki Murakami very much and want to know what clothes he wears and what records he listens to, that&#39;s all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, every piece of classical music has countless recording versions. Different conductors, orchestras, performance times, and even the same piece of music but different recording and pressing techniques make each record version unique. . In today&#39;s vast number of streaming music platforms, there are only the tip of the iceberg with different recorded versions. When reading this book by Murakami, I always think: Ah! It turns out that this song also has this version, and I really want to listen to it. However, it is not easy to retrieve the records introduced in the book according to the diagram. After all, many of the records introduced by Murakami in the book were produced in the 1950s and 1960s. You can either try your luck in old record stores or You can go to the famous record trading website discogs to hunt for treasures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Murakami said that his choice of records is based on personal preference, so many classical music fans have opinions on his choice, but when it comes to personal preference, naturally everyone has what they like. different. Just like Murakami himself said that he doesn&#39;t like pianist Alfred Brendel very much, but Brendel is liked by many people. Which version and conductor you like is often related to your own experience. Since Murakami is a good friend with the famous conductor Seiji Ozawa, he naturally prefers Ozawa Seiji’s version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beyond personal experience, another reason is the preference for interpretation of music. Sometimes musicians’ interpretation of music is very distinctive (even to the point of sensationalism), and music fans do not pay the price (or The reason why I like it (in turn) is relatively easy to explain. For example: Mahler&#39;s Seventh Symphony, if you listen to Otto Klemperer&#39;s version (compared to most versions, the whole piece is almost 20 minutes long), the extremely slow style feels like Watching the train in the distance enter the platform, the train gradually approaches but always seems to never arrive. Some people say this is a kind of tension, but I don&#39;t like it very much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what, Murakami always has his own unique approach when writing these music reviews, so that even if readers are just reading Murakami’s short reviews of classical records, they still have the pleasure of reading Haruki Murakami’s words. For example, he said that Mozart’s Piano Concerto No. 25 recorded by pianist Friedrich Gulda with the Vienna Philharmonic (conducted by Abbado) sounded “like eating clear soup udon at an Osaka udon shop” Such an incredible sense of security&quot;; or when Sir Thomas Beecham conducts Haydn&#39;s Symphony No. 94, there is always an impression of &quot;a graceful old-time British gentleman, even the &#39;surprise&#39; part of the second movement, The method of frightening is also steady and elegant. Even a woman holding a tea cup will not be frightened to the point where the black tea will overflow.&quot; These metaphors are very unique and very Haruki Murakami. How could Mozart or Gulda ever think that his work would turn into a bowl of Osaka&#39;s clear soup udon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, back to an important question: Why listen to vinyl records when listening to classical music now? Or the bigger question is: How can vinyl records be brought back to life? The return of vinyl records is one of the most inspiring stories in the history of human development. It has obviously been obsolete by the times, heavy and fragile, and has a pitiful carrying capacity, but facts have proved that as long as it is valuable, even if it is full of shortcomings, it still has the meaning of existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Haruki Murakami said in &quot;Murakami&#39;s Private Collection: Nostalgic and Beautiful Classical Music Records&quot; that listening to vinyl records is &quot;the kind of thing that will respond as long as you treat it carefully.&quot; In an age where everything is digital, giving and responding have long become a very formal exchange. Everything is just a button in exchange for a reaction, and the satisfaction gained by giving with heart has been lost. Just like no matter how carefully and gently you touch the streaming music platform on your mobile phone to play music, there will never be any difference in the music played (so in fact, we naturally don’t touch our mobile phones so gently). The quality of &quot;responsiveness&quot; has become rare in today&#39;s cold world, which is why vinyl records are enjoying a renaissance today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When listening to vinyl records, from buying the record to playing it, every step requires &quot;careful treatment&quot;. One of them is audio playback. Whether listening to vinyl records or streaming platforms, it is a knowledge as deep as the sea. For example, the most basic turntable, pre- and post-amplifiers (audio amplifiers), speakers, or the cartridge and stylus used in the turntable, the wires and connectors for connecting the equipment, and even the record pads on the turntable for placing records, are all very particular. Haruki Murakami also said that audio is a &quot;hobby that can only be cultivated if you have some spare time. There is nothing you can do about it, you can only have this awareness.&quot; Having said that, as long as you don&#39;t buy an all-in-one playback turntable that only costs a few hundred yuan and only looks good, a simple set of decent entry-level audio equipment is actually affordable, and it can already reflect the preciousness of vinyl records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not just audio equipment, buying (and finding) vinyl discs is also an activity that requires dedication. In places like Europe and the United States, there are stores selling second-hand items such as The Salvation Army and Lexi Club in different communities. In these thrift stores, there will always be a corner filled with boxes of old records. If there are some responsible people, The store clerk (or the neater owner) will sort the records and put them away. At this time, slowly squat down, flip through the records one by one, and take a look. Each one is unknown, and you can meet your favorites at any time. These old records are often only priced at ten yuan or eighty yuan, which is incredibly cheap. Unlike other used record stores, these used stores are non-profit-making. The people in charge do not have time to set prices slowly, and they usually do not understand the market and the value of the goods like an insider. So, it’s easy to find treasures in these thrift stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the records bought at thrift stores are in different states. It usually takes more time to clean them properly, and sometimes you get damaged records. There is no way to avoid these, so you have to Check carefully when buying. But as Haruki Murakami said, even if it is an old record, as long as it is cleaned carefully (cleaning records is also knowledgeable), there will still be a significant difference in the playback sound quality before and after cleaning. At least the stylus will not accumulate accumulation after the record is played. A pile of dirt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, stores that specialize in old records often do basic cleaning of the records and clearly indicate the condition and quality of the records. Correspondingly, the prices will be correspondingly expensive. Comparing different record stores around the world, Japanese record stores tend to be the neatest and cleanest. No wonder my good friend, Mr. Jiao Yuanpu, said that when he goes to a second-hand record store in Japan, he spends 7 hours every time there, and he goes there from dawn to dusk. Listening to his sharing, it is a very big sacrifice in terms of both mental and financial resources. Of course, it will be rewarded with a bumper harvest every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大城府：泰国那一抹“永恒的微笑”丨古国多少事⑦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Dark red ocean&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, whether you charter a car from Khao San Road in Bangkok or take a train to make an appointment For an hour, when you can see the spiers and the splendid street signs in the distance, the strong historical atmosphere will come to you - Ayutthaya is located on the alluvial plain of the Chao Phraya River, above the tide line of the Gulf of Siam, surrounded by the Mekong River. Surrounded by the Nan River, the Lopburi River and the Pasak Canal, it forms a unique island city. There are waterways leading to the Gulf of Siam in the south, which can connect China and Southeast Asian countries. It also tightly controls the sea gateway of Sukhothai in the north, becoming a gateway for China, India, and The geographical connection point between Europe and the United States also gave it unique conditions in trade, military, and diplomacy: from the 14th to the 18th century, its developed water and land transportation and dazzling Buddhist architecture made its reputation famous in Southeast Asia and even the entire Asia, and was even regarded as Southeast Asia. The largest and most beautiful city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/t0o7trafKMIk2PsnCo9PrdxkPIBcspxi8gj5WHEH.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199733&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Buddha statues and relics at Wat Mahathat&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1350, the leader of the Luo Zhen (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;now Lopburi&lt;/span>;) regime on the west bank of the Chao Phraya River was Ramathetbodhi (&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ramathibodi I, King Uthong&lt;/span>;) defeated Thailand&#39;s first feudal dynasty, the Sukhothai dynasty, and Luo Zhen merged with Siam, the Supan regime on the east bank of the river, to establish A The Yudaya Dynasty is called &quot;Siam&quot; in Chinese historical records. When Bangkok was still a little-known fishing village, the capital of the Ayutthaya Dynasty was already a prosperous &quot;big city&quot; - Chinese people in Thailand thought this city was the largest, so it was called &quot;Ayutthaya&quot;, and even the dynasty was also called &quot;Ayutthaya Dynasty&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In historical documents, Ayutthaya is called &quot;Paradise&quot;. At its peak, the population was about 1 million. Three royal palaces, more than 2,000 gilded minaret temples and more than 4,000 gilded Buddha statues made this place full of charm. The dynasty, which lasted 33 kings and lasted for 417 years, brought Buddhist culture to its peak. In the middle and late period of the Ayutthaya Dynasty, Zhang Xie of the Ming Dynasty also wrote in his &quot;Siam Articles&quot; in &quot;The Examination of Eastern and Western Oceans&quot;: &quot;The soil is wet underneath, the climate is hot and humid, and the people live in high-rise buildings. The rattan system is very strong, with rattan mats and bamboo mats for sleeping in the middle. The palace is more than nine feet high, decorated with gold and carved with eight trigrams, which is extremely magnificent.&quot; Beginning in the 16th century, Ayutthaya&#39;s reputation spread far and wide to Europe, in 1512 The Portuguese first arrived here in 1988, and Ayutthaya gradually became a trade center in the 17th century, with envoys from various European countries arriving in droves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the main color of Ayutthaya a few hundred years ago was gold, now here, to be more arbitrary, the city center only has two colors: reddish brown and burnt black: reddish brown is the dusty bricks of the building. Scorched by the scorching sun and eroded by wind and rain, the uneven floors and walls turned into a dark red ocean. Many ancient temples in Ayutthaya appear to be replicas of Angkor Wat at first glance, but after careful inspection, you will find that unlike Angkor temples, which are mostly made of large stones, red bricks are mostly used here; there are no carved walls, There are thousands of corridors here, but many unique architectural styles of the Ayutthaya Dynasty are derived here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wat Lokaya Sutha (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Lokaya Sutha&lt;/span>;) can no longer be called a &quot;temple&quot;. In a piece of overgrown grass, a huge reclining Buddha is exposed in nature to accept worship; the Wat Phra Si San Phet built in 1491 (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Phra Si San Phet (Temple of the Three Kings) The three remaining white Ceylon-style pagodas are lined up in a row and have become landmarks in Ayutthaya: In 1492, in order to enshrine the ashes of his father and brother, Rama Tepbodhi II built two pagodas in the temple. The pagoda started Thailand&#39;s funeral custom of using pagodas to store the king&#39;s ashes. In 1529, when Ramathebodhi II died, his son built another pagoda. Today, time has not completely destroyed them. Although the many small towers built by successive kings nearby are seriously damaged, they are still majestic and towering, like solemn guards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the east of Wat Pasi Sangbi is the Rajapurana Temple (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312) which is famous for the magnificent pagoda in the main courtyard. , STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Ratchaburana&lt;/span>;). This Khmer-style pagoda was originally Thai-style. It was built by the ninth king to hold the cremation for his two brothers who died in a duel for succession to the throne: in 1424, King Indraja died, and the two brothers fought each other on elephants. After the death of the first prince, the third son inherited the throne from Phitsanulok and became Borommarachathirat II (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat II&lt;/span>;). This temple houses the ashes of my brother. After passing through the gate with only one wall left like Ruins of St. Paul&#39;s, you are surrounded by fragmented Buddha statues and walls, as if you suddenly fell into the distant ancient times. On the main tower, which looks like a stick of corn, there are layers of corrugated tower decorations; surrounded by four small Ceylon-style towers, it is the most complete Khmer-style pagoda in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The oldest temple in the city is in the southeast corner outside the moat, Wat Yai Chaiyamongkho (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Yai Chaiyamongkho&lt;/span >;) Built in 1357 by King Utong to commemorate the birth of the dynasty. Different from the ruined temples in the city that are full of vicissitudes of life, traces of reconstruction can be seen everywhere here, but they do not make people feel obtrusive. They are not even as good as the yellow silk draped in the pagoda. The visual contrast with the mottled red bricks is strong. The 28-meter-long white reclining Buddha is the symbol here. Wearing a yellow cassock, he lies peacefully on his side under the hot white sun, looking indifferently at the weather-beaten land and rivers around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climb up to the Ceylon-style main tower. There are eight Buddha statues inside. What is even more unforgettable is that a strange mixed smell permeates it. The smell of gunpowder smoke is mixed with the smell of decaying plants, and more of the human body stench. , making it difficult to breathe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/O8ZavUlGZts4QzA5JEiQYYEJ6WNcHmgpnydEoF4Q.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chaiwatthanaram Temple, the back of the Buddha statue&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;The dark reflection of prosperity&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the tourists disappeared, only a piece of tranquility washed over the years remained around the reclining Buddha in Yacha Mengkong Temple - around the main tower, many headless Buddha statues stood silently , seeming not to want to tell the story of their experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The name of Ayutthaya comes from the birthplace of Rama in the Indian epic &quot;Ramayana&quot; and the place where Rama ascended the throne after his triumphant return (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ayodhya&lt;/span>;), Sanskrit means &quot;the invincible city&quot; or &quot;the city of eternal victory&quot;, but this name is just like the prophecy: as the second largest city after the Khmer Empire A &quot;superpower&quot; in Southeast Asia, when the Ayutthaya Dynasty reached its peak, the war between it and Myanmar also continued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All glory must come to an end. In 1766, King Meng Bo of Myanmar, who had coveted Ayutthaya for a long time, led his army to siege the city for 14 months. After 14 months of siege, he blew down the city wall and entered the city. After 15 days of burning, killing and looting, 30,000 people were taken prisoner and Ayutthaya was almost razed to the ground. Flat ground. The invincible city was destroyed in the war - the longest dynasty in the history of the Kingdom of Thailand, with all its splendor, came to an abrupt end in 1767, leaving only a dozen temples that had been &quot;washed away from the glory&quot;. ——There are many black fire stains on the red bricks, and the Buddha statues were also blackened by the flames. They stood silently in the city, testifying to the golden age of the Ayutthaya Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ayutthaya, the opposite of red is black. South of the Rajapurana Temple, Wat Mahathat (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Mahathat&lt;/span>;) is said to be the primary target of the Burmese army&#39;s attack on Thailand: This monastery was built in 1374 during the reign of King Borommarachathirat I (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Borommarachathirat I&lt;/span>;) and had 10 In the remaining monasteries, there are more than 200 pagodas like a jungle. Now only the huge square pagoda base is left in the middle of the temple, and many of the smaller pagodas are seriously tilted and crumbling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/6195U6sn6f8c0tGvvLkiR9ucZIqb3IjpSLOsZU80.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rows of headless Buddha statues at Chaiwatthanaram Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In Ayutthaya temples, many of the Buddha statues &quot;sitting in rows&quot; have no heads. A pair of stone Buddha feet or a huge Buddha hand will be &quot;surprised&quot; in the corner on the ground. The look is very &quot;post-modern&quot; &quot;. Perhaps for this reason, many tourists like to bend their knees and hide behind the Buddha statue, and stick their heads out from the broken neck of the Buddha statue to take pictures. In fact, the Buddha statues and pagodas in Wat Mahathat were plated with gold or contained gold leaves, which led the Burmese army to behead the Buddha statues or burn them in fires, causing the gold to separate from the stone, causing expansion and contraction of the Buddha statues&#39; heads. , hands and feet were broken, leaving the remains of limbs and arms devastated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ayutthaya is like the Old Summer Palace. The sunlight paints the high tower of Wat Chaiwatthanaram (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wat Chaiwatthanaram&lt;/span>;) in golden color, giving the red bricks a fierce beauty. , taking people back to the war-torn era. When the red has turned to black, the pagoda stands alone. The mottled pagodas, broken brick walls, dark Buddha statues, and vast monuments ruthlessly cover up the prosperity and destruction. Only the remaining documents and oral stories are passed down from generation to generation, and the years are like a passing cloud - -The prosperity of the prosperous times will also become the reflection of disillusionment, just like the long-lasting lonely back of the Buddha statue sitting high on the almost collapsed base in Chaiwatthanaram Temple in the sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the army invaded, the Buddhist temples were completely destroyed. Wherever the knife fell, as the writer Ondajie said, &quot;the towering Buddha image with profound meaning fell to the ground and fell into the soil.&quot; Over a long period of time, a Buddha&#39;s head was tightly wrapped by the thousand-year-old Bodhi root, and the surrounding branches and vines entangled it, forming the wonder of a tree wrapping the Buddha&#39;s head. It is also the most famous &quot;eternal smile&quot; of Wat Mahathat. . Just like the &quot;endgame&quot; of the view of Ta Prohm Temple in Angkor Wat, the strangulation phenomenon of trees in Southeast Asia will eventually cause plants to replace their hosts. However, the Buddha statue is still smiling in the Bodhi tree with his eyes closed and saying nothing, as if he has watched the changes in the dynasty. , it is a kind of magical demeanor that is with everything and transcends life and death, allowing people to stand in front of it and stare at it for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/lmZSQApUZC6H2cHR93AVBJ73b6xdvLXGmP79YlDz.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The wonder of the Buddha head wrapped in a tree at the Mahathat Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Thousands of people spent time building the Ayutthaya City, and the Ayutthaya City watched the world created by these thousands of people in the light and shadow. After the fall of the Ayutthaya dynasty, Taksin moved the Thai capital nearly 100 kilometers south to Thonburi. After only 15 years of the Thonburi dynasty, the Bangkok dynasty established its capital in Bangkok in 1782, writing prosperity on the new land, and Ayutthaya was Fading out of people&#39;s sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two hundred years have passed by, and now it is more like a small town full of rural atmosphere and leisure atmosphere. In the ruins park, lawns, green trees, and ponds create an idyllic scene; locals will spread out mats for picnics, or rent traditional costumes to imitate the popular TV series &quot;A Match Made in Heaven&quot; that was filmed here, and take photos in the ruins. The red and black ruins are close to the newly built houses and temples. The fireworks and water blend among the ruined bricks and stones, giving a sense of astonishment as if you have traveled through time and space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/07/02/x7hi1VxguExowXr794aIulu9kB1uHbU8QeHdUO1p.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;199734&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Elephant on the lawn of Bangbain Summer Palace&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Yameng/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Between Ayutthaya and Bangkok, Bang Pa-In Summer Palace was built in the 17th century (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bang Pa-In Summer Palace&lt;/span>; ) is the largest and most beautiful royal palace in Thailand. After being restored in the 19th century under the orders of King Rama IV and King Rama V of the Bangkok Dynasty, it has all the architectural styles of Thailand, China, Myanmar and Gothic; it also has the typical Thai &quot;three spires&quot; The golden water pavilion, the pink blue, lilac, and pure white buildings are quite fresh, and paired with tropical green plants that make up cute elephants, Bang Bain Summer Palace bids farewell to the strong red and tragic black. Overflowing with the refreshing green of a new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亚运女篮铜牌赛上演朝韩对决，韩国以93比63获胜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258150]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Park Jin, known as the &quot;North Korean Female Giant&quot; Ah Zai defended the Korean team players. She made 11 of 16 shots in this game and handed over a report card of 27 points, 9 rebounds, 3 assists and 1 block.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /06/6538a1ca76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253069&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, there will be a &quot;North Korean female giant&quot; Park Jin-ah, who is known as the Korean team player, is defending the Korean team players. In this game, she made 11 of 16 shots and handed over a report card of 27 points, 9 rebounds, 3 assists and 1 block. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, 2023, the women’s basketball bronze medal match of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou was held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium. The South Korean team defeated the North Korean team 96-63 and won the bronze medal in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;In the group stage encounter between the North and South Korean women&#39;s basketball teams, the South Korean women&#39;s basketball team relied on its overall outstanding performance to defeat the North Korean women&#39;s basketball team 81 to 62 and win the game. Although the game on October 5th was only a bronze medal match, it was still a highly watched game. Park Jin-ah, known as the &quot;North Korean female giant&quot;, missed the semi-finals against the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team and returned again against the South Korean team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, the North Korean women&#39;s basketball team, which is mysterious and rarely goes out to compete, stood at the height of the semi-finals, reflecting the This shows their tenacious and hard-working sportsmanship.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/50bf945329.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253070&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, the North Korean women&#39;s basketball team, which is mysterious and rarely goes out to compete, stood at the height of the semi-finals, reflecting their tenacious and hard-working sportsmanship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Park Jin-ah, the No. 17 player of the North Korean team, took off with the ball and shot the basket.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/06/d6e92f05e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253071&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 10 On March 5, Park Jin-ah, the No. 17 player of the North Korean team, took off with the ball and shot the basket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, players from North Korea and South Korea competed in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/06/2e7ccad5d6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253072&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023, North Korea Players from South Korea and South Korea competed in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the opening warm-up and training state, we can see the determination of the North Korean women&#39;s basketball team to revenge. Park Jin-ah was very efficient in the first quarter. Not only did he score with the ball, he also performed well in assists and rebounds. On both offense and defense, Park Jin-ah has the ability to revitalize the team. The North Korean team led 21-15 in the first quarter. However, entering the second quarter, the North Korean team made a lot of mistakes and their shooting percentage also dropped. South Korean team center Park Ji-soo also had an outstanding performance in the second half of the second quarter, unknowingly scoring 17 points. Before halftime, the South Korean team locked the score at 40 to 33, and the pressure came to the lagging North Korean team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, spectators cheering for the North Korean team in the auditorium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/06/f121c1845a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253073&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 On the same day, spectators cheered for the North Korean team in the auditorium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, South Korean team player Park Ji-soo broke through the defense of North Korean team players.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/06/11829a6fb8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253074&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 , South Korean team player Park Ji-soo broke through the defense of North Korean team players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, No. 12 player No. Shuying of the North Korean team made a breakthrough with the ball.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/06/35fe524b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253075&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 On the same day, No. 12 player No. Shuying of the North Korean team broke through with the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, the coach of the North Korean team gave instructions to the players.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/06/00511c4400.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253076&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023, North Korean team The coach gives instructions to the players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half, North Korea tied the score at 40 within three minutes, and then the centers of the two teams each scored a mid-range shot to tie at 42. Then Park Jin-ah and his teammates had continuous problems in communicating internally and externally, and the game entered the fourth quarter with the North Korean team trailing 44 to 61. The fourth quarter became the performance moment of the Korean team, especially Korean team veteran Kim Dan-bi, who quietly scored 21 points. He even made 5 of 8 three-pointers, taking the team&#39;s three-pointers to 13 of 25. With three and a half minutes left in the game, the South Korean team already led 84 to 51 by 33 points. North Korea threw a long three-pointer at the buzzer, and the score was fixed at 93-63. The North Korean women&#39;s basketball team lost to the South Korean women&#39;s basketball team by 30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, after the game, the players of the Korean team took a group photo to celebrate.&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/06/4e6748a0d3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253077&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 , after the game, the Korean team players took a group photo to celebrate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although Park Jin-ah, the North Korean player who played the whole game, scored a game-high 27 points, the gap in book strength between the two sides was too big. Facing South Korea The team made 14 of 27 three-pointers, which seemed like a drop in the bucket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欧洲公厕为什么很少且收费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258137]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Toilet may seem like a small thing, but it is also a necessity of society. In many cases, it can reflect the history and present of a society. , China and foreign countries are no exception. Everyone who has traveled to Europe will have experienced the toilet dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are generally very few public toilets in European countries, and it is often only possible to find one within a few kilometers, so there are apps for finding toilets in Europe. In contrast, in China, the function of finding toilets is covered by map apps. It is not a popular feature and cannot support an APP alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being cheap, toilets in Europe also charge a fee. In many European countries, such as the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, Germany and other places, you have to pay to use public toilets. For example, most of the toilets in high-speed service areas or shopping malls in Germany have to pay. Even the toilets in fast food restaurants, shopping malls, train stations, McDonald&#39;s, and KFC are charged. For example, in Cologne, Germany, there is a fee for using the toilets inside McDonald&#39;s. For another example, a KFC in Poland posted a notice: The restrooms in the store are only available to customers. People without consumption receipts need to pay 30 zloty (approximately 53 yuan) if they want to use the restroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also various forms of charging. There is a person sitting at the door to collect the fee, there is a gate that rotates after a coin is inserted, and some are trustworthy and put a tip tray. In some stores, the toilet door has a password, and the password is printed on the shopping receipt. Not every floor of German department stores has restrooms. They are usually located near the restaurant floor on the top floor. Using the restrooms is generally free, but if there are cleaners there, a tip of about 0.3 euros is usually required. If you are in a tourist area, we will also thoughtfully provide exchange rate conversion, and the prices in each country&#39;s currency are clearly marked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charges for European toilets are not cheap. The last trip to the toilet costs as little as 0.3 Euros and as much as 2 Euros. 1 euro is equivalent to 7.7 yuan, which is equivalent to between 2 yuan and 15 yuan. Even if the income is higher, going to the toilet in Europe is really not cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the richest regions in the world, Europe is also a region with the most complete &quot;social welfare&quot;. Why are there so few free public toilets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it’s because of history. In many European cities, such as London, England, Stockholm, Sweden, and Paris, France, there are semi-open open-air toilets on the streets. It wraps the lower body but can only be used by men. These open-air urinals are used very frequently in the local area. This strange street urinal has been around in Europe for nearly 200 years. This also reflects the historical origin of the lack of public toilets in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result of this historical path, people may not regard public toilets as a government obligation. In fact, public toilets in many places in Europe are basically privatized. In this case, solve the problem according to market thinking. Toilets require regular maintenance and repairs, and you also need to hire someone to clean them. Most European countries are developed countries, and labor costs are high. This has resulted in high maintenance costs for toilets. Businesses are unwilling to include it in a package of services, but charge separately. supply. Private toilets in European cafes, small bars and other commercial places assume some functions of public toilets. Of course, you must consume food first and then use the toilet. Europeans are also accustomed to paying to use public toilets, or go to a coffee shop to buy a cup of coffee to solve their internal problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation in European countries is not exactly the same. In Denmark, which has high taxes and high welfare, the government believes that the freedom to use public toilets is a public service that the government must meet. Therefore, in the urban area of ​​Copenhagen, the capital city with a small population, there are sufficient public toilets, good environment, and they are free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Chinese toilets also used to charge fees. From the late 1970s to the late 1980s, as the economy developed, cities in China began to build higher-grade public toilets one after another, implementing water flushing and mechanical pumping. As the level of public toilets has improved, the cost has also increased. Some cities have begun to charge for public toilets to alleviate the shortage of funds for public toilet construction and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the 20th century, with the further development of the economy, Chinese people began to have higher requirements for toilets. New residential areas were built, and toilets were increased from one to two bathrooms. However, public toilets are not free so early. In mid-tier cities like Qingdao, public toilets were not open for free until May 1, 2008, which is only 15 years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free public toilets, after all, the government has money. After years of accumulation of reform and opening up, especially after joining the WTO, the economy has developed rapidly, real estate has taken off, and local governments have obtained sufficient funds from land finance, so they are able to bear the entire cost of public toilets. Therefore, free public toilets in China are mainly the result of economic development. Whether to charge or not is closely related to the economic situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Toilet charges are essentially a matter of government revenue and the scope of government public services. If the situation of public toilets in Europe is very bad, it is because of historical, cultural and customary reasons. Society has also developed various alternative forms and people have adapted to them. In some countries, the benefit of free public toilets has never appeared, and naturally it is not felt much. But if you return from free to paid again, you will have a different perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[粉黛花海迷人眼丨指尖华夏⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the golden autumn, and Naluhua is in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province Domestic pink grass has entered its best viewing period, and the sea of ​​flowers is like a &quot;pink ocean&quot;, attracting tourists to come to watch, play and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists play among the Nalu flowers and flowers in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;772&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/叶顺强/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>