<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[一根跳绳卖78元？杭州中考专用绳调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261288]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;If it wasn&#39;t required by the school, I definitely wouldn&#39;t buy it&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“This brand of skipping rope is a bit heavy. Originally, children can jump more than 190 times per minute, but this kind of skipping rope can only jump 160 times. If it were not required by the school, I would definitely I won’t buy it.” Mr. Huang, a citizen of Hangzhou, said that his son will take the high school entrance examination next year, and the sports test will be skipping rope. Since the brand of skipping rope chosen for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination was &quot;Hengyou&quot;, in order to familiarize the children with the rope used for the exam in advance, he had no choice but to buy this skipping rope after being designated by the school teacher. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I checked the same type of rope online. One rope only costs more than ten yuan, and this one costs 78 yuan.” Similar to Mr. Huang, a primary school student in Shangcheng District, Hangzhou City Ms. Lu, the parent of a second-grade student, said that almost all of the 39 students in her child&#39;s class bought &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand skipping ropes at the teacher&#39;s request. Some parents even bought two, one for practicing at home and one for practicing at school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In August 2020, five departments including the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Opinions on Further Strengthening and Standardizing the Management of Education Fees&quot;, which clarified that &quot;students and parents shall not be forced or implied to purchase designated fees.&quot; Teaching aid software or materials”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Why do some schools recommend buying this rope even though it is explicitly prohibited? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some physical education teachers in primary and secondary schools in Hangzhou said frankly that rope skipping is a must-test sports event for grades one to six in primary schools; in middle schools, it is also one of the items in the high school entrance examination. Since the rope used in Hangzhou&#39;s high school entrance examination is &quot;Hengyou&quot;, some primary schools also use &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping ropes to compete with middle schools. &quot;It is better to use it early than to use it late. We will recommend parents to buy the &#39;Hengyou&#39; rope to strengthen training, but teachers are not forced to buy it. The school will also provide corresponding skipping ropes to try to meet the needs of students.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A junior high school student in Hangzhou told reporters that because the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope is relatively expensive, she usually uses rubber ropes that cost a few yuan a piece when practicing at home; Practice with the school&#39;s &quot;Hengyou&quot; rope. &quot;Some students in the class who are from well-off families also bought a &#39;Hengyou&#39; rope with a Bluetooth counting function, which costs more than 140 yuan.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter investigated and learned that, Some head teachers or physical education teachers in primary and secondary schools in Hangzhou asked parents to purchase ropes of this brand by verbal notification or by sending links to parents in groups. The customer service of the Hengyou Sports Taobao flagship store said that the Hangzhou high school entrance examination skipping rope provides &quot;Hengyou&quot;, and many schools in Hangzhou Shangcheng, Gongshu, and Xiaoshan recommend buying this rope. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Coach Huang from a &quot;rope skipping class&quot; in Hangzhou told reporters that more than 20 primary and secondary school students who came to his training also felt that the rope used for the high school entrance examination had heavy handles and thick ropes. Other ropes are easy to jump on. &quot;In order to prepare for the exam, the children can only sign up for training classes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Why did the &quot;Hengyou&quot; rope become a special rope for Hangzhou&#39;s high school entrance examination? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Is there a standard for the rope used in the high school entrance examination? Shen Hao, deputy director of the Hangzhou Municipal Education Examination Institute, who is responsible for purchasing sports equipment for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination, said that neither the country nor the province has standards for ropes used in the high school entrance examination. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is understood that the national skipping rope standard stipulates the length and diameter of the rope and the diameter and weight of the handle, but this standard is a recommended standard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“In fact, the length of the rope and the thickness of the handle of the &#39;Hengyou&#39; skipping rope are designed according to adult standards, which is not suitable for primary school students - primary school students are small and weak. The &#39;Hengyou&#39; skipping rope is heavy, not easy to jump, and easy to break,&quot; said some primary and secondary school physical education teachers in Hangzhou. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is understood that the manufacturer of &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope is Shenzhen Hengkang Jiaye Technology Co., Ltd. Tianyancha shows that the company was founded in 2006 and is an enterprise mainly engaged in the manufacturing of cultural, educational, industrial and aesthetic, sports and entertainment products; Hangzhou Feiniao Sports Goods Co., Ltd. and Hangzhou Xingti Education Technology Co., Ltd. have both represented the company in Zhejiang. Jump rope products. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The relevant person in charge of Hangzhou Feiniao Sports Goods Co., Ltd. admitted that since entering the Zhejiang market in 2011, the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope has been the test rope used for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination Sports; the current market It has covered all major urban areas in Hangzhou, and more than 100,000 tubes are sold in Zhejiang a year, of which more than 70% of users are primary and secondary school students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, how did the &quot;Hengyou&quot; rope become a special rope for Hangzhou&#39;s high school entrance examination? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Since about 2011, the Hangzhou Education Department has been leasing and using high school entrance examination sports equipment produced by Shenzhen Hengkang Jiaye Technology Company. After 2017, we have Using an open bidding method, the annual rental fee for leasing sporting goods produced by this manufacturer is 8.9 million yuan,&quot; Shen Hao said. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some skipping rope manufacturers said that they also tried to enter the range of sports ropes for Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination, but found it difficult. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter was in a &quot;Single Source Announcement on the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute&#39;s High School Entrance Exam Physical Examination Equipment Leasing Project&quot; (January 2019) published by the Zhejiang Provincial Government Procurement Network It has been seen that the Hangzhou Municipal Education Examination Authority plans to use the &quot;single source&quot; procurement method (leasing) to purchase high school entrance examination physical examination equipment from Hangzhou Xingti Education Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason for the application given by the Hangzhou Education Examination Authority is: &quot;For many years, the physical education examination of Hangzhou urban high school entrance examination has been using the products produced and produced by Shenzhen Hengkang Jiaye Technology Co., Ltd. The original equipment rental service provider for the physical education high school entrance examination equipment and examination system developed is Hangzhou Xingti Education Technology Co., Ltd. The equipment system operates stably, the service response is fast, and the high school entrance examination physical examination tasks are successfully completed every year. From the continuity of use, the examination system Considering the integrity and specificity of the software management platform, it meets the condition of &#39;can only purchase from the only supplier&#39; in single-source procurement.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Shen Hao said, ten For many years, Hangzhou Sports High School Entrance Examination has been leasing equipment from the manufacturer &quot;Hengyou&quot;, including skipping ropes, skipping rope testers, etc., so the result is that the rope used in the high school entrance examination today is &quot;Hengyou&quot;. In addition, this company is one of the earliest manufacturers to develop intelligent counting rope skipping. Compared with the past, invigilators used to count the number of rope skipping by candidates with their eyes, this kind of intelligent counting is fairer and more efficient. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“It is actually not profitable to lease physical examination equipment to the Hangzhou Education Examination Authority. Our market is more of the market for primary and secondary school students, which is under the physical examination mechanism of primary and secondary schools. Policy market.&quot; The person in charge of Hangzhou Feiniao Sports Goods Co., Ltd. said frankly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Break the hidden brand monopoly and give parents and schools more choices&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Some skipping rope manufacturers said that countable skipping ropes are not high-tech products and can be produced by any manufacturer. &quot;We hope that by improving the bidding methods and establishing standards for ropes for primary and secondary school physical education examinations, parents and schools will have more choices.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Now there is no The cost of a high school entrance examination rope with a counting function does not exceed 8 yuan per rope; the cost of a high school entrance examination rope with a counting function does not exceed 20 yuan. The prices of &#39;Hengyou&#39; non-counting and counting skipping ropes are respectively sold at 78 The price is 148 yuan, and the profit margin is huge.&quot; revealed a brand merchant in Zhejiang that produces skipping ropes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that administrative agencies and organizations authorized by laws and regulations to manage public affairs shall not abuse administrative power to eliminate or restrict competition. &quot;If the education and examination department uses a certain brand of skipping rope for a long time without justifiable reasons, especially if it simply purchases a certain product through the &#39;single source&#39; procurement method without extensive investigation and understanding of market products, it is obviously against fair competition in the market. Principle.&quot; said a staff member of the Zhejiang Provincial Market Supervision Department. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The relevant person in charge of the Hangzhou Municipal Education Bureau said: &quot;We are also reflecting now on whether we can improve the current high school entrance examination sports skipping evaluation method by referring to other places that have done well. Including whether students can be allowed to bring their own ropes to take exams, whether more brands of rope skipping equipment can be used, etc., to avoid unnecessary trouble and burden on students and parents.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打着“国家补贴”的幌子欺诈乡下老人，何以屡屡得逞？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261196]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, I turned on my phone camera as usual to see what my parents were doing, but found that the door to my home was locked. , it wasn’t until the phone call at night that my father found out that there was a place selling goods in neighboring villages these days, and villagers from all over the country came to join in the fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After calling several aunties in the village, I learned about the relevant situation: a week ago, a group of Mandarin-speaking outsiders chose to set up sheds in an open space beside the village road. There are people specially guarding the place, and the elderly are free to enter. There are many small benches inside, and loudspeakers are turned on. Young people are on the stage preaching the efficacy of a certain product, and then encouraging the elderly to buy it. Obviously, this is a product promotion meeting, but it has two obvious characteristics: first, the promotion location is in the village, located in a pure rural area; second, the sales target is the elderly, and they are all left-behind elderly people in rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is a sales meeting or a merchant advertising, it cannot be said that there are many violations, but upon closer inspection, it is still full of &quot;routines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About daily arrangements. It is understood that this kind of sales meeting usually lasts for 6-7 days. In the first 4-5 days, someone will explain the relevant knowledge to make the elderly believe it. One of the common tricks is to exaggerate certain aspects of the elderly&#39;s problems based on the characteristics of the product to be promoted. For example, when promoting water purifiers, one would say how poor the quality of water commonly used in rural areas is and what harm it causes to the body. The purpose It makes the elderly feel that if they do not buy their products, the consequences will be very serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second trick is to frequently use some scientific and technological means during the explanation process, such as on-site testing of water quality, using special instruments, professional testing methods, and demonstrations by academicians and scientists to convince the villagers. This is scientific, advanced and developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third trick is that a group of people will jointly &quot;perform&quot; the explanation process, including outsiders, locals, and perhaps people who are quite prestigious in the local area. The business owner&#39;s assumption is that you don&#39;t have to believe it. Foreigners, but locals should believe it, right? There is a high probability that merchants bribe a small number of local people through money and other means. The goods will be sold in the next 1-2 days. That is to say, there is a process of first acting with emotion, convincing people with reason, first brainwashing, winning people&#39;s hearts, and finally harvesting (money). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About identity changes. A few days ago, merchants used various videos, speeches, performances, etc. to gain the trust of the elderly. In the process, the merchants transformed into many roles. A few days ago, they were outsiders and they were technology explanators in the countryside. Members, they are rural revitalization helpers, they are psychologists who are familiar with and understand the psychology of the elderly, they are health guardians who care about the physical and mental health of the elderly, and they are philanthropists who send warmth to the countryside; two days later, they returned to their The essential role - a profit-seeking businessman, a villain and a villain who defrauds honest village elders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About what is sold and given away. What they ultimately want to sell is a certain brand of water purifier, and the items they give away are divided into two types: a few days ago, they were paper towels, wash basins, toothpaste, toothbrushes, washing powder, and laundry detergent. Only those who came to the scene could see it. portion; the next two days are range hoods, wall breakers and heating and cooling air conditioners. Obviously, the gifts given a few days ago were mostly cheap and practical things in rural areas. As long as you go there, they will give them to you. When people go there, there are so many people, it is easy to cover the eyes of some onlookers. Yes, there are people. A herd mentality, especially for old people in the countryside. They will think, &quot;Are they all fools, right? I&#39;ll go take a look too.&quot; The gifts in the next two days are also very practical, but anyone with a discerning eye will know at a glance that they are not cheap, but the condition is that you have to spend money to buy the net. Water vessels are only given by others. In other words, the things they sell and give away are not cheap. This method of selling one large item and getting three large items for free makes many elderly people feel that this business is full of sincerity and is not a profiteer in the ordinary sense. , some old people even stood up to speak for them, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter even if they are cheated in the end. Thousands of dollars are gone, but at least four real things are in hand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About price. Take the main product for sale, water purifiers, as an example. My mother told me that the price is 2,980 yuan per unit. I simply searched on regular e-commerce platforms such as JD.com and Taobao and found that I can buy it for only 400-500 yuan. Find similar products with good quality. Faced with such a huge price difference, merchants&#39; compensation tactics include intimidation, bragging and gifts. What’s even more annoying is that my mother told me that the merchant would say that the price of 2,980 yuan was still a lowered price after enjoying the national subsidy policy for technology products going to the countryside. In other words, the original price may be 4,980 yuan per unit. Now it is the business that benefits the people. After deducting the 2,000 yuan of state subsidies, the villagers have a rare opportunity and opportunity to buy one unit for 2,980 yuan. As soon as these words came out, the old people&#39;s previous defensive mentality was easily defeated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About people entering. My mother told me that those people were very friendly. Every morning at seven o&#39;clock, the car would arrive at the entrance of the village on time, pick up the elderly in the village, and prepare breakfasts such as fried dough sticks, steamed buns, and milk for the elderly, and deliver them to the sales meeting for free. When we arrived at the scene, someone brought us tea and water, and the service was quite attentive. At twelve o&#39;clock at noon, the car took the elderly home on time to cook and eat. At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, the car will appear in the village on time, waiting for the elderly; at 5:30, they will take the elderly back to their homes. A friend of mine who is about the same age as me told me that a similar activity was held in their village last weekend. He wanted to go into the shed and have a look, but did not want to be dissuaded by the person guarding the door. The meaning was obvious, only the elderly could enter, and young people could not go in. , middle-aged people, don’t give in. Obviously, businesses are afraid of the presence of young or middle-aged people because they are worried that young or middle-aged people will expose their tricks in public, and young people or middle-aged people will openly oppose them, which will seriously affect the elderly. purchasing psychology, reducing the purchasing intention of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above is the relevant situation that I heard or learned, which triggered some other thoughts in me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the basic fact is that some businesses defraud ignorant elderly people in the countryside under the guise of &quot;expanding domestic demand&quot; and &quot;enjoying national subsidies for technological products sent to the countryside.&quot; To be honest, many product manufacturing companies exist in name only. However, under market-oriented conditions, although many companies persist, their main products have long been eliminated by the market. Especially in urban markets, they are already saturated. What should we do? Of course, the company just thought about it and moved its tentacles downwards to occupy the urban and rural markets. There is no doubt that this is a move by companies to expand domestic demand. However, it is difficult to say how good the quality of this type of product is, and the price is many times higher than the price of similar products purchased online. It is undeniable that there is deception and fraud in the product sales process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the abnormal behavior of rural elderly deserves scrutiny. First, why do elderly people who have been living frugally for most of their lives not hesitate or feel distressed when faced with a large purchase of close to 3,000 yuan? I think there is a problem of transfer of family (words) rights (power) here. Nowadays, most of the things in many people’s homes are purchased online by their children outside the home. You buy it and I use it. In the past, I bought it and everyone used it. Now that I am old, I don’t need to buy it. You and your children buy it. That&#39;s good. I don&#39;t have much contribution to this family anymore, at least not as much as before. The elderly are more of just passive recipients of gifts and users of objects. They have little opportunity or need to participate in the purchase and sale of objects, especially large items. The process of selection, screening and purchasing is a deprivation of consumption. Now there is such an opportunity, I pay, I buy, I make the decision, I am happy. Even if they find out in the end that they have been fooled and deceived, they will feel distressed to some extent, but they will also accept the reality calmly, &quot;Where is the use of money other than money? I just spend money to buy something? You can easily spend hundreds of dollars on a meal in Guangzhou. Thousands, you think I don’t know? It’s too expensive for me to buy something?” My mother would use words like this to rebuke me, even in the face of my earnest attempts to dissuade her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, knowing clearly that there is a high probability that it is a trick of a liar, knowing clearly that there is no free lunch in the world, why do the elderly insist on &quot;traveling to the tiger mountain&quot; instead of believing in evil? This is mainly due to the fact that many elderly people have been in rural areas for a long time. They are kind-hearted and honest, and are prone to overflowing with sympathy. They do not understand the complexity of society enough, have limited knowledge of profiteers, have shallow knowledge, and lack basic anti-fraud awareness and skills. Businessmen They often take advantage of this fatal weakness of the elderly and succeed every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A grandfather who finally spent 800 yuan to buy ostrich milk said, &quot;You (young people) can&#39;t say that they are all liars. Hello, I have to say, I can&#39;t buy nothing, I can&#39;t be like this.&quot; Obviously, during the shopping process, the old man felt that it was not just a purely monetary transaction, but also included emotional feedback, that is, people If someone treats us well and takes good care of us, we should also &quot;treat others with courtesy&quot;. This &quot;courteous&quot; way is to buy other people&#39;s things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, why do the elderly not choose to consult their children outside for their opinions or suggestions? The author learned that during the few days of the sales meeting, many elderly people acted silently, went silently, bought silently, and returned silently. They would not take the initiative to inform their children outside of home about this situation. Of course, they were worried that their children would worry about them, or even Scold them. As old people, of course they care more about face. If they are scolded by their children, they will feel shameless. This is certainly not a situation they like to see. In fact, many elderly people are used to &quot;being independent&quot;. &quot;Don&#39;t interfere with what I do or what I buy. I&#39;m not old yet. I haven&#39;t reached the stage of Alzheimer&#39;s disease yet. I have my own judgment and ideas.&quot; , please mind your own business.&quot; This should be the true mentality of many elderly people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, another possibility is caused by the so-called &quot;disconnection&quot; phenomenon, that is, many children living outside have little contact with their parents on weekdays, and their care is relatively scarce, or even indifferent. When encountering this matter, they suddenly became &quot;doubly concerned&quot;. The old people would feel that the young people were &quot;hypocritical&quot; and &quot;too fake&quot;. Yesterday afternoon, one of my cousins ​​called his father several times at the sales venue to ask him not to buy any ostrich milk. Unexpectedly, his father got tired of hearing this and said angrily, &quot;It&#39;s not your money. I&#39;m willing to spend it. You don&#39;t have to pay for it.&quot; &quot;No matter what,&quot; then hung up the phone and turned off the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, joining in the fun is actually quite scarce in many rural areas. My mother went to the market for six days in a row. I didn&#39;t understand it, but my father said it was okay. &quot;I have nothing to do anyway. It&#39;s okay to go and have some fun. It&#39;s fine if I don&#39;t buy anything.&quot; My father&#39;s &quot;strategy&quot; was not to let my mother bring cash or mobile phones, and then not allow her to borrow money from others. Every night on the phone, my mother was cheerful, talking about who she met yesterday and who she met today, whose daughter got married, whose son bought a house, and the steamed buns she served today tasted good. Obviously, my mother&#39;s mind is not on the sales meeting or the product. What she cares about is being able to see and chat with her friends every day. Yes, in today&#39;s rural areas, young people have gone to cities, children have gone to school, and even the elderly are not far apart from one village to another, but they are not close either. For a mother who is nearly seventy years old, there is nothing special. I won&#39;t go to neighboring villages to visit. On weekdays, she just wandered around the village and spent time with her father every day. You looked at me and I looked at you. Occasionally, they would have a few words, saying that her later life was very fulfilling and not boring at all. That was a lie. Obviously, she will be lonely, she will be lonely, she will have nothing to do, social interaction is her real need, and going to the sales club every day for a walk can make her extremely happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can’t help but think of when I was a child. At that time, there were often acrobatic troupes performing in the village, and occasionally people would come to the village to show movies. The scene was spectacular and lively. Times have changed, and in today&#39;s rural areas, many people have their doors locked all year round. The only permanent residents in the village are the elderly. Hollow villages or hollowed-out villages abound. Obviously, the permanent population has dropped sharply, and there are no or few public recreational activities, making the elderly even more lonely, which will inevitably seriously affect the quality of life of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, regarding the fact that rural elderly people are (easily) deceived, I think young people might as well be more free and easy-going, encourage them to visit and go shopping, and tell them to be more vigilant. However, there is a basic fact that it is difficult for us to say now or in advance that the things they buy are fake or counterfeit. This requires a period of testing to see the effects after trial or consumption. If in the end, they find that the items they purchased are indeed inferior products, and they have really been fooled, there is no need to be angry or angry with them, because they have finally gained something, such as meeting and chatting with old friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山东莱荣高铁被举报偷工减料存在质量隐患，官方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261300]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 19:51:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On July 20, the media reported that there were some threaded piles in the construction of the first three sections of the Lairong High-speed Railway Station. The pile length did not reach the designed pile length, and the design change procedures were not completed, resulting in quality hazards and other problems. The National Railway Administration, the Shandong Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government attached great importance to it and immediately established a joint investigation team composed of the Shanghai Railway Supervision and Administration Bureau and the Shandong Provincial Department of Transportation to conduct investigations in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The joint investigation team dispatched more than 120 professionals from across the country to conduct on-site investigations, and organized 10 experts in railway, geology and other fields to provide technical guidance. It lasted more than two months, carried out geological exploration and drilling inspection, interviewed 14 relevant units and 83 people, reviewed more than 29,000 pieces of data in 130 categories, and formed an investigation report and more than 100,000 words of investigation supporting materials. After the investigation was completed, seven experts, including academicians of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, were invited to demonstrate the investigation and conclusions. The joint investigation team verified the issues reported by the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problem that the pile length of some threaded piles constructed by Sanjie Company did not reach the designed pile length. The joint investigation team entrusted a testing agency to carry out drilling and sampling tests on the threaded piles subcontracted by China Construction Eighth Engineering Group Co., Ltd. to Sanjie Company and other units for construction in accordance with relevant specifications, and simultaneously carried out infill geological exploration; it entrusted a professional agency to supervise the whole process and conduct inspections on the quality and safety of the roadbed foundation. Comprehensive Evaluation. Through the infill geological survey of the subgrade base constructed by Sanjie Company, it is shown that the thickness of the granite weathering layer and the fluctuation of the weathering layer interface in this section vary greatly. After on-site inspection and comprehensive analysis and evaluation, the construction pile length of the threaded piles in this subgrade section is consistent with the height and low fluctuations of the bearing layer revealed by the infill geological survey, and the &quot;unable to drive&quot; phenomenon has occurred. The construction pile lengths of some threaded piles have not reached the design pile length. , but the threaded pile pile end has entered a better bearing layer, which does not affect the quality and safety of the composite foundation. No corners-cutting was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the issue of failure to perform design change procedures. After investigation, when the threaded pile construction did not reach the designed pile length but the pile end entered the bearing layer, the participating units only met on site to confirm and failed to perform design change procedures in accordance with regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After comprehensive investigation and evaluation, the bearing capacity of the composite foundation in the subgrade section as reported by the media meets the engineering requirements, and the stability and post-construction settlement meet the requirements of relevant railway specifications. There are no composite foundation quality problems or safety hazards. It does not affect the safety of railway operations. At the same time, the settlement deformation was observed and evaluated after the completion of the composite foundation. The results showed that the actual measured and evaluated post-construction settlement of the entire Lai-Rong High-speed Railway line met the specification requirements. The acceptance results of the joint debugging and joint testing of the Lai-Rong High-speed Railway and other acceptance results show that the Lai-Rong High-speed Railway meets the track smoothness requirements during the operation of 350km/h high-speed railway and meets the safety and stability requirements of high-speed train operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation found that during the construction period, Sanjie Company and China Construction Eighth Engineering Bureau had conflicts in terms of construction progress and project payment. They had withdrawn from the construction in June 2021, and the two parties have not reached an agreement on resolving the disputes. . The investigation also found that there were problems in construction management such as inadequate on-site management and irregular project subcontracting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the investigation conclusion, in response to existing problems in design changes, construction management, project subcontracting, etc., the Shanghai Railway Supervision and Administration Bureau imposed administrative penalties on the relevant responsible units and 7 responsible persons in accordance with the law; in accordance with relevant regulations, The construction unit China Construction Eighth Engineering Bureau Co., Ltd., the supervision unit China Railway Second Institute (Chengdu) Consulting Supervision Co., Ltd., the design unit China Railway Fourth Survey and Design Institute Group Co., Ltd. and the construction unit Shandong Lairong High-speed Railway Co., Ltd. The person responsible shall be punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[活到110岁可领每月3500元津贴？四川“长寿之乡”真有老人领过]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261294]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 19:58:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;June 1, 2022, Meishan, Sichuan, Pengshan District Senior Citizens Association Golden Autumn Song Band, The theme activities to celebrate the &quot;June 1&quot; International Children&#39;s Day were carried out at the Changshou Archway Square. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3606e94891.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;753&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/3606e94891.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259567&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 1, 2022, in Meishan, Sichuan, the Golden Autumn Song Band of the Pengshan District Senior Citizens Association celebrated the &quot;June 1&quot; at the Changshou Archway Square. International Children&#39;s Day themed activities. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 21, 2023, the Social Affairs Bureau of Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District, Sichuan issued a notice to adjust the payment standards for senior-age allowances, raising the Old age allowance payment standards. One of the pieces of content sparked heated discussion - for seniors aged 110 and above, the allowance standard for each person has been adjusted to 3,500 yuan/month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Is there any old man who can receive this money?&quot; &quot;In order to receive this 3,500 yuan, I have to live to be 110 years old!&quot; before forwarding this news In the comments, netizens ridiculed one after another, and some people questioned that this standard was too high and lacked sincerity. Because of the heated discussion, this news became a hot search topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I have had it before, and I have been receiving it for several months.&quot; A staff member of the civil affairs system in a district and county under the jurisdiction of Meishan City responded to the Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;Longevity &quot;Culture&quot; is a major feature of the local area. After the introduction of the old age allowance, some 110-year-olds who meet the standards have indeed enjoyed this policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tianfu New District Meishan Management Committee is affiliated to Meishan City. Public information shows that the cumulative amount of senior-age allowances distributed in Meishan city has exceeded 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“It’s not superfluous”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The above notice shows that the adjusted old-age allowance payment standard is: 80 to 89 years old, 30 yuan /month/person; 90 years old to 99 years old, 100 yuan/month/person; 100 years old to 105 years old, 1,500 yuan/month/person; 106 years old to 109 years old, 2,500 yuan/month/person; 110 years old and above, 3,500 yuan Yuan/month/person. The adjusted old-age allowance payment standards will be implemented from January 1, 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tianfu New Area is a national-level new area under the jurisdiction of Sichuan Province. It is composed of Tianfu New Area Chengdu Area and Tianfu New Area Meishan Area. The Meishan area of ​​Tianfu New District includes the original 2 towns in Pengshan District of Meishan City and 5 towns in Renshou County. The Meishan Management Committee of Tianfu New District was established in 2015 and is at the county level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the notice aroused heated discussion, the Social Affairs Bureau of Meishan Administrative Committee of Tianfu New District confirmed the authenticity of the notice to the media. The relevant person in charge of the bureau said that the previous old-age allowances were distributed according to the standards of Renshou County and Pengshan District. Last year, after the bureau took over the specific matters of the payment of old-age allowances, it decided to adjust the payment standards based on the actual situation in the jurisdiction, &quot;so that more elderly people can enjoy this inclusive system.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, there are no elderly people over 110 years old in the new area. There were some who have passed away now. There are about 50 elderly people over 100 years old.&quot; The above-mentioned person in charge introduced to the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter learned that previously, the amount of elderly allowance in Pengshan District was relatively high, while that in Renshou County was relatively low and there was no age group over 110 years old. This adjustment In fact, the standards of Pengshan District are uniformly adopted in the Meishan area of ​​Tianfu New District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pengshan District is the main birthplace of Peng Zu, the ancestor of Chinese longevity stars, and is known as the &quot;Hometown of Longevity&quot;. As of the end of 2022, there are 55 people over 100 years old in Pengshan District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;They (Meishan District of Tianfu New District) have two towns, which Pengshan passed through, so many of the policy standards for benefiting the people are the same as ours.&quot; Pengshan District A staff member at a social assistance station told Southern Weekend reporters that the policy of providing subsidies to the elderly began in January 2020, and the 110-year-old age group is not superfluous. Some people have indeed enjoyed this benefit after the policy was launched. &quot;We once distributed payments (3,500 yuan per month) to elderly people over 110 years old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The staff member said that after the policy was launched to benefit the people, There was a 110-year-old man who met the highest standards and returned home after receiving a subsidy for several months. Currently, the oldest person in the jurisdiction is 107 years old. “If he is still alive in three years, he will receive a 110-year-old allowance.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The staff member said that there are currently a lot of elderly people over 100 years old in the jurisdiction, and there are even more people over 80 years old. Providing subsidies to the elderly is a people-friendly policy advocated by Sichuan Province. In June 2017, Sichuan issued the &quot;Notice of the Office of the Sichuan Provincial Working Committee on Aging, the Sichuan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, and the Sichuan Provincial Department of Finance on the Establishment of an Old Age Allowance System for Elderly People Over 80 Years Old (Sichuan Aging Office [2017] No. 45)&quot; and decided to In 2017, a comprehensive senior-age allowance system for people over 80 years old was established. The notice also stated that various localities can appropriately increase the payment standards according to the level of economic development, and encourage qualified areas to establish a universal system of seniority allowances for the elderly over 80 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The implementation of Meishan City’s elderly allowance system can be traced back to January 2018. In December 2017, the Meishan City Aging Working Committee Office, Meishan Civil Affairs Bureau, and Meishan City Finance Bureau jointly issued the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Establishing an Old-age Allowance System,&quot; stating that all elderly people with local household registration who are over 80 years old can receive the pension in 2018. Applications for old-age allowances will start in January (except those detained for suspected crimes and those whose sentences have not been completed), and will stop after death. The funds will be settled by the government at the same level, and the municipal finance will provide appropriate subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On June 2, 2022, in the south square of Renshou County, Meishan City, Sichuan Province, middle-aged and elderly people dance to keep fit. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/24/00654dfd71.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/24/00654dfd71.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259568&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;June 2022, Meishan City, Sichuan Province In the south square of Renshou County, middle-aged and elderly people dance to keep fit. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Distribute hundreds of millions of subsidies to 110,000 elderly people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 6, 2023, the Meishan City Government&#39;s official website released the &quot;Meishan City The Civil Affairs Bureau’s Reply to Recommendation No. 174 of the Third Session of the Fifth Municipal People’s Congress revealed the implementation of Meishan City’s senior-age allowance system: senior-age allowances are provided to Meishan registered seniors who are over 80 years old, and the payment standard is between 80 and 89 years old. No less than 25 yuan per person per month, no less than 100 yuan per month for each person aged 90 to 99, no less than 500 yuan per month for each person aged 100 and above. As of now (July 6, 2023), Distributed more than 100 million yuan in senior-age allowances to about 110,000 elderly people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Staff at the Pengshan District Social Assistance Station said that they will choose many local methods to promote the elderly allowance policy in the community, such as producing brochures and distributing them. Publicity is carried out on the bulletin boards of communities and village committees. &quot;This is an inclusive policy, and the publicity is very strong. (People) should all know about this policy. Some elderly people who live with their children in other places may give up on applying. This is a very small number. Basically, Everyone has already applied.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In addition to the elderly allowance, our Dongpo District will also distribute 600 yuan in condolence payments to senior citizens on their birthdays.&quot; A staff member of the Elderly Care Service Section of Dongpo District Civil Affairs Bureau of Meishan City said that the standards for elderly allowances in various districts of Meishan City will be different, but the difference is not very big. Elderly people who meet the criteria can apply at the community where their household registration is located in the first month after reaching the age of 80. If the elderly person has difficulty moving, a family member can handle it on their behalf by bringing the elderly ID card. After the form is filled out and the staff verifies the situation, the money will be distributed to the social security card on a monthly basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I&#39;m not joking, I really have hair.&quot; Mr. Xie from Huangfeng Town, Pengshan District, is in his 40s and 50s and is the youngest grandson of centenarian Luo Shuwen. He told Southern Weekend reporters that there is an old-age allowance of 1,500 yuan and a new rural cooperative pension of 100 yuan every month, which are paid to grandma&#39;s social security card on time. During festivals or birthday parties, people from the government will also come to visit, &quot;sometimes they send red envelopes, and sometimes they bring some condolences.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Shuwen is 101 years old this year. She also has a sister who is 5 years younger than herself and also lives to an old age. Mr. Xie introduced that grandma was born in a wealthy family and went to a private school. She was an educated &quot;eldest lady&quot; and had many rules. &quot;You can&#39;t cross your legs when eating, and you can&#39;t raise your hands too high. I was very afraid of grandma when I was a child.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Luo Shuwen also &quot;suffered a lot&quot; in her life. Her husband passed away very early, and she supported the entire family by herself. &quot;She is like the CEO of our family.&quot; Mr. Xie said that grandma did not start to enjoy happiness again until her later years, when her family was full of children and grandchildren. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I was joking with her a few days ago, trying to get 3,500 (elderly allowance) in a few years.&quot; Mr. Xie said that Meishan City has sorted out the city&#39;s A list of centenarians was produced and a handbook on the list of centenarians was issued to them. Looking through this directory, there are hundreds of centenarians, including dozens of 108-year-olds. &quot;When it comes to centenarians, 110 years old, netizens find it unimaginable. We have quite a few here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州这种“大肚子”树，盛放着粉色的秋日浪漫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261225]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传石家庄一高校没收学生物品挂闲鱼卖，校方发布声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261280]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 18:21:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/24/bfkZWffvsmIJ4rR7pmFy5SfA5hoFMRcVkxJXPDkG.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/bfkZWffvsmIJ4rR7pmFy5SfA5ho FMRcVkxJXPDkG. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259563&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/24/iEUOzftPHtJsmTQeNF3bKGYRTJhcbc8kIAQ0SwVQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/24/iEUOzftPHtJsmTQeNF3bKGYRTJhcbc8kIAQ0SwVQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259564&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[处分期满后被提拔的干部，再增一厅官丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261266]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rain disaster in Zhengzhou, Henan, 89 public officials were Accountability. The picture shows the streets of Zhengzhou on July 21, 2021.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/90d285fc8d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/24/90d285fc8d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259546&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;After the &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rain disaster in Zhengzhou, Henan, 89 public officials were held accountable. The picture shows the streets of Zhengzhou on July 21, 2021. (Photo courtesy of People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the website of the Zhengzhou Municipal Government in Henan Province has updated information showing that Chen Hongwei, the deputy mayor who was punished for the &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rain disaster in Zhengzhou, has been appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Zhengzhou Municipal Party Committee. At this time, 22 months have passed since Chen Hongwei was punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that in recent years, there have been many cases of public officials being promoted after the expiration of their punishment due to their outstanding performance. The public officials who were punished ranged from department and bureau level to township and branch level. Some of them were punished by government affairs, and some were punished by party discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Punishments against public officials include government affairs sanctions and party disciplinary sanctions. Among them, government sanctions are divided into warnings, demerits, major demerits, demotions, dismissals, expulsions, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Hongwei, who was further used this time, was punished with a major administrative demerit due to the &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rain disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Chen Hongwei was born in February 1967. He has a doctorate in economics and served as secretary of the Jinshui District Party Committee of Zhengzhou City. In January 2020, he was promoted to deputy mayor of Zhengzhou City, responsible for natural resources. and key tasks such as planning, urban and rural construction, urban management, landscaping, ecological construction, new urbanization construction, housing security, and transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One and a half years after Chen Hongwei served as deputy mayor of Zhengzhou City, in July 2021, Henan Province suffered a rare heavy rainstorm in history and suffered severe floods. The disaster caused a total of 380 deaths and missing persons in Zhengzhou City, accounting for 95.5% of the province, and direct economic losses of 40.9 billion yuan, accounting for 34.1% of the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 21, 2022, the investigation report on the &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rainstorm disaster in Zhengzhou, Henan Province was released, and it was determined that the Zhengzhou Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government and relevant districts, counties (cities), departments and units did not have strong awareness of risks and were not aware of the risks. There was insufficient preparation for this disaster, poor prevention organization, improper emergency response, and dereliction of duty, especially casualties that should not have occurred in subways, tunnels, etc. The main party committees and governments of Zhengzhou City and relevant districts, counties (cities) The person in charge has leadership responsibility for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Published on the same day as the investigation report, there is also a list of persons to be held accountable. The Henan Provincial Discipline Inspection and Supervision Bureau, in accordance with its cadre management authority, seriously held accountable 89 public officials including Chen Hongwei who were suspected of violating disciplines and laws during the disaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Law on Government Punishment for Public Servants, the period of government punishment shall be calculated from the date when the decision on the governmental punishment takes effect. Among them, the time for recording major demerits is 18 months. During the punishment period, employees are not allowed to be promoted to positions, ranks, ranks, or levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-one months after the Zhengzhou &quot;7·20&quot; heavy rain disaster investigation report was released, on October 27, 2023, the Organization Department of the Henan Provincial Party Committee issued an announcement of proposed cadres, and Chen Hongwei was proposed to be appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Provincial Municipal Party Committee . The publicity period is from October 28, 2023 to November 3, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the publicity period ended, on November 7, 2023, Chen Hongwei, as a member of the Standing Committee of the Zhengzhou Municipal Committee and deputy mayor, went to Xinmi City to supervise the thematic education subcontracting petition case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission pointed out in the article that cadres were promoted after the impact period of the punishment. &quot;It shows that giving disciplinary sanctions to party members and cadres does not mean &#39;beating them to death with a stick&#39;, but through Punishment is used to educate and inspire, and treatment is used to save people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 19, 2023, an article published by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission showed that in 2023, 19 cadres who were dealt with in Hangzhou were further used after the impact period of the punishment. The article pointed out that these cadres &quot;went through detailed, scientific, and heart-warming return visits to evaluate their &#39;quality&#39; before the organization made prudent decisions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by Ningxia Daily in March 2023, in the past three years, more than 20 cadres in Zhongning County, Zhongwei City, Ningxia have been re-promoted to other positions after expiration due to punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Jiangxi Branch of the China News Service, since 2022, the Shangrao Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision in Jiangxi Province has regarded return visit education as an important part of supervising the &quot;second half of the article&quot; in discipline enforcement, and has carried out punishments for those subject to punishment throughout the city. Return visit to special education activities. As of August 2023, Shangrao Municipal Discipline Inspection and Supervision Organs have conducted return visits and education for 453 party members and cadres who were punished. Among them, 8 party members and cadres were promoted and appointed due to outstanding work performance after the expiration of the punishment period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervisory Commission also announced the details of some officials who were promoted after their punishment expired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in March 2002, Ao, deputy secretary of the Party Committee and mayor of Zhushan Town, Yushui District, Xinyu City, Jiangxi Province, was revoked from his party positions and administratively dismissed due to illegal possession and other mistakes. From March 2002 to April 2006, Ao served as a cadre of the Yushui District Agricultural Bureau. After the period of punishment and the impact of the punishment, Ao worked diligently and achieved outstanding performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2006, Ao was re-promoted to deputy mayor and deputy secretary of the town party committee. In April 2011, Ao was appointed as Party Secretary and Director of the Letters and Calls Bureau of Yushui District, Xinyu City. While serving as the main person in charge of the Letters and Calls Bureau, Ao continued to work diligently and had outstanding ability to resolve conflicts. For four consecutive years, Yushui District&#39;s letters and calls received the &quot;Three No&#39;s&quot; counties in the province. In October 2016, Ao was promoted to member and vice chairman of the Party Leadership Group of Yushui District, Xinyu City. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Personnel Trends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A native of Changhua, Taiwan, Jiang Erxiong serves as the Vice Governor of Fujian Province&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312 , SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the seventh meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Fujian Provincial People’s Congress concluded. The meeting decided to appoint Jiang Erxiong as deputy governor of the Fujian Provincial People&#39;s Government. Before this job adjustment, Jiang Erxiong also served as a member of the Standing Committee of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, vice president of the National Taiwan Federation, president of the Fujian Taiwan Federation, member of the Central Standing Committee of the Taiwan League, and chairman of the Fujian Provincial Committee of the Taiwan League. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;According to public information, Jiang Erxiong was born in Minqing, Fujian in 1967. His father is from Changhua, Taiwan, and settled in mainland China in 1947. &lt;/span>;According to previous reports from Solidarity.com, as a Taiwanese, Jiang Erxiong has long served in the Taiwan League and Taiwan Union system, and is committed to promoting cross-strait exchanges and exchanges in various fields and promoting cross-strait peaceful development and integrated development. Especially on the National Two Sessions platform, she has received widespread attention as a Taiwanese representative and often provides advice on topics such as cross-strait exchanges and cooperation and equal treatment for Taiwan compatriots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences was officially established, with Yan Ning as the founding president]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, the Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences, with Yan Ning as the founding president, was announced at the Guangming Yungu International Conference Center in Shenzhen. According to the introduction published on the official website of the Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences, Yan Ning is currently the president of the Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences, a chair professor at Tsinghua University, a foreign academician of the National Academy of Sciences, a foreign academician of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, and the director of the Shenzhen Bay Laboratory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Financial Supervision Local Bureau&#39;s &quot;intensive coaching changes&quot;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the State Financial Supervision Bureau has ushered in a period of intensive adjustment for “top leaders” in local regulatory bureaus. As of November 23, regulatory bureaus in Beijing, Zhejiang, Ningbo, Inner Mongolia, Heilongjiang, Shanxi, Anhui, Hainan, Ningxia, Shenzhen, Qingdao, Jiangxi and other places have updated the changes in &quot;top leaders&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Red Star News, 2 of the 12 new directors came from the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission, 6 were transferred from the posts of directors of other regulatory bureaus, and 4 were promoted from deputy directors of other bureaus. The 12 new directors are all born in the 1970s and have long-term and rich experience at the local grassroots level. In addition, many of these new directors have served as secretaries of the Discipline Inspection Commission and have experience in disciplinary inspection work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;9 years after the &quot;cliff&quot; downgrade, Zhao Zhiyong was investigated&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 20, 2023, the official WeChat account &quot;Integrity Jiangxi&quot; of the Jiangxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision announced that Jiangxi Zhao Zhiyong (former member of the Standing Committee and Secretary-General of the Provincial Party Committee), a former staff member of the Beijing Office of the Provincial People&#39;s Government, is suspected of serious violations of the law and is currently under supervision and investigation by the Jiangxi Provincial Supervisory Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public resumes show that Zhao Zhiyong has worked at the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, the Jiangxi Provincial Branch of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Government, the Jiujiang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China, and the Beijing Office of the Jiangxi Provincial People&#39;s Government. In March 2002, Zhao Zhiyong was appointed as the deputy governor of Jiangxi Province. In 2006, he was appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee and deputy governor. In 2008, he was appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee and secretary-general of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2014, Zhao Zhiyong was removed from his position as a member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China; a month later, Zhao Zhiyong was expelled from the party, his deputy provincial status was revoked, and he was demoted to a staff member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[For accepting bribes of more than 49.84 million yuan, Zhang Jinghua, former deputy secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, was sentenced to 14 years in the first instance]&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; reported that on November 21, 2023, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Wuhan City, Hubei Province publicly pronounced Zhang Jinghua, the former deputy secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, on the bribery case, and sentenced Zhang Jinghua to fixed-term imprisonment for accepting bribes. Fourteen years and a fine of RMB 4 million; Zhang Jinghua&#39;s proceeds and interest from the crime of accepting bribes will be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 2008 to 2021, the defendant Zhang Jinghua used his position as director of the Environmental Protection Department of Jiangsu Province, deputy secretary and mayor of the Xuzhou Municipal Party Committee, secretary of the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee, and secretary-general of the Jiangsu Provincial Government, Jiangsu Vice governor of the provincial government, member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, secretary of the Nanjing Municipal Party Committee and secretary of the Party Working Committee of Jiangbei New District, Nanjing City, deputy secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status, provide relevant units and individuals with Providing assistance in engineering contracting, project development, job promotion, etc., and illegally receiving property directly or through others, totaling more than RMB 49.84 million, of which more than RMB 16.76 million was not actually obtained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Former Vice Governor of Guangdong Province Li Chunsheng pleads guilty&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span >;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Chenzhou City, Hunan Province held a first-instance public hearing on the bribery case of Li Chunsheng, former deputy secretary and deputy director of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chenzhou Municipal People’s Procuratorate accused: From the second half of 2001 to May 2022, Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County, Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security, and director of the Personnel Training Bureau, Guangdong Province The deputy governor, director of the Provincial Public Security Department, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress and other convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status provide relevant units and individuals with opportunities in business operations, project promotion, project contracting, and job promotions. provided help on matters such as other matters, and illegally accepted property from others, equivalent to a total of more than 79.4 million yuan in RMB. The procuratorate requested that Li Chunsheng be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ministry and commission information&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Finance: Guide and encourage local finances at all levels to allocate financial resources to Grassroots level, leaning towards difficult areas]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV news reports, the Ministry of Finance recently revised and issued the &quot;Measures for the Management of Reward and Subsidy Funds of the Central Finance County-level Basic Financial Guarantee Mechanism&quot;. According to the &quot;Administrative Measures&quot;, local financial departments at all levels implement a hierarchical responsibility system in accordance with the principle of &quot;county-level priority, municipal-level assistance, and provincial-level support.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The provincial financial department is responsible for improving the basic financial guarantee mechanism at the county level in the region, improving the management methods of reward and subsidy funds, and implementing emergency response plans for possible &quot;three guarantees&quot; risk events. Provincial and municipal finance departments are responsible for calculating and allocating reward and subsidy funds, and the funds are tilted towards grassroots areas with difficulties to improve the level and balance of county-level financial resources; they will appropriately increase subsidies and provide fund allocation support to counties and districts with difficulties, and effectively implement the responsibility of providing basic assistance. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Ministry of Public Security: Northern Myanmar handed over 31,000 telecommunications network fraud suspects to China&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;News from the website of the Ministry of Public Security on November 21, 2023, in response to the current telecommunications network fraud involving China in northern Myanmar Due to the severe crime situation, the Ministry of Public Security has deployed public security agencies in Yunnan and other places to continue to promote border police law enforcement cooperation and carry out multiple rounds of crackdowns. So far, relevant local law enforcement departments in northern Myanmar have handed over 31,000 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us. , including 63 behind-the-scenes &quot;financiers&quot;, organizational leaders and backbones, and 1,531 online fugitives. The crackdown has achieved remarkable results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Douyu CEO Chen Shaojie was arrested on suspicion of opening a casino]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On November 22, 2023, according to a police report issued by the Dujiangyan Municipal Public Security Bureau in Chengdu, the bureau found through investigation that Chen Moujie (male, 39 years old) was suspected of opening a casino. Currently, Chen Moujie has been arrested in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. According to previous news, Chen Moujie is Douyu CEO Chen Shaojie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;125 electronic fraud suspects who went to Indonesia to carry out cross-border nude chat blackmail were arrested&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti ;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, the official WeChat public account &quot;Fangshan Procuratorate&quot; of the Fangshan District People&#39;s Procuratorate of Beijing announced that recently, Fangshan District, Beijing After review in accordance with the law, the People&#39;s Procuratorate has requested approval from the Fangshan Branch of the Beijing Municipal Public Security Bureau to arrest a total of 125 criminal suspects from a telecommunications network fraud criminal gang who went to Indonesia to commit cross-border nude chatting and extortion, on suspicion of extortion, fraud, and illegally crossing the country ( A decision was made to approve the arrest for border crimes and other crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Science and Education News&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The results of the 2023 election of academicians of the two academies were announced, with a total of 133 people elected&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, Italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News, on November 22, the results of the 2023 election of academicians of the two academies were officially announced. 59 academicians were elected, and 74 additional academicians were elected by the Chinese Academy of Engineering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Education: Will focus on supporting county secondary vocational schools to open majors in urgent need of livelihood, such as elderly care and housekeeping]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, the Ministry of Education announced its response to Recommendation No. 3932 of the First Session of the 14th National People’s Congress on its official website. In response to the &quot;Recommendations on Promoting the Construction of Elderly-related Service Majors in County Secondary Vocational Education&quot;, the Ministry of Education stated that it will launch the &quot;Double Excellence Plan&quot; for secondary vocational schools and focus on building a number of high-quality secondary vocational schools and high-quality majors with a demonstration and leading role, focusing on Support county secondary vocational schools in offering majors in urgent need of livelihood, such as elderly care and home economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After eight consecutive years of growth, the number of applicants for the postgraduate entrance examination in 2024 has dropped by 360,000]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News Client, the 2024 National Master’s Degree Admissions Examination will be held from December 23 to 25, 2023. According to the report, according to statistics, the number of applicants for the national master&#39;s degree admissions examination in 2024 is 4.38 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that since 2016, the number of postgraduate applicants in my country has maintained a high growth trend. From 2015 to 2022, the seven-year average growth rate is 15.8%. Among them, in 2020, 2021 and 2022, the number of applicants for the postgraduate entrance examination was 3.41 million, 3.77 million and 4.57 million respectively. In 2023, this data rose to 4.74 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with 2022, the growth in the number of postgraduate entrance examination applicants in 2023 has slowed down significantly, with the growth rate falling from 21.2% to 3.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Local political situation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Guangzhou becomes the first first-tier city to lift the upper limit on land prices&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Securities Daily&quot; report, on November 21, 2023, according to the official website of the Guangzhou Public Resources Trading Center, Huangpu District, Guangzhou City listed the The first homestead of the fourth batch of land transfers. The announcement shows that the bidder will be determined based on the principle of the highest bidder for the sale of listed residential land, and there is no maximum transaction price limit for the land. This also means that Guangzhou has officially canceled the &quot;limited land price&quot; transfer policy for residential land, becoming the first first-tier city to cancel the upper limit on land prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The data is seriously untrue, and Minqin County in Gansu Province has two titles revoked by the Ministry of Water Resources]&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, 2023, according to the official WeChat account &quot;China Water Resources&quot; of the Ministry of Water Resources, verification found that Minqin County in Wuwei, Gansu Province failed to strictly implement relevant planning requirements, and the total water consumption far exceeded Control indicators, especially groundwater overexploitation, are seriously inaccurate. The total water consumption and other data provided when applying for the &quot;National High-efficiency Water-Saving Irrigation Demonstration County&quot; in 2015 and the &quot;Water-saving Social Construction Standard County&quot; in 2019 were seriously inaccurate. According to relevant regulations, the Ministry of Water Resources recently decided to cancel Minqin County&#39;s title of &quot;National High-efficiency Water-saving Irrigation Demonstration County&quot; and &quot;Water-saving Society Construction Standard County&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;[After the major fire accident in Yongju Coal Industry, the Secretary of the Luliang Municipal Party Committee randomly inspected production safety work]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 16, a major fire accident occurred in the Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction Building in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province. 26 people died, 34 people were hospitalized, and 4 people were kept for observation in the outpatient department. According to &quot;Lüliang Daily&quot;, on the afternoon of November 21, Luliang Municipal Party Committee Secretary Sun Dajun led the heads of the emergency and fire departments and relevant experts to randomly inspect production safety work in Lishi District. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Sound&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Secretary of the Zhuzhou Municipal Party Committee: People &quot;empty six wallets&quot; to buy a house, but in the end they cannot get the house. If not the government, who should they turn to? &lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Zhuzhou Daily&quot; , On November 19, 2023, Cao Huiquan, Secretary of the Zhuzhou Municipal Party Committee, made an unannounced visit to the issue of guaranteed delivery of the Greenland 21 City project. &quot;The masses &#39;empty six wallets&#39; to buy a house, but in the end they can&#39;t get the house. If not the government, who can they turn to?&quot; During the unannounced visit, Cao Huiquan emphasized that the work of ensuring the handover of buildings is one of the biggest people&#39;s livelihood tasks at present, and relevant departments at all levels in the city must Focusing on the goal of &quot;delivering houses to the hands of home buyers as soon as possible&quot;, we put ourselves in the shoes of the house buyers and go all out to promote the work of ensuring the delivery of buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive Ministry of Finance official website, Ministry of Education official website, &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot;, CCTV News, Xinhua News Agency, Red Star News, The Paper, etc.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[强调商业道德仍是企业履责的基础——10月企业社会责任警示事件分析]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 17:18:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The corporate social responsibility warning events in October cover information disclosure, false propaganda, production safety, employee responsibility, environmental protection, Product quality and many other aspects. Some companies are unaware of the strong regulatory situation formed during the transformation of my country&#39;s economy to high-quality development, and ignore business ethics and environmental and social responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this issue, we invited Dr. Lu Jianzhong, deputy director of the Sustainable Development Management Professional Committee of the Chinese Society of Management Science and director of the Global Reporting Initiative GRI, and Dr. Yin Juelin, professor and doctoral supervisor of the School of Management at Sun Yat-sen University, From the perspective of think tank experts, we comment on the overall characteristics and typical incidents of the corporate social responsibility warning events in October. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the selection process of this issue of corporate social responsibility warning events, you What social responsibility issues are you paying attention to? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lv Jianzhong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Every time I review corporate social responsibility warning events, I will pay special attention to corporate governance, compliance, major environmental accidents, and major workplace personal injuries. Casualty accidents and major violations of consumer rights and interests are the minimum things that companies must guard against. Regrettably, these heinous incidents occur every month in the warning events, causing outrage and disgust. I can’t help but ask: Where is the conscience of these business owners and companies who have touched the red line? This is no longer an issue of social responsibility, it is the most basic moral issue of a person or an organization. The selection of corporate social responsibility warning events is of great significance. It reminds us that we must resolutely fight against these bad behaviors and must be persistently committed to awakening our conscience and safeguarding social fairness and justice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yin Juelin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The outstanding feature of this issue of corporate social responsibility warning events is that many of them involve people’s food, clothing, housing and transportation. From toothpaste, medicines to entertainment, consumers may be &quot;fooled&quot; by merchants if they are not careful, and their lives may even be in danger. We hope to remind companies to protect their responsibilities and business bottom line, and while building safe and reliable products, establish a more sustainable and ethical business culture, so as not to let down the trust of consumers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the Pien Tze Huang false propaganda incident? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yin Juelin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The problem of toothpaste falsely labeling efficacy is an old problem that violates marketing ethics. The national &quot;Regulations on the Supervision and Administration of Cosmetics&quot; has clearly stipulated that toothpaste shall be managed in accordance with the regulations of ordinary cosmetics; claims of special effects must be evaluated in accordance with national standards and industry standards, and cannot expressly or imply that it has a medical effect. In other words, toothpaste is just an ordinary cosmetic, not a medicine. As a well-known time-honored pharmaceutical company, Pien Tze Huang has certain advantages in entering the toothpaste market, but it should not adopt the mentality of playing on the sidelines. This is both illegal and does not match its industry status as a well-known pharmaceutical company. At the same time, consumers are also reminded to keep their eyes open and rationally judge whether &quot;Internet celebrity products&quot; are not worthy of their name. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How does the issue of information disclosure of Guannong Shares affect the company? Social Responsibility? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lu Jianzhong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This incident has had a bad impact on society. First, the company tramples on the basic bottom line of honest management; second, it seriously undermines the seriousness and authenticity of information disclosure, thereby misleading stakeholders, and may even disrupt the normal advancement of ESG information disclosure. Companies must treat social responsibility and ESG information disclosure as a serious task of operating in compliance with regulations, maintaining reputation, and building social trust, and integrate it into the level of corporate governance. At the same time, relevant departments and the media should increase supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The explosion at the Xingyue Materials Factory in Guangxi has a negative impact on manufacturing companies Any warnings? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lv Jianzhong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The health and safety of employees in the workplace is not only the basic bottom line for a company’s legal and compliant operations, but also the foundation for its stable operations. Bottom line. Life is precious. One-sided pursuit of efficiency and profits regardless of the safety and health of employees is an illegal and shameful act, and the circumstances are extremely egregious. Enterprises must have strict, normalized and systematic safety and health measures, establish monitoring, prevention and assessment standards for safety and health, eliminate safety hazards and ensure safe production. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Three environmental responsibility-related events in this issue , how do you evaluate it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lv Jianzhong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The natural ecological environment is the basis for human survival. To destroy the natural ecological environment is to drain the lake. Business owners and companies who are eager for quick success, swaying their hands, and illegally emitting emissions regardless of the natural ecological environment must be strictly brought to justice and will never be tolerated. Relevant agencies and regulatory authorities should intensify supervision and law enforcement efforts, continuously and solidly investigate enterprises that have a fluke mentality and lack of regulatory measures in environmental protection, and put an end to negligence in their duties. It also calls on the society to supervise the business operations of enterprises and improve smooth reporting channels. All enterprises must establish complete management systems, monitoring systems and performance appraisal systems in accordance with national, industry and local regulations to ensure that the alarm bells sound. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Langdi received a sky-high fine due to product quality issues , what problems are reflected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yin Juelin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Landy’s brand slogan for many years has been “Suitable for Chinese people’s physique”. However, behind the overwhelming advertising, the bottom line of pharmaceutical product quality has actually failed to be maintained. For a pharmaceutical company, product quality and safety are the bottom line of social responsibility. We hope that this fine of more than 100 million yuan will serve as a wake-up call for the company to strengthen quality control of its product production lines. The problem may be solved in the short term by recalling products, but long-term reflection and rectification are essential. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Top Ten Corporate Social Responsibility Warning Events in October&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Xinjiang Guannong Co., Ltd. was fined 2.1 million yuan for falsely disclosing information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fields involved:&lt;/strong>;Responsible governance&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Event review:&lt;/strong>; On October 9, Guanong Shares issued an announcement stating that the China Securities Regulatory Commission Xinjiang The supervisory bureau issued an administrative penalty decision to them because they had violated laws and regulations in information disclosure. Guannong Shares violated securities laws and contained false records, misleading statements or major omissions in its information disclosure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; For listed companies, the accuracy of public information disclosure directly affects investors’ judgments and expectations of their value, which is one of the fundamental principles of the capital market. one. Enterprises cannot only consider short-term interests due to business pressure, but also need to consider the long-term interests of the enterprise and its shareholders from the perspective of compliance risk management and control. On the other hand, companies also need to fully consider the impact of negative news on corporate brands. Expecting to obtain short-term positive market feedback with false information is tantamount to drinking poison to quench thirst. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang subsidiary was fined 30,000 yuan for unfair competition&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Involved areas:&lt;/strong>;Fair operation&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Event review:&lt;/strong>; On October 11, the Chibi Municipal Administration for Market Regulation fined Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Shanghai Jahwa Oral Care Co., Ltd. 30,000 yuan. The administrative penalty letter shows that the products produced by the parties involved &quot;Pien Tze Huang Toothpaste&quot; (Xuanying Medicinal Fragrance) has not actually obtained an efficacy evaluation report issued by an institution that meets the legal qualifications. However, it uses the product packaging box as a carrier to claim that the product can &quot;relieve redness and swelling&quot;. , bleeding, dry mouth, odor, oral irritation&quot; are enough to make consumers mistakenly believe that the product has the efficacy claimed by the parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; In recent years, as my country’s supervision mechanism for product promotion has become more and more perfect, it is not uncommon to impose penalties on daily necessities and health care products that claim to have special functions. Traditional Chinese medicine health care toothpaste has always been an important part of the domestic toothpaste category. As a famous Chinese traditional medicine product and a Chinese time-honored brand, Pien Tze Huang should play a leading role in the development process of the rise of domestic products, consciously abide by relevant market supervision and management regulations, and provide Chinese people with We provide genuine products at reasonable prices and strive to enhance the responsible image of well-established domestic products in the minds of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. An explosion at the Xingyue Materials Factory in Guangxi resulted in 2 deaths, 4 injuries and 4 missing persons&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>;Safety and health &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Incident review:&lt;/strong>; On the evening of October 20, an explosion occurred in the workshop of an industrial enterprise in the Industrial Park of Pingguo City, Guangxi. The incident occurred in Guohua Town, Guangxi Xingyue Material Technology Co., Ltd., emergency and firefighting departments sent personnel to the scene of the incident to conduct investigation and rescue work. In the early morning of the 21st, the Propaganda Department of the Pingguo Municipal Party Committee issued a notice stating that 6 people had been rescued so far, 2 of whom were confirmed to be lifeless. According to physical signs, 4 people were slightly injured and 4 others were missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; For manufacturing companies, safety responsibilities are more important than Mount Tai. Ensuring production safety is not only the lifeline of the company, but also a high-voltage line that cannot be touched by the company. In underdeveloped areas that rely on traditional industries as the backbone of economic development, most of the relevant employees are local residents. If an enterprise fails to implement production safety and environmental protection responsibilities, it will not only threaten the life safety of employees and the health of local residents, but also Causes irreparable reputational damage to the business in the local community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Shenzhen Happy Valley closed for rectification due to a roller coaster collision&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>;Safety and health&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Incident review:&lt;/strong>; After the collision of the roller coaster &quot;Snowy Eagle&quot; on October 27, Shenzhen Happy Valley quickly activated the emergency mechanism and sent 8 injured tourists to the hospital for treatment immediately. Organize other tourists on site to go to nearby hospitals for examination and treatment. As of October 30, a total of 17 tourists continue to stay in the hospital for treatment or observation. All tourists in the hospital are in stable condition and their lives are not in danger. In order to cooperate with the urban joint investigation team&#39;s investigation and comprehensively carry out investigation and rectification of potential safety hazards in amusement facilities, Shenzhen Happy Valley will continue to be closed and the reopening time will be announced separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; Roller coasters are the most important category of amusement park rides. In recent years, similar news reports have continued to appear, and they have also attracted widespread social attention. Although this incident did not cause the death of tourists, it was a serious safety incident for the amusement park operating companies. As an industry benchmark, Shenzhen Happy Valley must do a good job in daily maintenance of amusement facilities on the one hand. On the other hand, as safety is the primary issue in amusement parks, it should promptly communicate responsibilities between consumers and the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. High-priced ice cream brand Zhong Xuegao was exposed for unpaid wages&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>;Employee responsibilities&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Event review:&lt;/strong>; On October 21, some media broke the news that Zhong Xuegao, a well-known high-priced ice cream brand, was in deep negative news such as owing employee wages, owing suppliers, and even being unable to redeem customer points. Zhong Xuegao&#39;s official WeChat and Weibo have not been updated in the past two months, and employees and partners have left messages &quot;debt collection&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; The employee wage arrears incident only reflects the tip of the iceberg of Zhong Xuegao’s business problems. After the epidemic control was relaxed, the domestic new consumer brand ice cream collectively suffered a cold spell. If The foundation of the enterprise itself is not strong, and it is foreseeable that more incidents of lack of social responsibility will occur. The concept of sustainable development should be integrated into the process of enterprise development of products and business models. Enterprises should try their best to avoid business strategies that rely entirely on capital and marketing and effectively create differentiated value for customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6. Haiou Housing Holdings subsidiary was fined 380,000 yuan for discharging sewage beyond the standard&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>;Environmental responsibility &lt;p>; According to Article 83, Paragraph 2 of the Water Pollution Prevention and Control Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Zhuhai Municipal Ecological Environment Bureau fined the company 380,000 yuan. In addition to the above-mentioned administrative penalties, Haiou Housing&#39;s 2023 semi-annual report disclosed that Zhuhai Chengou Bathroom Products Co., Ltd. was punished twice for &quot;discharging water pollutants in excess of water pollutant discharge standards&quot; in the first half of the year, one of which was fined 400,000 yuan. , another time he was asked to make corrections immediately and report the corrections in writing. The company took corrective measures for both penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; The company involved was punished twice for the same environmental violation within six months, and the two penalties were of the same amount, indicating that the company did not effectively implement the rectification requirements. As my country&#39;s ecological and environmental protection work is advanced in depth and practice, the concept of &quot;lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets&quot; is deeply rooted in the hearts of the people. If companies still fail to see the far-reaching significance of curbing environmental pollution for high-quality development, they will surely be ruthless by the market. of elimination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;7. Shenchi Electromechanical Holding subsidiary was fined 2.47 million yuan because its products did not meet emission standards&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fields involved:&lt;/strong>;Environment Responsibility&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Incident Review:&lt;/strong>; On October 10, Chongqing Kemier Power Machinery Co., Ltd., a subsidiary of Shenchi Electromechanical Holdings, was ordered to file a lawsuit in accordance with the &quot;People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; because &quot;the product did not meet the emission standards.&quot; Paragraph 1 of Article 109 of the Air Pollution Prevention and Control Law, the Chongqing Ecological and Environmental Protection Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Corps fined, confiscated illegal income and confiscated illegal property, including a fine of 2.4702 million yuan and confiscated illegal income of 1.4271 million yuan, totaling 3.8973 million yuan. Ten thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; my country has mature experience in real-time monitoring of exhaust emission data and local ecological environment bureaus. The cost of corporate violations in air pollution will further increase. . In this context, manufacturing companies need to change the concept of environmental responsibility as an external cost of the company, and actively adjust product structure and production processes based on the actual situation of their own operations as soon as possible and on the basis of comprehensive compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;8. Hunan Sailong Biopharmaceutical was fined 199,000 yuan for failing to install hazardous waste treatment facilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>; Environmental Responsibility&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Incident review:&lt;/strong>;On October 7, Hunan Sailon Biopharmaceutical Co., Ltd., a subsidiary of Sailon Pharmaceuticals, was found to have distillation residue in the hazardous waste storage room set up by the company. , waste organic solvents and other hazardous wastes that generate volatile organic waste gas. The storage room is not equipped with collection and treatment facilities in accordance with national environmental protection standards. The waste gas is directly discharged to the outside environment through the exhaust fan. According to Article 100 of the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Prevention and Control of Environmental Pollution by Solid Waste&quot; Article 12, paragraph 1, item 6, was fined 199,000 yuan by the Changsha Municipal Ecological Environment Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; The storage of hazardous chemicals is one of the core safety issues for production companies, and it is also one of the responsibilities most easily ignored by companies. Improper storage of hazardous chemicals can harm the health of employees internally and create potential environmental pollution risks externally. In addition to imposing penalties, relevant departments should pay attention to guiding and improving the safety awareness of production enterprises, especially improving the importance that employees attach to their own occupational safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;9. Beijing Langdi Pharmaceutical was suspended and fined more than 130 million yuan due to non-compliance with regulations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Areas involved:&lt;/strong>; Compliance management&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Event review:&lt;/strong>;On October 16, the administrative penalty information published on the official website of the Beijing Municipal Administration for Market Regulation showed that after inspection by the Gansu Provincial Institute for Drug Control, it was found that Beijing The vitamin D3 content determination of 32 batches of calcium carbonate products produced by Langdi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. and commissioned by Shanxi Zhendong Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. did not meet the regulations. Due to violation of the &quot;Drug Administration Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, Langdi Pharmaceutical was ordered to suspend production and operations for 30 days for rectification, confiscated a total of 54,000 boxes of related products, confiscated a total of 6.18 million yuan of illegal income, and imposed a fine of more than 130 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Responsibility warning:&lt;/strong>; Drug safety issues are no small matter, and the sound and healthy development of the pharmaceutical industry is directly related to the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood. Although it has been certified by third-party authoritative experts that the content of vitamin D3 is easily unstable due to objective environmental factors such as temperature and transportation. As an industry leader, there are still many issues worthy of reflection in Langdi&#39;s supply chain management and product quality control. This sky-high fine is not only a warning to &quot;China&#39;s Calcium King&quot;, but also a warning to major pharmaceutical companies under the high-pressure situation of deepening pharmaceutical reform in my country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;10. 22 APPs and SDKs were notified by the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology for infringing on user rights and interests&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Involved areas:&lt;/strong>;Compliance management&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Event review:&lt;/strong>; Recently, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has organized third-party testing agencies to conduct testing on mobile Internet application apps and third-party software development kits (SDKs) such as online video and online shopping that are of public concern. After inspection, it was found that 22 APPs and SDKs infringed on user rights, and a report was made on October 24. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liability warning:&lt;/strong>;The infringements reported this time include illegal collection of personal information, forced, frequent and excessive requests for permissions by the APP, forcing users to use targeted push functions, deception, misleading and coercion. User issues. After years of development, the mobile Internet has been fully integrated into the daily lives of ordinary consumers. The companies involved should have a more comprehensive understanding of behaviors that infringe on user rights, take the initiative to assume the responsibility of safeguarding consumer rights, and actively cooperate with relevant regulations Undertake comprehensive rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Selection Methods and processes: The selection of “Top Ten Corporate Social Responsibility Warning Events of the Month” adopts the expert voting method. At the beginning of the month, Southern Weekend China Corporate Social Responsibility Research Center collected and sorted out the social responsibility warning events that occurred last month and screened out candidate events. Afterwards, nine think tank experts were randomly invited to conduct &quot;back-to-back&quot; voting, and the &quot;Top Ten Corporate Social Responsibility Warning Events of the Month&quot; were rated from high to low based on the total number of votes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[呼吸道感染高发，儿科频频告急]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261217]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 16:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;The Joint Prevention and Control Mechanism of the State Council issued a notice that influenza is expected to peak in winter and spring across the country, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections will increase in some parts of the country in the coming period. Areas will continue to have high incidence rates. On November 21, Li Yuchuan, director of the outpatient department of Beijing Children&#39;s Hospital, said that the hospital&#39;s internal medicine department currently receives more than 7,000 patients per day, far exceeding the hospital&#39;s capacity.</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院联防联控机制：做好冬春季新冠等传染病防控]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261223]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 15:22:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Joint Prevention and Control Mechanism of the State Council issued a notice today, requiring all localities to prepare for new coronavirus infections and other key infectious diseases in winter and spring. Prevention and control work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; pointed out that winter and spring are the seasons with high incidence of infectious diseases such as COVID-19, influenza, norovirus gastroenteritis, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. The current COVID-19 epidemic situation across the country is generally stable, but there is still a risk of a rebound in my country&#39;s COVID-19 epidemic in winter. Since October 2023, influenza and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection activities have gradually increased in my country. It is expected that influenza will have a national epidemic peak in winter and spring, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection will continue to be high in some areas in the future. This winter and next spring, our country may face the superimposed epidemic situation of multiple respiratory diseases such as COVID-19, influenza, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice on Preventing and Controlling New Coronavirus Infections and Other Key Infectious Diseases in Winter and Spring&quot; mainly includes 6 key measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, effectively implement port epidemic prevention and control. Ports must strictly implement measures such as temperature monitoring of entry personnel, medical inspections, epidemiological investigations, and medical screening, and carry out new coronavirus mutation monitoring in accordance with regulations. Disease control, health, and customs departments should strengthen data sharing and information exchange, and coordinate risk analysis and prediction and early warning. Strengthen the publicity and interpretation of policies related to active health declaration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to continue to carry out dynamic monitoring and early warning of the epidemic. All localities must coordinate the surveillance of key infectious diseases such as COVID-19, influenza and norovirus gastroenteritis, and closely track changes in the epidemic situation. Strengthen the analysis and utilization of multi-source data such as online direct reporting, fever clinics, sentinel hospitals, laboratory testing, etc., carry out multi-pathogen comprehensive surveillance of acute respiratory infectious diseases based on actual conditions in areas where conditions permit, strengthen the reporting and management of statutory infectious disease information, and ensure information Timeliness and accuracy of reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to strengthen the prevention and control of key institutions and key groups. All localities should strengthen prevention and control in elderly care, childcare, schools, social welfare and other institutions as well as confined spaces, and urge daily protection and health monitoring. Strengthen the vaccination of key groups such as the elderly, patients with underlying diseases, and children against COVID-19, influenza, and pneumococcal vaccines, and strengthen classified and hierarchical health services and management for vulnerable groups such as the elderly over 65 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to strengthen preparations for medical treatment. All localities should coordinate the deployment of medical resources based on the epidemic situation of infectious diseases and the incidence of respiratory infectious diseases in winter and spring, and strengthen the production and supply of relevant treatment drugs. Dynamically monitor the supply situation of retail pharmacies, medical institutions, especially primary-level medical supplies, and strengthen the guarantee of appropriate dosage forms for children&#39;s medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fifth is to continue to strengthen science popularization and education. All localities must continue to provide health education and publicity guidance, make full use of various media at all levels to carry out publicity and policy interpretation on the prevention and control of COVID-19 and other key infectious diseases in winter and spring, and release epidemic and prevention and control information in a timely, accurate and objective manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sixth is to strengthen organizational leadership and responsibility implementation. All localities must strengthen the organization and leadership of infectious disease prevention and control in winter and spring, maintain a moderate and orderly prevention and control intensity and rhythm, maintain the effective operation of joint prevention and control mechanisms at all levels, be prepared for transition from emergency to emergency, and report promptly once clustered epidemics are discovered. , quick response and effective disposal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影《我本是高山》陷争议旋涡：“传记片难拍”其实是个世界性难题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the movie &quot;I am a mountain&quot; adapted from the real deeds of Zhang Guimei, the principal of Huaping Girls&#39; High School, was screened It triggered a wave of online scolding. Some viewers who watched the on-demand screening expressed dissatisfaction, accusing the film online of being &quot;misogynistic&quot; and &quot;smearing Principal Zhang&#39;s beliefs.&quot; In response, the screenwriter responded on social media with &quot;Your grandma, I was born to be a mountain&quot; and also Responding to critics with &quot;Mediocre gully! Humble coward!&quot; also triggered a war of words and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The disputes between the two parties probably focus on two parts. The first is the discrepancy between the plot and reality. Critics believe that many plots violate real history, such as &quot;Girls go to Internet cafes to stop studying because they fell in love while shopping&quot;, &quot;Principal Zhang forced girls to cut their hair short&quot;, &quot;Principal Zhang looks similar in appearance but not in spirit, like a chicken baby and a tiger mother&quot;; secondly, Regarding &quot;gender issues&quot;, critics believe that &quot;it is the father who is alcoholic, not the mother in the film&quot; and &quot;Principal Zhang insists on running the school because of his faith, not because he misses his deceased husband in the film&quot;, and then accuses the screenwriter and director of &quot;misogyny&quot; Discredit Principal Zhang’s faith.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the controversies encountered by &quot;I Am a Mountain&quot; are similar to those encountered by biographical films on a global scale. These two major controversies can also be reduced to &quot;issues of fact&quot; and &quot;issues of fact&quot;. A question of values”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of film art, &quot;biopics are difficult to make&quot; is actually a global problem, and eye-catching biopics are rare around the world. Especially for celebrities who are very recent, it is indeed difficult to make a biographical film commercially and artistically while respecting the facts. There is no other reason. Celebrities’ life stories are widely known. Any artistic processing and adaptation will inevitably reshape the celebrity’s public image and challenge the audience’s inherent perception of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as this &quot;factual issue&quot; is concerned, the decision-making power on how to collect materials, write scripts, and start shooting should be left entirely to the screenwriter and director. As long as the legal authorization of celebrities and their families is obtained and the potential for infringement is eliminated, the plot adaptation is actually not difficult, and it is purely a matter of choice and judgment in film art. If the director thinks that he cannot get the adaptation permission he wants, he can decide on his own whether to continue filming. For example, Gao Xiaosong gave up the idea of ​​filming the movie &quot;Lin Huiyin&quot; because &quot;Lin Huiyin&#39;s descendants requested that Xu Zhimo not be included.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although many biopics are completely loyal to real history, they have become a piece of history because they dare not let go of adaptation. The failure of &quot;Jobs&quot; falls into this category. The life of the Apple Godfather was filmed in a lukewarm manner; Many biopics hope to make breakthroughs in commerciality and artistry, but they have more or less fallen into the &quot;controversy&quot; and are under certain pressure from reputation. For example, &quot;The Imitation Game&quot; added an &quot;original plot&quot; and was fictional. The controversial plot of Turing, the father of computers, &quot;gives up reporting on fellow Soviet spies in order to prevent his homosexual identity from being exposed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for &quot;I Am a Mountain&quot;, Principal Zhang Guimei and other real people did not object to the screenwriter and director&#39;s processing and adaptation, but only appeared at the screening to say, &quot;I didn&#39;t really think anything of it at the time. how&quot;. Therefore, the film&#39;s factual issues cannot be considered a point of contention. The reason why the online scolding war was triggered was because of the second controversial point - &quot;the issue of values.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Critics believe that there are &quot;gender issues&quot; in the film, such as &quot;the mother is the drunkard, which vilifies women&quot; and &quot;the original theme was female awakening and female independence, but in the end it became the deceased husband of Principal Zhang &quot;Touched&quot; &quot;Girls skipping class, going shopping and falling in love are also vilifying women&quot;; and &quot;China Film Report&quot; sided with the screenwriters and gave an explanation that Principal Zhang not only saved the girl, but also saved the mother and allowed her to study in China. Ping Girls&#39; High School has started a new life, which is obviously the narrative of &quot;Girls help girls&quot; (GHG). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is not a phenomenon unique to Chinese movies. The same plot has long appeared in Hollywood movies. &amp;nbsp; &quot;Identity politics&quot; has been entangled in the American literary and artistic circles for many years, so that every movie has Americans spend a lot of energy discussing &quot;whether people with specific identities are given enough roles&quot; and &quot;whether specific groups are vilified&quot;. In the end, every time Hollywood releases information about a new film, people will joke that &quot;the skin color of the protagonist has already been determined.&quot; , and also send a funny P picture of the protagonist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts have proved that this &quot;American political correctness&quot; itself has gone beyond the discussion of art, but has become a complete choice of sides, which has caused harm to the artistic value of movies. If the audience&#39;s focus on a movie should be on &quot;whether it vilifies certain groups&quot; and &quot;whether certain groups have roles&quot; instead of whether the movie itself is good-looking or not and what its artistic value is, then I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s definitely not the luck of the film practitioners. , will also make film criticism out of focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oscar winner Alex Gibney believes that biographical films need to have a unique, sharp and novel angle, otherwise it will be difficult to succeed because of &quot;packing in a lot of big ideas&quot;. The 2016 movie &quot;The First Lady&quot; starring Kennedy&#39;s wife Jacqueline suffered a disastrous box office failure. The reason was not a gender issue, but the lack of skills of the screenwriter and director, who failed to star Natalie Portman. Jacqueline stepped out of the &quot;iconic shell&quot; that Americans are familiar with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the freedom of the director and screenwriter to express whatever truth they want to express. If the film is forced to comply with certain &quot;progressive issues&quot; and &quot;identity politics&quot;, then it will probably bring more artistic value to the film. Big damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>