<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[六问六答丨广州楼市部分放开限购，将会带来哪些影响？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 19:49:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 20, Guangzhou issued the &quot;Notice on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot; (Part 2 (called &quot;Notice&quot;), taking the first step in partially relaxing purchase restrictions in first-tier cities across the country. This new property market policy has the characteristics of large intensity and wide scope, striving to promote the transformation and high-quality development of the city&#39;s real estate market in an orderly and effective manner. At the same time, the &quot;Notice&quot; aims to implement classified and precise policies, continue to increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, better meet residents&#39; rigid and improved housing needs, and resolutely curb speculation and speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, in the critical period of structural adjustment of the real estate industry, Guangzhou City actively responds to and implements the national real estate macro-control policy. In recent days, Guangzhou has taken the lead in implementing the &quot;recognize the house but not the loan&quot; policy in the first-tier cities. Mortgage interest rates were the first to break through the lower limit of LPR. This time, Guangzhou still took the lead among first-tier cities and opened up a new development situation in the real estate industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; mainly includes three parts: including relaxing purchase restrictions in some areas, relaxing the qualifications for non-household registered persons to purchase houses, and adjusting the value-added tax exemption period for personal sales of housing from 5 years to 2 years, etc., and many measures. At the same time, we will promote the recovery of the real estate market. In addition, yesterday, the Guangzhou Municipal Bureau of Housing and Urban-Rural Development issued the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Further Strengthening Housing Security for Household Registration Households (Draft for Comments)&quot;, which will jointly improve Guangzhou&#39;s &quot;rental and purchase&quot; housing security. mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New Deal Questions and Answers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Q: What are the specific purchase restriction and non-purchase restriction areas in Guangzhou City in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The &quot;Notice&quot; states that households registered in Guangzhou are located in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, and Baiyun (excluding Jianggao Town, Taihe Town, Renhe Town, and Zhongluotan Town), Nansha and other areas still limit the purchase of two houses. This means that except for the areas mentioned above, purchase restrictions are no longer set in other areas of Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Can families who are not residents registered in this city enjoy the liberalized regional dividend? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The &quot;Notice&quot; clearly states that non-local resident households are limited to purchasing one house in the above-mentioned areas. The conditions for purchasing a house are that they must have paid continuous personal income tax payment certificates or social insurance certificates for 2 years in Guangzhou before the date of purchase. Year. Previously, non-registered residents in Guangzhou were required to meet proof of continuous payment of personal income tax or social insurance certificate for five years to purchase a house in Guangzhou. This new policy lowers the threshold for non-registered residents to purchase houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;Notice&quot; stipulates that in addition to calculations based on family units, adult single (including divorced) people with household registration in this city in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun (excluding Jianggao Town, Taiyuan) Hezhen, Renhe Town, and Zhongluotan Town) are still limited to purchasing one house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Will the new policy have any impact on foreigners purchasing houses in Guangzhou? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: Overseas institutions and individuals purchase houses in accordance with the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Access and Management of Foreign Investment in the Real Estate Market&quot; (Jianfanghuang [2006] No. 171), the &quot;Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development and other departments on the adjustment of foreign investment in the real estate market&quot; &quot;Notice on Relevant Policies for Access and Management&quot; (Jianfang [2015] No. 122) is implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: After the issuance of this &quot;Notice&quot;, what will be the timetable for policy implementation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The policy adjustment will be implemented from 0:00 on September 20, 2023. If the applicable policy for house purchase qualification review is inconsistent with this notice, this notice shall prevail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: The value-added tax exemption period for personal housing sales has been reduced from 5 years to 2 years. How to implement it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: The value-added tax exemption period for individual sales of housing in Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun, Huangpu, Panyu, Nansha, Zengcheng and other districts will be adjusted from 5 years to 2 years. The applicable determination of the policy is based on The specific review opinions of the tax department shall prevail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Q: Does the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot; mean that Guangzhou will realize that everyone has a place to live in the future, and the commercial housing market will be more dominated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Answer: Guangzhou City has always adhered to the housing security system of &quot;both renting and purchasing&quot;. During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, Guangzhou City proposed to add 660,000 units (rooms) of affordable housing, which is higher than The number of newly added commercial houses (650,000 units) during the same period made it the city with the largest supply of affordable housing among first-tier cities in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments of the Guangzhou Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau introduced that next, the city will further increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, and accelerate the establishment and improvement of public rental housing, affordable rental housing and allotment of affordable housing. A housing security system with housing as the mainstay and both renting and purchasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, we will continue to provide basic guarantees for public rental housing, raise the income threshold and rental subsidy standards for public rental housing in a timely manner, further expand the scope of public rental housing security, and guide some security targets to solve their housing problems by receiving subsidies. Difficult issues and improve public rental housing security methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Vigorously developing affordable rental housing will provide policy support for land, finance, taxation, etc. from the government, and guide various market entities to participate in raising affordable rental housing to alleviate the housing difficulties of new citizens and young people. Accelerate the establishment and improvement of supporting policy systems for allotment of affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;[Voice]&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In response to this new policy in Guangzhou’s real estate market, Southern+ reporters immediately contacted experts to explain what impact it will have on the city’s real estate industry in the subsequent stages after the new policy is released. ? Hear what the experts have to say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Jiangbo, director of the Economic Research Institute of the Guangzhou Academy of Social Sciences and deputy director of the Expert Committee of the Guangzhou and Guangdong Real Estate Association:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This adjustment and optimization of real estate development policies is very necessary. And importantly, it will play a very good role in boosting and promoting the real estate market and economic and social development of Guangzhou. Mainly reflected in the following three aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Conducive to the stable and healthy development of Guangzhou’s real estate market&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the huge changes in the development environment at home and abroad and the lagging impact of the three-year epidemic, the current real estate market There is indeed great downward pressure on the market and the macroeconomy, and relevant policies are in great need to be adjusted and optimized. The policies introduced in the early stage, such as &quot;recognizing a house but not a loan&quot; and &quot;lowering interest rates and lowering down payments,&quot; are generally indirect and mild, and the policy strength and effect are not enough. The relaxation of the &quot;purchase restriction and foreign purchase restriction&quot; policy introduced this time is a relaxation of administrative control policies. It is direct, substantive, very important, necessary and timely. I believe it will definitely boost and promote the market. effect. As a national central city and a first-tier city, the steady and healthy development of Guangzhou&#39;s real estate market will also serve as a good example and driving role for other second-, third-, and fourth-tier cities in the country. Therefore, Guangzhou’s policy optimization and adjustment this time is of great significance and deserves high recognition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Conducive to the coordinated and balanced development of the real estate market and housing security&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that this policy optimization and adjustment not only optimizes and adjusts the real estate market policy, but also further strengthens the The safeguard policy emphasizes the proper separation, balanced efforts, and mutual promotion of the market and safeguards. It clarifies fuzzy thinking conceptually and strengthens the direction and intensity of work in action, which is conducive to making the market bigger, stronger, and better, as well as better safeguards. It is conducive to the high-quality coordinated development of real estate, economy and society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. It is conducive to the coordinated and integrated development between various districts in Guangzhou and between Guangzhou and surrounding areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This policy optimization and adjustment is mainly aimed at the peripheral areas of Guangzhou, while the central urban area and Nansha District are still The implementation of relatively strict purchase restriction measures fully considers the actual conditions of industry, population and real estate market in each district, which well reflects the principle of &quot;district-specific policies&quot; and is conducive to better coordinated development among various districts in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, with the strong implementation of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area plan, the integration of the Greater Bay Area is accelerating. Currently, more than 50% of the working population in Guangzhou is non-locally registered. Guangzhou is a very open city. , a dynamic city, the appropriate relaxation of policies such as &quot;purchase restrictions and foreign purchase restrictions&quot; fully meets the objective needs of the integrated development of the Greater Bay Area. This optimization and adjustment of real estate policies will not only have great significance in promoting real estate in Guangzhou, but also be of great benefit to the long-term economic, spatial and social development of Guangzhou and the Greater Bay Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悬疑推理作家访谈录丨法医秦明：真正高智商的人不会犯罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among contemporary Chinese writers of detective novels, &quot;Forensic Physician Qin Ming&quot; is a very unique existence. On the one hand, there are actually many contemporary writers with police work experience, such as Remy, Ah Yi, etc., but authors like Qin Ming who combine their work experience and professional skills with detective novel writing so closely can be called &quot; Unparalleled.&quot; On the other hand, if &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; is regarded as a cultural phenomenon in a broader sense, it started from novels, and later gradually extended to different cultural forms such as film and television, variety shows, and even became the profession of &quot;forensic medicine&quot; in many people&#39;s minds. synonym. Among them, the intertwining of the forensic profession and literary creation has created an amazing cultural communication power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/c7tnNmyPxBgUYScX14uWqfeo1s7mGgALr6L6XBT2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/c7tnNmyPxBgUYScX14uWqfeo1s7mGgALr6L6XBT2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qin Ming is a front-line public security forensic doctor who has examined thousands of corpses for 26 years. He is also a suspense writer and has written the Forensic Qin Ming series, the Hummingbird series, the Night Watch series, and the popular science book series. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Yi/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a forensic doctor, I am full of awe and curiosity: why did he choose This career? After working in this somewhat mysterious profession for decades, how has your mentality changed? Faced with the large number of literature and film and television dramas about forensics or ghost stories today, what new perspectives can his profession provide? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have many questions about Qin Ming as a writer: How does he deal with the issues of fiction and reality in novel writing? How does he view the ethical boundaries of writing in crime novels? What is his reading tendency and self-identity towards the genre literary tradition of detective novels? And when I learned during the interview that Qin Ming’s favorite Chinese detective novel writer was Hai Yan, many of the questions I had previously had were solved, and a genealogy of the development of Chinese public security literature gradually became clear before my eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in the latest novel &quot;White Scroll&quot;, we get to know Qin Ming as a father. Compared with the &quot;bad boy&quot; narrative that was popular in detective literature in previous years, &quot;White Scroll&quot; is about Qin Ming. The way children imagine the weak may be more traditional, but it is also more in line with the real concerns and anxieties of contemporary parents. In this novel, the forensic doctor is still the main body of action in the novel, but the father is more able to convey the author&#39;s inner voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The chat with Qin Ming lasted less than two hours, but I felt a sense of solidity, trust and security on the other end of the phone. This may be due to the simplicity and sincerity revealed in his words and voice, or it may be due to his many years of professional experience in front-line police work. And during this chat, I also vaguely felt the possibility of another understanding of the sense of reality in the novel &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot;. This sense of reality does not lie in whether the story itself is &quot;purely fictional&quot;, but in a kind of Perseverance in writing attitude and inner belief in justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Forensic Medicine in Reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Qin Mingyou Well, since the publication of your first novel &quot;Corpse Whisperer&quot; in 2012, through the publication of more than a dozen novels, the adaptation of many film and television dramas, and now the very popular variety show &quot;Jobs -&quot; Forensic Season&quot;. Forensic medicine, which was originally a relatively niche and somewhat mysterious profession, has now gradually become well-known to the public. Why did you choose the profession of forensic medicine in the first place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was in middle school, I basically didn’t know much about forensic medicine. My father was a policeman and my mother was a nurse. My father had a special interest in me. I had the complex and expectation that a son should inherit his father&#39;s career and become a police officer. However, my mother felt that being a police officer was too dangerous. Later, when I applied for a volunteer, I compromised and applied for a forensic medicine job. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you take an anatomy class for the first time, What are the scenes and feelings like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I went to college in 1998 and began to study in the professional field of forensic medicine. In the process of studying and working, I gradually realized the forensic medicine importance. For example, the first story in my novel &quot;The Corpse Whisperer&quot; tells the story of a fight between several young people, and one person was stabbed to death. It was originally a very simple case, but it required forensic identification of the tools that caused the injuries in order to accurately determine their respective legal responsibilities. The key point is that the deceased in this case was an acquaintance of mine, so it posed a great psychological challenge to me. This was my first anatomy class, and I was very impressed. I was deeply shocked by the importance of forensic work, and from then on I set my life ambition: I must be a good forensic doctor in my life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you later engaged in forensic work, Will there be any changes in your mind? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At first I would feel very angry with the criminal and hate the evil as much as I hate them. But the sign of a true maturity of a forensic doctor is his indifference. He will not pay too much attention to things other than the case. Instead, he will put all his energy on the autopsy and try his best to find clues. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is, as forensic doctors continue to accumulate work experience, Not only has the professional and technical level been improved, but also the entire personality has been tempered and changed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it should be like this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before, I thought forensic medicine was a type of doctor. The main task is to perform an autopsy. But through your novels and the &quot;Forensic Season&quot; program, I discovered that forensic doctors also have to undertake a lot of work in on-site investigation, physical evidence identification, and even case reasoning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ACJAPjfdzIYaZVxRhcxS9mLdD2WvZgY9LZ5lBvRy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/ACJAPjfdzIYaZVxRhcxS9mLdD2WvZgY9LZ5lBvRy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, forensic doctor Qin Ming will participate in the reality show &quot;Forensic Medicine Season 2&quot; as a guest. The picture shows the poster of the show. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, our Chinese public security organs have set up As a forensic department, public security forensic doctors must participate in case scene investigation and case investigation. In some Western countries, forensic doctors, as independent inspection agencies, usually only need to identify three pieces of information: cause of death, time of death, and instrument of injury, and generally will not express opinions on other than these three issues. However, in our investigation process, all police types must play their maximum role within their professional scope, so that they can solve the case most efficiently. We often say that the center of a murder scene is the corpse, and the forensic doctor is the only police officer who comes into contact with the corpse, so the forensic doctor will have the core information of the entire scene. Therefore, our forensic doctors often have to participate in more case analysis and reasoning processes. This also ensures that our various police departments work together as a whole to maximize the effectiveness of the team and solve cases with the highest efficiency. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a story in my book about the murder of a family of five. The murderer used knives to kill the host and hostess, the host’s mother, nanny and children. The five bodies were all covered with knives. The injuries were fatal. Only the nanny and the old lady&#39;s heads still had scars from the hammer, and they were still injured after death. When encountering such a case, many Western forensic institutions will feel that the cause of death, time of death, and the instrument of injury are very clear when conducting examinations, and will not proceed to the next step of reasoning. But our forensic doctors will continue to reason based on these clues: Why did the murderer hit these two people&#39;s heads with a hammer after they died? The biggest possibility is that it is reinforced damage, just to ensure that the deceased will die, and if she is not dead, she will be hit twice. So under what circumstances would reinforced damage be used? That means the deceased knew the murderer. So why only use reinforced damage on old ladies and nannies? It means that only two of them in the family of five know the murderer, and no other family members know him. Who could the murderer be? We speculated that he might be a vegetable vendor in the market, who usually only has contact with old ladies and nannies. As a result, we greatly reduced the scope of investigation and improved the police&#39;s efficiency in solving crimes. Therefore, I say that allowing forensic doctors to be more involved in the entire process of investigation, reasoning and solving cases is actually an institutional arrangement that is more suitable for our country&#39;s national conditions and can greatly improve the efficiency of solving cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What a wonderful reasoning. In many other current criminal investigation dramas, suspense films, or mystery novels, the role of forensic doctors is also set up, and they are given important functions in solving crimes. However, most of the forensic characters in these film and television dramas or novels are women - such as the female forensic doctor Gao Yanan in the TV series &quot;White Night&quot; (2017), and the female forensic doctor in Hu Yanyun&#39;s novel &quot;Sweeping Rat Ridge&quot; (2020). Forensic doctor Lei Rong et al. I wonder what the gender ratio is between men and women in the real forensic profession? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Movies and TV dramas may be based on dramatic considerations, so many female forensic roles are set up. However, in the actual gender composition of the profession, the majority of forensic doctors are men. The ratio of men to women in Anhui Province is about 10:1. The advantage of men engaging in forensic medicine may be that many autopsies are actually laborious work, and sometimes they need to go to the remote mountains and forests in the middle of the night. But female forensic doctors also have their own advantages. For example, they are often more meticulous and can handle some details better. At the same time, a lot of the work of forensic doctors is to assess injuries. When it comes to female injured people, female forensic doctors also have their own conveniences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When it comes to forensic-themed film and television dramas, in addition to urban themes In addition, the profession of forensic medicine is now increasingly entering the public eye, which in turn has led to the popularity of another type of film and television dramas, which are works with ancient ghosts or autopsy personnel as the protagonists. From the early &quot;The Punisher of the Song Dynasty&quot; (2005) to the recent &quot;The Imperial Gift of Xiaowu&quot; (2021), even Gongsun Ce, who was beside Bao Zheng, had to some extent the ability to perform autopsies. In my opinion, this is actually using some modern forensic technology and spirit to reimagine an ancient puppeteer. Do you usually watch these film and television works? What do you think of these works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As you said, the essence of the &quot;criminal officials&quot; or &quot;husbands&quot; in these ancient film and television dramas is still based on modern Artistic image processing performed by forensic medicine. To give two examples, one is that according to ancient customs, in most cases corpses cannot be dissected, and the case can only be concluded through autopsy. Of course, for many cases, autopsy can also roughly clarify the basic situation of the case. Unless there are doubts that cannot be resolved by autopsy, the body can be dissected. Another is that the ancient corpses only had the function of cleaning and moving corpses, but did not have the function of identification. Only officials are qualified to conduct autopsies and appraisals. In the ancient status hierarchy, the robbers were often untouchables and did not have such qualifications. They did not even have the power to fill in the autopsy records, while our modern forensic doctors have the right to appraisal. So the two costume dramas you mentioned are actually quite different. Song Ci in &quot;The Punishment Officer of the Great Song Dynasty&quot; is a Tidian criminal prosecutor of the fourth rank, while the protagonist in &quot;The Imperial Gift of Xiaowu Zuo&quot; is a Xiaowu Zuo. The two people&#39;s job functions and scope of power are actually different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is to say, ancient works were subject to the feudal social class order Constrained by concepts, they cannot give full play to their professional knowledge and professional skills. This poses a significant limitation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Writing novels “completely stems from grievances”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to being a forensic doctor, your other important identity is a writer. Why did you initially choose to write a novel about your forensic experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My writing stems entirely from grievances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to say? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After I engage in the profession of forensic medicine, on the one hand, I will feel the importance, even greatness and sublimity of this profession. But on the other hand, in daily life, forensic doctors will also encounter some misunderstandings and discrimination. For example, after some people know that I am a forensic doctor, they are unwilling to shake my hand or eat at the same table with me, thinking that it is bad luck. Within the public security system, forensic medicine as a police force also needs to be paid more attention to and valued. We often tend to see the police who finally arrest the criminals, but tend to ignore the forensic doctors who are behind the scenes and have done a lot of identification and reasoning work. At the same time, I also write novels to popularize some basic forensic knowledge, so that when a case does occur, netizens will have better forensic literacy and will not be easily deceived by rumors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/IbzSDdVqLa25EXgvR7DppuaXEGEgG2ooKfVooyjB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/IbzSDdVqLa25EXgvR7DppuaXEGEgG2ooKfVooyjB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Forensic doctor Qin Ming. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ELLE Magazine/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is equivalent to obtaining correct forensic knowledge, which in some cases improves the ability to identify rumors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, at the same time, I also hope to deter crime. Someone asked me before, aren&#39;t you worried that readers will commit crimes after reading your novels? I said I&#39;m not afraid. I don&#39;t write novels to attract attention, but I hope my readers will understand after reading my novels that we have the most professional forensics and the highest detection rate. Here &quot;if you commit a crime, you will be caught.&quot; I hope that my novel can make kind people be more vigilant and make people with evil intentions put down their butcher knives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Well, in fact, the creative attitude determines the specific way of writing the novel. are different, correspondingly, the final writing effect and reader impact will also be different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, that’s true. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think is society’s current understanding of forensic medicine? Is it getting better? Do you still feel the grievances you felt when you first wrote? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Now the public knows more and more about forensic medicine, and they are increasingly aware of the characteristics and greatness of the profession of forensic medicine. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series of novels is particularly touching. What’s great about it is the sense of reality revealed in it, which is a reality derived from daily work experience. For example, in your novel, you talk about the details of the forensic doctor shaving the hair of the dead body. The scalpel must be used to shave the hair cleanly without damaging the scalp. At first glance, it is a detail that can only be written by a professional. So why did you initially choose the fictional literary form of novels? Have you ever considered writing non-fiction documentary works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This involves some issues of writing ethics and case confidentiality. The novels I write are basically a combination of fiction and reality. Forensic work and reasoning are &quot;real&quot;, but the case itself is &quot;fictitious&quot;. I may have made up a case story, but the daily routine and core reasoning points of forensic work are all real and come from life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This combination of virtuality and reality is also very interesting. Do you usually like to read detective novels? Who are your favorite detective novel writers and works? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My favorite writer has not changed in so many years, it is Hai Yan, but to be precise, he does not write detective novels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Well, actually Haiyan is in a broader sense It is written on the theme of public security and incorporates quite a few elements of romance novels into it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, he has an urban style. The first Hai Yan novel I read was &quot;Plain Clothes Police&quot;. The novel was written very early, but I only got into the trap after I went to college in 2000. Later, the second book was &quot;A Romantic Affair&quot;, as well as &quot;Death in Youth&quot;, &quot;Jade Guanyin&quot; and &quot;Deep Prison&quot;, including the later &quot;Dancer&quot; and &quot;Chang&#39;an Robbers&quot;, which I bought immediately. Among those who came here to read, I liked the book &quot;Deep Prison&quot; the most. Later, Jiao Junyan went to star in the movie &quot;The Bandits of Chang&#39;an&quot;. She was the heroine in my first online drama, and she was also from Anhui. We were very familiar with each other, so I was very excited when I heard that she was going to star in this movie adapted from Hai Yan&#39;s novel. . In addition to Hai Yan, I also read Remy&#39;s &quot;Psychological Crime&quot; series, Zhou Haohui&#39;s &quot;Death Notice&quot; series, including Ma Boyong&#39;s novels. I don&#39;t know if they are considered mystery novels, but I also like to read them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I heard that you and Remy have some fun relationship experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Remy is a teacher at the Criminal Police Academy. I am a student at the Criminal Police Academy. I went to the Criminal Police Academy to study for a degree after graduating from university. Double bachelor, so even though Remi and I are about the same age, he did serve as my teacher. In addition, after I finished writing my first novel and sent it to him for reading, he made three suggestions that have impressed me to this day: first, please clarify the usage of &quot;的,地,得&quot;; second, read less novels of the same type, Continue to maintain your own style; third, be a writer who can write for a long time. I think I have basically implemented the three suggestions he made at the beginning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What a very frank suggestion. Would you say that Remy&#39;s portraits of criminal psychology in Fang Mu are more fantasy and fiction, while your &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series is more realism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think the character Fang Mu is completely fictional. On the one hand, criminal psychological profiling technology is very important in specific crime research and solving cases. It does exist in the process; on the other hand, I think Fang Mu may be a collection of many successful cases of outstanding public security officers, and it is not completely fictitious. In contrast, my &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series may be more convincing because forensic science is a natural science. I will explain scientific principles to you and come up with a conclusion to solve the case, which you think is credible. But psychological analysis is also based on science. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Erasing the footprints will leave more traces of wiping”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If the &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series is also placed in the literary tradition of detective novels, since Conan Doyle&#39;s &quot;Sherlock Holmes&quot;, detective Holmes actually has two skills : One is the meticulous on-site observation ability. Footprints, fingerprints, bloodstains, hair, soot, no detail will escape Holmes&#39;s eyes, and these can often constitute the key clues for his final solution of the case; the other is his ability to observe the scene in detail. Strong logical reasoning ability, as Holmes himself said: &quot;Logicians can deduce from a drop of water whether it comes from the Atlantic Ocean or Niagara Falls, without having to see or hear about the Atlantic Ocean or Niagara Falls. Life is a huge chain, as long as we see one link, we can infer the characteristics of the entire chain.&quot; If we look at the two literary traditions created by Sherlock Holmes novels, the &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series seems to have inherited and developed the A tradition, and combining that tradition with a very specific, modern profession, creates a certain sense of authenticity. What do you think of these two traditions of detective fiction? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think different writers have different writing emphases and concerns. People often ask me whether I am a conservative or a socialist. I say that I do not belong to either school because the things I write are not reasoning for the sake of reasoning, but reasoning for the purpose of solving crimes. If I have to summarize it, I think it can be called &quot;realistic reasoning.&quot; On the one hand, real physical evidence is the premise and basis for reasoning; on the other hand, the combination of physical evidence and reasoning has the ultimate goal of solving the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nowadays, a very important branch of mystery novels It&#39;s &quot;secret room murder.&quot; In your &quot;Survivor&quot;, the fourth case is the &quot;Death Room&quot;. In &quot;White Scroll&quot;, the tenth case is also called &quot;The Heartbroken Chamber&quot;. Of course, I think the &quot;secret room&quot; mentioned in your novel is still very different from the concept of the &quot;secret room&quot; in current &quot;Xinbenge&quot; novels. What do you think of the secret room design in this mystery novel? If in &quot;new original style&quot; mystery novels, &quot;secret room&quot; often means a combination of some kind of wild imagination and rigorous logical reasoning, then in the eyes of forensic detectives, is it possible for a secret room to exist? Or will the so-called &quot;secret room&quot; definitely leave traces and clues deliberately forged by the murderer? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very touched, because you really understood the meaning of my novel. We often say that as long as someone appears at the crime scene, material exchange will occur. For example, if you set up a very complicated secret room, we usually call it a &quot;closed site&quot;. Can you not leave any traces? Many people say that just wiping off the footprints is enough, but wiping off the footprints will leave more traces of wiping. The more the suspect thinks about it and the more redundant actions he takes at the scene, the more clues and evidence he leaves for the police. Just like many people often ask me whether there are &quot;high IQ crimes&quot;, I say that truly high IQ people will not commit crimes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When it comes to &quot;high IQ crimes&quot;, I think of Zijin Chen’s novel, he has a novel called &quot;Undocumented Crime&quot;, in which there is a very interesting imagination, that is, the criminal is a top expert who is proficient in the two fields of forensics and forensics. When such a person commits a crime, there will be no scene at the scene. There will be some clues and evidence left. The detective who solved the case was a university mathematics teacher with super logical reasoning ability, so he formed a plot design in which the &quot;King of Reasoning&quot; solves the &quot;undocumented crime&quot;, which is somewhat similar to the peak showdown in traditional martial arts novels. What do you think of this type of literary imagination? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Qin Ming: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Different novelists have their own specialties and different ways of writing novels. I also like to read Zijin Chen’s novels. But our writing methods may be different. He is good at arranging reasoning, and my specialty is writing forensics. In my actual work, there is no &quot;crime without evidence&quot;. &quot;Undocumented&quot; means &quot;innocent&quot;. Only by finding evidence and forming a complete chain of evidence can a conviction be achieved, so my novel may focus more on evidence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your early novels, each story was They are relatively independent of each other, but the same group of forensic doctors connect these different cases and different short stories together. To a certain extent, it may be closer to a set of &quot;short story collections&quot; that are closely related to each other. You also said in the &quot;Preface&quot; to &quot;Survivor&quot; that one of the essences of the &quot;Forensic Qin Ming&quot; series is to &quot;based on individual cases and add the main thread that intersperses the whole book.&quot;而在最新的这本《白卷》中，我明显能感受到整部小说的整体性设计，首尾呼应、环环相扣，一个复杂的长篇小说的结构已然形成，这样一种从短篇故事连缀到长篇小说的变化是你有意为之的结果吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是的，其实“法医秦明”系列小说是成卷的，前六本《尸语者》《无声的证词》《第十一根手指》《清道夫》《幸存者》《偷窥者》都是“万象卷”，写的是人间万象，所以更接近短篇小说集的写法。然后从《天谴者》开始，《天谴者》《遗忘者》《玩偶》和《白卷》，是“众生卷”，我在写法上会有很大不同，就是每一本书虽然还是有好几个案件故事，但整体上围绕一个社会问题来写。比如《天谴者》主要聚焦的是社会责任感，《遗忘者》主要聚焦腐朽的女德思想，《玩偶》聚焦的是家暴，而这一本《白卷》主要是聚焦的是亲子关系里的沟通问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我写小说另外一个变化在于，我在“众生卷”里减少了命案的篇幅，而增加了其他意外死亡的故事，主要原因有三：一是老秦本身就是写实派的作者，而实际情况中，命案的确是越来越少了；二是法医工作绝对不仅仅是在命案中发挥作用，在死亡方式的判断和整个诉讼过程中都能发挥不可替代的作用，我希望我的读者可以看到法医在其他更多领域发挥作用的故事；三是法医工作博大精深，除了现场分析之外，还有很多其他的案件需要法医贡献力量，我想让我的读者全面地了解法医学专业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在《白卷》里面写的很多是关于父母和子女之间的日常相处、代际隔阂的问题，你这本书对于亲子问题的关注，和你作为一名父亲的身份有关系吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;秦明：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题不太好回答，因为我自己和我父亲一样，在孩子的成长过程中是缺位的。因为工作原因，我以前一年要出差两百多天，现在案子少了，也要出差几十天到一百天。所以平时工作也挺忙的，对孩子的教育过程我自认为还是属于半缺位的状态。但我还是很关注这个问题，希望通过小说引起大家对于青少年的关心，我是想去触发大家的思考，而不想去说教。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[广州多区放开限购，增值税“五改二”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257224]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 18:27:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月20日，广州发布《&lt;span>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/span>;》，广州成为全国一线城市中首个部分放开限购的城市。近日来，在“认房不认贷”、商贷利率下调等政策利好下，广州房地产市场出现回暖迹象，本次楼市新政则以“组合拳”方式，进一步有序有效促进房地产行业健康发展。以下为《&lt;span>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/span>;》内容：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;穗府办函〔2023〕49号&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州市人民政府办公厅关于优化我市房地产市场平稳健康发展政策的通知&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各区人民政府，市政府各部门、各直属机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为深入贯彻落实党中央、国务院决策部署，坚持房子是用来住的、不是用来炒的定位，适应房地产市场供求关系发生重大变化的新形势，围绕稳地价、稳房价、稳预期的目标，分类精准施策，持续加大保障性住房建设和供给力度，更好满足居民刚性和改善性住房需求，促进我市房地产市场平稳健康发展，坚决遏制投机炒作，根据我市房地产市场实际情况，经市人民政府同意，现就有关事项通知如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一、优化住房限购和增值税免税年限&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将本市住房限购政策调整为，在越秀、海珠、荔湾、天河、白云（不含江高镇、太和镇、人和镇、钟落潭镇）、南沙等区购买住房的，本市户籍居民家庭限购2套住房；非本市户籍居民家庭能提供购房之日前2年在本市连续缴纳个人所得税缴纳证明或社会保险证明的，限购1套住房。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;将越秀、海珠、荔湾、天河、白云、黄埔、番禺、南沙、增城等区个人销售住房增值税征免年限从5年调整为2年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二、加大保障性住房建设和供给&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大力加快推动公共租赁住房、保障性租赁住房和配售的保障性住房发展。提高公共租赁住房保障水平，完善户籍家庭公共租赁住房保障方式；支持各类市场主体积极参与，多主体、多渠道筹集建设保障性租赁住房；建立健全配售的保障性住房体系，稳慎有序开展规划建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本通知自印发之日起施行，原有政策与本通知不一致的，以本通知为准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;广州市人民政府办公厅&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;2023年9月19日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 18:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陪审员制度如何落槌？“无袍法官”的存在感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257009]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/P6dhXIftDzZEuh7z4QKo2gS8HtyqJcfnJX9kUHY9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/P6dhXIftDzZEuh7z4QKo2gS8HtyqJcfnJX9kUHY9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;多个地方法院开庭审理了省内首例由具有专门知识的人民陪审员参加的环资案件。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在人民陪审员的专业性探索上，贵州省江口县向前迈了一步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月8日，江口县法院、公安局、司法局联合发布公告，在全县常住居民中选任60名人民陪审员，其中包含10名具有环境资源专门知识的人民陪审员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前不久，最高法于2023年7月27日发布《关于具有专门知识的人民陪审员参加环境资源案件审理的若干规定》（以下简称“规定”）。这既是近年数量激增、专业性极强的环境资源案件（以下简称“环资案件”）的特殊需求，也是人民陪审员制度的一个新拓展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;规定发布后，吉林白城市、广东阳江市、河北围场县、山东利津县、辽宁沈阳市浑南区、黑龙江林区等地，先后开庭审理了省内首例由具有专门知识的人民陪审员参加的环资案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陪审制度在中国司法领域发挥作用的时间不长。 2004年8月，全国人大常委会审议通过《关于完善人民陪审员制度的决定》，第一次明确人民陪审员制度，中国有了“无袍法官”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，人民陪审员“陪而不审，审而不议”“形同虚设”等现象普遍存在，备受社会诟病和法学界批评。 2018年4月，陪审员法正式颁行，确立了陪审员随机选任、任期限制、“大合议庭制度”等原则，一定程度上改变了过去的弊端。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，中国司法体系已设置专家辅助人制度，2012年以后修订的刑诉法、民诉法及其他专门法律，也越来越多地倡导“有专门知识的人出庭”。但无论是“专家”还是“有专门知识的人”，都是为了解决审判中的专业性、技术性问题，都属于证人、证据的范畴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，一些特殊领域的案件中，合议庭也越来越多地出现“专家型”的人民陪审员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京大学法学教授陈永生表示，合议庭在审理案件过程中向专业人士咨询，在司法实践中一直存在，此次加以制度化，有利于提高环资类案件的专业审判水平。 “可以预见，由具有专门知识的人担任陪审员，未来也会出现在其它专业性较强的领域”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;身份存疑的“画眉鸟”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“画眉子”“点水雀”是什么鸟？是画眉鸟吗？是同一种鸟吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;在四川汉源县法院审理的一起非法狩猎鼬獾、“画眉鸟”案件中，主审法官何刚遇到了难题。 2023年5月开庭时，法院请了县林业局工作人员李志华、前域镇动物卫生监督所工作人员曹立祥参与审理，他们的身份是“专业人民陪审员”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是四川首例由“专业人民陪审员”参与审理的环资案件，发生在最高法的规定发布前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汉源县检察院指控，马烈村李某某从2018年以来非法制造、持有枪支，并从2020年以来使用弹弓、射钉枪猎杀多只“画眉鸟”和一只“花鼻纹”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于案情不严重，本案采取简易程序，合议庭采用“1（法官）+2（人民陪审员）”结构。主审法官何刚三十多岁，担任法官8年，虽然已有较丰富的审判经验，但生物学知识不足。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;案涉皮毛经四川农业大学鉴定，确系鼬獾，系国家“三有”保护野生动物。但画眉鸟是国家二级保护动物，案犯所说“画眉鸟”到底是什么鸟，多少只，涉及定罪量刑。曹立祥和汉源县林业局工作人员李志华，就是来帮助解决这一难题的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹立祥是一名兽医，已有30年的从业经历，从2015年起就经镇政府推荐，抽选为汉源县法院的人民陪审员。迄今，他已经参与过二三十起案件庭审，但大多是基层的民事纠纷。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月的这起案件，是曹立祥和李志华第一次利用职业背景，以“有专门知识的人民陪审员”身份陪审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹立祥和李志华提前阅读了法院提供的案卷。庭审中，曹立祥提了多个问题：你是用什么枪打的？在哪个地方打的？打了几枪？是一枪命中，还是几枪命中？鼬獾打的什么部位？询问过后，再与缴获的鼬獾皮毛相对照。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去几年实践中，曹立祥学会了核查人证、物证，“要看和他的供述是不是一致。防止替罪顶包”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹立祥进一步询问李某某所猎杀的“画眉鸟”特征：皮毛是什么样？是什么颜色？羽毛颜色在哪个地方有什么变化？头部、尾部、躯干有什么特点？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“画眉鸟”的问题上，李某某的表述中出现了“画眉鸟”“画眉子”等不同方言叫法。曹立祥和李志华说，在汉源县农村，“画眉（音mi）鸟”对应的不一定是真正的画眉鸟，也有可能是点水雀，或者是其他鸟。生物学中的画眉鸟，也分许多种类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曹立祥希望通过生物特征、生活习性、飞行高度和动作等，来确定李某某猎杀的鸟是否国家二级保护动物画眉鸟。但由于李某某供述的特征与生物学上的画眉鸟特征不符，且案发时已没有实物证据，不能排除合理怀疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终，因证据不足，法院对李某某“猎杀”画眉鸟的事实不予认定。李某某因猎杀鼬獾犯非法狩猎罪，被判拘役4个月，加上非法制造枪支、非法持有枪支两个罪名，数罪并罚，获刑三年六个月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ys29RW2wJIALlNMgvfDZyasJxXkL6kOvmOn7Augq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/ys29RW2wJIALlNMgvfDZyasJxXkL6kOvmOn7Augq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;有专门知识的人民陪审员发表意见后，四川汉源县法院对一被告人“猎杀”画眉鸟的事实不予认定。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不会说话的“物”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;何刚说，环资案件有别于一般案件，“影响环境的，大多时候是一种&#39;物&#39;，物是不会说话的，而且涉及专业性难题，比如一个地方的植物死了，它可能是有很多原因积累的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果法官自己去查资料，限于知识结构，要么消耗时间，要么不准确，不具权威性。这时候，有专门知识的人来提供专业意见，就至关重要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;环资案件还有一个特点，就是前期大家不重视，等发现后，污染或破坏的周期已很长了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天津大学中国绿色发展研究院执行院长孙佑海，曾任全国人大环境与资源保护委员会法案室主任，他在2022年发表的论文《环境司法专门化背景下专家陪审员制度研究》中提到，环境资源案件由于因果关系复杂，导致审理时间较长，当事人由于缺乏专业知识，容易对法庭审判的公正性产生怀疑，影响司法公信力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙佑海举例，2007 年福建某矿业化工公司排放废气案，从2010-2012年经历了起诉、一审判决、提起上诉、发回重审、二审判决、申请再审、再发回重审和再审判决的曲折过程，引发当事人不满。 “导致审判过程漫长而反复的一个核心原因就是不同鉴定机构的鉴定意见不一致，但环境法官不了解环境专业知识，故不能对鉴定意见及时作出准确的判断，从而导致司法机关在案件审理和判决中难以对案件定性”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从环资类案件审理实际来看，提升陪审员的专业性很有必要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在2019年4月，最高法公布的关于陪审员法的司法解释中，就规定“因案件类型需要具有相应专业知识的人民陪审员参加合议庭审判的，可以根据具体案情，在符合专业需求的人民陪审员名单中随机抽取确定”。此后，知识产权、未成年人、金融、医疗纠纷、网络科技等领域的案件纷纷选任“专家陪审员”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比而言，环资案件涉及化学、生物以及林业、畜牧、矿产、土地、水资源等细分门类，专业性更强，外行难以判断，因此对专业陪审员的需求也更为紧迫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;最高法针对环资案件发布的规定，明确“具有专门知识的人民陪审员”指具有环境资源领域专门知识，或在环境资源行政主管部门、科研院所、高等院校、企业、社会组织等单位从业三年以上的陪审员。该规定自2023年8月1日起实施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，在规定出台之前，全国各地各级法院已有不少相关探索和实践。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵州省清镇市人民法院于2007年成立了中国第一个生态保护法庭，2010年12月，该庭在审理一起造纸厂偷排污水的案件时，邀请了两位“人民陪审员”，一位是环保高级工程师、贵阳市两湖一库管理局局长帅江，一位是环保专业博士刘晓静，并召开了专家咨询委员会进行论证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2014年，重庆万州区法院经区人大常委会审议通过，聘请西南大学渔业资源研究院副院长姚维志、万州区林业科学研究所所长任凭等4名环境专家担任陪审员，参与审理了奉节县电磁辐射案、红豆杉污染案、开县养牛场土地污染案等一系列案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些地方还积极建设环境陪审员专家库。如贵州省高级人民法院于2014年初出台《关于环境专家陪审员参与案件审理的规定》，并建立生态环境陪审专家库。 2016年1月至2017年12月，重庆各级法院累计聘请18名专家作为专家陪审员，参加合议庭审理案件124 件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2022年，邀请具有环保专业知识背景的专家担任陪审员逐渐成为趋势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;随机与公平&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2018年，第一部关于人民陪审员制度的专门法律陪审员法出台，广受法学界好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京大学法学教授陈永生认为，陪审员法很重要的一点，是强化了陪审员产生的随机性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前，各级法院的人民陪审员主要来自所在单位和基层组织的推荐，或陪审员自荐。陪审员法出台后，虽然保留了推荐模式，但主要的产生方式，是由司法行政机关会同法院、公安机关从本地居民名单中随机抽选，进行资格审查后提交同级人大常委会予以通过和任命。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈永生还认为，在该法产生之前，许多地方的陪审员席位是固定化的，长期专职化的，与法官熟头熟脸，难以起作用。而陪审员的随机产生，有助于防止司法腐败，“心理学的规律表明，一个人在与熟人打交道时发生腐败的可能性比较高。相反，在一个生人面前，如果违法违规的话，对方可能举报，想谋取不当利益，应该还是会有顾忌。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20世纪八九十年代，中国的法律体系对陪审制是一种“否定态度”。学界称之为陪审制的“低潮期”。那时，后来成为中国人民大学法学教授的何家弘还在美国留学，已开始了解美国的陪审团制度。 1990年代发生的“辛普森案”，给了中国法律界巨大启发，“原来美国的案件还可以这么审，让一些普通老百姓来决定”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据陪审员法，法院抽选拟任陪审员数量的5倍作为候选人，而实际选任的陪审员名额数不低于本院法官数的3倍。有的试点法院，陪审员名额甚至是法官的10倍。这正是为了增强人民陪审员的广泛性和代表性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，陪审员法规定担任陪审员须年满28周岁，高于2004年规定的23周岁。陈永生曾提出，基于“同案审判”原则，应该扩大年龄限制，“这是为了扩大和增强审判员的代表性。因为现有规定，导致28岁以下的被告人，没有与身份构成相对应的同类陪审员”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一提议背后，体现了陪审制固有的精神——陪审员不能只选法律专业人士，如大学教授、司法助理，还应该引进民间智慧。换言之，要让“外行”参与审判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“为什么要设立陪审制？就因为学过法律的人，他的头脑对问题的思考方式已经被格式化了，他比普通人更加理性。而来自民间的陪审员基于感性的生活经验，比法官更能充分理解被告人产生行为时的因果联系、感受反应。”陈永生说，这有助于案件裁判更符合法律规定，也能帮助法庭在法律框架内最大限度地考虑当事人的人性和个人感受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近几年，最高法司法解释对“正当防卫”认定标准的变化，就是因多起重大案件引起的社会舆论，而更贴近人情伦理。 “陪审员制度要使用好的话，就可以实现国法和人情、国法和天理的有机统一。”陈永生说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英美陪审团制度一案一组团，每个案子都重新组团，大陆法系参审制的陪审员也有不超过两届的任期限制。 “无论英美法系还是大陆法系，都不能一直当陪审员，防止陪审员从外行变成内行。否则就发挥不了陪审员作为外行可能具有的优势”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另据最高法统计，截至2021年，全国有人民陪审员共计31.6万余人，比2018年增加了约50%。何家弘认为，近年，全国案件数量迅速增加，2019年以来，全国各级人民法院受理案件总数每年都在3000万件以上。 “涉及各个领域专门知识的案件也在增多。因此，法院面临人力、脑力双重不足的问题。”何家弘认为，此次出台规定，邀请有专门知识的人担任人民陪审员，可以有效解决法院人力、脑力不足。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MAnwC42xdiZsLdSFdeEYFFPyxO9AjO6hm41DCkSr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/MAnwC42xdiZsLdSFdeEYFFPyxO9AjO6hm41DCkSr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;人民陪审员曹立祥（中）和李志华（右）在查看相关证据。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（汉源县人民法院/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;从“专家”到“有专门知识”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“这个新的规定，只是在某个类型的案件中，把以前实践中广泛采用的做法给制度化了。”陈永生说，被中国法学界广为肯定的英国大法官丹宁勋爵所著《法律的正当程序》里也提到，陪审团的一项重要功能，就是聘请专业性的陪审员解决专业问题。 “可以预见，由具有专门知识的人担任陪审员，未来也会在其他专业性较强的领域推行，或出台相应规定”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈永生曾作为咨询专家，被公检法部门邀请去讨论一些环保案件，但他坦承，自己也只能就其中的法律问题发表意见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，陈永生遇到一个建筑垃圾堆放污染的刑事案件，检察院希望通过了解危害程度判断嫌疑人是否构成犯罪，以及是否起诉。 “一种垃圾对环境有没有损害，我是不懂的。我认为建筑垃圾无非是钢筋和水泥，应该无害。但专业人士表示，建筑垃圾堆放会破坏土壤，破坏耕地，雨水淋湿后还会沁出一些有毒物质。这都需要专门的研究人员才清楚。”最后，环保专家的意见起到了重要参考作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在规定出台前的2021年，天津大学法学院受托举办《最高人民法院关于专家人民陪审员参加环境资源案件审理的若干规定》（征求意见稿）专家研讨会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最终出台的规定中，“专家人民陪审员”改成了“有专门知识的人民陪审员”，称谓的变化，是基于现实操作性的考量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在陈永生看来，所谓专家，至少应该拥有硕士甚至博士学位，在大学或科研机构里工作，拥有中级乃至副高以上的职称。 “理想的状态当然是由专家担任陪审员。但全国有三千多家法院，90%以上都是基层法院，如果限定为专家身份，门槛太高，基层法院显然无法做到。”而实际上，大部分案件中的专业问题，只需有相关专业背景、从业经验的人来认定就足矣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，“有专门知识的人”也是法律上一个比较通用的专有名词，现行刑诉法、民诉法中均多处规定“聘请有专门知识的人”出庭或做鉴定。陈永生解释，“这个&#39;有专门知识的人&#39;，法学界上叫作专家辅助人，有时也称专家证人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但显然，这些均属于证人范畴，与在合议庭中引入有知识的陪审员是两个不同的司法路径和方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湖北环源律师事务所律师曾祥斌做过数十件环资案件的公益诉讼。 “我还没有发现一个因为专业性问题而影响到法院公正审判的”， “现有的诉讼制度，已经足够使用，不需要额外找一个专门性的人来” 。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，陈永生并不认同。陈永生认为，专家证人、司法鉴定制度，都是服务于争讼双方的，各方出具的鉴定报告一般也都是对自己有利，请来的专家证人往往也是对自己有利。同一个案件中，原告和被告的鉴定结果有时是相反的，甚至检察院前后几次鉴定结果不一致的情况也常常发生，“这时候，有专业知识的陪审员站在中立的立场上来判断控辩双方的意见，辨别真伪，去伪存真，就有必要”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙佑海也在论文中指出，专家辅助人只对当事人负责，其中立性和独立性有所欠缺，有专业知识的陪审员则不同，一方面可以科学认定案件证据事实，另一方面也可以代表人民有效监督法院的审判工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;要保证&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;与法官权力平等&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;最高法此次公布的规定，对基层人民法院和中级人民法院审理环境资源案件时，对“具有专门知识的人民陪审员”数量提出了明确要求，并根据案情不同，对合议庭人数也提出了要求，与陪审员法的原则基本一致。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何家弘和陈永生都认为，虽然立法比较完善，但司法实务中存在的最大问题是陪审制没有完全落实。近年一些社会影响重大的案件，并未全都采用陪审制。陈永生认为，“尽管办案机关也做了辩解，比如担心陪审员操纵不了，难作决定，但他们的辩解是没有说服力的。违背了陪审员法的立法宗旨。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;表示遗憾的还有何家弘，“包括法国等大陆法系国家的司法改革，都是重大、严重的刑事案件采用陪审制。但是我们国家这么多年一些重大案件不用陪审，反而日常的普通案件都用陪审制。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他和一些法学专家曾被法院邀请旁听一些庭审，有专家就提出，“这个案件也不是很重要，而且被告人也认罪，也没有争议，要陪审员干吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何家弘认为，这些社会影响重大的案件，原本是向社会宣传陪审制理念的绝好机会，却被浪费。 “关注度极高的情况下，对法院领导和法官如何驾驭大合议庭，也提出了更高要求”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;究其原因，陈永生说，许多案件都需要向专委会、审委会、庭长、院长汇报，甚至要向上级法院、政法委等上级单位请示，才能决定裁判结果。 “很多案件的决定权就不在合议庭”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈永生说，“合议庭都没有裁判决定权，陪审员更没有。陪审员发表了意见也无法影响案件结果，就导致陪审员不愿意积极行使陪审的权利。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体到环境资源类案件审理，孙佑海指出，要为有专门知识的人民陪审员提供保障制度，包括参审权、对案件的知情权和对案件的表决权，保证陪审员的权力与法官的权力平等，让他们“全身心地投入案件陪审工作，并且在履行陪审职务时没有后顾之忧”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在野党党首绝食抗议，日本核污水排海再引韩国朝野纷争]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 17:39:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/uMBu5GmaGxoYRYoG1X1WJetEUJcrCreencsaMH7u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/uMBu5GmaGxoYRYoG1X1WJetEUJcrCreencsaMH7u. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Congressman Lee, you are no longer alone.&quot; On the afternoon of September 19, 2023, former South Korean President Moon Jae-in appeared at a hospital in Seoul to visit Lee Jae-myung, leader of the opposition Democratic Party of Korea . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moon Jae-in held Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hands tightly and persuaded him to &quot;stop the hunger strike&quot; and engage in the &quot;long-term battle&quot; (of the Common Democratic Party) with a new attitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early the morning before, an ambulance took Li Zaiming to the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Lee was in extremely poor health tomorrow morning and was in a daze and had to make an emergency call.&quot; Park Sang-joon, spokesman for the Democratic Party of Korea, told South Korea&#39;s YTN radio station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 18, 2023 was the 19th day of Li Zaiming&#39;s &quot;hunger strike&quot; to demonstrate against the Yin Xiyue government. On that day, the South Korean court once again filed an application for detention of Li Zaiming on the charge of &quot;dereliction of duty.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lee Jae-myung accused the Yoon Seok-yue regime of undermining order and democracy in South Korea, and went on a hunger strike on August 31. As of now, Li Zaiming is out of danger, but his body is still weak. He stated that he would only maintain infusion treatment and continue his hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lee Jae-myung&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;’s “indefinite hunger strike”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“As one of the citizens, I start today to challenge the incompetent and violent regime. &#39;National&#39; resistance.&quot; On August 31, 2023, Lee Jae-myung announced an &quot;indefinite hunger strike&quot; at the press conference for the first anniversary of the Democratic Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zaiming made three demands to the ruling party: Yin Xiyue apologized to the people for destroying people&#39;s livelihood; the ruling party should oppose Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea; and reorganize the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lee Jae-myung is Moon Jae-in’s “successor” within the party. Before entering politics, Li Zaiming was a human rights lawyer and participated in human rights and citizen movements many times. From 2010 to 2021, Lee Jae-myung served successively as the mayor of Seongnam and the governor of Gyeonggi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2021, Lee Jae-myung resigned as governor of Gyeonggi Province and participated in the South Korean presidential election. He narrowly lost to South Korean President Yoon Seok-yue and later became the leader of the Democratic Party of Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early days of the hunger strike, Li Zaiming set up a tent in front of the Capitol and conducted a sit-in protest. As Lee Jae-myung&#39;s health declined, he began to move into the party leader&#39;s office. Many senior figures from the Democratic Party of Korea and South Korean politicians came to persuade him to stop his hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Korean media reports, the ruling National Power Party &quot;took no measures&quot; in response to Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike. &lt;p>; /p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Central Daily News&quot; editorial criticized the ruling party&#39;s inappropriate stance on &quot;Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike.&quot; The National Power Party once ridiculed that &quot;a seafood tasting event will be held near Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike tent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sit-ins, marches and hunger strikes are common practice in South Korea’s political arena, and both the ruling and opposition parties will express condolences to hunger strikers. In the 1980s, when former South Korean President Kim Young-sam went on a hunger strike, the secretary of the then ruling party went to express condolences and conveyed then President Chun Doo-hwan’s intention to urge an end to the hunger strike; in 1990, when former South Korean President Kim Dae-jung went on a hunger strike to demand the full implementation of local autonomy , Jin Yongsan also went to express condolences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing pressure from public opinion, Kim Ki-hyun posted on social media on September 16, &quot;solemnly requesting Lee Jae-myung to stop his hunger strike&quot; and proposing to hold a meeting between the leaders of the ruling and opposition parties to discuss people&#39;s livelihood affairs after he &quot;recovers his health.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“To avoid prosecution charges”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;South Korean prosecutors once believed that Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike was suspected of avoiding the prosecutor&#39;s investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is the first time I have gone on a hunger strike after being notified of being summoned by the prosecutor.” Korean Minister of Justice Han Dong-hoon complained that the continued operation of the judicial system cannot be suspended just because a suspect under investigation went on a hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, South Korean prosecutors investigated Lee Jae-ming in connection with the &quot;Sangling Group Bribery Case.&quot; It is believed that when he was the governor of Gyeonggi Province from 2019 to 2020, he was suspected of soliciting a bribe of approximately 10.6 billion won from Kim Sung-tae, chairman of Sangryong Group, on the pretext of paying for a visit to North Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Li Zaiming is related to two cases. From 2014 to 2015, while serving as the mayor of Seongnam City, Lee Jae-myung was suspected of taking care of real estate developers based on his position, causing the Seongnam Urban Development Corporation to lose 20 billion won. In February 2019, Lee Jae-myung was suspected of violating the Public Office Election Act and instigating others to provide false testimony that was favorable to him during his trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of September 18, when Li Zaiming was seeking medical treatment, South Korean prosecutors merged the two suspicions of the &quot;Sangling Group Bribery Case&quot; and the &quot;Real Estate Case&quot; and applied for an arrest warrant against Li Zaiming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, Yin Xiyue, who was attending the United Nations General Assembly in New York, approved the arrest consent request sent by the prosecutor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a current member of Congress, Lee Jae-myung enjoys the privilege of not being arrested without the consent of Congress. To arrest a member of Congress, more than half of the members must be present and more than half of the members must agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to South Korea&#39;s &quot;Parliament Law&quot;, after receiving the consent for arrest, the Speaker of the National Assembly needs to convene a plenary meeting report on the matter and vote &quot;within 24 hours and 72 hours&quot; after the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;South Korean prosecutors are using clues to bite Li Zaiming, but the possibility of him being arrested this time is not high.&quot; Li Jiacheng, associate professor at the School of International Economics and Politics at Liaoning University, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters, South Korea in February 2023 The prosecutor&#39;s request to arrest Lee Jae-myung for the real estate case was rejected by Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, South Korea has 297 current members of Congress, including 167 members from the Common Democratic Party, accounting for more than half of the opposition parties. This time, Li Zaiming&#39;s hunger strike received concern and condolences from important people within the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Central Daily News&quot; report, on September 20, the South Korean Congress will hold a plenary meeting to discuss the &quot;Lee Jae-myung Arrest Consent Case&quot; and vote on September 21. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the South Korean Congress will also vote on the &quot;Recommendation for the Removal of Prime Minister Han Deok-soo.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to Lee Jae-myung’s hunger strike, the Democratic Party of Korea submitted a proposal to dismiss Prime Minister Han Deok-soo on September 16, demanding the collective resignation of the ruling party’s cabinet. The move was seen as an attempt by the opposition parties to put pressure on the Yoon Seok-yue government. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The controversy behind the discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the recent &quot;issue of Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea&quot;, the Korean government and the opposition are quite divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of August 23, before the hunger strike, Lee Jae-myung led more than a thousand people related to the Democratic Party of Korea to hold a candlelight rally. He accused &quot;the East China Sea is turning into the Sea of ​​Japan&quot; and urged the Yoon Seok-yue government to oppose the discharge of Japan&#39;s nuclear-contaminated water into the sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Power Party represented by Yin Xiyue supports &quot;discharging nuclear contaminated water into the sea&quot; and sends a signal to the international community that &quot;you will not die if you eat aquatic products.&quot; On August 29, the ruling party held a two-day and one-night &quot;eating broadcast&quot; to promote aquatic products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Representative Lee (Jae-myeong) comes to a place like this and eats some (aquatic products)!&quot; Park Dae-chu, chairman of the policy committee of the National Power Party, joked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ordinary people in South Korea strongly oppose Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea, and the progressive Democratic Party supports the ordinary people. The National Power Party, which is dominated by conservative forces, is pro-American and pro-Japanese in foreign policy. Yoon Seok-yue The government strongly supports Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water. The opposition between South Korea&#39;s ruling party and public opinion has become a political opportunity for Lee Jae-myung,&quot; Li Jiacheng told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiacheng believes that Li Zaiming’s hunger strike is more like preparation for canvassing votes for the 2024 South Korean parliamentary election. On the one hand, he united the &quot;unknown&quot; forces within the Democratic Party of Korea, and on the other hand, he fought for the &quot;people&quot; and won the sympathy votes of voters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 10, 2024, the South Korean Congress will hold an election. Since Lee Jae-myung&#39;s Democratic Party holds a majority of seats in the National Assembly, the ruling National Power Party hopes to regain control of the National Assembly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Yin Xiyue narrowly defeated Democratic candidate Li Zaiming by a narrow margin of 0.73% in 2022, he has never admitted that Li Zaiming is his &quot;dialogue partner.&quot; The two have not held formal talks since the election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yin Xiyue disdains talks with the suspect (Lee Jae-myung).&quot; &quot;The Hankyoreh&quot; quoted a core figure of the ruling party as saying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, after Lee Jae-myung received medical treatment, according to a South Korean Media Tomato poll, less than 30% of the people gave a positive evaluation of &lt;span>;Yin Xiyue&#39;s administration&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly half of the people believe that Li Zaiming&#39;s hunger strike is a protest against &quot;Yin Xiyue&#39;s mismanagement&quot;, and nearly 42% of people oppose &quot;the arrest of Li Zaiming&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生林曦对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法发布危害药品安全犯罪典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Court released 5 typical cases of crimes endangering drug safety on the 18th, involving imported drugs, vaccines, and medical beauty. Different drug types such as drugs, special disease drugs, and dental over-the-counter drugs, including typical criminal methods such as cybercrimes, disinfectant products counterfeiting drugs, and medical insurance fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These five typical cases are: the case of Huang Moulin and others producing and selling counterfeit drugs; the case of Yan Mou selling fake and inferior products; the case of Zhang Mousong and others producing and selling counterfeit drugs; the case of Yang Mouyu and Cai covering up , a case of concealing criminal proceeds; a case of producing and selling counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Drug safety is related to the health and life safety of the people, the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood, and the overall stability of society. The cases announced this time are closely related to the daily medication safety of the people and are representative to a certain extent. Many of the defendants were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of more than ten years and imposed heavy fines, which reflects the people&#39;s court&#39;s clear attitude and firm determination to adhere to the people&#39;s supremacy and severely punish crimes that endanger drug safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, people&#39;s courts at all levels strictly implement the &quot;four most stringent&quot; requirements, give full play to their judicial functions, severely punish crimes that endanger drug safety in accordance with the law, and effectively ensure the drug safety of the people. From 2013 to 2022, courts across the country concluded more than 28,000 first-instance criminal cases involving the crimes of producing, selling, and providing counterfeit drugs, producing, selling, and providing inferior drugs, and obstructing drug management, and sentenced more than 38,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the Supreme People&#39;s Court will supervise and guide local people&#39;s courts at all levels to further improve their ideological understanding, consolidate the main responsibilities, conduct trials in accordance with the law, activate justice, and implement the implementation of safeguarding drug safety and protecting people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人文主义地理学之父段义孚终其一生都在思考啥问题？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257005]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8Gdihs9dKjOZzzDXXM4o2BOpZHSMlsdy5BXwBaHW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8Gdihs9dKjOZzzDXXM4o2BOpZHSMlsdy5B XwBaHW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tuan Yifu and his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;(Shanghai Bookstore Publishing House, 2023). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the pedestrian bridge, looking at the brightly lit city under the night sky, I can&#39;t help but think of Mondrian&#39;s paintings. It is an art composed of colorful grids and lines, and is a visual presentation of the balanced beauty of the universe. I have to think about: What is the connection between cities, landscapes, architecture, art, etc., and people? This is also a question that Yifu Tuan, the father of humanistic geography, has been thinking about throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about Duan Yifu, people may mention his birthplace of Tianjin, his childhood place of residence in Chongqing, his relationship with Duan Qirui, talk about the countries and countless cities he has traveled to, and admire his work in Despite his brilliant academic achievements, he may still lament his long and lonely life. Such a life is complicated - both brilliant and dull, surrounded by others and often alone. He settled in an apartment in a metropolis, but rooted his soul in the desert and the universe...&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Because of his rich, wise and simple inner world, Yifu Tuan is often called the &quot;little prince&quot; in the field of geography. His most well-known achievement is that in the 1960s and 1970s, when the positivism advocating instrumental rationality swept Western geography, he restored the humanistic spirit of geography in a simple, determined and wise way, and pioneered the study of geography. Humanistic geography, which had a far-reaching influence on later generations, became famous in the world academic circles. Although there have been many differences and tensions between the development of geography and Tuan Yifu&#39;s thoughts since the 1980s, and his own research and writing style is difficult to be inherited by later generations, his knowledge creation and wisdom enlightenment have always been beyond the reach of geography. An overlooked bright color. In other words, if Yifu Tuan had not been born in this world, the light of geography’s wisdom would be much dimmer than it is now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many scholars have written articles about Yifu Tuan’s life and contribution to geography. In my eyes, one of Yifu Tuan&#39;s most outstanding contributions to geography is that he restored the aesthetics and emotion of geography, thus greatly expanding the scope of geography research and writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Yifu Tuan, many geographers had emphasized that the expression of aesthetics and emotion is an important channel for understanding the natural environment. This actually goes back to a common question asked by scientists during the Enlightenment: How do people understand nature? Alexander von Humboldt, who had a profound influence on Yifu Tuan, was one of the important figures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/OFo8OX1dEBnqWuulC3E4n7CNjYjYnvhPftAYk0IV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;928&quot; height= &quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/OFo8OX1dEBnqWuulC3E4n7CNjYjYnvhPftAYk0IV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alexander von Humboldt. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt devoted his life to inspiring &quot;love of nature&quot; and advocated that &quot;nature must also be experienced through human feelings&quot;, Because Humboldt himself was greatly influenced by Kant&#39;s transcendental rationalism. Kant emphasized that human reason legislates nature, which naturally shifts the relationship between human beings and the environment to the human side. As a result, Humboldt&#39;s thought first brewed the &quot;people-centered&quot; humanistic geography perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, while Humboldt was in Jena, he lived with the poet Goethe day and night, and influenced each other, which made his study of nature constantly highlight human subjectivity. He shifted from his initial obsession with pure empirical analysis to Develop an understanding of nature, linking precise scientific evidence with emotional responses to landscapes. Furthermore, he also re-examined people&#39;s &quot;imagination&quot; and believed that imagination is as important as rational thinking and is also a necessary tool for understanding nature. These seeds of Humboldt&#39;s thoughts were sown in Tuan Yifu&#39;s thoughts. In many of Yifu Tuan&#39;s works, we can clearly feel the intertwining of reason and imagination, which constitutes an important channel for interpreting the meaning of the environment. For example, Yifu Tuan&#39;s work &quot;Place, Art and Self&quot; explores the bridge of meaning between environment, emotion and self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Humboldt inspired Yifu Tuan’s human-centered perspective, then the “semiotics” that attempts to connect people and things helped Yifu Tuan open up the emotional relationship between people and the environment. American philosopher Susan Lange is an important figure in semiotic aesthetics. Her &quot;Emotion and Form&quot; is a book often cited by Yi-fu Tuan. Her influence on Yifu Tuan is reflected in exploring the &quot;form&quot; relationship between human feelings and the environment. This relationship is known in geography as &quot;sense of place.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Susan Lange insists that the human senses are also capable of abstraction. As she puts it: &quot;Eye and ear must have their logic.&quot; Such logic is not a positivist inference of factual evidence. Logic, but the &quot;logic of representation&quot; when people experience environmental materials. For example, although waves have no direct relationship with life on the physical level, the image of never-ending waves is as continuous as life. This is what Susan Lange calls the similarity of representational logic, which is also the form of emotion, a symbol that connects people&#39;s feelings with the environment. Yifu Tuan uses metaphors in many works to describe such connections. For example, Yifu Tuan talked about how people would associate their bodies with the landscape, producing words like &quot;ridge&quot; and &quot;estuary&quot;. Although at the physical level, mountains have no backs and rivers have no mouths, there are similarities in apparent logic between them. Then, artificially creating these words expresses the formal isomorphic relationship between human feelings and natural objects. This kind of &quot;sense of place&quot; is exactly what Yifu Tuan is exploring. For example, the relationship between vision and color, body and architecture, imagination and mountains, etc. Furthermore, at the deepest level, the isomorphic relationship between &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;place&quot; can also be explored. Yifu Tuan summarizes all these relationships into one term - &quot;experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YEJQETUdhzENESNAVxpx6BdxfD754p2EkWQeWzaZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YEJQETUdhzENESNAVxpx6BdxfD754p2EkWQeWzaZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Susan Lange&#39;s &quot;Emotion and Form&quot; is a book that Yifu Tuan often quotes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the attributes of &quot;experience&quot;? In the book &quot;Space and Place&quot;, he pointed out: Experience is like a spectrum, with one end leaning toward emotion and the other end toward thought, but the two blend with each other from beginning to end. Therefore, Yifu Tuan&#39;s definition of the connotation of experience has greatly expanded the scope of geographical epistemology: while recognizing the value of rational analysis (scientific), it also gives equal status to emotional description. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Yifu Tuan’s geographical emotion is an emotion that can communicate with others, can form intersubjectivity, and has an objective logical form. In other words, this emotion starts from the individual and transcends the individual. It is a kind of intentionality with universal significance. It is precisely because of this that Yifu Tuan&#39;s geography can enter the public domain and generate extremely high academic value. Therefore, it is not as criticized by positivists that Tuan Yifu&#39;s geography is only individual and subjective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his academic career of more than sixty years, Yi-fu Tuan created a large number of geographical works rich in emotion and aesthetic form. For example, he successively explored the relationship between alienation and fragmentation between people and the environment (&quot;The Broken World and the Self&quot; in 1982), the coexistence of pampering and manipulation (&quot;Making Pets&quot; in 1984), and the relationship between localism and cosmopolitanism (1996 &quot;The Universe and the Hearth&quot; (1998)), and the relationship of escape (&quot;Escapism&quot; (1998)), etc. These works have greatly enriched the research content of geography. According to Tim Criswell, a former protégé of Yi-Fu Tuan and now a professor of geography at the University of Edinburgh, “When Yi-Fu Tuan was studying the desert landscapes of the American Southwest, few geographers cared about how the landscape reflected human life. Values, and no one will pay attention to people&#39;s emotions of pampering and controlling the environment, and no one will think that the most ordinary things in life, such as houses, gutters and scissors, have beauty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time , in order to explore these relationships, Duan Yifu not only wandered through various fragments of literature, ethnography, psychology, and ancient urban history, but also used poetic language to skillfully weave the themes he wanted to express. , the scope of geography writing has been greatly expanded, providing rich nutrients for the development of humanistic geography in later generations. Therefore, Tim Criswell said: Yifu Tuan’s influence has transcended the glorious 1970s of humanistic geography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Yifu Tuan’s geographical aesthetic appreciation is not entirely an objectified aesthetic appreciation. He even incorporated his own life experience into it. As Duan Yifu wrote in his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;&quot; said that geography helped him overcome the loss of life and find the meaning of life. It was geography that saved him. Therefore, Tuan Yifu&#39;s geography is often a kind of writing that &quot;uses itself as a method&quot;. In other words, he analyzed his life as a practical sample for the world to observe, allowing others to see his own joys, anger, sorrows, life and death, and then formed a kind of environmental aesthetics and emotional expression in which the author&#39;s &quot;subject appears&quot;, which is profound. The intensity and appeal far exceed the object-oriented aesthetic method of simply standing opposite the scenery and maintaining a certain distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, 92-year-old Yifu Tuan published a booklet titled &quot;Geography from 1947 to 2022: A Travel Record&quot;. He said:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly is my contribution to human geography? That is, I enriched the meaning of the word &quot;person&quot;. In the past, geographers in the field of natural science were people who had the courage to explore inaccessible places. When I was an undergraduate, the geography professors at Oxford and Cambridge were all such explorers. …They have little to no interest in people. When geographers talk about people, they just treat them as another natural force that changes the landscape of the earth. Since the 1930s, talents have been given other attributes. First, under the influence of Karl Saul, people were given cultural attributes; then in the 1960s, under the influence of David Lowenthal and Robert Gates, people were given psychological attributes; and finally in the 1970s, people were given psychological attributes. In the era, people are endowed with aesthetic attributes. But what baffles me is why such an obviously human attribute has been ignored for so long. The fact that it was ignored was due to the prevailing paradigm at the time. Therefore, I urge you once again, young traveler! Be sure to have the courage to steer your ship like a captain, albeit with only life&#39;s confusing clues and stars as your guides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Yifu Tuan’s contribution to geography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 16:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[三年4任董事长，“药中茅台”为何震荡不断？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257180]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/rCNgV1xm9msQKl2HYkAS2vgrqM209hWEGqk8Z4kU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/rCNgV1xm9msQKl2HYkAS2vgrqM209 hWEGqk8Z4kU. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many time-honored traditional Chinese medicine companies face the same anti-corruption problem. (Pien Tze Huang, composed of bezoars, musk, notoginseng, and snake gall, is used to clear away heat. Detoxify, cool blood and remove blood stasis, reduce swelling and relieve pain. This small pill is said to have been introduced from the Ming Dynasty. The company that manufactured it was founded in 1956 and has been on the market for 20 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Pien Tze Huang has reached a turning point again.” Li Bin, a long-term holder of Pien Tze Huang shares, private equity fund manager Li Bin, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 6, 2023, Lin Zhihui, the new chairman of Pien Tze Huang (600436.SH), with a total market value of more than 164 billion and known as the &quot;Moutai of Medicine&quot; by the market, attended the 6th &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; Traditional Chinese Medicine Development Forum. Investors believe this is his first appearance since becoming the new chairman in early August. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Pien Tze Huang’s fourth coaching change since 2021. The previous two chairman of the board were investigated by the Discipline Inspection Commission for suspected serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August, the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province released information that Liu Jianshun, who had served as chairman of Pien Tze Huang for seven years, was expelled from the party for violating laws and disciplines. He will retire in 2021. Pan Jie, who succeeded him, was also subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision in May for suspected serious violations of discipline and law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, five executives of Pien Tze Huang and its subsidiaries have been investigated in 2023. From June 2022 to the present, Pien Tze Huang’s board secretary, chief engineer, chief auditor, etc. Many senior executives have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Lu Dingliang, a lawyer at Jingshi Law Firm, the products of traditional Chinese medicine companies such as Pien Tze Huang leave room for power rent-seeking due to their certain resource nature and scarcity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The number of Pien Tze Huang executives who have been investigated is relatively prominent, which is closely related to the company’s stock price, product selling price and scarcity.” He analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chairman of &quot;Liu Shui&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. was founded in 1999 by the restructuring of Zhangzhou Pharmaceutical Factory, which was established in 1956. , currently has 13 directly held subsidiaries and 9 joint-stock companies. Its controlling shareholder is a state-owned enterprise in Zhangzhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August, the Zhangzhou Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released information that former chairman Liu Jianshun was expelled from the party for serious violations of discipline and law. It mentioned that he &quot;received gifts and large amounts of money in violation of regulations; relied on enterprises to support enterprises, and took advantage of his position to provide Others seek benefits and accept huge amounts of property from others.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jianshun is 60 years old and served as chairman of Pien Tze Huang from 2014 to 2021. During this period, Pien Tze Huang’s revenue increased from 1.4 billion yuan to 6.5 billion yuan, and the stock price rose from 21 yuan/share to 4 in 2021. The monthly highest price is around 350 yuan/share. Three months after he left office, Pien Tze Huang experienced a period of intense speculation, with its stock price rising to a new high of 480 yuan per share, and Pien Tze Huang tablets on the market selling for thousands of yuan per pill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, Liu Jianshun retired early due to &quot;personal physical reasons&quot; and resigned from relevant positions. Pan Jie, who had served as general manager of Pien Tze Huang and other positions, took over as chairman. But within eight months, Pan Jie resigned from the relevant position on the grounds of &quot;work adjustment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.sse.com.cn/disclosure/listedinfo/announcement/c/new/2022-04-16/600436_20220416_6_1FsQWSqY. pdf&quot;>;Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. 2021 Social Responsibility Report and ESG (Environmental, Social and Corporate Governance) Report&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&quot; mentioned that in 2021, Pien Tze Huang established the &quot;Zhangzhou Municipal Supervisory Committee in Office of the Ombudsman of Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July of the same year, according to information on Pien Tze Huang’s official website, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Offices of three Pien Tze Huang-owned enterprises, including Cosmetics Co., Ltd., were established, achieving full coverage of supervision of all public officials exercising public power in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Lin Weiqi, a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Director of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province, became the new chairman of Pien Tze Huang. During his tenure from June to July 2022, the then secretary of the board of directors, deputy general manager, supervisor, chief engineer, and chief auditor resigned one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than 17 months after taking office, in July 2023, Lin Weiqi resigned from the company due to &quot;work adjustment&quot;. A month later, Lin Zhihui became Pien Tze Huang&#39;s new chairman. According to the announcement issued by Pien Tze Huang, Lin Zhihui has served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and a member of the Zhangzhou Municipal Supervisory Committee. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking stock of official notifications over the past year: In May, former chairman Pan Jie was subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision on suspicion of serious violations of discipline and law; in June, the former deputy director of Pien Tze Huang Cosmetics Co., Ltd. Chairman Yang Puquan was put on file for review and investigation for serious violations of disciplines and laws; in August, former chairman Lin Jinsheng of Pien Tze Huang Cosmetics Co., Ltd. was expelled from the party and public office for serious violations of disciplines and laws; at the end of August, former chairman Liu Jianshun was expelled from the party for serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these intensive notifications, words such as &quot;relying on enterprises to eat enterprises&quot; and &quot;seeking personal gain&quot; were mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;More corruption problems occur in dealers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How much impact does frequent coaching changes have on the company? Pien Tze Huang&#39;s stock price has dropped from the highest of 482.33 yuan per share at the end of 2021 to the current price of 271.98 yuan per share, a drop of 43%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin believes that Pien Tze Huang has a very mature brand, system and customer base, so the role of management is relatively downplayed, and the replacement of senior executives will have little impact on the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the financial report, from 2020 to 2022, Pien Tze Huang’s revenue increased from 6.511 billion yuan to 8.694 billion yuan, and its net profit increased from 1.672 billion yuan to 2.472 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin said, &quot;Generally speaking, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s main sales channels are not in hospitals, but in pharmacies and the Internet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the financial report, in 2021, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s operating income was 8.022 billion yuan, and sales expenses were 650 million yuan. In 2022, operating income was 8.694 billion yuan, and sales expenses were 483 million yuan. Selling expenses account for 8.1%-5.55% of revenue. In comparison, the IPO report of Hanwang Pharmaceutical, a traditional Chinese medicine pharmaceutical company, showed that sales expenses accounted for more than 80% of its main business revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Dingliang believes that traditional Chinese medicine is different from Western medicine and equipment. “The public relations focus of medical equipment and Western medicine is to have a good relationship with doctors and hospitals. But the corruption of traditional Chinese medicine in the C-end market is more about distribution. Corruption issues have arisen in the business chain.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the financial report, Pien Tze Huang’s domestic sales model is mainly OTC, that is, over-the-counter drugs. The main sales channel for prescription drugs is hospitals, and for over-the-counter drugs is pharmacies. Pien Tze Huang&#39;s sales channels include Pien Tze Huang experience centers, retail pharmacies and regional distributors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Pien Tze Huang Experience Center&quot; appeared for the first time in the 2015 financial report. There were more than 20 experience centers that year. By the end of 2020, there were more than 300 “Pien Tze Huang Experience Centers” operating across the country. According to a report by China International Finance Securities in August 2023, there are nearly 400 Pien Tze Huang experience centers across the country, covering more than 100,000 terminal stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Liang became the person in charge of a Pien Tze Huang experience center in 2019. In his view, the changes in Pien Tze Huang’s management will not have a big impact on the experience center he runs. In comparison, the impact of price increases is more direct. &quot;The market is indeed relatively weak now, and the experience center itself does not want to increase prices. After the price increase, sales will decline,&quot; he told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is still growing, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s revenue growth rate in 2022 is the lowest in five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Pien Tze Huang stated that due to reasons such as the increase in main raw materials and labor costs, it would increase the domestic market retail price of its main product Pien Tze Huang tablets from 590 yuan/tablet to 760 yuan/tablet, and the supply price would be increased accordingly. About 170 yuan per pill, the largest price increase in history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Pien Tze Huang&#39;s 2003 prospectus, in 2000, the average domestic sales price of Pien Tze Huang was 93.2 yuan per pill. In twenty years, the price increase has been as high as 715%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the ex-factory price is 390 yuan/tablet, the market retail price of Pien Tze Huang tablets is 590 yuan/tablet. How much is the difference between the current ex-factory price and retail price of Pien Tze Huang tablets? Zhang Liang said, &quot;The ex-factory price is confidential, but our price difference is not high and cannot be compared with Moutai.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A long-term investor in Pien Tze Huang told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;This price adjustment (to 760 yuan), as far as I know, the ex-factory price should be 560 yuan.&quot; That is, the difference between the ex-factory price and the retail price is 200 yuan/pill, the same as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Pien Tze Huang Experience Center who is familiar with Li Bin also believes that after the price increase, there will be a certain impact on sales within half a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally, sales will gradually return to normal after half a year. This year&#39;s price increase directly increases the ex-factory price and retail price by the same amount. In other words, the profit from the price increase belongs to Pien Tze Huang Company, and the profit It will be reflected in the performance, and the dealers will not make more money,&quot; Li Bin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the 2023 semi-annual report, the gross profit margin of Pien Tze Huang pharmaceutical manufacturing industry was 74.2%. In the 2022 annual report, this figure was 78.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of a traditional Chinese medicine company told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;The high profits of traditional Chinese medicine companies do not mean high profits for dealers. Products that can be sold at the C-end will not have much price difference.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“ &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Depend on the success of the enterprise &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the pharmaceutical industry told Southern Weekend Reporter, in terms of drug research and development, Pien Tze Huang is a national secret formula with mysterious origin and high price. It seems to be widely used, but the price/performance ratio is unclear, but the sales volume is very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Drug Administration, the protection level of Pien Tze Huang is level 1, which is the highest level. Among the national traditional Chinese medicine varieties, only Pien Tze Huang and Yunnan Baiyao are national top-secret formulas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pien Tze Huang is now known as &quot;Moutai of Medicine&quot;, and the last one to be so called was Dong&#39;e Ejiao. From 2001 to the end of 2018, the price of Dong&#39;e Ejiao has been raised 18 times, an increase of 37 times. The reason for the price increase is &quot;the shortage of donkey skin resources.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the above-mentioned traditional Chinese medicine company also used Dong&#39;e E-jiao as an example. The profits of Dong&#39;e E-jiao dealers are also very thin. If the dealers stock up, the company will give a slight discount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The gameplay is to stock up downstream + increase prices. Frequent price increases are also because listed companies want to increase profits. I find Pien Tze Huang (price increases) a bit confusing, but only this type of company can have excess profits &quot;, he told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, Dong&#39;e Ejiao&#39;s growth has stagnated, and in 2019 it suffered its first loss in 23 years since its listing. From 2017 to 2019, the company&#39;s book inventory exceeded 3 billion yuan. It began cutting prices and selling stakes in its subsidiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, Dong&#39;e Ejiao (000423.SZ) issued continuous personnel change announcements. The then chairman and vice president both resigned due to &quot;job changes.&quot; This is the third chairman the company has replaced since November 2019. Similar to Pien Tze Huang, three chairmen resigned in three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2020, nine senior executives including Qin Yufeng, the president of Dong&#39;e Ejiao, the assistant president, and the vice president resigned one after another.两年后，秦玉峰涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受华润医药控股有限公司纪委和山东省聊城市监察委员会的纪律审查和监察调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与它们类似的，还有同仁堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在片仔癀被爆炒的2021年年底，同仁堂（600085.SH）将安宫牛黄丸的终端零售价从780元提至860元，称为中药原材料上涨所致，此后多个品种相继提价。安宫牛黄丸是同仁堂的核心单品，2022年，同仁堂营收154亿元，包括安宫牛黄丸在内的前五大产品实现收入45亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月，中纪委国家监委网站发布的相关报道中提及，北京同仁堂原总经理高振坤借安宫牛黄丸原料采购牟利1500万余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文中提及，在制作安宫牛黄丸、大活络丸、牛黄清心丸等同仁堂招牌成药时，豹骨、麝香、羚羊角、牛黄等成分不可或缺，这些需求量大、利润高的濒危细料，让高振坤看到了巨大的权力寻租空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在同仁堂集团二级企业股份有限公司任职期间，高振坤牢牢把住细料采购权，利用供给优势和信息优势牟取私利达1500万余元。为了维系与高振坤间的关系，多名供应商竞相为其打点吃穿用度，高振坤随口一句“孩子上学远”，就能换来一套两居室出租屋的钥匙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;裁判文书网发布的同仁堂副总经理、经营分公司经理王清泉受贿的相关信息中提及，其利用职务便利，多次以明显低于集团规定的内部价格向相关方购买安宫牛黄丸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前公布的片仔癀相关高管被查的信息中，也多次提及“靠企吃企”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卢鼎亮看来，中药产品属于中间环节较多、利润空间较大、专业和技术壁垒较高、采购透明度不足的领域，这些特点给腐败提供了空间。同时，该领域的利益输送方式较为隐蔽，腐败行为发现难度大、线索获取难、证据链形成难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“直面C端市场的中药，产品具有一定的稀缺性和不可替代性，经销商如果拿到了销售权，获利空间就比较大，就给&#39;靠企吃企&#39;提供了可能”，他对南方周末记者表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，片仔癀股价一度上涨至483.69元/股，截至发稿，报269.81元/股，跌幅已超40%。但对于长期持有片仔癀的李斌来说，他更看好自5月提价起，片仔癀在半年以后的业绩表现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中张亮为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳研究发现可致儿童痴呆症的145种遗传病]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚研究人员近期确定了145种可导致儿童痴呆症的遗传性疾病，旨在提高社会各界对这些疾病严重程度的认识。相关研究结果已发表在《脑》季刊上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿童痴呆症是由一系列遗传性疾病引起的进行性脑损伤造成的。就像成年痴呆症患者一样，儿童痴呆症患者也会出现记忆丧失、精神错乱、性格改变、睡眠严重紊乱，以及在集中注意力、理解能力、学习和沟通等方面的障碍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个由澳大利亚阿德莱德大学领衔的研究团队对该国及海外已发表的数据展开建模和分析，结果显示儿童痴呆症症状通常在患者两岁半时开始出现，平均诊断年龄约为四岁。患者的平均预期寿命仅为9年，70%的患者在18岁之前死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员表示，导致儿童痴呆症的这145种遗传性疾病非常复杂且多样，比如克拉伯病、桑德霍夫病、亨廷顿舞蹈病等，但共同点是都会造成进行性神经认知能力下降和预期寿命严重缩短。研究结果更清晰地揭示了哪些人易受到这些极具破坏性且未被充分认识的疾病带来的影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员呼吁加大资金投入来研究针对儿童痴呆症的有效治疗方法，同时迫切需要改善对受影响家庭的护理和支持。这项新研究将提高研究人员、临床医生、政府和政策制定者对这些疾病严重程度的认识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏宿迁遭遇强龙卷风，灾情造成5人死亡4人重伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:32:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月19日17时20分许，江苏省宿迁市宿豫区大兴镇、市经开区南蔡乡局地陆续发生强龙卷风，等级判定为EF2级，造成部分地区人员伤亡和财产损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次龙卷风灾情主要发生在乡镇镇区，人员稠密、建筑结构复杂，发生时段恰逢下班时间，由于此次龙卷风的侵袭来得突然，灾情共造成5人死亡，4人重伤。经初步统计，此次强龙卷风受灾人口5512人，1646户房屋一般受损，倒塌房屋137户，农作物受损41.8公顷，临时转移安置405人，2000余平方米猪舍部分墙体倒塌、顶部塌陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;灾情发生后，当地立即统筹指挥相关力量开展现场搜救、伤员转运救治、群众安置、核灾救灾等工作。应急、公安、消防、卫健、住建、供电等部门立即赶赴现场，开展应急救援和善后处置；受灾乡镇迅速组织当地群众开展自救互救。经连夜抢救，伤员已送至医院救治，受灾群众得到妥善安置，受灾地区供电全部恢复、道路交通恢复畅通。宿迁市应急管理局表示，目前灾区社会秩序恢复正常，相关保险公司已赶赴现场开展查勘理赔，其他善后处置工作全面展开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影的滋味丨凝视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256928]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr5dZZKv9GGN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;833&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr5dZZKv9GGN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《月光武士》改编自虹影同名长篇小说，讲述了一个始于1970年代重庆、绵延三十几年的故事。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚上的时间一般用来读书或看电影，昨天看阿加莎小说改编的电影《尼罗河上的惨案》，发现导演肯尼思·布拉纳即主演侦探波洛，也是诺兰最新电影《奥本海默》中尼尔斯·玻尔教授的饰演者。奥本海默认为自己的导师过分，不让他去听一场期待已久的讲座，在苹果里注入氰化钾，第二天他想起，狂奔而去，发现苹果在教授玻尔手里，玻尔正要吃时，被奥本海默阻止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人的绝望，怎么理得清？奥本海默那一刻是绝望的。好电影的滋味会让人浮想联翩。家人说遇到我之前，他在南法度假，想人生无常，心里空荡，毫无牵挂，朝河水走去，被好友发现，抓上河岸。没多久，他在英国一个生日宴上认识我，他说你当时头发一半长一半短，很前卫。我说人就是这样，如果你内心极苦，过得不像样，就会借助外在形式稀释这痛苦，比如有意无意偏向非正常，甚至衣服鞋子，好家伙，我有多少年是穿着高跟鞋，留着这样不规则的头发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还好，你没有文身。他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我有文身，你还会爱上我？我问他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，即便你有，当时我也绝不可能对你反感，人在对的时候遇见，一切都会原谅并包容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这话让我深思。这三年发生太多的事，每个人的命运都发生了变化。之前我是个恋物癖，每到一个地方，会收集纪念物，小到一个瓷器，大到一尊雕塑，喜欢在古董旧货市场淘老明信片老邮票。有一年参加法兰克福书展，和好友欢天喜地在当地最大的露天市场逛，见到老地毯银勺，不还价就收了。现在我不会收，身外之物，何其多，何其累。除了书，我不扔，从去年到今年，一直在清理可要可不要的物品，多余的锅碗筷子，多余的衣服鞋子家具，家渐渐有些留白，我心里一阵轻松。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;活着，比什么都好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《月光武士》这部电影、这个故事，我五岁第一次听见家人邻居说，中学街宽阔绵长的一坡石阶走着一家人，上方的母亲身着和服，得返回日本，下方是父亲带着三个女儿在后面赶。石阶两侧是观望的人。时光流逝几十年，那情景一直在我心中闪现。我由此写了三千字不到的短篇，之后将它改写为五万字剧本，又由剧本改为二十多万字的长篇小说，每个人物在我心里活灵活现。小说出版后，我打破之前的剧本，重新写，每个场景，根据实地来，按照剧本里人物的形象找演员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影的前期是剧本、筹备资金和班子，然后拍摄，后期是剪辑、声音音乐、调色特效，前期难，后期更难。好多人在这个过程中会失去耐心，我努力吸取新鲜的专业知识，研究思索，让自己的听觉、嗅觉、直觉始终处于敏锐的状态。仿佛从一个遥远的国度走向另一个国度，先确定地点，规划路线，准备一路上所需装备，再抛开一切顾虑，什么人也劝阻不了，都说前面是陷阱、是坑、是万劫不复之路，我却不信。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刮大风下暴雨？这个太经常了，不必害怕。路上出现强盗，路上出现乞丐，路上出现笑面虎。唐僧呀，你去西天取经遇见的是妖怪们，想吃你的肉，为的是长生不老。我呢，遇上的一切事和物，是上天来考验我对电影的一片赤诚。电影是这么苦涩，这么坚硬，完全不可食之，只可统统吞入肚里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;949&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《月光武士》的女主人公秦佳惠是一名护士，在工作中初识12岁少年窦小明。电影《月光武士》（2023）剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初剪定时，给人看，有朋友、有专业人士。定剪后，便有电影宣发公司看，有人喜欢，说它带着1970年代重庆的迷人雾幔，中心街老妈小面馆，那是真正的山城烟火气，滋味麻辣酸甜，值得细细品尝；有人不喜欢，说它不像中国惯常的电影，你胆子太大，居然跨界从作家到电影圈，做这么一部怀旧不讨好的电影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偶尔我会说说自己的看法，偶尔我会保持沉默。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《月光武士》男主角少年窦小明的扮演者是左航，他的好多粉丝在微博上催促《月光武士》赶快公映，甚至难听的话都说出来。我在微博上发表了看法，谈到做电影的周期不是他们想象的，拍这部电影是2021年底，后期做了一年，因为在疫情中，后期公司包括好多主创都在隔离中。我们的电影从拿到龙标到现在，才不到三个月，一直在做后续工作、找最适合的宣发公司，不是不想上院线、尽早与观众见面。这条微博引来两极分化的评论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苦闷中，我回忆自己喜爱的中外电影，想到《地道战》里日本鬼子进村被打得落荒而逃的情景；想到《简爱》里那在荒原奔走的身影；想到《卡萨布兰卡》里那钢琴弹奏的乐曲；想到《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》里迷人的沙漠；想到《四百击》里少年最后走到海边的长镜头，一望无际的大海，万里无云的天空；想到《甜蜜的生活》中女主走下楼梯时一道又一道阳光。我试着平静，去接受无法改变的事情，试着去改变我能够改变的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我沉浸在自己的工作，没来得及关注你们，而你们立刻将我踢出你们的世界，与我背道而驰，本来我们是多么好的朋友和亲人，因为做这电影，我失去了你们，也失去了同一个母亲生的大姐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，我遇到了好多这样让我莫名悲哀的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不时会遇到人教育我，为什么做电影没有事先找他/她？声称如果找他/她，我的电影会有明星，会有资金，会更有商业价值。我说，如果那时我找你，你不会理我，如果你理我，这时来向我伸出一只手也不迟。这种人说，世上第一流电影，是（造价）五亿以上的电影；第二流电影是五亿以下的，大制作、大演员；而第三流电影，小制作、没明星。虹影，你正是在做这第三流电影，你是作家，做作家就本分了，你要宣发你的电影，是痴人说梦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我打断对方的话：我做什么，是我的事，而你是在讲电影吗？你是在讲钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱可以生出电影，钱没有一流二流三流之分，钱就是钱，但钱永远不等于电影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影是艺术，第七艺术，乔托．卡努杜说电影是把静的艺术和动的艺术、时间艺术和空间艺术、造型艺术和节奏艺术全都包括在内的一种综合艺术。电影用镜头讲故事，讲一段渐渐淡忘的人的故事，讲那流转已久的传说，讲历史真相，用视觉音效讲述久远年代存在的正义和理想精神，电影就是实现不可能实现的梦，电影就是造梦，没有梦，我们如何做电影？如何看电影？英格玛·伯格曼说，我的电影不是让你的灵魂感到安逸，而是要让你和你的灵魂战斗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;虹影在电影《月光武士》拍摄现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影对我来说，意味着什么？我经常自问，也被人追问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好多时候感觉电影进入我的身体，在吸用我的血和灵气，我是否怀揣石头，走入河中？可是电影对我不放手，我只能折回头。我看见儿时，自己和父亲坐在长江边，注视江上行驶的船，全是定焦的，一帧帧，向我涌来，它们就是世界，这个世界不像我在江之南岸那么灰暗、无望，那么贫困，这个世界在江之彼岸有鲜亮的色彩和希望、无尽的激情和爱。这是电影，它永远属于那些不屈不挠的人，相信这个世界美好的一面，永远不失爱人爱世界的能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天夜里做梦，我又站在重庆江边，与执行导演一起，在等船运来拍摄机器。雾气涌来。我朝前走，河水小心流淌着，我听得见自己的脚步，我看见一个废弃的缆车在前面，跟小时我在江边走过千万遍一模一样，甚至有一个桥洞，我走过去，立即从洞里走回来，我看见雾气在散开，对岸的山峦、房子及一些厂棚若隐若现，江水碧绿，荡漾着波浪，往左望去，就是重庆城中心朝天门左侧嘉陵江的景致。我激动万分，而右边是宽阔的沙滩，我手指那里，对身边的人说，为什么我们要去对面拍那场打斗戏，不，就是这儿，这是小时候我最熟悉的场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冥冥之中，我觉得这是生我养我的重庆，给我坚定的心的一份礼物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我醒来，清晰地记着那是2021年冬天的一个早上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年了，好像很久，好像是一瞬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写下这篇文章时，读到微博《小凤直播室》主持人小凤的微博：“《月光武士》真是这一年度最神秘的电影，由蜚声国际的罗马文学奖得主虹影根据自己的小说改编，并首次拿起导筒执导，她是有多么爱这个故事。帕慕克喜欢《纯真博物馆》，也不过就建造了一座时空有限的博物馆，无法想象他自己挑选一个芙颂和凯末尔，让他们摇晃在伊斯坦布尔的老街上，但虹影做到了。她不仅在纸上将我们催眠，跟随着窦小明、秦佳惠一脚踏进山城弯曲的斜街，还将他们的故事搬上银幕，让山城的氤氲气息，江河的浩荡之美都流经我们的眼底。祝贺《月光武士》获得美国好莱坞下一代独立电影奖最佳剧本创作奖提名，这是于万千期盼中的又一个好消息。&#39;这个电影奖的最高荣誉授予了来自世界各地的杰出故事讲述者和富有远见的电影制作人。&#39;杰出的故事讲述者，是的，那个五岁时在长江边的细雨里奔跑与呼喊的女孩，那个十八岁才知道自己身世从此定格了一生的河流的女儿，她一直是那个山鲁佐德一般靠讲故事活着的女子啊！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的话触及我心最柔软处，哪怕有一个人看到我的行走轨迹，有一个人注意到我的电影，我也应该感恩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我像窦小明和秦佳惠一样摇晃在山城最陡峭的石梯上，看到城市的灯光一点点倾洒在江水上，那艘拖轮从暗下来的两江汇合处开过来，拉响气笛，还有人手持喇叭在喊，“停二号码头”，接着用重庆当地的脏话说起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好熟悉的情景，那不是别人的拖轮，那是父亲的，从他给我看的老照片上，我知道它的模样和形状，当然它早就成了一堆废铁，可我不止一百次想象它出现在江上，我把它复活在电影里，让它永久地存在下来。我的父亲，我相信，你在天之灵会看到这部电影，这部电影是向重庆和重庆人致敬的，又何尝不是向你一样的异乡人、异乡致敬，父亲，我相信，你看到电影最后，你会向我点头，会向我露出少见的笑容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>