<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[尽管发生尴尬的偷窃事件，南阳真的很想让音乐节留下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259039]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/zt64JEq393bR8kyisbmEvvuKcVh5qdtjrZnlCZaN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/zt64JEq393bR8kyisbmEvvuKcV h5qdtjrZnlCZaN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, the venue was muddy due to rain, and staff were on the ground Planks were laid &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Trouble&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Positioning To the &quot;Green Field Monologue&quot;, the taxi passed through Huangshan Village and stopped steadily at the entrance of a muddy open space. The driver asked, &quot;What are you doing here? Are you here to watch the Midi Music Festival?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I said yes, and the driver turned around and said, &quot;I heard that the police raided several houses before (looking for Something), the formation is quite big.&quot; After saying that, the car drove away, kicking up a cloud of dust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going along the entrance, part of the ground is still muddy due to the continuous rain for more than ten days. Drink bottles, plastic bags, and colorful flags are deeply sunk in the mud. Under the sun, a dozen middle-aged men wearing red vests bent down to clean up the garbage on the ground. The crane rumbled aside as workers demolished the remaining two stages in the venue. The harsh sound of the collision of aluminum alloy frames extended to the White River in the distance. In just four days, it was flat again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than ten days ago, the Central Plains Midi Music Festival ended here. It lasted for four days from September 29 to October 2, 2023. 80 bands including Cui Jian and the Pain Yang Band were invited to Musicians, more than 150,000 fans participated. According to official statistics, the scale of this music festival has set a record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at the end of such a huge performance, due to the large-scale theft incidents reported by music fans, it was on the hot search several times, causing heated discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/98g15DzFWElebqLF1zdK9pfoYUAENXjPvz2jV22d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/98g15DzFWElebqLF1zdK9pfoYUAENXjPvz2jV22d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, the only sunny day during the Central Plains Midi Music Festival&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 5, the Central Plains Midi Music Festival Organizing Committee issued an announcement stating that &quot;Due to the violation of regulations by netizen Chen (who has been arrested), he posted false information that &quot;the event has ended and the scene must be cleaned up.&quot; , causing nearby villagers to take advantage of the chaos, and there were many cases of property theft in the camping area. So far, Nanyang police have received 73 reports and implemented 65 theft cases. Some thieves have been captured and detained, and some of the thieves have been recovered. Property.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Yu stood behind her house. The distance between her backyard and the music festival venue was only two meters. After hearing my purpose, she looked at me warily, &quot;Are you here to blackmail us?&quot; After receiving a negative answer, she was dubious, &quot;This is the stage, this is my home, you can see it&#39;s so close.&quot; She said as she spoke Make gestures with your hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before the start of the music festival, people from the town government went to Huangshan Village to mobilize and called on everyone to visit relatives and friends. &quot;Especially those with children and elderly people at home, try not to live here.&quot; Aunt Yu&#39;s The grandson was sent to his grandmother&#39;s house and did not return until the music festival was over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the music festival, the speakers at the venue roared from 1pm to 10:30pm. Aunt Yu didn’t know what rock music was, and she just felt that her “heart was beating out of her chest.” The water heater in her home was &quot;whispering&quot; and the paintings in the house were shaking. More than a dozen security guards stood outside the door every night. After they left around 11 o&#39;clock, she would &quot;wash and tidy up before going to bed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I asked her how she slept. She waved her hands and said, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter. As Nanyang people, this is our pride.&quot; After she said this, the woman standing next to us nodded, and then talked about a time when a family in the village received music fans. of generosity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A lady riding an electric bike joined our chat and said that she was responsible for cleaning during the music festival. After work at night, she was asked for help by a music fan whose mobile phone fell into the mud. She helped him find it in the rain. For more than half an hour, &quot;the sleeves were all wet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the few days of &quot;Greenfield Monologues&quot;, every local person I came into contact with could tell a few words about what they had done for the festival. &quot;Effort&quot;, but &quot;effort&quot; was quickly overwritten by another voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, the music festival ended. As more and more music fans shared their experiences of having their property stolen on social media, the Nanyang and Midi Music Festivals also fell into controversy. Aunt Yu received a lot of doubts and abuses on her mobile phone, and she felt aggrieved, &quot;Everywhere (music festival) is held, there are positives and negatives. (We) have been busy for a month, and there are no benefits, but it has brought some benefits.&quot; A little trouble.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/fagp54LNjGm3dqw7TNBmJIt6DlntttUpcse3vufr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/fagp54LNjGm3dqw7TNBmJIt6DlntttUpcse3vufr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangshan Village, most of the people walking in the village during the day are women and the elderly&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Picture)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;No city is as hard-working as Nanyang&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The rain started in mid-September. People in Huangshan Village feel that the autumn in Nanyang in 2023 is abnormal. &quot;It has never rained for such a long time before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hired local workers planted grass in the &quot;Green Field Monologue&quot; more than a month in advance. The weather was not good, and &quot;people were working in the rain. On one day at most, there were more than 80 people on the site.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The road was built earlier, and construction started as soon as the contract was signed. Half a month before the opening of the music festival, workers began to build the stage, and trucks transporting equipment came and went. Because of the rain, the repaired road was no longer working. &quot;The soil compactor has been rolling, and wooden boards have been added.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&quot;Green Field Monologue&quot; is located in the north of Nanyang City, close to the Dushan Expressway Toll Station, covering an area of ​​three to four hundred acres. The name &quot;Green Field Monologue&quot; was given by Zhang Fanqi, the founder of Midi. When taken apart, it represents Green Grassland, Dushan and White River respectively. In the past, &quot;this land was expropriated by the government, and some rent was paid every year. It has always been in a state of neglect.&quot; Aunt Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August, Nanyang Wolong District signed an industry-wide strategic cooperation agreement with Midi Music School. Public reports indicate that the two parties will carry out all-round and in-depth cooperation starting from the holding of the 2023 Central Plains Midi Music Festival. Zhang Fan said in an interview, &quot;The fate between Midi and Nanyang began four years ago. During this period, the two parties had many exchanges to discuss cooperation. After three visits, this Midi Music Festival named &#39;Zhongyuan&#39; , with the sincere efforts of both parties, settled at the foot of Dushan Mountain and on the bank of Baihe River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /20/9RQnIPsAdw5UH23l9Od949RqPptQEH6G69AsZgSo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/9RQnIPsAdw5UH23l9Od949RqPptQEH6 G69AsZgSo.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;254771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the camping area, for privacy reasons, surveillance is only installed at the entrance and exit&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the opening of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival, Nanyang held a special preparatory meeting. At the meeting, Nanyang Municipal Party Committee Secretary Zhu Shixi pointed out that efforts should be made to make the Zhongyuan Midi Music Festival a city card that shows the image of Nanyang, a cultural feast that promotes the upgrading of cultural tourism, and achieve the goal of &quot;running a good music festival and activating a city.&quot; , the goal of making a city famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve this goal, the preparatory work will particularly emphasize: &quot;Learn from the experience and practices of Zibo Barbecue Out of the Circle, mobilize all walks of life and the general public to fully develop the sense of &#39;ownership&#39;, actively participate, proactively serve, and sincerely Hospitality, fully publicize and display the good image of Nanyang people&#39;s enthusiasm, kindness, civilization and hospitality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to welcome music fans from all over the city, promotional slogans related to the Midi Music Festival are posted throughout the city, such as &quot;Do A good music festival, a good host.” Some of them had not been demolished until ten days after the festival ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chang is a volunteer at the Media Center of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival. He started participating in the Midi Music Festival ten years ago. In her experience, Midi started &quot;going north&quot; in 2019. She took this opportunity to visit cities such as Binzhou and Chongli that she would not usually visit when traveling. She has traveled to many places, but she has never seen a city as hardworking as Nanyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chang arrived in Nanyang on September 28th earlier than the average music fan. Later, I heard from a friend that &quot;the mayor and the secretary of the municipal party committee personally went to the train station to greet the music fans on the 29th and gave out a large gift package.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first day of the music festival was the Mid-Autumn Festival. After the performance, as a volunteer, she also received mooncakes from the local area. In places where traffic is restricted, the local government provides free shuttle buses for music fans to ride until the early morning. After work every night, she would take a shuttle bus and then take a taxi back to the hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“They actually welcome (music fans). We wear muddy rain boots every day to take a taxi, and the driver doesn’t mind. There is also a special rain boots rinse for music fans at the entrance of the hotel where Midi staff stays. water gun.&quot; During his few days in Nanyang, the locals left a rustic impression on Liu Chang. Anti-riot iron horses separated the music festival site from nearby residential areas. Some villagers watched the performance with great interest on the second floor of their homes. On the iron horse, she saw a hole dug into some cloth with the word &quot;Midi&quot; printed on it. &quot;They were very curious.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/20/Xp9noKj9t19PWD8l4SRvf39Salic0kliIkDE8hyX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/20/Xp9noKj9t19PWD8l4SRvf39Salic0kliIkDE8hyX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the day Liu Chang left Nanyang, he saw it at the high-speed rail station Local volunteers held a banner to say goodbye &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Fangfang, the lead singer of the Laughing Band, has never been on the shuttle car, but she was still shocked by the battle at the end of the performance. &quot;It seemed like all the buses in Nanyang were sent.&quot; After the performance on the Mid-Autumn Festival, she returned to the hotel and found that her underwear and pantyhose had been washed by the staff. , and attached a note: &quot;Please forgive me if I am offended.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fangfang, whose ancestral home is Nanyang, performed in her hometown for the first time. &quot;The whole city is working very hard and wants to leave a good impression on everyone who comes here. I especially understand their mentality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Mud Flute&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Central Plains Midi The music festival first became a trending topic because of a widely circulated photo: music fans lifted Dong Yu, a boy in a wheelchair, to watch a performance in the rain. People say this is rock and roll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of the rain, the four-day music festival was nicknamed the &quot;Mud Flute&quot;, but this is not the first time the Midi Music Festival has encountered rainy days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, the Midi Music Festival held in Zhenjiang also had a particularly bad venue due to rain. &quot;But it was not as bad as this time. It was indeed a bit difficult this time.&quot; Music practitioner Chen Xiaobei recalled. &quot;Everyone had a great time in Zhenjiang last time. More than ten years later, we had another mud play experience, and it was in a worse environment. Everyone had a great time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the first original creation in China Music Festival, Midi has gone through 23 years, and Midi Music School was established even earlier. “The establishment of Midi Music School in 1993 provided professional knowledge and a river of convergence for young people who love rock music across the country. Opportunity; on the afternoon of April 30, 2000, the Trojan Band headed towards the first bass wave in the history of Midi Music Festival; since 2007, Midi began to share its experience in organizing music festivals and participated in many new brands of music In 2009, the Midi Music Festival left Beijing for the first time and headed south.&quot; Chen Xiaobei once wrote an article recording the exciting past thirty years of Midi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/uYIxLzVcNS0702O5joA6cWy9xO12wVD9rBOgT7nS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/uYIxLzVcNS0702O5joA6cWy9xO12wVD9rBOgT7nS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sheep pass by the festival&#39;s iconic graffitied jug. To this day, many locals still come to take photos and check in &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the theft incident, Liu Chang felt that many people followed Chen Xiaobei thought the same thing, &quot;It&#39;s fun even if you step in the mud.&quot; On the morning of October 3, she heard from her team member momo that three tents were missing. &quot;I was quite nervous, but at the time I didn&#39;t think it was a theft. I thought Maybe someone took it by mistake.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Missing along with the tent was Momo&#39;s suitcase. She later found it at the edge of a path in the venue. “It was opened, and there were a few hats, Midi posters, and power strips missing. Because I had always carried valuables with me, there were no A lot of property was lost.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When doing the finishing work that day, momo called an aunt riding a tricycle to help, &quot;She has been carrying some suitcases, maybe she wants to keep them for herself, but those boxes It belongs to our group, so I told her that it belongs to me, don’t move it around.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Exactly like the official report, Li Wei’s power bank was lost in the camping area. It rained all day on October 1 and the temperature dropped. Li Wei and his friends spent the night in the car. When he returned to the camp the next day, he found that not only his belongings were missing, but even his tent was gone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/zOY6niv2rnBveWiFEB5EuEeZYvXA0l9JyJ70XXvL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/zOY6niv2rnBveWiFEB5EuEeZYvXA0l9JyJ70XXvL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the music festival, staff rested on explosion-proof iron horses&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;On October 12, we contacted Qiang Chen, the person in charge of the Midi Music Festival. He said on the phone that he had heard that someone’s things had been stolen since the evening of October 2. “Mainly in the camping area. Lord.&quot; They and Nanyang police launched an emergency plan on the morning of the 3rd to conduct a special investigation, and started to compensate on the 5th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wolong Media released a message on the evening of the 5th, saying, &quot;According to the current registration situation of music fans, 79 ID cards, 3 computers, and 17 mobile phones have been returned, and the remaining items are being verified and contacted.&quot; &quot;At present, Le The compensation rate for lost property reaches 90%,&quot; Qiangchen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wei called the police on the day he lost his belongings. Fifteen minutes later, he received a call from the police, asking him what he had lost and how much it was worth, and advising him not to worry. A few days later, he received another call from Midi staff, asking him about the brand and picture of the lost power bank, and introducing the specific compensation mechanism. “Then let those of us who lost things tell each other about the current compensation measures.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From beginning to end, Li Wei received a total of three calls about compensation. &quot;Their attitude was also very sincere.&quot; Later, he received a Midi inflatable sofa as compensation. In a &quot;Music Festival Lost Items&quot; WeChat group composed of three to four hundred people, Li Wei saw that some people had received souvenirs such as Midi&#39;s bracelets, towels, mooncakes, etc. Everyone was very satisfied with this way of handling it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some voices of loss, such as Liu Qifan who lost all his luggage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All he had left was his clothes, his watch, and his mobile phone.&quot; Without the help of his friends, it was hard for Liu Qifan to imagine how he would return home. Since October 3, he has recalled the things he lost too many times, “a black leather bag, a commemorative hoodie from Hamifa, a commemorative T-shirt from Midi in Central Plains, a volunteer T-shirt from Hailar, a postcard handwritten by a friend, Identity cards, bank cards, medicine for rhinitis...&quot; For him, what is more important are those items whose value cannot be measured by money. &quot;Memories cannot be bought.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/49Vn0QDjm7k7DFVjCa5HVjYhG4GgtSxIYFnzyKQk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/49Vn0QDjm7k7DFVjCa5HVjYhG4GgtSxIYFnzyKQk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The stage being demolished&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Qifan also called the police. When he received a call from Midi’s official statistics on the value of lost items, he said that he had lost something worth 5,000 yuan. “As long as I can compensate 3,500 yuan, that’s enough.” The other party replied, “The amount needs to be submitted for approval before it will be released.” Later. 3,500 yuan was compressed to 3,000 yuan, and then to 2,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few days, Liu Qifan has called the Nanyang mayor’s hotline and received several calls from the local government and Midi, but has never received compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of his friends lost his camera, cosmetic bag and other items at the scene. The camera was later recovered, but the memory card was missing. Because of this incident, my friend still stays in Nanyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up this music festival, Qiang Chen believed, “On the one hand, after four days of intense work, the staff relaxed their security work at the end. On the other hand, this incident also gave us Warning, we should increase the publicity on legal awareness to music fans and residents near the music festival.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 3, Midi issued an announcement about the theft incident. Later, &quot;due to a large number of comments in the comment area, &quot;The remarks about Henan and Nanyang&quot; were deleted again. &quot;We don&#39;t want this matter to escalate into a regional confrontation. This is not what we want to do.&quot; Qiangchen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Qifan does not want the region to be dark. To be fair, this city has its tender side, but the day his things were stolen, he felt, &quot;I will never come to Henan again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Ashed Music Festival&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;After lunch, Huangshan Village was quiet. A woman grows garlic in the open space behind her house. She also grows green peppers and radishes in her vegetable patch, &quot;all of which are eaten by her family.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People in Huangshan Village like to be self-sufficient. The shelves of the small shop at the entrance of the village are stocked with water, drinks, melon seeds, tobacco and alcohol. &quot;People in the village are generally used to buying oil, salt, sauce and vinegar here.&quot; The shop is not big, and it mainly makes money by selling tobacco and alcohol. &quot;I can earn three to four thousand in a month. The key is that there are too many (supermarket operators), there are five or six.&quot; The middle-aged male shop owner complained to me while checking out. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the fate of many villages in Henan, most of the young adults in Huangshan Village have gone out to work, most recently in Nanyang City, and far away in various places, &quot;where they go.&quot; When people reach middle age, it becomes difficult to find a job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uncle Han is 67 years old. He and his wife work in greening management in a residential area in the city. They sprinkle water, spray pesticides, and weed weeds every day, earning 2,500 yuan a month. &quot;Just take care of life.&quot; His expenses are not big, except for buying cigarettes - &quot;I have to buy one every half month.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, he has been supervising work at construction sites, and earlier, he was under supervision one party. &quot;You can make money by doing this, but it&#39;s too tiring and dangerous.&quot; As he got older, his daughter stopped letting him do it. When he was talking about this, he was planting spinach in the vegetable field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Uncle Han’s vegetable patch is not far from Aunt Yu’s house. To the right is the quiet village. To the left, the dusty &quot;Greenfield Monologue.&quot; In addition to the entrance to the village, another entrance to the site leads to Kongming Avenue. These days, cars have been coming in and out of that entrance, either driving into the venue and making a U-turn, or three or two people coming down to laugh and check in, or simply coming to see something rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/FoWsD6mfCkot7IW7eyQZqZKOby48fdfvy0S5WDA6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/FoWsD6mfCkot7IW7eyQZqZKOby48fdfvy0S5WDA6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;More than ten days after the Central Plains Midi Music Festival, you can still see the equipment that has not yet been sorted out&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten days after the Central Plains Midi Music Festival ended, many people were still patrolling the &quot;Green Field Monologue&quot; and taking photos. Occasionally, villagers passed by and walked away silently when they saw a stranger&#39;s face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals do not welcome the media. A man supervising the work at the scene complained to the people watching the fun, &quot;You don&#39;t know how much garbage will be here after the music festival is over. If I don&#39;t arrange for sanitation workers to clean here now, look, someone will come over and take pictures.&quot; The scene is so dirty, no one in the area cares about it anymore. Every day, people want to come here to dig up dirt on us, but no one sees the efforts we put in.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the voice of many locals. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A villager tried to explain to me the reason for the theft - &quot;This is the first time we have held a music festival, and everyone is not very clear about what it does; if the security work is extended for another half day That’s great, there are too many people and I can’t take care of them. And some music fans did say that they left and didn’t want their things.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xiaobei feels that this cannot be solved by relying on security. &quot;Of course, the current security is not good enough, but even if a two-meter or five-meter-high wall is built, how many security guards are needed to keep an eye on everyone? Some of the harsh criticism online is too difficult and unrealistic for them.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;“No matter what music festival it is, losing things is a high probability.” Qiangchen once encountered a theft gang at a music festival he participated in in the past. “The number of mobile phones lost at that time was very large, and the total value was It may be similar to the loss of Midi this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chang remembers that when he participated in the Suzhou Midi Music Festival in 2022, there were people who went to &quot;pick up trash&quot; at the end. One of her team members at the time dissuaded her and later became the team leader. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this music festival, a couple Liu Chang knew came all the way to take additional wedding photos. The two met on Midi a few years ago. She had a great time for four or five days, but when she returned to Beijing, her colleagues were asking her if she had lost anything. &quot;Everyone&#39;s last impression of the music festival is that of stealing. No one will think you played really well. There is a gray feeling.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 19, after many communications with volunteers, Liu Qifan I received 2,000 yuan in compensation, as well as souvenirs containing moon cakes, eye protection patches, towels, and a midi bracelet. “As someone who has experienced it, it’s hard to say whether I am satisfied or not.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the opening ceremony of the Central Plains Midi Music Festival, the Director of Nanyang Culture, Radio, Television and Tourism Bureau once said, “Let the Midi Music Festival Taking root in Nanyang for ten years.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Nanyang Radio and Television, from September 29 to October 5, Nanyang received a total of 7.0987 million tourists and achieved tourism revenue of 2.899 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 1.944%. %, 33.29%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the scene, I asked an uncle who was cleaning up garbage: Do you still want to hold another music festival? He replied firmly, &quot;I still hope to do it, it will be beneficial.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiangchen confirmed to us that Midi and Nanyang will cooperate for a long time. “Next year (2024), we will still hold Midi Music in Nanyang.” Zhang Fan said in an interview with Nanyang Daily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Except Liu Chang, Chen Xiaobei, Qiang Chen, and Fangfang, the others are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叶刘淑仪： 多利用“软力量”向年轻人推广中国文化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-21 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我国拟修订文物保护法完善文物保护制度措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258951]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/20/44b67d29aa7a29fc929c1efdfe094098.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;903&quot; height=&quot;1514&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/20/44b67d29aa7a29fc929c1efdfe094098.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254696&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cultural relics and cultural heritage are non-renewable and irreplaceable outstanding Chinese civilization resources. The current Cultural Relics Protection Law was promulgated in November 1982. It has been revised five times and was comprehensively revised in 2002. Cultural relics work in the new era is facing new situations and new tasks. Some new situations and new problems have emerged in the field of cultural relics protection. In order to adapt to the needs of the development of cultural relics undertakings, revisions are urgently needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, the revised draft of the Cultural Relics Protection Law was submitted to the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People’s Congress for its first review. The revised draft implements the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and reflects the new requirements for cultural relics work in the new era; insists on putting protection first and further improves the cultural relics protection and management system; properly handles the relationship between protection and utilization and promotes the rational use of cultural relics; takes multiple measures simultaneously to increase Increase penalties and severely crack down on illegal acts that destroy cultural relics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长安最饶丨本草物色]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258773]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/sTw5HeYzjhS9pdXvXJOMaY4B285th4QWtAU8QY0Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/sTw5HeYzjhS9pdXvXJOMaY4B28 5th4QWtAU8QY0Q. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254312&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tribulus. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Historical Records&quot;, among the aristocratic families that record the rise and fall of various vassal states, Wei State is known for its civil strife. The bottom line of the king&#39;s lack of morality is also eye-catching. This important vassal state in the early Zhou Dynasty that collected the remnants of the Yin Dynasty and lived in the ancient Shang Ruins in Heqijian, despite the warnings of Zhou Gong&#39;s three imperial edicts and the beginning of Kang Shu&#39;s good governance, for most of the subsequent time, fathers and sons killed each other and brothers died. The paragraph goes on and on, and Confucius&#39;s sentence &quot;You must also correct your name&quot; comes from it. Among them, the one most criticized by historians is the so-called Xuanjiang Rebellion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuan Jiang is a famous beauty. She is the daughter of Duke Xi of Qi and the wife of Duke Xuang of Wei. The overlord Duke Huan of Qi is her brother, and the famous Lady Xu Mu is her daughter. She is regarded as a specimen of beauty&#39;s misfortunes. It is said that the five generations have been restless, and chaos started from Jiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duke Xuan of Wei had an affair with his concubine Yi Jiang and gave birth to his son Ji. Make him a prince and marry Qi&#39;s daughter for him. Before they got married, Duke Xuan heard that Qi&#39;s daughter was stunningly beautiful. He fell in love with her in a second and was so flirtatious that he immediately cut off her husband and took over the house without any worries, so that he could marry someone else for the prince. Qi Nu gave birth to sons Shou and Shuo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yijiang committed suicide because he fell out of favor. The daughter of Qi, also known as Xuan Jiang, who became the first wife, and her son Shuo slandered Duke Xuan and framed the prince. Duke Xuan was dissatisfied, so he ordered the prince to go to Qi as an envoy and sent people to intercept and kill the prince on the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shou told the prince the truth and persuaded him to escape, but the prince refused because he could not violate his father&#39;s orders. So Shou took the crown prince&#39;s banner and went to be killed on his brother&#39;s behalf. The prince arrived shortly after and announced that he should kill me, but he was also killed. So Gongshuo was declared the crown prince. After the death of Duke Xuan, Shuo ascended the throne as Duke Hui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because Hui Gong&#39;s family slandered the prince and replaced him, the Wei people were resentful, so they rebelled and made his younger brother Qian Mou the king. Hui Gong fled. Later, Duke Xiang of Qi led the princes to attack the guards on the king&#39;s order, Qian Mou fled, and Duke Hui was restored to power. Duke Xiang of Qi asked Xuan Jiang to remarry Ji&#39;s other brother Wan, and they gave birth to three sons and two daughters. However, the root of the slander has not been eliminated, and civil strife in Weiguo still occurs one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Placing blame for civil strife on women is a common tactic in traditional narratives. In fact, Jiang, who was in the vortex of scratching and superimposing, was also killed, which is enough to create another meaning of anxiety about appearance. Admittedly, the victim himself was not perfect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Book of Songs, which is called Si Wuxie, has many reflections on this incident, such as &quot;Xintai&quot;, &quot;Two Sons in a Boat&quot; and &quot;Wang Youci&quot;. &quot;The wall has thorns&quot; says:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wall has thorns and cannot be blocked. What you say in the middle is unreasonable. What can be said is ugly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wall has thorns and cannot support it. What Zhong Wei said cannot be specified. What can be described in detail is long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wall has thorns and cannot be restrained. The words in the middle are unreadable. It can be read, but it is insulting to say it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucian scholar Zhu Xi said: Ci is also called tribulus. Sprawling, thin leaves, triangular seeds, stinging. Pharmacist Tao Hongjing described that it grows on roads and walls, with leaves spread all over the ground and seeds with thorns, shaped like rhombus but small. Chang&#39;an is the most affluent place, and many people walk with wooden shoes. Nowadays, the military is made of cast iron to cover the enemy&#39;s roads, and it is called iron caltrop. &quot;Book of Changes&quot; says &quot;according to tribulus&quot;, which means it can cause severe damage. &quot;Poetry&quot; says that &quot;the wall has thorns and cannot be blocked&quot;, which is used to stave off filth. The prescription is very rare. Li Shizhen explained from the perspective of sound training: Tribulus means disease; Quinoa means benefit; Ci means thorn. It hurts people very quickly and is very beneficial. Materia Medica also has names such as Qu Ren and Zhi Xing, which are all derived from its ability to hurt people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common man in Chang&#39;an said that he had no choice but to wear wooden shoes for protection due to the proliferation of herbs. The caltrops made of cast iron bear witness to the early development of bionic weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shizhen’s analysis of Tribulus terrestris varieties: Tribulus terrestris leaves are like young honey locust leaves, neat and cute. Tribulus terrestris is shaped like red-rooted rapeseed and fine water chestnuts, with a triangle and four spines, and is actually a benevolent plant. The white Tribulus terrestris has pods that are about an inch long, with inner seeds as big as sesame seeds, shaped like sheep kidneys and tinged with green. People today call it Tribulus terrestris. Distinguish this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is mainly treated under the column, where the herbal medicine breaks the crux and accumulates, sore throat and breast difficulty. Taking it for a long time will build muscles, improve eyesight and lighten the body. It can be used to treat various wind ulcers, vomiting and pus, and remove dryness and heat. It induces abortion, and the woman&#39;s milk is released. Treats wind secretion and roundworm abdominal pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the prescription is rarely used, there are quite a few conveniences in the &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to take: One stone of Tribulus terrestris seeds, collected when ripe in July and August, dried every day , pound it to remove the thorns, and pestle it to remove the thorns. Take two qian for each dose, mix it with fresh water, and take it three times a day. Do not let it die, and it will cut off the grain and lead to longevity. After taking it for one year, it will not be cold in winter or hot in summer. In two years, the old man has become younger again, his hair has turned white and black again, and his teeth have fallen out again. If you take it for three years, you will be light and live forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Induced labor: difficult labor, the fetus is in the abdomen, cannot be coated and the fetus dies. Take four liang each of Tribulus terrestris and Fritillaria as powder, and take three qian in rice soup. Do not take it for a while, then take it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ascaris heartache: vomiting water. On July 7th, pluck Tribulus terrestris seeds, dry them in the shade, and burn them into ashes. Eat them first and take Fang Cun Dagger three times a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirty years of blindness: Liver-tonifying powder: Harvest Tribulus terrestris on July 7th, dry in the shade and pound into powder. Take Fang Cun Dagger with water after meals, for two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tooth shakes: pain and shock. Grind 5 qian of raw Tribulus terrestris into half a bowl of dilute water, dip it in water and add salt to warm it and rinse it, it is very effective. Or use the roots to burn the ashes, and the teeth will be firmly attached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nasal congestion and watery discharge: I have not smelled any fragrance for many years. Take two handfuls of tribulus and boil half a cup of it with a large cup of water when a cart runs over it. Lie on your back, put rice in your mouth first, and pour the juice into your nose. If it is blocked and re-administered, one or two polyps appear like red chrysalis, which will heal immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scars on the face: combine Tribulus terrestris and Shantouzi into powder, mix with vinegar, and apply it at night to wash. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vitiligo: 6 liang of Tribulus terrestris seeds, raw and pounded into powder, take 2 qian for each soup, twice a day. After one month, the roots will disappear, and after taking it for half a month, red spots will appear on the white areas, which is a miracle effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are not only the secrets of the gods that the winter will not be cold but the summer will not be hot, the old man will be reborn and his teeth will fall, the valley will be broken and the valley will be immortal, as well as the desperate and chronic disease of thirty years of blindness, as well as the emergency that prompts the birth of lower clothes, and more Shaking teeth, stuffy nose, and vitiligo are common and difficult diseases that are common in daily life. However, the prognosis of more effective or even miraculous effects, as well as the description of the situation described in the prescription, cannot be ruled out. Yun Er can present a mirrored ironing post. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爱上长者饭堂的年轻人，图什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258867]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Visit:&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Clean and hygienic prices are not expensive&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Elderly The canteen is popular among some young people&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The braised pork with pickled cabbage, stir-fried pork with cauliflower, green vegetables, corn and carrot soup... The reporter showed weekly items in the canteen of the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street in Tianhe District. It can be seen from the menu that the canteen serves lunch and dinner from Monday to Sunday. Each meal is a fixed set meal of three dishes, one soup and one rice. It has a complete range of meat and vegetables and rich combinations. It also provides &quot;special meals&quot; for the elderly with special needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Tianhe District meal subsidy standards, seniors of different ages and household registration status can receive subsidies ranging from 3 yuan to 6 yuan on the basis of the original price of 13 yuan. The package price for the public is It&#39;s 14 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with ordinary restaurants, the elderly canteen mainly caters to the tastes of the elderly. It uses boiling, stewing, steaming and other methods to make the ingredients soft and easy to digest, and focuses on less salt, less oil and lower fat. The reporter bought a meal at the scene and found that the overall taste was light and not greasy, and the vegetables were cut into small pieces for easy chewing and digestion. The staff in the canteen told reporters, &quot;Our ingredients are shipped back from the market every day. They are fresh and hygienic, and the quality is guaranteed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/19/f6e41a4d9497fa32c08613c6f6a9335a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/f6e41a4d9497fa32c08613c6f6a9335a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254625&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/19/47af6d44c18fb4bc438a66ae5d8eabd4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/19/47af6d44c18fb4bc438a66ae5d8eabd4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254623&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the canteen for the elderly at the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street, Tianhe District, reporters were at the scene I bought a portion of rice and found that the overall taste was light and not greasy, and the vegetables were cut into small pieces for easy chewing and digestion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At lunchtime, in the elderly canteen on Jinhua Street, Liwan District, people came to line up to eat, including many young people. The reporter noticed that there was a long queue at a restaurant 100 meters away from the elderly dining hall, and the waiting time was long, but here you can have a delicious meal in less than five minutes. &quot;It&#39;s easier than bringing food by yourself, and it&#39;s cheaper and more hygienic than ordering takeout. My aunt&#39;s hands don&#39;t shake when she cooks.&quot; The elderly canteen is the best choice for young office worker Xiao Lu (pseudonym) to have lunch at noon. She said that the elderly canteen The canteen is a good solution to the dietary needs of office workers in their fast-paced life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/09760323e8b0efda552ee4afa82e5388.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3006&quot; height=&quot;2255&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/09760323e8b0efda552ee4afa82e5388.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254621&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/51c0bd6bd6b64eb57eeb24d9b5553c0c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/51c0bd6bd6b64eb57eeb24d9b5553c0c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254622&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The menu posted at the senior citizens’ canteen on Jinhua Street, Liwan District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outside the door of the elderly canteen in Shigang Community, Haizhu District, a poster reads: &quot;Based on the latest situation of elderly care services, the Nanshitou Street Elderly Canteen is actively developing special services for this street and launching &#39; &quot;For the People&#39;s Canteen&#39; Model&quot;. Here, the canteen not only serves the elderly, but also serves as a social catering supplement to community residents of all ages in Nanshitou Street. Young people can also come to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the dining hall, there is a vertical row in the corridor, which shows that the opening hours of dining area A are 11:00-12:30 and 17:00-18:00. The &quot;Canteen Weekly Menu&quot; is also pasted on the wall, showing the recipes from Monday to Friday in detail. The reporter visited on Tuesday and found that the lunch included steamed chicken with mushrooms and cloud fungus, stir-fried pork with celery and bean curd skin, seasonal vegetables and hand-baked smooth meat. The dishes had a reasonable mix of meat and vegetables, and the overall taste was relatively light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A young lady who was taking her children to dine told reporters that she saw the relevant publicity of the &quot;Weimin Canteen&quot; on the Internet platform, and some elderly people nearby also recommended this canteen. She decided to bring her children over for dinner. &quot;The main thing is that the price is relatively cheap and the environment is clean and hygienic. Because it is positioned as a canteen for the elderly, the ingredients are relatively healthy and fresh, so you can feel free to bring your children here to eat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, not all senior citizen canteens are currently open to residents of all ages. When the reporter called the elderly canteen of Huaxin Community on Linhe Street, the person in charge said that young people cannot dine here. Only seniors over 60 years old can dine here with a senior citizen card. The service targets are limited to the elderly with Linhe Street household registration. Applicants need to book related services one day in advance. The central kitchen will prepare the food the next day and deliver it to their doorsteps in the form of fast food. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Trend:&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Some elderly canteens are becoming &quot;community canteens&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Young people and old people do not interfere with each other&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; More and more young people like to go to the elderly canteen. Some netizens are worried that the elderly canteen is designed and built for the elderly, and whether the influx of young people will crowd out the dining space and welfare of the elderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can young people eat in the elderly canteen? Does the emergence of young people affect the operation of the elderly canteen? Staff at the Yikang Center on Tianhe South Street said that at present, some elderly canteens are gradually evolving into &quot;community canteens&quot; open to residents of all ages. Secondly, the daily meal supply in the elderly canteen is sufficient, and young people cannot enjoy the elderly subsidy. &quot;Except for the elderly who meet the standards and can enjoy the subsidy, the rest buy it at the original price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;Old people usually come to eat after 11 o&#39;clock, while young people don&#39;t come back from work until after 12 o&#39;clock, and the elderly have already finished eating.&quot; The staff said that the meal times of young working people and the elderly are different, which naturally creates a staggered peak and does not conflict with each other. . Therefore, there is no problem of squeezing resources when young people come to dine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked whether the low pricing would put pressure on canteen operations, the staff said that the purpose of opening the elderly canteen is not to make a profit. At the same time, the Yee Hong Center is a comprehensive Elderly care service centers can also maintain normal operations of the institution through other services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the Shigang Community Elderly Canteen also said that young people and the elderly have different meal times. The elderly come earlier, while young people usually come to the canteen around 12 o&#39;clock after get off work. It said that during peak dining periods, the elderly canteen will have separate dining areas for young and elderly people. In order to make it easier for the elderly to get their meals, dining area A for the elderly is closer to the dining outlet, while dining area B for young people is located slightly further away. At the same time, for groups such as the elderly with registered residence in Guangzhou who are eligible for government subsidies, the government will subsidize varying amounts of meals based on the type of service recipients, such as for the elderly with registered residence in Guangzhou who are 60 years old and above, meal delivery elderly, 18-59 Disabled persons with first- or second-level household registration in Guangzhou will receive a subsidy of 3 yuan per meal, while those living in extreme poverty and living in scattered areas will receive a subsidy of 6 yuan per meal. Young people and the elderly who are not registered in Guangzhou do not have a subsidy amount and need to pay for their meals in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that when it comes to matching dishes, the canteen first considers the tastes of local elderly people in Guangzhou, paying attention to the nutrition of the dishes and the softness of the rice. At the same time, the dining area of ​​the canteen has 6-10 dishes to choose from, and they will also put one or two dishes suitable for young people&#39;s tastes, such as some spicy dishes. In addition, some small boxes of chili, soy sauce and other condiments will be placed on the dining table, so consumers with heavy tastes can freely use them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/99a4f7494057b24c81f00ed5e845637c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;3468&quot; height=&quot;4624&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/99a4f7494057b24c81f00ed5e845637c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254624&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The elderly canteen in Shigang Community, Haizhu District, launched the &quot;canteen for the people&quot; model, which not only serves the elderly, but also serves as a social The catering supplement covers community residents of all ages in Nanshitou Street, and young people can also come to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Guangzhou also has some dining spots for the elderly co-constructed with universities. For example, the cafeterias of South China University of Technology, Jinan University, South China Normal University, South China Agricultural University and other universities have set up dining halls for the elderly. . In order to ensure the quality of catering services for the elderly, the opening hours of the elderly canteen are staggered with students&#39; dining times, and a dedicated window is set up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7e28111a0d2e4bd1ca6fdb424fe2e078.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/7e28111a0d2e4bd1ca6fdb424fe2e078.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254626&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to ensure the quality of catering services for the elderly at Jinan University, the opening hours of the elderly canteen are staggered with students’ dining times, and a dedicated window. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Voice:&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Some people in charge hope to solve the problem of swiping social security cards on the spot as soon as possible&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At a fast food on Shipai East Road in Tianhe ( A restaurant that combines a simple meal with an elderly canteen. There is a price sign at the door. The person in charge told reporters: &quot;Ordinary customers calculate meal expenses based on this price standard, and additional discounts will be given to the elderly. , and the elderly can swipe their social security cards to pay for meals. The elderly and ordinary customers pay in two areas, which can reduce the time of queuing and save time for dining.&quot; The person in charge said that the dishes in the store have taken the public into consideration. It is formulated after the taste, so the tastes of both young and old can be basically satisfied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch time, the customers in the store were old and young, including many nearby students and working citizens. A college student interviewed said: &quot;It&#39;s close to the school, and you don&#39;t have to wait in line for too long. You can get food faster, which is very convenient.&quot; Some students who came to eat also said: &quot;The food here is very delicious. Yes, the price is okay.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/24eb98bc55783a93900c51772bb2eade.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/24eb98bc55783a93900c51772bb2eade.jpeg&quot; data-key =&quot;254627&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A two-in-one fast food (simple meal) and elderly canteen restaurant on Shipai East Road, Tianhe , the customers in the store are old and young, including many nearby students and citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An elderly canteen on Huajing North Road in Tianhe District also operates a two-in-one business model of fast food (simple meals) and an elderly canteen. The difference is that the elderly in this store Different from the dishes for ordinary customers, the store has a weekly menu specifically for the elderly, which changes every Monday. Meals for senior citizens cost 12 yuan, while meals for ordinary customers cost 18-20 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge said that if the elderly are not satisfied with the dishes of the day, or do not want to eat a certain dish, within their ability, they can discuss with the elders to change the desired dishes. For example, if the elderly don&#39;t want to eat, the store will also provide noodles, dumplings and other dishes for the elderly to choose from; or if the elderly say they don&#39;t want to eat fish, they will replace it with chicken. In this way, the elderly Can have more food choices. The person in charge said that because their home is more humane, it has attracted many elderly people to come here. Even the elderly from the nearby elderly center also come here to eat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge told reporters that he is 77 years old and has been running a canteen for the elderly for many years, but what has always made him regretful is that the restaurant’s catering system stipulates that the dining time for the elderly is from 11 a.m. to 11 a.m. At 1 o&#39;clock at noon, &quot;many elderly people who came back from the hospital for follow-up visits missed 1 o&#39;clock and had no meal supplements.&quot; The person in charge also told reporters that because only social security cards can be swiped in the store, elderly people with inconveniences cannot come. If you swipe your card in the store, you may not be able to use the discount. The person in charge hopes to solve the problem of only swiping cards (social security cards) on the spot as soon as possible, so that they can provide door-to-door card swiping services and deliver meals to more elderly people with limited mobility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二轮中央巡视启动，“回头看”两家单位丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259035]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/16CZ3PuVIXghK8WhmZW3FjXSzj7JLlMsIzWDZpjs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/16CZ3PuVIXghK8WhmZW3FjXSzj7 JLlMsIzWDZpjs. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254765&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China will carry out inspections of the Party Committee of China Railway Group &quot;Looking Back&quot; look&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China has begun. As of October 19, 2023, there are 14 inspection teams entered 24 inspected units and announced work information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission, the second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee will carry out regular inspections of party committees (party groups) of 31 units; inspections will be carried out on the party groups of the National Railway Administration and the party groups of China Railway Group. look back&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 31 companies regularly inspected include 5 government departments, namely the Ministry of Science and Technology, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, the State Administration of Science, Technology and Industry for National Defense, and the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration. Another 26 central enterprises were included in the inspection list, focusing on FAW, Dongfeng, Baowu Steel, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the division of labor, during this round of inspections, the Fifth Central Inspection Team was responsible for &quot;looking back&quot; at the two units. The team leader was Geng Changyou, who is currently the director of the Cadre Bureau of the Central Propaganda Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public reports, the Fifth Inspection Team of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China held a mobilization meeting recently to conduct a &quot;look back&quot; inspection of the National Railway Administration Party Group. Geng Changyou gave a mobilization speech. He said that the inspection team will keep a close eye on the powers and responsibilities, keep a close eye on the &quot;top leaders&quot; and the leadership team, keep a close eye on the outstanding issues that the masses have strongly reported, keep a close eye on the rectification and application of the results of the inspection, and strive to find and correct The Central Inspection Team will work in the National Railway Administration for about 2 months to detect political deviations and outstanding problems in the performance of duties by the inspected party organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the 24 inspection team leaders who have been stationed in the inspected units are cadres from the discipline inspection and supervision system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leader of the Central First Inspection Team stationed in China Minmetals Corporation, China Aluminum Corporation of China, and China Mineral Resources Corporation is Cui Peng, who is currently the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Committee in the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Wang Lishan, leader of the Central Third Inspection Team stationed in the Ministry of Science and Technology, was a member of the Standing Committee of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection. He is currently the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission at the National People&#39;s Congress. Li Yingchun, leader of the 7th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the 11th Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Chen Zhangyong, leader of the 10th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the 8th Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. Gao Fei, leader of the 14th Central Inspection Team, is the director of the First Supervision Office of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. La Yifan, leader of the 15th Central Inspection Team, is the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission in the Ministry of Culture and Tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 14 central inspection team leaders who have been stationed in the inspected units, Kong Shenggen, Wang Rongjun, Zhang Fugen, Gao Fei, Zhu Shumin, La Yifan, Li Yingchun, Chen Zhangyong, and Yu Changhui are all in the 20th Served as team leader in the first round of inspection activities of the Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China was launched. This inspection is the first time since the 18th CPC National Congress that three organizational methods, namely regular inspections, mobile inspections and &quot;look back&quot; inspections, are simultaneously arranged in one inspection round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first round of inspections carried out regular inspections of the party committees of 30 medium-sized enterprises, carried out &quot;look back&quot; inspections of the party committees of 5 medium-sized financial enterprises, and carried out mobile inspections of the party groups of the State Sports General Administration. This was also the first time in nearly 6 months. In 2016, the central government once again conducted mobile inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission announced that after half a year of work, the first round of inspection feedback work was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, many central management officials of the inspected units were dismissed, including Li Xiaopeng, former chairman of China Everbright Group Co., Ltd., Zhou Qingyu, vice president of China Development Bank, China Everbright Tang Shuangning, former chairman of the group, Wang Yongsheng, former vice president of China Development Bank, Du Zhaocai, former deputy director of the State Sports General Administration, Xu Wenrong, former deputy general manager of PetroChina, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;A report published in the &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision Magazine&quot; published on October 15, 2023 stated that the second round of inspections was the second round of inspections of centrally managed enterprises after the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. In the centralized political examination, &quot;the two rounds of inspections basically covered all centrally managed enterprises, reflecting the distinctive characteristics of political inspections highlighting key points, and sending a strong signal to strictly manage state-owned central enterprises.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/R2hzaOqQspythqvDnqccZ817OPPpxAVl3BUDuyyc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;613&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/R2hzaOqQspythqvDnqccZ817OPPpxAVl3BUDuyyc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The president of Qiushi Magazine has recently adjusted &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Chen Yangyong is appointed as the president of Qiushi Magazine]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Chen Yangyong Born in December 1963, he holds a Ph.D. in history from Fudan University and is a researcher. He has served as deputy director of the Central Literature Research Office and deputy director of the Central Party History and Literature Research Institute. In 2018, he was appointed editor-in-chief of Qiushi Magazine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yangyong has long been engaged in researching the thoughts and lives of major leaders of the party and the country and editing works. He has participated in &quot;Selected Works of Jiang Zemin&quot;, Jiang Zemin&#39;s &quot;On the Development of China&#39;s Information Technology Industry&quot;, &quot;Mao Zedong, Deng Xiaoping and Jiang Zemin on Scientific Development&quot;, He is the editor of &quot;Li Peng on Rejuvenating the Nation through Science and Education&quot; and other works, and participated in the compilation of &quot;Jiang Zemin&#39;s Thoughts Chronicles (1989-2008)&quot; and &quot;Zhou Enlai&#39;s Chronicle (1949-1976)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Han Wenxiu is appointed director of the Central Agricultural Office]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Zhejiang Daily&quot; 》News, the national on-site promotion meeting for learning and applying the &quot;Ten Million Project&quot; experience was held on October 13 in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. Han Wenxiu, deputy director of the Central Finance Office in charge of daily work and director of the Central Agricultural Office, presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above reports show that Han Wenxiu has been appointed director of the Central Agricultural Office. Han Wenxiu, born in September 1963, is a native of Zanhuang County, Hebei Province. In his early years, he worked as an editor in the editorial department of the Journal of Peking University. In 1989, he joined the Economic Research Center of the former State Planning Commission (now the Macroeconomic Research Institute of the National Development and Reform Commission). In 2005, Han Wenxiu was transferred to the macro group leader (bureau level) of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group Office. From 2010 to 2011, he served as deputy secretary-general of the Guangdong Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China. In 2011, Han Wenxiu was transferred to deputy director of the Research Office of the State Council. In April 2018, he was transferred to deputy director of the Central Finance Office, and later served as deputy director (at the ministerial level) of the Central Finance Office in charge of daily work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The fourth deputy secretary-general of the State Council took office during the year]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People According to news from the Ministry of Social Affairs website on October 17, the State Council appointed Sun Guangyu as deputy secretary-general of the State Council; Chen Min was appointed deputy minister of the Ministry of Water Resources; Xiao Yanshun was appointed deputy director of the Research Office of the State Council; Wang Jingtao was appointed deputy director of the National Internet Information Office; Fan Yun was appointed Deputy Editor-in-Chief of China Central Radio and Television. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu, male, Han nationality, born in December 1966, university degree, Master of Engineering, member of the Communist Party of China. He once served as director of the Department of Safety Supervision and Management of Hazardous Chemicals of the Ministry of Emergency Management and other positions. In June 2022, he was appointed as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2023, the State Council has appointed three deputy secretaries-general. On July 4, Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong took office. Wang Zhijun served as deputy secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee, and Wang Yonghong served as party secretary and director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. On August 30, Xu Shouben took office. He previously served as vice president and party committee member of the China Development Bank. &lt;p>; >;According to Fujian Daily, the Organization Department of the Fujian Provincial Party Committee issued a pre-appointment announcement on October 17, in which Dang Shuai, secretary of the Pingnan County Party Committee in Ningde, is proposed to serve as deputy party and government deputy in the districted city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dang Shuai, male, from Weifang, Shandong, was born in February 1984. He is a doctor of power engineering and engineering thermophysics who was selected and introduced from Tsinghua University in Ningde, Fujian Province in 2012. In July 2012, he was appointed as the deputy county magistrate of science and technology of Zhelong County, Ningde. In October 2014, he was appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Pingnan County Party Committee and the Minister of the Propaganda Department. In 2015, In November, he was appointed as Secretary of the Ningde Municipal Committee and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Communist Youth League. In June 2016, he was appointed as Deputy Secretary of the Gutian County Committee, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the County Government, and Acting County Magistrate. In December of the same year, he was appointed Deputy Secretary of the Gutian County Committee, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the County Government, and County Magistrate. In July 2020, Dang Shuai took office as Secretary of the Pingnan County Party Committee and has been working ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Two new vice-governors of Sichuan Province]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 2023 On the morning of March 13, the Standing Committee of the Sichuan Provincial People&#39;s Congress decided to appoint Phubtendup and Zuo Yongxiang as deputy governors of the Sichuan Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pubu Dundup, male, Tibetan, born in November 1972, from Gyantse, Tibet. He has been working in Tibet since 1996. In October 2023, he was transferred from the Standing Committee of the Tibet Autonomous Region Party Committee and Secretary of the Lhasa Municipal Party Committee to the Standing Committee of the Sichuan Provincial Party Committee and Vice Governor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zuo Yongxiang, male, born in August 1968, is a longevity native of Chongqing. After graduating from Fudan University in 1991 with a major in mathematical statistics, he worked in Changshou County (later changed to Changshou District) in Chongqing for a long time. In 2018, he was transferred to the deputy secretary and district chief of Tongliang District, Chongqing. Since then, he has worked in Yuzhong District and Chongqing District. Work with Chongqing High-tech Zone and Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission. Before this job adjustment, Zuo Yongxiang served as Party Secretary and Director of the Chongqing Municipal Development and Reform Commission, and Director (concurrently) of the Chongqing Municipal Grain Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anti-corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Han Yong, former chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference Under investigation]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 19, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission reported that Han Yong, the former Party Secretary and Chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, was suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Central Committee. Disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the National Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Yong, born in October 1956, is from Jiutai, Jilin Province. He worked in Jilin Province in his early years and served successively as deputy director of the Criminal Prosecution Division of the Jilin Provincial Procuratorate, deputy director and director of the Economic Procuratorial Division. , Director of the Prison Office, Deputy Mayor of Yushu City (temporary position), Chief Prosecutor of the Songyuan City Procuratorate, Deputy Prosecutor General of the Provincial Procuratorate and Director of the Anti-Corruption Bureau, Member and Deputy Secretary of the Standing Committee of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection, Director of the Provincial Supervision Department, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Han Yong went to work in Xinjiang and successively served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, Minister of the Organization Department, Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region, and Director of the Organization Department. In 2015, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of the Autonomous Region and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps Party committee secretary, political commissar, chairman of China New Construction Group Corporation, and clearly at the ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2016, Han Yong was transferred to the position of Chairman and Party Secretary of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, and will retire in January 2022. In March 2022, Han Yong was appointed deputy director of the Population Resources and Environment Committee of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/6vxCJtnVwPAQ1n3VfTX6PCgCSC4SHBuHW63rJl3s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/6vxCJtnVwPAQ1n3VfTX6PCgCSC4SHBuHW63rJl3s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Han Yong, former chairman of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. &quot; Cadres born in the 1990s began to embezzle public funds three months after being admitted to public offices]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, the website of the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released a report on the construction of villages and towns in Duma Town, Tianzhu County, Qiandongnan Prefecture The warning about the case of Long Li, a former worker at the service center, revealed that just three months after being admitted to public office, this &quot;post-90s&quot; cadre could no longer withstand temptation and began to embezzle public funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long Li, male, born in May 1991, is from Sansui, Guizhou. He started working in November 2019 and serves as a staff member of the Village and Town Construction Service Center in Duma Town, Tianzhu County. In January 2020, when Long Li was handling the issuance of reclamation and greening funds for the masses, he discovered that after township staff provided explanations, the funds could be transferred directly to the account number provided by the staff. From January 2020 to September 2021, in just one year and nine months, Long Li took advantage of his position to falsely report other people&#39;s bank accounts and fraudulently receive more than 200,000 yuan in state funds for personal daily consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2021, Long Li was placed under investigation. In September 2021, Long Li was fired from public office. In December 2021, Long Li was sentenced to three years in prison for corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Female department official was notified of &quot;beauty corruption&quot;]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing City On October 18, the website of the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision reported serious violations of discipline and law by Chen Guifen (deputy bureau level), former member of the Party Group and Vice Chairman of the Beijing Yanqing District Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Guifen was born in Yanqing in July 1970 and was investigated in March 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The report stated that Chen Guifen was disloyal and dishonest to the party and resisted organizational review; she violated the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepted gifts and arrangements for beauty activities in violation of regulations. &lt;p>; >;On October 18, the &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot; published an article &quot;Original Intentions Are Dusted by Greed and Destroy Your Body&quot;, which analyzed the serious disciplinary and law violation case of Guo Qing, a former party member and deputy mayor of the Luzhou Municipal Government in Sichuan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Qing, male, was born in October 1963 and started working in July 1983. In November 2021, the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision opened a case for review and investigation into Guo Qing&#39;s suspected serious violations of discipline and law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above report, October 23, 2021, is Guo Qing’s 58th birthday. On this day, he was walking alone on the Luzhou Yangtze River Bridge and felt that the situation was serious. He once had the idea of ​​​​jumping into the river to &quot;finish it once and for all.&quot; However, a call from his family urging him to go home for dinner brought him back to reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2022, Guo Qing was expelled from the party and public office. In December 2022, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Ziyang City, Sichuan Province sentenced Guo Qing to nine years in prison for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ministry and Commission Information&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Commerce: Consumers can check Credit information of housekeeping staff】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the CCTV News Client report on October 17, 2023, recently, the &quot;Housekeeping Credit Check&quot; applet established by the Ministry of Commerce was newly launched. Domestic companies will be supported to establish credit records for domestic workers and carry out professional background information verification and verification. At the same time, free credit information inquiry services for domestic companies and domestic workers will be provided to consumers. It is understood that the &quot;Housekeeping Credit Check&quot; applet is an important part of the national housekeeping service credit information platform. Up to now, the platform has collected 19,000 domestic service companies and more than 15 million pieces of credit information about domestic workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Development and Reform Commission: Interview with 4 provinces and cities due to lagging progress due to declining energy intensity]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; According to news from the National Development and Reform Commission website on October 19, the Environmental Protection Department of the National Development and Reform Commission recently interviewed responsible officials of the energy conservation authorities of Zhejiang Province, Anhui Province, Guangdong Province, and Chongqing Municipality regarding the lagging progress in reducing energy intensity during the “14th Five-Year Plan” . In the first two years of the “14th Five-Year Plan”, after deducting the energy consumption of raw materials and renewable energy consumption, the decline in energy intensity in Zhejiang, Anhui, Guangdong, Chongqing and other regions still lags behind the target progress requirements of the “14th Five-Year Plan”. Renewable energy consumption The level needs to be improved, and the energy-saving situation is very serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Health Commission: Fill in the shortcomings and weaknesses of local hospitals in oncology, pediatrics, etc.]&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 19, the National Health Commission held a press conference. Xue Haining, deputy director of the Department of Structural Reform of the National Health Commission, said that my country is vigorously promoting the construction of national medical centers and national and provincial regional medical centers to fill the gap in local medical centers through expert support, technology transfer, homogeneous management and other measures. Through these measures, the shortcomings and weaknesses in key diseases and key specialties such as oncology and pediatrics are gradually being alleviated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[National Medical Insurance Administration: The efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected through centralized procurement are equivalent to those of original drugs]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;CCTV News Client reported that on October 17, the National Medical Insurance Administration held a press conference to introduce the real-world research results on the clinical efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected from the second and third batches of nationally organized drug centralized procurement. In June 2021, entrusted by the National Medical Insurance Administration, Xuanwu Hospital of Capital Medical University led 29 medical institutions in 16 provinces across the country to conduct clinical efficacy and safety studies on 23 representative varieties collected by the second and third batches of national organizations. A real-world study conducted over the past two years, a total of 38 brands of selected generic drugs were evaluated. The research results show that the clinical efficacy and safety of the selected generic drugs are equivalent to those of the original drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Zhengzhou, Henan: Career by 2025 More than 60% of college graduates stay in the local area]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhengzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government website, on October 18, the General Office of the Zhengzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government issued &quot;Deepening the Integration of Industry and Education to Promote Vocational Education High-Quality Development Implementation Plan. The &quot;Plan&quot; proposes that by 2025, 100 industry-education integrated enterprises at the municipal level and above, 10 industry-education integrated training bases at the municipal level and above, 10 industry-education integrated education groups (alliances), and 15 school-enterprise cooperation Demonstrative industrial colleges, 30 industry-education integration practice centers, 50 industry-education integration key majors, 50 government-industry-university-research collaborative education projects, and more than 60% of vocational college graduates stay in the local area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei: the first regional coordinated local standard release in the field of people&#39;s livelihood]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; According to the Beijing Daily client report, in order to promote the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei, Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei recently issued the &quot;Standards for the Psychological Assessment of Minors in Assistance, Protection and Child Welfare Institutions&quot;, which will be implemented on January 1, 2024. The reporter learned that this is the first regional coordinated local standard in the field of basic people&#39;s livelihood security issued by Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. The norms will be implemented through the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei rescue and protection and child welfare agencies. Mental health, social adaptation and other aspects of the minors under the custody of the civil affairs department will be assessed, their psychological problems will be identified, and targeted psychological counseling will be carried out. Enrich and expand the content and methods of rescue and protection, explore and establish a new social protection system for minors with Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei characteristics, and further promote the healthy growth and all-round development of minors. &lt;p>; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hunan Daily, recently, the General Office of the Hunan Provincial Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the Hunan Provincial People&#39;s Government issued the &quot;Notice on Implementing Three Systems and Mechanisms including the &quot;Negative List&quot; Management of Prominent Issues in Official Receptions&quot;. Implement a &quot;negative list&quot; management system for prominent issues in official reception throughout the province. Situations that are included in the &quot;negative list&quot; include: not paying accommodation, meals, transportation and other expenses as required; drinking alcohol during official receptions (including personally carrying alcohol); accepting receptions in violation of regulations during official events in the same city; engaging in various private clubs, &quot;One-table meal&quot; venues, high-consumption catering venues, internal reception venues of private enterprises not operated by external parties, and other places accept official receptions in violation of regulations; it is required to include vacations, family visits, tourism and other activities into the scope of official receptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Broadcast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Law Issues Judicial Protection of National Parks Typical cases: many types of lawsuits involved]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, 2023, the website of the Supreme People&#39;s Court reported that the Supreme People&#39;s Court released 10 typical cases of judicial protection of national parks. The typical cases released this time involve many types of litigation and a wide range of protection, including different types of litigation such as environmental resources criminal, civil and public interest litigation, covering the main scope of environmental resources trials; the national parks involved include Sanjiangyuan, Giant Panda, etc. The five first batch of national parks established, including Siberian Tiger and Leopard, Hainan Tropical Rainforest, and Wuyi Mountain, as well as Qianjiangyuan-Baishanzu National Park, a national park candidate area included in the &quot;National Park Spatial Layout Plan&quot; selection, reflect The People&#39;s Court hears cases involving national park protection with many types of litigation and a wide scope of national park protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The President of the Supreme Court stated that he will not accept cases at the end of the year]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On October 17, the Supreme People&#39;s Court held a consultation on judicial trial data analysis and judgment for the first three quarters of 2023. Zhang Jun, President of the Supreme Court, said that the quality, efficiency, and effectiveness of trials in courts across the country have steadily improved in the first three quarters. The requirements for case closure rates within trial limits must be strictly implemented, and the annual closing ratio and case closure rate indicators must no longer be used, and resolutely put an end to failure to complete cases at the end of the year. end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The food security law is to be clarified: enterprises and institutions should strengthen canteen management and correct waste]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On October 19, the Legal Affairs Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee held a press conference. Spokesperson Yang Heqing introduced that the second review draft of the Food Security Law will be submitted to the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee meeting for review this month. The second review of the draft The draft stipulates that agencies, groups, enterprises and institutions, etc. should strengthen the management of their own canteens and correct wasteful behaviors. In June 2023, the third meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress conducted its first review of the draft Food Security Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Justice: Strictly rectify campaign-style law enforcement, brutal law enforcement, and profit-seeking law enforcement]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Recently, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Three-Year Action Plan for Improving the Quality of Administrative Law Enforcement (2023-2025)&quot;, which puts forward clear requirements for comprehensively improving the quality and effectiveness of administrative law enforcement. The action plan proposes to comprehensively promote strict, standardized, fair and civilized law enforcement, vigorously rectify outstanding problems in administrative law enforcement, establish and improve administrative law enforcement standards and regulations, and improve administrative law enforcement working mechanisms. According to the deployment, all regions and departments must carry out special rectification and supervision actions, vigorously rectify outstanding problems in administrative law enforcement, and clarify the time nodes and work steps for carrying out special rectification and supervision actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sheng Laiyun, Deputy Director of the National Bureau of Statistics : I appeal and urge survey households to actively cooperate]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 18, 2023, at the press conference on the performance of the national economy in the first three quarters held by the State Council Information Office, the National Bureau of Statistics Deputy Director Sheng Laiyun said: &quot;The household survey will start on November 1 (2023). This is the standard time point. It will last approximately two weeks and will end on November 15. Here I appeal and implore us survey households, actively cooperate with the sample survey on population changes, and fill in relevant information truthfully and accurately.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Refer to CCTV News, The Paper , &quot;Fujian Daily&quot;, &quot;Hunan Daily&quot;, &quot;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News&quot; and other reports)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[AI生成书籍泛滥：谁在制造“假书”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258953]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/20/tcvzL0Peu3haQYDXZNgvFe0uYRJlEzgeptumIYvn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/tcvzL0Peu3haQYDXZNgvFe0uYRJlEzg eptumIYvn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254698&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Amazon&#39;s self-publishing system allows anyone to self-publish and sell books on Amazon. This provides a loophole for the proliferation of AI-generated books. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Who is writing my biography?&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Dang Luo Li When Ciaran Jones discovered a biography of himself on Amazon, he had a strange question. He flipped through part of the book and it showed that he lived in an academic family, his father was an affable scholar and his mother was a teacher. The book is almost comparable to his own memoirs, except that the information in it is &quot;total fantasy&quot;, he told the Guardian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Rory&#39;s father is a BBC television director, and his mother also works at the BBC. One day, he discovers the emotional stories of his parents in a shoebox containing letters, and thus uncovers the truth about his family&#39;s history. These stories are recorded in his real memoirs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the biography about him, Rory had never heard of the biographer, but he soon discovered that the book was generated by AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lori’s experience is not an isolated one. According to multiple foreign media reports, AI-generated books are flooding Amazon. These books range from biographies, cookbooks, popular science books to travel guides, etc. Some of the misinformation in some of these books can even be life-threatening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The New York Mycological Society (NYMS) publicly stated that many AI-generated mushroom foraging popular science books on Amazon and other e-commerce platforms contain many erroneous descriptions, which may mislead the public into eating poisonous mushrooms, &quot;meaning of life and death.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“A&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;has crushed Amazon”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In June, writer Caitlin Lynch posted on social platforms, pointing out that among the top 100 best-selling Amazon teen contemporary romance e-books, only 19 are normal books, and the rest are AI-generated &quot;nonsense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also attached a screenshot of a book called &quot;Waiting for You to Love Me&quot;, with a black and white photo of a seagull on the cover. Previously, the book was ranked No. 90 on Amazon&#39;s top 100 bestsellers list in the Teen Contemporary Romance category. The two one-star reviews below also pointed out that it is a book generated by AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;AI has defeated Amazon.&quot; Lynch wrote in a tweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the New York Times in August, travel guides have also become one of the main categories where AI books are flooding. In March, traveler Amy Korsky purchased a travel guide on Amazon for her upcoming trip to France. When she entered a few search keywords &quot;travel&quot;, &quot;guidebook&quot; and &quot;France&quot;, a top-ranked &quot;France Travel Guide&quot; caught her attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the author page, the author of the book, Mike Steves, is a &quot;famous travel writer.&quot; There are more than a hundred five-star reviews on the book&#39;s interface, and the guide also promises itineraries and recommendations from locals. So Amy Kolsky placed the order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To her disappointment, when she received the book, she found that the descriptions inside were vague, the text was repetitive, and the itinerary lacked an itinerary that looked like it had been copied and pasted from Wikipedia. She returned the book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The New York Times discovered that things are not simple. They were unable to find any previously published works by the so-called &quot;author&quot; of the book. Even the photo of the &quot;author&quot; on the interface looked strange, such as abnormal elements near the ears, crooked clothes, etc., which seemed to be photos generated by AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the results of the AI ​​detection tool Originality.ai, Mike Steves&#39; book was almost certainly AI-generated. In addition, the New York Times found that AI-generated books have also begun to penetrate cooking, programming, medicine, gardening and many other categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many media reports, AI-generated books not only bring misleading information to readers, but also cause great trouble to real authors. In August, writer Jane Friedman stated on her blog that some “junk books” had been uploaded to Amazon. Her name was listed in the author column, but she did not write these books. They were extremely misleading. Most likely generated by AI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has been blogging since 2009. Many of the contents are public and can be used for AI model training. So when she reads the first page of these &quot;fake books,&quot; it&#39;s like she&#39;s reading a self-generated ChatGPT reply. To make matters worse for her, these &quot;fake books&quot; were added to her Goodreads profile, which could easily be misleading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After she complained about this on social platforms, some authors responded that they had had similar experiences. &quot;People keep telling me they bought my new book and it has my name on it but I never wrote it,&quot; one author said. Some authors reported 29 books with similar situations in just one week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The scary thing is that this can happen to anyone with a reputation, a status, a need, and someone sees a way to profit from it.&quot; In an interview with CNN , said Jane Friedman. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Effectively allowing &#39;junk books&#39; to exist&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Amazon after Rory discovered that his biography was AI-generated Sent him an email with a recommendation that said, &quot;You might like this book.&quot; This made Rory angry that Amazon&#39;s algorithm thought this was a book he wanted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;They are essentially allowing &#39;junk books&#39; to exist and recommending them to the people who hate them the most,&quot; Rory told the Guardian. Although Amazon later removed the book, many titles passed through a filtering system designed to weed out low-quality books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the appearance of many AI-generated books on the Amazon platform has a lot to do with the abuse of its own self-publishing system KDP (Kindle Direct Publishing). In 2007, Amazon created KDP to allow anyone to self-publish and sell books on Amazon. Currently, it offers more than 45 language options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Amazon KDP platform, authors can freely choose to self-publish e-books or paper books. After completing the upload process of self-published books, Amazon can pass the review and sell them in about 72 hours. Self-publishing a book on this platform is free, however, if publishing a physical book, the printing costs are deducted from the royalties earned from each book sale. Generally speaking, authors can receive royalties of up to 60% for paper books and 35% or 70% for e-books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, with the development of artificial intelligence technology, many tutorials using AI to generate books have appeared on platforms such as YouTube and TikTok. Their topics range from a wide range of topics, and many users can quickly master AI generation from them. book method, coupled with the convenience and benefits of Amazon’s self-publishing function, it is difficult to avoid the abuse of this function for AI book publishing and sales. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, Amazon introduced new rules and guidelines on its KDP community page after receiving complaints from many authors. The new regulations require authors to answer the system’s questions about whether the work is generated by artificial intelligence when publishing their work. In its content guide section, Amazon has also added content about AI, including definitions of “AI-generated” and “AI-assisted.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Guardian&quot; report, due to concerns about artificial intelligence, Amazon introduced new rules that limit self-publishers to publish a maximum of three books per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even though the new regulations have been released, some impacts have already been caused. In the wake of the Jane Friedman scandal, books bearing her name were removed from Amazon and her Goodreads profile. But the process wasn&#39;t smooth, and Amazon initially refused to stop selling the books. Jane Friedman believes it was ultimately her popularity and reputation in the writing and publishing world that prompted Amazon to pull the books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“With the deluge of AI-powered content now posted on Amazon, sometimes with misleading or fraudulent attribution to authors, how can working authors be expected to spend time every week for the rest of their lives policing this? What&#39;s the content?&quot; she asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And even if those books no longer appear on her Amazon or Goodreads pages, their impact remains. Jane Friedman wrote on her blog: &quot;Unfortunately, even if you remove these crazy books from your official profile, they will still be with your name...and you have no idea about it. But there is nothing we can do.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[毕业生求职，“我全都要”容易实现吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258810]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Affected by the economic environment and the number of graduates, the employment situation of college students graduating this year is severe. Although my friend Xiaoyan, a recent graduate student, received several offers (job opportunities), he was not happy at all, but became even more anxious. After some inquiries, he found out that none of these jobs seemed to meet the standards of his ideal job. How to choose a suitable job is a question that every graduate needs to think about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of economics, there is a famous &quot;Mundell&#39;s Impossible Triangle&quot;. This theory is that the country cannot simultaneously satisfy the independence of monetary policy, the stability of exchange rates, and the free flow of capital, and can only choose two of them at most. Similarly, in the job market, I think there is a similar &quot;impossible triangle&quot; law. It involves three conditions: salary level, work platform and relative stability of a job. It is difficult to achieve at the same time, and only two of them can be met at most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let me briefly introduce the basic information of this friend: Xiaoyan comes from a rural family in a provincial capital in the northwest. He graduated from a 211 university with a bachelor&#39;s degree and a doctorate from a well-known 985 university in Beijing, with excellent grades; he published many publications during his studies. He has written SCI papers, participated in many national-level projects, and won many high-level competition awards. The three offers he got each have clear characteristics. His first job was as an official in the national ministries and commissions. He had a household registration, a good job platform, and a relatively high social status. However, his income level was in a first-tier city like Beijing, and there might not be much left after excluding expenses. Faced with the high housing prices, he was more than satisfied. The second job belongs to a monopoly institution in the industry, with a staff and a guaranteed income, but the platform is average, and there are more restrictions on job-hopping in the future; the third job is in a 211 university in my hometown, with a high level of scientific research platform and strong academic strength. The job is rich and the working hours are relatively free. The only drawback is that with the reform of universities and institutions, this job has no establishment and the employment period assessment pressure is high. He is worried that in the future he will face the outcome of promotion or resignation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Xiaoyan’s final choice has not yet been determined, I suggest that when he is looking for a job, his first priority is to learn to lower his expectations for a specific factor, rather than falling into a &quot;I want it all&quot; situation. As far as these three jobs are concerned, if he prefers a stable working environment within the system, he should probably lower his salary expectations. The first job may be the best choice; if he pursues better salary and treatment, he needs Compromise on the requirements of the work platform, so that the second job may be more suitable; if you yearn for a better scientific research platform and are interested in academic development, Xiaoyan can try to be less optimistic about the establishment of this indicator and challenge the third university teaching position. The job is not bad either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the moon waxes and wanes, and work also has its flaws. For most graduating college students, the jobs they find basically conform to the &quot;impossible triangle&quot; law. Therefore, when necessary, we need to identify the needs and learn to make trade-offs, so that we can feel less anxious and face the severe employment environment calmly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a doctoral graduate in 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email ：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[歌枕之巅——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（四）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgSx4Ep.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/gAXZuPLXeiaWEXiOOMVw0is3TGpubj7FJLgS x4Ep. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254353&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho once lived facing the sea when he traveled to Matsushima. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continue to walk further north, passing through Akita and entering Aomori. Along the railway line are apple orchards in the harvest season. In some areas, branches and leaves covered with red fruits are brushing against your hands, separated by the glass windows of the train. That kind of surprise is really quite strong. To really touch an apple, you have to go to the station supermarket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aomori’s apple production accounts for half of Japan’s national production. It is the birthplace of the world-famous Fuji apple, as well as twenty or thirty other varieties of apples. The &quot;world&#39;s best&quot; apples grown in Aomori weigh more than 500 grams each, and some can reach 1,000 or even 1,500 grams. When we were shopping in the supermarket, we saw that those Aomori apples were also huge. They were sold one by one for about 500 yen each, which is equivalent to about 30 yuan in RMB. It&#39;s a little more expensive, but it&#39;s juicy and tastes sweet. The three of us bought a shared meal while changing trains at a small station, and we were all full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in Aomori, of course I had a destination - go to Kaneki to see Dazai Osamu&#39;s former residence &quot;Seiyangkan&quot;, and also went to Towada to visit the famous Towada Museum of Art. As for Basho&#39;s whereabouts, it has to reach a climax after this cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We turned around from north to south, took the bus from Aomori to Sendai, and then transferred to the main route to Matsushima Kaigan Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bajiao chants: &quot;On a summer moonlit night in Songdao, the clear water is my clothes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho and Zeng Liang’s trip to Oshu, he said, was purely a whim, so he didn’t care about Wu Tianbai’s hatred. This whim was mentioned in his preface, because the Moon of Songdao appeared in his heart, tempting him to go on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Tian&#39;s white hair is a reference to Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;I arrived in Dongluo on the 9th last year, and I came to Wuxiang on the 9th this year. The hair on both sides was white for a while, and the chrysanthemums in three places were the same color.&quot; , &quot;Shoes fragrant with Chu ground flowers&quot; all mean that the journey is long and difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/jZeCav7eKr5CrSenYdxKPRvuuJUexS5tydhfHScY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254354&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsushima is located in Miyagi-gun, Miyagi Prefecture, northeastern Japan. It is a scenic spot in Matsuo Basho&#39;s &quot;Song Pillow&quot; and is named after the pine trees planted all over the islands. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Songdao is named after the pine trees planted all over it. The ancient Japanese traditional color name is pine leaf color. As the name suggests, the color of pine leaves is a dark green that is evergreen all year round. Among the traditional Japanese colors, there are several colors related to pine leaves, including sea pine color, which is a green that is close to black; and sea pine brown, which is a dark green mixed with brown and yellow, which is a calm and pretty green. Then there are sea pine blue, yellow sea pine tea, blue sea pine tea, etc., which in my opinion are various derivatives of pine leaf color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot;, Basho would occasionally note that he had reached a certain &quot;singing pillow&quot;. The word &quot;Utabu&quot; means a place of interest that has appeared in Japanese Waka since ancient times. At the top of Japan&#39;s singing pillow, there are three scenic spots: Amanohashidate, Matsushima and Itsukushima (also called Miyajima). These three major attractions have been famous since the early Edo period. For me, Matsushima feels more literary because of Basho&#39;s description in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. Basho&#39;s &quot;aphasia&quot; was particularly interesting. He shouted, &quot;Matsushima! Ah! Ah! Matsushima! Matsushima!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/18/7ApEi9HKrHnqZ1Pl4VExcQcLavIICeH0KLTKSTjH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The dry landscape garden of Zuiam Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matsushima is a group of islands in the bay, Miyagi-gun, Miyagi Prefecture, northeastern Japan. It is composed of 260 small islands, large and small. They are named because they are covered with black pine and red pine. The four colors here are blue waves, white sand, limestone, and green pine. The colors are quite bright and harmonious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, 2019, Wei Dong, Yan Ning and I set off from Hachinohe in Aomori to Matsushima. Take the bus from Hachinohe Station to Sendai, then transfer to the main line to Matsushima Kaigan Station. A very small station platform stands in the middle of the railway. When we arrive at night, the biting cold wind blows from all sides of the platform. After all, it is already autumn. The sun is warm during the day, but disappears at night. We quickly got on the shuttle bus between the hotel and the station, turned a hill, and arrived at the hotel &quot;Daguanzhuang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large rectangular building lying on its back, with a huge lobby extending to both ends of the building. This large-scale resort hotel is almost identical and can be found in Hakone and Hokkaido. I highly doubt it was done by a designer. When you see a hotel of this size, you know how popular Songdo is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you enter Songdo at night, you can’t see much. When you wake up in the morning and open the curtains, you will be greeted by a 180-degree sea view. Beautiful indeed. Her pure and simple beauty is suitable for people like Basho who are in a light and lonely state of mind. Basho also lives in Songdao facing the sea, on the second floor (we live higher than him on the third floor). He said, “Opening the window and facing the sea, the so-called traveling and sleeping in the wind and clouds, the wonderful feeling is indescribable. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I carry &quot;The Secret Path of the Oku&quot; with me. When I arrived at Songdao, I read the chapter about &quot;Songdao&quot; in the book carefully. Basho sighed, &quot;According to old legend, Fusang ranks first in the scenery of Songdao, and its coverage is not inferior to that of Dongting and West Lake. From the southeast, the sea enters the bay, and within three miles of the bay, it surges like the tide of Zhejiang. There are countless big and small islands, and the towering ones point directly to the sea. Outside the sky, prostrate ones are crawling on the waves. Either two layers overlap, or three layers are piled up; the islands on the left and right are either separated or connected; those with burdens and those with hugs are like loving children and grandchildren. The pines are lush, the tide is blowing, the wind is blowing, the branches and leaves The curves are natural, but appear to be the result of manipulation. The scenery is natural, with the appearance of a beautiful woman condensing her makeup. Could it be that the mountains were only made by the gods in ancient times? Who can use the colorful brushes of the heavens to achieve their beauty? Really?&quot; (Translated by Zheng Qingmao)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bajiao has never been to China, but he is not reluctant to borrow the scenery of China. Through reading Chinese classics and paintings, ancient Japanese literati became quite familiar with and intimate with Chinese scenic spots such as the West Lake, Dongting Lake, and Qianjiang Tide. A matter of course. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of 2018, my friends and I visited the Sumio Goto Museum of Art in Furano. I vaguely remember that he seemed to have a painting of Songdao, and it was a very long painting. I remember that I took a photo (Special note, many art museums in Japan are not allowed to take photos of exhibits, or can only take photos of some of the exhibits. I strictly abide by this rule. Photography is allowed for all exhibits in the Goto Juno Museum of Art) ). In November 2019, after returning home from a trip to Oshu, I turned on my computer to check, and I found this painting. I was very surprised. Isn’t this the view we saw from our room in Daikanso? I think Goto Juno stayed at Daikanso when he visited Matsushima, and it was one of the rooms on the third floor of our row facing the sea. This painting by Juno Goto was painted in 1987 and is called &quot;Morning on Matsushima&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ud8QPlbfKJzhSCfAI3lRj04aLAniveD7G2jmoqTK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Autumn leaves at Entsu-in Temple, an affiliated temple of Zuigan-ji Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I stood in front of the window in the early morning and looked at the Matsushima sea view in front of me, and I thought of the Japanese cultural essayist In a passage from Hakushu Masako, she said, &quot;Japan is an isolated island in the East, and the good and the bad are all in the word &#39;iso&#39;. This isolated island is like a wind-swept corner of world culture. No matter what it is, as long as it passes through the hands of the Japanese, it will It will transform into something more indescribable, delicate, and dense.” I agree with this statement. There is no clear distinction between cultural forms, but there are completely different differences in rhythm, speed, and texture. Japanese culture is a condensed representation of world culture. Strong winds and waves transported various cultures to this island country in the Far East, and that&#39;s where it ended. Then, after being eliminated and transformed, they were condensed into a crystallized cultural form. Its static and density are completely different from mainland culture and corridor culture. The wind and waves stop here, but they are condensed in it, like a drop of amber between heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the scenery of Songdao in front of the window, I suddenly remembered these. During the trip, generally, abstract words will continue to stimulate my thinking, while visual beauty will make me quite distracted. Songdo is an exception. It seems that this is indeed an unusual Songdo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Small Path of the Oku&quot;, Basho&#39;s disciple Zeng Liang recited a haiku, &quot;On the pine island, the cuckoo should use the crane&#39;s body to sing throughout the bay.&quot; This haiku was engraved. The stele was erected at the entrance of Zuiyan Temple, juxtaposed with the &quot;Bajiao stele&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core of Songdo is Zuiam Temple. Basho and Zeng Liang visited Ruiyan Temple in the summer, and they thought it was peaceful and peaceful. We arrived in mid-autumn, and the tranquility was still there, with the subtle yellow and red colors of autumn mixed in with it. The smell of the sky must be completely different. The sky in all four seasons is really wonderful, equally clear and high, but the autumn sky is more profound and vague, like a pair of eyes with deeper sockets, which is different from the other three seasons. Starting from Sendai Station, I saw Matsushima red foliage tourism promotion posters posted all the way. They were overwhelmingly popular. The poster selects the red leaves of Zuigan Temple, or to be precise, the red leaves of Entsuin Temple, an affiliated temple of Zuigan Temple. The courtyard of Yuantongyuan is winding and graceful. It is a courtyard specially prepared for autumn. It is planted with maple trees, which will be full of red in late autumn. What was it like when we arrived? Take the marathon as an analogy. The starting gun of Hongfeng has already sounded. Some runners have already rushed out, but the huge team is still at the starting point. Imagine that as soon as we walked away, the red leaves in Yuantongyuan would start running wildly on a large scale until the whole garden was burning. It would be impossible not to feel a little sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zuigan Temple is an important temple of the Rinzai Sect. It was built in 828 AD. There is a room in the temple where Emperor Meiji once stayed, which is specially marked. After walking around the main hall and cloisters along the tour route, my attention was focused on the garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once the autumn light settles, it is gray-blue. Especially in the morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning from Songdo, I often looked at the photos of the dry landscape garden at Zuiganji Temple. A wonderful scene separated by light. In the shadows, the white sand turns into a clear gray-blue. There are tiny wind and thunder in the wrinkles of the sand. The dark and light moss has a wonderful sense of exquisiteness. Beyond the shadows, in the strong light, the white walls and rocks, and the pine trees rolling down the cliff outside the temple, with the cluster of red leaves as the boundary, have lost their tension here and calmed down. But this stillness seems to be broken at any time, if the light changes slightly. As a result, those watching couldn&#39;t help but hold their breath. Therefore, it is right to freeze it into a photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Art philosopher Professor Arthur Danto has studied Basho very well and believes that the texture of Basho haiku is &quot;quiet, concise, as crystal clear and cool as a diamond&quot;. He once said that he wanted to be like Basho. Basho&#39;s journey is a pilgrimage to art, nature and the heart. He is humorous, self-deprecating, proud and lonely, but has a strong sense of humility. He regards his ancestors, nature and the very act of tapping the ground with his feet. They all have very pious thoughts. His practice has been successfully completed in the process of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Danto once said it well. He said, &quot;...Bashō, as an individual, exists in such a reality where the expression of personality and the disappearance of personality are unified. It is neither worldly nor independent. So out of the world; as he mocked himself, he was like a bat, neither a mouse nor a bird, but a hybrid shape-shifting creature between two animal states of existence. I was always moved by his travel notes . These travel notes are a symbol of the restlessness in his body. He always starts from a feeling or a hope for the end, with no intention of returning, in order to seek some ultimate escape. In the end, he discovers that escape itself is an achievement.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;As for Basho, I once said that I regard him as a literary lover. In other words, I want to be like him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国草”与“东方神药”的丝路之旅]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the arrival of the rainy season, the incidence of malaria on the African island of Sao Tome has begun to rise. Guangzhou University of Traditional Chinese Medicine went to Sao Tome Huang Xinan, leader of the Dome-Príncipe Artemisia annua anti-malarial expert team, is increasingly busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 16, 2023, shortly after it rained, he and his colleagues set off from downtown Sao Tome in a pickup truck and walked on the dirt road to Diogo Nunez (Diogo Nunez). Nunes) village. There, expert team teachers guided center employees to collect samples door-to-door to screen for potential cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/VtYO8mMHyaXbgJDWiTy90yXEXlacasevoPowyJj2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Under the guidance of Chinese anti-malarial experts, staff went door-to-door to collect samples and screen for potential cases. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the outskirts of Nadi, Fiji, 85-year-old farmer Kumar is still in good spirits. On the 16th, he drove a small truck and brought back a load of Juncao oyster mushroom waste from the China-aided Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Fiji. This waste mushroom material can be used as organic fertilizer for fruits and vegetables on the farm. Two months ago, under the guidance of Chinese Juncao technical experts, Kumar was still planting Juncao on the landslide on the farm&#39;s river bank to control the worsening water and soil erosion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative was proposed, one after another &quot;small but beautiful&quot; projects that benefit people&#39;s livelihood have been implemented in countries along the initiative. Combining its own development experience and technological advantages, it provides Chinese solutions for local poverty alleviation, public health and environmental governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/ybXmglmJkHiHYtescPrMyUKXKnuyv5ar7SbtErGS.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kuma, an 85-year-old farmer in Nadi, Fiji, uses waste mushroom material as organic fertilizer for fruits and vegetables on the farm. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Juncao&quot; and &quot;Artemisia annua&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many For Fijians, Juncao is the &quot;magic grass&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Juncao planting base of the Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Fiji, you can see these &quot;guests&quot; who have traveled across the ocean. These giant grasses are several meters long, with thick stems, wide leaves and well-developed root systems. Even the tallest people in the crowd feel as if they are walking into a reed marsh as soon as they enter the grassland, and they are instantly overwhelmed by the green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local people often pronounce Juncao as Junkao according to their English pronunciation habits. In fact, Juncao technology is an original technology that China has completely independent intellectual property rights. Until now, the international English name of Juncao is &quot;Juncao&quot; in Chinese pinyin. In 2001, China&#39;s first foreign aid Juncao technology demonstration base was built in Papua New Guinea. So far, this technology has been promoted to more than 100 countries and regions around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 22, 2023, the China-Pacific Island Countries Juncao Technology Demonstration Center was unveiled and launched in Fiji. Lin Xingsheng, an expert at the National Juncao Engineering Technology Research Center of Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University, came to Fiji in January this year. Since then, his tasks have become even heavier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In Fiji, Juncao can be used as high-quality feed for livestock and poultry, and can also be used to cultivate edible fungi—traditionally, it is a high-quality culture material for growing mushrooms.” He told Southern Weekend reporters that their Work includes production, scientific research, demonstration, training, promotion, etc. Since the implementation of Juncao technology in Fiji in 2014, more than 2,300 local Juncao technical talents have been trained, more than 700 farmers have grown Juncao mushrooms, and more than 1,000 farmers have developed Juncao farming, ending Fiji’s inability to The history of mushroom production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Juncao is full of treasures and can be used for many purposes.&quot; Lin Xingsheng said that in addition to &quot;replacing wood with grass&quot; as a culture substrate for edible and medicinal fungi, Juncao can also be used as a culture medium for cattle and sheep. and other livestock feed, effectively alleviating the dry season feed shortage problem in the arid western Fiji area and promoting the development of local animal husbandry. In addition, Juncao grows quickly and has a well-developed root system. It can also be used to prevent local soil erosion and improve saline-alkali land. Planting one hectare of giant fungus in Fiji can absorb more than 100 tons of carbon dioxide, which is an effective way to combat climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, with the help of Lin Xingsheng and other experts, Juncao was planted on the river bank of the farm of Kumar’s family, a local in Nadi. Just over a month has passed, and clumps of green grass have grown on the originally bare steep slopes. After entering the tillering stage and jointing stage, Juncao will grow faster and faster. Lin Xingsheng is &quot;confident&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Soil and water loss was very serious on the landslide before. When it rained, the sediment would rush into the river. Planting Juncao can effectively solidify the soil and store water. This is why we carry out Juncao slope protection and bank protection in Fiji to prevent soil and water loss. One of the demonstration sites of ecological governance.&quot; Lin Xingsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the tall Juncao, Artemisia annua looks particularly &quot;weak&quot;. The ancient name of Artemisia annua is &quot;裣&quot;, which means &quot;grass that treats malaria&quot; and was first recorded in &quot;Shen Nong&#39;s Materia Medica&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 1,700 years ago, Ge Hong, a Taoist priest and medical scientist in the Eastern Jin Dynasty, left a record of artemisia annua against malaria in &quot;Emergency Prescriptions&quot; - &quot;A handful of artemisia annua, soak it with two liters of water, and wring it out. Just take it.&quot; This 15-character ancient prescription has inspired generations of Chinese medicine practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tu Youyou, a researcher at the China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences, was also inspired by this, changing the extraction method from high temperature to low temperature, and finally successfully discovered artemisinin, which has benefited millions of malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 30, 2021, the World Health Organization announced that China had passed the malaria elimination certification. According to disclosed data, the number of local primary cases of malaria in China has dropped from 30 million per year before the founding of New China to &quot;zero for four consecutive years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the advancement of the Belt and Road Initiative, China’s anti-malarial experience with Artemisia annua has also been introduced to other countries in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sao Tome and Principe (referred to as &quot;Sao Tome and Principe&quot;) is an island country in the west of the African continent with a population of about 220,000. The year here is divided into dry season and rainy season. Among them, during the rainy season from October to May of the following year, the humid and high temperature weather is very conducive to the breeding of mosquitoes. Mosquitoes are an important vector for the spread of malaria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, Huang Xinan, an associate researcher at the Artemisia Research Center of Guangzhou University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, who is carrying out anti-malarial assistance in Sao Tome and Principe, told Southern Weekend reporters that while the rainy season has just begun, they must speed up monitoring and control. pace. Currently in Sao Tome, a village can be classified as an epidemic source village if there are more than 3 cases of malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, a hospital in Água Grande, São Tomé City, reported three malaria cases. On October 16, they deployed manpower to carry out a large-scale malaria epidemic prevention and control operation in key epidemic source villages. Screening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally, we will determine the source village through feedback data from hospitals, epidemic control centers and other channels, and then work with malaria prevention team members to carry out case screening, drug distribution, mosquito disinfecting and other tasks.&quot; Huang Xinan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, in Liberdade, Dashui District, São Tomé City, the China Artemisia annua anti-malarial project team adopted a &quot;source elimination and malaria&quot; program that prioritized removing the source of infection to conduct an anti-malarial pilot . Prior to this, this village with a population of more than 600 had 300 to 400 malaria cases every year. After three rounds of medication, the team continued to carry out measures such as monitoring the floating population and investigating the infection rate. During the long rainy season that followed for eight months, there were no local cases of malaria infection in Liberty Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The success of the Free Village pilot has given the Sao Tome and Principe government and local WHO officials greater confidence in defeating malaria. Because of its immediate therapeutic effect, the Artemisia annua compound medicine distributed by the expert team was also called the &quot;Oriental Miracle Medicine&quot; by the villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/geojCBVSi5UwUXjMZ5rz4X4lMnNTkoO2NsMuWGgN.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;With the help of Chinese Juncao technical experts, Juncao was planted on the river bank of Kumar&#39;s farm. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Business opportunities&quot; and connections&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Juncao mushroom cultivation project is It brings business opportunities to local farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Xingsheng, leader of the expert team of the China-aided Fiji Juncao Technology Demonstration Center, gave an example. The Fiji Juncao Center provides technical training to local farmers and provides fungus bags full of mycelium. After farmers receive the mushroom bags from the center, they can cultivate the mushrooms under the forest or in the shade of the shed by covering the soil with soil. They only need simple management measures such as simple watering and maintenance, lifting the film for ventilation, and the first crop of oyster mushrooms can be harvested in about 7-10 days. , you can have income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Fiji, ordinary farmers only need to plant 10 square meters of Juncao oyster mushrooms in front of and behind their houses. If they plant 4 times a year, they can harvest 1,200 kilograms of fresh oyster mushrooms and earn 20,000 Fijian dollars. The equivalent of RMB is almost over 60,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is much higher than the annual income of ordinary local farmers, so the locals call the Juncao project ‘quick money, easy money’ (money is easy and fast).” Lin Xingsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rwanda, a country in central and eastern Africa, the economic benefits of growing mushrooms also attract ordinary farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xiaobin, leader of the expert team of China’s Juncao Technology Demonstration Center in Rwanda, told Southern Weekend reporters that Rwanda has a large population but little land and underdeveloped industry. Local workers have low incomes, with an average daily income of only 9 yuan. Through the simple and easy-to-operate Juncao technology, ordinary people only need a small piece of open land and basic care to grow cash crops that make money quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with previous local mushroom growing technologies, China’s Juncao mushroom growing technology has low cost, high yield and easy operation, and is welcomed by many mushroom growers. In neighboring countries adjacent to Rwanda, such as Uganda and the Democratic Republic of the Congo, mushroom merchants also go to border trading points to purchase fresh mushrooms. The ever-expanding domestic and foreign market demand has also stimulated the enthusiasm of mushroom growers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to growing mushrooms in mushroom bags, some people are also studying mushroom bag production technology to achieve &quot;technical localization.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Nadi, Fiji, farmer Ashniel is an expert at growing mushrooms. Not only did he fully master the management technology of Juncao mushrooms, he also learned to produce mushroom bags independently. At the same time, he also modified a humidifier to adjust the humidity in the mushroom-producing place. The oyster mushrooms he grows have thick flesh and good quality, which not only attracts many people to visit and study, but is also favored by customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rwanda, many locals who come for training are college students with higher education. After completing their studies, they started their own business and sold fungus bags to local farmers for a fee. According to preliminary statistics, there are about 50 local companies and cooperatives that independently produce mushroom bags. According to Chen Xiaobin, in Rwanda, Chinese Juncao technology is a symbol of high-quality mushrooms. Mushroom growers or mushroom bag manufacturers will rush to put the &quot;Juncao Technology&quot; label on their products when promoting their products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the introduction of Juncao mushroom cultivation technology, Chinese mushrooms have also quietly integrated into the local food culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Xiaobin of the Rwanda Juncao Technology Demonstration Center said that every time when training students, teachers will arrange cooking classes to demonstrate various ways of eating mushrooms. &quot;Such as deep-frying, stir-frying, mushroom soup, etc.&quot; After students read it, they will also make innovations based on local eating habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Fiji, mushroom growers process the mushrooms and add cassava flour and other materials to turn them into mushroom drinks. In Rwanda, Sambusa (the Chinese call it Triangle) is a traditional pasta made of dough and stuffing. Bao), in addition to regular fillings such as potatoes, beef, and onions, recently the hot-selling mushrooms have also been added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Eastern Highlands Province of Papua New Guinea (referred to as &quot;PNG&quot;), the first stop for &quot;Juncao going overseas&quot;, the Juncao and upland rice industries have become the second and third largest industries in the region after coffee. three major agricultural industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early 2000, China&#39;s Fujian Province and Papua New Guinea&#39;s Eastern Highlands Province signed a sister province agreement, listing Juncao and upland rice technology as Fujian Province&#39;s assistance projects to Eastern Highlands Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Yingxing, leader of the expert team of China’s Juncao Technology Demonstration Base in Papua New Guinea, told Southern Weekend reporters that over the years, the Juncao project’s promotion area in Papua New Guinea, the number of participating farmers, training personnel, and experts have increased significantly. improve. Currently, subdivided projects such as Juncao mushroom cultivation, Juncao livestock husbandry, and upland rice cultivation have been promoted to many provinces in the country, benefiting more than 10,000 farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report by the &quot;PNG Courier&quot; on October 4, 2023, this project has become a model for the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; cooperation between China and Papua New Guinea. The friendly relations between the new Eastern Highlands provinces played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/DcAQuuhEf58ZJEm5CWhquZSmUTKwD0tQyhU0KgGe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Nadi, Fiji, the oyster mushrooms grown by farmer Ashniel have thick flesh and good quality. They not only attract many people to visit and learn, but are also favored by customers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Prescribe the right medicine to the case&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to WHO data in 2020, Among the six major regions in the world, Africa is the most severely affected by malaria. In 2020, the region accounted for 95% of the global total of malaria cases and 96% of the global malaria deaths. An estimated 80% of malaria deaths in the region occur among children under 5 years of age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, Deng Changsheng, an associate researcher at the Artemisia annua Research Center of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, provided anti-malarial assistance in the African island nation of Comoros. He saw from preliminary survey data that at that time, about 60% of outpatient cases in medical institutions in Comoros were malaria. More than half of the hospitalized cases were malaria patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It can be said that malaria was the most troublesome health problem in this country at that time.” He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Comoros at that time, many residents were accustomed to collecting rainwater in cellars during the rainy season for use in the dry season. During field research, Deng Changsheng saw mosquito larvae crawling densely in the water cellars of many residents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Poor drinking water environment is undoubtedly one of the reasons for the spread of malaria. Even in recent years, the malaria situation in Africa is still not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Song Jianping, director of the Artemisia annua Research Center of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2017, the team conducted random checks among about 150,000 people in the Est-Mono region of Togo, Africa. Among more than 2,000 people randomly checked, the infection rate among the sample population was as high as 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to extremely high infection rates, many African countries have very weak anti-malarial medical systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many African countries have a common problem, that is, there is no primary medical care, or there is an urgent shortage of emergency doctors.” According to Song Jianping, people with malaria are unable to seek medical treatment for various reasons after they develop symptoms. Some residents need to spend their own money for tests and high-priced drugs; some residents have inconvenient transportation and cannot reach regular hospitals. If it cannot be detected in time, it will be impossible to achieve the effect of early treatment and early prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many years, Chinese artemisia annua anti-malarial experts, including Song Jianping’s team, have launched artemisia annua anti-malarial campaigns in African countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Comoros, his team implemented a campaign of universal administration of artemisinin compound to eliminate the source of infection, curbing the country&#39;s malaria epidemic and achieving zero malaria deaths. In Papua New Guinea, only one year after the project was implemented, the average population infection rate was 0.07%, a decrease of more than 99%, and zero malaria deaths were achieved. In Sao Tome, the project team has gradually established a three-level anti-malaria system of &quot;Ministry of Health - County - Village&quot; in São Tomé and Principe. According to the malaria incidence rate and the number of outbreaks, targeted early intervention is carried out in high-incidence villages to suppress malaria outbreaks. Popularity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Over the years, these programs have been verified by millions of people in many countries, and there is very rich clinical data. The data proves that the Chinese programs are effective and immediate. For compound artemisia annua anti- We are very confident in our plan to combat malaria,&quot; Deng Changsheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Jianping believes that malaria prevention and control is a complex and huge task. In terms of the drug itself, the compound artemisia annua antimalarial regimen has its own advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the team is constantly optimizing the drug ratio in anti-malarial drugs so that it can maintain the advantages of artemisinin’s high cure rate while reducing adverse reactions and taking rounds as much as possible. Suitable for large-scale drug administration sites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The incidence rate of adverse reactions of some drugs is as high as 20 to 30%, which can cause fear in patients. Low participation means low coverage, which cannot achieve prevention and treatment effects.” Song Jianping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the African continent, Nigeria and the Democratic Republic of Congo account for 70% of malaria cases in the world. Compared with island countries, the incidence rate here is higher, the infection level is more severe, the population is larger, and the population is more mobile. Implementation of the plan may require larger amounts of funds and greater coordination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, Song Jianping hopes to continue to develop more effective antimalarial drugs on the one hand, and on the other hand, extend the antimalarial experience to more areas. &quot;In the future we hope to make a difference on the African continent,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Zhai Huan and Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/ a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[个人养老金保险名单增加18款税延养老产品 总名单扩容至69款]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, according to the official website of China Banking and Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Banking and Insurance&quot;), The list of personal pension insurance products has been expanded to 69 products, involving 22 insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that this expansion not only added 3 new product types to the 48 at the end of July, but also added 18 personal tax-deferred pension annuity insurance (hereinafter referred to as &quot;tax &quot;Extended Pension Products&quot;) has been incorporated into the personal pension product system. After the expansion, the types of personal pension insurance products include exclusive commercial pension insurance, endowment insurance, annuity insurance and tax-deferred pension products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254620&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(Picture source:&amp;nbsp;China Bank &amp; Credit Insurance Co., Ltd.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above 18 items are included in personal pension Financial tax-deferred pension products are provided by China Pacific Life Insurance Co., Ltd., Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Ping An Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Taikang Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Taiping Life Insurance Co., Ltd. and Generali Life Insurance Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kaiyuan Securities research report shows that the integration of tax-deferred commercial pension insurance into personal pensions mainly helps policyholders of tax-deferred pension insurance to coordinate and unify the third pillar tax preferential policies and reduce the personal income tax rate when receiving them. , which is conducive to the further improvement of the personal pension system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, on August 31, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Matters Concerning the Connection between the Pilot Program of Personal Tax-Deferred Commercial Pension Insurance and Personal Pensions.&quot; The main content of the &quot;Notice&quot; includes clarifying the work requirements, business adjustments, product management, policy transfer, etc. in the process of connecting the tax-deferred pension insurance pilot and personal pensions, and also clarifies the customer information confirmation and strengthens system construction for China Banking and Credit Insurance Co., Ltd. , as well as requirements for business operations, announcements and information submissions of tax-deferred pension insurance pilot insurance companies. In principle, all work should be completed before the end of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders said that personal tax-deferred pension insurance highlights the &quot;burden reduction&quot; effect, and the tax burden after retirement is lighter. The expansion of the list means that the connection between the tax-deferred pension insurance business and the personal pension system is progressing in an orderly manner, in line with work expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2018, the Ministry of Finance and other departments jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Launching the Pilot of Personal Tax-Deferred Commercial Pension Insurance&quot;, launching the pilot business operation in the country. The pilot areas are Shanghai, Fujian and Suzhou Industrial Parks, and the maximum pre-tax deduction amount is 6% of personal taxable income or 12,000 yuan per year, whichever is lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ping An Securities stated that the pilot policy is not attractive to low-income people, and the tax benefits are limited for those who can enjoy tax benefits. Under the personal pension system, there are more product choices and simpler tax deduction procedures. The two types of products have similar attributes and share tax preferential quotas. The integration of tax-deferred commercial pension insurance into personal pensions will straighten out the relationship between tax-advantaged pension insurance. Relevant procedures will be simplified to make it easier for investors to understand. At the same time, it will further enrich the selection of personal pension products and increase investors&#39; willingness to insure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the official implementation of the personal pension system in November 2022, personal pension insurance products have continued to expand. According to the official website of China Banking and Insurance Corporation, by the end of July 2023, the number of personal pension insurance products has increased from The initial 7 models were expanded to 48 products, and currently it has been expanded to 69 products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ping An Securities stated that residents’ demand for retirement savings continues to expand under the background of an aging population. However, since this year, long-term interest rates have remained low and volatile, many commercial banks have lowered deposit interest rates, the equity market has fluctuated greatly, and the returns of competing products have Rates have declined, and insurance products follow pricing interest rates, have guaranteed yields, and can provide protection against risks such as death, total disability, and disability, further highlighting their differentiated advantages. As an important part of the third pillar of pension insurance, commercial pension insurance is expected to achieve rapid development under the personal pension system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>