<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“没有见过需要那么多雕塑的”：四川达州古名天下景区烂尾调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261047]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 11:34:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; are famous all over the world in ancient times. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/135bfa3138.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; The ancient world-famous &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot;. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County in Sichuan Province was once the county with the largest number of people who have not been lifted out of poverty, apart from the national and provincial poverty-stricken counties in Sichuan. There is a scenic spot in the mountains here, spanning three counties and three towns, with a planned area of ​​15.3 square kilometers, equivalent to the size of 15 Forbidden City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is known as &quot;the only imperial cultural area in the world&quot; and includes nearly 2,000 statues, including nearly 500 portraits of emperors and generals, thousands of imitation &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, and more than 3 meters high. Images such as &quot;Seven Fairies&quot; and &quot;Eight Immortals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was not completed. No one cared about it for many years. The statue gradually peeled off and faded, disappearing in the grass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2021, someone asked on the official website of &quot;Ask Politics in Sichuan&quot;: &quot;The ancient Fengdian Town in Zhongjiang, Sichuan is famous all over the world. What is the reason why it has not been completed for many years?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fengdian Town is famous all over the world. The town government responded in November that the capital chain of the scenic spot builder was broken, with about 28 million yuan in arrears in project payments and more than 80 million yuan in arrears in financing, involving more than 2,700 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more surprising is that the judgment document website states that the legal representative of the developer was sentenced at the end of 2019 for illegally occupying agricultural land for the construction of a scenic spot. While he was on probation, he was still actively soliciting investment. In June 2022, the scenic spot announced its temporary closure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How was such a behemoth built? Who is responsible for its failure? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses from Sichuan&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area is affiliated to Deyang City. According to promotional materials, the project was launched in 2014 with a total planned investment of approximately 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Its location is relatively remote, more than an hour&#39;s drive from the center of Deyang and surrounding cities, such as Chengdu and Guanghan. Drive from the Fengdian section exit of Zhongjiang County on the Hurong Expressway and turn right. You will see 9 golden bull elephant sculptures, which are the main entrance of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The tour loop is 19 kilometers long. Welcome to take the sightseeing bus.&quot; A line of golden characters at the main entrance reminds tourists of the scale of the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance is built in imitation of ancient city walls, with couplets in red letters on a gold background hanging on both sides: North, south, east, west, there is no other place in the world, but this place has existed in the world throughout the ages. After the scenic spot was temporarily closed, the gates were locked and items in the ticket room were smashed. Nearby villagers gather under the &quot;golden elephant&quot; to chat, and occasionally give directions to curious tourists from out of town. &quot;You can climb over the wall.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beside the Jade Dragon Gate at the entrance of the scenic spot, the Fengdian Town Government posted a notice in March 2023, warning tourists not to enter the scenic spot in any way, because the current infrastructure is incomplete and there are major safety risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone opened a trail from the left side of Jade Dragon Gate. If you walk forward for a few minutes against the weeds more than 1 meter high, you will see a statue of an emperor more than 2 meters high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The statue of the emperor in the grass. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f8c7564035.jpeg&quot; data- key=&quot;259128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A statue of an emperor in the grass. Photographed by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three Sovereigns and Five Emperors are making CALL online. Qin Emperor and Han Wu invite you to point out the country together.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion, there are nearly 500 statues here, including Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty, Wu Zetian, Taizu of the Song Dynasty, etc. The emperors of modernization also include the leaders of the &quot;Five Hus and Sixteen Kingdoms&quot; and the &quot;Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hong Hai participated in the construction of about 100 emperor statues from the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty and stayed in the scenic spot for more than two months. He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters on the phone that the developer was inspired by &quot;Pictures of Emperors of the Past&quot; by Yan Liben, a painter from the Tang Dynasty, and wanted to present the emperors of the past dynasties in the form of sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statue is placed in a cement field called &quot;Chinese Historical Process Park&quot;. The scenic spot hopes to allow tourists to appreciate five thousand years of Chinese culture by displaying the emperor&#39;s style and introducing his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if tourists look carefully, they will laugh. For example, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty Yang You (605-619) only lived 15 years old, but the statue of Yang You in the scenic area has a thick long beard and wrinkles on his face, making him look like a mature uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The text introduction is not rigorous enough. For example, in the introduction to Song Taizu, &quot;Zhao Kuangyin practiced martial arts when he was young, and first joined Guo Wei, Taizu of the Northern Zhou Dynasty. Later, he followed Chai Rong, Emperor Shizong of the Zhou Dynasty, to fight in various places, and made many military exploits. There were commanders and envoys in front of the palace, and he mastered ice boxing.&quot; Not only is the sentence incomplete, it also contains typos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Hong Hai said that he and his team were not involved in the coloring and text introduction of the statue. The appearance of the emperor was also built based on the drawings provided by the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that the raw materials of these imperial statues are mainly steel bars and cement, which are cheaper than copper. He did not disclose the total price, citing commercial confidentiality. Due to lack of maintenance and management, hundreds of emperors are now living with dead grass. Under the sun and rain, the acrylic paint on many statues has faded, exposing gray cement, and steel bars are also exposed at the joints of the bases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far from the emperor&#39;s statue, nearly a thousand &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are quietly guarding in the mud. These &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; imitate armored warrior warriors, wearing battle uniforms, armor, and hair tied in high buns. However, compared with the various terracotta warriors and horses in the Qin Shihuang Mausoleum in Xi&#39;an, the &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses Sichuan&quot; are rough in workmanship, lack details in their expressions and costumes, and are weak in momentum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot once attracted tourists with the gimmick that &quot;you can see the Terracotta Warriors and Horses without leaving Sichuan&quot;. Now these replicas are surrounded by moss and wild grass on the edge of the mountain forest, and some have white thatch inserted into their hands. &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot;, who was wearing a dragon robe, had a red ribbon &quot;praying for peace&quot; wrapped around his bun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a sign under the feet of &quot;Qin Shihuang&quot; that reads: &quot;No destruction of property!&quot; However, due to no one taking care of them, these imitations have faded and have cracks in many places. Some &quot;Kneeling Shooting Figurines&quot; were cut off at the waist, and many &quot;Warrior Figurines&quot; lost their arms and even their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early November 2023, Southern Weekend reporters also saw giant sculptures placed in scenic spots such as Seven Fairies, Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea, Mother Earth, Chang&#39;e Flying to the Moon, Queens of the Four Seasons, and Zhuzi Square. They are three to four meters high, but the workmanship is rough when seen up close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity, there are more than 20 scenic spots in the scenic area, such as the Drunken Concubine, the Sifang Wealth Saint, the Yue Laotai, the Nine Fox Fairy Cave, and the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl. &quot;Their huge lineup and magnificent momentum are truly unmatched throughout the ages. Unparalleled.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making emperor statues for Gu Ming Tian Xia, Hong Hai saw the terracotta warriors and horses and other statues being moved into the scenic spot. He has been engaged in the sculpture industry for nearly 20 years and lamented, &quot;I have never seen anything that requires so many sculptures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity of the scenic spot, the ancient name of the world is based on the five thousand years of Chinese civilization as the core theme, integrating the Chinese cultural story line into the natural ecology and cultural landscape, allowing the story to connect, empower and cast the soul of the landscape. Thus forming an internal logical connection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Driving local people to get rich&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Developers came to this town in 2014. According to (2019) Sichuan 0623 Xingchu No. 409 Judgment, on March 7, 2014, Sichuan Gumingtianxia Investment Management Co., Ltd. signed an investment cooperation framework agreement with the Fengdian Town Government of Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhongjiang County is a major agricultural county in the hilly areas of Sichuan. The food crops grown are mainly rice, rapeseed and wheat. Fengdian Town under its jurisdiction is also a typical remote agricultural town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia Investment Company will invest 370 million yuan to build a new wintersweet viewing base and agricultural tourism project in Fengdian Town. The Fengdian Town Government agrees to provide its company with the land for this project within the ownership and land scope of Huangping Village and Hejia Village Committees. The area shall be based on the lease area signed between the company and the village, but it shall not change the land without authorization. Nature of land use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the investment cooperation framework agreement obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, the two parties also agreed that Gumingtianxia Investment Company should register and establish a Zhongjiang branch within the jurisdiction of Zhongjiang County. After the project is completed and put into operation, taxes will be paid in the territory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 21, 2014, Zhou Lizhu registered and established Sichuan Guming Tianxia Tourism Development Co., Ltd. in the name of her daughter Zhou Xiaxia (in 2016, the legal representative became Zhou Lizhu, hereinafter referred to as &quot; &quot;Anciently Famous&quot;), with a registered capital of 100 million yuan, and Zhou Lizhu holds 100% of the shares. The registered address of Gu Ming Tian Xia is No. 5, Huangping Village, Fengdian Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main entrance of the scenic spot is built in Huangping Village. Southern Weekend reporters learned from many Huangping Village villagers that rents in scenic spots range from 400 yuan/mu/year to 1,000 yuan/mu/year. One villager said that the land on the mountain was basically unable to grow food and was originally abandoned with no income. The scenic spot also hired local people to do cleaning, maintenance and other work, providing some jobs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenic spot also mentioned in its publicity that it will &quot;drive local people to become rich.&quot; The economy of Zhongjiang County is relatively backward. Information disclosed by the Sichuan Provincial Poverty Alleviation and Immigration Bureau shows that there were 92,500 poor people in Zhongjiang County in 2014. From 2011 to 2014, the province allocated 65.642 million yuan in special financial poverty alleviation funds for Zhongjiang County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investment cooperation framework agreement stipulates that Gumingtianxia plans to invest 370 million yuan, and the project construction period will be 4 years and will be completed at the end of December 2018. After completion, it can achieve annual sales revenue of 200 million yuan and tax revenue of 20 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Lizhu is from Dazhou, Sichuan Province. Local media in Dazhou reported his story twice. In 1980, Zhou Lizhu worked as a cashier in a mining company in Dazhou, earning more than 60 yuan a month. But he felt &quot;so tired&quot; that he resigned after five months and set up a leather factory. Zhou Lizhu was only 17 years old at the time and was called the &quot;Doll Factory Manager&quot; by her 10 workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mr. Zhou Lizhu, who has been in business for a long time, has a heroic spirit between his brows, and his beard makes his outline more subtle and elegant.&quot; According to the scenic spot promotion article, Zhou Lizhu has since He has worked in communication equipment, steel manufacturing, real estate, tourism and other industries, and has also studied in the EMBA class of Xiamen University and Peking University Guanghua School of Management. However, according to the verdict, Zhou Lizhu only had a junior high school education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to &quot;well-known entrepreneur&quot;, another label attached to Zhou Lizhu is &quot;philanthropist&quot;. According to the &quot;Dazhou Evening News&quot; report, Zhou Lizhu once used part of Gumingtianxia&#39;s operating income to establish the &quot;Love Weekly Special Fund&quot;. In October 2015, he donated 200 cherry blossom saplings worth 100,000 yuan to his hometown of Dazhu County, Dazhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It took four years of construction before it was found to be illegal&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhongjiang County Government website, in August 2016, the first phase of the Gumingtianxia project was registered, and the scenic area is planned to cover an area of ​​about 3,000 acres. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an investor, Southern Weekend reporters obtained the registration notice for the scenic spot’s corporate investment project from Gumingtianxia’s investment recruiters. The project name is “Gumingtianxia Sightseeing and Tourism Project—Planting Base and Historical, Cultural and Leisure Plaza” Construction Project&quot;, with a total planned investment of 180 million yuan, and the source of funds will be self-raised funds. The planned land area is 2,400 acres, and the construction area of ​​the main buildings is 10,000 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction content includes a planting base, office building, visitor center, exhibition hall, cultural and leisure square and ancillary facilities. The scale of products and services is to plant 100,000 balengang crabapples and wintersweet plants each year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registration notice shall be stamped by the Zhongjiang County Development and Reform Bureau. According to the remarks, the project unit can handle environmental protection, urban planning, land use, construction permit and other procedures in accordance with the law based on the notice. Construction of projects with incomplete relevant procedures shall not begin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice is valid for one year. During the validity period, if there are important changes (including changes in the project investment entity, construction location, main construction content, product technical solutions, and the expected change in the total investment or construction scale of the project by more than 20%, etc.), the project unit should apply for re- Filing. In October 2016, Gumingtianxia applied for re-registration, and the original planned land use of 2,400 acres was changed to 3,590.5 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another document obtained by Southern Weekend reporters showed that in August 2016, the Zhongjiang County Tourism Bureau sent a letter to Gu Ming Tian Xia, &quot;In principle, we agree that your company will invest in the development of Gu Ming Tian Xia Tourism in Fengdian Town.&quot; Tourism &#39;Project&#39;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fourth year of signing the contract, the scenic spot was found to have illegally occupied agricultural land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned judgment stated that, “In addition to planting wintersweet, crabapple and other agricultural planting projects on the rented land, the company also carried out agricultural projects from 2014 to 2018 without obtaining any construction land approval documents and procedures. During the year, the use nature of the original leased land was changed and construction projects were started.&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, through the appraisal led by the former Deyang City Land and Resources Bureau and Zhongjiang County Forest Public Security Bureau, the scenic spot involved the occupation of damaged cultivated land. The area is 140.1595 acres, involving an occupied forest area of ​​18,360 square meters (approximately 27.54 acres). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two parts of the area actually account for a very small proportion in the scenic spot, accounting for approximately 4.67% of the registered planned land area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2019, the Zhongjiang County People’s Court sentenced Gu Mingtianxia to the crime of illegal occupation of agricultural land and was fined 50,000 yuan; Zhou Lizhu was sentenced to two years and six months in prison, suspended for three years, and fined Ten thousand yuan in gold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past four years involving illegal construction, the scenic spot has still received support from the local government many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the public account of the scenic spot, in February 2016, the then Secretary of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee brought an inspection team to the scenic spot for guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Zhongjiang County Government, on August 9, 2016, the former deputy county magistrate presided over the Gumingtianxia project construction promotion meeting and listened to the project planning unit’s status report, the project investor’s construction plan report and related Opinions and suggestions from department heads. The meeting requested that relevant departments should work together to coordinate and solve problems existing in project construction to ensure the smooth progress of the construction project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing, one of the original managers of the scenic spot, told Southern Weekend reporters that the scenic spot did not clearly occupy basic farmland at the beginning of its construction. &quot;If he (the government) does not agree, does he dare to touch the land?&quot; Liao Xing said. Since 2014, she has followed Zhou Lizhu to work in Gumingtianxia, ​​mainly responsible for project management. After being owed wages, she resigned in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2017, the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Protection of Cultivated Land and Improving the Balance of Acquisition and Compensation&quot; to implement the strictest cultivated land protection system. According to the official website of the Sichuan Provincial Department of Land and Resources in September 2018, the Deyang Municipal Land and Resources Bureau paid close attention to the protection of cultivated land. In that year, the city carried out 685 dynamic inspections, discovered and stopped 10 land violations, and filed 4 cases for investigation and punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing and the above-mentioned investment personnel said that after Gu Mingtianxia and Zhou Lizhu were sentenced and paid fines, the local government had adjusted the basic farmland and forestland occupied by the scenic spot into general land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the publicity materials of the scenic spot, on April 10, 2020, members of the Standing Committee of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, Director of the County Culture and Tourism Bureau, and Deputy Director of the County Natural Resources Bureau visited the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Spot to guide the work and provide opinions. Or suggest that Zhou Lizhu and others accompany him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Twenty million is owed to build the scenic spot&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2015, the construction team began to enter the site. However, the construction of the scenic spot was carried out illegally at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A judgment shows that in August 2015, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd. signed a contract with Gumingtianxia, ​​agreeing to undertake the construction of anti-corrosion cabin projects for office buildings, hotels, and commercial streets in scenic spots. However, because Gu Ming Tianxia did not obtain the approval procedures for the construction of the office building, the competent authorities prohibited the construction, and Chongqing Jingwu Industrial immediately stopped the construction of the office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, the two parties signed a contract, agreeing to outsource the road pavement projects in the scenic area to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial. After June 2019, Chongqing Jingwu Industrial completed the roadbed construction, but because Gumingtianxia did not provide construction drawings and did not connect electricity for construction, it was unable to continue to complete the road pavement construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong was once one of the management members of the scenic spot. He told Southern Weekend reporters that because the scenic spot is a tourism project for investment promotion by the local government, the policy may be more liberal and construction will start first. He wants to build it first and then build it later. formalities. At present, Wang Rong is still owed about 100,000 yuan in salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong admitted that the scenic spot violated the relevant regulations on temporary land use at the beginning of its construction. &quot;There is no planning or construction report.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Gumingtianxia is facing a shortage of funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned judgment, in October 2016, Guming Tianxia issued an IOU to Chongqing Jingwu Industrial and admitted that it owed 2.6158 million yuan in project payment and 100,000 yuan in deposit. After returning the deposit, Gu Mingtianxia has been in arrears with the project payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from many construction parties that they had agreed with Gumingtianxia to &quot;advance funds first and then settle the settlement.&quot; Li Chengwu, a native of Sichuan, is in his fifties and has been in this business for more than 30 years, mainly contracting earthwork construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He saw that Zhou Lizhu had two companies under his name and thought he was quite strong. By the end of 2016, Li Chengwu calculated the accounts and found that the advance amount had reached nearly 5 million yuan. At this time, Zhou Lizhu still couldn&#39;t get the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Chinese New Year approached, Jiang Tao, who was in charge of the infrastructure project, and Yang Tinghong, who was doing the green sandstone paving project, also went to Zhou Lizhu to settle the bill, but they couldn&#39;t get their money back either. Zhou Lizhu&#39;s arrears to them were 2.9 million and 270,000 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Li Chengwu and others began to report the situation to the government. On September 1, 2017, at the Zhongjiang County Labor and Social Security Bureau, Gu Mingtianxia promised that Li Chengwu would pay off the project payment before August 30, 2018. After Zhou Lizhu signed, she wrote the word &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Li Chengwu and others belong to the &quot;Ancient Debt Collection Group&quot; with 88 people, including construction teams for landscaping, door and window guardrails, hardened roads, and paving bluestone in scenic spots. In November 2023, a boss who made doors and windows for scenic spots compiled statistics in the group. At least 22 construction teams were owed a total of about 20 million yuan in project payments, wages and deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many construction team bosses told Southern Weekend reporters that the reason why construction teams continued to enter the site in 2017 was because Gu Ming Tian Xia’s quotations were 5% to 10% higher than the market price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Judgment Documents Network, since the second half of 2017, construction parties have successively sued Zhou Lizhu and Gu Mingtianxia, ​​and won the lawsuit. Several plaintiffs applied for compulsory execution, but the court was unable to find any property or property clues in the name of the person subject to execution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the construction company, but also the villagers of Huangping Village, Fengdian Town, have been unable to get the rent from the scenic spot since about 2017. The investment promotion personnel of the above-mentioned scenic spots said that about 90% of the scenic spots are built in Fengdian Town, and so far the land rent arrears is about 9 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;This scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/ac29a45071.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The scenic spot spans three counties and three towns, with an area comparable to 15 Forbidden City. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is the ancient world always short of money? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the verdict, Gu Ming Tianxia initially planned to invest 370 million yuan in Fengdian Town. However, according to the publicity of the scenic spot, the total planned investment is about 3.1 billion yuan, and the scenic spot will be constructed in four phases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He did many things, including running a leather factory, selling steel products, selling communications, and also did crowdfunding.” Qiu Song, a Dazhou native and a fellow villager of Zhou Lizhu, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that Zhou Lizhu Lizhu &quot;crowdfunded&quot; a sum of money to start a company in Dazhou, and then went to Fengdian to build a scenic spot. Qiu Song built the steel frame structure for the scenic spot and is now owed about 1 million yuan by Gumingtianxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Dazhou native took Zhou Lizhu to court in 2018. According to the judgment, since December 2013, Zhou Lizhu borrowed a total of 1.2 million yuan from the plaintiff&#39;s father and used three houses in Tongchuan District, Dazhou City to pay off the debt. However, the plaintiff discovered that the owner of the mortgaged property was not Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also heard from Zhou Lizhu that he had a real estate development project in Dazhou. In order to collect debts, Li Chengwu went to the prefecture several times to look for Zhou Lizhu&#39;s property. &quot;Later I found out that he was deceived. He had no projects in Dazhou to draw money from.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu also went to Hainan because Zhou Lizhu claimed that there were 16 suites in a certain real estate in Sanya, which he could get. Several sets of money were paid to him. After he went there, he found that the person guarding the property was fellow Zhou Lizhu, and the property had nothing to do with Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong said that Zhou Lizhu once set up a financing company in Dazhou, financing money with 3 cents of interest and lending it to others at 5 cents or 8 cents. But later there were bad debts that could not be recovered, and he squandered some of them, resulting in arrears of hundreds of millions of yuan to investors. So Zhou Lizhu thought of setting up a scenic spot and claimed that all the financing funds had been invested in the construction of the scenic spot. &quot;Write a promise to those who owe money. The scenic spot will give you shares, and after the park opens, it will pay you dividends every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Tear down the east wall to pay for the west wall, and the capital hole is getting bigger and bigger.&quot; Nanfang. Over the weekend, reporters learned from an official in Fengdian Town as an investor that Zhou Lizhu initially brought about 40 million yuan to build the scenic spot. After the money ran out, she went to Mianyang, Deyang, Suining, Chengdu, Nanchong and other places to raise funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that from 2017 to 2018, Zhou Lizhu registered companies related to Guming Tianxia in Deyang, Chengdu, Mianyang, and Suining. According to the Fengdian Town Government, Gu Ming Tianxia’s arrears in financing amounted to more than 80 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that he did not know the source of Zhou Lizhu’s funds. He mentioned that due to road construction, the scenic spot received a road subsidy of about 1 million yuan from the local government, but other than that, it did not enjoy other subsidies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Tao, who is in charge of infrastructure projects, said that he saw two tourist buses parked in the scenic spot in 2017, and they were investors attracted by Gumingtianxia. &quot;Cheating the elderly out of their money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the judgment documents website, there are three judgments on private lending disputes related to Gu Ming Tianxia. The three judgments show that in March, May, and June 2019, Gu Mingtianxia borrowed 100,000, 10,000, and 100,000 from three people respectively, all promising an annual interest rate of 24%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the three plaintiffs are all older, and were 71, 60, and 63 years old respectively when they borrowed the money. Two of them are from Mianyang and one is from Deyang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the Blog China website, an investor who visited the scenic spot in October 2018 recorded the visit. At that time, the construction of the scenic spot was initially completed. The promoter said that the scenic spot was built solely by Zhou Lizhu. The original funds were sufficient. However, due to the continuous increase in raw material and labor prices in recent years, there was a gap in funds, so private funds were borrowed for the construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investor saw a retired man in his seventies investing 30,000 yuan at the scene. The old man had been defrauded of 210,000 yuan for buying &quot;health products.&quot; Seeing that the old man believed in Zhou Lizhu so much, the investor &quot;invested a little more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 13, 2019, Guming Tianxia also announced that it would be listed on the Tianfu (Sichuan) United Equity Trading Center with the code 610161. Tianfu Equity Exchange Center is a regional equity market operating institution that provides financing channels for small, medium and micro enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above three judgments, as of January 2020, Gumingtianxia failed to pay interest to the three plaintiffs as agreed, nor could it repay the principal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where did Zhou Lizhu spend her money? Liao Xing said that all the money was invested in the project. Not all of the project money was paid, but part of it was paid. For example, he said that excluding transportation and installation fees, the production cost of each emperor statue is about 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Rong said that before 2017, Gumingtianxia’s investment in the scenic spot did not exceed 5 million yuan. &quot;The government did not require capital verification at that time, and in the end he could not get out a penny.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Chengwu heard from Zhou Lizhu that the scenic spot was originally planned to open in May 2017. But it was not officially opened to the public until the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing said that the company’s capital chain was broken because the scenic spot was affected by the epidemic and stopped operating just after it opened, leaving no income. &quot;Roads were built, trees were planted, the projects were all placed there and they were not taken away.&quot; He felt that Zhou Lizhu was &quot;a person who wants to do things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Rong believed that Zhou Lizhu was using the scenic spot as a guise to make money outside and was not serious about developing the scenic spot. &quot;There is nothing inside except statues, and tourists will not come here a second time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liao Xing also had doubts about the development of the scenic spot. “The plan is indeed too big.” He once received other companies that came to visit the scenic spot, and they told him that in order to complete the planning of the scenic spot, at least another 1 billion yuan must be invested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses&quot;, Gumingtianxia originally planned to build a Zen medicine health and wellness ecological park, a low-altitude sports base, a Chinese history and culture study and travel base, a grand theater, an ancient Shaolin Temple and other attractions. Liao Xing said that the purpose of building a large scenic spot is to retain tourists staying overnight. Only when tourists stay there can the income be high. However, until the scenic spot closed, Gumingtianxia had not yet built a hotel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the scenic spot is not very attractive to tourists. In the East Square, Southern Weekend reporters saw several discarded tickets, priced at 98 yuan. There are 20 reviews of the scenic spot on Dianping. Most of them complain about the high fees, &quot;a bunch of fake sculptures in barren mountains and mountains&quot; and &quot;a waste of time and money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;There are thousands of imitation terracotta warriors and horses here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/22/67491062de.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22 /67491062de.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are thousands of imitation &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;While on probation, he is still running around&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the three years of probation, Zhou Lizhu is still soliciting investment. The Fengdian Town Government stated in November 2021 that it was actively urging Gumingtianxia investors to raise funds and finance from various sources to resolve the debt problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the scenic spot’s promotion, in December 2020, Zhou Lizhu signed a strategic cooperation agreement with the Chengdu Tourism Association Travel Agency Branch on behalf of the scenic spot at the 2020 China (Sichuan) Tourist Attractions and Cultural and Creative Industry Innovation and Development Expo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I must do everything possible to repay your funds as soon as possible.&quot; At the beginning of 2022, Zhou Lizhu wrote a letter to investment members. The letter mentioned that in response to the issue of &quot;expiration of investment member contracts&quot;, under the guidance of the Zhongjiang County Party Committee, County People&#39;s Government and relevant superior departments, the company is vigorously promoting investment promotion and adopting a combination of project implantation cooperation + equity cooperation. Mode increases hematopoietic function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the scenic spot announced its temporary closure. In July, Li Chengwu went to the office to find Zhou Lizhu and saw him talking to two or three investors in the reception room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The office of Gumingtianxia is located in the courtyard-style &quot;Guming Courtyard&quot;. When Southern Weekend reporters visited the &quot;Ancient Courtyard&quot; in early November 2023, the office was already empty. The yellowed and wrinkled leaflets of the scenic spot were blown to the corners along with the fallen leaves by the wind and rain. There were sheep dung and insect corpses everywhere on the ground. It looked like the yard had been abandoned for a while. The reception room, financial room and other office areas were in a mess. Overturned office cabinets, broken glass and scattered papers showed signs of fierce conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the foot of &quot;Queen of Four Seasons&quot; is another office location that is famous all over the world. Nowadays, there are renderings of the scenic spot and a calligraphy painting of &quot;Swallowing Mountains and Rivers&quot; hanging indoors. Dust, sheep dung, and corpses of insects and ants are everywhere. There was probably a conflict here. The jewelry cabinet that originally contained sterling silver bracelets and natural Gobi red agate was broken, and the empty jewelry box and price tag fell to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Zhongjiang County Government website, on the morning of July 23, 2022, members of the Standing Committee of the County Party Committee, Minister of Propaganda, and Chairman of the County Federation of Trade Unions went to Fengdian Town to hold an on-site coordination meeting for the &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; petition stabilization work. The County Public Security Bureau Bureau, County Culture and Tourism Bureau, County Natural Resources Bureau, County Economic and Foreign Affairs Bureau and other departments jointly participated in the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September of the same year, news about Zhou Lizhu appeared for the last time on the public account of the scenic spot. In his Mid-Autumn Festival message, he continued to convey to the outside world the company&#39;s determination to move forward, saying that it would &quot;fight the tough battle of attracting investment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official account of the scenic spot left an investment phone number. The contact person told Southern Weekend reporters that he was mainly responsible for updating the official account of the scenic spot and marketing. He had helped receive interested investors, but he had not met &quot;sincere investors&quot;. big investors”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The investment in tourist attractions is large and the return cycle is very slow. If the natural endowment is average, it is difficult to find investors. Other scenic spots have also gone bankrupt. They have no hematopoietic function and the profit model is unclear. Sooner or later, they will go bankrupt. Things.&quot; The contact claimed to have resigned at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from multiple creditors that Zhou Lizhu was admitted to the hospital at the end of 2022. Zhou Lizhu was 56 years old at the time. But Wang Rong believed that Zhou Lizhu had faked the news to avoid debts. On November 11, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter called Zhou Lizhu’s mobile phone number, and the other party denied that she was Zhou Lizhu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned scenic spot investment personnel and Fengdian Town officials, the scenic spot has not yet found a buyer. In early November 2023, the area near the &quot;Chang&#39;e Flying to the Moon&quot; statue at the entrance of the scenic spot and on both sides of the main entrance have been re-cultivated, and villagers have planted rows of rapeseed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ At the request of the interviewees, Hong Hai, Wang Rong and Liao Xing are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从喝无糖茶到内卷茶叶，年轻人又爱杯泡茶了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261035]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/604305f84ececbd8da5f7176dc8f4c18.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/21/604305f84ececbd8da5f7176dc8f4c18.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（Visual China&amp;nbsp; / Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, more and more young people have begun to drink tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that drinking tea here does not refer to milk tea or tea drinks, but to making tea yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, young people began to show off the tea or Kung Fu tea they brewed in a cup, and a cup of black tea or green tea became a standard addition to their desks. Whether you are studying for postgraduate entrance exams, working as a migrant worker, or working overtime, drinking tea has gradually become a fashion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Sugar-free tea is once again popular&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, before making tea in cups, Suntory, Oriental Leaf, etc. Sugar-free tea has begun to be favored by young people. This kind of tea drink made from original tea leaves is different from other milk teas. It focuses on sugar-free and tea flavor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether it is the well-established Suntory or Oriental Leaf under Nongfu Spring, when recommending its own products, they emphasize the use of natural tea as raw materials, the fermentation process used, and the absence of additives. No sweeteners or additives, etc., and strive to have the purest original tea as its characteristic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For young people who are under pressure from work and family, if they pay attention to their own sub-health and start to maintain health, they will inevitably start&lt;/span>; to consider nutritional content. intake, as well as a lifestyle of reducing and quitting sugar. This change in consumer mentality is the main mechanism that brings huge room for growth to sugar-free tea drinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant data shows that from 2017 to 2022, the average annual compound growth rate of the market size of sugar-free tea reached 28%. It is expected to maintain a growth of around 10.9% from 2022 to 2027. ——Obviously, this wave of young people are starting to adapt to its taste and starting to buy it repeatedly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, for this kind of tea packaged in plastic bottles, of course, there are still shortcomings such as not being fresh enough, and the main way of drinking is cold drink. Especially cold drinks are actually not friendly to some girls who don’t like freezing. Even if it is heated in a convenience store, it will taste ordinary and may even affect the taste. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/f64539bbdceb90d4ec2b592dc48cdd6b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/f64539bbdceb90d4ec2b592dc48cdd6b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259009 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（Visual China&amp;nbsp;/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Cup bubble tea has become popular&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nowadays, young people are choosing between sugary milk tea and frozen sugar-free tea. During the contact, more and more young people began to have &quot;new needs&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The &quot;2022 High-Quality Development Report of New Tea Drinks&quot; released by the Tea Research Institute of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences&lt;/span>; and other institutions shows that 46.90% of the &quot;post-90s&quot; He said that he got to know more traditional teas in the process of consuming new tea drinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Douyin data, in 2023, the proportion of interested users in the tea industry aged 18 to 30 will increase to 38.4%. This shows that the age group of tea drinking awareness is moving downwards, young people&#39;s tea drinking awareness is constantly improving, and the tea audience continues to show a younger trend. CCTV Finance&#39;s &quot;Zhengdian Finance&quot; column recently reported a market observation on the theme &quot;Young people are becoming more and more fond of drinking tea, becoming a new driving force for tea consumption&quot;, which also attracted attention and heated discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with sugar-free tea, making your own tea actually has many benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, you can choose the fresh &lt;span>; tea you like. Whether it&#39;s Mingqian Longjing with the aroma of beans, Wuyi Rock Tea with a mellow and sweet aroma, or Oolong or Pu&#39;er that removes oil and greasiness, different tea leaves bring different tastes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Fresh tea leaves can immediately produce a fresh taste, and the taste is actually more mellow. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; And, making tea is very friendly for the young ladies and sisters who like hot drinks. You don&#39;t have to be afraid that cold drinking tea will hurt your stomach. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; And buy several different tea leaves, change to drink according to the season or mood, and can also adapt to your taste needs at any time. In the production of tea, it takes a little time to cook water, throw tea, and wait for juice, etc., which can make people feel quiet and comfortable in simple hand work. It is also a buffer of learning or work pressure. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the choice of tea, compared with sugar -free tea, the choice of fresh raw materials tea is rich and colorful. Those who like black tea, there are Yunnan red in Yunnan, Jinjunmei, Yinjunmei in Fujian, Qimen black tea in Anhui. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Like green tea, West Lake Longjing, Dongting Biluochun, Huangshan Maofeng, Xinyang Maojian, and Liu&#39;an Melon in Anhui. Some fragrances are tangy, and some are mellow and moist, which can be described as their own characteristics. Others, there are all kinds of tea such as Shengpu, Mature Pu, Jasmine Tea, Oolong Tea, etc. to choose from. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Tea can be selected according to the region, production area, year &lt;/span>;, and the production area or craftsman. For young people who have just started, the basic knowledge of some tea is still very interesting. Make some choices in categories and regions, find a few of their favorite tea, and learn simple tea skills. It is actually very fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, there are some things to pay attention to when making tea, water quality, water temperature, what utensils are used for soaking, etc. Tea people still need to know. Such as purple sand pots are suitable for brewing black tea, Pu&#39;er tea, oolong tea, Wuyi rock tea, etc., which are not suitable for making green tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Green tea such as Longjing, which is more delicate, cannot be rushed immediately with too hot boiling water. It will destroy the chlorophyll in the tea, make it yellow, and lose the flavor and taste. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Tea is a forever track &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;sp>; &lt;span>; At the beginning of drinking, the cooking method of tea has not stopped updating. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; From cooking tea from the Tang Dynasty, to tea from the Song Dynasty, and then the tea made of tea in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, and the spread of matcha overseas such as overseas in Japan. In the age, the tea drinking method has undergone changes. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In modern times, with the changes in technology and technology, there are new Chinese tea drinks represented by various milk tea today. Various sugar -free tea, composite tea drinks containing tea ingredients, and all kinds of bags for making tea. Various tea varieties and tea drinking methods are still changing and iterative, and young people also repeatedly explore and try to consume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For young people who like to be popular and follow the trend, the traditional way of &quot;making tea&quot;, because of the driving between social platforms and video platforms and friends, it is very Easy to become a social symbol and communication method, making tea quickly become a lifestyle of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The preferences and tastes of young people will also be projected into tea -related &lt;span>; products, such as tea sets, etc., may become younger, simple, and fashionable. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the future, I believe that there will still be various ways to drink tea for young people. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Whether it is the Renaissance of Tea, or the new tea drinking new taste, more and more young people fall in love with tea -related products and consume it. It will further increase the overall market of the tea industry to make the tea ecosystem richer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为保住工作买公司产品？企业与员工间应建立合理边界丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261008]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 10:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Weilai layoffs are a recent hot topic. First of all, the industry was rumored. On November 3, 2023, Li Bin, the founder, chairman and CEO of Weilai Automobile, said in the internal letter of &quot;Organization Optimization and Two Years Priority&quot; that in order to further improve the efficiency of execution and ensure that the key businesses have sufficient resources, there are sufficient resources Investing, the company will reduce positions of about 10%, and the specific adjustment will be completed in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the 2022 ESG report released by Weilai on September 25, a total of 2,6763 employees were released. Based on this, it is estimated that there will be more than 2,600 or more layoffs. For Weilai layoffs, the mainstream narrative on the market is based on the situation of the electric vehicle industry or the company itself. This is of course a meaningful perspective. Here you can also cut into the perspective of employees. According to the &quot;China Business Daily&quot; report, from Weilai&#39;s internal employees, it is learned that the compensation plan is N+3, which should be good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, a user named &quot;Sugarbao&quot; posted in Xiaohongshu, saying that he has worked in Weilai for 5.5 years (also known as &quot;turning right a year ago&quot;, which seems to suggest that it was not officially before Work), nearly forty years old, there are old and young, especially cherish this job. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TA charges that the Weilai employees of &quot;almost 80%&quot; have been explicitly shown or implied that if you want to keep this job, you must buy Weilai Automobile. In order to avoid middle -aged unemployment, the Mercedes -Benz CLA, who had only bought it for two years by the end of last year, was replaced with Weilai ET5. This person wrote a post of &quot;ET5&#39;s January&quot; at the end of last year, saying that &quot;in terms of user first (car owner father), Weilai said that no one dares to say the first.&quot; This seems to confirm the authenticity of TA purchasing an ET5. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Then TA wrote again: &quot;The leader talked to me and said that if he wanted to be promoted, you must mobilize the friends and relatives around you to buy a car together.&quot; Then TA recommended his cousin and cousin to let them buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately to buy separately. Weilai ES7 and ES6; Earlier this year, in order to be promoted, I bought another ET5. There is a certificate of successful purchase-lending in the back, showing that the total price of ET5 it purchased is 345,200 yuan, of which nearly 300,000 are loans, and the monthly supply is 8150.56 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TA claims to be the first car ET5 car loan for 3,000 per month, then the monthly car loan is more than 10,000 yuan. Work and promotion? One family needs to buy two ET5? And the interval between the two purchases is very short. Therefore, some netizens have questioned, and some netizens believe that it is credible and believes that &quot;Weilai originally mobilized employees to buy cars (even linked to performance).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this regard, Weilai should clarify: Is this the staff of Weilai? Did you buy two ET5? This claims that &quot;in order to support the company and the stability of their positions, dozens of cars were pushed to relatives and friends around them, and they were almost sold part -time.&quot; Is it true or false? Does the enterprise ask employees to buy Weilai Automobile with performance or hidden rules for performance, retention and promotion linked? The media can also investigate these issues with face -to -law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The products from the enterprise are good, and the employees also need it and buy it voluntarily. There is no problem. However, if employees are required to buy a certain number or amount of the company&#39;s products, they can stay, and they can be promoted to increase their salary. The problem is very large: it is ugly to eat, break through the public and private border with employees, because the company is There is no right to interfere with employees&#39; personal consumption options; to the point, this is the &quot;pyramidization&quot; of the business-profit model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The true money routine of the MLM organization is to squeeze the money of each participant, and let the participants trust and cash with them, that is, the important interpersonal relationship of the participants to extract the participants The value of money, then sweep it out. A large number of systems destroy the personal social capital of participants, and the greatest social harm of MLM is this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Given that after the vast majority of people go out of school, they want to work in a business or organization, so there is a problem worth discussing: the employees are first, everyone is the first person, how to keep as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to hold as a person, how to keep your act as a person. The basic principles of people? Is it because you are not easy to find, or you are worried that you lose your job, or if you want to be promoted, you can take the initiative to do anything under the explicit or hint of the company and superior? &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As an employee, especially engaged in the free competition industry, the best strategy to keep your own work is always to enhance your strength. Replacement, creating irreplaceable value for enterprises or making the replacement cost of the enterprise very high. This strength may be your technical ability, you may be your ability to analyze and judge, or it may be your ability to dig and expand customers. In short, it is best to have the ability to be alone and who you have, and maintain and maintain your choice. In this way, you can have the unreasonable requirements of rejection of the enterprise or your boss, and keep the reasonable boundary with the enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In turn, if your ability, courage, or confidence is insufficient, the company or your boss must not use you, then you may eat some &quot;flies&quot; in order to keep your position, such as making you spend you giant Buy a company&#39;s products, let you borrow or loan to the company. If you do it, can you be able to pay it as expected? One company or boss may destroy the contract, uninstall it, and will cross the river to dismantle the bridge. As a result of holding your own salary to save the enterprise, you still have been cut. Isn&#39;t it a loss of money? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Those who know people, those who know themselves clearly. The beginning of a person&#39;s wisdom and courage is to dare to face his weakness. Facing the problem is always the first step to solve the problem; a person who has no courage cannot have a strong values ​​core, and often goes back and loses the evidence.就算为了生存，你也不需要在心灵上依附于任何人或任何外物，这是软弱与无能的体现；你需要激发出内在的勇气，培植基于实力的勇气，然后去开拓，去工作，去fighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以色列内阁投票同意与哈马斯达成临时停火协议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261041]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 09:23:28 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;pan>; According to the Israeli &quot;Land News&quot;, the Israeli cabinet vote in the early morning of the 22nd local time with Palestine Islamic Islamic Resistance movement (Hamas) reaches temporary ceasefire agreement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[三季度罚没金额145亿，近七成罚金来自第三方支付丨金融合规榜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261039]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; In the third quarter of 2023, the third-party payment industry became the area with the highest amount of administrative penalties in the financial industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Researcher researcher at the New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend of Southern weekend, based on the statistical analysis of the &quot;Shepherd -China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud Platform&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;) found that in the third quarter of 2023, 1105 institutions The total of 2881 individuals were fined 14.531 billion yuan, of which about 70 % of the third -party payment industry was fined. However, the number of punishment institutions is the head of the banking industry, of which the Rural Commercial Bank is the hardest hit area. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Guangdong sent institution &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; The amount of the penalty &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; 居 &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; each &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; province &lt;/strongRong >; &lt;strong>; City &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Shou &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot; is now publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Finance and Administration of Finance Administrative punishment information is included in real time, and artificial verification is performed simultaneously, with a completeness and accuracy of 100%. Researchers in the New Financial Research Center in the Southern Weekend Weekend found the data mining analysis of the &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; found that from July to September 2023, the above-mentioned institutions released a total of 3203 penalties, and 1105 institutions and 2881 individuals were fined; the fines were 14.531 billion yuan, and 53 people were banned for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ZIEVFHMKUT9WGCy2YMSKXBZ5DV3.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 658 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zun9IEVFHMKUT9WGCY2YMSKXBZ5DV3.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259083 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vrozcrgkz8portvg7g7h34qotmyotuiq.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;831&quot; height = &quot;1045&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/3vrozcrgkz8porjrm0b7G7HOTMYOTMYOTMYOTUIQ.PNG&quot; Data-KE y = &quot;259084&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Which regulatory agency has the largest amount of fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to statistics, the amount of fines issued by the General Office and the General Administration of HKMA is the largest, over 6.25 billion yuan. From the perspective of the dispatch agency, the amount of fines of the Guangdong sent institutions of the two institutions ranked first in 31 provinces and cities, reaching 3.717 billion yuan; It was 554 million yuan and 553 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/oiaaeko0fuznhyqadlxwideri8fwgddoeh6uq.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/oiaaeko0fuznhyqadlxwideri8fwgddoeh6uq.png.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259085 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Number of Shadow Penalty Institutions &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; The most &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Many &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Which region is the largest number of penalties? The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that from the perspective of the region, the number of penalties in Shandong sent institutions in the two institutions of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the General Administration of HKMA is top -ranked, and it is far exceeding the second Shanxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bldnlvoexmdojtlx20v5w4kwuv8HEQAD9O.PNG&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bldnlvoExmdojtlx20v5W4kwuv8Heqad9o.pn g &quot;data-key =&quot; 259086 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; The top two of the financial institutions are consistent with the &quot;Total List of the Third quarter of the third quarter of 2023&quot;. strong>;. &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wllzlx5v528kag46g6dnqwzpfxmim.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 669 &quot;Height =&quot; 1396 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wllzlx5v528Tyu0kag46A2T8M6DNQ wzpfxmim.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259087 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In terms of industries, the top three of the number of tickets for banking institutions are Shandong, Jiangxi Province, and Henan Province. However, Guizhou&#39;s banking institutions were fined to the first of the provinces and cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/AZOLPTUV5KAZU0CTOJQIFOF3G5ornkthati4x.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/AZOLPTUVCTOJQIFOF3G5ornkthati4x.png &quot; data-key = &quot;259088&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkagzahy5xato9effl19rlzzejf0s5wms.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;669&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/k03283bkagzahy5XATO9EFFL19rlzzejfo0s5WMS.png&quot; Data- K ey = &quot;259089&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the insurance industry, &lt;SPAN>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; institutional ticket &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; institutional ticket amount &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Span>; all top the list. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgvsfgpsu2hrit8vnlapwidirbmezxxc.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;&quot; height = &quot;1396&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qgvsfgpsu2hrtbr2LAPWIDIR bmezxzxc.png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259090 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src =&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/cd7dkkap9dhnenikfmr2vn8kj6c159gbmqKyq &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;ST YLE = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 669 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/cd7dkkap9dhnenikfmr2vn8kj6c159gbmqkyq. png &quot;data-key =&quot; 259091 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; The highest penalty of third -party payments &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In all penalty financial institutions, which areas are the most institutions? &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Statistics found that among the 1105 institutions of the penalty, banks and insurance were 647 and 366, respectively, and were fined 585 million yuan and 78 million yuan, respectively. In terms of quantity composition, &lt;span>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; >; 1.4 billion, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 The list of financial convergence &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; announced 2 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 023 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; In the first half of the year &lt;/span>; The data is consistent, it is still the most bank and the insurance is second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the penalties in various fields in the third quarter were large compared with the first half of the year. In the third quarter, although the number of non -bank insurance financial institutions was fined only 15, the amount of penalties was as high as 9.82 billion yuan, far exceeding the banking and insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the 15 non -bank insurance financial institutions, 12 are third -party payment companies. Twelve third -party payment companies received a penalty of 9.77 billion yuan, accounting for 67.53%of all institutions&#39; fines. It is worth noting that in the top ten fines in the third quarter, the four fines are related to violating the management regulations of payment accounts. It can be seen that the field of payment is a concentrated area in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qomi7srkerjexw58fw1wutixdk6coac1ymjloc.png&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 1205 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/qomi7srkerjexw58fw1wutixdk6coac1ymjloc.png &quot;d ata-key = &quot;259092&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; The sky -high price fines in the field of third -party payment are the two major platforms of &quot;Ant Department&quot; and &quot;Tencent&quot;. The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that of the top ten fines and ten personal tickets in the third quarter, the &quot;Ant Department&quot; and &quot;Tencent&quot; enterprises and the person in charge of the payment business or department manager were on the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1sRguy5p3fwfsr9nav5ihdp9s4xmszyczxjl.png&quot; 0 &quot;STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 831 &quot;Height =&quot; 391 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/1sRguy5p3fwfsr9NAV5IHDP9S4XMSZYCZXJL.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259094 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wg5hi1uoyhmbcx208jnrn3s8dehetav7e6mwjnes.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;831&quot; Height = &quot;294&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/wg5hi1uoyhmbcx208jnrn3s8dehetav7e6mwjnes.png&quot; Data- K ey = &quot;259095&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; The largest number of agencies of the Rural Commercial Bank &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In the banking industry with the largest number of fines, a total of 192 state -owned banks and joint -stock banks and branches have a fine of nearly 238 million yuan. , Accounting for 40.6%of the banking industry; Agricultural Commercial Bank, City Commercial Bank, Rural Credit Co., Ltd., village and township banks, private banks and rural cooperative banks, a total of 327 million yuan, accounting for 55.94%of the bank industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among them, the number of fined and fined by the Rural Commercial Bank exceeded the state -owned bank, becoming a prominent phenomenon in the third quarter. The &quot;Sheep Dog Platform&quot; shows that there are up to 206 rural commercial banks received by the ticket, with a total of 140 million yuan, which is higher than 119 and 97.54 million yuan.而在&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;amp;source_1=255993&quot;>;&lt;u>;《半年罚没金额&lt;/u>;&lt;u>;14亿， The top three banks in the three banks &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; The number of agricultural and commercial banks&#39; penalty institutions and the amount of penalties are approaching state -owned banks. This shows that the degree of compliance of the Rural Commercial Bank has always been at a lower level, and there is a growth trend in violation of regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zdjeuxu1NPGKSMYLKJ9TeqrfjmdivixFgwyer.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;width =&quot; 811 &quot;height =&quot; 1396 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/zdjeuxu1NPGKSMYLX5RFJMDIXFGWYER.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259093 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bnuzxmpjx1sst1zlydhgmwiaupb4wq9iiegm.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;811&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/bnuzx0x1zwlydhgmwiaupb4wq9iegm.png&quot; data-k &quot; ey = &quot;259096&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For a single bank&#39;s penalties, joint -stock banks and state -owned banks still have the top three. Ping An Bank, Minsheng Bank and Postal Savings Bank ranks in the top three. Among the three banks, except for the penalty of Minsheng Bank for loan violations, the penalties of the other two banks involved &quot;the obligation to not perform customer identity in accordance with regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the statistics of the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;, the number of bank penalties information involved in &quot;illegal use of identity information&quot; or &quot;trading with unknown customers&quot; in the third quarter, a total of 164 pieces of bank penalties, with a total penalty amount of 142 million Yuan, accounting for 24.3%of the bank&#39;s penalty for the number of bank institutions in the third quarter. The number of loans of violations reached 325, and the total penalty was 280 million yuan, accounting for 47.9%of the bank institutions&#39; penalties in the third quarter. This shows that these two major issues are more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/abp2zaqcf5tu1zvyqymgiailhpoli.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 831 &quot;Height =&quot; 1345 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/abp2zaqcf5tuzvyqymgiailhplfoli.pn g &quot;data-key =&quot; 259097 &quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Property Insurance &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Institution &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Quantity of being fined &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Still the most &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;/strongRongG>; >; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Compared with the banking industry, the insurance industry&#39;s fined amount and quantity are lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the third quarter of 2023, the punishment of the insurance industry and the &lt;span>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/Contents/254429?source=101&amp;MP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; &quot;There is no amount for half a year of penalty &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; 1.4 billion, the three banks&quot; take &quot;the top three 丨 finance rules list &lt;/u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; announced In the first half of 2023, the insurance industry was penalized. Regardless of whether it is a comprehensive insurance group or other insurance companies, the number of property insurance institutions has the largest number and the largest amount of fined. A total of 113 property insurance companies under the comprehensive insurance group of punishment groups, with a total fine of 32.463 million yuan; 65 other property insurance companies were punished with a fine of 18.04 million yuan. Life insurance business followed closely. The number of life insurance companies of comprehensive insurance groups was fined 88, with a fine of 10.968 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fotzzz5coifywxocubnavrhlk6pdfg.png&quot; Border = &quot;0&quot; STY le = &quot;OPACITY: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 831 &quot;height =&quot; 1167 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/q9fotzzz5qqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqqcoCSNAVRF6PDFG.PNG.PNG.PNG.PNG &quot;data-key =&quot; 259098 &quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/lhus1FF1UBXCTDLZSFU6U4TWU5RRKZIIWYYF.PNG&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot; &quot;OPACITY: 1;&quot; Width = &quot;811&quot; Height = &quot;1396&quot; Data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21FF1FF1UBXCTDLZSFU6U4TWU5RRKZIIWYYYYYYYYYYY ey = &quot;259099&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared to &lt;aver>; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; &quot;There is no amount of fine fine &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; 1.4 billion, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 Financial Formation List &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; The insurance company&#39;s fined amount list in the first half of 2023, Chinese Insurance And China Life is still the top three of the list, while Ping An of China is the sixth place in the list. Although the business scale and the number of institutions in China, China Life, and Ping An of China are relatively large, the amount of Ping An of Ping An is much lower than the fined amount of the previous two. It can be seen that in the third quarter, the degree of Ping An compliance in China improved compared to the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/md7yrkeyfarkmezmvartib6mabzwo20ajws.png&quot; 0 &quot;style =&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot;Opacity: 1; 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 791 &quot;Height =&quot; 1396 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/md7yrkeyfarkmezmvartib6MABZWO20AJWS.PNG &quot;&quot; data-key = &quot;259100&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; According to statistics from the &quot;Shepherd Dog Platform&quot;, in the third quarter of 2023, there were 199 penalties involved in providing false information among 384 insurance companies, with a total fine of 52.137 million yuan, accounting for all insurance companies. 66.66%of the total fine. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Do not touch the red line &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Do not step on the bottom line &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In summary, it can be seen in the third quarter finance The violations of banks are mainly concentrated in the three areas of payment field, loan business and fictional documents. The latter two are both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/Contents/254429?source=101&amp;AMP ;Source_1=255993&quot;>; &lt;u>; 100 million, the top three banks in the three banks 丨 The list of financial convergence &lt;/u>; &lt;u>; &lt;/u>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; mentioned 2 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 023 &lt; /span>; &lt;span>; Focusing on the rules of the first half of the year &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; field &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, it is also the &quot;old problem&quot; of the banking and insurance industry. Each financial institution urgently needs to cure &quot;old faults&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; third party &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Payment &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; The industry&#39;s highlights &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; and online payment business &lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;span>; Fast &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Development &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; and &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Platform enterprise financial innovation. Online &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; third party &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Payment &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; brings great convenience for people &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; At the same time &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, also &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; illegal elements &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; &quot;Drilling the money&quot; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;span>; channel &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Researchers at the New Financial Research Center of the Southern Weekend suggested that when financial institutions and platform enterprises are carried out, they must consider both innovation and inclusiveness, and always pay attention to regulatory policies. Touch the red line and don&#39;t step on the bottom line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (All drawing of this article: Feng Qingchao) &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; &lt;br>; href = &quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[控诉菊花被偷采之后：公安出警、村干部下田维持秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261037]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum land, some tourists are picking flowers. &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/a2f4d2c512.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1197&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images .infzm.com/CMS/Medias/Image/23/11/21/A2F4D2C512.JPEG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 259064 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;&quot; >; Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum field, some tourists are picking flowers. Interviewees confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; mid-November 2023, when the chrysanthemum was bloomed, a chrysanthemum farm in Nanyang City, Henan Province advocated a bright release video, saying that it was planted by home. Four or five hundred acres of chrysanthemums are picked and stolen every day. In the video he posted, three people were picking chrysanthemums in the ground. Zhang Liang pretended to be a passerby to the person who picked the chrysanthemums of the semi -plastic bag and asked: &quot;This pick is also a lot of miles. ? &quot;The other party replied:&quot; Pick a little less, pick and pick. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; On November 19, 26-year-old Zhang Liang told the Southern Weekend reporter that he was heeletes that he was The villagers of Zhang Xiuyuzhuang, a Zhang Xiuyuzhuang in Qinghe Town, Qinghe Town, Qinghe Town, Nanyang City. In 2017, they began to contracted land to plant chrysanthemums near home to process chrysanthemum tea. It is currently the time of chrysanthemum opening and harvest. Zhang Liang said that there are dozens of stolen every day, &quot;hundreds of pounds of loss every day, like the drone shouted and scolded last year, and people couldn&#39;t get away, which caused a lot of losses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Video shot by Zhang Liang quickly caused controversy. Two days later, Zhang Liang deleted the video. He explained: &quot;Some netizens think that I have discredited Henan people, so I delete the video and have nothing to do with anyone.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Lost the face of Henan people&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p stylele = &quot;Text-Align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Liang introduced, the main crops of the Fang &lt;SPAN>; City &lt;/span>; county are wheat and corn. In 2017, &quot;Seeing other people planted chrysanthemums, the profit point was relatively high at that time, and it was planted.&quot; In July 2021, Zhang Liang established Fang &lt;SPAN>; City &lt;/span>; County Yicheng Family Farm. Golden Emperor Chrysanthemum, Wuyuan Huangju, Little Emperor Chrysanthemum and other chrysanthemums, the annual income depends on the market. The market is good and can sell more. &quot;But the market is not good in the past two years.&quot; Chrysanthemum is always taking care of Zhang Liang&#39;s parents. Zhang Liang, who worked outside the farmer when he was busy, would also go home to help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Liang recalled that when the chrysanthemum was planted from the first year, someone came to the ground to see flowers. At the time, because there were fewer chrysanthemums in large areas, many people were fresh. Zhang Liang said that most of the people around the chrysanthemums are surrounding people, almost all of them are raw faces. There are more people on weekends, but he cannot estimate how many people are. Small snacks such as sugarcane juice are set up nearby. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There are many people who see flowers, and the situation of climbing and picking chrysanthemums will appear at will. In the previous videos, Zhang Liang said that there were dozens of chrysanthemums every day every day. He had previously surrounded the fence at the main intersection, but &quot;stopped the gentleman not stopped the villain.&quot; He told the southern weekend reporter that in 2022, he reported the police because of stealing chrysanthemums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Liang believes that so many people in their chrysanthemum land are inseparable from the &quot;publicity&quot; of some local media bloggers. Those who made small videos, they passed ten, ten passes. &quot; In the online world, Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum land has a name. It is called &quot;Fang &lt;SPAN>; City &lt;/span>; Qinghe Chrysanthemum Garden&quot;, and hundreds of acres of chrysanthemum gardens are also exaggerated as &quot;thousands of acres&quot; and &quot;10,000 acres&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A blogger named &quot;Xie Er&quot; has recommended Zhang Liang&#39;s chrysanthemum land on November 12. There is a piece of chrysanthemum at the door of the house, and no money is needed. &quot;An employee of the&quot; Xie Lao Er &quot;account told the southern weekend that&quot; Xie Lao &quot;is a tour guide, and the usual account will be sent to the beautiful scenery in various places. &quot;Let others know where to play.&quot; After the videos of picking chrysanthemums caused controversy, the &quot;Xie Lao Er&quot; comment area was not quite flat. Some netizens accused him of &quot;the harm of others was miserable.&quot; &quot;Xie Lao&quot; declined the interview with the reporter from the Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The above employees told the southern weekend reporter that she felt that &quot;Xie&#39;s second&quot; did not guide everyone to pick the flowers. Tell others to see it. Just there are a lot of other people picking flowers, and there are still many people with quality &quot;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; At the end of the recommendation video of &quot;Xie&#39;s second&quot;, he emphasized to tourists that &quot;do not pick up the chrysanthemums of others, cherish the results of others, and do not step on the ground.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As Nanyang, the above employees believe that there are people who can pick others at will, &quot;not just say that there are people in Henan.&quot; After learning about the news, she was even more angry, and those unconscious people &quot;lost the face of Henan people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;A tourist squatting on the ground and picking chrysanthemums. The interviewee&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /21/89e2fbf9bc.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 1080 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/Image/23/11/89E2FBF9BC.JPEG &quot;Data-key =&quot; 259065 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; A tourist squatting on the ground picking chrysanthemums. The interviewees confessed &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Picking flowers exist, but there are very few&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Zhang Liang thinks it is the face he lost for Henan people, given to People in Henan wiped out black. &quot;As a Henan, I should add glory to Henan people. As a result, I did not expect (passing the video online) will cause so many adverse effects.&quot; Zhang Liang explained that only the people who saw the flowers took the flowers. It did not cause serious economic losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 18, Zhang Liang released a clarified video. &quot;The purpose of my video is to persuade everyone It will cause such a big misunderstanding. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In an interview with a reporter from the Southern Weekend, Zhang Liang repeated the attitude. Sometimes he admitted that all this was his personal fault. /span>; Sometimes I am full of anger: &quot;I&#39;m telling the truth, sometimes I really don&#39;t want to speak conscience, I am right.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-alft;&quot;>; Zhang Liang&#39;s attitude is also vague. Sometimes he feels that &quot;people are running so far, they are fresh, there is nothing to pick up.&quot; &lt;Span>;, &lt;/span>; sometimes feel that &quot;someone should not pick it up, this is my private property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the evening of November 19th, a staff member of the Propaganda Department of the County Party Committee told the reporter of the Southern Weekend, &quot;Either the local government, It is impossible for us to put pressure on people&#39;s propaganda departments. But the local government saw the video as soon as possible. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-alft; &quot;>;工作人员称：“他们这块地，是一个集观光、采摘、加工销售为一体的基地。周末或是天气好的时候，会有游客到那打卡，只不过个别市民有一些不文明行为，比如If you want your children to smell the fragrance, or have a lot of thoughts, there are individual, very few people who will pick people&#39;s chrysanthemums. This does exist, but it must be very small. >; City &lt;/span>; Millions of people in the county are so unqualified, impossible, no existence of robbing or stealing. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; After the incident, the local public security has been involved, and the police force to the chrysanthemum land to maintain order. &quot;The local government has asked the village cadres and party members and cadres in the village to walk into the field and inform citizens who go to sightseeing and punch in. They can be punched here, but they cannot be picked or stepped into the house. It is necessary to ensure that the chrysanthemums contracted by the farmers are not lost. This is the most important. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Zhang Liang has denied that his chrysanthemum land can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Selands&quot; or &quot;picking up&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Stealing chrysanthemum incident is not a case. Reporters from the southern weekend sort out and found that during the 2023 autumn harvest stage, there were many crazy incidents. On October 3, many fans of the Nanyang Music Festival were stolen; on October 14, &quot;100 acres of corn fields were robbed by more than 100 people&quot; in Dancheng County, Zhoukou City; on October 31, Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City &quot;Hundreds of people grabbing medicinal materials&quot; incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 19th, Qiu Jun, the party of &quot;hundreds of people grabbing medicinal materials&quot;, recalled in an interview with the southern weekend reporter that on the afternoon of October 31, the machine was underway. In the second time the medicinal materials were harvested, when the receipt of two -thirds, the machine failed to work. At that time, Tianbian had surrounded one or two hundred people, mostly older old people. After the machine could not be harvested, some villagers picked up. Later, there were more and more people. Qiu Jun and he hired more than 20 people who hired &lt;/span>; to dissuade invalidation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Qiu Jun is a large Chinese medicine atractylum planting household in Dailou Village, Fengtang Township, Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City. This year is the sixth year of his planting.习惯，上百亩地里会剩余一两千斤机器无法收割到的白术供村民捡拾。事件发生后，邱军感到心里不舒服，但又无力劝阻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;邱军告诉南方周末记者，该事件被媒体报道后，当地民警共追回约八百斤白术，村干部也挨家挨户教育村民， “人家不让你进地，你进，说好听了你去捡，说不好听你这就是抢。”村里的喇叭也广播，教育大家“这种捡拾行为是不好的行为，违反了法律” . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;回过头再看这件事，邱军认为“也不能怪老百姓”，捡拾的村民都是年纪大的老人，好多都是文盲，也不懂法律，他们觉得这个东西掉在地里就能捡。对于该事件在网上引起的舆论，邱军认为对当地的名声影响很不好，采访中，他不断纠正记者的措辞，将“哄抢”改为“捡拾”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京德和衡（广州）律师事务所高级合伙人赵绍华担心，这种处理方式可能使大多数违法者认为他们的行为不会受到处罚，助长违法行为，使得更多的种植户遭受损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵绍华坦言，对于此类未经农户同意擅自攀折、采摘他人农作物的行为，定性为违法行为仍有难度。首先是证据的固定和收集难，因大面积的农作物种植场一般在郊区，场地面积大，难以直接固定和收集行为人攀折、采摘的直接行为，往往是事后发现农作物被毁损；主观认定上也难，因部分农村地区确有允许本地村民在种植场内捡拾收割后遗留的少量或残次农作物的习惯，对此在法律评价层面，&lt;span>;判断&lt;/span>;行为人是否具有非法占有的主观目的存在难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;赵绍华建议，在农村地区执法要突破“法不责众”的错误认识。 “像有的偷盗、哄抢农作物达到法定的程度，就应该严格依法采取执法行动，而不是继续依&#39;习惯&#39;来模糊处理解决。要让当地村民知道，偷盗、哄抢或破坏他人财物将依法被追究法律责任，法不责众不会成为任何人的保护伞”&lt;span>;，&lt;/span>;同时，也需要加强农村社会的普法工作，包括产权意识、物权意识，特别是向村民普及《中华人民共和国民法典》物权编关于土地承包经营权的专项规定，向村民讲解刑法和治安管理处罚法的相关规定，告知村民其行为是违法的，是要受到处罚的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，张亮、邱军为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 08:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么晚清的改良派、维新派、革命派都推崇黄宗羲？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260980]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxRmek3qIAAc6Lhq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5pv15XwHBkkf38072k6Eaaw9rxRmek3qIAAc6Lhq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郑观应（前排中）为《原君·原臣》小册子写了introduction. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1895年秋第一次广州起义失败，孙中山流亡日本，在横滨发展兴中会组织，文经商店东主冯镜如出任横滨兴中会首任会长，其子冯自由年仅14岁，亦加入为会员。 Zheng Guanying&#39;s &quot;Yuan Jun · Yuanchen&quot; booklet, which was copied and prefaced, was printed by Hengbinwen through the store. Feng Free&#39;s &quot;Revolutionary History&quot; said: &quot;There are only two propaganda materials of the Shixing Middle School: one for&quot; Yangzhou Ten Diary &quot;, and at the end of the article, the Qing regent Wang Doru and the Ming Pavilion Department Shi Kefa resumed the second book; the second为黄梨洲《明夷待访录》选本之《原君·原臣》篇。均由余店代为印刷。”冯自由又言：“兴中会初期，文人墨士极感缺乏，所用宣传工具，仅有《扬州十日记》《嘉定屠城记》，及选录《明夷待访录》内《原君》《原臣》数种。”1896年，清廷驻旧金山总领事派人潜入孙中山住处偷窥，随后报告称“查阅该犯书册两本，一系摘录明黄梨洲《明夷待访录》中《原君》《原臣》二篇，卷端加一小引，自称杞忧公子”。 1897年6 月，孙中山在英国时，将《原君·原臣》小册子赠送给日本友人南方熊楠。 《原君·原臣》为黄宗羲《明夷待访录》中《原君》《原臣》两篇的节钞本，1895年冬在日本印刷，卷前有“杞忧公子”撰写的小引：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从来天生民而立之君长，所以为民役者也，君一人不能独治万几，于是建设臣工以分治之，凡佐君为民役者也。孟子曰:“民为贵，社稷次之，君为轻。”此千古之通义，先觉言之，后世讳之，皆未知君臣之义，悉为治民而生。苟大地孑孑无生民，又何从有君？又何从有臣工哉？惟不知立君之为民，故一人晏安，百姓失所；惟不知立臣之亦为民，故百僚阿顺，损下益上。呜乎! 此其弊，人人心非之而人人不能深知之、明言之，陵夷以至于今天，心之所深恫也。唯有明黄梨洲先生，家传忠孝，卓荦能文章，高瞻远识，超越千古。尝著《明夷待访录》一编，附托于箕子之蒙难艰贞。内有《原君》《原臣》二论，尤足握全书之要，垂万世之谟。爰摘录印行，希以启迪后生小子之蒙，而张中国自强之本。孔子云:“知我者其惟《春秋》乎，罪我者其惟《春秋》乎？”窃遵斯旨，以告夫当世之有心富强者。乙未立夏，杞忧公子小引。 &lt;/span>;（转引自孙卫华《〈原君原臣〉小引作者考》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“杞忧公子”是谁，学界有王韬、孙中山等不同说法，小野和子、李敖认为是郑观应。中南民族大学孙卫华作了深入考证，从郑观应《盛世危言》内容、早年著作《易言》使用“杞忧生”笔名等，认定作者即郑观应，论证有力。笔者检索《申报》发现，郑观应还用过“铁城杞忧生”笔名发表诗作，“铁城”为香山县城石岐别称。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王韬曾为郑观应《易言》作跋：“杞忧生不知其何许人也，继乃知其居铁城，氏荥阳，足迹遍南北，而旅处沪渎最久。其地为冠盖之往来，商贾所辐辏，杞忧生居其间，不仕不隐，亦吏亦儒。日交其贤豪长者，而与之纵谈天下事，时或慷慨泣下，击碎唾壶。今湘乡郭筠仙侍郎、吴川陈荔秋司宪皆赏识之，屡欲加以拂拭，拟招佐星轺以备谘访，而杞忧生悉坚辞弗往，日惟寄情缃素，肆志林泉，慨慕黄、虞，读书自娱而已。”熟悉王韬、郑观应的学者不难发现，小引行文风格跟《盛世危言》十分相似，厚重而略显笨拙，与王韬跌宕有节奏的老练文风迥然不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1894年郑观应为孙中山上书李鸿章奔走出力，在孙中山“造反”之后，郑观应销毁了两人密切接触的资料。据易惠莉的研究，1895年秋孙中山发动广州起义之前，“郑观应5、6月间在广东”，光绪帝要求刷印《盛世危言》二千部的消息“促使郑观应中断在广东的活动返回上海&quot;.这个时间，跟小引落款时间“乙未立夏”（1895年5月6日）吻合。大胆一点猜测，郑观应将节抄本《原君·原臣》连同小引交给了孙中山。孙中山流亡日本后，将书稿交冯镜如出版。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《原君》《原臣》两名篇，出自黄宗羲《明夷待访录》。 《原君》批判君主“以我之大私为天下之大公”“为天下之大害”，《原臣》指出臣子的责任是“为天下，非为君也；为万民，非为一姓also&quot;.两名篇所阐述的民主思想，很适合孙中山用来批判清廷，也切合激进改良派、维新党人的需要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1895—1898年间，康有为与郑观应有过深度合作。 1895年12月1日，郑观应致函王韬：“康长素主政奉南皮命到沪，设立强学书局，约弟午后两点钟同谒先生……”郑观应曾陪康有为拜访王韬。郑观应也是强学书局主要负责人之一，他的作用被康梁有意淡化了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超后来在《中国近三百年学术史》中评论《明夷待访录》称：“光绪间，我们一班朋友曾私印许多送人，作为宣传民主主义的工具。”在《清代学术概论》一书中，梁启超又言：“梁启超、谭嗣同辈倡民权共和之说，则将其节抄，印数万本，秘密散布，于晚清思想之骤变，极有力焉。”俞国林为中华书局新版《清代学术概论》撰写长篇《校订说明》，即指出“节录《明夷待访录》之《原君》《原臣》两篇，印成小册宣传者，实为杞忧公子”“此节本实为革命派之宣传工具也”。梁氏只提《明夷待访录》而不点出《原君》《原臣》，或是有意为之。戊戌政变前，在与日本志士宫崎寅藏（宫崎滔天）的笔谈中，孙中山说他跟梁启超之间有一套“秘语”，相互通信不怕泄密：“弟近欲发信上海，请梁启超或其亲信一人到此一游。”这说明孙、梁之间早有联系，不是梁启超流亡日本之后才开始交往。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超、孙中山共用郑观应编篡的《原君·原臣》小册子作宣传工具，揭示有些历史人物的派系归属，并没有想象中那么固定。晚清投身革命的知识分子，或多或少都经历过“改良”阶段，孙中山上书李鸿章就是最好的证明；梁启超一度倾向革命排满；郑观应未必就没有“革命”的想法，只是不便公开。黄宗羲《原君》《原臣》名篇，可为各派进步势力所共用，也表明在甲午战争爆发后一段时间，进步势力还没有找到合适的舆论武器，黄宗羲的雄文是最“趁手”的宣传工具，革命派用来宣传革命排满，激进改良派、维新派以此宣传改革的迫切性。黄宗羲的历史地位在晚清突然提升，有利于宣传排满、虚君共和，但若说《明夷待访录》对郑观应、孙中山有思想启蒙作用，则又过于溢美，毕竟这两人能直接阅读英文著作，他们接触到的思想比黄宗羲更加有力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（原标题为“《原君·原臣》：郑观应、梁启超、孙中山的共享文本”，现标题为编者所拟）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女足的跌宕与辉煌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261025]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;11月20日下午，中国足协官宣：水庆霞不再担任中国女足主教练，原因是女足未能获得巴黎奥运会参赛资格。2021年11月，水庆霞临危受命，在两年时间里与中国女足共担风雨彩虹。她们带来胜利和希望，时隔16年后再夺亚洲杯冠军。她们也带来失利甚至绝望，亚运会无缘决赛、世界杯1：6惨败英格兰。走过风雨、见过风浪，期待铿锵玫瑰再绽放。</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[青岛等大城市推行“租房入户”：实质上的迁徙自由意味着什么？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261018]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，青岛市发布通知，放宽居住落户政策。 The notice stipulates that persons who live in urban leased houses and handle lease contracts and residential registration shall be applied for collective households during the housing leasing period in Qingdao who have no legal property houses in Qingdao.一言以蔽之，可租房入户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据官方数据，截至2022年末，青岛市常住人口1034.21万人，其中市区人口740.61万人；2022年全市生产总值14920.75亿元。 Entry in Qingdao is attractive for many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛并不是第一座推行租房入户的大城市。 Earlier, many big cities such as Jinan, Suzhou, and Zhengzhou have issued similar policies, showing that the competition of large cities has entered a new stage.相对于积分入户、技能入户、学历入户、购房入户等各种方式，租房入户大城市可以说是成本与门槛最低的，近乎已经没有门槛了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了一些大城市（即所谓的超大城市与特大城市）之外，中小城市早已放开了入户限制，不过并没有见到哪个中小城市人口数量因此出现井喷。说到底，人口的流向从来不是按照层级规格逐次往上爬的，并不是说村里的到镇里、镇里的到县里、县里的到市里、市里的到省会，而是无论来自村里、镇里、县里还是市里，大家都争相往大城市、向一线城市涌，去那里寻找更好的机会、建立新的生活，这就是“大城市化”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大城市也需要不断补充新鲜血液。某种程度上，大城市存有一个内在的悖论：一方面，它在高度压缩的空间里创造了商业与文明的奇迹，一眼望不到边的摩天大楼、车水马龙的街道、熙熙攘攘的人群、琳琅满目的商品、丰富多彩的文艺，显得生机勃勃；但另一方面，大城市往往都处于超低生育率现状之中，没有能力再生产出这座城市所需要的新生儿与年轻人规模，如果没有外来人口持续补充，任何一座大城市都难以为继。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这个意义上，大城市为了吸引人口净流入而出台的种种措施，事关它的命运与未来。从术的角度看，人来了，会租房或买房，会工作挣钱纳税缴社保，会消费，会结婚养孩子，会在孩子教育上花钱，养活自己与家人的同时，给城市创造了价值：让其他人挣到了钱，让政府有了财政收入，让退休者有养老金可领。从道的角度看，大城市就是一个超有机体，每一个新来的人就是一个新生的细胞，消耗了自我，延续与维持了大城市的生机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最理想的情况，是户籍淡化到没有存在感乃至不存在。一个人搬到一座城市，有了新的住处，找了一份新工作，稳定居住了一段时间后就自然而然成为这座城市的居民，通过身份登记确认这个事实就行了。户是家庭，家安在哪里，就注册登记在哪里，户籍是对家庭的注册登记，这是户籍的本来含义。而在有了市民身份登记后，户籍在某种程度上是叠床架屋、多此一举，与身份登记确认的是同一个事实。至于纳税时限或数额达到多少才拥有当地提供的福利，是另一回事，逻辑上完全可以和某座城市的居民身份或户籍相剥离。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，诸多大城市不断放宽入户门槛，其实就是朝着淡化、弱化户籍的方向不断在迈进。青岛等大城市推行“租房入户”，对稳定工作没有要求，对学历、技能乃至财产都没有要求，想来就来，想来定居悉听君便，实质上已是迁徙自由，户籍已经等同于城市居民身份确认的书面凭证，入户已经等同于城市居民身份登记的例行手续。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一个（尤其是过去）导致大城市户籍制度坚挺的因素是附着在户籍上的管控。如房市繁荣期推出的房产限购政策。不过，随着房市走弱，此类管制呈涣然冰释之势，就算是某些一线城市，限购也已羞答答在郊区县放开了。又如一线城市以治理拥堵与环保名义的汽车购置管制，北京实行的是摇号，上海是牌照拍卖，广州是两者兼而有之。以上海为例，除了本市户籍之外，目前持居住证且缴纳社保或个税达一定年限者也可参加竞拍，这本身就是与户籍的某种脱钩。所以，从趋势上看不构成阻碍户籍弱化的因素。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体上，大城市是户籍制度最后的堡垒，这些地方淡化、弱化户籍，人口自由流动最后的障碍也就趋于消失。当然，反过来，理论上谁都可以来，并不等于谁都会来、谁都能来。能否在一座城市生存下来，是要看个人实力的，要么你有一技之长，或至少肯吃苦肯干，要么你家底雄厚，并没有纯吃福利、纯寄生的通道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人口实质上自由流动，还会促成一个不可避免的结果，令某些地方的“本地人”反中考移民、高考移民的努力变得没有意义。因为“外地人”要成为“本地人”没有门槛，来了能定居下来的都是“本地人”，再也没法通过户籍建立森严的区隔与屏障，所以在高中与大学录取中有名额优势的地方，所谓的优势会很快被熨平，就像热量会从高温部分流向低温部分，势所必然，导向一种自然而然的均衡或曰“教育公平”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人口第一大县关停50所幼儿园 学前教育普及普惠考验保障能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261031]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Linquan County, Fuyang City, Anhui Province is the most populous county in China, with a registered population of 2.293 million in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August this year, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens would cease operations, accounting for 11.8% of the total number of kindergartens in the county in 2022 and 24.5% of the total number of private kindergartens in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, with the decrease in the number of births, the number of kindergartens and the number of kindergarten students in the country has decreased. In 2022, the total number of kindergartens nationwide will decrease by 5,610 compared with the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, news of large-scale closure of kindergartens has spread in many places. After the annual inspection of private kindergartens in Haikou ended recently, a total of 33 kindergartens were suspended, accounting for 6.4% of the total number of private kindergartens in the country; in September this year, 17 kindergartens in Longhai District, Zhangzhou City were terminated, accounting for 7.8% of the total number of kindergartens in the district in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts believe that the number and number of kindergartens may decrease at an accelerated pace in 2023. While the demographic dividend is declining, it has provided an opportunity to adjust the layout of preschool education and promote universal and inclusive development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National County Preschool Education Popularization Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference was held recently. The 21st Century Business Herald learned that the information at the meeting showed that the popularity rate of preschool education in some places has increased significantly. The next step for supervision and evaluation is to Adhere to problem orientation and accurately grasp key points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the school-age population has been significantly reduced, it will still be a medium- to long-term process for preschool education to reach universal standards. The crux of the problem is that kindergarten teachers have low incomes and large salary gaps, which urgently require local governments to increase financial security. intensity. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kindergarten closures continue&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Data from the Linquan County Government in February this year showed that there were 58,243 children in kindergarten in the county in 2023, a 9.2% decrease from the previous year. It decreased in the fourth year, and the decline suddenly increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from 2019 to 2022, the number of kindergartens in Linquan County was 377, 422, 425, and 425 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August this year, the Linquan County Education Bureau issued an announcement that 50 local private kindergartens would cease operations. Among them, 12 private kindergartens applied to terminate their operations, 38 private kindergartens had no actual enrollment or school operation, and their school operating licenses had expired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that many of the 12 kindergartens that applied to terminate their operations have only been registered since 2021, and the latest of them was registered in June 2022. It was closed just one year after opening, which shows that the student supply situation of local kindergartens is tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The large-scale closure of kindergartens does not only occur in Linquan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, 17 private kindergartens in Longhai District, Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province applied to terminate their operations. In November, the results of the 2023 annual inspection of private primary and secondary schools and kindergartens in Haikou City were released, and 33 private kindergartens were suspended. Recently, six kindergartens in Ruian City under the jurisdiction of Wenzhou City have ceased operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts predict that the number and number of kindergartens will further decrease. On the one hand, it is due to the continued decrease in the number of births in recent years, and on the other hand, the gross enrollment rate in kindergartens has reached a high level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the national gross enrollment rate for preschool education will be 89.7%, but it is close to or reaching 100% in many places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Linquan County has reached 96.57% in 2022, and Anhui Province has reached 98.2% in 2022. Data released by the Henan Provincial Department of Education on November 14 show that the current gross enrollment rate of preschool education in the province is 91.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that preschool education degrees in various places will face overall saturation, with a surplus in rural areas and a shortage in urban areas. Taking Linquan County as an example, 37 of the 50 kindergartens closed were rural kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poses new challenges to kindergarten layout. Kindergarten children are too young to be suitable for boarding, so rural kindergartens cannot be blindly withdrawn and merged, but the retained kindergartens need to meet specified standards. Too few rural students will make it difficult to operate high-standard kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some places are cracking down on planning. Shandong Province issued a document in August this year to optimize the layout of rural primary and secondary kindergartens and clarify planning and layout requirements in terms of school-age population, enrollment radius, and regional coordination. On November 7, the Shandong Provincial Department of Education began soliciting opinions on the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Comprehensively Promoting the Integrated Management of Kindergarten Towns and Villages&quot;. This document proposed that when counties (cities, districts) prepare overall kindergarten layout plans, they should simultaneously clarify the kindergartens in each town and town. Layout, in accordance with the requirements for promoting integrated management of towns and villages, clarify the establishment and construction of the central park and branch parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total number of rural kindergartens has decreased. In fact, the decrease is greater than the increase. In October this year, Linquan County approved the construction of three more rural kindergartens to meet the kindergarten admission needs of different regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are great differences in the development of universal and inclusive education in various regions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reduction in the number of kindergartens and the number of children has provided an opportunity for the universal and inclusive development of preschool education. After all, limited resources can be more fully allocated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 10, the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference was held in Jinan City, Shandong Province. The meeting emphasized that we should steadily carry out supervision and evaluation work on universal preschool education in counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carrying out supervision and evaluation of universal preschool education in counties is a deployment made in the &quot;Several Opinions on Deepening Reform and Standardized Development of Preschool Education&quot; in November 2018. The Ministry of Education issued notices twice in 2020, clarifying Indicators and processes for supervision and evaluation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is another important educational supervision work carried out in the field of basic education in addition to the supervision and evaluation of the high-quality and balanced development of compulsory education in our country. The establishment of counties (cities, districts) must achieve &quot;quantity standards and quality standards&quot;. After two rounds of evaluation at the provincial and national levels, it was finally recognized as a national county for the universalization of preschool education in five aspects: &quot;qualified, well-guaranteed, sound system, and satisfied with the masses&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the national to the local level, special attention is paid to this work. In December 2020, an on-site meeting to launch the national accreditation of national pre-school education universalization and inclusiveness supervision and evaluation in counties was held in Chengdu, Sichuan Province. The then deputy director of the Ministry of Education attended the meeting, and the expert group gave feedback to Qingbaijiang District and Shuangliu District of Chengdu City, which applied for national assessment at that time. In March 2021, these two districts were the first in the country to be recognized as national pre-school education universal HP counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, no public information has disclosed the progress of national recognition. Until the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Work Promotion Conference was held on November 10. Vice Minister of Education Wang Jiayi attended the meeting, and the expert group fed back the supervision and evaluation opinions to the Shandong Provincial Department of Education. 21st Century Business Herald learned that more than 20 counties (cities, districts) in Shandong Province have applied for national assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the differences between regions are too large, and the assessment work will not be completed overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Sichuan Province took the lead in breaking through the national assessment in 2021, it proposed to achieve the entire region to pass the national assessment by 2030. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The economically developed eastern region is moving relatively quickly. For example, Zhejiang Province has proposed to complete the assessment and identification of more than 90% of counties (cities, districts) by 2025, and strives to complete all of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But even in Zhejiang, regional disparities are large. In terms of indicators, the &quot;quantity standards&quot; requirements such as the gross kindergarten enrollment rate in the three years of preschool, the coverage rate of inclusive kindergartens, and the proportion of children in public kindergartens are easy to achieve, and the regional differences are not large; the teachers are qualified, the conditions for running kindergartens are qualified, It is difficult to achieve &quot;qualified quality&quot; indicators such as qualified nursing and education, and there are large regional differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A questionnaire survey of 100,000 kindergarten principals and full-time teachers across the country showed that only 85.04% of teachers hold teacher qualification certificates, of which only 77.95% hold kindergarten teacher qualification certificates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person from an educational and scientific research institution in an economically developed prefecture-level city in Zhejiang Province told the 21st Century Business Herald that the number of kindergartens in the city is similar to that in Hangzhou, but the total number of children in the kindergarten is about 100,000 less than that in Hangzhou. This is This means that the average number of children in the city&#39;s kindergartens is small, mainly because the local rural kindergartens are &quot;low, small and scattered&quot; and the degree of group education is not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he also pointed out that “the assessment of graded kindergartens mainly examines hardware indicators such as houses, venues, and toys. The more important factors affecting the quality of childcare are actually teachers and childcare workers. In addition, rural kindergartens pay too much attention to hardware facilities. There are also questions about whether it is wasteful and whether it can adapt to future population changes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Adhere to a problem-oriented approach to strengthen supervision&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Teachers are the most important factor affecting the quality of preschool education, and they are also the biggest obstacle to universal education. factors that benefit development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference on November 10 required that all localities should adhere to a problem orientation, strengthen the number of kindergarten teachers with qualified qualifications, &quot;equal pay for equal work&quot; for both staff and non-staff teachers in public kindergartens, and pay for teaching staff Supervision on issues such as &quot;five insurances and one housing fund&quot;, safe and hygienic food in kindergartens. Regarding teachers’ requirements, “four accounted for three.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A kindergarten teacher in Linquan County told the 21st Century Business Herald that local kindergartens still have large class sizes because there is a shortage of kindergarten teachers. The shortage of teachers is mainly due to low salary and limited attractiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My monthly salary is about 3,000 yuan.” The above-mentioned kindergarten teacher said, “Whether there is a staff establishment or not has a great impact on the income of kindergarten teachers. Teachers on staff are paid very well, and all the benefits combined can reach 3,000 yuan per year. 70,000 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coordinating the number of kindergarten teachers is the key to ensuring teachers&#39; remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shangyou County, Jiangxi Province, gave a speech at the National County Preschool Education Supervision and Evaluation Promotion Conference on experience exchange. It was said that the county currently has 564 kindergarten teachers, including 350 teachers in public kindergartens and 214 teachers in private kindergartens. name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are currently only 134 teachers in public kindergartens in the county. This is the result of adding 86 public kindergarten teachers in the past five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Shangyou County has innovated a mechanism. Public kindergarten teachers are composed of two parts: the approved establishment number and the employment registration number. In response to the shortage of teachers in public kindergartens, the county editorial committee approved the total number of registered kindergarten teachers, and publicly recruited 216 registered kindergarten teachers within the total control, which better met the needs of teachers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Increasing local financial support is the basis for ensuring teachers’ remuneration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yantai High-tech Zone has applied for national assessment. According to an article on the website of the Shandong Provincial Department of Education on November 15, from 2020 to 2022, the proportion of preschool education funding in the High-tech Zone has increased year by year, with a cumulative investment of 140 million yuan. Accounting for 23.17% of education funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu Zhaohui, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Educational Sciences, told the 21st Century Business Herald that in 2008, when he participated in the formulation and demonstration of the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot;, he calculated Preschool education funding should account for 9% of local education funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“But except for developed areas such as Beijing and Shanghai, many places have not yet achieved this.” Chu Zhaohui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problems of incomplete preschool education guarantee mechanism and insufficient universal resources, the Ministry of Education and other three departments’ &quot;Opinions on Implementing the Action Plan for Expanding and Improving Basic Education in the New Era&quot; clearly stated that students in public kindergartens in various regions In principle, the average public expenditure standard should reach 600 yuan per person per year in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The lack of funding guarantee will inevitably affect the recruitment of kindergarten teachers and the guarantee of wages and benefits. Therefore, to truly attach importance to preschool education, we need to improve funding guarantee, especially the financial subsidies for private inclusive kindergartens must be in place.” Zhaohui said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访国际货币基金组织原秘书长林建海：中国在IMF的“份额”大幅提升只是时间问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261014]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the first year after the epidemic, my country’s economic recovery momentum has attracted the attention of all countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the International Monetary Fund (hereinafter referred to as the IMF in English) raised China&#39;s economic growth forecast for 2023 and 2024, saying that China is building a high-quality, sustainable and inclusive economy. Efforts are being made on multiple fronts to achieve sexual growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The IMF is the world&#39;s two largest financial institution alongside the World Bank. It has the important mission of promoting international monetary cooperation, supporting trade development and economic growth, and preventing policies that are detrimental to prosperity. Whenever there is an economic crisis or financial crisis globally or locally, the IMF will always appear in time. Therefore, the IMF is known as the &quot;fire brigade&quot; in financial crises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reform and opening up, our country has gradually become an important member of the IMF. Since the restoration of its legal seat in the IMF in 1980, my country&#39;s &quot;quota&quot; share has jumped to the third place; since the RMB joined the Special Drawing Rights (SDR, also known as &quot;paper gold&quot;) in 2016, it is the IMF&#39;s currency based on the recognition of member states. A book asset that is allocated according to the share of contributions to the IMF and can be used to repay IMF debts and make up for the international balance of payments deficit among member governments.) Currency Basket So far, the weight of the RMB in the currency basket has been increased to 12.28%, becoming an international reserve currency. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did my country and the IMF go from acquaintance to becoming important partners? How can China gradually increase its “share”? Why does China’s “share” not match China’s proportion in the global economy? What far-reaching significance does the increase in the weight of &quot;inclusion&quot; have on the internationalization of the RMB? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Lin Jianhai, former Secretary-General of the IMF and Executive Vice Chairman of the International Financial Forum (IFF). Since joining the IMF in 1989, Lin Jianhai has served in the IMF for more than 30 years. He grew from an ordinary employee to an IMF executive. During this period, he took office as the Deputy Secretary-General of the IMF in March 2010 and was promoted to the Secretary-General of the IMF from 2012 to 2020. He is the first Chinese to hold this position. He has personally experienced and deeply participated in the entire decision-making process of many major events such as the IMF quota reform and the inclusion of the RMB into the basket. He is the main organizer of major meetings of the IMF and the World Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, Lin Jianhai said that it is imperative for the IMF to play its due role in the global economic system and reform its own governance structure and effectiveness without waiting for others. China&#39;s current share in the IMF is far lower than its share in the global economy. As the economy continues to develop, my country&#39;s share of IMF China will definitely increase significantly. This is not a matter of if, but a matter of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Vo2Gp2TlGRdvAffzQkKNZijggSkQ4rjNVODVgjRA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;475&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/Vo2Gp2TlGRdvAffzQkKNZijggSkQ4rjNVODVgjRA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Jianhai, former Secretary-General of the International Monetary Fund and current Executive Vice Chairman of the International Financial Forum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;RMB&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Into the Basket&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;a milestone&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;international monetary history&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion, how has the relationship between my country and the IMF changed? of? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;my country is a founding country of the IMF and participated in the Bretton Woods Conference held in New Hampshire, USA in 1944. This conference laid the foundation for the stable development of the global economy after World War II and established the IMF and World Bank. At that time, delegations from 44 countries participated in this historic meeting, and the Kuomintang government delegation was one of them. Therefore, the relationship between my country and the IMF can be said to have a long history. In 1980, my country restored its seat in the IMF and opened a new chapter in exchanges with the IMF. Over the past four decades, my country and the IMF have grown to know each other and become important partners. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you personally get involved with the IMF? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Interestingly, although my country did not have many contacts with the IMF at the beginning of its restoration of seats, it has been mentioned in some international financial publications. There is a brief description of the IMF. For example, in the spring of 1981, I co-wrote an article titled &quot;On the Multiple Exchange Rate System and the Internal Settlement Price of my country&#39;s Trade Foreign Exchange&quot; with a teacher who taught international finance at the Beijing Institute of Foreign Trade at the time, which was published in the school&#39;s &quot;Foreign Trade Research&quot; &quot;Phase one. In this article, we introduce the concept and types of multiple exchange rate systems, the IMF&#39;s regulations restricting member states from implementing multiple exchange rate systems, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than forty years have passed in the blink of an eye. In order to write this article, I still vividly remember the scene of browsing reference materials. To be honest, when I wrote this article, I knew nothing about the IMF. At that time, there were no systematic international finance textbooks in China. I only found a brief introduction to the IMF from the teaching materials printed by the school. However, what I didn&#39;t expect was that from then on, I would form a lifelong bond with the IMF. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your more than 30 years of service at the IMF, the relationship between China and the IMF has Which thing in the movie impressed you the most? Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the past few decades, there have been many memorable stories in my country’s cooperation with the IMF, one of which is very meaningful. The thing is that in 2016, the RMB was included in the IMF&#39;s Special Drawing Rights (SDR) currency basket, and together with the U.S. dollar, euro, Japanese yen and pound sterling, it constitutes an internationally freely usable currency officially recognized by the international community. This is a milestone in the history of the development of the international monetary and financial system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerning this matter, I quoted in a short article the then IMF President Christine Lagarde’s statement after the IMF Executive Board meeting: “The Executive Board has decided to include the RMB in the SDR currency basket. The decision is an important milestone in China&#39;s economic integration into the global financial system. It is a recognition of China&#39;s achievements in reforming its currency and financial system over the past many years. China&#39;s continued advancement and deepening in this area will promote Establish a more dynamic international monetary and financial system.&quot; In the book &quot;Turning Crisis into Opportunities - A Closer Look at the IMF&quot; recently published by Xinhua Publishing House, I gave a relatively detailed introduction to the inclusion of the RMB in the basket and its significance. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From learning to active participation and leadership&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just said that my country restored its seat in the IMF in 1980. Is the launch of reform and opening up the main reason for our country to regain its seat? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. The reform and opening up launched in 1978 was a great initiative and a milestone in the history of world economic development. Since then, our country’s economy has continued to grow and develop, and it has become deeply integrated into global economic development and governance. Significant achievements include China&#39;s restoration of its seats in the IMF and World Bank in 1980; China&#39;s accession to the World Trade Organization in 2001; the launch and establishment of the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank in 2015; in 2016, the RMB was added to the SDR currency basket, and the RMB&#39;s status as an international reserve currency was confirmed; By actively participating in the G20, APEC and other summit agendas, my country has begun to play a leading role in some fields. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;my country is deeply integrated into global economic development and governance . What do you think it means? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;my country’s deep participation in global economic governance has not only created a good external environment for its own development, but also played its due role in global economic governance. role. Overall, three aspects stand out: first, from zero participation in 1980 to multi-faceted participation later; second, from one-way to multi-faceted cooperation; third, from learning to active participation and leadership. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you predict my country’s performance in international economic governance? participation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the long run, as our country’s economic strength increases, our country’s participation in international affairs will continue to deepen, and in many economies It has played a certain leading role in , trade and financial issues. Especially with the increase in China&#39;s economic size and the deepening of foreign economic, trade and financial ties, my country is having an increasingly extensive impact on the economic development of other countries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How can our country play a more responsible role? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, our country has a relatively small number of staff in international organizations, and even fewer high-level officials. Therefore, it is necessary to increase efforts to broaden and improve the training of international civil servants, improve relevant international organization management regulations, and provide a supportive environment for international organizations to set up headquarters or branches in China and achieve good operation and development. Our country&#39;s think tanks and universities should also take the initiative to maintain dialogue and cooperation with international organizations and other institutions in this field. They must be able to express their opinions rationally and rationally based on data and facts in the dialogue; they must be good at empathizing with others. , tell the story of China well and make the other party understand the story of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Our country&#39;s share in the IMF is lower than its share in the global economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of the restoration of the IMF seat, my country&#39;s share in the organization accounted for about 2% of the total share. Do you think this share is in line with the national conditions at that time? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1980, my country’s GDP accounted for only about 2% of the global economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;share&quot; of the IMF is equivalent to a country&#39;s shares in the IMF, which constitutes the IMF&#39;s equity capital, that is, its own funds. When a country joins the IMF, it is assigned an initial quota that roughly reflects the member&#39;s global economic size and contribution. The IMF determines share allocation through a formula. The current share formula consists of the weighted average of four variables, namely GDP (weighting 50%), openness (30%), economic volatility (15%) and international reserves (5 %). Therefore, calculating a country&#39;s &quot;share&quot; in the IMF is more complicated. We can simply understand &quot;share&quot; as the relative proportion of a country in the global economy, but it is not exactly the same. This is the difficulty in understanding &quot;share&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Quota&quot; determines the limit of capital contribution of member states to the IMF, and is also related to the amount of loans that member states can obtain from the IMF. &quot;Quota&quot; also determines the voting rights of member states, as well as the allocation of SDRs. the quantity obtained. Therefore, the number of “shares” is very important to member states, especially regarding their right to speak on the international economic stage. This also explains why each &quot;share&quot; reform is so important, but also so difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;36 years after my country resumed its IMF seat, that is, in January 2016 On the 27th, the IMF announced that the 2010 quota and governance reform plan officially came into effect. my country has officially become the third largest shareholder of the IMF. my country&#39;s share increased to 6.394%, and its ranking jumped from sixth to third, second only to the United States and Japan. The share almost doubled. How do you evaluate this achievement? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Currently, my country’s share in the IMF is 6.4%, which is far lower than the United States’ 17.4% and Japan’s 6.5% %, even lower than China’s share of about 18% in the global economy. At the same time, the share of many developed economies, especially European countries, is much higher than their share in the global economy. This is a challenge facing the IMF, which requires the IMF to keep pace with the times and intensify reforms to ensure its legitimacy, effectiveness and credibility. In this regard, the IMF still has a long and difficult road to go. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;IMF&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Reforming in Difficulties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is the IMF undergoing reform? When is it expected to be completed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The IMF is undergoing a new round of quota reform, which is scheduled to be completed in mid-December 2023. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of IMF quota reform is mainly two-fold: first, to increase the IMF’s quota funds to enhance the IMF’s “ammunition arsenal” to help member countries cope with financial crises; second, to adjust the quotas of member countries. share to reflect changes in their status in the global economy, that is, to increase the voice of emerging markets and developing countries. In the IMF&#39;s recent statement, the IMF Executive Board proposed to the Board of Governors to increase the IMF&#39;s share by 50% and distribute it according to the current share proportions of each member country, but without adjusting the share proportions of member countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this so-called &quot;capital increase&quot; is not a substantive increase in capital, but a replacement of part of the non-quota funds with newly increased quota funds, leaving the total amount of IMF loanable funds unchanged. About a trillion dollars. Although the quota reform has made progress, it is understandable that this quota reform is not ideal and does not meet the calls of emerging markets and developing countries to reform the existing international economic governance system and improve their voice. &amp;nbsp;In the current complex international situation, this may be a realistic and desirable reform option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In this way, the IMF has been reforming under difficulties. What efforts have you made in the process of increasing my country&#39;s share? Was it particularly difficult? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From 2012 to 2020, as the Secretary-General of the IMF, I was responsible for the Board of Governors and the International Monetary Fund composed of global finance ministers and central bank governors. Coordinates with the Financial Committee and is responsible for the daily administrative affairs of the IMF Executive Board, as well as the arrangement and convening of nearly 350 Executive Board meetings each year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this position, I have personally experienced and deeply participated in global macroeconomic policy supervision and financial crisis relief work. I have also participated in the reform of IMF quotas and voice rights and the addition of RMB to the IMF Special Drawing Rights currency. basket and other major decisions. During this period, I learned a lot and did a lot of work. I deeply realized the importance of the knowledge, experience, thinking methods and judgment accumulated in the past work process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as quota reform is concerned, I mainly do a good job in communication and coordination, assisting the IMF president to fully understand the views of member countries, eliminate doubts, and reach a consensus as much as possible. This is a long process. For example, the quota reform plan passed in 2010 did not take effect until 2016. It went through countless meetings and face-to-face discussions, but the reform finally achieved relatively ideal results. China rose from the sixth largest shareholder of the IMF to the third largest shareholder. Third, Russia, India and Brazil among the BRICS countries have also joined the ranks of the top ten shareholders of the IMF. Therefore, work is both hard, fun and rewarding, because all efforts are for the benefit of member states and the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Although it is difficult and slow, the IMF is still reforming. How do you anticipate my country&#39;s share in the IMF and its role? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;With the continuous development of the economy, my country’s share of the IMF will definitely increase significantly. This is not a question of whether. It&#39;s a matter of time. In order for the IMF (including the World Bank) to play its due role in the global economic system, it is imperative to reform its own governance structure and effectiveness. This requires IMF member countries to stand at the height of global economic development and changes, transcend narrow self-interests, and work together to promote the reform of voice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The internationalization of the RMB still has a long way to go&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2022, while maintaining the currency composition of the existing SDR basket unchanged, the IMF will increase the weight of the RMB in the SDR currency basket from 10.92% to 12.28%. This is the first review result since the RMB became an SDR basket currency in 2016. Is this the result of the two-way opening up of China’s financial market? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2022, the IMF will increase the weight of the RMB in the Special Drawing Rights (SDR) currency basket from 10.92% to 12.28%. This is the first review completed since the RMB was officially added to the Special Drawing Rights currency basket on October 1, 2016. It reflects the IMF&#39;s recognition of the progress made in China&#39;s financial market reform and will also promote the internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The RMB has become the fifth currency in the SDR basket since October 1, 2016. This is an important milestone for China’s economic integration into the global financial system. It is also a sign of the IMF’s reform and opening up to China, especially the It is a recognition of China’s achievements in monetary policy and financial system. The inclusion of RMB into the SDR basket makes the basket more diversified and representative, thereby helping to improve the stability of the SDR and its attractiveness as an international reserve asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently, what profound impact has it had on the IMF and China? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The currency composition in the IMF SDR basket reflects the importance of these currencies in the international trade and financial system, and its composition and interest rates The level directly determines the level of IMF credit interest rates. The importance of this to lending countries is self-evident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The IMF&#39;s review once again confirmed the rationality of the SDR basket currency combination and increased the weight of the RMB in the SDR basket, which also shows that the internationalization of the RMB is constantly advancing. For China, this is an important recognition and a responsibility, and it is also the driving force for the continued internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If the RMB is to achieve continued internationalization, how can my country’s financial industry achieve a high level? Reform and Opening? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lin Jianhai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking forward to the prospects of RMB internationalization, the following aspects deserve attention:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, economy Sustained growth is the basis for the further internationalization of the RMB. Over the past four decades, with rapid economic development, my country has become the world&#39;s second largest economy and largest trading nation, laying the foundation for the gradual internationalization of the RMB. Continuing to maintain stable economic growth, improving the macroeconomic and financial policy framework, and preventing violent fluctuations in the financial market are crucial to the further internationalization of the RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, reform and opening up is the guarantee for the further internationalization of the RMB. China&#39;s foreign economic activities continue to grow and develop, driving the overseas transactions and use of RMB. It is imperative to steadily advance the opening of capital accounts, continue to expand financial opening to the outside world, and promote the cross-border use of RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, improving the financial system and deepening the development of the financial market are the driving forces for the further internationalization of the RMB. The depth, breadth and openness of the domestic financial market are conducive to enhancing the confidence and use of the RMB in foreign markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, continuous improvement of the exchange rate system is a booster for the further internationalization of the RMB. Adhering to market supply and demand as the basis, enhancing the flexibility of the RMB exchange rate, and giving full play to the function of the exchange rate as an automatic stabilizer in regulating macroeconomics and the balance of payments, will help to give full play to its price signal role and improve the efficiency of resource allocation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifth, promoting cross-border trade pricing and settlement is a breakthrough for the further internationalization of the RMB. China&#39;s huge foreign trade scale is the biggest advantage in promoting the internationalization of the RMB. At present, the proportion of local currency settlement in China&#39;s trade still has considerable room for growth. Starting from cross-border trade pricing and settlement, improving cross-border RMB settlement services can achieve twice the result with half the effort in promoting the internationalization of RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the RMB’s inclusion in the SDR and the increase in its weight are important events for China, the IMF and its member countries, and will benefit the country in the long run. In the foreseeable future, the currencies in the SDR basket will continue to serve as the world&#39;s major reserve currencies. However, compared with the role of the US dollar in the international financial system, the internationalization of the RMB still has a long way to go, and it can be said that there is a long way to go. The further internationalization of the RMB is inseparable from the support of China&#39;s sustained economic growth, high-level opening up, and continuous improvement of the financial system and market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>